Depending on how clever you are and how
much you already know about this topic,
a variety of answers are possible.
Here's the one that I
was really looking for.
It's really just the trivial
lower bound of reading the array.
So that would be an asymptotic cost of
ceiling of n over L, or just n over L.
There's an n because you need to
touch every word at least once.
And you need to divide by L because,
in the best case,
you'll read these elements
one block at a time.
The ceiling would just account for the
possibility that L does not divide n,
but if you left that out, that's fine.
Now, if you happen to come up
with the following answer,
I would've been really,
really impressed.
We'll do that result soon enough.