So what do we exactly mean by state and
measurement?
Let's try to understand with an example.
Say you're looking at a pendulum
swinging back and forth and assume that
it has a marker on it that you can
detect reliably, using one of the corner
finding or template based matching
techniques you've learned so far.
Now we can identify different
quantities to describe the system.
For instance,
the center of the target can be
located using an x and y coordinate.
Similarly, the pendulum
rod has a certain length.
Let's call this l.
The circular weight at
the end has a radius r.
We could even say that the pendulum
makes an angle with the vertical line.
Let's call this theta.
When defining a model for
this system, which of these quantities
would you include in its state, and
which quantities are directly
observable from images?
That is part of the measurement model.
Again, the quantities we are looking at
are, the x, y location of the target,
the length of the pendulum l,
the radius of the circular weight,
r, and
the angle made with the vertical theta.
Mark the appropriate check boxes.