So here's the correct output of
generating an anaglyph image.
We basically use the numpy function
dstack, which takes you know, different
images, in this case, and stacks them
together to create one combined image.
The secret here is also knowing a little
bit about how RGB is represented
in OpenCV.
So if you remember,
in OpenCV images are B, G and R.
The first channel is blue.
The second channel is green and
the third channel is red.
So blue, green, red.
Why do we have image right, and
image right, and image left?
Well, remember, image left is
the one I want to show as left,
because that's where I want the right
information to be for the left image.
And then this is blue and green,
which basically means now as our
mixture of blue and green is cyan.
So if I now basically put
the right image in blue and green,
that will become cyan,
this will remain red.
And just stacking this up together,
you should be able to see result
that will be a stereopair.
We run this, this is the left image.
That's the right image.
And that's the anaglyph image.
Now, I will admit, I actually don't
see 3D vision very well because that
requires both of your eyes to be
equally strong, and many people do have
issues with both their eyes being
perfectly the same strength.