Here's how I completed
my implementation.
My next error was undefined
is not a function, and
that's not a terribly useful error,
but if I look at the line number,
it tells me, it was line six,
in AddressBookSpec.
If I look at that line, I can see it's
referring to this addContact method
of my addressBook class.
So I just need to write this addContact.
I did this by adding a new property
to the class called contacts which
is an array.
I then wrote a new function
called addContact that accepts
a contact as a parameter and just
pushes that contact on to this array.
My next error is on line
eight of AddressBookSpec.
And it's related to my use of
this getContact method here.
That method doesn't exist.
So, I need to go write that.
So, I wrote a getContact function,
which just accepts an index, and
returns the element of
the array with that index.
If I reload my spec runner,
I now see that all my specs are passing.
My address book should be
able to add a contact.