So we have this piece of code and I'd
like you to explain a bit how it works.
For example here, I create a constant
called URL with this type,
and then I create a variable by
calling some methods of this constant.
And I’m using this syntax over here.
So what would happen if
when I called this line?
The URL is empty.
It has a nil.
It's bound to nil and
what would happen if it had a real URL?
>> Okay.
So in the first case here we
have the optional unwrapping so
the case where the URL
is nill the unwrapping
process is going to stop here and
nill will be assigned to string.
However for string two we're
trying to force unwrap URL so
it's the case that it is nil.
Then we're going to crash.
It's kind of like an all or
nothing type of use.
But that can sometimes be good.
Probably not in this case but
in cases like with a view controller
that's getting initialized from
a storyboard you expect there
to be maybe a UI component.
So, you see that happen
quite commonly for
like the IB outlets
to be forced on rend.
>> Okay, so, when would you use this
when you expect something to have
a value which is different from nil and,
if not, it should crash immediately?
>> Right, right, so
like in the case of initializing a view.
If it doesn't initialize
correctly from Storyboard,
then you don't want to crash and you
could go in and check the Storyboard and
figure out what the problem was and
fix it.
>> Okay, perfect, makes sense.