Okay, so given all that, I've come
up with a couple of alternative
ways we could have structured the data.
What do you think we should have done?
Before you dive in,
I wanted to give you some tips so
that you have a foundation for analyzing
the different database schema options.
First and foremost,
when you're making your database schema,
you should be clear what
you're optimizing for.
With Firebase, the first thing
that you're trying to optimize for
is the amount of data
transferred over the network.
You want it to be as small as possible.
This means that you shouldn't be pulling
down tons and tons of data every time
the user changes a shopping list item
if you don't need or use that data.
Of secondary importance is the number
of network requests that you make.
When you're writing to your database,
this means being aware of whether you
should use updateChildren or setValue.
setValue is great for writing data
to one location in a database, but
if you need to write data to
multiple locations in a database,
it's better to use updateChildren.
For reading, analyzing whether
a series of network requests
is excessive is a little
bit more complicated.
Mainly, you want to be aware of how
many listeners that you're making.
I'll show you an example of how you
can tell how many listeners that
you're creating.
Say that you want to have a screen
that shows a user's friends.
One way you could organize the data is
to have a list of friends' emails for
each user.
If we had six users, there'd be
six friends' emails listed here.
Now, in the UI, it looks like you
want to display the name of the user.
So what you'd probably end
up doing is using the email
here as an index into the users data
structure to be able to grab the name.
To count listeners, there'd be one here
to get all of your friends' emails, and
then for each friend,
you'd have another listener that
would then grab their name.
If you have six friends, that is
a grand total of seven listeners.
But there are other alternatives
that you can think about.
If, instead of just storing the email
here, you stored the email and
the user's name,
this means that you would only need
one listener to display this data.
Another alternative would be trying to
cache the user data on the client side.
But at the end of the day, what you
should really be thinking about is if
these extra listeners seem
to be affecting the users.
If they don't,
then you could decide that the data
structure's okay the way that it is.
But you should always be aware when you
might be generating a bunch of overhead
by adding tons and
tons of extra listeners.
My second tip is to
think about the future.
And we really messed up with this
one with ShoppingList++, and
look where we are now.
You should try to think about the parts
of your database that are going to
get very big.
For example, you might ask yourself, how
many users am I going to end up with?
If the app gets extremely popular,
you could end up with millions of users.
On the other hand,
another thing we store in our
app are shopping list items.
So you might be wondering how many
shopping list items might we have for
a single shopping list.
Maybe ten?
Certainly the number's
unlikely to go over 100.
So when you're trying to make a
trade-off between a data structure that
would divide up the number of users
that you need to search through or
display on a screen versus
one that would optimize for
the number of items displayed for
a single shopping list,
you would probably want to choose
one that favors the number of users.
Remember, we kind of already did
optimize for shopping list items
by dividing them up based on
the shopping list that they're part of.
So, at least, that was good on us.
In tip one, I clarified what
you're optimizing for in general.
To apply this specifically to your app,
you should be using your
activities as guides.
And what I mean by that is, take all of
the activities that are in your app, and
figure out, what information do
they need from the database?
For each activity,
you should be optimizing the database so
that it's able to quickly retrieve the
exact information that it needs, again,
with minimal data transfer and
not too many network requests.
My next tip is basically to
take denormalization to heart.
Don't be afraid to have data that seems
like it would be related in different
parts of the app if it optimizes
displaying for one of these activities.
Just make sure that you always
denormalize with a purpose.
A deeply nested database is often
a symptom that somewhere in your app,
you're going to be forced to
download a lot of unnecessary data.
If you see that you have a many-leveled
nest, you should quickly look into
whether or not this is actually
the case, and of course fix it if it is.
But if it's not the case that you're
downloading a lot of extra data,
then a little nesting can be fine.
All right, with all of those tips in
mind, here are some suggestions about
how we could have reorganized our data
structure had we thought of it earlier.
Out of these, check off the ones that
you think might have actually helped.
In the instructor notes below,
I've given detailed explanations about
what exactly each of these means and
what the data actually looks like.
So make sure to take a look at
those before you answer anything.