Well the internet
lights are blinking and
that can only mean one thing,
we've got a Mike incoming.
>> Hey, it's time for
a coding challenge.
>> Couldn't agree more.
Take it away, Mike.
>> Your task is to update the CSS in
a way that doesn't disrupt the currently
running version of the site.
First, to get you started,
you need to get your project
into the same state as Jake's.
Go to the project directory
in the command line and
run git reset --hard to remove
any local changes you have.
Then git checkout task-handling-updates.
This time make sure force
update on reload is disabled.
We want to retain the full
service life cycle here.
Over in the service worker
script in public/js/sw/index.js
your task is to change
the theme of the site.
Thankfully this is pretty easy as all
the colors are stored in variables.
You can see those in
public/scss/_theme.scss.
You can either uncomment the green and
pink theme or make one of your own up.
The only requirement is that
the primary color changes so
that the site's header changes color.
Then in the service worker you
need to update the cache name and
use the activate event
to remove the old cache.
Once you've coded it up,
reload the page to see it working.
In the service worker's dev tools,
you should see a worker
in the waiting position.
Don't let it activate yet.
Instead, head over to
the settings page and
type new-cache-ready into
the test field and press Enter.
This will confirm it's all working.