Here is the implementation of
the queuing lock or the so
called Anderson lock.
The lock is an array and the array
elements have values has lock or
must wait.
Initially the first element of
the array has the value has lock and
all the other elements
have the value must wait.
Also part of the lock structure
is the global variable queuelast.
To obtain a ticket
into this queueing lock
a process must first perform a read and
increment atomic operation.
That will return the myplace so
the index into that particular
process into the queue.
The process will then continue
to spin on the corresponding
element of the array as long
as its value is must-wait.
For the very first thread
that arrives at this lock,
the value of flags of zero will
be has-lock, so that one will
successfully acquire the lock and
proceed in the critical section.
Every subsequent thread, as long as the
first thread is in the critical section,
will come and
will get tickets that will point to some
elements of the flags array that
are from zero to p minus one.
And they will not be able to proceed,
their value will be must-wait.
When the owner of the lock is done with
the critical section, it will reset its
element in the array, you must wait
in order to get this build ready for
the next threads and next processes
that try to acquire this lock.
Notice that we're using some modular
math in order to wrap around this index
read in increment and
just continue increasing the value
queuelast where as our
array's of limited size.
Releasing the lock means that we
need to change the value of the next
element in the array.
So myplace+1, we will change its value
from must-wait, it will become has-lock.
That means that that thread,
that process,
will now come out of
the spin loop that it's in.
Notice that the atomic in this spin
lock implementation involves a read and
increment on a variable, queuelast.
All of this spinning disc implementation
happens on completely different
variables.
So, the elements of the flags array.
For this reason, issuing the atomic
operation, read an increment.
Any kind of invalidation
traffic is not going to concern
any of the spinning on
the elements of the flags array.
These are two different memory
locations, two different variables.
From a latency perspective, this lock is
not very efficient, because it performs
a more complex atomic operation,
the read and increment.
This read and increment operation takes
more cycles than an atomic test and set.
In addition, it needs to perform
this modular shift in order to
find the right index into the array.
All of that needs to happen before
it can determine whether or
not it has to spin or
be in the critical section.
So the latency is not good.
The delays really good however
when a lock is freed, the next
processor to run is directly signaled
by changing the value of its flag.
Since we're spinning on different
locations, we can afford to spin all
the time, and therefore we can notice
that the value has changed immediately.
From a contention perspective,
this lock is much better than any of the
other alternatives that we discussed.
Since the atomic is only
executed once up front and
it's not part of the spinning code.
Plus, the atomic instructions and
the spinning
are done on different variables, so
the invalidations that are triggered by
the atomic will not affect the processor
stability to spin on local caches.
However, in order for
us to achieve this,
we have to make sure that first we
have a cache coherent architecture.
If we don't have cache
coherent architecture,
this spinning has to happen on
potentially remote memory refer.
Second we also have to make
sure that every element
is in a separate cache line.
Otherwise when we change the value
of one element of the array,
we will invalidate
the entire cache line so
we will invalidate potentially
the caches of the other
elements in the array of the processors
that are spinning on other elements.
And that's clearly not
something we want to achieve.
To summarize the benefits of this lock,
come from the fact that it addresses
the key problem that we mentioned with
the other spin lock implementations.
In that everyone saw hat the log
was free at the same time and
everyone tried to acquire
the lock at the same time.
The queue in lock solves that problem.
By having a separate, essentially
a private, lock in this array of locks,
only one thread at a time sees
that the lock is free, and
only one thread at a time
attempts to acquire the lock.