All right, so
I took your comment to mean, and
don't correct me yet,
that when you have multiple bandit arms,
you want to choose the one that
has the highest confidence.
>> That's not what I said, but okay.
>> I said, don't correct me yet.
So here we have two bandit arms,
a and b.
And we've pulled b twice and we've seen
one pay out, and we pulled a once.
And we didn't see it pay out.
So, in terms of expected value,
b is winning.
>> Yes, B is winning.
>> And in terms of confidence,
b is winning.
>> Right.
>> So, what do you think the best thing
to do is?
Do you think at this point we
should just always pick a?
Always pick b?
Or maybe something else.
>> I'm going to go with something else.
>> [LAUGH] All right, so
if we didn't have that third option
though, which would you choose?
>> That depends,
how many more times do I get to do this?
Well wait, I'm forced to always
choose a or always choose b?
>> Yes.
>> I guess I'd always choose B.
>> Yeah.
That actually is not a bad idea but the
fact of the matter is that it's always
this problematic and the reason you want
to do something else is because well,
let me first tell you this because
I bothered to compute it so
I might as well share it with you.
I did the following calculation.
I said, if we were to randomly choose
the payoff rates for both a and b, and
then we pull a once and we pull b twice.
If we happen to see no payoffs for
a, one payoff for
b, how often is it the case that
b is the better arm than a?
>> Okay.
>> And you were right, that from
the data that we have at the moment
b is a pretty good guess and in fact 70%
of the time b is the better of the two
arms, but a full 30% of the time
>> A is the right arm.
So you don't just want to go with b.
because you're going to be wrong
almost a third of the time.
A better thing to do is something else.
So what is, what's an idea for
something else?
What's a reasonable thing to do if we
got an arbitrary number of polls left.
>> So if we have an arbitrary number
than we might as well talk about what
happens after an infinite
amount of time.
If I had an infinite amount of time
then I know my true expected values for
a and b and so I know which one to pull.
Right?
So another way of saying that is
I want to do the thing that gets me
more confidence in my expectations.