Now I want to talk about one more
representation for planning,
called Situation Calculus.
[INAUDIBLE], suppose we wanted to have
the goal of moving all the cargo from
airport A to airport B, regardless of
how many pieces of cargo there are.
You can't express the notion of all in
propositional languages like classical
planning, but
you can in first order logic.
And there are several ways to use
first order logic for planning.
The best known is situation calculus.
It's not a new kind of logic, rather,
it's regular first order logic with
a set of conventions for
how to represent states and actions.
I'll show you what the conventions are.
First, actions
are represented as objects in
first order logic,
normally by functions.
And so we would have a function,
like the function
fly of a plane in a from airport and
to airport,
which represents an object
which is the action.
Then we have situations.
In situations,
are also objects in a logic and
they correspond not to states but
rather to past,
the past of actions that we
have in states base search.
So, if you arrive at what
will be the same world state
by two different sets of actions,
those would be considered two different
situations in situation calculus.
We describe situations by objects.
So we usually have an initial situation,
often called S0.
And then we have a function
on situations called result.
So the result of
the situation object and
an action object is equal
to another situation.
And now, instead of describing
the actions that are applicable
in a situation with
a predicate actions of s,
situation calculus for
some reason decided not to do that.
And instead, we're going to talk about
the actions that are possible in
a state and
we're going to do that with a predicate.
We have a predicate possible of a and
a, is an action a possible in a state.
Now there's a specific form for
describing these predicates.
And in general it has
the form of some precondition
of state s implies that it's
possible to do action a in state s.
I'll show the possibility axiom for
the fly action.
We would say, if there is some
p which is a plane in state s,
and there is some x which
an airport in state x, and
there is some y which is also
an airport in state s, and
p is at location x in state s,
then that implies that it's possible
to fly p from x to y in state s.
And that's known as a possibility
axiom for the action fly.