Before we move forward,
we need to consider how I/O operations affect scheduling.
So far, we know the operating system manages how processes access resources on
the hardware platform.
And this in addition to the CPU and memory will include I/O devices,
peripherals like keyboards, network cards, disks, et cetera.
So in this diagram, imagine a process had made an I/O request.
The operating system delivered that request.
For instance, it was a read request to disk.
And then plays the process on the I/O queue that's associated with that
particular disk device.
So the process is now waiting in the I/O queue.
The process will remain waiting in the queue until the device
completes the operations, so
the I/O event is complete, and responds to that particular request.
So once the I/O request is met, the process is ready to run again, and depending
on the current load in the system, it may be placed in the ready queue.
Or it may be actually scheduled on
the CPU if there's nothing else waiting in the ready queue before it.
So to summarize,
a process can make its way into the ready queue in a number of ways.
A process which was waiting on an I/O event ultimately found its way
into the ready queue.
A process which was running on the CPU, but
its time slice expired goes back on the ready queue.
When a new process is created via the fork call,
it ultimately ends its way on the ready queue.
Or a process which is waiting for an interrupt,
once the interrupt occurs, it will also be placed on the ready queue.