To submit your understanding of loaders,
try this exercise.
Temporarily add log messages
in the places in your app
that have code related to loaders.
I've listed the key spots here.
For example, add a log message
in the activity on create method
at a log message when
the loader is initialized,
when onCreateLoader is triggered and
so on.
Feel free to add log messages
in any other places,
then run the app on your device and
check the log messages and log cat.
Experiment with what will actually
cause the loader to request data from
USGS more than once.
In the notes below the quiz,
I've included some ideas
of scenarios to test.
What if you rotate the device?
What log messages get printed out then?
Does going to the home screen and
back make the loader to load again?
How about pressing the back button?
When you're done experimenting, you can
remove the log messages you've added.
Then click the check box here and
continue to the last coding
task of this lesson.