Okay, let's take a look at the code.
So now I'm looking at
the my application class.
I have a couple of extra imports for
tag manager and container holder.
The variables to hold the container
holder and the tag manager.
Method to get the tag manager,
fairly simple.
Check if it already exists.
If not, get instance to create it and
then return it.
And then we have simple setter and
getter methods to set and
get the container holder.
Now, over in main activity,
again we have some imports.
We need to import PendingResult,
ResultCallback, ContainerHolder,
TagManager.
and Oncreate I call
load GTM container and
here in GTM container I get
the TagManager instance.
I load the container, I set
the callback on the pending result.
I deal with the failure or
in this case I punt that to later.
I refresh the container holder.
I store the container holder,
calling setContainerHolder.
I set a timeout of two seconds for
the container to load.