So far,
we've been loading each daily forecast
into a single scrolling text view.
This is easy, but it doesn't allow
us to create the kind of formatting
we need for
the final version of Sunshine.
in the final version of Sunshine,
the main user interface contains
a list of mostly similar items.
Rather than being a single text field,
each list item is made up of a series
of views for each image and text block.
Allowing us to make a rich experience
containing different font sizes and
images.
Even though only this region of the list
is viewable, our code has to create and
lay out and populate all of
the off screen views as well.
In addition, any images that are
displayed have to be loaded into memory.
This is reasonable for some small
lists with minimal formatting, but for
large lists it becomes impractical.
For each item in the list,
we would have to handle interactions
such as assigning on click handlers.
All of this set up time turns into delay
that the user experiences before they
are able to see anything.
Even worse, since all of these items and
any images they are displaying are in
memory at once, it can cause
the app to run out of memory.
We need another way.