In the notification versus
delegate question, I'm not
100% sure how the candidate
understands this,
because he mentioned that an object
can have more than one delegate.
This is definitely not very usual and
you won't see any class designed
that way in foundation.
So I'm not sure if he was saying
that you can change the delegate.
But I like to make absolutely sure
that whoever is going to join our team
understands that delegate is for
when you have to send information from
one object to a single other object and
one object can only have one delegate.
And notifications are more as he said
broadcast that part was pretty good.
So when you need to send information
to many objects you should use
notifications.
So I have maybe a few
reservations there,
but it looks like he understand
what he's talking about.