Now we have spent a lot of time looking
at various methods of processing images.
So in essence, the same kinds
of stuff can be done for videos.
So rather than apply
to individual frames,
we want to apply it to
whole video volume.
Again, remember, in essence, what
we're talking about is now, basically,
this a stack of volume.
And when the t deck sees this putting
up this way, x and y, sorry, y and
x are still there.
So, in essence, what we're trying to
talk about is how we're going to now
take a video volume, and
this is of course the number of frames,
how would we actually run the filtering
mechanisms we've talked about.
So all of the stuff that we
learned about convolutions,
cross correlation, and
using those methods can be
applied in this case to
a three-dimensional dataset.
So of course,
we can do all of this stuff in 3D.
What we basically do is, our space
that we interact with is x, y, and t.
An interesting point to also remember is
that this kind of motion information and
filtering is widely used in compression
for videos too, not only do in images.
Remember we talked about
compression briefly.
We just did this in space,
that is in x and y, but
now we can actually do this x, y, and
also use the motion information in t,
to compress the amount of data.
Similarly, all the stuff we looked at,
change detection for
doing gradient computation,
we looked at how to do this in x and
y where we can do this
thing also in video.
Except that this time around
we can apply an x and t and
also y and t, besides x and y.
So now we have three
different dimentions.
So simple observation that I like to
make right now is that if I have two
images, and if each and every pixel
from that one image to the other
image is different, then it's just
likely that there is a drastic change,
or a motion change
from those two frames.
So, for example here in this image,
you're seeing a lotta changes,
but they're changes right
in certain parts of it.
What we could be actually doing is,
if this whole image, each and
every pixel changes, then we can
actually look for a much drastic change.
And those kinds of drastic
motion change could actually
be indicative of something
special about the video also.