So the first one seems tempting.
You have these values.
Why not use them directly?
But note that these are just
likelihoods of observing x.
They are missing prior probabilities.
The probability that our random pixel,
regardless of its value,
is a skin pixel or not, is important.
Take this image for example.
All these pixels on the face and
on the neck are skin pixels.
But as you can see,
this is a really small area
compared to the total image area.
If this is all the data that we had,
then the prior probability of a pixel
being skin pixel would be pretty low.
Say around 0.2.
The sum of this and the prior
probability of not skin must sum to one.
So therefore that value would be 0.8.
These two values must be multiplied
on their respective sides
to weight the likelihoods.
All of a sudden,
the distinction is not as clear.
Okay, so the first one is not enough.
The second choice is
exactly what we're after.
If we find that the probability of skin
given x is greater than the probability
of not skin given x,
then we have no reason not to
believe that it is a skin pixel.
Well, that was clear.
Okay, the third choice is exactly
the same as the first one, except,
we have the prior's multiplied.
So yes, this is a valid condition.
You'll see why shortly.
The last one is a little less useful.
In fact,
it's the same as the second form but
with P of x multiplied on both sides.
Okay, if it's the same as the second
then I guess it's also valid, but
not too useful.