We started off this whole lecture by showing you two examples of my two friends,
let's look at what happens with those two images.
Here, with the two images, while they found a lot of features,
we detected a lot of features in these two images.
But, we really wanted to find matchable features between these two,
so, the red here points out the features that are common between both of them,
and once I have those, what I can do is, match them,
and that allows me to now, bring those two images together, and
here I'm showing you basically that both those images now match, and, of course,
I could use this, to now create a panorama between those two images,
because what I basically, do is, align those two pixels, and do a little bit of
warping that we've talked about before to allow us to do this kind of stuff.