According to the Center for
Strategic and International Studies and
reports from various antivirus and
security companies,
the correct answer is
$100 to $500 billion.
This is a huge amount of money.
For comparison, drug trafficking
results in about $600 billion a year.
So cybercrime is in par
with drug trafficking.
And you may wonder why
such a huge number.
Now of course, this number includes
the direct financial losses,
such as when a credit card number is
stolen, or bank account is compromised.
But it also includes the cost
due to productivity loss,
such as the need to compare the computer
and systems after a cyberattack.
And it also includes losses due
to intellectual property when
valuable information is stolen.