Color constancy is that the hue of something, the hue and
pretty much saturation, under different color, over different spectra or
color of lighting, you're still good at seeing.
So, you know, you,
you go outside and or you go inside where lights are different colors,
and purple shirts look purple, green, green pants look green.
Purple shirts and green pants together look bizarre.
But you know, it's okay, you can still,
you can still see it, regardless of the color of the illumination.
The same thing, lightness constancy is like,
what I was talking about the, the, the black piece of coal always looks black,
even though more light is hitting your eye from the black piece of
coal outdoors, than from the white piece of paper indoors.
So humans are very good at perceiving ,.
What color a surface would have looked like if the light had
actually been white?
So you sort of remove the effect of the illumination.
We're pretty good at also being able to figure out what's
actually hitting our eyes, so you can say well it's a bluish thing, but
I actually see kind of a more purplish light coming in.
You can sort of make that distinction.
What humans are not so
good at is being able to tell you what the color of the light is,
because they're brain is spending all this time trying to eliminate,
the color of the light and they're not so good at being able to report that.
So there are lots of methods that are used to try to
accomplish this kind of computationally.
One method is.
Let's suppose I don't know the color of a light, but
I want to render something well on, say, a color CCD image.
Right?
Well, one thing you can do is you can say,
let me assume that the average color is gray.
That the average intensity is gray.
And so those of you who have auto white balance on your cameras.
And most of us with digital cameras do.
It's essentially averaging over all that and saying.
Let me take a look at all the different average color and
assume that it's really grey out there, so anything that's
makes the whole average not grey is due to the illuminant and I'll change that.
And it works okay it can sort of fail in that.
So, you know that tungsten film, right, so
if you're, if you're, you know, if things aren't, aren't really great,
you're ability to automatically do white balance, is really difficult.
There's another really very simple method,
assume that the brightest thing I see is white.
So that way if the brightest thing I see is actually light blueish, I say okay,
that was really supposed to be white.
So I'm going to assume the light is kind of blue, and
I'll undo the blue light that's there.
Okay, those of you that ever done, manual white balancing in cameras,
you know that you put out a white card, or white piece of paper,
you take an image of it, you say this is a white balance image, and
you're telling it, this thing is really white, so
that any color that you see in there is because of the illuminant.
Pull that out when you're doing the, when,
when you're trying to do the color balancing.
There are other things that say,
I'm going to assume that the colors are supposed to span the entire color gamut.
And so if I see the color sort of shifted, let me try to bring it back and
fill the whole gamut.
So, these methods work sort of okay for photography because,
it turns out that even if you get it a little wrong, your brain,
when looking at the photograph, will often undo the right thing to begin with.
But none of these methods really work well enough for
computer vision in order to analyze what's going on out there.
It's still really an open problem.