So far in our discussion,
we assume that the task that's
executing on the CPU cannot be
interrupted, cannot be preempted.
Let's now relax that requirement, and
start talking about preemptive
scheduling, scheduling
in which the tasks don't just get the
CPU and hog it until they're completed.
So we'll consider preemption.
First in the context of
the shortest job first algorithm.
And for this,
we will also make another assumption or
we will modify another
assumption that we made earlier.
Tasks don't all have to
arrive at the same time.
So we're going to look at
the system that has three tasks.
T1, T2, and T3.
We know their execution time,
so that assumption still holds.
And we will assume that they
arrive now at arbitrary times.
In this particular case,
T2 arrives first.
When T2 arrives,
it's the only task in the system.
T1 and T3 haven't arrived yet.
So the scheduler will clearly schedule
it and it will start executing.
When the tasks T1 and T3 show up,
then T2 should be preempted.
We're using shortest job first,
and T1 and
T3 have shortest jobs compared to T2.
The execution of the rest of the
scenario will look something as follows.
Let's say at T2 when the tasks T1 and
T3 show up.
T1 is the one that's scheduled next.
Then once it completes, T3 is the next
one that has the shortest running time.
So T3 will execute.
And once these two have completed,
then T2 can take the remaining
of its time to execute.
So basically, what would need to happen
in order for us to achieve this kind of
behavior is that, whenever tasks
enter the run queue, like T1 and
T3, the scheduler needs to be involved,
so that the scheduler can
inspect their execution times, and
then decide whether to preempt
the currently running task, task T2, and
schedule one of the newly readied tasks.
Now, so far we talked as if we
know the execution time of a task.
But it's principle, that's,
that's hard to tell.
It's really hard to claim that you know
what is the execution time of a task.
There are a number of factors that
depend on the inputs of the task,
on whether the data is
present in the cache or not.
Which other tasks
are running in the system.
So in principle, we have to use some
kind of heuristics in order to estimate,
or rather guesstimate what
the execution time of a task will be.
When it comes to the execution time, so
the future execution time of the task,
it's probably useful to consider,
what was the past execution
time of that task, or that job.
So in a sense, history is a good
predictor of what will happen, so
we will use the past execution
time to predict the future.
For instance,
we can think about how long a task ran
the very last time it was executed.
Or maybe we can take an average
over a period of time or
over a number of past runs
of that particular task.
We call this scenario in which we
compute the averages over a period of
the past, a windowed average, so
we compute some kind of metric based
on a window of values from the past,
and the window of historic values.
And then use that average for
prediction of the behavior
of the task in the future.