Let's do the vertices
first since they're easy.
These two become one, and
these three become one.
So we should have entered a 2
in this box and a 3 in this box.
For the edges here are the answers.
The interesting cases are this edge,
which comes from these two edges, and
this edge which comes
from these three edges.
This one on the left is probably easy to
see, because it's the simple case of,
well, there are two vertices
connected to the same vertex.
The other case might be a little
bit trickier to see, but
it's the same principle.
You could, for example,
imagine taking these three vertices,
collapsing them into a single vertex.
In which case,
now I have a single super vertex over
here connected to these two guys.
If it helps, let's take a look
at an intermediate graph.
So what I'm showing here is the graph
you get if you first collapse these two
in a super vertex, but
before you collapse these three.
In this case notice that these two
edges would combine into this edge.
So there should be a two here.
I hope you can now easily see that when
you collapse these three vertices,
these two edges will have to combine.
So that's two plus one, or three.