I want to start by introducing you to
a couple of really important properties
about a network whenever you're
thinking about designing algorithms.
Remember that abstractly our model of
a distributive memory machine is a bunch
of computing nodes
connected by a network.
Let's take three examples.
The first is a linear or 1D network.
It's a set of p nodes
connected in a line.
A second example is a 2D mesh network.
Again it's a set of p nodes, but
this time arranged in a grid.
Notice how every node is connected to
its north, south, east, west neighbor.
Now this third network is
a fully connected network.
Notice how every node has a direct
connection to every other node.
That brings us to our first important
property which is the number of
connections, or links.
So given P nodes, a linear network
evidently has P minus one links.
A 2-D mesh network has this many
links which is about 2 times P.
A fully connected network has
about P squared over 2 links.
You care about the number of links,
because it's a proxy for cost.
That is, a network with many wires
will probably be much more expensive
than one with fewer wires.
I don't know what they paid
the person who wired this machine.
But whatever it was, it's not enough.
A second important property
of a network is its diameter.
To calculate it, you take all pairs of
nodes, and compute the shortest path.
Then you take the longest such path.
That longest shortest path,
is the diameter which I'll
denote by capital delta.
For the linear network,
the longest shortest path is the one
that connects the end points.
The end points are separated by P- 1
links, therefore the diameter is P- 1.
What about the mesh?
The longest shortest path is the one
that connects either of these end
points.
The distance is just
the Manhattan distance.
That's basically, root P- 1, followed
by root P- 1 or 2 time root P- 1 links.
A fully connected network has a link
between every pair of nodes so
it's diameter is just one.
Diameter's an interesting property.
Essentially it's a proxy for the maximum
distance that any message must travel in
the absence of network contention.
I really wish I was running on
a network with smaller diameter.