All right, welcome back, and
good job with the first two tests.
So to answer the third question, the
ViewGroup we used was the LinearLayout.
And now let's take a look into
the code of how we accomplished
steps one and two.
So here we are in the list
item layout file.
So to match our code,
we'll need to add a view ID of TextView.
And have this text view,
have an id of default text view.
Now to test it out,
I'm going to show you a cool trick using
something called the tools namespace.
In XML, a namespace provides a way so
that elements don't have name conflicts.
This is similar to having
a very unique family name.
So that no one else will ever
share the same name as you,
even if they might have the same first
name so XMLNS stands for XML NameSpace.
And if you notice here we've been
using another namespace in our
code all along XMLNS:android.
So the attributes that we've been
using in Android already such as
android:layout _width or android:layout_
height all start with Android; and
these are already part of
the Android namespace.
So I want to add a namespace
here called the tools namespace.
So this line here maps the tools
prefixed to this namespace
schemas.Android.com/tools and
this means that any element or attribute
whose name starts with the prefix
tools is part of the tools namespace.
So for each of these two
text views I'm going to add
two attributes using
the tools namespace.
So you may be wondering where I
found out about this text attribute
from the tools namespace.
So the tools namespace was created
by the Android's tools team and
has a bunch of attributes that can help
you out with writing your layouts.
So we can see the attributes were
created by checking out their
documentation online and I just
searched up Android Tools namespace.
So on this page we see a whole
list of different attributes.
So when we scroll down to the bottom,
we see a section about
designtime attributes.
So Designtime Attributes help us when
we're developing our code, but won't
actually show up at runtime, so let's
take a look and see more of them here.
For example, if we add the tools:text
attribute on a text view.
Then in the design preview in
Android Studio, it will show this text.
However, this text won't show up
when the app is actually running,
which is good.
because we don't want all
the text views to always have
this particular text that we've set in.
So you can think of this as
a placeholder text to help us as
developers make sure the code looks
all right when we're testing it
Android Studio.
So let's switch back to the code,
and notice here that I've added two
text attributes, one for
lutti and one for one.
And so making sure that these don't
show up at run time is really important.
Because the list of items will
be created dynamically on
the spot when needed.
So will set the text of the English and
words in the Java code instead of just
hard coding them and specifying
them directly in XML layout file.
And since the text in these text
views will change dynamically,
we won't need to add the Android
text attribute view,
just to help us see what it looks like,
but not actually see it at runtime.
So I'm going to switch back into the
design pane and from the design preview
you'll notice that the text is right
up against the edges on the left and
top sides.
So we'll need to add some padding.
So let's go back to the text pane and
add some padding here.
All right, so let's take a look at what
that looks like in the design pane now.
Nice, so this is what the list item
layout looks after those changes.
While this is not the final look and
feel of the list item in our app,
it's good enough to continue working on
displaying the list of
numbers in our app.