Actually, this was
a very large percentage.
It was over 90%, the people who felt
that it is important that they be able
to control information
that is private and
about them, and they should have
the ability to control that.
So based on this survey, obviously,
what we're saying here is that
internet privacy is
an important thing for people.
How hard they work to protect it,
that's a different question.
But if you were to go and sort of ask
someone, should you be able to control
it, it is not a surprising result,
of course, of this survey.
But yeah, people would like to be able
to control who can get information about
their online things that they do.