This is where a game design start to
be more of an art than a science.
But, I'd argue that GigaGal
should handle her own collisions.
It's GigaGal's jump state and
velocity that will need to change
based on the result of the collision.
So making her responsible
is the logical choice.
Leaving the collision detection up to
the level is also a reasonable choice.
It depends on how smart you
want to make your entities.
There are certainly cases where you want
your game entities to just hold on to
their position, velocity,
and texture, and
not handle any of the logic themselves.
That's not the direction we've
gone with this game, but
it can be a reasonable choice.
The platforms probably shouldn't be
the one checking to see if GigaGal
has landed on them.
If we were organizing things that way,
the platform would need to reach
into GigaGal to fix her fall state and
that's probably not a good idea.
We need to be careful about what
entities can affect other entities,
lest we end up with a complicated web
of interactions that we can no longer
reason about.
We'll come back to this sort of
topic when we add enemies and
bullets to the game.