So let's think about it.
Well actually in fact, the answer, and
we would normally write it this way, M squared N squared right?
Because every pixel I have to multiply all of
the coefficients times the pixels that are underneath.
So there are M times N coefficients.
And I have to do that over all of the N times N pixels.
So the number of operations is on the order of M squared N squared,
which can get pretty large if M and N are moderate size.
Later we'll talk just a little bit
about what are called linearly separable filters.
We don't use them a lot anymore if you've got really fast computers, but it,
it can make things be much quicker.