All right so hopefully you have a better
understanding of why OnClickListener is
interface with an abstract
method called OnClick.
Your role as the developer is to
set up the event listeners for
the input events you want
to handle in your app.
More specifically, for each listener,
you will need to follow three steps.
Number one, define the event
listener and a custom behavior for
when the event happens.
Number two, create a new object instance
of the event listener by calling
the constructor.
And number three, attach a listener
to the view you want to listen for
events on, and I'll show you
the code you need at each step.
First we need to define an event
listener class that implements
the interface.
You can call anything you want as long
as it falls the Java conventions for
naming classes.
In this case, we name the class
NumbersClickListener, and
this code is located in a new file
called NumbersClickListener.java.
When we define the NumbersClickListener
class, the declaration should say public
class followed by the name of the class,
followed by the word implements, and
then the interface name,
which is OnClickListener in this case.
So note that implements is a Java
keyword that has a special meaning, and
you can find a list of these
special keywords in In Java Oracle
documentation here.
We use implements to express that the
NumbersClickListener class will support
the specified interface and provide
code for all its abstract methods.
By implementing
the OnClickListener interface for
every piece in the Android code that
expects an OnClickListener object type,
we can use the NumbersClickListener.
And right before the method we
have this @override annotation.
This means that we are overrriding
the blank method in the interface and
providing our own implementation.
Our implementation of the OnClick
method is that we want a toast
message to pop up that says
open the list of numbers.
We could have provided any other custom
behavior here, this is just an example.
Once we define our
NumbersClickListener class,
we need to create
an object instance of it.
If you remember from the last course,
we have the class template, but
we need to create
object instances of it.
We just created the floor plan,
but we need an actual house.
Remember back to the syntax for
creating an object using a constructor.
To create a NumbersClickListener
object instance,
we can call the constructor for
the class with the new keyword.
This creates a new object,
though we can store in this variable
on the left-hand side, where
the variable is of the static type.
Within the Miwok app,
this is what the code looks
like in the MainActivity file.
We modify the MainActivity so that we
can immediately start listening for
click events as soon as
the activity is created.
We're creating a new
NumbersClickListener object, and
storing it in a variable
called clickListener,
which is of the variable data
type NumbersClickListener.
So once we have an object instance
of the NumbersClickListener,
we need to attach it to the view that
we want to listen for clicks on.
And this is the code for that.
Assuming we have the view stored as a
variable called ButtonView, we just need
to call the setOnClickListener
method on that view and
pass in one parameter argument,
the clickListener variable.
Well how do we know to call this method
with this particular input argument?
Back to our handy dandy documentation.
Here we'll take a look at the View
class, and it has a method
called setOnClickListener,
where you pass in an onClickListener.
Since the NumbersClickListener
implements this interface,
it is also considered an onClick
listener data type, and
we can pass that in as
an input to the method.
Now let's see what the code looks
like within the context of the app.
However, you won't need to
make these changes just yet.
The quiz in the next video will
give you more specific instructions
on what we need to do, so just follow
along and try to understand the logic.
So here I've created
a NumbersClickListener class and
defined it in its own Java file.
Remember that we specify
the package name in the code, so
that our code is bundled under
this unique package name.
Then we have the import statements
because we are using the View and
the Toast classes and we can use them
even though we didn't create them
ourselves because we're importing them.
Then in the class declaration,
we have implements View.OnClickListener.
And I'd like to point out that
we add View.OnClickListener
to be very explicit that we're
referring to the OnClickListener
that is part of the View.java
file in this package.
And recall that we use the dot
operator to access Java class members.
So here in the NumbersClickListener,
I've created an onClick method.
And in it, I've said that when
the numbers category is clicked on,
we choose to display a toast message
that says, Open the list of numbers.
And there you have it,
this is the NumbersClickListener.
Now I want to switch
over to the MainActivity.
And at the end of the onCreate method,
we need to create a new
ClickListener object.
Now, we need to attach the ClickListener
to the numbers category view.
However, first we need to find that
view object in the view hierarchy.
And this process should be
familiar to you from the Just-Java
app in the last course.
So here's how we're
going to write that code.
So to find the view that
shows the number category, so
here I call the findViewById method and
request the view with the id numbers.
So once we find the TextView we can
store it in a variable that I'm going to
call numbers.
Then we can call the setOnClickListener
method on this text view and
pass the ClickListener
object as the input.
So here's how that would look.
So here we set the setOnClickListener
method on the text view and
pass in the ClickListener
object as its input.
So the text view numbers in our case
will store the ClickListener object, and
later, if this text view is pressed,
the ClickListener jumps into action.
In order to test that this Java
code I wrote actually works,
I have to delete some old code that
we wrote for the button click.
So in the activity_main.xml file,
I'll need to delete the Android onClick
attribute on the numbers TextView.
So in the MainActivity, I'll also need
to remove the openNumbersList method,
and this leaves the main activity
with one method, onCreate method.
Now when I run the app on my device,
clicking the numbers category
pops up a toast message, great!
So now my ClickListener code is working.