Hopefully you got something like this.
The taskForPOSTMethod should
start very similarly to how
the taskForGETMethod started.
We should add the ApiKey
to the parameters.
And then for the request,
it should be an NSMutableURLRequest
instead of just the NSURLRequest.
And we want to configure the method to
be of type POST, whoops, there we go.
And then we want to add the header
values or the Accept and
Content-Type header.
And finally we want to
add the HTTP body.
From here the rest of the method
is almost a carbon copy.
The main difference being that we
use completionHandlerforPOST instead
of completionHandlerforGET.
Now the fact that the rest of this
code is almost a carbon copy of
taskForGetMethod means that it could
probably have been placed in its own
method too.
But we're going to pause just short
of doing that like we said earlier.
We're just going to focus on
taskForGETMethod and taskForPOSTMethod.
Now, this is only half the battle.
We have to use these methods.
So, to make this work, we're going to
pair task forget method, and task for
post method, with what we're
going to call convenience functions.
And, these convenience functions
will be the perfect solution for
removing all the web service
logic away from our controllers,
and we'll implement
those in just a moment.
But first,
let's outline our new authentication
flow that we're going to be using.