I want to introduce one more problem that can be solved with search techniques.
This is a sliding blocks puzzle, called a 15 puzzle.
You may have seen something like this.
So there are a bunch of little squares or blocks or tiles
and you can slide them around.
and the goal is to get into a certain configuration.
So we'll say that this is the goal state, where the numbers 1-15 are in order
left to right, top to bottom.
The starting state would be some state where all the positions are messed up.
Now the question is: Can we come up with a good heuristic for this?
Let's examine that as a way of thinking about where heuristics come from.
The first heuristic we're going to consider
we'll call h1, and that is equal to the number of misplaced blocks.
So here 10 and 11 are misplaced because they should be there and there, respectively,
12 is in the right place, 13 is in the right place,
and 14 and 15 are misplaced.
That's a total of 4 misplaced blocks.
The 2nd heuristic, h2, is equal to
the sum of the distances that each block would have to move to get to the right position.
For this position, 10 would have to move 1 space to get to the right position,
11 would have to move 1, so that's a total of 2 so far,
13 is in the right place,
14 is 1 displaced,
and 15 is 1 displaced,
so that would also be a total of 4.
Now, the question is: Which, if any, of these heuristics are admissible?
Check the boxes next to the heuristics that you think
are admissible.