Another benefit of nomparies is that
they support something called vectorized
operations.
The name is taken from linear algebra.
But if you aren't familiar with
linear algebra, that's fine.
For the purposes of this discussion,
you can think of a vector as
just being a list of numbers.
So, for example, one, two three or
four, five, six would both be vectors.
Now in linear algebra you can add
two vectors of the same length.
This is called vector addition.
Now if you were defining vector
addition how would you define it?
Specifically, if you were
to add these two vectors
what would you expect the result to be?
I've added some choices here.
There's no right or
wrong answer to this question,
just select the one you would choose.