Strings and characters in Swift
are pretty much as you'd expect
from our experience
with other languages.
Naturally, the character type
holds a single character and
the string type represents
an ordered collection of characters.
Here we're declaring the variable
excitement as a character.
And here we're defining
myFirstString and
mySecondString, using string literals.
Technically, a string doesn't
have to have any characters.
You can also initialize an empty string,
like so, using double quotes with
nothing in between them, or by calling
the string initializer, like this.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The string type comes with a handy
bag of tricks that makes string
manipulations nice and concise.
Like the simple string concatenation
you saw in the previous exercise.
Here it is again.
This time I'm adding a space
between these two sentences.
And then if we print out the result and
press Test Run,
we can see our two strings are combined.