So, let me step back a step and talk a bit about
overfitting prevention in machine learning
because it's such an important topic.
We talked about Occam's Razor,
which in a generalized way suggests there is
a tradeoff between how well we can fit the data
and how smooth our learning algorithm is.
In our class in smoothing, we already found 1 way
to let Occam's Razor play, which is by
selecting the value K to make our statistical counts smoother.
I alluded to a similar way in the image recognition domain
where we smoothed the image so the neighboring pixels count similar.
This all raises the question of how to choose the smoothing parameter.
So, in particular, in Laplacian smoothing, how to choose the K.
There is a method called cross-validation
which can help you find an answer.
This method assumes there is plenty of training examples, but
to tell you the truth, in spam filtering there is more than you'd ever want.
Take your training data
and divide it into 3 buckets.
Train, cross-validate, and test.
Typical ratios will be 80% goes into train,
10% into cross-validate,
and 10% into test.
You use the train to find all your parameters.
For example, the probabilities of a base network.
You use your cross-validation set
to find the optimal K, and the way you do this is
you train for different values of K,
you observe how well the training model performs on the CV data,
not touching the test data,
and then you maximize over all the Ks to get the best performance
on the cross-validation set.
You iterate this many times until you find the best K.
When you're done with the best K,
you train again, and then finally
only one you touch the test data
to verify the performance,
and this is the performance you report.
It's really important in cross-validation
split apart a cross-validation set that's different from the test set.
If you were to use the test set to find the optimal K,
then your test set becomes an effective part of your training routine,
and you might overfit your test data,
and you wouldn't even know.
By keeping the test data separate from the beginning,
and train on the training data, you use
the cross-validation data to find how good your train data is doing,
and the unknown parameters of K to fine-tune the K.
Finally, only once you use the test data
do you get a fair answer to the question,
"How well will your model perform on future data?"
So, pretty much everybody in machine learning
uses this model.
You can redo the split between training and the cross-validation part,
people often use the word 10-fold cross-validation
where they do 10 different forwardings
and run the model 10 times to find the optimal K
or smoothing parameter.
No matter which way you do it, find the optimal smoothing parameter
and then use a test set exactly once to verify in a report.