Hi, welcome to 2D game
development at Udacity.
I'm Peter,
Developer Evangelist of Amazon.
>> And I'm Jeremy,
a Course Developer at Udacity.
>> With the explosion of mobile gaming,
there's never been a better time to get
your games into the hands of players.
>> And 2D cross-platform game
development libraries make it
easy to write games that run anywhere.
Hey Peter, what was the first
game you ever worked on?
>> Actually, my first project was
the Amiga port of Red Baron which
was one of the first World War I
flight simulators for PC.
How about you?
>> Well the first game I ever touched
the source code of was actually
Asteroids on my graphing calculator.
I hacked it so
I got an unbeatable top score.
But the first game I ever wrote from
scratch was a Choose Your Own Adventure
for the TI83+.
>> Hm, how about you you?
Have you made any games in the past?
>> Or if you're brand new to the gaming
industry what's the first project that
you're itching to write?