This piece of code starts out by declaring a variable called audioPlayer.
And it seems to be using colons and bangs in the declaration.
That's interesting.
Then I notice this if keyword, so that's probably an if statement coming, and
sure enough, we see that there is an else statement a few lines down.
There are also frequent examples of the dot notation, and
I wonder if that is a function call.
There is also a reference to this variable called filePath.
And it seems to me that the name of that file is love_story, and
the type of that file is an MP3.
Oh, and there's the super clue, which is audioPlayer.play.
And it seems to me that this line of code is playing this MP3 file.
So my best guess at this point is that this code seems to
run when the user taps on a song in their iPhone playlist.
Now, we will learn how to write this code in our app soon.
Let's begin making that app.