So let me ask the simple question here.
Why stereo vision?
Here the question that
really comes to mind is,
why do we want to take a pair of
two images taken at the same time?
Pretty much model our human vision
system of two eyes looking at a scene
at the same time,
how can that be used to generate
a 3D geometric model of that scene?
Again, let's start off with our simple
camera model that we looked at.
Here I'm basically going to start
off again with a simple object.
And of course in the real world, here
I'm basically going to give it point P,
capital P, with coordinates X,Y and
Z in the real world.
Let's first take first viewpoint, which
is actually shown by this point here.
And this is, of course, the world
coordinates from this viewpoint here.
And of course this is my image.
So here, basically,
at focal length f is an image.
Of course,
it has its own coordinate axes.
Just for simplicity,
I'm putting the coordinate axes
at the center of the image
plane itself rather the corner.
But you know that's
a simple transformation.
Of course, basically, what we're trying
to do is capture this whole object,
which basically means this ray of
light and really kind of coming
down to small x, small y to point out
this point in the image plane itself.
So that's my image.
And of course, this image parameterized
with both the location and
the image itself by x and y and,
of course, the focal length, f.
Now let's actually take the same
instance that we had looked at before
that was the ambiguity of all
points that lie on this line
actually being a problem because I think
all of those points on this line will
appear to be here on this image.
So, for example this point
will appear exactly here.
So will this.
So will this, and so will this one.
So that's the problem we have.
How can we mitigate this
by another viewpoint?
Well, let's take this as a left view and
this is the right view.
I have another image coming in and,
of course, all of these points
are coming to the point here this is
the optical point of this image here,
and basically converging here.
But now I actually have one, two,
three, four, five rays of light.
This should start telling you that now
we can actually resolve the ambiguity.
Because all these five points actually
now come in in the image plane here.
But this is the only point
that appears here and there.
So, by just looking at these points,
and doing things like triangulation,
we now know exactly this is the same
point that's visible from both.
So no longer are we having
the ambiguity that we had before.
So hopefully this convinces you
that having multiple viewpoints
allows us to now get rid
of the ambiguity and
extract more information about
exactly which point I'm looking at.