We'll start our discussion with a very
simple approximation algorithm, one for
the minimum vertex cover problem.
As input, we're given a graph, and
we want to find the smallest set
of vertices such that every edge
has at least one end in this set.
Recall that this problem is NP-complete.
We reduced a maximum independent
set to it earlier on in the course.
The approximation
algorithm goes like this.
We start with the empty set, and then,
while there's still an edge we haven't
covered yet, we choose one of
the edges from the graph arbitrarily.
Say these two here, and then we add both
of these vertices to the set like so,
and then we go and repeat the process.
Picking an arbitrary edge from
the remaining part of the graph,
let's say these two here, and
then removing all the edges incident
on these two vertices, like so.
And so on,
picking this edge here, and so
forth, removing all edges
incident on those two.
And we keep doing this until
there aren't any edges left.
This set C, which we've chosen,
must be a cover.
Looking back at the original graph it's
not too hard to see that this cover of
six vertices is not a minimum one.
Here is an optimal cover.
It only has three vertices.
So this approx VC
algorithm returned a cover
twice as large as the optimal cover.
Fortunately this is as bad as it gets.
Given a graph G having
a minimum vertex cover, say C*,
the algorithm ApproxVC returns
a cover C such that the ratio
between the cover that it returns and
the optimum one is at most two.
To prove this,
it's useful to consider the set of
edges chosen in this line here.
We'll call this set M.
We use M here because this
set is a maximum matching.
It pairs off vertices in such a way that
no vertex is part of more than one pair.
In other words, this set of
edges must be vertex disjoint.
That means that in order to
cover just this set of vertices,
any vertex cover must include at
least one vertex from each of these.
Therefore, the size of this set M
is a lower bound on the size of
the minimum vertex cover, C*.
Since C* is a minimum cover, the set C,
chosen by the algorithm,
can only be larger.
IT is of size twice M, which is at most,
C star, as we already argued.
Dividing through by C star here,
then gives the desired result.