Here's another interesting
example I'm going to show you.
This reminds me, and
I hope it reminds you folks,
of the kinds of stuff we
see in Harry Potter movies.
By the way,
this work was done in 2000, so
before any of the Harry Potter movies or
books.
And the idea was we basically had was
let's actually put a camera on a person
and create a video portrait, where they
sit and make a few expressions and
then we actually now create a portrait
that actually has them alive,
that is moving around in infinitely
long doing this kind of stuff.
That's what we did in this case is we
basically video recorded a person for
a few seconds and used that to generate
an infinitely long live video portrait.
Here is, of course,
you can see the red bar will jump and
it's kind of showing it's going
from one frame to the other
in showcasing a little bit
more of the alive scene.
Again, to me this reminds me of the
kinds of stuff of video portraits we see
in Harry Potter movies.
In this instance we actually go one step
further and actually we use two cameras.
Remember all of the stereo
stuff we looked at, and
allow it also to kind of give
a little bit of depth to the scene.
So now the video texture is
actually going on when we do have
two different cameras and
we're moving them around and
kind of going from one
frame to the other.
This is referred to as view morphing and
allows us to kind of give it
a much more alive video portrait.
By the way, we will be doing an
assignment on using video textures and
you can actually try to do this for
yourselves also.