[Norvig] I want to describe a notation which we call classical planning,
which is a representation language for dealing with states and actions and plans,
and it's also an approach for dealing with the problem of complexity
by factoring the world into variables.
So under classical planning, a state space consists of all the possible assignments
to k Boolean variables.
So that means they'll be 2 to the k states in that state space.
And if we think about the 2 location vacuum world,
we would have 3 Boolean variables.
We could have dirt in location A, dirt in location B, and vacuum in location A.
The vacuum has to be in either A or B.
So these 3 variables will do, and there will be 8 possible states in that world,
but they can be succinctly represented through the 3 variables.
And then a world state consists of a complete assignment of true or false
through each of the 3 variables.
And then a belief state.
Just as in problem solving, the belief state depends on
what type of environment you want to deal with.
In the core classical planning, the belief state had to be a complete assignment,
and that was useful for dealing with deterministic fully observable domains.
But we can easily extend classical planning,
and we can deal with belief states that are partial assignments--
that is, some of the variables have values and others don't.
So we could have the belief state consisting of vacuum in A is true
and the others are unknown, and that small formula represents 4 possible world states.
We can even have a belief state which is an arbitrary formula in Boolean logic,
and that can represent anything we want.
So that's what states look like.
Now we have to figure out what actions look like
and what the results of those actions look like.
These are represented in classical planning by something called an action schema.
It's called a schema because it represents many possible actions that are similar to each other.
So let's take an example of we want to send cargo around the world,
and we've got a bunch of planes in airports, and we have cargo and so on.
I'll show you the action for having a plane fly from one location to another.
Here's one possible representation.
We say it's an action schema, so we write the word Action
and then we write the action operator and its arguments,
so it's a Fly of P from X to Y.
And then we list the preconditions,
what needs to be true in order to be able to execute this action.
We can say something like P better be a plane.
It's no good trying to fly a truck or a submarine.
And we'll use the And formula from Boolean propositional logic.
X better be an airport.
We don't want to try to take off from my backyard.
And similarly, Y better be an airport.
And, most importantly, P better be at airport X in order to take off from there.
And then we represent the effects of the action by saying
what's going to happen.
Once we fly from X to Y,
the plane is no longer at X,
so we say not at P,X--the plane is no longer at X--
and the plane is now at Y.
This is called an action schema.
It represents a set of actions for all possible planes, for all X and for all Y,
represents all of those actions in one schema
that says what we need to know in order to apply the action and it says what will happen.
In terms of the transition from state spaces, this variable will become false
and this one will become true.
When we look at this formula, this looks like a term in first order logic,
but we're actually dealing with a completely propositional world.
It just looks like that because this is a schema.
We can apply this schema to specific ground states, specific world states,
and then P and X would have specific values,
and you could just think of it as concatenating their names all together,
and that's just the name of one variable.
The name just happens to have this complex form with parentheses and commas in it
to make it easier to write one schema that covers all the individual fly actions.