So cyber insurance was one way to,
remember managing risk accepted,
transfer it.
So cyber insurance is
how you transfer it.
Is not very popular.
Based on a 2014 survey, what percentage
of customer's major insurance
brokers were interested in
buying cyber insurance?
There is more to read about it,
but car insurance is mandated,
you have to have it.
So when it comes to cyber,
the question is how many people
actually are interested in
buying cyber insurance.
Small, which is really,
the exact number is not important.
Is small or significant?
These are the two buckets
you're asked to choose from.
So, what do you think?
Which answer is the right one?
Think and mark, and
then we'll talk about the solution.