Now this is how the finished Miwok app
will look by the end of this lesson.
So if we tap into a category and
tap on a list item.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Each list item will play
the pronunciation for each word.
Let's try it out with some other ones.
Try family members, let's try daughter.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Nice.
How about phrases?
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Now,
how can we go about adding
audio support to the app?
Well first, let's create a plan to help
us scope out the work for this feature.
And while it may be tempting to skip
this question and move on to the answer,
I strongly recommend that you take some
time to think over this question and
write something down.
Now as I mentioned to you in the
beginning of Lesson 3, it's common for
your team to ask you to
build out a certain feature.
And you may have absolutely
no idea where to start.
And that's exactly why we're guiding
you through this thought process
of adding this audio feature.
Remember that you can review
the steps from when we added
the images to the app.
So those steps will be similar
to what we're doing when we
adding the audio to the app.
Now if you need additional help,
remember to check out
the hint below the quiz.
Now after you have your plan, the
biggest question you probably have is,
how do you even play
an audio file on Android?
Now I want you to go online and
research what classes in Android
can help us play an audio file, and
go ahead and write your answers here.
I want to emphasize that the goal
of this lesson is not for
you to become an expert in
audio playback on Android.
The goal of this lesson is to give
you skills to learn a new part of
the Android platform that
you've never used before.
You'll get practice reading tutorials,
scanning documentation and
even building out a small sample app,
all to help you figure out how to add
this new feature into the Miwok app.
And in the future, we hope that you can
apply these skills to learning a new
part of Android that you wouldn't
have ever encountered before.