Let's start by adding the code
snippet that we provided for you.
And add that at the app.
So I'm going to copy that here and
then switch over to Android Studio and
paste it at the bottom
of my numbers activity.
All right so now I want to call
this method that we just added
releaseMediaPlayer when the audio
file has finished playing.
And this means that I need to
register an onCompletion listener
with the media player.
So remember that this needs to be set
up after the media player has started.
So I'm going to add the code below
this line mMediaPlayer.start.
And I let Android studio auto complete
adding the interface callback for
me here.
Now with in the on completion method
callback I can call the release
Media Player method.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So I just realized there's going to be
a more efficient way of doing this.
So instead of creating a new on
completion listener every time we click
on a list item we can just create
a single instance of this on completion
listener and then reuse it each time.
So doing it that way would be more
efficient because we wouldn't be
creating a new object each time
that would take up new resources.
So I want to move this block of code
here that implements the on completion
listener interface and
put it into a global variable.
So here's what that looks like.
So I move the code there was
implementing the on completion
listener interface.
And moved it into a global variable
that I called mCompletionListener.
Now back here again, every time I create
a new media player object and start
the player I can set the on completion
listener to be that global variable.
So I'll pass in mCompletionListener and
to further clarify that I'm
going to add some comments.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
All right, so
that completes the first task.
So we've hooked up the numbers
activity so that when it has finished
playing a sound file, it will
release the media player resources.
Now the second task here says to also
release the media player resources
before the media player is initialized
to play a different sound.
So this might happen if, for example,
the user quickly tapped
multiple list items in a row.
The device may not have enough time
to finish playing each audio file, so
the on completion listener
might not get triggered.
So if we're in the middle
of playing a sound and
the user clicks on
a completely different sound,
then we need to stop and
release the media player resources and
immediately create a new media
player object for the current zone.
So back in the numbers activity in
the on item method here before the media
player is created we should release
the media player resources as well.
We do that just in case it was
configured to play a different
audio file.
Alright so those were all the changes we
needed to do for the numbers activity
and now I'm going to repeat the same
thing for all the other activities.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
All right, so those are all the changes
we need to make to all the activities
and now I'm going to test the app
to make sure nothing broke.
So here's the app running
on my device and visually,
it looks like nothing's changed.
So that's good.
Now let's check to see if
the audio's still working.
So I'm going to tap into
the phrases activity.
So here, whether I click to
play a sound for a word and
just let a finish or I click a bunch
of list items in rapid succession,
the media player resources
should be cleaned up.
So I'm going to first try it with
a single word and letting it finish.
>> All right so now I'm going to
test it with several list items
in rapid succession and
it should cut it off.
[SOUND]
All right so that looks good.