Okay, so we saw how this
linear layout contains two
children text views inside it.
By the way, these background colors
are just a teaching tool to help you
understand that these two children
text views are inside this parent.
The red and blue colors actually
won't show up on the device
unless you specifically set them as
background colors on these views.
To show you what I mean let's
go to the XML Visualizer.
If we drop in the code
to the XML Visualizer,
this is what it looks
like on the device.
So first we have
a LinearLayout viewgroup, and
this is transparent because there's
no background color set on it.
The first child is a TextView
that sets guest list, so
that shows up at the top here.
The second child is a TextView
that says Kunal and
that shows up below the first TextView.
Now, if I copy this TextView and
paste it below this one,
what do you think will happen?
Yup, we have another Kunal that
shows out right below the first one.
Okay, so the pattern seems to
be if we add more TextViews,
here, then they'll just show up
one after the other in this list.
Now let's look at the code more closely.
It starts with an opening
angle bracket and
then the view name,
which is LinearLayout.
Then it lists a bunch of attributes and
then there's a closing angle bracket.
Notice that there's no forward slash
because this is just the opening
tag of the LinearLayout.
The closing tag is all
the way down here, because we
want to insert children elements in
between the opening and the closing tag.
But for example, for this test view,
since there are no children within that,
then we can just use
a self closing tag for it.
Same for this text view here,
and this text view here.
So when we say a view group
contains children views,
then we need to inset them in between
the opening and closing tags.
Now, the other thing you may have
noticed is this attribute called Android
orientation equals vertical.
We haven't seen this before, so
let's look at the Android documentation
like I showed you earlier.
I open up a new browser window, and
then I type in android orientation.
The first result is about
a LinearLayout, and
it's on the developer.android.com site.
So let's click on it.
Just like the textview documentation,
it was a little overwhelming.
We can ignore most of this text.
We just need to verify that this indeed
is the page for LinearLayout, and
then we scroll down and
look at the XML attributes.
Now, we're looking for the attribute
that is called Android orientation, and
here it is.
So let's click on it to
look at more details.
The description says that this attribute
determines whether the layout
should be a column or a row.
The value of this attribute
should be horizontal for
a row, where the value should
be vertical for a column.
And then it lists those two values here.
Cool, so our code currently says that
the android orientation is vertical.
So that explains why the views
are showing up as a column.
Now, to satisfy our curiosity,
we should also try the other value.
Let's set the orientation to be
horizontal and see what happens.
I'm going to go into the code and
erase the vertical value.
I'm going to type horizontal, and look,
now the views are in a horizontal row.
I don't know about you, but
I don't really like to read
my guest list horizontally.
But there are still many other useful
cases where you would want
a horizontal linear layout.
For example, if you're creating a list
item, you might want an image on
the left hand side, and then
a description on the right hand side.
I'm going to let you try this
out on your own in a second, but
first I want to point out
this additional line of code.
This is the XML namespace declaration.
We use this namespace in order to
specify that all of these attributes
here belong to android.
That's why they all start
with android colon.
This is essentially short hand for this
specific URL that's unique to android.
You can actually create
your own custom attributes.
So to prevent name conflicts, where two
attributes are named the same thing,
but actually have different behaviors,
we always add this prefix here,
android:, to signify that
these are android attributes.
So basically, always remember to
add this XML namespace declaration
in the opening tag of the root
view of your XML file.
Now it's your turn.
We want you to be able to experiment
with the linear layout code now.
Try to add more TextViews so
there's more items in this column.
Who would you put on an exclusive
guest list for your party?
Also try changing the linear
layout orientation attribute.
Remember that it can be set
to vertical or horizontal.