Couple of things to point out here now,
and
this is something that you may
have started thinking about.
So, imagine there is a pendulum,
which is swinging.
Of course, in the case of a pendulum,
there are two place it might
be the most similar, right?
When it's coming down this way,
if I'm just doing an image, it's similar
here, and of course, it's coming down,
but it might be also similar
when it's on this side.
So, what will happen in this
instance is something like this.
So, if you notice it started finding
similarities before it's come all
the way down, and of course,
it's kind of jittering because of it.
Again, simply put what
happens in a pendulum is,
that it's similar at this point,
both when it's coming down and up, so
basically it might just do this,
rather than go all the way down.
Well, that allows,
kind of creates a problem, and
the way we fix it is by modeling
a little bit more of the dynamics.
So, the pendulum here is
basically coming this way,
there are two different options.
I want to be able to kind of
make sure that I kind of keep
the motion trajectories in check.
And that allows us to then create,
even an infinitely long
pendulum motion like this.
So, just keeping in mind, and
doing a little bit of look ahead,
modeling the dynamics
allows us to do this, and
the Markov chains
representation supports this.