>> First provide
confidentiality of a message.
This is typically not a strength
of asymmetric encryption,
because asymmetric encryption is much
slower than symmetric encryption.
And therefore let me try to protect
the confidentiality of a message,
we typically use symmetric encryption
instead of using asymmetric encryption.
Therefore, this is not a task that
asymmetric encryption is good at.
Second, securely
distribute a session key.
A session key is used to encrypt
all messages during a session.
For example, a web browsing session.
We can use a session key to encrypt and
provide confidentiality of all
the communications within that session.
This is a task that asymmetric
encryption is better at.
For example, if Alice and Bob wants to
establish a session key between them.
It is easy for Bob for example,
to create a session key and then
encrypt the session key using Alice's
public key and send over to Alice.
It is guaranteed that only
Alice can decrypt a message and
extract the session key, because only
Alice has the corresponding private key.
Therefore, this is a task that
asymmetric encryption is good at.
Third, scalability.
Imagine we have N users and they need to
communicate with each other securely.
For example to have confidentiality
in their communication.
In this case,
we need N square number of keys.
Whereas for
asymmetric encryption, regardless
of how many users are involved.
We only require that each user has
one public key and one private key.
Therefore, asymmetric encryption
is much more scalable.