Here's the sequence I calculated,
h-d-l-b-a-c-f-e-g-j-i-k-n-m-o.
So how did I get that?
Recall that the first step is
to divide the levels in half.
Everything in the upper subtree
goes into the output array first,
followed by the remaining subtrees.
So what about the order
within a subtree?
To get that order,
you apply the partitioning recursively.
So this result HDL is the first thing
you'd get after a whole recursive
partitioning of the upper subtree.
Let's make one last observation
about this ordering.
Notice the traversal path.
If you know anything about
space-filling curves,
the pattern should kind
of remind you of that.
I think it's kind of neat
how the path snakes and
slithers its way around the tree,
don't you?
Thibbit.
That is the sound a snake makes but