Jake, did you sort this one out?
>> Yep, and here is what I did.
Over in showCachedMessages I start
by creating a transaction for
the Wittrs store.
Then I get the objectStore.
Then I get the by-date index.
I use getAll, which returns a promise
for everything in the index.
And I pass the results to addPosts.
However, the messages here will be
in date-ascending order by default.
So, I reverse them so
the latest post appears at the top.
I want to see how this update
works the natural way.
So I'm going to bump the service
worker cache version.
Then over in the browser,
I'm going to disable Force update.
Then I'll refresh the page.
There's our update.
We'll take it.
And now,
if I take the server offline and
refresh the page,
we get the last post we saw.