Open up the ViewController.swift
file and navigate to the top.
Here you see a line that shows the
ViewController class that inherits from
UIViewController. If you hold down the
option key, you can see that the cursor
changes to a question mark. Move the question mark
over to the ViewController and left click.
Clicking anywhere else dismisses
the documentation pop up. And I'll show
it again. We hold down the option key and
left click. And left clicking on the
UIViewController shows us some
documentation for that particular class.
Another way to see the full
documentation is to hold down the option
key and double-click the
UIViewController. This will show you a
full documentation window. Let's click on
UIViewController. Another way to find this
documentation is to go to the menu bar
for Xcode. Go to Help and then
Documentation and API Reference, and we
can see that option here. You can also
get this window to appear by pressing
the key combination shift command + 0
anywhere in Xcode. Just like that.
Take a moment now to look for the
viewDidLoad() function under the
UIViewController documentation