For anything to interact,
with the physics engine, we need to set
a collider component, to whatever
game object we're interested in.
These come in four main types.
Box, capsule, mesh and sphere colliders.
These colliders, define the area that we
want to apply physics, onto our objects.
As you might infer from their names,
the box, sphere and
capsule collider all represent generic
shapes that we can use for collisions.
In fact, if we create a standard Unity
cube, sphere or capsule, they will
already have their corresponding
collider attached and ready to go.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
If we have an object that
doesn't fit any of those shapes,
we can create our own mesh and
use that for collision detection.
Once we've appropriately
defined the collision area for
an object, we then need to assign
a rigid body component to it.
A rigid body is a component
that enables a game object
to interface with the Unity
physics simulation.
It contains many properties such
as mass, drag, and whether or
not to use gravity, just to name a few.
And with some programming we're able
to add a lot more dynamic interactions,
such as applying forces,
updating an objects velocity, and
detecting collisions.
To get started playing
around with physics,
let's create a really simple scene.
First let's create
a plane at the origin.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
A sphere called ball.
And a cube that will act as our ramp for
the ball to slide down.
Once we have the scene set up by
positioning and scaling our ball and
ramp, all we need to do is
add a rigid body to our ball.
Now, we can just hit play, and watch
our ball slowly roll down our ramp.
And all that movement is calculated
by the Unity physics engine.
Neat, right?
Now that we've set up this simple scene,
take some time now to play around with
all of these parameters,
and create a fun slide.
Afterwards, let's dive into how
we can use physics and scripting.