Hi, and
welcome to the lesson on VR interaction.
So, Chris,
what do you think are the most
important elements of VR interaction?
&gt;&gt; Well,
I think that in virtual reality,
what's important is that instead
of the traditional two-dimensional
user interfaces we're used to,
the whole world becomes interactive.
So we'll be using scripts to make
3-D objects react to your gaze and
then you can use these
objects as well as
traditional user interface to move from
scene to scene and put it all together.
&gt;&gt; Very cool, yeah,
that sounds like a lot of fun.
&gt;&gt; We'll also be looking at how you
can change scenes so that you can
put together an entire interactive
experience that the user can go through.
And I think it'll be a lot of fun.
Let's get started.