The first watch has an OLED display
with low-bit ambient mode and
is currently in ambient mode.
The correct answer for
this is number four.
It does not use an NTA listing,
the colors are solid and it uses less
than 5% of the screen to save
battery and not burn in the display.
We have an OLED display with
a low-bit ambient mode and
it's currently in interactive mode.
The correct answer for this is number
one, the watch is in interactive mode.
So full color animation and anything
else, so totally fine and recommended.
The next watch has an LCD display, which
does not show color in ambient mode and
it is currently in ambient mode.
The correct answer for
this one is number two.
Since it can show grey scale images,
although three and
four would also be acceptable here.
And for the final question,
we have an LCD display,
no color in ambient mode and
we're currently in interactive mode.
The correct answer for
this one is also number one, as well.
The watch is in interactive mode.
So full color animation and
anything else are totally fine and
recommended here, as well.