All right, so now we have a nice
structure for a pets table.
And we know the columns that we want,
so Name, Breed, Gender and Weight.
Now what?
So for the rest of this lesson, you'll
learn how to make SQLite databases
outside the context of Andriod.
And doing so
will prepare you using SQLite later when
we put it into our Pets app in Andriod.
Now, what exactly is SQLite?
SQLite is a library
that makes it easy for
us to create a local database on the
device that our app is interacting with.
Now the Lite part of it, refers to the
fact that it's a lightweight version of
a typical database.
So there are more heavyweight
database options such as MySQL,
which offer more complicated features.
We won't be dealing with
this option in this course.
So for SQLite no server is needed,
the data is saved into a text
file locally on our device.
The SQLite library is free and
open source.
It's built into Android which is why
you'll be learning this particular
database library.
You can also use SQLite in your Android
apps without needing to download or
install anything extra.
And you can also use the SQL
library directly on your computer,
which is what we'll be doing next.
So while SQLite is on our phone already,
it
is not something that comes necessarily
pre-installed on our computer yet.
So that's why I'll be giving you some
instructions soon about how to download
and install SQLite onto our computer.