So far, we've created the contract that
will define what the database looks like
for the rest of the application, but we
haven't really created a database yet.
To do that, we need to create
a new class known as DBHelper.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Because we will be using
SQLite as our database,
we'll extend the Android Class
SQLiteOpenHelper to create our DBHelper.
SQLiteOpenHelper exists mainly to take
care of creating the database for
the first time, and
upgrading it when the schema changes.
The DBHelper also provides other classes
with a reference to the database,
giving them a way to access its
information through queries.
SQLiteOpenHelper provides us with
two important methods, onCreate and
onUpgrade.
OnCreate is responsible for
creating the actual database for
the first time,
while onUpgrade is responsible for
making sure the database
schema is up to date.
We'll be overriding both onCreate and
onUpgrade in our DBHelper class.
In exercise two, create the database.
Open up WaitListDBHelper.java, and
modify the class declaration
to extend SQLiteOpenHelper.
Inside the DBHelper class, create
a final string called DATABASE_NAME
to specify the database file name,
let's call it waitlist.db.
This will be the name of a local file
on the Android device that will store
all our data.
Then create another final integer to
store the current database version
number.
This should always start from one,
and anytime you decide to modify
the database schema in your code,
you should increment it.
This will force users to
upgrade their databases,
whenever you release
a new version of the app.
Also, don't forget to
change the contract if you
ever do change the database schema.
The constructor shouldn't do anything
special here, so let's just simply call
the parents constructor, and let the
parent class handle everything for us.
To call the parent constructor,
call super and pass through the context,
which is usually the calling activity,
the database name, and
the version number.
This null argument is supposed to be
something called a CursorFactory, but
we won't be using one in the scope of
this app, so let's just pass null.
Now it's time to override
the onCreate method that will
actually create the database
file when called.
Start by writing the SQL statement that
will describe the database schema.
Remember to follow the contract that
we created in the previous exercise.
And SQL CREATE TABLE statement
starts with CREATE TABLE,
followed by the TABLE_NAME and
the table description.
That is a comma-separated
list of each column name,
followed by its type,
all in a set of parenthesis.
Here's what our SQL CREATE
statement should look like.
The ID column is our primary
key with autoincrement,
meaning that it should generate its own
values each time we insert a new row.
The GUEST_NAME is just the text
field that cannot be null.
The PARTY_SIZE is an integer
that is also not null.
Finally, the TIMESTAMP field
is of type TIMESTAMP, and
the default value is TIMESTAMP,
which means the SQL database system
will automatically assign the current
time, every time a new row is added.
Notice how we've used the constant
strings from the contract to
programmatically generate
this SQL String.
This is because if we decide to rename a
column in the future, we'll only need to
do so in the contract and every time
we reference that column in the app,
it will automatically be updated.
Once we get our string variable
SQL_CREATE_WAITLIST_TABLE ready,
we can now call execSQL on our database,
passing in that string,
which creates the database.
The last step is to override
the onUpgrade method,
this is only called when
the version number we defined
earlier becomes larger than the version
number of the database on the device.
It's meant to update the database
schema, without losing any user data.
So ideally, this should include
a schema update statement.
Since we only have one version so far,
all we'll do here is drop the current
database if it exists and
create a fresh one.
But say later on you decide to add
a new column to the WaitList_Table.
Then you should change
the version number up here to 2,
and implement onUpgrade with an SQL
statement that would append that
column to the database
without having to drop it.
Perfect, if everything
is done correctly,
then you should be able to pass all
the test that we've created for you.
Try to follow these steps yourself and
see if you can pass all the tests,
then you can run those tests
by doing a right-click, and
going down to Run 'Database Test'.
And when it comes up,
it will ask you which device
you want to run the test on.