All right. So, look, that ends the motivation and sort of what computer vision
is and why you might do it and how we're going to do it in this class.
Arvid, you have anything else you want to add?
>> Yeah.
I just hope that you're excited about the course by now.
To make sure that you don't listen to the entire course like a podcast,
I'm going to step in with some annoying little quizzes.
>> Annoying, huh?
>> Yes. >> Oh, okay.
>> They we'll find out.
>> Okay.
Arvid has been practicing all his life about how to be annoying,
that's what his mother told me.
So I think he's got it down.
But anyway, it's time we get started, it's a bit of work but
I think if if you do it, you'll learn a lot of computer vision, so
let's strap ourselves in and just get going.