Now remember, one of the things that
we've talked about in this class,
is how the camera has evolved.
Our relationship with the camera has
gone from this kind of a tripod setup,
to much more distant, to even
this kind of casual relationship.
And that's what's important and
especially true now that we have
cameras like this or even Go-Pros, which
is like the, one I showed you earlier.
And you know variable cameras and
stuff showing up.
So more and
more of these devices are coming up.
So now we need to start looking at
other ways of doing stabilization
without actually having to carry a
profession rig like the one we just saw.