So first,
spy on employees of a specific company.
You can do this with a trojan horse.
For example, the trojan horse can come
in the form of a utility program,
such as a company calendar,
that also spies on the employees.
The second task,
cripple an organization's computers.
This is a logic bomb.
For example, a logic bomb can be
inserted into the company's computer
servers so that when the time is right,
the server will shut down.
The third task,
quickly spread information and
drive traffic to a specific website.
This is a virus.
As we know, virus can spread quickly,
for example, through email attachment.
And, when triggered, it can perform
a number of malicious activities,
such as driving traffic to a website.