So basically you're saying that
iterative deepening is almost free
because of the exponential
nature of the problem?
>> Yep.
>> And I bet that iterative deepening
really helps when you have a game like
Isolation with a widely
varying branching factor.
>> How so?
>> Well, when we calculated that
we should only go nine levels deep
in a five by five isolation tree
to return within two second,
we assumed the branching
factor of eight, yet
toward the end game, isolation players
only have a few moves available.
We might be able to search
much more deeply at end game.
>> And often,
end game is precisely the time that
you want to search more deeply so
you can see what will happen.
>> On the other hand,
at the beginning of the game,
the branching factor is quite large.
Our compter player might not
return within two seconds.
>> Correct, iterative deepening
means that our computer player
always has an answer ready
in case it runs out of time.
And it can search as far as possible
within it's time constraints.
We limited our time to
two seconds per move.
Yet, in some games, like speed chess,
we limit the total time a player
can take for the entire game.
In those situations, our computer player
will want to search deeper at some
parts of the game and
shallower at other parts of the game.
Often we can create a strategy for
how deep we want to search.
>> So something like having a book
of standard initial moves for
the beginning of the game,
then search deeper in the middle and
use less time towards the end, relying
on the reduction and branching factor,
and iterative deepening to still allow
our computer player to search the end
game, or as deep as it can
given the remaining time.
>> Or we might want to have
a conservative amount of time we
dedicate per move and
use iterative deepening and
quiescence search to determine the few
moves we want to spend extra time.
All these are great strategies, but
we can still get in trouble due to
something called the horizon effect.