In this example,
I'm going to create a few constraints.
This is mostly for educational purposes,
as we won't be doing this very often.
Mostly, we'll used stack views for
RUI and most of the time we will create
constraints only for
positioning the outermost stack view.
In order to create a constraint,
we can do it two ways.
By Ctrl dragging, and
also by using the constraints icon,
the one that looks like a TIE Fighter.
In order for
the position of a view to be 100% clear,
we need four constraints,
two vertical and two horizontal.
Actually, there's a shortcut that
allows us to specify the exact position
with only two constraints,
one vertical and one horizontal.
Can you think of it?
If a view has an intrinsic content size,
then we only need to set two
constraints, as the remaining
information can be obtained from
the intrinsic content size.