So, for this quiz, I want you to try and
create your own customized watchface.
You'll notice in
the SweepWatchFaceService and
the AnalogWatchFaceService that
it draws an mBackgroundBitmap.
The existing bitmap is a very dark
gradient, so you'll barely see it.
What I want you to do is to
replace the image this references
to your own custom image.
So, you could put up a picture of a
friend or a pet, like my dog Mila here.
You can use any 320x320 image
in either PNG or JPG format.
Don't use anything too large, or
it could cause the watchface to
run out of memory resizing it.
Also, make sure you test your watchface
in interactive and ambient mode.
You'll need to hide the background
image in ambient mode, and
clear the canvas to black instead.
So, go and implement your change in
either the SweepWatchFaceService or
the AnalogWatchFaceService.
And then test it on your device or
emulator.