The model of noise we have, and we're going to refer to it as a generative model
because I have a model of how the noise is actually put within the system.
Essentially we have a particular model that we believe in.
Computer vision, you have to have faith.
The model that we believe is, there's actually some real line underneath.
And that each point has been perturbed off that line.
Here it's written as epsilon.
By some Gaussian noise that has moved you off that line.
And the probability of a Gaussian goes down by a function of what?
X squared.
So if you wanted to find the most likely solution, you would want to
find the points that make the data that you're observing most likely.
So those would be the ones where the sum of the square distances are the least
because, and things,
just thinking about the Gaussian, won't go into too much detail.
If you assume all those points were independently done, so the probability of
getting all those points is just the product of those probabilities.
The product of those probabilities is a product of all those Gaussians.
Those Gaussians go e to the minus x squared.
When you multiply all those e to the minus x squared, right?
You just sum up all of those x squareds and so whatever makes that sum of
squared difference the smallest, right, will be the highest probability.
And so,
there's a whole bunch of assumptions going on underneath here in terms of
the probability distributions and being independent and all that kind of stuff.
But basically this idea of minimizing the perpendicular least squares comes from
this idea that closer points are more likely, right?
It's more likely a point will land closer to a line then
further away from that line, if the point actually came from the line.
Got that?
That's going to be important to remember for, for our next lesson.
All right.
So that's written here in this equation.
Basically we're saying the point x y that we actually measure is just some
real point on the line u v, okay?
That has been perturbed in the direction perpendicular to that line, a b,
that's the line that we were solving for.
And that perturbation has been some amount of noise that came from a Gaussian
with a zero mean and some standard deviation sigma or variance sigma squared.
So, for the line fitting or in this case,
a model fit in general, this is our underlying generative model.
That it is a Gaussian perturbation.