So do you get it now?
Do you now understand how you
can earn money from an app?
Yeah!
And the great thing is that we haven't
even started coding our app yet.
This way we can plan right from
the start how to get ads in our app.
Creating a great experience for
our users.
That's right.
Designing your app from the start with
ads in mind is the way to look at it.
I got these ad things cold down now.
I can't wait to get started!
Hold on.
Hold your horses.
We've barely scratched the surface.
There are so many more things
to learn and use for ads.
For example, analytics.
So you can see how the user
interacts with your ad.
There is mediation, to interact
with additional ad networks, and
house ads, to cross promote
your ads in our purchases.
And then you can also.
Okay, Okay.
I understand, but
don't confuse the student.
Dear student, look at the instructor
notes here for lots more information.
And since there is so
much more in ads we might just create
the sequel lesson to cover those.
Now, you're talking.
And, you there student,
have enough to get started.
That's right.
Happy coding.