I tried to put a little mathematics into this to try to understand it.
So, say we have a document that's 1,000 lines long.
And our viewport is 100 lines high, high.
Then our handle would need to be one-tenth of the tray as we scroll.
So the size is dependent on that relationship between,
how many lines can currently be displayed by the viewport, and
how many lines in total does the document have?
>> Kay, sounds, sounds good.
The size of the scroll bar handle with respect to the size of
the scroll bar tray indicates the portion of the document's lines provided by
the file manager that are currently visible in the viewport.
We're going to call this the handle proportion association, and
it's also a ternary association.