So, now that you have
the pets app codebase for
this exercise, I'd like you to take
some time to analyze the starter code.
So in order to help you focus your
attention on important components,
go ahead and
answer these five questions.
So, first name the 2
activities in the code.
Second, what type of button are we
using to connect the 2 activities?
Are we using a toggle button,
a floating action button, or a spinner?
And third, which of these many
options exists in either activity?
And check all that apply.
So, is there a Delete All Pets
menu option, an Insert Dummy Data
menu option, a Settings menu option,
or perhaps a Quit menu option?
And fourth, what type of view allows
us to show a dropdown menu for gender?
Did we use a checkbox,
a picker or a spinner?
And fifth, what activity method do
you need to override in order
to handle menu option clicks?
Did we override the onCreateOptionsMenu,
the onOptionsItemSelected() method or
perhaps the onClick() method?
So go through these questions and
then have fun looking through that and
starter code.