Now it's time to make some changes in
Sunshine so that you always get fresh
data and you display a notification
everyday when the weather updates.
To do this,
we'll first start by setting Sunshine up
with a background
synchronization IntentService.
This IntentService will keep
the database up to date with
live weather information
from the server.
Next, we'll optimize this so
the synchronization should only happen
if the database was never
synchronized before.
After that,
we'll be using FirebaseJobDispatcher.
We'll schedule a job that runs every
three to four hours that performs
the same synchronization process.
And finally, we'll have
Sunshine trigger notifications
everyday with updated
weather information.
As usual, the exercise code provided
has all of the steps you need to follow
marked as to do comments.
And the solution code is also there
to help you if you ever get stuck.
Good luck.