Most of this feedback was really useful.
Feedbacks one, four, and
five, all expressed confusion
at the design, and a sense that the user
cannot do what they need to do.
Feedback number two,
is a useful thought on a question we
weren't hoping to answer just yet.
Which is also awesome.
Users will often bring to your attention
things that you should endeavor to
keep in your app.
And its important to listen to them.
However, feedback number three,
is less useful.
For two important reasons.
First, as a low fidelity prototype,
we haven't settled on a font yet, and so
we can't make use of feedback
about the font we've chosen.
Secondly, this feedback is a suggestion.
Suggestions are great at identifying
places that need to change, but
should never be followed blindly.