Welcome, this lesson is all about
elements and how to size them.
At this point you should feel pretty
comfortable applying style with CSS and
picking the right elements for the page.
Now that's great, but
you haven't really explored
changing the sizes of elements yet.
So that's what you'll be
doing in this lession.
You'll be learning how to use something
called the box model to change
the dimensions of your elements and
along the way, you'll improve the way
that you write meaningful
markup with semantic elements.
To help out, James is going to be there.
Hey James.
>> Hey there.
>> Now, before we jump into the box
model and semantic elements, James and
I are going to play a quick
game called guess the render
Now this is going to help us demonstrate
just how useful semantic elements are.
>> Cam, by playing a game
do you mean you're going to be
playing a game and
I'm going to be winning a game?
>> No.
James and
I are actually in different rooms and
can't hear each other at the moment.
I have no idea what he just said.
I'll assume that he said
he's probably going to win.
But I don't need to respond because
I know I'm going to win because
I rigged the game.
Now, to play guess the render, James and
I wrote a handful of HTML files for
some simple sites.
Hezekiah is going to pick
out two files ar random, and
give one of my files to James and
one of James' files to me.
Whoever can read the HTML and
draw the website closet to the way it
should be actually rendered will win.
And I rigged it because I
know that Hezakya is going to
give me some HTML that
uses semantic elements,
while James is just going to get
one big mess of divs and p tags.
>> That's fair.
>> Yeah I know.
Well, take this over
>> All right, will do.
This is going to be fun.