To begin talking about this course, let's look at the learning goals.
In this course, you will learn what operating systems are,
why are they needed, and how are they designed and implemented.
This will include discussion of key mechanisms and abstractions that
operating systems must support to provide the required functionality.
In this course, we will cover a number of topics in depth.
In particular, we will describe the design and implementation of
operating systems' abstractions, mechanisms, and policies related
to several of the key types of functionality provided by operating systems.
This includes processes and process management, threads and concurrency, and
in general, challenges related to multithreading.
OS functionality for managing hardware resources like CPU and memory.
OS services for communication and I/O, which includes file I/O.
OS support for distributed services, including remote procedure calls.
We call those RPCMs.
Distributed file systems, distributed shared memory.
And we will briefly review systems software that's common in data center and
cloud environments.