Here are the solutions for the systems.
The first system turns
out to be inconsistent.
The second system has unique solution,
X = 4, Y = 3, Z = 1.
And the last system has
infinitely many solutions.
The parameterization of
the solution set is X = 3- 2Y.
Y equals Y and Z = -4.
Let's look at how to
solve the first system.
Start by clearing the first
column underneath the top X term.
We'll subtract the first equation
from the second to get 2y- 3z =3 and
then add the first equation to
the third equation to get 2y- 3z=-1.
These bottom two equations don't look so
good.
We have the same quantity on the left
hand side equaling both 3 and
negative 1.
In fact, after subtracting
the second equation from the third,
we have the contradictions 0 =- 4.
So we can stop here.
The system is inconsistent and
has no solution.
Now let's look at the second system.
We need to have an x
term in the top equation
in order to proceed with
eliminating the first column.
So let's start by swapping the first and
second equations.
And then we can subtract three times
the first equation from the third.
The X column is cleared, so
now we can start clearing the Y
term in the third equation.
We can do this by adding
the second equation to the third.
We're now in triangular form and
we have three distinct leading
variables in the three rows.
So things are looking good for
us to have a unique solution.
Now let's solve for
z by multiplying the bottom equation
through by negative one-third.
And now we have that z = 1.
Now let's add the third equation
to the second equation,
which incidentally gives us that y = 3.
Finally, let's subtract the third
equation from the first
to finish clearing the last column.
This gives us x- y = 1 in
the last thing we need to do
is add the second equation to the first
to finish clearing the why terms.
This gives us the unique solution
x = 4 y = 3 z =1 to the original
system of equations.
Now let's look at the last system.
Our first step will be to subtract
3 times the first equation
from the second equation.
This makes the second
equation into your- z =4.
Then, we'll add the first
equation to the third,
which gives us
an equation reading 0 = 0.
Our equation is in triangular form now.
So we can identify the pivot
variables which will be x and z.
Since y is not a pivot variable,
we have a free variable,
meaning we're going to have an infinite
number of solutions to our system.
Now, we can go ahead and
ignore the 0 = 0 row, because
that's just redundant information.
Concentrating on
the first two equations,
to isolate z, we need to multiply
the second equation through, by -1.
This gives us z=-4, then we can subtract
the second equation from the first to
eliminate z term in the first equation.
This means the first equation reads x +
2y= 3, since the pivot variables x and
x are now in only one equation each,
we can parametrize the solution set for
the system in terms of
the remaining variable y.
If the point x, y,
z is in the solution set then
by rearranging the first equation
x will equal three minus 2 y.
Y, since it is a free variable
will be equal to itself and
z because of the second equation
will equal negative four.
This gives us a parameterization
of our solution set.
With the base point of 3, 0, -4,
in a direction vector -2, 1, 0.
So in our answer boxes we write
x = 3- 2y, y = y, and z = -4.