In this exercise, I'm going to
show you how to use traceview,
to identify a function that's
messing with your apps frame rate.
Now if you want to follow along,
you'll need to download the compute and
memory sample app from the linked
in the instructor notes below.
After you install the sample app,
go ahead and press the slow on click
handler button, you'll notice
the familiar dancing pirate.
Then go ahead and press the button
labeled,display an image.
See as you can see, the pirate's dance
pauses and then resumes again when you
do this, and then the Android image
is displayed underneath the button.
Just like before,
it seems like pressing the button,
relates to the pause in
the pirate's dance, so hopefully,
you know what comes next, and
more importantly what tool to use.
We're going to profile
the app using traceview, so
let's go ahead and do that.
All right, so I want to come
over here to my devices list and
make sure that the compute activity's
selected, before we start profiling,
I'm going to click on the slow unclick
handler to launch the activity,
let's go ahead and
start a trace, like so.
Go ahead and hit OK, all right, so the
trace is running now, let's go ahead and
click this display an image button,
and there we go.
Let's stop our trace.
So let's go ahead and
look at our output.
All right, so we have a lot
of data here in our output,
but what does all of it mean?
Now here's a task,
look through the traceview output and
see if you can identify some methods
coming from the sample app,that
are using significant CPU resources.
Jot down your top two answers here.