Now, here are the changes that
we made to the NumbersActivity
to use an array list
instead of an array.
We had started out with
an array of words, but
to change it to an array list, I'm
going to change the data type here and
put in string between angle brackets.
Now, notice that the A and
the L in ArrayList are capitalized
because we're using
the exact name of the class.
And also remember to capitalize
S in string because string
is an object data type and
not a primitive data type.
So, we'll keep the words variable and
to initialize the surrealist
we also use the new keyword,
but will modify this portion.
So we have ArrayList and
it stores a String
object out of types and
we end up with two parentheses.
And notice that these are empty
parentheses because there's no input for
this constructor.
Now since we've changed the data
type of the words variable and
your pseudo complains
with a bunch of errors.
Now let's take a look
at fixing these errors.
In order to add an element to an array
list, we need to call the add method and
pass in the new element.
So rather than using the assignment
operator like we did for the array.
This is how it would
look in the ArrayList.
Now I'm going to delete
the portion from the array.
And when we're done adding all
the words to the word array,
this is what the solution
should look like.
And now it looks like we have a lot
of errors in the log messages and
let's check out how we can update that.
Instead of accessing an array
element with the name words
followed by the position
index in closed in braces.
We're going to access each element in
the array list by calling the get method
on the word's object.
So this is what that would look like.
In here we're passing in one input,
which is the position index.
So I'm passing in zero because I want to
cheat the element at the zero the index.
All right, so I finish typing
out the rest of the logs and
I've modify the comments to reflect
that we're using an array list now.
And great, all the errors are gone.
Now let's run the app on the device to
make sure everything still works okay.
So when we open the numbers activity,
the screen is blank and that's expected.
When we take a look at the Android
LogCat we see messages in the log.
So the output should be
the same as last time, but
this time we accomplish the results
with an ArrayList instead of an array.