Understanding that there could be
a number of different objectives behind
creating segments, let's explore a few
examples of how the objective of
your analysis helps determine
the data to use for your model.
For example,
to create a benchmarking system,
we would definitely need data
around the store attributes itself.
Data like square footage of the store,
the hours the store is open, and
how long management has been
assigned to the specific store,
are just a few variables to
think about having available.
Plus, you might want data on street
traffic accessibility, and how many
employees are assigned to the store,
along with how many hours they work.
Population around the store
can also be important,
as well as how many
competitors each store has.
However, if our objective for
the segments is to create manageable
pricing rules for our products and have
them clustered into store segments, some
of the store attributes we mentioned for
the first clustering objective might not
be nearly as important as say, income or
life stage demographics for
people living around the store.
Distance to the competition and the type
of competition could be important,
as well as whether stores are in
a certain regulatory zone.
And finally, if the objective is
to optimize product allocation and
space planning, that along with area
demographics, important data to include
would be product category sales history,
sell-through, which can measure
allocation and pricing effectiveness,
and product discount trends.