Let's talk about a question
that actually comes from an ad
that was run on TV by a well known
computer vendor, I will not name it.
But that ad basically claimed
that its systems didn't suffer
from any of the ailments that the
competition system had to worry about.
So this claim that was made by
this vendor who said it's system
was superior, and when it came to
security could have been well founded,
or it may have been a marketing thing.
Here we want to sort of dig deeper and
to sort of think about vendor A and
vendor B, and
they both supply operating systems.
And vendor A's making this claim about
better security that its
system offers in some sense.
So what could be
the basis of that claim?
So we haven't talked that
a lot about how one would
validate this sort of a claim, but
we know what a trusted system is and
what requirements it must meet.
And we also talked
about the threat model,
that is who targets these kind of
systems, and one of our design
principles said it is easier to get
things right when they're simpler, okay.
Complexity is the enemy,
leads to vulnerabilities that
can be exploited and so on.
So I want you to use your
knowledge about threat modeling,
about design of secure systems,
and the trusted computing system
requirements to think about the options
that we have here and check
the ones that you think there is some
reason to believe that it may be true.
Once you do that, we'll come back and
talk about the answers.