In this example, initially the first
ten pages will be loaded into
memory one at a time,
as they're being accessed one-by-one.
First page 9, then page 2, then page 10.
Now at this point,
page 11 needs to be accessed.
And that will mean that the first page,
which is the one that's least recently
used, needs to be swapped out of memory,
given that the physical
memory only has 10 pages.
Now the really unfortunate thing is that
just as we swapped page 1 out of memory,
given that the pages are accessed
one-by-one in a loop,
that exact same page, page 1,
is the very next page that's needed.
We will have to demand page that in.
And given that our physical
memory has 10 pages,
we need to pick out another
page to swap out to replace.
And that's going to be page 2,
given that that's the least
recently used page right now.
And guess what, the next page that will
be needed will be exactly page 2 that we
just swapped out.
So the process will continue for
all of the remaining pages during
the execution of the program.
And therefore, the nearest percentage
of the number of pages that need to
be demand paged using
the LRU policy is 100.
This is clearly a very
pathological scenario.
But what it's trying to demonstrate
is that an intuitive policy such
as LRU can result in really poor
behavior under certain conditions.
For that reasons, operating systems
can be configured to support different
kinds of replacement policies that are
used to manage their physical memory.