We said multiple times throughout this
lecture that the exact details of how
a distributed shared memory system
should be designed or how the coherence
mechanisms will be triggered depends
on the exact Consistency Model.
But before describing
several Consistency Models,
let's first explain what
is a Consistency Model.
Consistency models
exist in the context of
the implementations of applications or
services that manage distributed state.
The consistency model is
a guarantee that the state changes
will behave in a certain way,
as long as the upper software layers
follow a certain set of rules.
For the memory to behave
correctly what that means is that
we're making some guarantees how our
memory access is going to be ordered.
For the memory to behave correctly,
what that means is that
the way that the operations will
access memory will somehow be
representative to how those operations
were issued in the first place.
And that, we will be able to make some
guarantees that whenever somebody is
trying to read the memory location
that the value that they will see will
be a value that's representative of what
was written to that location recently.
Now, what it means is that a consistency
model guarantees that the memory will
behave correctly, that the accesses will
be correctly interleaved and the updates
will be correctly propagated only if
the software follows certain rules.
That implies that the software
needs to either use specific APIs
when it performs an update or when
it requests to perform an access, or
that the software needs to
set certain expectations,
based on what this memory guarantee is.
For instance that I'm just not going
to enforce that updates the particular
memory location are written in the exact
same order as they were issued.
If the software knows this
particular information,
then it is up to the programmer to
use some additional operations,
such as locking constructs or similar
in order to get the desired behavior.
This is not something that's
specific to a distributed system.
Even in a single CPU, when we have
multiple threads that are trying to
access a particular memory location,
we know that there's no guarantee how
those thread accesses will be ordered.
And which particular update
will be returned when,
let's say, thread end tries to
read a particular shared variable.
If we want to achieve some guaranties
that are stronger than that,
the software will have to use locks,
would have to use atomic operations,
would have to use some counters.
So, a consistency model, it specifies
how the memory will behave and
the upper layers of the software
must understand that and
set their expectations accordingly.
At the same time, the memory
layer may export certain API's,
certain operations like
the locks that we mentioned.
And then, if the software
uses those API's correctly,
then perhaps the memory system can
make even stronger guarantees.
In the discussion of consistency models,
we will use timeline diagrams
which will look like this.
Which will show when certain operations
occur according to real time,
based on some neutral
external observer that sees
everything instantaneously
the minute those operations occur.
Our notation for
this is as follows: R_m1(x) means that
this value x was read from
a particular memory location m1.
What this means here, is that at
this particular point of time,
the value x was read
from memory location m1.
And then at this later point in time,
the value y was read
from memory location m2.
Similarly, W_m1(y) means that the value
y was written to in this case,
memory location m1.
So, at this particular point in time,
the value z was written
to a memory location m3.
We will also assume that initially at
the start of this timeline diagrams
all of the memory set to zero