We just enabled email and password
authentication in Friendly Chat.
Now, we'll make some minor adjustments
to add Google Authentication.
First, we need to provide a way for
Friendly Chat to communicate
with Google Authentication.
To do so, we must add support for
a URL scheme to our app.
A URL scheme is a means and protocol for
communication with other apps.
For more information on URL schemes and
how apps communicate,
check out the link in the resources.
The URL scheme that we want to
add is the reverse client ID,
which can be found in the Google
service dash info file.
So let's navigate to that file and
find the reverse client ID.
Copy it, and then select the friendly
chat Swift app to see the app settings.
Click the info tab, go to URL types,
and you'll see a box for
a URL scheme labeled reversed client ID.
Paste your ID into this field and
you can leave the other fields as blank.
Now, Friendly Chat has
a means of communicating
with Google Authentication, but
there's still a little bit left to do.
Let's go back to the app
delegate in Friendly Chat.
In order to use Google Authentication,
we must provide functionality for
handling when the app
transitions to a web URL.
Like the Google sign-in page,
that's what this function is for.
We've already included the code
to handle passing data from a URL
back to Friendly Chat,
we just wanted to point that out.
Now we need to tell our authorization
view controller to include Google
as an authorization provider.
Open FCViewController and add a new
import for FirebaseGoogleAuthUI.
Now go back to
the ConfigureAuth function.
This is where we want to specify
authorization providers like Google.
The default authorization UI has an
array called providers where we can set
this up.
To add Google, we just need to add
the FIRGoogleAuthUI object in the array.
And that's it.
Now Fiendly Chat is enabled
with Google Authentication.
Go ahead and run the app and
you'll see the Google sign in button.
When we click on it we're redirected
to the Google sign in page.
And I'll log in with one
of my Google accounts.
Once I complete the login flow, it may
or may not ask me to allow Friendly Chat
to access my email address and
basic profile information for Google.
I'll go ahead and click Allow.
Awesome, the login flow is complete.
Now let's try sending a message
with this new authenticated user.
And as we can see the display name for
this message is updated since I'm using
my Google account instead of
the other account we saw previously.