The file is created by a certain user.
So the file belongs to user Alice,
let's say.
She then becomes the owner of this file.
And let's say here she
can choose to decide
who should have access to this file,
and in what manner.
So if confidentiality is
what we are concerned about,
then what kind of access
should be controlled for
this file that contains
this confidential data?
Okay, so that's the quiz about.
Remember, entries in an access
controlled matrix cell
in a matrix ACM that we just defined,
are some subset of access rights.
So here is the question of saying,
if confidentiality is important what
access rights should you focus on?
What should be present in that entry
in an Access Control Metrics or
what right should not
not be present in it?
So think about the 3 options, and so
let the one that you think
makes the most sense