Believe it or not the correct answer
is that they have the same scope.
In both cases the browser
has to assume the worst.
Meaning that the change
invalidated the entire dom.
The browser then has to keep the entire
dom in scope while it's running layout.
This is the timeline panel in dev
tools which you'll be spending
quite a bit of time with
later in this course.
To see what happens when I click around
on the page, I will go ahead and
click this button which
starts recording and
then I will click once, twice,
three times and then stop recording.
Like I said, you'll be spending quite
a bit of time with this tool later in
the course, so I’m going to quickly zoom
in and show you what you need to see.
This is the first click event which
affected the geometry of the body.
You can see that the click
lead to other pieces of work,
including this one right here.
Which is the layout that was triggered.
I can scroll down and see that the scope
of the layout was the whole document.
Which means that the entire
dom was in scope.
Okay now that shouldn't be too
surprising because the click effect
the body.
But I wonder what it looks like for
the other two elements.
Here's the second click event,
which affected the top level div.
And this is the resulting layout.
Notice that, in this case,
the scope is still the whole document.
Meaning the whole DOM was in scope for
this layout event.
Now I'll look at the last one.
Here's the last click
event on the child div.
So this div is the farthest
down on the DOM.
And here's the resulting layout.
Once again, notice that the scope of
this layout is still the entire DOM.
You may have noticed as I was going
through the clicks that the different
layout events affected
different numbers of nodes.
But the whole time
the entire dom was in scope.
In case you're wondering,
it's possible but
very difficult to limit layout scope.
You can use something called
a layout boundary but Paul and
I won't be getting into
that in this class.
Check out the instructor notes for
more information.
So if there is one take
away from this question,
it's that the layout
process is complicated and
it's probably best to assume that
the entire dom is always in scope.