It's been awhile since we coded
a toy app from scratch so
this next bit is review.
But it's important set up for
the main event of sending in intent and
recreating the toy app you just saw.
If you want to follow along with me,
open the O4A exercise
add new activity folder.
Use the new activity wizard to create
an empty activity named ChildActivity.
You can also select the type of
activity from the drop down.
ChildActivity receives a text
string from the main activity,
so let's set that up.
Add a TextView and set the idea of
the TextView to tv _display and
while we're at it we'll adjust the text
size and add some default text.
Finally in the ChildActivity class
we need to create a variable to
hold a text view.
On create, we retrieve a reference
from the Text View form the layout.
Because we haven't
created the intent yet,
running the app still
shows the main activity.
We can verify that our ChildActivity
was properly created by editing
the android manifest to launch
ChildActivity instead of main activity.
We can do that by moving this intent
filter, which says to launch this
activity when the application starts
from main activity to ChildActivity.
And when we run our app again, we see
it with the default text we added.
Now before I forget,
let me switch that back.