Remember that a bitonic merge
is a sequence of splits.
And a sequence of splits is
just a set of minmax pairs.
Now the input is a length eight, so
the first split should pair elements
that are four away from each other.
Now with this pairing, the first four
wires will be one bitonic subsequence,
and the second four
wires will be another.
You should then split
these two subsequences.
Again, within each subsequence,
which is of length four, pair elements
that are two away from each other.
Let's see, so what would that look like?
This should give you four
bitonic subsequences.
We then repeat with the remaining pairs.
To make this a little bit easier to see,
here is what the final
network would look like.
Check it by computing a trace
of the values on each wire.
A good follow up exercise
is to compare this circuit
with the bitonic merge pseudo code.