Now for the answer--Is this a Bohr Bug, which is repeatable under
under a well-defined set of conditions?
Well, if you include a debugger in the conditions, it could be a Bohr Bug.
Normally, we don't do that.
Heisenbugs change as the program is being observed,
and therefore, this is a perfect instance of a Heisenbug.
Mandelbugs have very complex causes--not the case over here.
A Schroedinbug appears as soon as somebody looks at this program,
and it probably stops working--Not the case over here.
I would love to see a Schroedinbug in practice.
It's a very interesting theoretical concept.
So, how does this bug come to be?
What we have here is a C-specialty.
This is an initialized variable.
When in a C program, we read an uninitialized variable as in here.
Then the behavior of the program is undefined
according to the semantics of C and also C+ does follow.
Since the behavior is undefined, crashing was a perfect option.
When executed normally x would simply take
whatever random value was on the stack.
Therefore, the assertion would fail.
However, the debugger would always set the entire stack to zero
before execution, and therefore x would take a zero value.
Therefore, the assertion would hold.
You can even have such distinction between running normally
and being run on a debugger on purpose.
Some malware actively checks if it's being run in a debugger
and then automatically turns itself off.
So, if you try to diagnose on malware,
the malware may be specifically set up to prevent all sorts of probing.
If you suspect a Heisenbug,
think what the debugger does differently than the normal execution,
and observe the program execution by at least two independent means,
say a debugger and logging output or two different debuggers
or whatever you have in order to find out what's going on.