All right? Well, what's the answer?
Well, the answer is still six, remember there were six degrees of freedom?
There are, only three angles heading, pitch, and roll.
Euler omega, phi, kappa, or whatever.
There are, three angles that define that rotation matrix, so
that's not nine independent numbers, all right,
there's only three angles, and then there are three translational values, and
that's why there are still six extrinsic parameters,
even though we can use a three by four or sometimes even a four by four.
So, we've just basically taken away of turning those six numbers into a matrix
form that allows us to apply it to the location of the points in one frame,
to get the location of the points of another frame.