We have our basic response status line,
and
just like the request, the status line
is followed by a number of headers.
I'll give you a few examples.
Here are some headers that are commonly
included with HTTP responses.
Now, just like the client request,
the headers that you see
aren't always the same.
Some of them are required.
And when I say required,
I mean usually there.
But the web has evolved organically
over time, so many of the headers that
are required are often not there,
or things will work without them.
But anyway, okay.
So Date is there all the time,
that's when the request happened.
No surprise there.
Server, this is similar to
the User Agent header on the request.
This is the, generally the name and
version number of the server
that's handling the response.
Now, personally,
I try to never include this.
Or if I do include it,
I make something up.
Because otherwise,
you're just giving free information to
a would-be hacker who wants to know
what vulnerabilities work against you.
Content- Type, very popular.
This is the type of document
that's being returned, this is so
your browser knows how to display it.
So text/html is a common one, obviously.
That's what an HTML page would be.
You could see image/png, or image/gif
if it's an image, that sort of thing.
Your Content- Length is how long
the document that follows is.
Content- Length is often included but
it's not strictly required because
the browser will know when that
document's done receiving data
because the connection may close.
There's other ways of also telling the
browser that I'm done sending data, but
it's not super relevant
right this second.