The next step in the off-low is
to authenticate the user using
the movie data base website.
In code, we go right into this step and
we call it the login with token method.
Let's dive into this method and
see how it works.
First, we construct the URL
specified in the documentation that
ends with our request token.
Using this URL, we create a request, and
then we create a instance of
the TMDBAuthViewController.
This TMDBAuthViewController
itself contains a UIWebView.
If you haven't used a UIWebView before,
it's a view provided from UIkit that
can be used to display web content.
So once we create this ViewController,
we start setting its properties that
are going to control how
the WebView behaves.
Notice this really important step here.
We set the ViewController's
completionHandlerForView property equal
to the completionHandlerAccepted
by the login with token method.
What this will allow the ViewController
to do is to redirect execution
back to our API client,
once the WebView has dismissed.
So now the real question, how do we
know when to dismiss the WebView?
Let's run the app to gain some insight.
If I tap the authenticate button,
then the WebView should appear.
Now this WebView will appear with
either this screen or the login screen,
if you haven't logged in yet.
But once you log in, let's click Allow.
The next screen tells us
that we have given consent.
But we need to dismiss the view.
Now let's go back to
the TMDBAuthViewController.
The key to dismissing this view is
implementing a function that's part of
the UIWebViewDelegate.
In particular, we need to determine when
the WebView has redirected us to a page
that confirms that the user has given us
consent, like when they clicked Allow.
So for this exercise,
you'll be implementing this behavior.
First, determine the appropriate
UIWebViewDelegate function to use.
This function should allow you to check
the URL that is loaded by the WebView.
And you'll want to check if the URL
indicates that the user has
given consent.
If that URL is loaded,
then dismiss the controller.
When you're done adding this
functionality, check this box.