Let's see another way to use memcache.
You don't have to set anything
up to get ndb to use memcache,
but you can also use the memcache API
directly and save custom strings to it.
So we're going to use memcache for
saving and
getting announcements about
conferences that are nearly sold out.
You can imagine, for example, that your
web application might display a banner
ad to encourage people for
conferences that are nearly sold out.
There might be other things you would
want to announce on your website too.
Maybe if you get a special speaker for
a particular conference or
to announce a special promotion.
For the sake of simplicity, we're just
going to create announcements about
conferences that are nearly sold out,
because the goal here is just
to learn how to use memcache.
But announcements are a good example of
the kind of thing you might want to save
in memcache without saving
them to the datastore.
If an announcement gets evicted from
memcache, there's no loss of real data.
And it doesn't really matter,
no business transactions are affected.
No one loses their
place at a conference.
And the next announcement will
likely come along soon, anyway.
Announcements are very transient and
they don't need to be saved for
long-term or backed up.
So they're perfect candidates to be
saved in memcache and only in Memcache,
they don't need to go in datastore.
That way you get all your announcements
without using any datastore quota.