Now it's time to finish creating our
new view by drawing its contents.
And we do that within our
custom view's onDraw method.
Now the Android canvas is pretty
standard, as far as canvas APIs go.
Used as a painter's algorithm,
meaning that each new thing you paint
will cover anything beneath it.
The canvas and paint classes.
Up for a variety of brushes and
help us to draw and fill lines, boxes,
circles, and text with colors,
patterns, gradients, and images.
As well as offering the ability to move,
rotate, and
scale the campus while you draw.
And I could spend a lot of time here
detailing exactly how to use each of
these tools, but
there's nothing unique to Android and
it's covered really well on
the documentation link below.
It is possible though to create
pretty advanced UIs this way.
For example if we start by drawing
a circle and then add a second circle,
and then you just need to finish
drawing the rest of the compass.
Here's an example I prepared earlier.
The specifics of what you draw are
different for every view, but one thing
that is consistent is the resource
constraint device you're drawing on.
And that the onDraw method will be
called every time the screen is
refreshed.
Potentially many times a second.
That means any object created
here within your onDraw method,
including things like paint
objects will be created and
destroyed with alarming frequency.
Object creation and destruction can
be expensive on Android, potentially
affecting the smoothness of your UI
when garbage collection is initiated.
The solution?
Move the scope of any object
used within the onDraw loop.
Into the class scope.
Go ahead and override the onDraw
method within your new view, and
draw the new control.
In fact, why not take this opportunity
to create a custom control
that can display the wind speed, and
direction fused within sunshine.
Once you're done, you can add it to your
layout, using its full package name and
class name in your XML, like this.
Run it, and then post a screenshot
of your new view into the forum.