Given that we have chosen a Training and a test set, it is important to
think of how the classifiers perform for a given size of the Training set.
Learning curves are a plot of the model performance,
usually denoted by the risk, the cost or
the score versus the size of the Training set and the test set.
In the case of classifiers we can always use the score or one minus score
versus the Training Set and the Test Set size to draw our learning curves.
The learning curves are useful in a further iteration back to
determining how much data we might need to optimally train the model.
Now let's go to I pod phone notebook and make some learning curve plots.
Up to now, we have trained our models using the X_train and Y_train data sets.
Now let us look at how to draw learning curves.
In this piece of the code, which is taken from the Scikit learns libraries, we
are going to draw some learning curves for the three models that we have built.
Let's go ahead and run this piece of code to see what happens.
The piece of code here defines how we are going to plot the learning curve.
Notice if you use the side kit learn libraries directly,
you will be plotting the score versus the Training examples.
In our case, we are plotting one minus score.
This is so that the graph resembles the same trend as that of an error that we
plotted before.
Let us run this piece of code first.
As you see, this simply defined what we want to draw.
Using this piece of code we are going to now actually draw the learning curves.
Hopefully you'll have three plots that look similar to this one.
What we have here is that on the X axis we
have plotted the Training examples and on the Y axis we have
plotted the cost which we have defined to be one minus the score.
This is the learning curve for the logistic regression.
The blue line shows you one minus the Training score, and
the red line shows you one minus the test score.
Scrolling down, you can see the learning curves for
the other models that we have built.
The second curve here.
Is the second model in our list, the random forest classifier.
Notice that the Training and
the test scores don't change very much after the 25th Training example.
Here, we can see that using 25 examples we can
do just as well as using larger number of examples.
This is the advantage of drawing a learning curve.
You can see the number of Training examples after which the score does not
improve very much.