As I mentioned before,
the timeline you're working on
is specific to your Cohort.
We've talked already about what a big
commitment Nanodegrees are, and
we designed the timeline for
this Nanodegree with a commitment
of ten hours a week in mind.
Now you're going to find out what your
timeline is in just a second, and please
note the dates listed are the dates by
which you need to submit your projects.
Now, that doesn't mean you have
to have met specifications for
each of those projects
by the dates listed.
It just means that you need to have
put your best effort forward for
each of those projects.
And be in a good place to finish
them up, if you haven't already.
Remember though,
by the time you graduate,
you'll need to have met specifications
for each of these projects.