Styles may seem like just a fun
addition, but it can be important to
make sure your visualized map is in
line with your brand, website, or
general mood.
Choose a theme from your website's
color pallet, or just your favorites.
Then, try to change the land,
highway, and water feature colors and
styles to incorporate it.
The fullest of feature type and
element type values is provided
in the google.maps.maptypes style
feature type reference documentation,
linked in the notes below.
Style your map using a styles array.
Reference the documentation
at the pages listed below for
a full list of feature types and
element types.
Did you apply custom styles to your map?