We're going to talk about some
possible MDP optimization criteria.
And, well I guess this isn't
really an optimization criterion.
But we talked about exploring
randomly being problematic
because you can have
MDPs that look like this.
Where there's a chain and
you have to keep taking some specific
action to get to the high reward state.
And if you're always
choosing actions randomly,
then the probability you would even ever
reach that is exponentially small, so
we have to be a little bit careful.
For example, in this MDP, it's not
really clear what to do from this state.
>> From which state, that state?
No, it's pretty clear what
to do from that state.
Go left.
>> Oh, okay.
Sure.
No, I mean in the reinforcement learning
setting, we have just two actions.
If we choose wisely, as you just did,
then we end up in this state and
we get reward and that's yea.
If we choose not wisely,
then we get stuck in this trap state and
we get bad reward forever and
theres no way out.
And so in the reinforcement learning
setting, we don't know which of those,
where the different arrows are pointing,
until we try it.
So, it's a little bit unfair to say
what we should be doing is maximizing
all possible reward values, right?
Because it could be that we get
ourselves into a position where we just
can't any more.
So here's what I advocate.
Remember we talked in the bandit
case about a mistake bound.
The idea of the number of times you pull
an arm that's not the right arm to pull,
is bounded by some polynomial.
It turns out that works really
nicely in MDPs as well.
So, the idea is that.
Think about this state
here in this trap example.
It has only one action
choice from the state.
So, what's the right action
to choose from here?
>> Go to one action?
>> Yeah.
So, we're not wrong.
>> True, true.
>> Right?
So, in fact.
No matter what in this particular MDP,
then total number of mistakes
we could ever make is one.
[LAUGH] We might make this
wrong first action, and
then we're making optimal
actions thereafter.
Again, optimal is relative to
the state that we're in, but
we're in the state that we're in.
>> Oh, that's kind of deep.
Okay.
>> Thanks.
So the criterion that I'm
going to advocate for here
is that what we're going to do is count
the number of epsilon suboptimal action.
That is to say the number of
times that we're in a state,
we choose an action and
that action in that state was not
epsilon close to the best
action in that state.
That we want that to be
bounded by some polynomial,
and let's say one over epsilon,
one over delta, the number states n,
and the number actions in each state k.
>> Okay.
[LAUGH] K so, oh, so yeah,
the actions are like bandits.
I like where this is going.
>> A little bit, a little bit.
We're going to bring it all together.
And so this wasn't really
an analysis of different criteria.
This was basically me just
trying to justify one criterion
because it has some nice properties.
It lets you deal with the fact
that there can be trap states and
that doesn't hurt us
in a learning setting.
And well, we're going to have to come up
with an algorithm that's going to deal
with this randomness,
you can't explore randomly idea.
>> Okay, so I think there should be
a fourth criteria in here by the way,
which was inspired by your listening
to William Shatner saying.
Which is the Marusha Criteria,
which is we minimize the number
of times we have to cheat.
I do not remember recommending that
you listen to William Shatner.
>> But everyone should.
>> Okay, but that's a separate issue.
So minimize, in the Kobayashi Maru test,
he reprogrammed it so
that he could win,
even though you couldn't win.
So this is [LAUGH] kind of like that,
in that we're defining winning.
Well, it's not really like that.
But it's defining winning to
be doing the best thing given
the state that you're in.
And it's not actually penalizing you for
having done something really stupid for
having gotten into that state.
As long as the total number of
really stupid things is bounded.
>> Huh, everything really
does come back to Star Trek.
Okay.
I'll buy that.
Three and four are the same.
>> [LAUGH] Well, we can't cheat.
You can't cheat in
reinforcement learning.
>> Oh, I beg to differ.