Now that we've finished coding the
Gaussian elimination algorithm and we've
coded how to extract a solution from the
reduced row echelon form of a system,
let's go one step further and
give our program the ability to output
a Parameterization of the solution set
if there are infinitely many solutions.
I've added a new class called
Parameterization to my lynsis module.
To initialize a Parameterization object,
you need to pass in a base point,
which is a vector and a list of vectors,
the direction vectors.
For an example of what this means,
let's look at the plain x + y + z = 1.
Suppose this is the solution set
to some system of equations.
We could rewrite x as 1-y-z and
then treat y and z as free variables.
So if we parameterize x, y, and
z, the base point would be 1 0 0,
because y and z don't have constant
terms, and x has a constant term of 1.
Then the vector multiplied
by y would be -1 1 0 because
x has a -y term, y has 1 times y and
z has no y term.
And similarly, the vector
multiplied by z would be -1 0 1.
In this case, y and z are the parameters
of the parametrization.
The base point of this parameterization
would be the constant vector 1 0 0 and
the direction vectors are the vectors
multiplied by y and z, the parameters.
These are the vectors -1 1 0 and -1 0 1.
You can find the code for
the parameterization class in
the instructor notes as well.
For this quiz, your goal is to write
a program that outputs a parametrization
object representing the solution to
a system with infinitely many solutions.
To test that your program
is working correctly,
here are three systems with
infinitely many solutions.
Enter the correct parameterizations
into the boxes provided.
The first system is 0.786x + 0.786y
+ 0.588z = -0.714 and
-0.138x- 0.138y +
0.244z = 0.319.
The second system is 8.631x +
5.112y- 1.816z = -5.113.
And 4.315x +11.132y-
5.27z = -6.77 and
-2.158 + 3.01y-
1.727z = -0.831.
The third system is 0.935x
+ 1.76y- 9.365z = -9.955 and
0.187x + 0.352y-
1.873z = -9.991 and
0.374x + 0.704y-
3.746z = -3.982 and
-0.561x- 1.056y
+ 5.619z = 5.973.
In the code for
the parameterization object,
the parameters are named t sub i for
some number i.
But, for the purposes of this quiz,
please use the letters t for
a parameter if there's
just one parameter.
This would be called t1
in the Python module.
And used t and
s if there are two parameters.
So t would be t1 in the python module,
and s would be t2.
Good luck.