Now that we've written
the code to open a web page,
we're going to use
intents to open a map.
Although the code for opening a location
on a map isn't exactly the same,
the concepts are similar.
Now let's go
back to the Common Intents page on
the Android Developer Documentation.
You can quickly get to it
by Googling common intents.
I want to open a map, so
I'll click on the Maps link in
the In this document section.
Before I write the code to open a map,
let's talk a little bit
more about the data URI.
A URI or a Uniform Resource Identifier
is a string of characters
that identifies a resource.
One of the ways you use URIs every day
is when you navigate to web addresses
like udacity.com.
The formal name of a web address is
a URL or Uniform Resource Locator.
A URL is a URI that identifies a web or
network resource.
But as we saw in the Android
documentation for opening a map,
a URI like geo can describe
a physical location.
Here's the full form of a URI, with all
the optional parts shown in brackets.
It begins with a scheme.
The scheme describes what type
of resource we're pointing to.
Popular schemes on the web are HTTP and
HTTPS,
mailto, FTP, file, and geo,
but there are many more.
Depending on the particular scheme,
it might be followed by two slashes and
an authority part.
The authority indicates an optional
username and password to log in, a host
name, which could be a domain name or
an IP address, and an optional port.
For HTTP requests, unless otherwise
stated, browsers assume port 80.
So if we try that in our browser,
we'll see that baidu.com,
the Chinese web search engine,
navigates to the same place if we leave
off the ports or add it on to the end.
After the authority part,
there's a path to a resource.
If the authority exists, there must
be a slash between the authority and
the path.
In this case, between the authority,
which contains
www.udacity.com as the host.
In this case, we have an authority
that contains www.udacity.com and
the path courses/all.
Mailto is one of the schemes that
doesn't require the authority part and
can work with just a path, in this case,
the person you want to email.
The query is next, and
it has no required format other than
it begins with a question mark.
It's common to use key value pairs to
specify data, but that isn't required.
Despite its name,
the query isn't always about searching.
Officially, it has no size limit, but in
practice, it can range from about 8,000
characters to over 190,000 characters,
depending on the browser being used.
If you've seen links that
say email this article,
it might be including the full text of
the article in the link using the query.
The last element of
the URI is the fragment.
This is preceded by a hash and
indicates secondary data that
the path resource will use.
What the fragment does depends
on the path, the browser, and
possibly the application
that's being run.
For example, in the Android
Developer Nanodegree trailer,
this links to ten seconds from
the beginning of the video.
Next, you're going to look at some
URIs and identify parts of them.