You may be thinking, wow this app looks
cool, but how do I even get started?
So lets go over a few quick basics.
First, this app is sort of similar to
some of the previous apps we've made
in this networking course.
You should feel comfortable using
those apps as references, or even for
some starting code.
Secondly, in the previous
apps we've made,
we've used various client API's to
build out the apps functionality.
For on the map you'll be using two
such client APIs, the Udacity API and
the Parse API.
You'll be using the Udacity API
to authenticate users.
You'll do this by working with a web
service method that we've exposed for
this purpose.
This Udacity API guide should
take you through the process.
The Parse API you'll be
using to access data for
the student pin locations and lengths.
Parse is a common solution
used by mobile apps for
a persistent data in the cloud, and
is an alternative to using core data,
which we'll actually be talking
about in the next course.
Note that while Parse does
have a SDK available for
iOS, we want you to use the Parse
web API for the on the map project.
This Parse API guide should take you
through the process of using Parse for
this purpose.
For this app,
you'll also have the option to enable
users to login through Facebook.
This feature is not required, but
we still want to give you some info
in case you decide to attempt it.
To enable Facebook login,
you'll need to do the following.
Read through Facebook's documentation
on their login feature.
Connect your own Udacity user
account to your Facebook account,
which can be done on the account
settings page of the Udacity website.
And at the bottom of the Udacity API
Guide, you'll find some methods that
you'll need to implement to get
the Facebook login working.
The last point I want to make is if you
think of the app as one massive project,
it can appear very daunting and
make it hard to get started.
That's why it's better to see the app as
a bunch of pieces that make a whole, and
tackle one chunk at a time.
Making a simple wire frame or
setting up the networking code of one of
the aforementioned clients
is a good place to start.
As always, check out the forums for
help or pointers.