Here's what I got.
1 Watt for the dynamic power and
4 times longer for the execution time.
I got this from the dynamic
power equation.
Bling!
You've reduced the frequency
by a factor of 4.
So, the program will slow
down also by a factor of 4.
Now, what about power?
Let's think about it relative to
the dynamic power of the first design.
First, since the frequency went down by
4, then from the dynamic power equation,
so too will the dynamic power
decrease by at least the same factor.
Why at least?
Well, remember that frequency and
supply voltage are supposed to be
adjusted together proportionately.
So that's an additional one-sixteenth
reduction in dynamic power.
Overall that's a 64 fold
reduction to just 1 Watt.
In fact, this exercise is the usual
argument people make for going parallel
through multi-core designs, rather than,
say, increase in clock frequency.
In this case, suppose you had enough
parallelism to use multiple cores.
Then you could take this chip,
replicate it four times in order to get
these programs to run in the same time,
and you'd still save power overall.
It would just run at 4
Watts instead of 64 Watts.