Colors are a big part of app design,
from branding to visual consistency.
And I like a lot of colors, but
a little can go a long way.
If you think about some nicely designed
apps like Google Maps, music players, or
email, they generally
use only a few colors.
And they use contrast to highlight
different components within the app.
In general,
colors should always work together and
help to distinguish between views and
interactive components like buttons.
For these reasons,
Android material design guidelines
recommend having a primary color and
an accent color.
The primary color is the main
color base for your app.
Views and components like the menu bar
will generally include this color.
And the accent color is
typically brighter, and
serves to draw attention to key
elements like buttons in an app.
In fact,
there is some helpful online tools that
can help you chose a color pallet.
And I've linked to a couple
in the notes below.
It's common to chose three slightly
different shades of the primary
color to use and one accent color.
For our app, we'll be using a dark
purple as a primary color, and
orange as an accent color.
I've chosen purple and orange because
they are near opposite colors.
Which means they have a high contrast
that's great for visibility.
Choosing two very different
colors like this will make
anything I want to highlight very clear.
And when you choose colors for
any app, keep in mind how you'll use
them to add clarity and consistency.