Now to displace those rectangles
that surround the airport codes,
we've provided you with some drawables
that would help, namely this
shape_rectangles_stroke.xml, don't
worry about what's inside this xml for
now, just think of it
as a typical image.
So we simply go back to the activity
name and then drag in an image view,
we can specify the drawable to
be the shape rectangle stroke.
And then lets move back
to the text view, so
that we can change it with a height.
Lets set it with 60dp, and
the height to 80dp, and so
now we can go back to the design mode,
and start creating our constraints.
I'll create a left
constraint to the parent and
a top constraint to our passenger name.
And then in the text view,
I'll just make sure the margin left
is equal to 32dp and
the margin top is 16.
Also if you ever change the margin left
you just need to make sure the margin
start is the same.
And then let's have a look,
it looks a lot better.
And then we can do the exact same
thing with our right rectangle
except that we set
the constraint to the right.
And then, the top to the bottom of name.
That line between those two rectangles
is simply in view with the heights up to
one pixel and having the background
color the same as the rectangles.
But to make this line stretch out
as these rectangles move apart or
come closer, we have to set
the constraints from the left,
to the left rectangle and
from the right to right rectangle.
And to center it vertically, we've also
set the top constraint to the bottom of
one of the rectangles and the bottom
constraint to top of another rectangles.
Again, it might not be very obvious
here in the visual editor so
let's go back to the text.
You can see that I've
created the constraint left
to the right of the left rectangle.
And the right constraint to
the left of the right rectangle.
And then the top to the bottom
of the right rectangle.
And the bottom to the top
These two here guarantee that
the line would be centered
vertically between the rectangles.
And this here going to use other line
will stretch and shrink as those
rectangles move depending on the size
of your phone or the orientation of it.
You can see I have also hard coded
the layout height to be one.
And I have set the layout width to be
zero because it will stretch based
on those constraints here.
Now when you set to horizontal or
vertical constraints from the both sides
of a view, the view can react
in one of three different ways.
You can see that from the properties
window on the side here.
The view can either have a fixed size,
which means that you
specify the dimension.
Either in the textbox here or
in the text in the XML file itself.
And that means that regardless
of what these constraints are,
it will maintain its dimension
that you've specified.
It could also be set to be any size,
which means it.
Something like a spring,
that stretches or
shrinks to maintain those constraints.
The final option is Wrap Content.
Which means it would only expand or
shrink to make sure that it
wraps its contents inside.
So, we'll set the vertical
type to be fixed.
And the horizontal type to be any size.
You could also change
the bias of how strong or
weak each of the constraints are and
that moves the line either up or
down depending on how
strong each constraint is.
So for
now we're just going to set that at 50%.
Now I just went ahead and
added those two extra text views and
I've set the constraint to be from the
left and right for the rectangles and
the top and bottom to the line.
This guarantee's that the text would
be centered within the rectangle and
aligned with the line.
Then I added four more text views and
created for all of them,
left constraints and
then four more text fields for
the boarding and arrival times.
I'll make sure that it is on top
label here is align to the right, and
then everything else is
constraint to the left.
Now there is one more constrain
type that I want to show here and
it's called the baseline constraint.
And this is symboled with this line
here which is only for text views.
And it allows you to create constraints
between different text views regardless
of how large the text
view size itself is.
It just allows you to
align the text inside it.
Now it's time to create the design for
the blue table down here.
Again, the header of the table is just
a rectangle with a background color, and
the body is another rectangle
with another background color.
So I've added two new image views here.
One for the table header,
another one for the table body.
I've set the background color to
be colorPrimary for the body and
colorPrimaryLight for the header.
And I'll set the headers constraint
to be pointing to the departure time
on the top, and
to the parent from the left.
And then I'll just add
the text views for
all the information inside the table.
Next is the bar code,
which should go down here, and
that's just another image view.
Which I can add here in the text and
I'm just planning to source to this MIP
map which I've also provided you with.
And then finally the flight code and
the plane image are the things
that are still missing.
So the flight code is
just another text view.
I've set the text up in Display1.
And use the primary color, offset
the top constraint to be the divider so
that it's always underneath this
line divider we created earlier.
And the left constraint to
the left rectangle, and
the right constraint to
the right rectangle.
That guarantees that it's always
going to be centered between them.
Perfect, that's looking pretty good so
far.
In the next video let's see
how to add this plain image.