One of the biggest challenges to VR,
is simulator sickness.
You may have heard that some VR
experiences can make you feel queasy,
dizzy, or give you headaches.
And this is absolutely true.
Some experiences can
cause those effects.
The good news is that you as a VR
developer, have the power to fix it.
This nano degree will teach you how to
make a VR app that is comfortable for
everyone.
Okay, so
what makes people uncomfortable?
Well pretty much anything that causes
a mismatch between your body's internal
sense of motion and the data your brain
receives from your visual system.
So if what you see doesn't
line up with your body feels,
then you'll start to
become uncomfortable.
Scientists believe natural
selection favored this trait
because of poison berries and other
innocuous-looking foods that harm you.
Poisons tend to make you feel dizzy.
And the best response is to eject
the bad food from your stomach
as quickly as possible.
Well, when VR isn't done correctly the
mismatch between your visual system and
your bodies internal sense of motion
triggers the exact same response.
This course is going to talk a lot
about the things that trigger simulator
sickness and we're going to
talk about how to fix them.
By the end of this course,
you'll be making VR apps that
are comfortable for everyone.