Hopefully you found this exercise interesting as a way to modify topologies.
So this is the topology we're starting out with, and we have our random
sentence spout linked to the exclaim1 bolt using a shuffleGrouping
that appends three exclamation points to the end of our sentence.
Next we have the exclaim2 bolt, linked with a shuffleGrouping to exclaim1.
That appends three more exclamations for
a total of six, to each of our random sentence.
To tackle the first topology, we simply want the random
sentence spout connected to exclaim1 only, using the shuffle grouping.
This one is simple.
We simply break the connection between exclaim1 and exclaim2.
In code, we can simply comment out exclaim2.
Once exclaim2 is commented out,
we see that the random sentence connects to exclaim1.
And we should have, not six, but three.
Let's run through the maven package and submitting our program to Storm.
Remember that your lesson should say lesson1, stage2, but
I'm working on lesson1, stage3 in this solution.
So, in lesson1, stage2 type mvn package.
Once we have BUILD SUCCESS, we submit our program,
storm jar target/udacity remember with dependencies,
udacity.storm, and this is ReporterExclamationTopology.
Once the program is submitted, we can go back to our visualization, and
sure enough our sentences have three exclamation points.
So I think our topology number 1 is a success.
Going on to topology 2, notice that our random sentence spout is
connected only to exclaim2, bypassing exclaim1 using a shuffle grouping.
To do this, notice that we'll need to break the connection of our
random sentence spout to exclaim1.
And instead connect our random sentence bout directly to exclaim2.
In code this is also very straightforward.
In our topology we first uncomment exclaim2 and comment exclaim1.
But notice that exclaim2 connects to exclaim1,
which is no longer in our topology.
If we were to build and run this topology, we would get a build success, but
a runtime failure.
Let's try it.
We mvn package, we get a BUILD SUCCESS.
But when we submit our topology, we get a failure and
our visualization does not run.
To fix this, we need to link exclaim2 to rand-sentence, and
that simply is defining the shuffleGrouping to rand-sentence.
So we delete our our exclaim1 and we enter in rand-sentence.
That forms this connection from rand-sentence to exclaim2.
And we should get three exclamations.
Let's try this.
We'll mvn package again.
And once we get build success, I'm using the up arrow and submit our job again.
Finally we come back to our visualization.
We see the Storm program running in the background.
And here are our sentences with three exclamations.
This is just off the side of our SVG container.
And there we go.
So that completes topology number 2.
Finally, for our last topology, notice how exclaim1 and
exclaim2 are both connected to the random sentence spout.
In code, we already have one connection to the random sentence spout for
exclaim two we simply want this topology.
Both bolts will add on three exclamation points to a random sentence, but
the total output coming from both bolts will only be three exclamations.
To do this in code is also very simple.
We simply uncomment exclaim1 which is already connected to the random sentence.
And our topology is complete.
We run mvn package again.
Remember to save your file.
And once we get a build success, I won't use the up arrow this but
I'll write in store jar target, using the tab key
udacity-jar-with-dependencies udacity.storm.ReporterExclamationTopology.
Once we submit our jar we go back to our visualization.
You can hit refresh just to make sure that your visualization starts out blank,
and finally our topology three is correct.
We see three exclamations coming on our random sentences.
So finally our, we can say that our final topology is correct.
And for the final point,
remember that you can go to stage2 > spout > RandomSentenceSpout.
Scroll down to the sentences and uncomment the sentences and
add in your own to personalize your visualization.
You can take a screenshot or video and post this to the forum.
And why don't you comment on two of your other fellow learners visualizations.
Great job completing stage2 and lesson1.