And surprisingly, the probability for this message to be spam is 0.
It's not 0.001. It's flat 0.
In other words, it's impossible, according to our model,
that this text could be a spam message.
Why is this?
When we apply the same rule as before, we get the prior for spam which is 3/8.
And we multiple the conditional for each word into this.
For "secret," we know it to be 1/3.
For "is," to be 1/9, but for today, it's 0.
It's 0 because the maximum of the estimate for the probability of "today" in spam is 0.
"Today" just never occurred in a spam message so far.
Now, this 0 is troublesome because as we compute the outcome--
and I'm plugging in all the numbers as before--
none of the words matter anymore, just the 0 matters.
So, we get 0 over something which is plain 0.
Are we overfitting? You bet.
We are clearly overfitting.
It can't be that a single word determines the entire outcome of our analysis.
The reason is that our model, to assign a probability of 0 for the word "today"
to be in the class of spam is just too aggressive.
Let's change this.
One technique to deal with the overfitting problem is called Laplace smoothing.
In maximum likelihood estimation, we assign towards our probability
the quotient of the count of this specific event over all events in our data set.
For example, for the prior probability, we found that 3/8 messages are spam.
Therefore, our maximum likelihood estimate
for the prior probability of spam was 3/8.
In Laplace Smoothing, we use a different estimate.
We add the value k to the count
and normalize as if we added k to every single class
that we've tried to estimate something over.
This is equivalent to assuming we have a couple of fake training examples
where we add k to each observation count.
Now, if k equals 0, we get our maximum likelihood estimator.
But if k is larger than 0 and n is finite, we get different answers.
Let's say k equals 1,
and let's assume we get one message,
and that message was spam, so we're going to write it one message, one spam.
What is p (spam) for the Laplace smoothing of k + 1?
Let's do the same with 10 messages, and we get 6 spam.
And 100 messages, of which 60 are spam.
Please enter your numbers into the boxes over here.