We just used the ideas of
conditional probability and
independence in the context of our
polynomial verification algorithm.
Now let's discuss these
ideas in general.
We define the conditional
probability that an event E occurs,
given that an event F occurs,
as the probability that E and
F occur divided by
the probability that F occurs.
We can visualize this quantity
using a traditional Venn diagram.
We draw the whole sample
space as a large rectangle.
And within here we draw the set F,
like so.
When we talk about
the conditional probability of E,
given F, we are restricting ourselves
to the set F within the sample space.
Thus, only the portion of E that
is in F is important to us.
And to make this a proper probability,
we have to renormalize by
dividing by the probability of F.
That way the probability of E,
given F, and the probability of not E,
given F sum up to one.
An interesting situation is where
the probability of an event E, given F,
is the same as the probability
when F isn't given.
This implies that E and
F are independent,
one event doesn't depend on the other.
Formally, we say that two events, E and
F, are independent if the probability of
E and F is the probability of
E times the probability of F.
Note that this is a slightly more
general statement than this equality.
The probability of E, given F, isn't
defined if the probability of F is zero.