As with any other software API or
framework, you'll want to become
very comfortable with finding your
way around the Gradle documentation.
Gradle provides a few different
forms of documentation, but
we'll focus specifically on the DSL
reference, which is a good first place
to look if you want to know what all
configuration options are available,
in any given part of your build script.
The Gradle DSL reference covers all
the different build script components.
Many of which we'll talk
about later in this course.
Since we're currently concerned with
tasks, let's take a look at the task
types that are available as part
of the Gradle distribution.
As you can see there are a number
of built in task types,
varying from followup operations to
compilation, to source code analysis.
Since one of the most common build
actions involves copying files.
Let's take a look at the copy task API.
For most built in task types
examples are provided for
common configuration use cases.
If we look further, we can see the
various task configuration properties
as well as methods available.
Many of the method descriptions
reference other greater API types.
Since many API methods take
a groovy closure as an argument,
it's helpful to know what arguments
will be passed into the closure.
The eachFile method, for example,
takes a closure as an argument.
The closure that we
pass in as an argument,
is then given an instance of
FileCopyDetails as its argument.
We can click this link, and then get
additional details about the options
that are available on this class.
The Gradle DSL reference
is your best friend.
Learn it, love it, and it will
help you out of all sorts of jams.