Let's update the viewDidLoad function,
so that the stop recording button is
disabled right from the start.
Like this line “stopRecordingButton.isEnabled = false”.
This disables
the stop recording button by default.
But now we need a way to re-enable this
button after the user begins recording
in the same way we want to disable the
stop recording button again after the
user finishes recording. There are two
functions that you wrote earlier that
can help us here. They are recordAudio
and stopRecording. In the recordAudio
function, add a line to enable the stop
recording button and add another line to
disable the record button, as the user is
already recording at this point.
I’m also going to remove our print statement
from earlier.
Finally, in the stop recording button
we should add these three lines
The first enables the record button.
Since we're done recording,
we could start a new recording at this point.
The next line is to disable the stop
recording button, because at this point
there's nothing left to stop. And finally
we'll update the label to Tap to Record.
And I’m also going to remove our print
statement from this function.
Alright, let's test it. We can see right
away that the stop recording button has
been disabled when the view loads.
If we click to record, the label changes and
the stop recording button becomes enabled.
At the same time, the recording
button is disabled, because we should be
recording at this point. If we hit stop,
then the recording button is enabled
again and the label changes back to its
original state.