Inside my project.pi file I will create
a route and function called fbconnect.
Similarly to my Google login,
I will verify the value of state
to protect against cross-site
reference forgery attacks.
I will then exchange this short-lived
token for a long-lived token here.
Notice that I have to send my
app secret along to Facebook
to verify my server's identity.
This token includes an expires
field that indicates how long this
token is valid.
Long term tokens can
last up to two months.
I'm going to strip the expires
tag from my token since I don't
need it to make API calls.
If the token works, I should be able to
make API calls with my new token like so
and populate my login session.
Facebook uses a separate API call
to retrieve a profile picture.
So I will make that call separately and
populate the login session with the URL
for the user's profile picture here.
Now I can use the exact same code from
my Google login to retrieve a user or
create a new one.
And go ahead and send that welcome
splash screen that we had before.