Now that you know about
different types of ideas and
how to find some of your own, it's time
for your to brainstorm a lot of ideas.
You want to generate many ideas so
you can test them later to determine
which one will be the best to pursue.
To get in brainstorming mode,
check out some of the links
in the instructor notes.
This brainstorming activity will
take two minutes of your time
Remember that at this point in
the process there are no bad ideas and
you shouldn't edit yourself.
We'll get to refining your ideas next.
For the first minutes, write down as
many problems you personally want
a solution for or you think someone
else, or another company could use.
If you don't have a physical timer,
there are many timers available online.
Then for the next minute,
write down any ideas you have for
solving those problems.
Once you brainstorm,
check this box to continue.