All right, Charles.
So
now that I've talked through how we can
compute these outcome based estimates
with these TD1 estimates,
I'm going to try to tell you that
it's not exactly what we want.
I'm going try to explain why
TD1 kind of is wrong sometimes.
>> Okay.
>> To do this we're going to go back to
the example we've looked at before where
we've got this markup chain with rewards
and we're observing some trajectories
through it like S1, S3, S4, S final.
And so we observe a bunch of those and
then the last one we
observe starting from S2.
S2, S3 S5, SF, okay?
And now what we want to figure
out is what does TD1, or
an outcome based estimate,
give us as an approximation for
the value of S2 given this set of data?
And then we'll compare it to what we get
with the maximum likelihood estimate.
>> Okay.
Wait, you want me to do this?
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, okay, so it really is a quiz?
>> Yeah, that's what this word is.
>> All right, fine.
I think I have some questions, but
in fact, let me ask some of them now.
>> Yeah, I think we should make sure
it's clear enough that
you can work on it.
>> Okay, so you want me to tell you
what the value of S2 is or what I would
estimate the value of S2 to be using
sort of the TD1 outcome based estimate.
>> And there it should be the average
of the reward sequences that we've
seen upon encountering S2.
>> Okay that makes sense but
that has to start from somewhere.
>> Right, the equations require
you start from somewhere?
>> We can just average it across all the
encounters that we've had of that thing.
Since we're averaging the first time
we see it, that is the estimate.
The second time we see
it that's half of it.
>> Okay that's fair.
Okay I can deal with that.
And by maximum likelihood
estimate you just mean the value
that best fits the model,
which in this case is the MDP itself?
>> Yeah, so given the data that we've
seen so far, you can make an estimate of
how likely it is to go from S3 to S4,
S3 to S5, S1 to S3, S2 to S3.
So you can use the data that you’ve seen
to estimate the probabilities in this
model, which aren’t going to be exactly
what they show here because this
is the true model.
But we can estimate
it based on the data.
And then we can say, okay, given that
estimate, what is the value of S2?
>> Okay, that seems reasonable.
Okay, I can do that.
>> All right.
So but
you should probably also ask
what the discount factor is.
>> Oh, yeah, what’s the discount factor?
>> Good question.
Just for simplicity we'll go
with gam equals one again.
>> Okay, go.