So here you can see I've implemented
the ActivityDetectionBroadcastReceiver
class, and this extends
BroadcastReceiver as we had said.
In here I've just created
the onReceive @Override and
this takes a Context context and
an Intent intent.
Now you may notice that this class
is embedded within the main class,
here's my opening bracket for the class,
and here's the closing bracket for
the class.
But underneath here, we still have
the closing bracket of the main class,
our main activity, and
there is its opening bracket.
So our entire class is encapsulated
within the main class, and
this is really useful because we can
then pass data back to the main class,
or call methods on the main
class from inside here.
So what we're going to do now is
implement the onReceive function.
So this is going to catch the data that
was broadcasted by the local broadcast
manager with the activities details.
And we'll take them and use that to
update the UI on the main class itself.