In this lesson we're going to create and
save Conference entities.
These will represent the conferences
that users of our app
will create and attend.
Then we'll learn how to run queries and
use filters to query for conferences.
Let's say you've got a trip
to San Francisco in June.
You might want to check to see if there
are any conferences going on in June
while you're here.
I'll show you how to write
the code to run queries like that.
You've already learned that App Engine
optimizes query results by using
indexes.
I'll help you explore how
to create indexes, and
how to structure your queries
to make the best use of indexes.
Constructing queries and
app engines have some differences in
querying over a relational database.
We'll explore how some of those
differences affect the way you write
queries.
Another key feature our application
needs is to let users register
for a conference.
The registration process
involves several steps.
If you enter your credit
card number to buy a ticket,
you want to make sure you get the ticket
before the payment goes through.
So we'll use the registration process
to show how to use transactions to
make sure all the different
steps happen together.
Let's go create some conferences.