Ready to validate some numeric inputs?
Well, here's a gradebook that
calculates, well, grades.
The way this gradebook works is that
you just enter four grades here and
then hit Calculate.
And you see the average
show up right here.
Each of these grades should be a
multiple of 10, which means they should
be either 0, 10, 20, 30, and so
on all the way up to a maximum of 100.
There are a few issues with these
inputs that I want you to fix.
As it is right now,
these inputs only take numbers, but
the controls here on the side
are less than useful.
For instance, you can click and
hold on this one and
it will go up well above 100 and
really, all the way up to infinity.
And it needs to stop at 100.
For this input you can actually
go down into negative numbers,
and there's no such thing
as a negative grade.
In this one we'll go up by 1s,
which is fine, but we're expecting that
all grades are multiples of 10, so
there's no reason to go up by only 1.
Now just so
you know with HTML attributes alone,
you won't be able to prevent people
from typing crazy numbers like this one.
But you can make these
controls more useful.
So for this quiz,
it's your job to make them more useful.
To do so apply the numeric validation
attributes that you just learned about.
You can see what each input
is missing right here.
And for bonus points,
which don't actually exist [LAUGH],
take a look at this text input for
a letter grade.
Try using the pattern attribute
with regular expressions
to validate possible letter grades.
I'm thinking you could use American
letter grades which go from A, B, C,
D and then skips E and then goes to F,
with subgrades of plus and minus.
But feel free to validate for
whatever grading system you're used to.
And lastly, it's worth noting that
these numeric inputs look and
behave slightly differently
in different browsers.
So test in different browsers
to see the differences.
As always, check the instructor
notes for more information.
Have fun.