[Thrun] This is a quiz in which I compare EM versus K-means.
Suppose we are giving you 4 data points, as indicated by those circles.
Suppose we have 2 initial cluster centers, shown here in red,
and those converge to possible places that are indicated by those 4 squares.
Of course they won't take all 4 of them; they will just take 2 of them.
But for now I'm going to give you 4 choices.
We call this cluster 1, cluster 2, A, B, C, and D.
In EM will C1 move towards A or will C1 move towards B?
And in contrast, in K-means will C1 move towards A
or will C1 move towards B?
This is just asking about the left side of the diagram.
So the question is will K-means find itself in the more extreme situation,
or will EM find itself in the more extreme situation?