A common pattern is when the most
important element of your UI
is the content.
Think of a catalog or a photo app.
The most important
aspect is the picture.
Put some extra chrome here and
there, content is king.
Now, let's layout the views,
we'll have a label here,
an image view in the middle and
down here I'll have a button.
Now, we're going to put this three
views inside a vertical stack view.
And then,
pin the stack view to the margins.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[SOUND] Not good.
Auto layout is not using
the frame that is was instructed.
You can fix this quite easily by
clicking here and update frames.
So still not exactly
what we're looking for.
Let's see how it looks
like on landscape.
So let's make a check list of
all the little things that
aren't working as they should.
First of all,
the button is way too tall and
there's a lot of wasted
space on the sides.
So remember the commandments?
The first commandment,
tweak the properties of the stack view,
will fix our problem number two.
So we're going to set
the alignment to fill.
To fix the other issues we
need the third commandment,
change compression and hugging.
The image over here is being too
stubborn about it's size, so
let's lower that.
Both the content hugging and
the compression.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Last but not least, let's make sure
that the whole image is always shown,
and has the right proportions so
we need to set its mode to aspect fit.
Just to make sure that the image
view is working correctly
I'll use one of the images
that I have here.
Now, it's perfect although we could add
some separation between the elements.
That's very easy,
we just select the Stack View and
create some spacing, let's say 8.
And now, it does look perfect.
So try it on some other
devices by clicking here and
also some orientations.
Make sure it works, try it on
a simulator, maybe even on a device.
Before you move on, please make
sure you understand everything that
didn't work at the beginning,
why it didn't, and how we fixed it.
[BLANK_AUDIO]