Okay, so you're sold and
want to implement Auto Layout.
There's more than one
way to skin that cat.
Actually, there's four.
Let's check them out.
First of all, you can do it
with Swift Code by creating
instances of constraints and
adding them to a view.
That's the Chuck Norris way.
We won't get into that.
Then there is the visual formats.
This is kind of a micro
language different from Swift
that you insert into strings and
then feed those to views.
It's weird as in wavy gravy weird.
You won't use it either.
You may also create the constraints
in interface builder.
This is exactly the same as option one.
But using a graphic
tool instead of code.
We'll add a pinch of this stuff to
our stew but only as a last resort.
Finally, we have the holy grail,
the one and
only way of implementing auto layout
without losing your, StackViews.
This will be our bread and
butter along all this course.
We will always use StackViews first.
And only if we can't move forward,
will we resort to creating
constraints in Interface Builder.
Let's learn more about StackViews.