It's now time to put together everything
you've learned thus far into a single
Mashup web application.
Let's leave the puppy application
aside for a moment and
go back to the restaurant
menu application.
In this exercise you will
first have an endpoint
that takes in a city name and meal type.
Geo codes the location,
finds a nearby restaurant with that
meal type, stores it in a database, and
then returns a JSON object of
that restaurant to the user.
And this should happen
on a post request.
On this same route, handle a get request
that returns all of the restaurants in
your database, along with their name,
ID number, Address and
Image inside of a JSON object.
Then you will make another end
point that takes in a restaurant's
ID in the route.
A get request to this route should
return the name, ID number, address, and
image of a specific restaurant.
An update along with any or
all of the name, location and
image parameters should update this
restaurant information in your database.
And a delete to this route will remove
this restaurant from your database.
In the instructor notes,
you will find a collection of Python
templates to help you get started.
FindARestaurant.py has the API
methods created in lesson two.
Be sure to update this file with
your client ID and client secret.
Inside views.py you will add all of the
routing and Python code, /restaurants
to view all the restaurant in your
database and post a new restaurant.
And /restaurant/id to get the specific
information about a restaurant,
update its name, address, or image or
delete it from the database.
When you are finished,
use the tester.py file
to test the functionality of
your web app's API endpoints.