Let's take a quiz that looks at
a problem involving timeslices and
their values.
On a single CPU system, consider
the following workload and conditions.
We have ten I/O bound tasks in
the system and one CPU bound task.
The I/O bound tasks
issue one I/O operation
every one milliseconds
of CPU compute time.
I/O operations always take
10 milliseconds to complete.
The context switching
overhead is 0.1 millisecond.
And at the end also all
tasks are long running.
So we're not reporting any kind
of execution time for the tasks.
Given this, answer first,
what is the CPU utilization for
a round robin scheduler with
a timeslice of one millisecond.
How about for
a 10 millisecond timeslice?
Provide the two answers here, and round
them up to the nearest percent value.
The formula for
computing CPU utilization is
provided in the Instructor's Notes.