And the answer is 48.6.
And obviously, it's not quite as trivial as the calculation before
because there's 2 competing actions.
We can try to go north, which gives us the 77
but risks the chance of falling into the -100.
Or we can go west, as before, which gives us a much smaller chance
to reach 77, but avoids the -100.
Let's do both and see which one is better.
If we go north, we have a 0.8 chance of reaching 77.
There's now a 10% chance of paying -100
and a 10% chance of staying in the same location,
which at this point is still a value of 0.
We subtract our costs of 3, and we get 61.6
- 10 - 3 = 48.6.
Let's check the west action value.
We reach the 77 with probability 0.1
with 0.8 chance we stay in the same cell,
which has the value of 0,
and with 0.1 chance, we end up down here,
which also has a value of 0.
We subtract our costs of -3,
and that gives us 7.7 - 3 = 4.7.
At this point, going west is vastly inferior
to going north, and the reason is we already propagated
a great value of 77 for this cell over here,
whereas this one is still set to 0.
So, we will set it to 48.6.