Here are my plots for
the total number of minutes spent
in the classroom in the first week.
We saw earlier that the mean number
of minutes spent was much higher for
students who passed the project, and
we can see that here since these labels
are increasing faster than these.
We can also see that for students who
passed, the number of students who fall
into one of the longer buckets is higher
relative to the non-passing students.
On the other hand, the rough shape of
the two histograms is fairly similar.
Most students spent
the shortest amount of time.
And then fewer and
fewer students fall in each bucket
as you increase the amount of time.
This shape holds for
both students who pass and
students who don't
pass the first project.
These are the histograms for
number of lessons completed.
Again, the shapes of the two histograms
look fairly similar to each other
although you can see that the mean
is higher for passing students.
Which is in line with
what we saw earlier.
Finally, here are the histograms
that I got for number days visited.
You'll notice that in both histograms
there are these weird gaps.
That's because of
the number of bins chosen.
This data can only be
integers from 0 to 7,
so if too many bins are created,
then some bins will be completely empty.
And that's what happened here.
I'm going to fix this later in the
lesson, but if you'd like to fix it now,
there's some advice in
the instructor notes.
Ignoring the gaps for
a moment, I can see that the shapes of
these two histograms are very different.
For non-passing students, the shape
is similar to earlier, where less and
less students are in each bucket as
the bucket corresponds to more and
more days.
However, for the passing students,
there's a very different pattern.
You can see that students who passed the
first project are about equally likely
to visit the classroom 7 days
during their first week, as 0 days.
To make these histograms,
I added to the line plt.hist(data)
to my described data function.
That way I would be able to
easily make the histogram for
each metric by rerunning the later
cells where I describe the data.
And the histograms would show up
next to the summary statistics.
Of course in order for this line to
work I needed to import map plot lib.
And I also added the line %pylab
inline to the top of the cell.
So that my plots would show up within my
notebook and not in a separate window.