The active life cycle is when your
activity is in the foreground and
has focus.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Here it's actively receiving
input from user events.
And no other activities
are obscuring it.
[SOUND].
onPause's call, and the active lifetime
ends as soon as your activity is
partially obscured,
like in this example.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
You can see here the permissions dialog
is displayed in front of Google Play for
an app install.
Or the same thing happens when
you have another activity
trying to fulfill an implicit intent and
the user needs to make a selection.
So to make efficient use
of limited resources,
you'll want to use these signals to
adjust your app's resource burden.
So mo updates to your UI can be
paused when this life time ends
which is announced by enforce.
But as you see,
the app is still visible so
you shouldn't pause any processes
that are drawing your UI.
The visible lifetime on the other hand,
continues whenever the app
is at all visible and
ends as soon as it's completely
obscured by another app, like this.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
At this point our app is
moved to the background.
So when you see onStop you know
the user can't see your app at all.
So while onCreate and
onDestroy will be called at most
once each time your app is run,
these handlers are likely to be called
many times while the app is running.
And this is where things
get a little different.
On almost all platforms app
life cycles are deterministic.
Generally you'll start a program and
it will keep running until either it
completes or the user cancels it.
You look at traditional desktop
development, that means your app
keeps running until your user chooses
quit or exit from the file menu.
At that point, you can save state and
free resources.
But as we know, on Android lifecycles
work a little differently.
So let's take a closer look at
exactly how that works now.