Our past quiz showed the power of string
concatenation and string slicing.
We could generate new mad lib sentences,
by just changing verb and
noun replacement variables, rather than
having to rewrite the sentence over and
over again.
But finding where noun or verb are,
by guessing what the index may be, and
adjusting until we found the right
position, can be a bit tedious.
Imagine if we had to find where noun or
verb is in a string of
a thousand characters long.
That would take far
too much of our time.
Luckily, we've already learned about
a method that can help us out with this.
For the following quiz, you'll be asked
to use the string.find method you
learned about with Dave
in the last lesson.
To find out where instances of noun and
verb occur in a longer string.
As a refresher if we set
a string test to how are you, and
we then use test.find("are"),
we'll be returned with the index
word in the parenthesis is found.
In this case will be returned with 4.