Here's a brief quiz on the component models.
You might have heard of WordPress,
it is a content management solution for blogs.
Here are some requirements taken from the WordPress codex, for
requirement stocking.
For each requirement, determine whether it concerns component syntax,
component semantics, or component composition.
The first requirement states, any text output by the Action function,
will appear in the page sources at the locations where the action was invoked.
Secondly, use well-structured, error-free PHP and valid HTML.
The third requirement states, actions are triggered by specific events that
take place in WordPress, such as publishing a post, changing themes, or
displaying an administration screen.
The action is a custom PHP function, defined in your plugin, and
hooked that is set to respond to some of these events.