So ultimately we're going to run, this
is going to be algorithm c by the way.
We're going to run this algorithm c for
some number of steps.
We're going to call tau prime,
k, epsilon prime, delta prime.
And let's say that the algorithm
that we actually run for
this amount of time is algorithm b.
>> Mm-hm.
>> What do we know?
We know that it could
be that it made tau k,
oh lets say epsilon prime,
delta prime mistakes.
And then all the rest have
to be actual near optimal.
In fact,
well it's going to be epsilon optimal.
So we might need a different
epsilon than epsilon prime.
But, so let's say that it's epsilon
optimal for the rest of these steps.
>> Mm-hm.
>> What do we have to do to make it so
that this average is close to optimal?
>> Well from that point on, we just
pull anything that's epsilon optimal.
And it'll sort of all average out,
right?
>> No, because we don't know
how to pull things that are epsilon
optimal from that point on.
All we know is that this algorithm b,
is going to make it most tau k
epsilon delta prime mistakes.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So, on those trials how close to
optimal is it on the trials where
it actually makes a mistake?
>> Where it makes a mistake?
>> Yeah.
>> Something greater than epsilon.
>> Sure.
What's the largest it can be?
>> One.
>> Good, right.
because remember,
we're talking about a Bernoulli bandit,
which is a bandit you pull the arm and
it either pays off with probably 0 or
1, or something in between.
So the worst we can do is,
we pulled an arm, but
it actually has a payoff of 0, but
the right arm had a payoff of 1.
>> Right.
>> So the maximum error,
the maximum first step reward cost
that we could have in this case is
going to be one.
>> Times tau.
>> For those trials.
>> Right.
>> That's times taro, that's right.
In fact let's write that.
And how close to optimal are we
going to be in these other trials?
>> Epsilon optimal.
>> Epsilon, right.
Alright so this is going to be our
total suboptimality over the end steps.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And
our average per step optimality
is going to be that.
>> Right.
>> And we want this to be
founded by epsilon prime.
>> Yes.
>> And we get to pick two things, right?
We get to pick n and
we get to pick epsilon.
So, can we solve this?
How do we do that?
So I'm going to suggest that
we just pick an epsilon.
It's going to be problematic if we
pick epsilon to be epsilon prime.
Because then we're making
these big mistakes here and
we're making even
biggest mistakes there.
So, on average,
it's not going to work out.
>> Mm-hm.
>> But,
if we set epsilon to epsilon
prime over 2, right.
So, we want our average per step
reward to be epsilon close.
But, to do that,
we're going to run this algorithm B,
with an even tighter epsilon.
>> Okay.
>> Alright.
So, that gives us this inequality.
With only one free variable, which is n.
So how big does n have to be,
so that everything works out?
So, that should be solvable.
>> Yeah.
>> Multiply both sides by n.
You do some algebra.
>> Okay, so
the algebra got us to this point.
Where we say that the n, the number of
steps that we need to run before we have
near optimal reward per step.
Is at least m, the number of mistakes
that the algorithm b is going to make,
times 2 over epsilon prime minus 1.
So epsilon prime,
if you think of epsilon prime
as being some teeny tiny number.
So 2 over epsilon prime is going to
be some fairly big number.
We have to run that minus 1.
But it's still a polynomial in
the epsilon prime that we were
originally given.
>> Right.
Or 1 over epsilon prime.
So epsilon prime has to be,
>> Less than 1.
>> Right.
>> So we're good.
What's going to happen here,
is we could get something like 2 over
1 minus 1 which is going to be 1.
But as epsilon prime gets closer and
closer to 0, this blows up, but
again, it's polynomial
in 1 over epsilon prime.
So we're good.
It just means that we
have to run a bit longer
than the number of mistakes
that we are bounded by.
So that on average, things work out,
because we're going to be
essentially optimal here.
We're going to be epsilon
over 2 optimal here.
And so when we've actually
worked that all the way through,
we're going to get something that,
averaged out
over this very long time interval,
it's nearly optimal per time step.
So that the reward that we're going to
get is actually close to optimal.