Now, there's one more type of search for
plans that we can do with
the classical planning language
that we couldn't do before.
And this is searching
through the space of plans
rather than searching
through the space of states.
In forward search, we were searching
through concrete world states.
In backward search, we were
searching through abstract states,
in which some of the variables
were unspecified.
But in plan space search,
we search through the space of plans.
And here's how it works.
We start off with an empty plan.
We have the start state and
the goal state.
And that's all we know about the plan.
So obviously, this plan is flawed.
It doesn't lead us from
the start to the goal.
And then we say,
let's do an operation to edit or
modify that plan by
adding something in new.
And here, we're tackling the problem
of how to get dressed and
put on all the clothes
in the right order.
So we say at about
the operators we have,
we could add one of those
operators into the plan.
And so here we say, well what if we
added the put on right shoe operator,
and then we end up with this plan.
That still doesn't solve the problem,
so we need to keep refining that plan.
Then we come here and say,
well, maybe we could add in
the put on left shoe operator.
And here I've shown the plan as
a parallel branching structure rather
than just as sequence.
And that's a useful thing to do because
it captures the fact these can be done
in either order.
And then we will keep refining like
that, adding on new branches or
new operators into the plan, until we
got a plan that was guaranteed to work.
Now this approach was popular in the
1980s, but it's faded from popularity.
Right now, the most popular approaches
have to do with forward search.
Now, we saw some of
the advantages of backward search.
The advantage of forward
search seems to be
that we can come up with
very good heuristics.
So we can do heuristic search.
And we saw how important it was to have
good heuristics, to do heuristic search.
And because the forward search
deals with concrete plan states,
it seems to be easier to
come up with good heuristics