Great job so far.
You now have all the tools you need to
build the first stage of the project.
To get you started in
the right direction,
we're going to show you step-by-step how
to use these tools to map out the lane
on an image of the road.
>> Let's review what steps you'll take.
First, you need to calibrate the camera.
Second, correct for image distortion.
Third, implement a color and
gradient threshold.
And fourth, warp the image
using perspective transform.
Is that it?
>> Well,
that gets us most of the way but
we still need to decide which
pixels are lane line pixels.
And then determine the line shape and
position.
So next we're going to go
through an example of that so
you have a clear picture of
how to approach the project.