Besides unary and binary constraints, we
could have constraints that involve 3 or
more variables or soft constraints,
like the fact that I prefer to teach
on a Tuesday/Thursday schedule.
Problems with preference constraints are
called constraint optimization problems
and are solved with linear programming.
>> There are lots of examples of
constraint satisfaction problems.
Sudoku is a classic game which can be
solved with any of the methods we will
be teaching.
>> Other examples include car assembly,
job scheduling in factories, class
scheduling, spreadsheets, transportation
scheduling, or floor planning.
Many of these require
real valued variables.