To answer the quiz questions,
we've provided a link to
the AsyncTask documentation site.
One section called the four steps
is particularly relevant, and
discusses the purpose of
each call back method.
All right, let's talk about
the answers for this quiz.
The important part is that
you understand immediately
after Async has started, onPreExecute
is called on the main thread.
Then, doinBackground will
happen on a background thread.
While doinBackground is executing,
if you call publishProgress,
then the onProgressUpdate callback will
be triggered with a new progress value.
This happens on the main thread, so
you can update the user on
the progress of the task.
Finally, after doinBackground finishes,
then the result is passed to
the onPostExecute method.
This method runs on the main thread so
that you can update your app UI.
Great work.
You're well on your way to
understanding how to take advantage
of the background thread
with the AsyncTask class.