So the first thing you want
to do is download this file,
fresh_tomatoes.py from
the instructor notes.
Once you've downloaded it, make sure you
save this file in the exact same folder
as the Python file where we created
all of these movie instances.
Okay, so I'm going to begin to
use the fresh_tomatoes file.
And then call the function
open_movies_page.
Now I know that this function
open_movies_page takes in a list
on an array of movies.
I do have a bunch of movies that
I have created over here, but
I do need to put them all
in a list on an array.
Let me do that next.
So, I will define an empty array or
a list called movies.
There it is.
And to this list, I will add all of
the movies I had created previously.
So, the first movie to add is toy_story,
next one is avatar,
next is school_of_rock,
the next one is ratatouille,
it's spelling is a little difficult.
I think I got it.
Next in line is midnight_in_paris and
the final one is hunger_games.
So there is our movies array.
By the way, in case you need
more information about lists or
arrays, you can find a helpful
link in the instructor notes.
All right.
Now that I have a list of movies,
I can give this list as input to
the open_movies_page function.
Let me do that next.
So I will provide movies as the argument
to open_movies_page function.
There it is.
Now before I save and
run this entire program,
I know that I still haven't imported
the file fresh_tomatoes in my program.
So I will scroll all the way up,
and import fresh_tomatoes.
Notice that this line of code will
work only if the fresh_tomatoes file
is in the exact same folder
as our current Python file.
Okay.
Time to save and run this program.
And there is our movies website.
If I click on any one of the links,
its trailer will play.
[MUSIC]