VR technology can't
exist without tracking.
It allows a computer to know
where you are in space.
To do this,
all major VR systems rely on a chip
called an Inertial Measurement Unit,
or IMU for short.
An Inertial Measurement Unit enables
high speed rotational tracking.
This means the chip knows
how it is being rotated.
We're going to talk more about
IMUs in an upcoming lesson.
Unfortunately, IMUs can't
tell where an object
is actually located in space,
only how it's rotated.
In order to tell where
objects are located,
modern VR systems employ a variety
of positional tracking techniques.
Sometimes they use cameras.
Sometimes they use lasers and
precise clocks.
Sometime they use magnetic fields.
Positional tracking is
an area of active research.
And there isn't yet
a universally accepted technique.
We'll talk more about this
too in the upcoming lesson.
But for now just know that VR requires
some kind of tracking in order to work.
It’s how the system allows your body
movements to control the VR world, okay.
We've looked at the major
components of VR hardware,
now let’s talk about some of the biggest
challenges in creating high quality VR.