Change is going to be about what when we talk about functions?
Well change is going to be about derivatives, all right?
And this is why we're going to be
able to talk about derivatives with respect to our functions.
So here we have a very simple image, and
I'm going to show you a plot here of a horizontal row, so if we just take a row.
And we would just plot it.
You'd see it starts out high and then it comes down smoothly and
then it goes back up again.
All right, so this is a nice smooth image.
Well as you remember, when you were taking a look at change back in
calculus class, you would take the derivative.
If I apply the derivative to that function,
I would get a function that looks like this.
So this is the first derivative of that scan line, and these edges,
which are these edges, correspond to these extrema of the derivative.
That is, here's, somewhere down here is where the maximum negative slope is.
And somewhere over here is where the maximum positive slope.
This is the maximum negative.
That's the maximum positive.
So, finding edges is going to have something to do
with finding peaks in the derivative.
So how are we going to find these extreme in the derivatives?
Well, the same way we found other things, right.
How do we find Waldo?
We ran some filter, we applied some filter and looked for its response.
So we're going to filter our image with the appropriate word is
operator in order to find these peaks in the derivatives.