And finally, one more point regarding signal handling.
We have two types of signals.
The first type are the so-called one-shot signals.
One property of these signals is that we know that if they're multiple instances
of the same signal that will occur, they will be handled at least once.
So it is possible that if we have a situation in which only one signal of
that kind occurred versus n signals of that same kind occurred,
that only one execution of the actual signal handler is performed.
The other thing about the one-shot signals is that the handling routine must be
re-enabled every single time.
So, if the process wants to install some custom handler for a particular signal,
then invoking the operation will mean that once when the signal occurs,
the process specific handling routine will be invoked.
However, any future instances of that signal will be handled by
the default operating system action.
Or, if the operating system chooses to ignore such signals then they
will be lost.
Another type of signals are so-called real time signals that are supported in
an operating system like Linux, for instance.
And their behavior is such that if a signal is raised n times,
then the handler is guaranteed to be called n times as well.
So, they have sort of a queuing behavior as opposed to an overriding behavior,
as is the case with the one-shot signals.