Does this code look familiar?
For this quiz you'll be refactoring
it and making it actually work.
To do so, you're going to need to create
a chain or a sequence of promises.
I want you to loop through the array of
URLs that comes in the search results,
create a promise for
each one and then use that promise to
create a thumbnail once it resolves.
There are probably a few different
ways to solve this challenge.
You'll know you've done it correctly
when the thumbnails show up in the same
order on the page as they did in the
original URL from the search results.
Also, don't forget to handle errors.
I'm going to let you decide
what you want to do with them.
When you're done I have a question for
you.
How are the requests executed?
Are they executed in series or
in parallel?
Even if you think you know the answer,
make sure you check the network
panel because you may be surprised.
I'm going to give you
some hints to help out.
But if you want a challenge,
go ahead and skip to the quiz.
Of course there's always help
in the instructor notes.
Are you still here?
Okay.
I want you to think about
a loop that looks like this.
For every iteration through the loop,
x increases by 1 before the iteration,
x is at 0.
Then you add 1 to x and get 1.
You add another 1 to x and get 2.
And then so on, add another one.
You get 3.
And at some point you've chained so
many ones together that you've got 10.
I want you to treat the sequence
similarly, but don't use addition here.
For every iteration through the loop,
add another then to
the end of the sequence.
Remember that for each planet
you're going to need two actions.
You'll need to get the JSON and
create a planet thumbnail.
In this way the sequence
will grow by one request and
one thumbnail for every iteration.
Okay good luck.