The correct steps for
setting up a location services
application are as follows.
First, you create a GoogleApiClient
that uses the location services API.
Then, you extend your activity with
the GoogleApiClientConnectionCallbacks.
The next step is to extend
your activity with the
GoogleApiClient.OnConnectionFailedListe-
ner.
You use this in case
the connection fails.
Following that, you'll extend your
activity using a location listener, and
this listens for location updates.
After you've connected the Google API
clients, you'll wait for
the on connected callback.
And then finally, in this callback,
the onConnected callback,
you'll set up
the onLocationChanged call back.
And in this you can capture
your location information.
This sequence will be used in every app
that uses the location provider and
you'll want to be sure you know all of
these as you move on throughout the rest
of this class.
Since this sequence is so
important, take some time to think of
a good way to remember all these steps.
And then go ahead and
post in the forum about it.
Practice always makes perfect of course.
And do take some time to read in
the forums what other people have said,
and you might find a pneumonic
that works for you.
I just got it down after a little while.
I hope you could do something similar.