Here are the answers I got.
The magnitude of the first
vector is 7.440.
The magnitude of the second
vector is 10.884.
Now for the normalizations, for
the first vector I got 0.934, -0.357.
And for the last vector,
I got 0.340, 0.530,
and -0.777.
Now let's take a look at the code
I wrote to get these answers.
I worked on the magnitude
function first,
since I can leverage it in
my normalized function.
Remember that the magnitude of
a vector can be found by squaring its
coordinates, adding them together.
And then taking the square
root of the sum.
Let's implement that in this function.
First, I imported square
root from the module math
since I'll need it in my function.
Next, I used a list comprehension
to make a list of the squares
of the coordinates, x** for
x in self.coordinates.
And I called this list
coordinate_squared.
I can find the sum of this list
using the built in sum function, and
then I can return the square root of
the sum using the square root function.
So it returns
sqrt(sum(coordinates_squared)).
Now using the magnitude function,
I can code the normalized function.
Recall that we can normalize
the vector by multiplying it by1
over its magnitude.
Therefore, if I let magnitude
= self.magnitude(),
I can return
self.times_scalar(1./magnitude).
To deal with the case that
self might be the 0 vector,
I wrap this code in a try block.
If self is the 0 vector,
then magnitude will become 0.
And then dividing by magnitude
will raise a 0 division error.
I can then catch this error with
the statement, except ZeroDivisionError.
And then raise a new exception
with the message Cannot normalize
the zero vector..
Note that I'm already starting to
leverage some of our preexisting
functions to define
the normalized function.
This trend will continue as we
progress throughout the lesson.
Now, using the two functions I've coded,
I can compute the magnitudes and
normalizations of the vectors, giving
me the answers that I showed earlier.