To teach you how to implement implicit
intents, we have another toy app.
Within the app,
there are these four buttons,
with a label describing what
each one should do when clicked.
Currently, each button
simply displays a toast.
One by one, we'll walk you through
creating the implicit intent, and
then you will do it on your own for
practice.
Let's start by the open website button.
If you'd like to follow along,
open the exercise that's called
OpenWebpage exercise folder.
The best place for learning how to
create certain functionality in your
Android app is on the Android
developer documentation site.
In order to find the code I'm looking
for, I'm going to search Google for
common intents.
The result I want should
be the first one listed.
If it's not there,
please visit the link that's mentioned
in the notes underneath the video.
As you'll come to learn throughout your
experience as an Android developer,
the documentation almost always
has what you're looking for
if you know where to search.
It can be overwhelming at first,
but trust me, over time, you'll begin
to get more comfortable with it.
All right, so we're looking for
opening a web page.
Let's check out in this
document links over here and
see if any of those links might
help me find what I'm looking for.
Aha, web browser.
That looks promising.
Let's click at that and have a read.
Perfect, that's exactly
what we're looking for.
And there is an even an example
on how to load a web URL.
Most implicit intents include two
things, an action and a data.
The action says what
you're trying to do and
the data is what you're
passing onto the action.
Let's go back to our code and
start by creating a function that will
be called when the button is pressed.
This method expects a URL for
the website that I'd
like to open as a string.
The intent, however, requires any
data to be identified as a URI.
A URI is like an address
that points to the data
you're planning to pass through
to the intended action.
In this case, our web page URL
should be parsed into a URI.
And then we create the intent and
pass in that URI.
Intent.ACTION_VIEW tells the Android
system that we want to view content.
In this case, our content is a web
page with the URL specified.
And then I'm ready to start my activity.
This if condition here asks the Android
system if there's an app that can handle
our request.
If we didn't include this check,
the request would probably work
with most users, but would crash if
a device doesn't have an app installed
that can handle our request.
Okay, now that I've written
the code to open a website,
I can replace my toast message
with a call to that method.
I'll first remove that Toast message,
and then create a string to store
the Udacity homepage and
pass it to the openWebPage function.
Now, I can run the app and
open the web page from within it.
And if I load the application
into the emulator and
click the Open Website button,
it actually opens the Udacity website.
Pretty cool?