After hearing about these
approximation schemes,
the optimist may be saying, hey,
maybe every NP complete problem
admits a fully polynomial
time approximation scheme.
Unfortunately, this isn't
true unless P is equal to NP.
There are some problems where
approximating the optimum within certain
factors, would lead to
a polynomial algorithm for
solving every NP complete problem.
This phenomenon is known as
the hardness of approximation, and
occupies an important place
in the study of complexity.
We'll illustrate this idea by showing
that the traveling salesman problem
is hard to approximate to
within any constant factor.
In case you haven't seen the traveling
salesman problem before,
it can be stated like this, we're given
a graph G and usually all the edges
are present and with each one of them
is associated some cost or a distance.
We'll assume that all edges are present,
so
we won't draw them in our example
graphs like this one here.
The goal is to find the minimum
cost Hamiltonian cycle.
That is to say, we want to visit each
of the vertices without ever visiting
the same one twice, and to do so
in a way that minimizes
the sum of the costs associated with
each of the edges that we chose.
This problem is NP-complete in general.
And even a constant factor approximation
is impossible unless P = NP,
as we will prove next.