The answers at the app bar should
stay in place at the first and
the third screens.
Let's take a look.
In the first screen,
since the app bar is above the content,
forming a step, the content surface
should slide beneath the app bar.
In the second screen,
since the app bar and
content are adjacent surfaces,
they form a seam.
When you slide the content surface,
the app bar has to move as well to
make space for the content surface.
In the last screen, the app bar is
below the content surface, again,
forming a step.
But, this time,
when scrolling the content, it should
cover the app bar since the content
surface is at a higher elevation.