You're actually using HTTP right now.
If you take a look at your browser,
there's probably something in the web
address bar that looks
like https://udacity.com.
We're not going to worry
about the s right now, but
we'll focus on the http part.
So, what exactly is HTTP?
Or more importantly, what is a protocol?
A protocol is a way of communicating,
a standard operating procedure or
the rules for communication.
All these definitions work.
For instance, think about shaking hands.
In certain places around the world,
it's customary to shake hands
when you first meet someone.
We might call this a protocol or
following protocol.
But sometimes even when people
should shake hands, they don't.
When this happens, the protocol isn't
followed and for humans this is okay.
If I forgot to shake your hand, then our
conversation may start awkwardly but
will probably keep chatting.
This is very different from
how computers use protocol.
Computers must follow protocol,
in order to communicate.
If computers don't follow protocol,
then they don't know what's going on.
And this is where HTTP
comes into the picture.
HTTP is a protocol
built specifically for
communicating hypertext
data between computers.
This could consist of images,
text, video.
But for now,
we can just think of all this as data.
But how does HTTP work?
As developers we don't really need
to know the low-level details.
And instead we can just look
at a high-level abstraction.
And we'll show that to you next.