So let's look at the example of blurring and frequencies a little bit.
Remember our peppers image from a while ago?
This was my original image.
We can blur this by a five by five Gaussian kernel.
You can see a little bit of blurriness.
It's not very exaggerated because our kernel is very small.
Now, I can just take these two images.
And if I was to subtract this image from the original,
I should figure out where all the high frequency information was, right?
And this is shown here, a dark image.
I don't know if you can see all the details.
But you can see all of the edges.
Because, if you remember, when we do Gaussian blurs,
that's the one point that we preserve a lot.
Because we look at information out there.
So while everything is blurred, the sharp edges remain.
And now, if I was to just do subtraction of the smooth minus the original,
we figure out where all the sharp information is.
Now, of course, this is one way of being able to
extract information about where all the high frequency information is.
And of course, this allows us to start paying attention just to
high frequency information.
And we can run different processes on it.
So basically, the bottom line is, by doing all of this kind of stuff, we can now
specifically channel our efforts to improve quality of images, either at the low
frequency or the high frequency, and similarly, not just improve processing.
We can actually start putting in more attention to the details that
are available at high frequencies and
low frequencies if you do analysis like this.
And that was one of the major parts of us trying to look at
the frequency domain.