First let's dive into the HTML.
I took the entire div that surrounds our cat, and
I said data bind equals with current cat.
That means that all of the data binds inside will be
relative to our current cat.
So when we say h2 data bind equals text name,
we're really saying current cat.name.
Same with title and click count and image source and nick names.
That's a pretty simple change.
However, for the click binding here we need to say increment counter and
run it on the view model.
Not on current cat, current cat does not have an increment counter function.
If you look through the documentation you'll find that with,
with, you can use $parent, to get up out of the scope.
Or in this case, instead of the word,
scope, knockout calls it a binding context.
Now the incrementCounter method is the real main thing that need changing in
the app.js.
Now it used to say this.currentcat.clickcount, and
then this.currentcat.clickcount plus 1.
Now this is the tricky part.
Here's what it looked like previously.
When we would click on the cat,
we were clicking on the view model binding context.
We hadn't created a new binding context with with binding yet.
So when we clicked on the image,
we were effectively within the binding context of the view model here.
But when we added the with here, now when you click on
the image you are within the binding context of currentCat.
So here in app.js we don't need to say
this.currentCat anymore because we're already in the currentCat binding context.
Instead we can say this and
this represents the binding context of the current cat.
So this current cat binding context.click count.
Now that's one way we could have approached this.
Let me show a different way.
So once again this is what we had before.
This .currentCat.clickCount now this we've already established just
now represents the currentCat's binding context because of
the with in our index.html.
So rather than say this, the currentCat context,
we could instead say var self equals this while we're here in the view model.
Then we can use self here and here.
Now we're not using this which represents the binding context when you
click on increment counter,
we're talking about self which represents the view model here.
Sure enough that also works.
Now neither of these two methods are better or
worse than the other, but it is important to know about this trick here.
Whenever you want to access the outer this.
In this case the view model, you can store it somewhere.
In this case I'm storing it to self.
And now inside of functions that are nested,
I can say self.foo, self.var, self.currentCat.
Now my special this keyword isn't messing me up.
Self is always going to be defined as the view model,
because I defined it right here.
Keep this trick in mind.
Some other developers write var that equals this.
And then they use that throughout their entire function.
But whether you call it self or that, it's a very good method for
keeping a pointer, keeping a way of accessing our outer this, and
not getting confused by our inner this.
Now if you want to take a minute right now and go and
refactor your code feel free.
Remember that neither of these two approaches here are right or wrong.
Both are just two different ways of solving the same problem.