In lesson 2, stage 1, you'll implement the Count Bolt methods execute and
declare output fields to complete the word count topology.
We've also implemented a reporter bolt to connect your Redis database, and
D3 visualization.
You must link the reporter bolt viewer topology to visualize your results.
In part 1, on your local machine, in your favorite text editor, and again,
I'm using Atom.
Navigate to lesson two >stage one > source >jvm >udacity > storm and
open up the word count topology.
Switch over to your virtual machine and
make sure you are in lesson two stage one.
You can check that to make sure that you're in your virtual machine.
Folder /vagrant/lesson2/stage1.
In part 2,
implement the CountBolt method execute, scroll down to the class CountBolt, and
scroll down further to the method execute, execute takes in a tuple.
Begin by filling in the missing code labelled part 1 of 3.
This code takes in a tuple, extracts the word using the syntax provided,
which you will have to uncomment, that takes in a tuple,
uses the getString method at position 0 to extract the word.
Next, write code to check if the word is present in the map declared in
the prepare method.
CountMap that is a HashMap with key string and value integer.
Right code to check if the word is present in the map.
If the word already exists in the countMap increment the count by one.
If not add the word to the HashMap with a value of one.
Finally after your countMap is updated, admit the word and
count out the collector by simply un-commenting the provided code.
Notice that the collector method.admit is being called with the word and
the countMap.get word which will return the value count.
In part 3, since we are emmitting the word and
count, we need to declare output fields, word and count.
In part two of three, un-comment the line that calls the declare method on
the output fields declarer that declares the field word and count.
This completes the count bolt implementation.
Remember to package your program in maven,
submit the program to storm to view on your command line.
In part 4 of this lesson, once your program is running correctly to
the command line, the report bolt must be connected to the topology.
Scroll down to your TopologyBuilder.
In the mean method you'll see the TopologyBuilder declaration builder.
The syntax we used in our quiz is here.
Here the Spout word-spout is connected to the count bolt
using the fields grouping on field word.
And finally, in part 3 of 3 use the set bolt method to add the provided report
bolt with an id report bolt and global grouping with parallelism of one.
After implementing the count bolt and implementing the report bolt to
your topology, you are ready to run your Storm word count with visualization.
In part five of the written instructions, scroll up to the report bolt.
Just to review the syntax we've used to publish the word in count.
Here we have a redis instance that we call the method publish.
Here's our word, here's our count.
And here we use a pipe character to separate the two.
The visualization takes in the string published by redis,
splits according to the pipe and loads the word in count.
Finally, in part six of the written instructions, at the command line,
run maven package.
Remember the syntax is mvn package.
And once you see BUILD SUCCESS, run your topology by submitting to storm.
Storm jar target/udacity, remember to use tab,-
tab to get
the package jar-with-dependencies.jar udacity.storm.wordCountTopology.
Remember that for
your visualization to run, your Flask server needs to be running.
If it's not running already, go into the viz directory and type python app.py.
As your program runs, refresh your page, and you can see Storm running in
the background, and your visualization should appear.
Notice that the size of the words is linked to the count, so
as the topology runs longer, our names increase in size.
Good luck with the exercise.