This all raises the question,
how to minimize more complicated loss functions
than the one we discussed so far.
Are there closed-form solutions of the type we found for linear regression?
Or do we have to resort to iterative methods?
The general answer is, unfortunantly, we have to resort to iterative methods.
Even though there are special cases in which corresponding solutions may exist,
in general, our loss functions now become complicated enough
that all we can do is iterate.
Here is a prototypical loss function
and the method for interation will be called gradient descent.
In gradient descent, you start with an initial guess,
W-0, where 0 is your iteration number,
and then you up with it iteratively.
Your i plus 1st parameter guess will be obtained by taking your i-th guess
and subtracting from it the gradient of your loss function,
and that guess multiplied by a small learning weight alpha,
where alpha is often as small as 0.01.
I have a couple of questions for you.
Consider the following 3 points.
We call them A, B, C.
I wish to know, for points A, B, and C,
Is the gradient at this point positive, about zero, or negative?
For each of those, check exactly one of those cases.