Let me take my example world
and apply value iteration in a quiz.
As before, assume the value is initialized as
+100 and -100 for the absorbing states
and 0 everywhere else.
And let me make the assumption that our transition probability is deterministic.
That is, if I execute the east action of this state over here
with probability 1 item over here,
if I assume the north action over here, probability 1,
I will find myself in the same state as before.
There is no uncertainty anymore.
That's really important for now, just for this one quiz.
I'll also assume gamma equals 1,
just to make things a little bit simpler.
And the cost over here is -3 unless you reach an absorbing state.
What I'd like to know, after a single backup,
what's the value of A3?