One of the most basic synchronization
constructs that's commonly supported in
an operating system is spinlock.
In some ways,
spinlocks are similar to a mutex.
The lock is used to protect the critical
section to provide mutual exclusion
among potentially multiple threads or
processes that are trying to
perform this critical section.
And it has certain constructs that
are equivalent to the lock and
unlock constructs that
we saw with mutexes.
The use of these lock and
unlock operations is similar
to the case of the mutexes.
If the lock is free,
then we can acquire it and
proceed with the execution
of the critical section.
And if the lock is not free, we will be
suspended at this particular point and
unable to go on.
The way spinlocks differ than mutexes,
however, is that when the lock is busy,
the thread that's suspended in its
execution at this particular point of
time isn't blocked, like in the case of
mutexes, but instead, it is spinning.
It is running on the CPU and
repeatedly checking to see
whether this lock became free.
With mutexes, the thread would have
relinquished the CPU and allowed for
another thread to run.
With spinlocks, the thread will spin.
It will burn CPU cycles until
the lock becomes free or
until the thread gets preempted for
some reason.
For instance, maybe it was spinning
until ultimately its time slice expired,
or potentially a higher
priority thread became runable.
Because of their simplicities, spinlocks
are a basic synchronization primitive,
and they can be used to
implement more complex,
more sophisticated
synchronization constructs.
Because they're a basic construct,
we will revisit spinlocks a little bit
later in this lesson, and we will spend
some time discussing different
implementation strategies for spinlocks.