Now its your turn.
Add activity transitions
between the main activity and
the detail activity for
both portrait and landscape views.
So, start by creating new themes,
the main and detail activity and
applying them in the android manifest.
The, create enter and return transition
resources for both portrait and
landscape that match the video
that we have playing here.
Note that the animation resources for
the main activity just set the window
content transitions flag to true.
Add the transition resources then to v21
versions of the app in detail activity
styles, and
the start the activity using the bundle
from makeSceneTransitionAnimations.