So now that you know a test is based
around expectations, you'll need to
start identifying areas in our code
in which you're setting expectations.
By doing this, you'll know exactly
what kind of test you need to run.
Imagine I have this function
in one of my applications.
It's pretty simple.
It just adds two numbers together.
And it would be called like this.
The result of 2 plus 3 is 5.
Pretty simple.
But despite the simplicity of
this function, I've already set
a whole lot of expectations about
how this function will be used.
Right off the bat, when calling this
function, the first expectation I have
is that the add function has been
defined and it actually exists.
In this example, it's pretty obvious.
But what if I had this function defined
in another file, like a library?
This function wouldn't be so
obvious anymore.
Secondly, I had the expectation that the
function is actually accomplishing our
intended task.
If this call were to return a different
number, like 6, it would be a clear
indicator I've messed up the actual
implementation of the function somehow.
Finally, I'm expecting this function
will always be called as I intended,
with numbers as the parameter.
But what if I were to call this
function with strings being
passed in instead of numbers?
I'd get the result 23,
which you'll notice is also a string,
since the plus operator can
catonate strings together.
It's important to identify each of these
expectations as early as possible so
you can write tests against them,
from whether the function even exists
to the output that is expected.
This certainly isn't a comprehensive
list of every expectation, but as you
continue to identify other expectations,
or opportunities for a test.
You can always go back and
update your test suite.