Hi, I'm Matt Sonic.
And I'll be your instructor for
this course.
And this is.
And he'll be your instructor later on.
&gt;&gt; Before we get started we'd like
to show you the final project,
which is called Modern Apartment.
&gt;&gt; Modern Apartment is
a virtual reality environment,
built using the Unity editor.
&gt;&gt; Along the way,
you'll learn how to place objects.
&gt;&gt; Yep, you'll also learn how to
rotate them and scale them, as well.
&gt;&gt; You'll also be able to change
their color by using materials,
just like this.
&gt;&gt; It's pretty cool, right?
At the very end, we'll learn how to set
the mood using some dramatic lighting,
something like this.
&gt;&gt; And then get to view that
within our cardboard VR viewers.
Cool, right?
&gt;&gt; Let's get started.