So that was a pretty tough question.
If you didn't get it correct,
no worries.
We'll go over the solution now.
So we know that our function's
input is the string,
madlib, that can contain
instances of noun and verb.
And our goal is to return
a new string processed
where all those instances are replaced
with the random nouns and verbs.
So we'll be using the idea of
the four character long box
to solve this problem, which we
went over before writing code for
a function word transformer.
Since we need to keep track
of our box's position,
because it's moving up the sting
by increments of one or
four, we'll need to introduce
a new variable for that purpose.
We'll set the variable index to 0 and
we chose 0 because our box will start at
the beginning of the string passed in.
Since the length of the string passed in
can vary and because we want to repeat
the same steps of checking everything in
the box, and adding to process based on
what's inside over and over again,
we'll want to use this while loop.
But now we need to figure
out what our condition is.
Since we're going through the string
madlib character by character
until we've reached the end of
the string, the conditional use for
a while loop will be while index
is less than the length of madlib.
Let's write that down.
Cool, now that we have
our while loop set up,
let's start writing
the internals of the loop.
Since all our decisions on whether
to add a single character or
a random verb or noun is based on the
idea of this four character long box,
we need to set that up first.
In code, the box will be this
four character long substring
starting from index, or at
the beginning of the box to index + 4.
Now the only thing I don't like about
this string slice is this number 4 here.
Although we know it represents
the length of the box,
this quote unquote magic number
can cause confusion later on.
If you come back to this program after a
while or someone looks at your code for
the first time they might have trouble
figuring out what this number means or
what its purpose is which
is something we don't want.
To fix this I set this
variable box length to 4, and
use that in our string slice.
Now it's clear what
the number 4 represents.
Now that we have our four
character box set up properly,
let's refresh ourselves on what we need
to do based on the contents of this box.
So if the box over the variable
frame is equal to noun or
verb we add the respective random
noun or verb to processed and
move our box over by four characters.
If the box isn't equal to noun or verb
we add the first character of frame to
processed and move our box over by one.
This variable, to_add,
has the proper random word or
single character we need to
add to our string processed,
since it uses the function
word_transformer which we wrote before.
To_add will be equal to a random verb
if frame is equal to the string verb,
a random noun,
if frame is equal to the string noun,
else it would be equal to
the first character of frame.
Let's add this now to
our processed string.
Now that our processed string
has the right value added to it
the only thing left to do is move our
box over by one or four characters so
we can repeat this process.
How can we do this?
Why don't we check the length of
to_add or the word returned and
make our decision based on that?
If the length of to_add is one character
long, then we obviously haven't been
returned with a random verb or noun so
we'll just inch our box by one index.
If that wasn't the case, you're for sure
returned with a random verb or noun so
we'll add 4 to index instead.
The last thing we need to do is
return the processed string.
So let's add that to the end of
our function, outside of the loop.
And there we have it, we now have
a fully functioning madlibs generator,
that can replace instances of noun and
verb with the random nouns and verbs.
Pretty cool.