The communication all comes from
the two broadcast operations.
Their cost depends on what
you assume about the cost of
a broadcast.
The little m in these formulas
denotes the size of the message.
Now for this question,
little m corresponds to the size
of these little blocks.
How large are they?
Recall that the dimensions
are n over root P by s.
Now to get the total
volume of communication,
remember that we execute this pair
of broadcasts, n over s times.
Thus the total communication
volume we have to pay for
is n/s times the size of each message.
That, it turns out is n
squared over square root of P.
So assuming a choice of
these two implementations,
here are two possible correct pairings.
If you assume the tree based algorithm,
then a correct pair would be log P and
log P.
If, on the other hand, you assume
the bucketing based algorithm,
then a correct pairing would be P and 1.