To understand why we need RPC,
let's look at two example applications.
The first one is an application, where
a client requests a file from a server.
And uses a simple get file
protocol that's like HTTP request,
but less complex.
In this application the client and
the server interact using
a socket based API.
And as a developer you would
have to explicitly create and
initialize the sockets,
then allocate any buffers that
are going to be sent via those sockets,
and populate them with anything that
includes protocol related information.
Like for instance,
this protocol will have something like,
get file directives.
And you have to specify
the size of the buffer.
And also you'll have to explicitly copy
the data in and out of these buffers.
So copy the file name, string or the
actual file in and out of these buffers.
Now imagine another application that's
also a client server application
in which the client interacts with
a server to upload some images and
that it requests then from the server
for these images to be modified.
To create a gray scale version
of an image, to create a low
resolution version of an image,
to apply some phase detection algorithm.
So it's in some sense
similar to get file, but
there are some additional
functionalities,
some additional processing that needs
to be performed for every image.
The steps that are required from the
developer of this particular application
are very similar, in fact some of
them are identical to the steps that
are required in the get
file application.
One difference is that the protocol
related information that would have
to be included in the buffers would have
to specify things like the algorithm
that the client is requesting
from the server to be performed.
Like whether it's grace key link or
whether its some face detection
algorithm along with any parameters
are relevant for that algorithm.
And also the data that is being sent
between the client and the server,
we said in this case the client
uploads an image to the server and
then the server returns that image
back to the client after this
particular function has been performed.
That's different than the file name, the
string that's being sent from the client
to the server, and the actual
file that's returned in response.
But a lot of the steps end up
being identical in both cases.
In the 80s, as networks
are becoming faster, and more and
more of distributed applications
were being developed.
It became obvious that these kinds
of steps are really very common
in a related interprocess
communications, and need to be
repeatedly reimplemented for a majority
of these kinds of applications.
It was obvious that we need some system
solution that will simplify this process
that will capture all the common
steps that are related to remote
interprocess communications.
And this key do
Remote Procedure Calls or RPC.