In this lesson, I want to introduce
you to the concept of video textures.
Video textures basically takes
the concept of what we have learned in
images, that is, looking for
textures in the spatial domain,
something repeating over an image.
For example, like a, a pattern of some
sort could be grass or could be water.
Now, in this instance,
we're going to take this concept and
apply it to the domain of video.
How does one process and
analyze a sequence of images that
have flowing water, moving grass, and
other types of repeating phenomenon,
natural phenomenon like this?
And you learn actually how to
synthesize novel versions of this
by just doing a simple bit of
analysis on a small bit of video.
You're also going to have fun
experimenting with this in one of
the assignments.