Hi, and welcome to
Introduction to Data Analysis.
I'm Caroline and
I'll be your instructor for the course.
Now a data analyst is someone who
uses data to answer questions, and
that's exactly what you'll
be doing in this course.
You'll tackle questions like what
makes students more likely to
submit their projects, or what countries
around the world have the highest and
lowest employment rates, and how does
the country you live in compare?
Or how the subway ridership varied
by location, time of day and
weather conditions, and many more.
For each data set you'll have the chance
to pose your own questions and
perform your own investigations.
Along the way you'll learn to use some
libraries that make data analysis
a lot easier.
Specifically, you'll work with NumPy,
Pandas and Matplotlib.
But you'll start off analyzing
data using pure Python.
Now you won't need any experience
with data analysis in order to
take this course.
But you will need to be
comfortable programming in Python.
You should be familiar with things like
loops, functions, lists, dictionaries,
objects, and things like that.
If you need to learn more
about any of those topics,
check out the links in
the instructor notes.
Now let's get started.