Here's the answer, log (n/s).
Why?
Imagine the best case scenario.
A single run of the maximal matchings
algorithm will match every vertex.
So, for instance, here's a sample graph,
with eight vertices, and notice
that under this particular matching,
every vertex is part of a matched edge.
This also means that this graph
with eight vertices will,
when coarsened,
become a graph with four supervertices.
Okay, so let's turn to the general case.
How many vertices must this graph have?
Compared to the previous level, it has
to have at least half as many vertices.
This idea has to hold at every level.
In other words,
relative to the original graph,
the final graph has to have
n/2 to the k or more vertices.
So what does this tell you?
Well, it says you need at
least a logarithmic number of
coarsening steps in order
to shrink the graph.
Of course, this is a lower
bound on the number of steps.
So you might need more if for
some reason it's hard to find a lot
of large matchings in the graph.
In fact, can you think of
a worst case graph to coarsen?