Once you've got all of
your features implemented,
you'll have a working prototype for
your app.
There might still be one or
two bugs that you need to work out, but
it's a really great time to start
getting feedback from other students and
family and friends.
So go ahead, take a minute and
share your app to the forums.
You can just export a zip file and
share that, or even better, you can
share a link to your GitHub repo.
The goal here is to get user feedback
on the look and the feel and
the functionality of the app.
It's a lot easier to
implement changes now than it
will be further on in
the development cycle.
Also make sure that you let users know
of any known bugs so that you're not
getting duplicate reports of things
that you already know are wrong.
Then, take the time to review
two of your classmates' apps.
You never know.
You might learn something.
Check this box when you're done.