First things first,
inside the QRCodeManager
object I created the worker.
The worker points to the script
at scripts/jsqrcode/qrworker.js.
Next up, I went into qrworker.js and
took a look at the scripts
that were being imported.
Index.html also has all those
scripts being included.
However, these are no longer needed,
as they're being imported
by the web worker.
So I'll just delete them.
Back inside the qrworker, it looks
like the image is being decoded, but
then nothing else happens.
All I have to do is use
the postMessage method to
send the result back to the main thread.
In the event that something
goes wrong up here,
the catch block will
post back undefined.
Back in the detectQRCode
function inside the main thread,
I'm posting the imageData to the Worker.
This is how the Worker
gets the image to work on.
This callback for detectQRCode is what
actually displays the URL on the screen.
So I moved all that logic
into the onmessage handler.
When the worker posts a message
back to the main thread,
the onmessage handler gets called and
this function runs.
And here's the bug that
I mentioned before.
Instead of just simply using result,
you have to use result.data.
This result is now a message object
which is the different than the object
that was received when all of the work
was being done by the main thread.
As a result,
simply grab the .data property.
And then just for the heck of it,
I added an onerror
handler just in case something
happens with the worker thread.
It'll display a WorkerException
if something goes wrong.
I'll run gulp serve to
see how the page looks.
And voila, it looks like
the QR code app is working.
I'll go ahead and open up a timeline,
and see how this looks.
Now the timeline's showing that
there are two threads running,
the main thread and a worker.
Looks like it worked.