To help us with this module,
we have Sezan Camacho,
who is one of our resident computer
vision experts here at Udacity.
So, Sezan, how should we get
started finding Lane Lines?
>> Well, your ultimate goal in this
first section is to measure some of
the quantities that need to be
known in order to control the car.
For example, to steer a car,
you'll need to measure how
much your lane is curving.
To do that, you need to map out
the lens in your camera images,
after transforming them to
a different perspective.
One way, you're looking down
on the road from above.
But, in order to get this
perspective transformation right,
you first have to correct for
the effect of image distortion.
>> So, by image distortion,
do you mean something like this?
>> Well hopefully, the distortion we're
dealing with isn't quite that bad, but
yes, that's the idea.
Cameras don't create perfect images.
Some of the objects in the images,
especially ones near the edges,
can get stretched or skewed in various
ways and you need to correct for that.
>> Cool, let's jump into step one,
how to undistort your
distorted camera images.