The answers are.
The first sentence is valid.
It's always true.
Why is that?
Because every model has to have at least
one object and we can have both x and
y refer to that same object, and so
that object must be equal to itself.
Second, the left hand side of
this implication has to be true,
x is always equal to x.
and the right hand side says for
every y does there exist
a z since that y equals z.
And we can say yes, there is.
We can always choose y itself for
the value of z and then y equals y.
So true implies true,
that's always true.
Now, third sentence for
all x P of x or not P of x, and
that's always true, because everything
has to be either in the relation for
P, or out of the relation for
P, so that's valid.
And the fourth,
there exists in x P of x.
That's true for the models in which
there is some x that is a member of P,
but there doesn't necessarily
have to be any at all.
P might be an empty relation.
So this is satisfiable.
True in some models, but
not true in all models.