In this lesson, we will start looking
at the details of what you need to do
in order to perform a cluster analysis.
The first thing we need to do is to make
sure that we have a good set of data
that provides the information needed
to be able to accomplish the analysis.
Once we have that, we'll take
a look at the actual data format,
to make sure it fits with
how clustering works.
I'll be showing you how to do this
process in a software platform called
Ultrix.
However, the principles you'll learn
will help you become proficient in
segmentation and clustering,
regardless of the tool you use.
If you need a refresher on how
to generally clean up a dataset,
check out the course linked
to it in the notes below.
Ready?
Let's get started.