By now, we've learned how to
connect our app to the Internet and
displayed data from that connection
in a simple Android layout.
This is a great start.
In this lesson, you're going to
learn how to effectively display and
interact with scrolling lists of
information using a RecyclerView.
So why are we doing a full
lesson on RecyclerView?
Well simple.
RecyclerView and the design patterns
behind it are things that you see and
interact with many times a day.
After working through the toy app,
you will update the way Sunshine is
implemented to get it
closer to it's final state.
Instead of displaying all the weather
data in a single text view, by the end
of this lesson, Sunshine will load
weather data into individual views for
each date and respond to clicks
on a view with a toast message.
So let's get started.