Just to now start to comparing these technologies.
Look at SLRs, single lens reflex cameras to camera phones.
The DSLR advantages are,
they are because of the fact that they're much bigger can take in more light.
They can actually take in, actually capture depth of field.
All photographers know what that is, and love it.
Shutter lag is not an issue, because when you press the button,
that's when you get the picture.
Controlled field of view, we can actually control it by zooming in and
out, also changing the telephoto on the lens.
Of course we have really nice, optics and
glass in these cameras to capture light.
And there are other types of things which are available allowing you to do
manual control.
Again, DSLR remains as the choice for professionals, or
people really serious about photography.
But, of course, smartphone cameras, here are the advantages.
Well, they actually have computation right there.
In fact, more and more, that's the kind of stuff that we see,
where basic computation is happening when you take a picture.
So for example most of the time when you take a picture,
it's taking more than one picture and actually using a fusion of all of those.
Computed right there locally on the device to give you a better picture.
Data, it can actually capture a lot of data,
and do a lot of other types of computation right there.
Of course, there is a growth of, you know, programmers because of all them now
come with APIs and even, you know, high school kids are writing programs to
generate better computational frameworks of doing photography on these devices.
Of course, not to forget the pipeline is efficient.
I take a picture, I see it right there, I can do things with it right there.
As opposed to download it to a computer and do something with it later