Hey congratulations.
You finished lesson three.
And in this lesson, we learned how
to add images to the word list.
But more importantly,
you learned about the thought process
that goes into adding a new app feature.
And then we rounded out the lesson
by adding visual polish to the app.
So it's really quite
beautiful to look at.
Now balancing all these challenges
was rather tricky because there were
a number of files to modify, but
by planning your steps
accordingly you did it.
Great job.
So now's that time again.
I'd like you to reflect on
what we just covered and
even the things that you struggled with.
How can you have apply these
learnings to your future projects?