So, let me actually show you first, the set up that we use for this class.
So, of course, I'm not trying to get any sympathy points from you,
but in producing this class I spend a lot of time in a dark room like
this working with you know, a tablet that's attached to a computer.
And what's basically happening, there's a camera above.
Of course part of the content is on this computer.
Which is then displayed on this tablet.
And of course using a pen like this, I write on top of this tablet.
And then of course a camera is capturing the images of also what's going on.
So in essence, there are two different images being captured.
One from the camera, which basically has whatever I'm doing with my hands.
And then another one, which basically captures all of the writing I do here.
So in essence this screen, that's actually shown here, is also captured.
On this computer, and
then this camera captures everything from the top down of what's going on.
And the final artifact of course is the combination of these two images.