All right, let's find out which of
these functions print, and which don't.
Let's start with the function double 1.
If you look at the code for
this function,
you don't even see a print statement.
All we do is return two times
the variable x that's passed in, so
double1 clearly doesn't print.
Taking a look at the function double2,
we see only one line of code,
which prints two times
whatever the variable x is.
So we can check double two off
as a function that prints.
The function double3 is a bit trickier.
Although the second line prints
two times the variable x,
this line of code will never be executed
no matter what's passed in for x.
The reason is because of
the order we have our print and
our term statements in.
And Python and a fair amount of other
programming languages you may encounter,
once their return statement is executed,
no other lines of code
after it will be run.
So, the function double3 does not print.
Our final function,
double4, will print though.
The order of the print and
return statements is switched,
which makes all the difference.
The first line of code
prints two times x,
and the second line returns two times x.
So, the function double4 prints.