In this lesson, we will be talking
at length about scheduling and
OS schedulers.
So continuing with our visual metaphor,
we'll try to visualize what are some of
the issues when it
comes to OS scheduling.
Using our toy shop analogies,
we'll think of an OS scheduler and
we'll compare it with
a toy shop manager.
like an OS scheduler, the toy shop
manager schedules work in the toy shop.
For a toy shop manager,
there are multiple ways how it can
choose to schedule the toy shop workers
and dispatch them two
workers in the toy shop.
First, the toy shop owner can
dispatch orders immediately,
as soon as they arrive in the toy shop.
Or the manager may decide to
dispatch the simple orders first.
Or, even conversely, the manager can
decide to dispatch the complex orders as
soon as they arrive in the shop.
The motivation for
each of these choices is based
on some of the high level
goals of the manager and
how he wants to manage the shop and
utilize the resources in the shop.
Let's investigate these
choices a little more.
If the manager wants low
scheduling overhead,
not to have to analyze too much what
he needs to do when an order comes,
he can choose to dispatch
the orders immediately.
The scheduling in this case is very
simple, we can think of it as a FIFO.
First order that comes in,
is the first one that will be served.
If the manager is concerned
with the total number of
orders that get processed
over a period of time,
it would be good to dispatch the simple
orders as soon as they arrive.
They will be the ones that will
be completing more quickly, and
that will maximize
this particular metric.
Obviously, in order to do this,
the manager has to spend a little bit
more time whenever an order comes,
because he needs to check what
kind of order that it is,
whether it's going to be a simple one or
not, and then decide what to do with it.
So basically, it will be important for
the manager to be able to assess
the complexity of the orders.
On the other hand,
on each of the work benches in the shop,
there may be different kinds of tools,
and these simple orders,
these may not really
exercise all of these tools,
they may not require the use of
all aspects of the work benches.
So if the manager wishes to keep all
of the resources that are available on
the work benches as busy as possible,
he may choose to schedule complex
orders as soon as they arrive.
And then whenever simple ones come in,
perhaps the workers can pause
the processing of the complex
order to get a simple one in and
to finish it as soon as possible.
In comparison,
the scheduling options for
a toy shop manager are surprisingly
similar to those of an OS scheduler.
For an OS scheduler, these choices
are analyzed in terms of tasks,
which is either a thread or a process.
And these are being scheduled onto
the CPUs that are managed by the OS
scheduler, like the work benches in
the case of the toy shop manager.
For an OS scheduler, we can choose
a simple approach to schedule tasks
in a first come, first serve manner.
The benefit is that
the scheduling is simple and
that we don't spend a lot of
overhead in the OS scheduler itself.
Using a similar analogy to what the toy
shop manager was thinking of when
he chose to dispatch
the simple orders first,
an OS scheduler can assign,
can dispatch simple tasks first.
The outcome of this kind of scheduling
can be that the throughput of the system
overall is maximized.
And there are schedulers that actually
follow this kind of algorithm and
those are called shortest job first.
So simple in terms of the task
is equal to its running time, so
shortest job first.
And finally, the scheduling logic
behind assigning complex task first
is similar to the case in the toy shop.
Here, the scheduler's calls are to
maximize all aspects of the platform.
So to utilize well both the CPUs as
well as any other devices, memory,
or other resources that
are present on that platform.
As we move through this lesson, we will
discuss some of the options that need to
be considered when designing
algorithms such as these.
And, in general, we will discuss
various aspects of the design and
implementation of OS schedulers.