Welcome back.
In the last lesson,
you learned all about functions.
Functions are great for
simplifying your code and
creating reuseable
shortcuts in your programs.
But let's switch gears for
a moment to talk more about data.
>> Up until this point,
we've only worked with a few
pieces of data at a time.
A couple of numbers, some strings,
and maybe a few booleans.
But what happens when you want to
work with a lot of data all at once?
Let's say we own a doughnut shop.
And let's say we need a way to
keep track of all the doughnuts we
could sell at our shop.
We've got glazed doughnuts, chocolate
frosted doughnuts, Boston cream
doughnuts, powdered doughnuts,
sprinkled doughnuts, maple doughnuts,
coconut doughnuts, coconut jelly
doughnuts, and finally, doughnut holes.
Hey, James, wake up.
>> Right, a lot of doughnuts.
>> Exactly, and
wouldn't it be nice if there were a way
to keep track of all this information?
A way to store it all in one place or
in one variable,
where we could keep a list
of all these doughnuts.
>> Well, we can do just that with
a data structure called an array.
Arrays are a data structure that
can hold multiple data values,
kind of like a list.
In this section, you'll explore how to
create arrays, how to use arrays, and
how arrays are structured.
To start, let's look at how
we could create an array
to keep track of all
the doughnuts in our shop.