Let's build that logic into our app.
We should check that we do
get a 200 response code
before we continue trying
to parse the JSON response.
Now, if we received an error response
code, just return an empty string for
the JSON response.
It wouldn't make sense to try to project
the feature array from the response
because there would be no
information in that response.
So within the Soonami app's code, I
want you to check the HTTP response code
in the makeHttpRequest method and
handle it accordingly.
Also, make sure to double-check the code
to make sure you handle empty or
null cases in the networking
code in a reasonable manner.
See the note below the quiz for
more details.
For example, if the URL's null, we
shouldn't try to make the HTTPrequest.
Or if the JSON is null,
or an empty string,
we shouldn't try to
continue with parsing it.