So this is the second in the series of
three lectures on camera calibration.
Again, I'm going to rely on my
dear friend Aaron Bobick, and
use his lectures on camera calibration.
In the last lecture on
camera calibration,
he introduced the whole mathematics of
how we do extrinsic camera calibration,
that is, being able to capture the world
information of where the camera is
in an environment from
a series of images.
In this one we're going to talk about,
more about the intrinsics,
the focal length and other information
related to the camera, that is,
once the light enters the camera,
how is it generated into an image.
So that's what the focus of this one is.
Again, it's a fun lecture, it's going to
cover a lot of variety of topics.
Pay attention to the concepts.
Again, I wanted to introduce these
ideas to you in an optional framework.