What else can we do?
Well, if I can warp between planes, arbitrary planes,
that means that I can take planes that, say, are in some particular orientation,
and think about what would they look like turned in a different orientation.
So here we have a si, a situation where we've got a plane,
that's the side of this building, I'm assuming the building is more or
less planar, and I'd like to rectify that.
That is, I want to remove the slant.
So you see this window here.
All right, you see how if I were to extend out, these are vanishing point lines.
All right, so these are not parallel, they're going to converge,
you can see that here.
They'll converge all the way out there.
All right, but if they were,
if it was frontal parallel, then they would remain as parallel lines.
Well, if we could compute the relationship between this quadrilateral,
which is essentially like a trapezoid, between that and
a rectangle, we would be able to rectify the entire building.
And in fact that would look like this.
At which point you're supposed to say, ooh, that's cool.
>> Ooh, that's cool.
>> Very good.
So here's the corrected image where now everything is rectilinear.
And in fact, if you take a look at these windows.
In fact notice that these are sort of narrow windows here, and
wide windows here, and narrow windows there.
If you want to think about that from a measurement perspective,
you can see that the, the windows that are sort of
two panes wide were narrower than the ones that are three panes wide.
Even though clearly this is wider than this in the image, but
when I rectified it I was able to measure the whole thing.
Show you another example of that.
So here's a picture.
Suppose you want to measure something, let's say you start with on the floor,
okay, so something about across what's on the floor.
Well, so they have tiles, and those tiles are actually rectangles.
So I could unwarp this picture so that those tiles are now squares.
Because they're,
let's say nine by nine inch squares, which is some number of centimeters.
9 times 2.54, it's 18 to 4 and a-half, I don't know, 23, 24 centimeters?
Anyway, I can rectify that image and then I can go ahead and
I can measure in that new image directly about the tiles.
likewise, if I wanted to measure something on the side of this wall, and
that's a planar surface also.
It happens to be very skewed.
I could rectify that.
And here, I've taken that wall, and
I've spread it back out to being rectangular.
Actually, I didn't, the person I stole the slide from did.
And I can now measure on that.
And what kind of warp is this?
What kind of transformation?
Plane to a plane.
That's right, it's your friend, the homography.
Just to show you what I was talking about from not from quadrilaterals to
rectangles, here on the left hand side I've identified four points.
And you can see those four points are the four corners of a two by
two tile matrix.
But of course, the points aren't rectangular because of
perspective foreshortening, right?
But I can warp that to being a regular square or rectangle.
And the rest of the image will come along for the ride.