This exercise describes a game played between
the federal reserve board and politicians.
Now the politicians have a choice whether they want to contract fiscal policy,
expand it, or do nothing, and the Fed has the same three choices.
Each party has preference for what outcome they would like to see.
Here we've ranked them for each party from 1 being the worst outcome
to 9 being the best outcome.
What I want you is find the equilibrium point for this game.
There will be one equilibrium point. I want you to find it.
The equilibrium point defines a pure strategy for each player.
Tell me the pure strategy for the Fed.
It is contract, do nothing, or expand?
Click on the right box here.
Similarly, for the politicians, click on the right box for their strategy,
which leads to the equilibrium point.
Then tell me the outcome for the game for each player for that equilibrium point.
Then tell me if the equilibrium is Pareto optimal.