If your app lets people buy things, you
can use analytics to track how well your
app is doing at getting them to view
products, put things in the shopping
cart, go through the checkout process,
and close the deal with a purchase.
The first step in tracking how users
navigate to the shopping steps
is to enable Enhanced Ecommerce
in the Admin tab.
So, in the Admin tab >
View > Ecommerce Settings.
You enable Ecommerce,
just switch the status to on and
then go to the Next step.
And then you enable Enhanced Ecommerce,
switch it on.
For now don't worry about the Checkout
Labeling or the FUNNEL STEPS,
we'll come back to those later.
And then you Submit.
Oh look, it says Success.
That's nice.
So now it's your turn.
In the Admin tab > Ecommerce settings.
First, you enable Ecommerce, and
then you enable Enhanced Ecommerce.
And when you're done,
check here and here.