So, three is a new unit for us, and
we're going to start talking about camera models, and it's going to start off
gentle, and then get a little a little rougher later where
we start to get into things like perspective projection, so just bare with us.
In the middle we'll do something cool in stereo,
which you're actually going to to do for a a problem set, and
it's pretty straightforward.
But, that's what that class will, will keep trying to do,
we'll, we'll dive down into the math a little bit, come back up,
try to make sure you always have the math you need for doing the problem sets.
Some of the stuff we'll give you you won't use directly, on the problem sets for
the assignments, or even the exam but
it's important that you, that you, that you know about it.
So, what is an image?
Well, up until today, we've been talking about images as functions, remember,
they were a, two dimensional function or
a function of intensity, of two dimensions, x, y, u, v, i, j.
Today, we're going to start saying wait a minute,
it's not just an arbitrary function, these images are actually projections of
three dimensional scenes, of three dimensional points.