Okay.
So let's take a look at the big picture.
First, your app gets a reference to the ContentResolver,
which handles any provider communication that you need.
You tell the ContentResolver what content provider you're trying to access and
what data in that content provider that you're trying to manipulate.
I'm going to show what happens with a query example.
So first off, your app requests a ContentResolver.
It then uses the Contentresolver to start communications with your
content provider.
Remember, to say what content provider that you're trying to access, and
what data that you're trying to modify, you need to pass a URI.
What you're going to do to that data is designated by whatever method you
choose to call.
Since we're doing a query example, let's assume that I'm using the query method.
There's also some additional parameters that you pass with a query,
which designate what exact rows and
columns in the data source that you're interested in.
The ContentResolver takes the URI from your app, and
just passes it on to the right content provider.
It also calls the same method that your app called on the ContentResolver onto
the ContentProvider.
With the information from this URI, the ContentProvider and
the data source have a little exchange.
And the content provider does whatever manipulations that you told it to.
At that point we have a cursor.
And remember, that cursor gets all the way back to your app, and
it contains some of the data in the data source.
And lucky for you, this data is really easy to iterate through.
So you could do what you want with it.
So the question is, what do you want to do do with it?
So, as we've already discussed,
one of the most powerful features of content providers is that they allow us to
hook into a lot of standard Android classes seamlessly.
I don't mean to be mean, but our UI right now is pretty ugly.
It's also highly inefficient if we had a table with say thousands of rows and
we're trying to scroll through it.
All right.
So let's change all of that and
add a new list view, which is going to look a lot like this.
Of course, it's going to have your own words in it.
This will involve adding something to your program called a cursor adapter.
A cursor adapter is a lot like an arrayadapter.
But instead of taking an array to populate a listview,
we're going to use a cursor to populate that same listview.
So, after getting the cursor back from our content provider,
we can simply pass it off to an instance of simple cursor adapter,
which in turn is linked to a listview.
The cursor will then populate the listview.
And all this can be done with only a few lines of code.
So let's get started.