Now remember that
the string data type here
is just the data type of the constants,
and not the type
of these individual attributes
that are stored in the columns.
Also I explicitly stated where
this ID variable came from
by writing it out here.
So it came from our base columns class.
So remember in the exercise
instructions, I mentioned,
we should also include here any
constants related to the pets table.
And the ones we need
are the gender constants.
So let me write out what the constants
will look like when defined
in our contract here.
All right, so
I've set up that the gender unknown
constant is set to the value 0.
GENDER_MALE constant set to 1,
GENDER_FEMALE is set to the value 2.
And because these constants deal
with the data in our pets table,
we could keep them inside
our PetEntry class.
So now that we have these constants for
genders, we can use them in our editor
activity inside the if statement here,
where we allow the spinner selection for
gender.
So I'm going to replace these values.
So replace 1 with the constant for
GENDER_MALE,
replace 2 with
the GENDER_FEMALE constant, and
replace unknown with our
GENDER_UNKNOWN constant.
So since we're using well named
constants here instead of just numbers,
our code is a lot easier to read.
So if the user selected, say female,
then we would see that nGender is set to
the GENDER_FEMALE constant, instead
of just 2 which would be unclear.
So one more thing to
help with readability.
Notice here that all these constants
come from pet contract .PetEntry.
Well, to remove the redundancy of
having to say PetContract every time,
we can actually import
from PetContract.PetEntry.
So notice up here in
our import statement,
Android Studio has helped us by pulling
in the import statement for PetContract.
But we can make it even more specific,
by adding in PetEntry.
So this means we can remove
this call to PetContract here.
And this is because Android Studio knows
to go one step into the PetContract,
into PetEntry, and
knows where to retrieve these constants.
All right, so
that pretty much sums it up.
So to finish it up,
let's answer these questions.
So first off, we made five constants for
our five different columns.
ID, name, breed, weight, and gender.
We also made a single entry
class because there's
a single table on
the database right now.
The table, remember, is the pet's table.
So our last couple of
questions about gender.
We'll have three constants used for
gender.
And those gender constants
would be of type integer.
And finally, we will need to
update our EditorActivity so
that we can use those constants.