It is now really easy to explain expectation maximization
as a generalization of K-means.
Again, we have a couple of data points here
and 2 randomly chosen cluster centers.
But in the correspondence step instead of making a hard correspondence
we make a soft correspondence.
Each data point is attracted to a cluster center
in proportion to the posterior likelihood
which we will define in a minute.
In the adjustment step or the maximization step
the cluster centers are being optimized just like before
but now the correspondence is a soft variable
and they correspond to all data points in different strengths
not just the nearest ones.
As a result, in EM the cluster centers
tend not to move as far as in K-means.
Their movement is smooth away.
A new correspondence over here gives us different strength
as indicated by the different coloring of the links
and another relaxation step gives us better cluster centers.
And as you can see over time, gradually
the EM will then converge to about the same solution as K-means.
However, all the correspondences are still alive.
Which means there is not a 0, 1 correspondence.
There is a soft correspondence
which relates to a posterior probability, which I will explain next.