So now actually, lets start thinking
about how we can build a pinhole camera.
Let me do this by a simple exercise.
Lets imagine I have a scene
with an object like this.
So now the reason I chose
a simple object, four corners and
we can actually now trace
rays of light through it.
Let me build a small pinhole camera,
which is right here.
Rays of light coming from the three
corners go through the pinhole and
of course, hit the image plane here.
And I can of course now recreate
the image of this thing on my camera.
So this would be a single pinhole.
What happens if I can actually now
play around with multiple pin holes.
Remember, we talked about stereo?
Well, this is equivalent to that,
but in essence also trying to now give
me more information at the camera level.
Remember, this would be two
different images forming.
And now if I could save both of them,
I can actually create more information,
perhaps geometry, and
then use that to create pixels later.
So in this case, of course,
two images would be formed.
And of course I can use that to create
geometry of the scene or a depth map.
This would be an example
of double pinhole.
Another example, again,
to look at the same scene.
I have one pinhole camera.
All the rays are coming in this way.
But, of course what I also do
is move this camera by a bit.
Another pinhole camera,
same aspect here except that I have
basically moved the camera
to be able to do this.
This allows us to capture
things like motion parallax.
Depth parallax is what we've got here.
Motion parallax is what we get here.
Again, recall what we had looked at
when we looked at, stereo imagery.
Final example, it would be at
this instance here, right?
In place of pinholes, we can replace
it with the lens, and of course, if
the lens does the right kinds of things
we would be able to create an image, and
be able to catch a variety
of things with that image.
But, of course, remember,
now we can actually play around with
control of the lens to get
different types of things too.