So remember,
I did say that something has to be read.
So the input may be through
a form where the user types in.
And then we're going to use these
three variables that we have.
So these login, password and
PIN the values that are input,
those are going to be added to this
query that we are producing here.
So, this query to run properly,
one thing to notice here is that
there's an AND, so,
the login value has to match.
The password value has to match.
And the pin value has to match, okay?
We're sort of doing three-factor
authentication here, if you like.
So for the query to execute correctly,
because of this conjunction we have,
all three of the values
have to be correct.
Okay?
So
we have to have the correct login name,
we have to have the correct password,
and we also have to have the matching
PIN for that login name.
So all three are necessary.
All three must be provided
correctly because of this AND
operator that we have.
So for each each tuple that
we have in the table, and
the table here is users, we have to
see that these three values match
the values that are there in the tuple.
And when they do,
that tuple is going to be selected, and
we're going to return
the account's attribute from that.
This is how the script is
going to generate a query that
is going to produce the result
that I just talked about.