So, if you want to draw Bayes rule graphically,
we have a situation where we have an internal variable A,
like whether I'm going to die of cancer, but we can't sense A.
Instead, we have a second variable, called B,
which is our test, and B is observable, but A isn't.
This is a classical example of a Bayes network.
The Bayes network is composed of 2 variables, A and B.
We know the prior probability for A,
and we know the conditional.
A causes B--whether or not we have cancer,
causes the test result to be positive or not,
although there was some randomness involved.
So, we know what the probability of B given the different values for A,
and what we care about in this specific instance is called diagnostic reasoning,
which is the inverse of the causal reasoning,
the probability of A given B or similarly, probability of A given not B.
This is our very first Bayes network, and the graphical representation
of drawing 2 variables, A and B, connected with an arc
that goes from A to B is the graphical representation of a distribution
of 2 variables that are specified in the structure over here,
which has a prior probability and has a conditional probability as shown over here.
Now, I do have a quick quiz for you.
How many parameters does it take to specify
the entire joint probability within A and B, or differently, the entire Bayes network?
I'm not looking for structural parameters that relate to the graph over here.
I'm just looking for the numerical parameters of the underlying probabilities.