And the answer to the question is that
the first four apply, but not the fifth.
Let's go through those.
With library privilege '1'
you can borrow books.
You will use the privledge
but you'll get it back. You won't consume it.
And you can do this for the first book,
the Zweben book,
and the second book, the Nau book,
in which case, you now have both books.
And then you go and study those books.
They are about the correct topic,
and finally, you know what's going on.
You won't even need the 50 dollars.
With library privledge '2' you can do the same, which is even better
than library privledge '1'.
And again, library privilege '1' is sufficient.
You won't need any money
to do what you're out to do.
Now without library privileges,
you can try to buy a book, but
40 bucks is not enough to buy the book.
It costs you 50 dollars.
So the only way to do this is to watch videos.
It turns out there's a video about planning
and a video about scheduling
in the initial state.
Both can be watched
using a bandwidth of '2.5'.
And you have a bandwidth of '3' over here.
So by doing both,
and by observing that you don't consume the bandwidth, it still stays with you,
you can watch them. And as a result,
you know about planning and scheduling.
The only thing that fails is the last one.
With 95 dollars, you can buy one book
but not two.
With one book, you can go and buy it,
you own it, you have the book.
And then you can study the book,
and be knowledgeable about a specific topic.
But it's not enough to buy two books.
Bandwidth '2' is not sufficient to watch a video.
So this action over here, won't get you there.
So what you'll find in the last case, E,
is that the dollar amount
and the bandwidth is insufficient
to make you knowledgeable about
planning and scheduling at the same time.
So it's the only case that fails.