So, let's look at that
a little bit more carefully.
Left camera is basically
giving me these equations,
right camera is giving me this equation.
Looking into the from that image we
looked at, I have Xl and Xr here.
That was just showing you the image
itself and, of course, Yr and
Yl are the same.
Let's now come up with a new term here.
We'll call this d for disparity.
And, that's the distance
between point Xr and Xl.
D, basically, is difference between Xr,
Xl and Xr, the two positions in
the left view and the right view, which
are now projected on the same view here.
So, in essence,
d now because basically becomes f
X over Z minus f X minus Tx over
Z from these two equations here.
And now, of course, by doing simple
you know, math on this kind of stuff,
f X over Z would actually
subtract each other.
This would become a plus sign and
actually the disparity d would just be f
Tx, that is the translation
of the camera, for
when we point to the other,
divided by Z.
Of course, now,
we can do something interesting here and
now we can use this.
If we know the disparity, right,
if we know the disparity,
we can now actually compute that.
That, in essence,
is the important cri, equation.
This, in essence,
is the important equation of
computing depth from two viewpoints.
Of course, if you recall,
this is baseline.
This is depth.
This is disparity,
which we've been looking at.
F is focal length.
Of course, that mean I need to
know the focal length of a camera.