Sun RPC is an RPC package originally
developed by Sun in the 80s for
their network file system NFS for
UNIX systems but it became popular and
now it's widely available
in other platforms.
Sun RPC makes the following
design choices.
In Sun RPC it's assumed that the server
machine is known up front and therefore
the registry design choice is such that
there is a registry daemon per-machine.
When a client wants to talk
to a particular service,
it needs to first talk to the registry
on that particular machine to find out
how to contact the exact
service that it requires.
Sun RPC makes no assumption
regarding the programming
language that used by the client or
by the server process.
To maintain neutrality
Center PC relays on a language
agnostic interface definition language,
XDR.
And this is used both for
the specification of the interface of
the RPC service, as well as for
the specification of the encoding.
How data types will be
encoded when they're being
transmitted amongst machines?
Some RPC does allow
the use of pointers and
data structures that are pointed by
these pointers will be serialized.
And finally, Sun RPC incorporates some
mechanisms for dealing with errors.
First, it has internally retry mechanism
to retry contacting a server
when a connection times out.
This will be done for
a specific number of times.
Second, as much as possible,
the RPC run time will try to
return meaningful errors.
So that a caller can at least
distinguish between things like
the server is not available, or
there is a mismatch, or
unsupported protocol or version.
Or there is simply a time
out related failure that
just covers all of the other
types of possible failures.