So, that's just a little bit on some
initial video processing where you have
a static camera moving object.
I'll show you something
else that's kind of cool.
What if you have a static scene?
So, the right?
But your video is generated
by a moving camera.
Right?
What sort of
interesting analysis might you do there?
Remember, we talked about
when we talked about stereo,
we talked about motion parallax and
disparity.
The disparity is inversely
proportional to depth.
So, the farther something is, the less
disparity it has, the closer it is,
the more it moves as I move.
So, and you probably thought of that
as motion parallax in other contexts.
So, if I have cameras that are moving,
looking at a scene,
I could pull out the separate objects
by just looking at the relative motion.
So, faster relative motion
means objects are closer to me.
All right?
This was first done in what
was called epipolar plane,
epipolar plane image analysis, or
just EPI image analysis, that was done
by actually Bolles, Baker and Marimont.
Bob Bolles who his,
his friend and some, by the way,
it's the same Bolles from RANSAC.
So, he's got his name against
couple of pretty cool algorithms.
So, here's a cute image that was taken.
This was back in the days when you used
to draw images because we couldn't
actually get computers to make them.
So, the idea was,
what if you have a camera that's
looking sideways and you can extend
this to looking arbitrary ways but
it's easy to think
about looking sideways.
And here is some point on
what it looks to me to be, I,
I don't know if it's a taxi cab or
a police car.
And the idea is that this point, of
course, as this camera moves this way,
this point will move across the image.
The rate at which that point
will move across the image is,
depends upon how far away it is, right?
So, a point that's here
will move faster, and
a point that's out here in infinity,
will move slower.
So, if you go to their original paper,
you'll see pictures that look like this.
This is an indoor scene, and
what you can see is that the camera
is moving just a little bit this way.
Right?
because here,
you can see this thing is
occluding that thing there.
But then, as the camera moves,
I can now see through there.
All right?
So as the camera's moving to the left,
this object is essentially
moving to the right.
So, you can take all of those images and
you can stack them up and
here they stack them.
This is x.
This is y.
So, this is the first image that we saw.
And this is time.
Okay?
Now, this little edge here.
You know what that is?
That's the right most column
at each of the times.
Now, this might just look
like another picture to you,
and it is, because if you
look over here, this right
most column is just as the camera moves,
it's just sweeping across here.
So, we just pull out each of those
columns, you'll get another picture.
And so, that's what you're seeing here,
that's what this side is,
it's the right most column.
But what's really cool about
this volume, remember,
we took videos of volume of data?
Is I can slice that volume of data,
right?
And so, suppose, we just take
a look at a cut through there.
So, that would be,
that's what this would be here.
And you see that image there, okay?
And you'll notice, and we're going to
do this more specifically in a minute,
that I get these streaks and
these streaks are at different slopes.