Now out of the five boxes her the GPU
can do three of these things.
It can respond to CPU requests for
sends and receives.
But it cannot initiate
requests on its own.
Again, the CPU is the boss
in this relationship.
It can also compute a kernel
that is launched by the CPU.
Note, I have a box next to this final
one because this is something that's
currently changing.
So the issue is,
can a GPU launch its own work?
Now, later on in the course, we'll cover
some advanced code of topics that go
beyond this basic CPU, GPU model.
Among the other things, you'll learn how
newer GPU's can launch their own kernels
and pull directly from the CPU's memory.
But for now, we're going to stick
with this basic CPU, GPU model.
Now let's move on and
see what a typical program looks like.