When we assign types to columns,
we're restricting what sorts of
values can later be put into them.
If we say that a column is an integer,
we shouldn't be able to
put the word pies in it.
That's important, because if we
later want to take the sum or
something, we can't add
the string pies to some numbers.
But that's not the only sort of
restriction we might
want to put onto a column.
Imagine that we're building
a database for a retail store.
In one table, we have a list of all
the products that we have for sale.
In another,
we have all the sales that we've made.
Whenever we sell something, we insert
a new row into the sales table.
By the way, the name S-K-U or
sku on these columns, is just a name for
stock keeping unit, which is an ID
number or code that's commonly used for
products in stores and
warehouses and so forth.
We'd expect that every
SKU in the sales tables,
would refer to one over
in the products table.
But what if we inserted
a row in the sales table,
that didn't match any row
on the products table.
It wouldn't make any sense.
We don't have a product number 23,
inserting this row must be a mistake.
And its a mistake that the database
can catch, but only if we tell it to.
When we create a table, we can tell the
database that a particular column should
only have values that refer
to the key of another table.
To do this,
we use the references keyword.
Create table sales,
sku text references products.
If the name of the column
is the same in both tables,
then we can just use,
the name of the table over here.
Otherwise, we would use the name of
the table followed by the column and
parenthesis.
In this case, this is actually
unnecessary, so we don't need to use it.
So a references constraint,
is a little bit like type checking.
It catches bugs that might lead to our
database not making sense any more.
In database terminology,
we'd say that references constraints
help us maintain referential integrity.
Which is our assurance that
values in a column over here,
will always refer to values
in a column over here.