[Probabilistic Interference]
[Male] Welcome back. In the previous unit, we went over the basics
of probability theory and saw how
a Bayes network could concisely represent a joint probability distribution,
including the representation of independence between the variables.
In this unit, we will see how to do probabilistic inference.
That is, how to answer probability questions using Bayes nets.
Let's put up a simple Bayes net.
We'll use the familiar example of the earthquake
where we can have a burglary or an earthquake
setting off an alarm, and if the alarm goes off,
either John or Mary might call.
Now, what kinds of questions can we ask to do inference about?
The simplest type of question is the same question we ask
with an ordinary subroutine or function in a programming language.
Namely, given some inputs, what are the outputs?
So, in this case, we could say given the inputs of B and E,
what are the outputs, J and M?
Rather than call them input and output variables,
in probabilistic inference, we'll call them evidence and query variables.
That is, the variables that we know the values of are the evidence,
and the ones that we want to find out the values of are the query variables.
Anything that is neither evidence nor query is known as a hidden variable.
That is, we won't tell you what its value is.
We won't figure out what its value is and report it,
but we'll have to compute with it internally.
And now furthermore, in probabilistic inference,
the output is not a single number for each of the query variables,
but rather, it's a probability distribution.
So, the answer is going to be a complete, joint probability distribution
over the query variables.
We call this the posterior distribution, given the evidence,
and we can write it like this.
It's the probability distribution of one or more query variables
given the values of the evidence variables.
And there can be zero or more evidence variables,
and each of them are given an exact value.
And that's the computation we want to come up with.
There's another question we can ask.
Which is the most likely explanation?
That is, out of all the possible values for all the query variables,
which combination of values has the highest probability?
We write the formula like this, asking which Q values
are maxable given the evidence values.
Now, in an ordinary programming language, each function goes only one way.
It has input variables, does some computation,
and comes up with a result variable or result variables.
One great thing about Bayes nets is that we're not restricted
to going only in one direction.
We could go in the causal direction, giving as evidence
the route nodes of the tree and asking as query values the nodes at the bottom.
Or, we could reverse that causal flow.
For example, we could have J and M be the evidence variables
and B and E be the query variables,
or we could have any other combination.
For example, we could have M be the evidence variable
and J and B be the query variables.
Here's a question for you.
Imagine the situation where Mary has called to report that the alarm is going off,
and we want to know whether or not there has been a burglary.
For each of the nodes, click on the circle to tell us
if the node is an evidence node, a hidden node,
or a query node.