So if images are just functions,
then we can do things to images that we can do to functions.
Like we can just add them, right?
You can add two functions, right?
Well, then we can add two images.
And to introduce this a little bit,
we're going to introduce the concept of noise, okay?
So noise in an image.
Is just another function that, combined with the original image,
gives us a new function.
So, we'll just write this, this way as our new image.
We'll call it I prime.
It's just I of x, y plus this noise function.
You know, well what does that mean?
Well, we have to take a look at what this noise function would be.
Okay, so there are lots of different kinds of noise functions.
Here's one, and this stuff's courtesy of Steve Sites,
there's a type of noise called salt and pepper noise.
Which doesn't take a rocket scientist for
you to figure out that probably what it does is, it takes your original picture
and it sprinkles occasional white spots and occasional dark spots.
And that's called salt and pepper noise for the, for the obvious reason.
A, a relative to that is something called an impulse noise,
where you just get little white specks now and then.
Different kind of imaging systems might give you that kind of noise.
But by far, the noise that you're most familiar with
is typically Gaussian noise, or normally distributed noise.
Where we basically assume that at every pixel we take the original image and
we stick on here some value that is independent identically
distributed from some normal or some Gaussian distribution.
All right, and that's Gaussian noise.
And most of the time when we talk about noise we'll talk about that function.
Okay?
We can actually have Matlab make us a noise function.
It's real easy.
So here we say, look we're going to make a noise array, which is just,
I take the size of my image, random n,
randn generates a noise signal that has a mean of zero and
a standard deviation of one, and if we scale that up by some sigma.
Okay?
That will spread that out and make it bigger so that's
essentially the noise with mean of zero and a, a standard deviation of sigma.
And because functions are just functions and
images are functions, I can just add them.
I can say let my output just be the image plus the noise.
And if I were to plot that, you would see what's here, right?
And on the right you can see that there's all this noise in our peppers.
And if we plot this, you can see here we get this nice clean plot and
here we have all this extra noise that's been added.
And so that's our noise function.