To fully understand and appreciate OS internals,
we will supplement the theoretical part of the course material with
a practical component, and that will be a sequence of programming projects.
The goal of these projects is to
give you a hands-on experience with operating systems.
For instance, you will be put face-to-face with challenges related to
multithreading, concurrency, and synchronization.
You will have to use operating system services for
interaction among multiple processes on a single node, like a server machine.
You will also have to look beyond the single node and
prototype distributed, or multi-node services, using some of the mechanisms that
are supported at the operating system level, like remote procedure calls.
Finally, one key issue with operating systems design and
implementation is the performance that they can deliver.
You will gain experience with designing and performing experimental evaluations.
These experiments will ideally provide you with insight into the behavior of
the operating system so you can better understand its performance capabilities,
overheads, limitations, or other issues.
Each of the projects will require you to program in the C
programming language in a Linux environment, and you will have to use some of
the standard Linux libraries, such as Pthreads, for threads.