>> To start, I'd like a feature
where I can say I bought eggs
from one of my shopping lists.
And then, everyone that shared on
that shopping list sees that I have,
in fact, bought the eggs,
wherever they happen to be.
I'm imagining a style that would
have a strike-through like this and
that would say who bought the item.
I've been thinking about the best
way to break this one down.
And here's what I came up with.
To start,
you can update the items to track
whether they are bought or un-bought.
And then, you can also add
an attribute to see who bought them.
You can then add a click listener to
the adapter that would allow items to
be toggled between bought and un-bought.
So, all you need to do
is press on an item and
then it would be
considered bought by you.
And if you pressed again,
it would be un-bought by you.
Finally, we should probably change
how the item looks in the adapter
if it is bought or un-bought.
That's what I was talking about when I
mentioned having a strike-through if
the item was bought.
And maybe even having some
text to show who bought it.
Now, these three steps
relate to different things.
The first one involves
changing around a POJO.
The second one involves writing
something to the database
about the status of the item.
And then, the third one is reading the
status of the item from the database and
then changing the UI accordingly.
So, this is really not too
different than the stuff that we've
already been doing.
Okay.
So,
why don't you talk me through this
one and what you're going to do.
Given what you know about Firebase,
what POJO should we be changing?
Answer that here.
Then, in the on click
listener of the adaptor,
what write method will you call?
Finally, in what method will
you change how the item looks
when it's bought or unbought?