[Thrun] The mathematics of the structure from motion problem are involved,
and I don't want to go into detail here.
Here is our perspective projection model with our well-known equation on the right.
Under the assumption that the camera itself might be at a random location
and a random orientation, this equation becomes a really complicated composition
of original image points in 3D, 3 rotation matrices as shown over here,
and an offset over here that relates to the camera coordinates.
You do this for X divided by Z over here.
This will be the projected camera input coordinates.
This is the generative math that specifies how cameras work under arbitrary orientations
and arbitrary translations.
If you now want to solve it, you can look at the observed measurements
minus the predicted measurements, minimize all this,
and solve for the translations, the point locations, and the orientations simultaneously.
This is entirely nontrivial, and nonlinear optimization techniques
have been used extensively to solve this problem.
They go by names like gradient descent, conjugate gradient,
Gauss-Newton, Levenberg Marquardt, and other things like singular value decomposition.
I won't go into detail--just to give you a flavor of the problem.
Instead I'd like to ask you a question.