Okay. Let's write some code.
We'll use one dimensional data to begin with.
Given a discrete signal s as a vector and
a template t our job is to find where that template occurs in the signal.
This is just like finding a substring in a longer string.
Here we are playing with numerical values which has some implications.
Note that here we want to find the starting index where the template occurs.
Let's print out the signal and template to see what we mean.
Here we've used colon to generate the sequence of column numbers.
Size of s, 2 is the number of columns in s.
Let's see what the output looks like.
The top row here is the column numbers.
Can you find the template?
Yes.
It is located here.
Starting at index 5 in the signal.
So this is what I want you to do.
I want you to write a function find_template_1D.
That takes two parameters, t and s, the template and signal.
It should return the index, where template is found in s.
Once the index is found we should be able to display it.
Let me get you started with some template code.
By the way, you most likely need to use the image package.
Make sure you test out your function with different signal and template values.
When you submit your code your function will be evaluated against other
test sets.