Really the only thing that you
absolutely need to keep track of
is the score.
You might be wondering why.
Well, between button clicks we want
some way to save the value that's been
accumulating for
how much Team A has scored.
Well, we don't really care
about the number of fouls.
There's nothing on the screen
that represents that, or
does a calculation with that number.
Nor do we care about
the number of shots attempted.
Now, the other three
possibilities are for
the amount of points that you get for
each shot.
These numbers won't vary.
A user isn't inputting
a different value.
And the three point shot isn't suddenly
going to become worth five points in
the middle of a game.
This means there isn't a huge amount
of necessity in making these guys
variables.
Now, that said, it is perfectly
reasonable for you to say,
I want a number in my app that
doesn't change, but that has a name.
like a variable.
Now what I've just described
is called a constant, and
a constant is kind of like a variable.
It has a name and a value.
The thing that's different though
is the value is, for sure,
never going to change.
Now we won't be using
constants in this app, but
I've provided some documentation in the
instructor notes if you're interested in
learning more about them.