So, are you familiar with the closure?
>> Yes.
>> All right, so,
explain to me what a closure is,
and when would you use one?
What are the advantages?
>> Yeah, so basically.
Can I erase this?
>> Yeah, go ahead.
>> Yeah.
It goes back to the whole
theory of pointers.
>> Okay.
>> And point of references because
whenever we create a variable,
like say, var.
I'll create your variable, mike, right?
>> All right.
>> var mike = 8.
mike is actually a reference to 8,
somewhere in our memory.
So what mike is is actually
a point of reference,
it's some sort of memory, like some
sort of like number that points to
this actual 8 in this memory space.
So whenever I, say,
create an array, so var array =.
And I want mike inside, right?
This actually holds
a point of reference to 8.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And okay, what's so wrong about that?
If this pointer actually starts
pointing to a different number,
let's say if I'm looping.
If I'm creating some sort of,
I'm training anonymous functions,
and I want to loop through them.
And I want to create anonymous functions
that will hold a certain variable.
>> Okay.
>> Let's say, oops, let's say this.
For (i=0,
i<10, i++).
Let's say,
let's declare this array, right?
So i is my variable, and
i is similar to mike here,
because like i will point
to some number in space.
And then if I want to say,
I want to create an array that,
Creates anonymous functions,
I want to create a new function that
we'll say that will cause a log.
Some sort, something very simple, i.
What this does is that once I,
say, I create 10.
So once I do array, (0),
I call this an array,
say, all the way to 9,
the number 9, I call this,
they're all going to equal 10.
So basically, Like at the end of my for
loop here, the i will all point to 10.
And since I have this function
here that references i,
it just contains like a reference.
And if I do this, counts of log will
all equal 10, which I don't want.
What I want is like for
every number, I want, say,
array 0, it will cause a log to 0.
And then array 9, it will cause a log 9.
So I need to create a closure, so
basically, whenever you pass a verbal
inside a function, it creates a closure,
it closes that variable.
So basically in a nutshell,
Function, say, my-func,
say some numbers, num.
As soon as I do this in JavaScript,
this creates a closure.
It actually copies
whatever I'm passing in,
and it creates a new variable,
a new value.
That stores it into memory.
It creates its own space,
it's scoped inside there, so
I could really then do
whatever I want with number,
do whatever, With number.
And not have to worry about this
number changing in the future,
because I'm referencing this number.
because otherwise, if I do something
like this, I'm referencing,
I'm not creating a closure,
I'm just referencing i here.
i will change in the future.
And it gives me.
And that's why it's very important,
so if I'm creating
any sort of anonymous functions that
I want to pass in variables to it,
I need to make sure that
like my variable reference.
I'm actually getting the value and
not just getting
the reference to the value.
>> Okay.
>> So that's that's why closures
are important when we're like ever
creating because in JavaScript we
always create new anonymous functions.
Whenever we try to do Ajax requests or
anything like that sort of scenario.
>> Okay.
Let's see,
so let me just make sure I'm kind of
understanding where you're going here.
>> Yeah.
>> So let's say, I have, excuse me.
We have a function called rate.
>> Yeah.
>> And so we're going to write
a rate limiting function.
The purpose of this function
will be to always return
a function that's safe to call based off
of some rate limiting API, let's say.
>> Okay.
>> We can only call this API
a certain number of times per minute.
>> Okay.
>> And
we want to make sure that we're always
returning a safe to call function.
So we'll just say time = 0, return.
And then here, we'll have logic,
Call.
>> Okay.
>> And let's just say it, Okay.
>> So every time this function's called,
we will increase by 50,
this variable, right?
>> Okay, so that's a plus equal?
>> Yeah, sorry, plus equal 50.
So if I were to,
let's say, so now our var
limiter equals rate.
So now limiter is a function.
>> Okay.
>> So if I recall.
If I were to call limiter twice,
what would the output of each of these,
let's say there's a console log.
Right, in there.
Run me through what's occurring
on these three lines, and
what the output would be.
>> Right.
So basically, you're calling rate.
And rate will return this function.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So it's just a function
that will reference time.
And what is time?
It's referencing time
in this scope here.
>> Okay.
>> So right here, var, it's still
a local scope within the right scope.
So basically,
all anonymous functions that's created
will share the same variable,
the time variable.
>> Okay.
>> So if a different function accesses,
changes time,
then this will change as well.
So basically, I call this.
Okay, I assign a function.
This has not been called yet.
So, time is still 0.
So, I'll say time is still 0,
Once I do this.
Now, I call this.
Time equals 50 now.
Once I call this,
Time is actually going to equal 100.
>> Okay, so when you were talking
about this line right here.
>> Yeah.
>> Is this line changing the value
of a global variable called time, or
is it changing this variable time?
>> It's changing this variable.
>> Okay, cool.
>> Yeah.
>> So what is, kind of getting
away from this example but
talking about closures in general.
>> Yeah.
>> So we can say that a closure is
a way of maintaining state, correct?
>> Okay.
>> What is the downfall of
maintaining that state like this?
>> Maintaining in this code, right?
>> Any closure,
[CROSSTALK] a potential downfall of a
closure if you're not careful with them.
>> You have a ton of different variables
that you need to keep track of.
And if that one variable, time,
which is that one time that you want to
keep track, I know it's not global,
that's like your main time.
But if you do a closure here,
you have like each time you run it,
you're going to create
new time variables.
And it's hard for you to keep
track of what's the main time.
>> Well,
we'd only be updating the one time, but
you're down the right track,
so we're maintaining states.
>> Yeah.
>> So keeping variables, and
where do variables reside?
>> In our memory.
>> In memory, right?
And so
if we're not careful with our closures,
all of a sudden, we could potentially
have memory leaks when we have all these
reference states that you're
not actually using anymore.
>> That's true.
Yeah, you're right, you're totally right
because like basically if we have all
these memory states and
they're not being referenced anymore,
like there's a lot of garbage.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Out there.
>> Yep, so it can't be garbage collected
because the JavaScript processor thinks
it's still being used,
it's still maintaining that state.
>> That's true.
>> So you might never run through GC.
>> So you're blowing up
your whole memory state and
your whole application will
slow down eventually and.
>> Not a bad thing,
you just gotta be careful with them.
>> Got it, yeah.