So, I did mention something in
the last slide about rolling shutter.
Before we go there,
remember that in a CCD versus CMOS,
there's two different things we
talked about when we looked at
the camera inside of the camera
in one of our earlier lectures.
In a CCD, all of the photosites,
which are these color chan,
color sensors here.
Give basic information and
they're kind of then read into
an amplifier after at the end.
In CMOS, the complement the
complementary metal oxide semiconductor,
what they do is they actually
take the photosites and
they put the amplifier
right at the photosites.
For example, in this pipeline,
what would happen is basically,
all of the information
would be read off and
the amplification would happen after
things are read off from the photosites.
But in CMOS, what happens really is
there's an amplifier in each and
every photosite.
So, it actually does a little bit more
work to read out the information and
it force all distributed at
the location of the sensory cell.
Now, of course,
CMOS sensors are cheaper.
They can also be better than CCD
sensors in many different ways.
But when ha, what happens is when you
start putting these types of CMOS
sensors on in smaller bodies and
cellphones and stuff like that,
they don't actually have a very good
refresh rate as things are scanned.
For example, this is a video from
a simple, handheld cellphone camera and
you'll notice an interesting thing.
It seems like the whole
scene is nonrigid.
For example, if you look at it,
this pillar here seems to be
nonrigid as it's warping.
And if you look at any of the lines,
they don't remain straight anymore.
You saw that a little bit in
the other video I just showed you
with the trucks and stuff like that.
But this is much more easier to see
now the fact that there is nonrigid
deformation going on.
Of course,
this is because of rolling shutter,
I will talk about that in a bit.
Let me actually show you how we can
take the original video like this, with
rolling shutter and now using techniques
like the one I've talked about with more
modifications, allow us to generate
a video that looks much more stable.
Again, original video, this was
deliberately shaken, handheld camera.
And if you don't believe it,
that this is video,
you can actually see the person
going up on the bridge.
This is completely stabilized,
what we've done basically is model this
motion and then removed it and
we synthesized it.