All right.
So brace yourself for
a kind of long solution video.
But we'll tackle it one step at a time.
So first,
we want to request audio focus,
which means that we need
an audio manager object instance.
Now, within the NumbersActivity, I'm
going to create a global variable for
the audio managers that I can initialize
it once during the lifetime activity.
Next, within the entre method
of the numbers activity.
I'm going to initialize the Audio
Manager by calling get system service
and passing in the audio
service constant.
Now the reason that I knew
to write this line of code,
was because I saw in this
media player tutorial,
that it shows how to get a reference
to the Audio Manager system service.
Now once we have
the audio manager object.
We can call the request
audio focused method on it.
So let's copy this snippet of code and
then add into our app.
Now where's the proper place
to request audio focus?
Now, I know that when
an item is clicked on.
I want to use the Audio Manager
to request audio focus there
before setting up the media
player to play the sound.
So I'm going to paste the code in
here after we've gotten the code for
the word object, and
after we've released our media player.
Now, I want to be more descriptive
with these variable names.
So I'm going to change the current
variable name from am to mAudioManager.
Now when we request audio focus.
I'm going to pass in three inputs.
I need to pass in a listener.
I need to specify the music stream type.
And also,
how long we need to request audio for.
So the code sample we copied
over requested AUDIOFOCUS_GAIN.
In order to request audio focus for
a long unknown duration period for
something like playing a music song.
However, in army walk up our audio clips
are only about one or two seconds long.
So we only need audio focus for
short period of time.
Hence we're going to
change AUDIOOCUS_GAIN to
AUDIOOCUS_GAIN_TARNSIENT.
All right, so it looks like we're
still getting a couple of errors here.
And that's because Android Studio
is still reporting an error that
it doesn't recognize
the listener define.
And that's because we haven't
defined a listener yet.
But we can get back
to fixing this later.
Now if we head back to our tutorial, and
check more into the request
audio focus method.
We see that this method
returned an integer.
And guess what?
The result is also a constant value.
So down here in the documentation for
the method.
It shows the two possible return
values are the constants.
AudioFocus _request_failed or
audiofocus_request_granted.
So each of these constants
are static final variables
that are equal to a fixed integer value.
Now if we go back to
the code sample here.
If the result is equal to
audio focus request granted.
Then we've successfully
gained audio focus, and
can proceed with playing
audio on our app.
So back in our code.
We added that if statement under this
block where we requested audio focus.
Now once we've gained audio focus.
We want to create and
start the media player, and
then set up the completion listener.
So, this block of code here needs
to go within our if statement.
So, I'm going to move this
closing bracket, down here.
So, I'm going to modify this comment.
I'm going to say,
we have audio focus now.
And then,
I'm going to indent these lines of code.
Because they're inside the if statement.
So if we don't receive audio focus.
Then we don't need to
set up the media player.
The user will have to
click the list item again.
And hopefully at that point,
we can gain audio focus.
All right, so that took care of task
number one, requesting audio focus.
Now let's focus on implementing
the OnAudioFocusChangeListener.
And that will help us get rid of
the current air that's in our code.
Let's figure out what
the listener should look like.
So if you scroll down on this tutorial.
There's an example of what
the listener could be.
So since we need to pass in the listener
as an input every time we request
audio focus.
Let's make this listener
a global variable.
So we can reuse the same one each time.
So I'm going to ahead and just copy and
paste this code snippet, and
paste it into our numbers activity.
So I'm going to paste that code snippet
below all our other global variables.
So you can rename this
variable to whatever you want.
In my case, I'm going to rename it
to mOnAudioFocusChangeListener.
All right, so here we're creating
a new object instance that implements
the listener interface.
So this means that we'll need to
override the onAudioFocusChange method.
The one that's taking in one parameter,
which is a new audio focus state.
So within this method
on audio focus change.
We're putting in our instructions for
what should happen when
the system calls this method.
Because the audio focus state
has changed within our app.
So the smart thing to do here would be
to figure out what the new state is,
by looking at the focus change
variable that we passed in.
So here we're using the conditional if
else statements to check what the value
of the focus change variable is.
Remember that the double equal
sign checks that both the left and
right hand values are equal.
And if so,
this whole expression is true.
And then we execute the code
that's in this if block.
Otherwise, if this expression is false.
Then we skip over this
first block of code and
go down here straight to
the else if statement.
If the audio focus variable is equal
to audio focus loss transient state.
Then we've temporarily lost audio focus.
So this means that we can
pause the media player.
So I add that line of code here.
So with the media player seek to method.
I'm going to change the position
to start at the beginning of
the audio file.
So start at position zero.
And this is because,
if we do gain audio focus back.
It would be better for
the user to hear the word from
the beginning of the audio file.
Instead of just hearing
the remaining of the word.
Since our words are pretty short anyway.
Now I want to modify
this test case here.
because I want this behavior to be
applied also to the loss transient
can duck state.
I'm also going to resolve this
error here by specifying that it's
AudioManager.AUDIOFOCUS_LOSS_TRANSIENT.
So if you recall from the last quiz.
We decided that these two states,
AUDIOFOCUS_LOSS_TRANSIENT, and
AUDIOFOCUS_LOSS_TRANSIENT_CAN_DUCK, are
two states that can be handled the same.
So the media player should
be paused in both cases.
So we can use this double
vertical bar symbol to mean or.
So O-R.
Now this is the first
time that we're using it.
So it's expected if it looks unfamiliar.
So using that, this statement reads.
If the focusChange variable equals
the AUDIOFOCUS_LOSS_TRANSIENT state,
or if the focusChange variable equals
the AUDIOFOCUS_LOSS_TRANSIENT_CAN_DUCK
state.
Then this whole expression is true.
And we can execute the if block of code.
This means that either expression
to the left of the or symbol, or
the expression to the right of the or
symbol must be true for
this entire expression
to be valid it is true.
Now, if you don't want to use this or
symbol.
You could have simply created
another ELSE IF block.
In order to check the audio focus
loss transient can duck state.
Now in our case,
we just combined into one check.
Because the logic for pausing and
resetting the position of the media
player will be the same for both cases.
So I'm going to add a comment to help
you remember why we chose this behavior.
All right, so
if the focus change variable is
not any of these two above states.
Then we check if it's equal
to the AUDIOFOCUS_GAIN state.
Now, back to the table from last quiz.
When we gain audio focus, remember
that we can resume the media player.
In the media player API,
there is no resume method.
Remember that you can just
call the start method, and
it'll pick up from where
you last left off.
So I'll change this comment
to be mMediaPlayer.start().
I'll also add in a comment to
help describe that case as well.
Now lastly, if our focus change
variable is not equal to any of
these three states, but it's equal
to the audio focus loss state.
Then we execute this block of code.
Now once again back to our
table from the last quiz.
We said that we would stop and
clean up the media player when
we permanently lose audio focus.
And luckily,
we have a helper method called release
media player to help us handle that.
So inside this last else if block.
I'm going to delete the sample code, and
color our own release
media player method.
And I'll also add in
a comment to be consistent,
and help describe what's going on.
All right, so
that took care of task number two.
Creating an instance of
the focus change listener, and
overwriting the callback method.
And that also took care
of task number three.
So we modify the media playback behavior
based on these focus state changes.
Looks like we just have
one more task left.
We need to release audio focus
when we're done playing audio.
Now going back to our managing
audio focus tutorial.
There was an example code snippet
here for abandoning audio focus.
So this paragraph above
the code snippet here.
Says that when you're done playing
audio, you should abandon audio focus.
So this unregisters
the listener that's specified.
So our input parameter here.
So that we no longer get
notified of focus state changes.
It also says that if you request
a transient focus, which we did.
It allows any interrupted app on the
device to continue with their playback.
So let's copy this code and
paste into our app.
So where should we put that line
of code in our numbers activity?
Well, once we finish
playing the audio file.
We should've been in focus.
So we could paste it in the on
completion callback of the media player.
But, we also want to be careful
of the activity life-cycle.
So we added code earlier.
So that when the activity is stopped,
and also hidden from the user.
We stop and clean up the media player.
So we want to abandon audio
focus in both places.
And both places already call
the release Media Player method.
So let's just abandon audio
focus within that helper method,
release media player.
Now at the bottom of this method,
I'm going to add the line
to abandon audio focus.
I'm going to add that with in dif block.
We know it's safe to release
the audio focus here,
because we no longer are playing audio.
So, I'm going to have to switch
our variable names from A.M.
to M Audio Manager.
And also change our listener name
to be mOnAudioFocusChangeListener.
So I'll also update the comments
to this section as well.
All right.
So that took care of step number four.
So I know there were a lot
of code changes, but
we're done with all four steps now.
So give yourselves a pat on the back.
And if there are any remaining
variables that need to be updated.
Let's make those changes here.
All right, so no more errors.
Now let's make sure the app is working.
So let's run it.
So here's the app running on my device.
And let's make sure that it's still
working it behaves as expected.
So let's go into our numbers activity.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> All right, so
the audio is stopping when
another one starts playing.
But I won't go through all
the test cases right now.
If you want to test that we're
handling audio interruptions properly.
You should try playing the sound
in the middle of a phone call.
Or even pulling down
the notification shade
while you're trying to play a sound.
So ideally you want to test
every case that we have here,
in our if else statements.
To make sure that we can pause
the audio when we lose focus, and
then resume it back again
when we gain focus.
So once I have the numbers
activity working.
I'm going to apply the same
changes to the other activities.
So here are what the code
changes look like for
the colors activity, family activity,
and phrases activity.
So for a link to the solution code,
see the notes below.
Wow.
So that was a major beast of a feature.
And congratulations on finishing
the app focus coding task.