All right.
This is a pretty large quiz.
We're going to convert Sunshine from
using Listview to using Recyclerview.
And the goal here is not to get
Sunshine completely functioning again.
It is just to get
the list in the forecast
displaying something with Recyclerview.
So, you're going to grab
the initial code drop.
And then you're going to add
the RecyclerView library as a project
dependency.
You'll then swap the android.support.v7
widget.RecyclerVIew for
ListView in fragment_main_base.
And then in ForecastFragment,
swap RecyclerView for ListView.
In the Forecast Fragment then your
going to set the layout manager
to being a linear layout manager.
In the forecast adapter you're
going to convert the viewholder
to a recylerview.viewholder.
Finally in forecast adapter you're
going to add a cursor class member
along with getCursor and
swapCursor functions.
And swapCursor should call notify
data set change it's very important.
So essentially in this section you're
going to build a little miniature
cursor adaptor.
Again, make sure to look at
the instructor notes to see if there's
anything we have to help with this one.