Now let's add to our code to create
a unique responsive tablet layout for
this sample article display.
Right now, this layout looks pretty good
on a phone screen, but the image and
text get pretty stretched
out on a tablet.
Here's that same view on a tablet.
So I want to create a new tablet layout
that moves this image to the left of
the text and adds some padding
between the image and text views.
To create a layout for
a tablet, the first thing I'll need
to do is create a new layout folder.
So to do that, I'll right-click
on our res directory and
select New, Android resource directory.
Then a window will pop up prompting for
the type of directory.
Since we're creating a new layout
directory, we'll select layout and
I'll add a smallest
screen width qualifier.
I want the smallest screen width to be
600dp, which is the usual cutoff for
seven inch tablet screens, so
type this in and click OK.
Now, you should see this
new layout-sw600dp folder.
Then in this layout folder,
I am going to overwrite the responsive
activity layout for tablets.
To start, I'll copy and paste this base
layout file into the new layout folder,
then I'll modify it for tablet.
So now I just copy and
pasted our base responsive activity
layout in this new layout folder.
The most important thing here is
that you have the same named layout
in both of these folders.
This way, Android will know to override
the base responsive activity layout file
with the same name when it sees devices
with the smallest width of 600 dp.
Okay great, now let's open this file and
modify it for tablet.
So this is the responsive activity
XML In the layout-sw600dip folder.
In the first to do's in here,
we've already accomplished.
We created a new layout folder for
devices,
with the smallest width
equal to 600 dip, and
we copied over the responsive activity
XML from the base layout folder.
Our next to do's will be to change the
image view so that it's to the left of
our text, and also add a little padding
between the text and the image.
There are a few ways to do this and I'll
just be creating a horizontal linear
layout that contains the imagery on the
left and our already existing vertical
linear layout that holds the headline,
date and body text on the right.
So I'll make our main layout
a horizontal layout, and
this will surround all our views.
Then, I'll add another linear layout
that just surrounds our text views.
So here's a vertical linear
layout that holds our text views.
I'll also need to modify the layout
width and height a little bit
of each of these so that it fits
our horizontal linear layout.
The image view will have
a height of 200dp, and
I'll define the width so that it
takes up about a third of the screen,
by giving it a weight equal to 1 and
a width equal to zero dp.
Similarly, I'll have to
give our linear layout for
our text a layout weight of 2 and
a width of 0.
This way, it will take up twice
as much space as our image.
Now, our image view will
be to the left of our text.
Next I'll add a little more
padding to the right and
left of this vertical linear layout.
I'll add 8dp on both sides to space this
out a little bit from our image view.
Now, let's save this and see what it's
look like on a phone and on a tablet.
So here's our responsive sample
article layout on our phone.
The image placeholder is above the
sample article headline and body text,
and I'll be using a Nexus 6 Emulator for
the phone and a Nexus 9 for the tablet.
Now, here's our layout on our tablet.
The image is to the left of
the sample article text and
uses the space a little more naturally
on this wider tablet screen.
So by using the smallest
width qualifier,
you can create unique layouts for
larger screens.
This way, your layouts look great
across these differently sized devices.