Here are the truth tables for
all the logical connectives.
What a truth table does is
list all the possibilities for
the propositional symbols.
So P and Q can be false and false,
false and true, true and false, or
true and true.
Those are the only four possibilities.
And then for
each of those possibilities,
the truth table lists the truth
value of the compound sentence.
So the sentence not P is true when P
is false and false when P is true.
The sentence P and
Q is true only when both P and
Q are true and false otherwise.
The sentence P or
Q is true when either P or
Q is true, and
false when both are false.
Now so far, those mostly correspond
to the English meaning of those
sentences with one exception.
Which is that in English, the word or
is somewhat ambiguous
between the inclusive and
exclusive or and this or
means either or both.
We translate this mark into English
as P implies Q or as if P then Q.
But the meaning in logic is not quite
the same as the meaning in ordinary
English.
The meaning in logic is defined
explicitly by this truth table and
by nothing else.
But let's look at some
examples in ordinary English.
If we have the proposition O and
have that mean five is an odd number.
And P,
meaning Paris is the capital of France.
Then, under the ordinary model
of truth in the real world,
what could we say about
the sentence O implies P?
That is, five is an odd number implies
Paris is the capital of France.
Would that be true or false?
And let's look at one more example.
If E is the proposition that
five is an even number, and
M is the proposition that Moscow
is the capital of France,
what about E implies M?
Five is an even number implies
Moscow is the capital of France.
Is that true or false?