Again, as in the previous case,
this implementation will be
both inefficient and incorrect.
The inefficiency comes from
the fact that again we have
continuous loop that is spinning
as long as the lock is busy.
Now, the implementation
is incorrect because
although we did put
this while check here,
multiple threads again will see that
the lock is free once it becomes free.
They will exit this while loop and
will move on here and
try to set the lock value to be busy.
If these threads are allowed
to execute concurrently,
there's absolutely no way purely in
software to guarantee that there
won't be some interleaving of exactly
how these threads perform this
check in these set operations and that
a race condition will not occur here.
We can try to come up with
multiple purely software-based
implementations of a spinlock.
And we'll ultimately come to the same
conclusion that we need some kind of
support from the hardware in order to
make sure that some of this checking and
setting of the lock value happens
atomically via hardware support.