Okay.
As I'm comparing what we have now and
our final goal,
I see a number of differences.
The first of these differences,
is that the text of the goal is much
larger than what we have right now.
Also the final font that we're using
is different from the font that we're
starting out with here.
Similarly, the text here is black and
the text here is white.
Now if you take a look at the image here
versus the image of the goal screen,
we also see that the image
has actually expanded,
to fill the entire screen of the phone.
Now this last one is
a little bit more subtle.
If you look over here at
the text that we have right now,
it's smushed right up against
the corner of the screen.
Whereas the text of the goal
has this space here.
Between the side of the screen and
the text itself.
And those were all
the differences that I saw.
So let's go ahead and work through
these one by one, adding attributes and
setting them to values,
which will turn this into this.