As you were moving around between apps,
you probably noticed that from a user
perspective, Android doesn't
announce changes in app state.
It doesn't announce that
it's low on memory or
ask users to close apps
to free up resources.
In fact, it does everything it can
to make the resource limitations of
the device invisible to the user.
That means keeping the foreground
app running smoothly and
switching between apps seamless.
And that means killing
apps in the background.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And it does that if it needs
their resources to make sure that
the foreground apps can continue to run.
So we know that as soon as
your app isn't visible,
its lifetime is as perilous as that
of a Stark at the Red Wedding.
Likely to die without notice but
ready to return from the dead.
That tells us some very important
things about how our apps
should behave to be good citizens and
provide a great user experience.
>From a system perspective, on pause and
on stop are signals that our
app may be killed imminently.
So we need to clean up any resources
that need an orderly tear down,
such as closing an open connections or
sockets.