So this was the third and
final lecture on camera calibration.
The series of three lectures
that Aaron Bovick talked about.
Camera calibration starting from
extrinsic parameter calibration,
then intrinsic parameter calibration,
all the way to a practical guide on how
to use checkerboard patterns
to calibrate in a real world.
This is an important part of what we
need to know about cameras in general.
While it may not be directly relevant to
the kinds of stuff we have talked about
so far, it's an important foundational
principle of what we can do with
computational photography.
Especially when we want to get into
knowing more about the structure,
the range, and the depth of a scene.
And hopefully that's what you
found interesting about it.
More on this topic, we'll follow up
when you get to topics like video.
We won't be talking much more about
calibration anymore in this context.
But again, as I said, its a foundational
thing, I want you all to know about.