So far, we've looked at the state
space of cities in Romania,
a two-dimensional physical space.
But the technology for
problem-solving through search can
deal with many types of state spaces.
Dealing with abstract properties,
not just x-y position in a plane.
Here I introduce another state space,
the vacuum world.
It's a very simple world in which
there are only two positions,
as opposed to the many positions
in the Romania state space.
But there are additional
properties to deal with as well.
So the robot vacuum cleaner can be
in either of the two conditions.
But as well as that, each of the
positions can either have dirt in it or
not have dirt in it.
And now the question is,
to represent this as a state space,
how many states do we need?
The number of states,
can fill in this box here.
[BLANK_AUDIO]