Here's a quiz to make sure you understand how to calculate these probabilistic models.
We're going to calculate the probability of the string "woe is me,"
and we're going to calculate that beginning at the beginning of the sentence,
which we'll mark with this dot character,
given that we are starting at the beginning of the sentence.
I want you to figure that out, put the probability in here,
and it's going to be a small number with a lot of zeros to the right of the decimal place.
So scale that by a factor of 1 billion--the probability times 10 to -9.
Now, of course, I'm going to have to give you some data to make this make sense.
I'm going to tell you that the probability that "woe" occurs at position i
given that the start-of-sentence marker occurs at position i minus 1.
I should say what we're doing here is we're sort of artificially introducing a token
into our data of the start-of-sentence marker,
which could be either what comes after a period or exclamation point
or at the beginning of the file. That all counts as a start-of-sentence marker.
That probability is 0.002.
The probability that "is" occurs at position i given that "woe" occurred at i minus 1 is 0.07,
and the probability that "me" occurs at position i given that "is" occurred at i minus 1 is 0.0005.
Tell me the probability of the whole string "woe is me" at the beginning of a sentence
given that we're starting at the beginning of a sentence and put your answer in here.