The tag manager class is the entry
point for working with tag manager.
It has methods for loading the container
and you get an instance of it by calling
get instance on the tag
manager class itself.
The first thing you need to
do is load the container.
The tag manager class has several
methods for doing this and
we're going to start out using
loadContainerPreferFresh() so
that we'll get the latest
container if possible.
And then you have to wait
until the loading finishes.
Use setResultCallback() to set
the callback that gets invoked when
the loading is done and this callback
is passed the container holder.
In the callback,
store the container holder so
it can be accessed from
other places in your app.
And remember how we used the application
instance to store the analytics tracker
back in the first lesson.
We can do a similar thing here and
store the container holder
in the application instance.
So now let's take a look at the code for
loading and storing the container.
So here in main activity,
I've defined a method,
loadGTMContainer that gets
the tag manager instance.
here I've disenabled logging and
here I load the container,
calling loadContainerPreferFresh.
Now you need to parse it the container
Id and the default container.
So this is the default container
that you downloaded and
copied into the role folder.
Then I set the result Callback and
it gets the ContainerHolder,
deal with failure if there is any.
Here, I'm actually manually refreshing
the container to make sure I really do
get the latest container and
then I'm strobing the ContainerHolder.
In the application instance and
here, at the end of the method,
we specify how long to wait,
two and the time unit seconds, so
we're going to wait two seconds for
the loading to finish.
Let's take a real quick look at
the Tag Manager UI to remind ourselves
where to get the tag manager account ID.
And here in the tag manager UI,
there's the account ID.
So that's what you need to put in your
call to load container preferred fresh.
Now it's your turn to add the code
to load and install the container.
First, update the application
clas,s that's the sub-class
of application that you created
in the analytics lessons.
Update it to have methods that
get the Tag Manage instance and
that set and get the container holder.