You've already seen a lot
of semantic elements.
These are elements where the tag name
reflects the purpose of the element.
It starts with paragraphs and spans, but
it goes all the way to elements like
footer, and article, and section.
There are many of these, and most of
them have predefined styles, shapes,
sizes, and purposes.
The nice thing about them is that they
make HTML really easy to read and
understand.
For instance, a div at the bottom
of an HTML document could serve
any purpose and look like anything.
But a footer element must take up
the full width of the screen, and
it's probably going to contain
information about whoever made the page.
So, with that in mind
let's see how this looks.
I will start off by drawing a big
ole rectangle to represent the page.
Those lines look straight enough, okay.
And let's see,
the top of the page has a header.
So that's going to be helpful and
it looks like there are two
main components to it.
So I'll go ahead and draw a big line for
the header because there is a logo.
And it says Udacity logo so
I'm just going to draw a U because
I can't really do that 3D thing.
And then there is a nav.
Now, that nav is really helpful.
That tells me that these are basically
buttons at the top of the page that
explain and give you an idea
of what you can click on.
Okay, so that's good, now let's see.
After the header there's a main section.
I'm not actually going to mark that
off because it sounds like that's
basically going to be the rest of
the page unless there's a footer.
And then right underneath the main,
there's an article.
So an article is supposed
to be standalone.
So I'm going to draw that as
a big standalone rectangle.
Oop, not really centered.
That's okay, doesn't have to be perfect.
And let's see, there is a title.
It's a header, h2.
So I'm going to just draw
Title in big letters.
And then there's an address that looks
like it's saying who wrote this.
We'll just put that there,
and there's a figure.
Now, a figure has usually something
like an image plus a caption.
And that's what I'm seeing here.
I'm seeing an image of cats.
This is a cat, I promise this is a cat,
take my word for it.
And there's a caption, a figcaption
underneath it, there's my figcaption.
And then it looks like there's
a div called a teaser, and
it's got a lot of text in it.
So I assume that this is going to
be the rest of the article.
Okay, that looks pretty good.
Let's see, and
then there's some more buttons.
I didn't leave myself any space.
Let's just put those over here.
These are the social media buttons.
Okay, not great,
that should probably be here.
That's okay.
Next up, there's an hr,
which is a horizontal rule.
Now that actually would
show up on the page.
You would actually see this.
It's not just me separating and
assuming there's one.
We know this has to be here.
Then there's another article.
And I am completely out of space, so
I'm just going to draw the top of it.
Okay, and it looks like it has
basically the same structure.
So there is a title with
some address underneath it.
Let us know where it's from,
and a figure.
And there I'm just going to draw
the very top of the figure and
leave it at that.
I'm going to go ahead and
guess that the page that James
gave me looks something like this.