Notifications are seriously awesome,
so let's set them up.
First you'll need to make sure that you
have the Firebase messaging dependency
in the build.gradle file.
So here I'll grab that dependency and
I will add it over here and
of course, you should sync.
Now what this dependency does
is it allows our app to receive
Firebase notifications
from the Firebase console,
as well as messages from
Firebase Cloud messaging.
And after syncing with Gradle,
that's it, that is literally it.
Having this one line
dependency in our project
means firebase is now set up
to receive notifications.
So let's try it out.
I'm here in the console and
I'm going to go ahead over here and
under the grow header you'll
see the notifications tab.
We'll click SEND YOUR FIRST MESSAGE
to well, send your first message.
This brings us to the message
composer section.
As you could see, it's pretty simple to
use, but also has a lot of options for
you.
We're going to just send
the simplest notification which will
only require us to
edit two of the fields.
First, we'll add some message
text to the notification.
This gets displayed in the notification
received on the device.
We'll leave the optional
message label part blank
which is only displayed internally for
our eyes in the console anyway.
Scrolling down, we'll also leave
the default delivery date for
the notification date so
it's sent immediately.
Next, we'll choose how much of our
apps audience to actually target.
We could target a user by their segment,
by topic, or
even just target a single device.
For now, we'll just simply
target all of our apps users.
So I'll go ahead and
select friendly chat.
If I scroll down I'll see that the send
message button is now highlighted blue,
meaning that we're ready
to send our notification.
But before we do that, let's make sure
that the newest version of our app
is running, and that our app is
in the background on our device.
Our notification as it setup right now,
won't actually be received if
our app is in the fourth run.
With a little bit of coding, you could
get around this but if this example with
no code running on the client side we're
restricted to background notifications.
Okay, let's go back to the console,
and I'm going to click send message.
This lets us review and
looks good so I'm going to send.
Now back on our device we should see
the notification instantly show up.
And there it is.
Also bonus feature tapping
on the notification
takes us straight into the app.
And you did all of this with just
one line in your build.gradle file.
Pretty amazing.