Unlike the service class we just talked
about, IntentService is a service that
actually runs in a separate
background thread altogether.
Here's the code for
starting an activity using Intent,
like we've been doing before.
The code for starting a service, and
in this case an Intent Service,
looks very similar.
First, you create a class that
extends from IntentService.
Inside that class, you will specify
what your IntentService should do in
the background by overwriting
the onHandleIntent method.
Then you simply create an Intent and
pass in that service class.
Finally, to start it,
you just call startService
as opposed to startActivity.
You pass in the Intent you just created
which inside has your IntentService.
Yap, that's an IntentService inside
an Intent, an Intent-ception.
Here is a sample, IntentService class.
Inside onHandleIntent is where
you put the code that will run in
the background.
Once on startService is called,
it launches an IntentService,
runs the code inside the onHandleIntent
on a background thread, and
then stops itself when it's done.
Notice that the intent object passed
into the onHandleIntent method
is the same intent you created
when using the startService.
Which means,
you could attach extra data to that
Intent when creating it down here.
And then you can access that
data inside onHandleIntent and
use it to say decide what action
to perform using that Intent.
It's important to note that
all IntentService requests
are handled in a single background
thread, and they are issued in order.
Each IntentService will take
as long as necessary and
will not block
the application's main thread.
But only one call to the IntentServices
onHandleIntent method
will be processed at a time.
This makes IntentService great for
tasks that need to occur in order such
as updating the counter in our case.
Okay enough with all the theory and
let's start coding our toy app for
this lesson.