Now let's go back to the two
location vacuum world and
represent it in first order logic.
So first of all, we can add locations.
We can call the left location A and
the right location B.
And the vacuum V, and
the dirt say, D1 and D2.
Then we can have relations, the relation
Loc which is true of any location.
Vacuum which is true of the vacuum.
Dirt which is true of dirt.
And At which is true of an object and
a location.
And so if we wanted to say
the vacuum is at location A,
we just say At(V,A).
If we want to say there's
no dirt in any location,
it's a little bit more complicated.
We can say for all dirt and for
all locations if the d is a dirt and
l is a location, then d is not at l.
So that says there's no
dirt in any location.
Now note, if there were thousands
of locations instead of just two,
this sentence would still hold.
And that's really the power
of first order logic.
Let's keep going and
try some more examples.
If I want to say,
the vacuum is in a location with
dirt without specifying what
location it's in, I can do that.
And I can say there exists an l and
there exists a d,
such that d is the dirt and
l is the location and
the vacuum is at the location,
and the dirt is at that same location.
And that is the power
of first order logic.
Now one final thing,
you might ask what first order means.
It means that the relations
are on objects, but
not on relations, and
that would be called higher-order.
In higher-order logic, we could say
define the notion of a transitive
relation talking about relations itself.
And so we could say for all R,
transitive of R Is equivalent to for
all a, b, and c.
R(a,b) and R(b,c)
implies R(a,c).
So that would be a valid statement in
higher-order logic that would define
the notion of a transitive relation.
But this would be invalid
in first-order logic.