To recap,
you learned how to use multiple
tools to diagnose memory problems.
Now we started with our familiar
friend Trace You, but you also
learned about some memory-specific
tools including Memory Monitor,
Heat Viewer Allocation Tracker.
But most importantly,
you want to evaluate your problematic
code against several tools and
seek multiple perspectives as to what is
actually happening underneath the hood.
Finally, it's important to
understand each tool has a strength.
Memory Monitor's a great way to get
a dynamic view of your memory over time
and Heap Viewer's great for
showing what exactly is on your heap.
And lastly,
Allocation Tracker shows you where a
particular location came from your code.