So let’s go ahead and
see how to answer these questions.
So the following statements here in
Java create a projection, selection and
selectionArgs variable.
And then performs a query on our pets
table and receives a cursor as a result.
Now this collection statements here
translate into this row SQLite query.
Note that when checking for
a quality in SQLite,
you can use a single equal sign or
a double equal sign.
And here I've used a single equal sign.
So let's walk through how each
part of the Java statements
maps to apart in SQLite statement.
So first of, selecting breed and weight
come from the projection up here in Java
which is made up of these two columns,
our PET_BREED and our PET_WEIGHT.
Next the table name that
we're querying from in SQLite
comes from the first parameter
of our query method up in Java.
And lastly, our WHERE statement
here comes from the selection and
selectionArgs variable.
So this selection here,
we have our COLUMN_PET_GENDER.
And this expression plus
the selectionArgs which we've narrowed
down to the GENDER_FEMALE constant.
And remember that mapped back
to the constant value 1.
And as a whole, this means our WHERE
statement becomes WHERE gender=1.
And remember we put these into
our query method down here.
So this selection criteria will show
only female pets from the table.
And this means our resulting cursor
contains these following two rows.
So visually,
here's how adding those parameters
narrows the information to
the cursor that we want returned.
So first, we're selecting
all the pets from our table.
Next, we know the constraints
by adding this WHERE statement.
Now we've limit it to just
these two rows of female pets.
And then lastly, we only want to
select the breed and weight columns.
So this means we just get these
two columns from these two rows.
So, back to the quiz question of
describing the resulting cursor where
we saw that it has two rows, and
the columns that were present
were the breed and the weight.