Here's a way to group the houses which
doesn't require us to specify the number
of clusters beforehand.
Let's say the houses
are arranged like this.
It would make sense
to say the following,
if two houses are close they should
be served by the same pizza parlor.
So going by this philosophy
let's try to group the houses.
Let's look at which houses
are the closest to each other.
It's these two over here,
so we group those two.
Now, which are the next
two closest houses?
It's these two over here,
so we group them.
The next two closest houses are these
two, so we group them and we keep going.
The next two closest houses are here and
now something funny happens because
one house is already grouped.
What we do, is we join the clusters
containing each of the houses.
The next two clusters are here,
so we join the respective groups.
The next two are here,
so we joined our groups.
And now the next two closest
houses are these two over here.
But that's already too far.
So let's stop there.
What we did here is we picked
a distance to begin with and said,
whenever the two closest houses are this
distance apart we'll stop the algorithm.
That will control how far we
want the clusters to be apart.
This algorithm is known as
hierarchical clustering.
So we can see that hierarchical
clustering is useful
when we may not know
the number of clusters, but
we have an idea about how
far we want them to be.