We talked about that,
there were different ways of transforming images one to another.
And you know, so
I might have two images that are related by some transformation.
And we talked about how if I know the transformation, and
I know it go from one image to the next.
But suppose I have two images.
And I'd like to figure out the transformation that takes image 1 to image 2.
How would I go about doing that?
Well, to do this, I need matching or corresponding points.
So, the way we're going to go about finding corresponding points is,
using something that we're going to call Local Features.
You know, this is a little 1 and a little 2 there.
We're going to put some meat behind defining what we mean to be Local, and
what we mean to be Features.
By the way, some of you have taken machine learning courses and
things like that.
And then and, you've seen feature vectors.
That's not what we mean here.
We're actually going to mean that later in the course,
here features are going to be things that we compute about some little
local spot, they're related to feature vectors but, but we were here first.
All right.
Our goal is to find points in an image, that can be found in other images.
And by the way, not just found in other images, but found precisely.
And what that means is, you know, you, you tell me about,
I should be able to precisely determine where that point is.
So just saying it's the middle of this gray panel, not so great.
But if you told me it's this tip of this spear,
that would be better in terms of being localized.
Also I want to reliably do the matching, right?
So if I find this point,
if I find a bunch of other points, I want to be really sure that they say no,
it's not this one, it's not, it's definitely that one, right?
So this is this idea of well matched points.
All right? So why do I want to do this?
Well, we talked about things like I might want to recover the fundamental matrix
to recover geometry,
remember we said that if you give if you give it enough correspondences.
In robotics and other computer vision things, we might want to see how a bunch
of points have moved from one frame to the next, and in order to do that.
I have to figure out which points were, were which.
Or, I might want to build a panorama.
Now, we've talked about this is general.
But here's really a beautiful example.
This comes from a paper by Brown and Lowe in CV, in ICCV in 2003.
Let me just play that again, because it's so cool.
All right, and
here what they've done is they've figured out what matching points.
How to place each one of the pictures on top of a another?
In order to do that they had to find these matching points.