Okay.
Let's see how a very
simplified particle filter can
help us estimate the ant's position.
Initially, at t equals 0,
we have no idea where the ant is.
So we might as well assume that it is in
one of these squares, any one of them.
This is our initial prediction.
Now the observation says that
we are on a white square.
The likelihood of us getting a white
observation when we are on a black
square is really low.
So, in our simple case, we get rid of
the particles In the black squares.
You can think of this as a correction.
Okay.
Now we see that the action
taken was move up.
So we take our entire
distribution of particles and
we shift the whole thing up, like that.
Any particles that went outside
the valid area are discarded.
Now this is our best guest or
prediction at time t equals 1.
This time,
we see that the observation is black.
So, all the particles on white
squares are basically inconsistent
with the observation.
As before, we get rid of them.
All right.
Our next step at t equals
1 is to move left.
Observation at time two is white, so
we get rid of all the black particles.
Next, we move up.
Interestingly, all the particles
on the board are consistent with
the observation.
At step three, we move up again.
Now the observation at
step four is black, so
we get rid of the white particles.
Now we're left with only three.
Well, from here, we move right and
the observation is white, so
we get rid of the one black particle and
that's it.
We're left with two possible
positions for the ant.
Since we don't have any further
information, that is our best guess.
Are you wondering where
the ant's started?
Well, it could have started
here at t equals 0.
Move up, see black.
Move to the left, see white.
Move up again, white.
Move up, black.
Move to the right and you see white,
but that's one possible path.
The other starting point could have been
down at the bottom here, same thing.
You move up, black.
Left, white.
Up, white.
Up, black.
Right, white.
So particle fillers, useful aren't they?