So the Summa algorithm
seems pretty good, but
how close is it to
the best possible scheme?
Imagine a machine with P nodes
connected by some topology,
further suppose each node
has M words of main memory.
Now let's say you take the matrix
operands and you chop them up into
little bits and distribute the little
bits across all the nodes.
What I want you to do now, is pick
one of the nodes, zoom in on it and
study its possible behavior.
Now recall that each node
has M words of main memory.
Let's further suppose that during
the entire distributed matrix multiply,
this particular node
does W multiplications.
We don't know what W is, but
you'll determine that later.
Now let me pose the following
question to you.
How many words must this node send or
receive?
To figure this out, let's start by
imagining that the word performs its
work as a sequence of computation and
communication steps.
We'll visualize what the node does by
a hypothetical timeline, like this one.
So time precedes horizontally.
And the node alternates
between phases of, say,
communication followed
by some computation,
followed by some more communication,
followed by computation, and so on.
Now let's divide this timeline
into L distinct phases.
A phase is special.
We’ll assume, in each phase, that every
node sends and receives exactly M words.
The exception is the last phase.
In last phase, you might send or
receive fewer than M words.
The reason is simply that
the total number of words sent and
received might not be divisible by L.
Here's a question.
What is the largest number of multiplies
that each phase can possibly do?
To figure this out,
let's consider one of the phases.
Let S sub A be the number of unique
elements of A seen during this phase.
And similarly, let's let S sub B,
and S sub C, be the number of
unique elements of B and C that we
see during this phase respectively.
By Loomis-Whitney, you can compute the
maximum number of multiplies performed
in this phase given S sub A,
S sub B, and S sub C.
So all we need to figure out now is,
how big are these sets?
Let's start by considering just S of A.
Now imagine the node and
the state of it's memory.
It's possible that at the very
beginning of the phase,
the memory is full of
only elements from A.
And of course,
because the memory capacity is M,
there can't be more than M such words.
Now remember, that by definition
the phase performs exactly M sends or
receives.
So let's think about
what that might mean.
It's possible that during the phase,
all of these words are used
to do computation.
It's also possible that all M of these
words, at some point, get pushed out.
And when I said pushed out, I don't
necessarily mean being communicated,
I just mean we get rid of them and
make space for other words.
It's then possible that all these
communications bring in a whole new set
of elements of A.
These are M completely brand new set of
elements and it's possible that before
the end of the phase, we use all of
them to form more multiplications.
So what have we said so
far about the capacity of S sub A?
Basically, we just said that it's
possible, during this phase,
that we might have seen up to
2 times M elements from A.
Now remember,
this is just an upper bound.
And I realize it might seem a little
loosey goosey, as far as bounds go.
Honk.
Now even if this bound a bit loose,
remember, we're just after a bound, so
there's nothing incorrect
about this reasoning.
It just might not be as
precise as it could be.
Now by similar reasoning, you can
find that the maximum size of S B and
S C are also 2 times M.
When you plug all that in you'll get 2
root 2, times M to the three-halves.
You might want to stop and
check that you agree.
What we've just said is that the maximum
number of multiplies that might have
occurred during this phase is 2 times
root 2, times M to the three-halves.
A natural follow-up question is,
how many phases are there?
Let's go back to the timeline.
I told you this node did
a total of W multiplies.
Remember, that every phase does at
most this number of multiplies.
So what might L be?
Well, L has to be at least equal
to the number of full phases.
And the number of full phases has to be
at least the number of multiplies that
the node does, divided by the maximum
number of multiplies per phase.
And of course, you just computed that,
so we can plug that in.
And then, of course, get rid of
the floors, leaving you with this.
Now remember, that every full
phase does exactly M transfers.
That means you can get a lower bound
on the total number of transfers,
which would just be the number
of full phases times M.
So the number of words
communicated by at least one node,
has to be at least the number
of full phases times M.
Let's plug all this stuff in.
Okay, whew, you're almost there.
Now what about W?
If the matrix operands had been of
size mby k, k by n, and m by n,
then you know the total number
of multiplies is just mnk.
Now, if that's a total
number of multiplies, and
all the processes
are executing in parallel,
then at least one node has to
execute mnk over P multiplications.
That is, there's some node for
which W is at least mnk over P.
Let's plug that in.
What you now have is a lower bound on
the volume of communication by at least
1 node.
Let's simplify this a little bit for
the square case.
That would be n cubed over P multiplies,
per node.
Now there's just one more piece
of useful information which is
the value of M.
Remember, that we distributed the
matrices, evenly, over all the nodes.
So that means M has to be
proportional to n squared over P.
So if you plugged that in and
simplify, you'll get this.
So to summarize,
at least one node sends and
receives n squared over root P words.
Let's connect this back to
the big picture of this segment.
This analysis is about the volume of
communication seen by at least one
processor.
In terms of the time
to do communication,
it allows you to conclude that the
bandwidth term should have this form.
At least one node sends this much data.
And it can only send
it at a rate of beta.
That's because beta is
the minimum time per word.
And your lower bound tells you the
minimum number of words that at least
one node must have sent.
So that gives us a lower
bound on this beta term.
That's super cool.
The only question now, is what is this?