So, in order to learn about
supported vector machines,
we have to talk about what
are called linear classifiers.
And linear classifiers
are exactly what you might think.
So here I have some data points.
I got blue ones and, and pink ones.
And the idea would be,
what if we just wanted to find a linear
separator that separated things.
Well, in this particular case,
we could do that, no problem.
So it would be something like that.
Ta-da, there's our,
our linear classifier.
And you know, what we'd like to do is to
talk about finding these kinds of things
automatically, and then the whole
point of support vector machines,
is to do these in well, what you'll see
are some higher dimensional spaces which
will give us some very
effective classifications,
some powerful classification machinery.
So, let's talk a little bit about lines.
So here's just lines in,
in regular 2D space.
So here's an equation of our line, and
this is the normalized equation, and
we used to write ax plus by plus c
equals 0 when we did a bunch of things.
And I'm not doing that here because in
SVM land, where it's derived, b has
a particular value, it talks about, it,
it, it's written in a particular way.
So I wrote it as px + qy + b equals 0.
And really, what I mean to say is that
we're going to let some w, here it's,
be pq, and pretty soon those will go
away and we'll only talk about w.
Let w be pq, and
if we have some point, x, which
will be sort of little x, little y.
Then the line, px plus qy plus b,
that's the same thing as this
line w dot x plus b equals 0.
All right?
And w here, this vector here, that's
going to be in this direction there.
Okay?
One thing that should be
clear from this, right?
I could scale w and b and
it'll still be 0, right?
Multiply both of them by 3 and
I get the same value.
All right.
Now, if I have some point, x0, y0,
I might want to talk about the distance
cap D of that point to the line.
Okay?
So here we have our,
our point and then there's this question
of what that distance D is, all right?
Well, given the equation of the line,
we can express that distance in
just the, the following way.
It's just essentially,
find the dot product of that on w,
subtract off or, or
think of that as being connected to b.
Whatever that value is,
that's how far off the line it is, and
you then have to normalize because from
a distance, by the magnitude of p and
q, so that's why it's divided by the
square root of p squared plus q squared.
And that can be just written like this.
Okay, so it's just w transposed,
x plus b,
the line equation up there,
divided by the magnitude of w.
Okay, so that's the distance D.