Let's talk about localization of a car like our DARPA Urban Challenge car Junior.
This car uses a map of the environment--
it knows it advance where the lay markers are--
and uses probabilistic localization to keep track of where it is.
The reason for that is it could use GPS, the global positioning system,
but that has enormous errors, sometimes in order of 5 or more meters,
which is very unsafe for driving.
By localizing utilizing particle filters or histogram filters,
our car can do the same with about 10 cm error,
which means it can really understand where to stay in the lane
just by known where the lane is in advance and using localization techniques
like the ones we'll discuss right now.