All right, so now we're going to figure
out how many samples we need, and
in particular we want to be epsilon
over 2 accurate in our estimate.
And we want to be 1 minus delta over k
certain that our estimate is correct.
And so just so
substituting those values into the
hoeffding bound that we had before gives
us one half times natural log of 2k
over delta, the search parameter.
Divided by square root of c,
the number of times we do the sample
is going to be less than or
equal to epsilon over 2.
So now we just have to solve for c.
>> Okay,
that seems pretty straight forward.
>> All right, so
substituting these constraints.
Epsilon over 2 and
the 1 minus delta over k
into our hufting bound from before gives
us something that looks like this.
The square of one half, natural log
of 2k over delta in the numerator,
squared of the number of samples,
c, in the denominator.
And that gives us an estimate
that's within epsilon over 2.
So now we should be good to go.
All we need to know is how
big does c have to be.
So we just have to solve for c.
>> Right, so we do some algebra and
some other algebra and
the very thing happens.