Okay, so we'll start with an example.
We are the apps store or Google Play.
And our goal is to
recommend apps to users.
So to each user,
we're going to try to recommend them the
app they are most likely to download.
So here we have a table of data that
we're going to use to make the rules.
And the table contains six people.
And for each one of these six people,
we have recorded their gender, and
their age, and the app they downloaded.
So for example, the first person
is a 15 year old female, and
she downloaded Pokemon Go.
So here's a quiz.
Between gender and age, which
one seems more decisive for predicting
what app will the users download?
Submit your answer below.