Actually Cal images have 2 dimensions--not just 1.
Here's an X and a Y,
and the perspective laws apply to both dimensions.
The projection of the X-coordinate into the camera plane
is governed by the perspective law over here.
And the same is true for Y.
In both cases, the appearance of an object, of size X and Y,
is scaled inversely with the distance of the object to the camera plane.
One of the interesting consequences of perspective projection is
that parallel lines in the world seem to result in vanishing points over here
so that these lines are parallel in the physical world.
Because things shrink in inverse proportion to the distance, you'd find it far away.
The perceived distance is much smaller,
resulting all the way in a vanishing point that sits somewhere over here.
So sometimes there's more than 1 vanishing point.
In this specific instance, there's a vanishing point over here,
and a vanishing point over here--and those correspond to parallel lines,
like the curb over here or the house facades
that all shrink, with distance, in their visual appearance.