And the answer is we have an unbounded
solution, if every leaf in the plan,
ends up in a goal.
So if we follow through the plan
no matter what path we execute
based on the observations.
And remember, we don't get to pick the
observations, the observations come into
us and we follow one path or
another based on what we observe.
So we can't guide it in one direction or
another, and so
we need every possible leaf node.
This one only had one, but
if a plan had multiple leaf nodes every
one of them would have to be a goal.
Now, in terms of a bounded solution,
it's okay to have branches but
not to have loops.
If we had branches, and we ended up
with one goal here, and one goal here
in one-two-three steps, one-two-three
steps, that would be a bounded solution.
But if we have a loop,
rate might be one, two, three,
four, five, you don't know how
many steps it's going to take.