Sure, so just relying back on kind of
experiences I've had with web
development and also some other GUI
programs we could probably use a model
view controller type of architecture?
>> Sure, so model view controller is
a typical, it came out of originally,
the small talk world and is provided
as a set of classes in Java Swing for
example, very commonly used for GUI.
What else do you have?
>> Maybe something where we have,
I guess
what were using right now is kind of
like registering events and callback.
Does that?
>> Yeah sure.
>> So, I don't know, I think that
what we've described here and
then kind of in NBC are my first two,
the ones that I gravitate towards.
>> Okay, you can always find a way in
these situations thinking things
in terms of client server.
That is, we have the file
manager serving the file.
We have the GUI components serving
what the user is seeing and so on.
So client server's always a possibility.
Later on we'll talk about some
other architectural styles,
one that might be applied here
is shared memory where all of
the components are accessing
the data out of a single place.
Or another style, if you've ever been
involved with Microsoft Windows Com
architecture, component based
architecture, we can try that as well.
But for this exercise,
we're going to stick with this layered
implicit invocation architectural style.