So we need to get some
help from the hardware,
looking at this spinlock example
from the previous video.
We somehow needed the checking
of the lock value and
the setting of the lock value to happen
indivisibly, atomically, so that we
can guarantee that only one thread at
a time can successfully obtain the lock.
The problem with this implementation is
that it takes multiple cycles to perform
the check in this setting and
during these multiple cycles,
threads can be interleaved
in arbitrary ways.
If they're running on
multiple processors,
their execution can
completely overlap in time.
To make this work,
we have to rely on support from
hardware-supported atomic instructions