The first step in coding Gaussian
elimination will be to code the three
basic operations we've been using
in the elimination procedure.
Swapping two equations, multiplying
an equation by a non-zero number, and
adding a multiple of one
equation to another.
In the Linear System class, I've defined
three functions to correspond to these
operations, but have left them blank.
For this quiz, go ahead and
fill in those three functions,
either in the module I've provided or
in your own program.
Make sure to test your
code before moving on.
You'll find some test cases in
the instructor notes to run your
code against.
They will be in Python and will use the
notation from the Linear System Module.
But please feel free to modify
the syntax as needed to run them
in your own code.
Once you're confident your code is
working, check the box here and
click Submit to complete the quiz.