So things are looking great.
But at the moment,
we're only adding things to a database.
At some point,
you'll end up with thousands and
thousands of items in there.
And the browser's going to go,
hey, you know what?
I've had enough of you doing that.
You're not allowed any more storage.
So we need to make sure we're
only keeping what we need.
And it looks like this
is going to be your job.
Mike?
This is kind of a tricky one.
>> Yeah, but they've played with
all the commands and tools.
They can do this.
In this task, you're going to ensure
the database only has 30 Witter
items in it at any single time.
Some of the methods have
been subbed out for you, so
you want to check out that code.
To do that, run git reset --hard to
remove any local changes you have.
Then git checkout task-clean-db
to get the stubbed methods.
Now head over to
public/js/main/IndexController.js.
Down in underscore on socket message,
we're already adding
items into the database.
But after that, you need to ensure there
are no more than 30 in the object store.
The code in public/js/idbtext/index.j.s
should act as a good reference.
Again, if your database gets into
a bad state, go into dev tools and
run indexedDB.deleteDatabase and
pass at the parameter wittr.
This will remove the database and
let you start fresh.
Once you put the code in place, refresh
wittr in the browser to run your code.
I recommend shift refreshing to bypass
service worker until you've got
everything working.
Then bump the version of
the service worker static cache
to pick up your changes.
If everything's working, you should
see the wittr database in dev tools.
And in there,
you should see no more than 30 messages.
To double check everything is working,
head to the settings page.
And type idb-clean into the test field.
And press Enter.