So, let's look at the app that
we will build in this lesson.
It will have three activities.
The main launcher activity you see here,
which has two buttons,
the banner ad and
the interstitial ad buttons.
Each of these buttons will bring
you to a separate activity,
showing a banner ad and
an interstitial ad.
So when I press on the banner ad button,
you will see a banner ad
being displayed onscreen.
And we have this entire area above
to display your app contents.
I can also click on the ad.
And you see that we navigate off our app
to see more information about the ad.
And we can also go back and
continue to interact with our app.
And when we are clicking around here,
you can see toast messages
appear on the screen.
These are messages that
our app will generate so
you can see how the app
interacts with the add and
also note that the banner acts as text
banner because this is a test ad.
And what I will tell you now is
very important, so pay attention.
When we are developing our app, we will
use test ads because advertisers do
not and should not have to pay for
real ads while you are developing.
Using real ads during development is
a violation against the terms and
conditions and it can result
in your accounts being banned.
So this is really, really important.
Now, let's go back and
look at the other parts of the app.
We can also click on
the interstitial app button.
And that brings us to another
activity with two buttons here.
So we talked about, interstitial
ads use the entire screen when they
are displayed and
they also support video content.
Therefore, we first load
the interstitial ads and
after they've been loaded,
we can display them.
So this button here will
load an interstitial ad.
You can see that it's loaded and
now we have the option to show the ad.
So we press on this show button and
here, you can see the ad come up.
And again, when developing our app,
we use test ads.
And that's what you see here,
a test interstitial ad.
And as with banner ads, we can click
on the ad which will bring us to
the content and then we can go back.
All right, so
that's the app we're going to build.
So let's get right to it and
do some coding.
So let's get you started building
an app that can show ads.
Some of these steps we assume you
are familiar with since you should
have taken the location
lesson before this one.
So in Android Studio, I want you to do
the following things, create a project
with a blank activity, add the metadata
com.google.android.gms.version
to the manifest, add the dependencies
to your build.gradle file.
And also add the following
permissions to the manifest,
android.permission.INTERNET and
android.permission.access_network_st-
ate".
The Internet permission is required
since we're going to fetch
ads from the Internet.
And the access network state allows
Admob to check if an Internet connection
is available before trying to fetch
the ad and check here when you're done.