Okay, so what'd you think? Was that enough information
to kind of chew on it a little bit?
>> Maybe. [LAUGH] So, let's see, I have, I guess,
k hypotheses I have to chose from. I know that basically
you always return the output of one. I don't get
to chose what those examples are, they're drawn from some distribution.
>> Right.
>> And I want to know whether I'm going to need to see, another of examples
that are, polynomial, in the error that I'm
interested in, with the certainty that I'm interested in.
And I gotta be able to come up with
an algorithim, a learning algorithm that will do that.
>> Exactly. So what do you think?
>> I want to say the answer is yes.
>> So how would you argue that though?
Do you have a particular algarythm in mind?
>> Well I actually did, I was going to keep the
all the hypothesis that are consistent with the data that I've seen.
>> Okay, alright
and what is that called?
>> The version space.
>> Right. Okay.
>> So keep track of that and then, whenever I stop getting samples, I have
to pick one of those. So I'm just going to, pick one of them uniformly.
>> Okay. Well that seems good so far. You
could pick one uniformly. So what makes you think that
that's actually going to. Be able to return the
right answer, or a, a close enough answer with not
that much data. How do we actually bound the number of samples that we need
to make it so that when we pick uniformly we actually get a good answer?
>> Well, it's a little hard, I mean my, my intuition is that, given
what we don't know what the concept is only the class that it comes from
If I do anything other than choose uniformly, then I can be very unlucky.
I basically... uniformly basically means in this
case I don't know anything else to do.
So there's sort of no better algorithm than the one that
we just came up with, which is find all the
hypotheses that are consistent... And you have no reason to
choose one over the other because you don't have anymore data.
So you should just close your eyes and pick one.
And if you do anything else, then in the absence of
some specific domain knowledge that tells you to do otherwise,
you know, you can just basically end up being very unlucky.
>> So, I, I agree with you and this is a good algorithm. But what we
lack at the moment is an argument as to why the number of
samples that it needs, isn't exponential.
Right? Cause there's an exponentially. Large, you
know, 2 to the K different possible inputs. If we had to see
all of them to be able to guess right, that would be too many.
>> Mm hm.
>> So, we really want it to be, you know,
a polynomial in, in K. Not an exponential in K. So
I'm going to say that we don't have enough background
yet to be able to answer this definitively. The, yes is
the right answer. But we're going to need to dive in a little bit more
deeply, and develop some more concepts to be
able to argue why that's the right answer.