Brent's Theorem is an upperbound
on the execution time.
That means if I give you a DAG and
a PRAM machine,
the PRAM machine might run the DAG in
less time than PRAM would predict.
So, looking at this example,
it has a work of six units and
a critical path length of four.
So on a 2-processor system Brent would
predict that the time is less than or
equal to five time units.
Now looking at the stag you can probably
easily see a why to execute this.
Using only four time units.
For example when we divided
it to phases like this.
So there are four phases and every
phase has at most two units of work.
So I can keep my
2-processor PRAM busy and
the total time will be
four instead of five.
So this tells you that
Brent's Theorem has some slack in it.
So here's my question for you.
Can you find a different, but
valid assignment of vertices to
phases that instead takes five
time units instead of four.
So what I've done is I put a set
of boxes next to each vertex, and
in each box I want you
to enter a phase number.
And the phase number should be one,
two, three, or four.
And remember the rule about phases
every phase has to include exactly one
critical path for text,
no more and no less.