Here is a sequence of MDP questions.
We're given a maze environment with 8 fields
where we receive +100 over here and -100 in the corner over here.
Our agent can go north, south, west, or east, but actions may fail at random.
With probability "P," and P is a number between 0 and 1, the action succeeds,
and with 1 - P we go into reverse.
For example, if we take the action go east into this state over here,
with P probability we find ourselves over there.
With 1 - P we find ourselves right over here in the exact opposite direction.
Here is the east action again. With P we go to the right, and with 1 - P we go to the left.
Of course, if you bounce into a wall we stay where we are.
For my first question, I'll assume P equals 1.
There is no uncertainty in action outcome, and there is no failure.
The state transition function is deterministic.
I want you to fill in for each state the final value after running value iteration to completion,
and please assume the cost is -4 and we use gamma equals 1 as the discount factor.
Please fill in those missing six values over here.