But we know that you might get stuck along the
way. That's just part of the process. That's why we have
forums where you can ask your peers about a particular
quiz or problem set exercise. Look below this video in the
Discussions section. You should see a forum topic. And you
should also see a button that says Ask a Question. If
you're confused about what I'm saying in a particular video or
you're confused about a particular quiz, you can click that button
that says Ask a Question, and your amazing peers
are usually quick to respond. And every once in a
while, Professor Rogers, Dr. Laraway and I will jump in,
too. Now go ahead and click on the discussion topic
entitled Why is Statistics Important? Feel free to read through
all the different applications of statistics that people have posted.
Scroll down to one of the posts that I wrote,
where I list the most recent statistics for the average
degrees of separation between any two people. What is it?