To understand why
the code is not updating,
we can refer back to
our life cycle diagram.
In the Android life cycle,
when you navigate away from an activity,
onPause and onStop are called.
When you come back, onStart and
onResume are called.
OnCreate is never called unless
you rotate the activity or
reopen the activity after being closed.
So one option for
loading up our preferences
would be to read from shared preferences
in the OnResume or OnStart call back.
But there's a better way.
The shared preferences object allows
you to register an object that
implements an OnShared
preference change listener.
This object that gets called whenever
a value in the shared preferences file
changes.
In this way, you can actually be
triggered to update the UI if and
only if a preference
is actually changed.
Setting this up will take four steps.
First, we determine the activity
that needs to get called
when the preferences changed.
In this case,
that's going to be Visualizer Activity.
This is because Visualizer Activity
is the one whose UI needs to change.
Second we're going to need
Visualizer Activity to implement
an on shared preference change listener.
This will then require
that Visualizer Activity
implement a method called
OnShared preference change.
Which will be triggered whenever
a preference is changed.
Third, you need to link
the onSharedPreferenceChangeListener
with the sharedPreferenceObject
it should be listening to.
You can do this using
registerOnSharedPreferenceChangeListe-
ner.
And then fourth,
you also need to unregister the listener
when the activity is shut down.
You can do this, using the
.unregisterOnSharedPreferenceListener.
[SOUND] That was a mouthful.
Okay, let's do this.
I'll start in Visualizer Activity
by implementing
the OnSharedPreferenceChangeListener.
This is red now because I actually have
to override onSharedPreferenceChange.
So I will go ahead and do that.
Here, I'm going to check
what preference changed and
then I'm going to update my
VizualizerView accordingly.
This is a lot like what I'm doing
in the current onCreate method.
Note, that up here, I'm passed both
a reference to sharePreferences and
the key of the preference
that was changed.
So I don't actually need to
use the preference manager to
get a reference to shared preferences
because I already have one.
This also makes taking
shared preferences and
getting the Boolean from it pretty easy.
Now that I've made Visualizer Activity
implement onSharedPreferenceChange,
I'm going to register the listener.
I'll want to do this in onCreate,
when the activity's created.
So I'm going to do it in
the setupSharedPreferences method.
I'm going to take
the SharedPreferences object.
And call
registerOnSharedPreferenceChangeListe-
ner.
Passing in this,
remember Visualizer Activity implements
shared preference on shared
preference change listener.
Which is why, I can pass in this.
Now that I've registered the listener,
I also have to unregister the listener.
And I'll do that in OnCreates
corresponding on destroy method.
So I'm going to override on destroy.
And in that method, I'm going to
just get my PreferenceManager,
and I'm going to get
the DefaultSharedPreferences.
And I'm going to unregister
the OnSharedPreferenceChangeListener.
Great, let's run the app and
see what happens.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And it updated.