Let's take a quiz in which we'll take a look at an example of
a critical section.
The critical section that we will look at corresponds to a critical section in
a toy shop similar to the toy shop examples that we looked at.
In the toy shop, there will be new orders that will be coming in.
As well as there will be orders for repairs of toys that have
already been process, so, like, old orders that need to be revisited.
Only a certain number of threads, a certain number of workers,
will be able to operate in the toy shop at any given point of time.
So there will be a mutex,
orders_mutex, that controls which workers have access to the toy shop.
Basically, which orders can be processed.
The toy shop has the following policy.
At any given point of time,
there can be up to three new orders processed in the toy shop.
In addition, if there is up to only one new order being processed, then
any number of requests to service old orders can be handled in the toy shop.
The code shown in this box describes the critical section entry code that's
executed by the workers performing new orders.
As expected, we first lock the mutex and
then check a condition, and this condition must correspond to this policy.
Depending on this condition, on this predicate, we determine whether the thread,
whether the new order, can go ahead and
be processed in the toy shop, or if we must wait.
With the wait statement,
we use a condition variable new_cond as well as we include the mutex.
Because as we mentioned, a mutex must be associated with a wait statement so
that it can be atomically released.
The predicate statement that we must check on
before determining whether a thread will wait or can proceed, is missing.
For this quiz, you need to select the appropriate check that needs to
be made in order to enter the critical section.
There are four choices given here.
You should select all that apply.