So, this command rm-rf
/ is pretty scary.
rm is the command for
removing files, deleting things.
The r stands for recursive, which means
that it will delete whole directories
and everything underneath them,
and the f means force,
which keeps it from checking
whether you really want to delete.
So what this command rm-rf/ does is
to delete everything on your Linux
file system, or at least everything that
your user account has access to delete.
If you wanted to delete really
everything you'd have to switch accounts
up to the super user account first.
But fortunately Linux has gotten
safer in the past few years.
On most systems today,
if you try to do this command, the RM
command will give you an error message.
That's because people who weren't
very nice kept telling people to run
this command and
made them break their computers.