Regular Android applications
use the notification API
to show important information to
the user of phones and tablets.
Android Auto Support for
messaging uses the same notification
API to the underlying implementation.
The Android Auto app that runs on the
phone looks at the notification screen
being generated, and
it notices those that contain the car
extender, like these two red ones here.
Let's look inside one of these
objects to see what it contains.
The Unread Conversation object contains
the text to speak out to the driver,
and this is handled automatically for
you.
Speech Recognition is then used
to get the reply from the driver.
And Remote Input is used to
help capture this for you and
give you a string of the spoken
audio via this intent here.
Remember, the phone is handling the text
to speech and speech recognition, and
the car is just displaying images and
capturing audio.
Let's get started with some code to
understand how notifications work and
how to add these extensions.
We'll use the basic notification sample,
which is the same starting point
that we use when we discuss
notifications on Android Wear.
So, let's find a sample in Android
Studio that demonstrates what we need.
So here, we go to File, Import Sample,
and we're going to look for
a sample called Basic Notifications.
See it there, we hit Next, and
we can leave everything
with the default values.
So now we've got a new
project on our machine
with the basic notification sample.
You've had this dialogue box here,
we just hit yes to that because we just
want to reload it after some small
changes that have been made, and
now we have our sample
that we can get started.
The next thing we need to do is
get an emulator ready to start
the sample within.
Go to Tools, Android, and
start the AVD manager.
Now what we do here is we
create a virtual device, and
you need to select a phone
model to use here.
I'm going to pick a Galaxy Nexus,
since it's an older device
with a small display and
a smaller memory footprint that will
work on my small laptop display easily.
So, now we hit Next.
And it's important here that
we select Lollipop API 21,
although any newer API
will work as well.
And we need to make sure we pick the
Google APIs, since that's required for
the Android Auto Support.
If you pick the x86 emulator, and
have the HAXM driver installed,
the emulator will also run a lot faster.
So we hit Next.
Now here on this scale, you may need to
select 2DP on device is 1px on screen
to make sure the emulator
fits on your screen.
Otherwise, leave all
the defaults as they are, and
then click finish to create the ADV.
Now you have a list of emulators
available, so select it and
click on the play button
to get it started.