Okay, it's that time again for
another toy app.
We'll be creating a simple app to
search GitHub repositories by name.
Along the way, you'll be building query
URLs and learning network basics.
If you run into problems,
you might want to use that logging
stuff we just learned about.
So let's start there.
Here's the URL stream we'll
be using in our toy app.
It uses GitHub's API and searches for
repositories with a given name.
It also allows you to sort the results
or see a certain page of the results.
This request doesn't require any
sort of API key authentication.
You can send requests to this API from a
web browser without any special set-up.
Let's try that.
Enter that URL into a browser,
and we get a list of the GitHub
repositories named Android.
It sounds like something that we could
make into a simple app, so let's begin.