Now that you've evaluated ideas and
thought about your own connection to
them, it's time to choose just one idea.
For the rest of the course,
you will use one of your ideas to work
on tasks related to the final project.
If no idea seems compelling,
you can complete the final project
using the Shopping App idea or
some version of it.
Don't get caught up in whether
your idea is good enough.
Most entrepreneurs
don't succeed at first.
But even when they don't succeed
with an idea, they learn from it.
You should have the same mindset.
You're learning how to move fast,
get feedback and iterate on your ideas.
Based on your own work of evaluating
your ideas and your reflection on
the Manipulation Matrix, I'd like you
to select one of the following options.
Have you chosen to work on your own
idea for the rest of the course?
Or will you work on a version
of the Super Duper Shopping App?
And then finally,
is your idea B2C or B2B?
Select one of these options and
select one of these options.