[Thrun] So one of the questions you might ask for a Markov chain like this is
what happens if time becomes really large?
What happens for the probability of A1000?
Or let's go extreme.
What about in the limit, A infinity, often written as the limits of time
going to infinity of any P of At.
That's like the fancy math notation, but what it really means is we just wait a long, long time.
What is going to happen to the Markov chain over here? What is that probability?
This probability is called a stationary distribution,
and a Markov chain settles to a stationary distribution
or sometimes a limit cycle if the transition is alternativistic(?), which we don't care about.
And the key to calculating this is to realize that the probability for any t
must be the same as the probability 1 times (?)
This can be resolved as follows.
We know that P of At is P of At given At minus 1 times P of At minus 1
plus P of At given Bt minus 1
times probability of Bt minus 1.
This is just the theorem of total probability or forward propagation rule
applied to this case over here, so nothing really new.
But if you call this guy over here X, then we now have X
equals probability of At given At minus 1 is 0.5
times--and this is the same X as this one over here
because you're looking for the stationary distribution, so it's X again.
This probability over here, A following B, is 1 in this special case,
and the probability of Bt minus 1 is 1 minus At minus 1.
And if you plug this in, that's the same as 1 minus X.
And we can now solve this for X.
Let me just do this.
X equals, if you put these 2 Xs together we get minus 0.5 plus 1
or, differently, 1.5X equals 1.
That means X equals 1 over 1.5, which is 2/3.
So the answer here is the stationary distribution will have A occurring with 2/3 chance
and B with 1/3 chance.
It's still a Markov chain--it flips from A to B--
but these are the frequencies at which A occurs
and this is the frequency at which B occurs.