So you might be wondering
what is exactly is a meme.
>> A meme is an idea, behavior,
or style that spreads from person
to person within a culture.
>> And they aren't restricted
to a single language or country.
Any place where
the Internet is available,
memes based on popular movies,
sports and political figures will form.
>> Sometimes, the visuals of
the original are recreated.
While other times, the source
image is used with some new text.
Hey, so what's your favorite meme?
>> I have to say Futurama Fry.
How about you?
>> I'm going to go with Brace Yourself,
because usually it shows up before
really big meme-worthy events.
>> Cool.
If you'd like to learn more about
any of the images we've used,
check the instructor's notes.