So, here are the simple answers for
this one.
We knew this one already.
Here the red light is
going to be hitting the t.
And the blue one is hitting r.
So, this would be my output for
this one.
And, of course, as we've seen for
everything else,
could be flipped completely.
Blue is, of course, r, but for
this bin, not this bin anymore.
Similarly blue was in this bin,
and red for this bin, and
this is how I would
actually get the result.
So now, just by putting a bunch
of pinholes after the lens,
the camera plane, and pinhole here,
we were able to extract more
information about the light itself,
the rays of light, beyond just,
kind of, what were the intensities.
Right?
And that's the one thing which we
actually want to start encoding.
So when encoding the direction and
intensity of light using the simple way
of combining a camera system with
a bunch of smaller camera systems.
The lens system and small pinholes,
but an array of them.
So, in essence what we've done is
we've added miniature pinholes
at the image plane, and
this allows us to analyze the structure
of light at each and every micro-pixel.