To get started let's replace the hash
tag in our delete link with the password
/restaurant/ id number / delete.
Here inside my do get block.
I'm going to make a confirmation page
to call to the user's attention in
the restaurant they
were about to delete.
Within it I create a post form that
only contains the button element,
to confirm the delete.
Then I use w file to write my
output back out to the client.
Similarly to my edit post,
I grab the ID part of my URL and
create a query to find
that restaurant object.
I then call session.delete on the object
and commit the delete to the database.
I redirect once again to
the main restaurants page.
Let's save our code and
fire up the server one more time.
And we see that we can now create, read,
update and delete via our webpage.
All objectives complete.
And of course, the source code for
objective five can also be
found in the instructor notes.