There are a few terms related
to Packer that you need to know.
A template is a JSON
file that defines one or
more builds by configuring
the various components of Packer.
Packer will read the template and
use that information to create
multiple machine images in parallel.
Builders are components of Packer that
are able to create a machine image for
a single platform.
Builders read in some configuration and
use that to run and
generate a machine image.
A builder is invoked as
part of a build in order to
create the actual resulting image.
Example builders include VirtualBox,
VMware,
Amazon EC2 and more can be created and
added to Packer in the form of plug-ins.
Builders take a source image that is
different for each specific builder.
So, this Virtual Box builder
will have an ISO as a source.
Where as an Amazon EC2 builder
will have an AMI as a source.
Provisioners are components
of Packer that install and
configure software within
a running machine,
prior to that machine being
turned into a static image.
They perform the major work of making
the image contain useful software.
Examples of provisioners include
shell scripts, and also Chef or
Puppet scripts, that install software.
Post-processors are Packer components
that take the result of a builder or
another post-processor and
process that to create a new artifact.
Examples of post-processors
are compressed to compress artifacts,
upload/upvote artifacts, in this case,
vagrant builder vagrant box.
Artifacts are the result of a single
build and are usually a set of ID's or
files to represent a machine image.
Every builder produces
a single artifact.
And a build is a single task that
eventually produces an image.
For example, the same Packer script
could run builds for VMware,
AWS, and VirtualBox.
So Packer reads a template file,
picks the appropriate builder for each
platform that's listed in the template,
and runs a build to produce an image.
Then once the machine is up and
running on that platform using that
image, it runs the appropriate
provisioners to install whatever other
software configuration you need it to.
That's then saved out
as a modified image.
And after that's done, it optionally
runs one or more post-processors on it,
and in the end saves
the resulting artifact.
So, given what you've seen here,
how would you switch from
Ubuntu to CentOS in Packer?
Would you run Packer on a machine or
VM that's already running CentOS?
Would you change the source
in the builder configuration?
Would you change the source in
the provisioner configuration?
Would you change the target in
the post-processor configuration?
Or is the answer that you can't,
Packer only supports Ubuntu?