In this problem, a passive TD-reinforcement learning agent starts at S and moves to G
under a fixed policy which says first, make moves that get closest to G.
So if we started here, we'd want to go in this direction because it's closest to G,
and (b) stay on these gray squares which represent roads,
and (c) if you do happen to go off the road, then move it back onto the road immediately.
The actions are stochastic, and they may go in the intended direction,
or they may go 90 degrees off, so if we were here, we'd plan to start under this policy
going in this direction. We might end up there, but we might end up here or here.
And if we did end up here, then we'd immediately head back towards the road,
so we'd aim back down in this direction.
And what I want you to do is click on all the squares that would never be explored
by this reinforcement learning agent following this passive fixed policy.