Well, we made it to Core Data at last.
Core Data is Apple's favorite
framework for the model layer.
Learning to use it is an important
step but not necessarily an easy one.
The goal of Core Data is to persist
runtime state just like NSCoding but
it's a bigger, more comprehensive
approach as you'll see.
When you learn the framework, you
need to learn how to get all of these
Core Data components
snapped together correctly.
We call them the Core Data stack.
Learning the stack turns a lot
of people off to the topic.
It seems complicated but in truth,
the set up work is usually the same
every time that you write an app.
S we're going to try
something a little different.
Here in lesson three,
we're going to work on an app in which
the Core Data is already set up.
That's how you spend most of
your development time anyways.
After that, in lesson four,
we'll come back and
look at the steps involved in adding
Core Data to an app from scratch.
So we hope that you're feeling brave.
We're going to try to make this into
a tool that you'll really like.