[BLANK_AUDIO]
To succeed in a Kaggle competition,
there's a couple core skills
that you need to have.
The first is that you need to be really
fluent and learn to be fluent in working
with a data programming
language such as Python or
R, that has a lot of libraries installed
that really facilitate machine learning.
The second, is you need to be good
at interactively exploring and
understanding for
data and its structure.
So tools like ggplot2 and all,
really facilitate rapid visualization
and exploratory
analytics over that data.
And then the third component is that
you need to set up an environment that
enables rapid aeration and
experimentation.
So to do that includes things
like having, get set up for
code version control.
So you can go back to
any point in time and
rerun work that you've done before and
reproduce that work.
As well as having a standardized
computational environment set
up with a lot of good machine learning
packages in it, like xgboost for
To Python R To boost the machines or
another library called
is really good for flexibly
exploring deep neutral networks.
One of the patterns that we've seen for
people who do competitions is
there's kind of two categories.
There's a category of people
who approach a problem and
think I have this great idea that I'm
really confident that'll work out.
I think it's creative,
I think it's innovative and new,
then they spend two months going and
trying to develop that great idea,
implement it in code and
then see how it performs.
Inevitably when they actually go and
submit it, then see how it performs,
it doesn't work out, and
that's a wrong mindset to take too,
trying to do well in a machine
learning competition.
Instead the mindset to have is,
I have a lot of different ideas
that I think might work out.
I want to experiment with them and
explore to see how they work
in this specific problem, and
I want to get through as many of these
ideas as possible, to find the couple
that really matter and
the couple that make a big difference.
One very common pattern that we've
seen amongst the winners is that they
make hundreds to close to
a thousand submissions and
they get through the iterative loop of
making a new results that measuring
it's performance and then learning from
how it performed very, very quickly.
And they optimize their environments and
their workflows to get through that
iterative loop as fast as possible.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The two most popular programming
languages are platform R R and Python.
The scientific computing ecosystem for
Python over the last five years
has really evolved and matured.
The big advantage that people have when
they're working with Python is it's very
easy to go from experimentation
to production code.
And we have access to all
the capabilities, a rich and
full featured programming language has.
Then on the flip side,
R is really great for
machine learning and
exploratory data analytics.
However it doesn't necessarily have
the same set of web capabilities, for
example, that Python has.
So we see those two languages
as being the ones that
are predominantly
successful on our platform.
However it's by no
means limited to that,
we see some people in competitions
using C++ or C# or Java as well but
those are very much outliers,
more unusual results.
One of the kind of things that's
funnier is we have many people
participate in our competitions
using tools like SaaS.
I think at one point I surveyed the user
base, about 20% of the user base used
SaaS, however not a single person has
ever won a competition with SaaS.