In Python,
the contents of a CSV file are commonly
represented as a list of rows.
There are two common choices for
how to represent each row.
In the first option, each row is a list.
So then the overall data
structure is a list of lists.
In the second option,
each row is a dictionary.
This option works well if you have a CSV
header because then the keys of each
dictionary can be column names and
the fields can be values.
So then your overall data structure
would be a list of dictionaries.
Now you could write the code to read
in the data from the CSV yourself and
it wouldn't be too hard, but
there are libraries already
written to do it for you.
Here I've written some code using
Python's unicodecsv library
to read in the student enrollments and
print out the first record.
I'll go ahead and run the cell.
This code is taken pretty directly
from the example code on the CSV
module's documentation page.
There's a link to this page
in the instructor notes.
So in this code,
first I create the list of enrollment.
Then I open the file.
The mode, rb, here, means that
the file will be opened for reading.
And the b flag changes the format
of how the file is read.
The CSV documentation page mentions that
I need to use this when I'm using this
library.
Next, you'll notice I'm
using the DictReader,
which means each row
will be a dictionary.
I chose this since our data does have
a header row, and this will allow me to
refer to each column by its name,
rather than its number.
Now the reader won't
actually be a list of rows.
Instead it will be something
called an interator.
If you're curious, you can learn more
about iterators by following the link in
the instructor notes.
What you need to know here though, is
that the iterator let's you write a for
loop to access each element,
but only once.
So if I were to add this second loop
to print out all the row in the reader,
then actually nothing would be printed,
because you can only loop
over an iterator once.
Since I want to access
the data multiple times,
I used my one loop to
append each row to a list.
And finally I need to close the file.
Then since this row is
the last row in the cell,
it gets the output in the output area.
And actually this code is a bit
like lengthier than it needs to be
in a couple of ways.
The first is that I can avoid having to
close the file by instead using a with
statement.
When I open the file
using a with statement,
I need to indent everything
that accesses that file.
Then, once the indented block ends,
the file will automatically be closed.
This is closer to how the example code
in the CSV documentation page looked.
And second, there's actually an easier
way to convert an iterator to a list.
Here, by calling list,
I've created a list of the enrollment
data without using a loop.
So now I can delete this line and
this line.
Now I'd like you to write code to
read in the other two CSV files.
And also take a look at the first row
of each file to make sure it worked
properly.
In case you're still getting everything
set up, you'll also be able to
complete this exercise in the Udacity
code editor at the end of this video.
If you do, you can use test run to
see the output of your code, and
submit to see if your
solution is correct.
If you do have everything
set up locally,
then the starter notebook will contain
the codes that I've just written,
as well as some other code
you'll see later in the course.
Find the point marked number 1,
and add your code there.
Make sure you name your variables,
daily_engagement, and
project_submissions, or
some of the later code will not work.