Congratulations on completing Stage 2, and implementing bolts in Python.
You're exploring some of the more advanced concepts of Storm apologies, and
now we're going to add more cool functionality.
In Lesson 3, Stage 4, rather than displaying a word cloud,
what we're going to do is calculate and display the top N words.
In this stage we're going to switch out the rolling CountBolt for
the CountBolt, and we're going to use open source bolts,
the total rankings bolt, and the intermediate rankings bolt.
This is an extremely useful function, and one of the applications is
display the top-N hashtags, that continuously update in real time.
This is a complex assignment that requires some patience to import and
connect successfully.
But this is also an authentic real world assignment that you may
want to use as the basis of a starter project.
Our hackathon groups use this stage as a launching point for
most of their ideas, let's get started.
In part 0, add your credentials to your Tweet Topology, and
rename your Tweet Topology to the TopNTweetTopology.
Next, in part 1 remove the RollingCountBolt, and use the CountBolt.
And as a hint, remember this requires modifications to connect.
Next, import and connect the total rankings bolt, and required dependencies.
At this stage I give multiple hints below in the reading node, to help you
along, but I would really urge you to try working this out on your own first.
This is a realistic experience working with open source tools, and
it requires some trial and error.
Delving into code and finding examples.
Use the hints or
simply check out my approach in Stage 5, if you want further help.
If you're still with me and you want further hints,
one is to use MavinPackage often and learn from build failures.
Mainly to bring in import statements not listed as dependencies.
And then two, after you've duplicated the total rankings bolt, read very
carefully that the total rankings bolt, requires the intermediate rankings bolt,
and that this bolt is configured using a global grouping.
In hint three remember that the tuple schema must match between the count
bolt and the intermediate rankings bolt.
I also suggest connecting the count bolt to the report bolt,
as a type of print statement to test your implementation.
But remember that this connection can fail when the tuple schema is changed.
In hint 4, I give some helpful syntax to connect the ReportBolt to
the TotalTankingBolt if needed.
But remember that since we're using open source bolts with no documentation,
I actually had to look though all the dependencies in order to get this syntax.
Once completed with part one, in part two, visualize your topology and
change the TopN variable you created, to change the number of words to keep.
Displaying TopN words is an extremely useful function, and
one of the applications is, display the TopN hashtags.
We can go from our word cloud that looks like this, to displaying,
say the top 100 words that looks like this, and finally to this,
where we are displaying the top 20 hashtags.
Next, in part three, add a filter using skip words list,
to the parse tweet bolt to skip undesirable words.
What I did was actually use my top N visualization,
to choose the words to skip based on words that come up often in Twitter.
Next, in part four, update the tweet spout to emit hashtags instead of words,
and remember that, hashtags simply begin with the # character.
This is a fairly trivial update, and finally in part 5,
visualize the top end hashtags.
Remember to hit refresh periodically, and you can also use
the Visualization http://127.0.0.1 :5000/basic.
This visualization is simpler, and
can be used as the starting point for some of your project ideas.
But as you can see as the counter updated the size and
location, of our top hashtags move along the screen.
Once you're completed with the top and hashtags, take a screenshot and
post it to the forums,
comment on two other posts and, why not Tweet your image to your followers?
Good luck.