To answer the question of which of these
two data structures you think is better,
I want you to think about the requests
you need to make to display the data
on the two main screens of the app.
Let's look at the active
lists details activity first.
We don't have any items left, but
eventually we do plan to have them here.
So we should be picking
a data structure accordingly.
If you decide to go with Data Structure
A, you simply need to attach a listener
on the list that you're interested in,
such as this list right here and
then that will contain all of the data
that you need to display this screen.
You have all the list properties here
such as the owner and the edit time.
And then you have all of the items,
which I'll display here.
Now with data structure b, you'd
actually need to attach two listeners.
You need to attach one here to
get the shopping list data.
get all the shopping list data.
And you need to attach a corresponding
listener here to get all the shopping
list items.
Now you're retrieving the same amount of
data in Data Structure B as you are in
Data Structure A, but
in Data Structure B it just happens
to be in two different places.
Overall that's an extra listener.
So it looks like Data Structure A is
a better choice for
ActiveListDetail screen.
But let's go ahead and
take a look at ShoppingListsFragment.
On this screen I simply need to
get a list of shopping lists.
If we're looking at Data Structure A and
I attach a listener to active lists,
I would be grabbing all of this data.
And that's great, but
it also includes a lot of item data.
Now looking at the screen,
you might notice there isn't actually
any item data that's displayed here.
So essentially you're
downloading a lot of extra data,
which doesn't sound too great.
In comparison we have data structure B,
and similarly we could attach a listener
to activeLists and
that would grab all of this data.
And because the item data
is separated out down here,
you wouldn't be grabbing
any of that item data.
So in this case Data Structure B is
a much better option because you'd
just receive the data that you need.
And the disparity between how good
Data Structure A is and Data Structure B
just grows bigger as you start to
get more users and more items.
Overall pulling down extra data
is a much bigger deal than making
an extra listeners.
Listeners were built to
be pretty lightweight and
when you're using Data Structure B
on the details page,
you're actually not
requesting any more data.
So Data Structure B turns out
to be the better option overall.