What this program here is part of is
a program that shows an email directory
for the Just Java Coffee Shop.
And employees of the Just Java
Coffee Shop all have email addresses
that are their last name and then a
period, their first name @justjava.com.
Now what the program should be
printing is the employee's name
followed by their email
address in this format.
Let's see if it does that.
Okay, so the first line here is making
a variable called first name and
setting it's value to Lyla.
All right, good.
And then the next line is has a variable
called last name which its creating and
it's setting that to Fujiwara.
Okay, and now we're creating
a variable called contactInfo, and
setting it to something
a little bit more complicated.
Let me just make the variable right now.
Okay, so we're setting it equal to the
concatenation of the value in firstName
plus a space,
plus the value in lastName.
So, first name is Lyla.
Last name is Fujiwara.
And this is going to be
Lyla space Fujiwara.
Okay, looks pretty good.
Now for this next statement,
I want to just say that these two
bits are actually all one line.
So we're taking contact info
which we've already declared, and
resetting its value equal to this.
So let's figure out what this is.
Well last name is Fujiwara,
the value of first name is still Lyla.
Okay so what this is doing is erasing
what was in contact info before, and
now setting it equal to opening bracket,
concatenated with Fujiwara,
concatenated with a period,
concatenated with Lyla,
concatenated with @justjava.com and
then a closing bracket.
So this is the current
value of contact info.
And on this next line here
we display contact info,
meaning that we're going
to display this here, but
this string right here is not
the same as this string right here.
In fact it's only part of the string,
this part.
We're missing the Lyla Fujiwara.
Now, before we changed the string,
it was storing Lyla Fujiwara,
but we sort of overrode it
in this line here when we said it
equaled to a completely different value.
What we really want is
the concatenation of these two.
So if you wanted to fix this program,
you could add right here contactInfo+,
and then all of this.
That would have taken the current
value of contact info, Lyla Fujiwara,
and concatenated it with
the email address in this format.
One other short note,
I am making an assumption that for
our email addresses @justjava.com, it
doesn't matter if this is a capital or
lowercase F or if this is a capital or
a lowercase L.
For many email services that
consumers use, this is true.
For example, for Gmail, this is true.
You can leave this as lower case or
upper case and
it will still reach the same person, but
if you were worried about the difference
here, that's definitely a good catch.
As I've said and I'll say it again,
case really does matter a lot of
the time when we're talking about
anything to do with computers.