How many points?
Well, the answer is 4, which is d.
All right.
Why?
Because we have, well wait a minute, it looks like nine unknowns, right?
It's three by three, but no, you've seen this before.
It's only matters up to a scale factor, right?
I can scale all those entries in the matrix by a constant and
when I map it back out to the non-homogeneous coordinates,
when I divide it out, that scale factor goes away.
So there are eight unknowns, eight degrees of freedom.
Again, I can take four points, the four points of a rectangle, pop them down
here, they don't have to be four points of a rectangle, it's just easier to see.
And once I've mapped four points to four points, assuming I
don't have any weird degeneracies, then I could compute, the homography.
What do I mean about weird degeneracies?
Well here would be one.
We said, that points that start on a line, have to stay on a line.
So, if I took four points that were on a line,
and then I mapped them to four new points that were not on the line,
the system should explode and it would, and your computer would melt and
all that kind of stuff, because, there is no linear solution of this
projection that would map four collinear points into four non-collinear points.
But in general if I have four points distributed spatially and
I put them down and I map them to four other points distributed spatially then
I'm able to compute the homography.
Many times through this class I'm going to ask you, how many points do
you need to compute a homography and I hope at least you'll scream four.
I'm amazed when I do this in class,
I say how many points you need to do amography?
And they don't know, and
it's only been like eight minutes since I did this, so pay attention.