(Peter) So here's Michael Grotik in Barcelona, wants to know, "What kind of computer processing do you need
on an autonomous vehicle? Do you need fancy CPUs and a lot of RAM?"
(Sebastian) Well, you need a lot of processing. We tend to have usually a quad core computer or two on the device.
Most of the processing is actually sensor data, so camera data tends to occupy at least one or two cores of a CPU.
And then exadata, in our case, comes a million points a second, occupies another core.
And then it goes down into the processing needs. So our current (unintelligible) cars can safely live
on a single quad core computer and drive just fine.
It's actually not an exercise in computing. Evaluating a Google instant query takes, I don't know, I'm guessing,
10,000 times as many computers, for a short amount of time, and they're really fast.
It's much more a question of algorithms. To make sure that the computer software actually makes the right decisions
is much harder. So if someone gave us a supercomputer, we actually wouldn't know what to do with it on a car.
So here's by Pravin in Chennai, Indiana--actually, India.
"This is definitely one of the best classes I've ever had. Thank you, instructors. It would be really great
"if you considered doing a class in advanced A.I. What are the research options that can be formulated
"by some of the ideas described in this class?" Peter?
(Peter) Yeah, so they keep on asking for the advanced A.I. class. I guess we'll have to get around to that.
(Sebastian) Do you think there's a message in there, "Let's do it?" (Peter) Yeah, we should do it.
(Sebastian) You know what? I like sleep, I like my family. (Peter) We're going to sleep for a little while,
but then we'll think about getting back to it. (Sebastian) And I love all of you who are seeing this online.
You guys are my heroes. I've received some unbelievable emails that really broke my heart.
I received recently an email from a mother of three children who was raising their kids and doing their midterm exam
with one hand while having a teething child in her other hand, and it was just completely mind-blowing,
what effect this class has had, and how many of you feel so positive about it. I'm really humbled by it.
I just want to express this.
The second part of the question was--let's see, let me scroll up again--
"What are the research options that can be formulated from the ideas described in this class?"
I think we covered, basically we did a short coverage of all of A.I. That's not quite true. There's areas of A.I. that are missing.
Like genetic algorithms and ontologies and knowledge-based systems. And we probably brought to air
some of our personal biases in the direction of the material. But if you go to a modern-day A.I. conference,
like, there's a couple (unintelligible) I'm sharing in 2013, in China, you would find that this is kind of basically
what's happening in the field. And all of those we touched just superficially. So if you read Peter's amazing book,
you'd find in the book alone you get twice, three times as deep a treatment of all of those.
The key thing for researchers, in my opinion, just pick a problem, something that bothers you.
Like if you're walking to your house and you're bothered by the fact that you have to flip on the light switch,
just solve it, okay? If you open your fridge and you have like old produce and you keep forgetting that
the salad only lasts for a week, and you want to make it so that in the future, that your produce doesn't get old,
just solve it. And if you solve this problem through A.I. and you can leverage some of the skills you learned in this class,
and it'll be amazing. (Peter) Yeah. So I agree with that. We talked about that in a lot of office hours,
of just picking out a problem and doing it. I think another way to look at it, though, is you can look at it from the side of,
"What do I want?" or you can look at it from the side of, "What do I have?" and that if you have a lot of data available,
if you have an autonomous car, then do something with that. If you have a copy of the web, then do something
with that data. So you can approach it in either direction, or maybe have the two meet somewhere in the middle.
(Sebastian) And there are so many other options. If you have a smartphone, you can make it learn how fast you walked,
how far you walked. The problem of finding out what the angular orientation is of a smartphone is an open problem,
because compasses aren't very reliable. Little small things sometimes are just really amazing to do A.I. about.
Here's a question from Washington, D.C., by Terry, who's a Stanford alum.
"Thank you for this great experiment." Of course, I love reading these questions. They're all about how great the class was.
"It's been long since my days at Stanford. I'm so proud that my alma mater is doing such pioneering work.
"And makes sure that it should catch up with other institutions." So here's the real question, Peter:
"How does this online teaching experience compare to your regular teaching experience?"
(Peter) Well, like most things in life that are worth doing, it ends up being a lot harder than you ever thought it was going to be.
I thought that doing the online work would be a little bit harder because you've got to prepare the videos,
and if you stumble in the middle of a video, you've got to rewind and do it over again.
What I didn't realize is how hard it is to anticipate what you all are thinking, and try to put that into the video in the right way.
When you're in class and I'm talking and things aren't going right, I can see the puzzled faces,
and then I can back up and try something new. But with the videos, I don't have that immediate feedback.
So I have to anticipate what could possibly go wrong, and try to get that all right the first time.
And so it really leads to a little bit different material in terms of what you teach, and a very different approach
in terms of the quiz questions that we came up with. And I think we were really breaking ground as we were going,
trying to think of what are good mechanisms for coming up with good quiz questions?
And I hope we did okay, and I know we can learn more and do a better job with it next time.
(Sebastian) Yeah, I learned a good number of things. I learned that, I think the digital medium is a much more amenable tool
to interaction than I thought. I got a lot of feedback that even though technically--I'm not really talking to you right now, personally--
But we still got a lot of intimacy in the setting, by asking questions, and we got a lot of engagement
by students solving problems. It was much better than, I think, the Stanford classroom,
where I'm basically just lecturing students and they all get the skill of listening, but they don't get the skill of problem-solving.
In fact, all my Stanford students have extensively watched our online videos, and they all say their experience
is substantially better as a result. So I'm getting to the point of asking, "Why am I lecturing?"
And I might just not lecture again in the same class at Stanford.
The second thing I've learned is that while I'm kind of primed as a teacher to make really hard questions,
and at Stanford we do this a lot, and it's frustrating for the students, I've learned this is much more about
empowering the students, you guys, than showing what a smart question I can ask.
So I've really focused on trying to get material together to make this experience as positive for all of you
as I possibly could. And I'm not sure I succeeded, but I worked really hard.
The final thing I've learned is I get about maybe one invitation per day to give a keynote at a conference,
and I've said no to every single one of them since the class started. And the reason is,
I can fly to India, I can fly to China, I can talk to maybe three, four (unintelligible) 2,000 people.
But talking to 30,000 people is such an amazing (feast). I feel my personal time is much better spent making this class
than pretty much anything I do right now. Possibly with the exception of changing a lot of transportation.
It's been really amazing. I mean to some extent, we're sitting in front of a video camera right now,
and we can't really see all of you. But then we're getting so many beautiful emails and so many beautiful questions
on this forum that I can actually see everyone, and I'm going to try my best to respond to emails.
I haven't responded to every single one of them. But I've often spent an hour or two a day just responding to email.
And we try to respond to you through these questions. It's been really gratifying what kind of scale we can achieve with this new medium.
(Peter) All right. Here's one from Andy in New York. "I made a bot with (Dred), Sonar and Bluetooth for $200
"to do some mapping experiments, and Bluetooth allows processing on a P.C. Did not have laser rangefinders.
"Can you suggest other inexpensive platforms for experimenting?"
(Sebastian) Yeah, there's a company called Neato that does a vacuum cleaning robot, and they built
an insanely cheap laser rangefinder. Rumors have it that the laser rangefinder is made for about $10 apiece.
If you build a robot for $200, that's wonderful. I would love to see more insanely low-cost robots in the market
that people can program and play with. There's Lego Mindstorm, there's a few other kits that people can use,
and they generally tend to be out of people's price range. I think if you had platforms--
In fact, if you had a platform that people could buy for very little money, I'd be much more enticed to teach a robotics class
because I think (unintelligible) could be a really essential experience in robotics.
So (unintelligible) question. Monica in San Francisco, California--hi, Monica, hi, San Francisco--
says, "I've decided to take this class because I studied A.I. in college and used Peter Norvig's book at the time.
"I've been beyond impressed with the enthusiasm and passion of the professors, and the quality of the content.
"Thank you." Not a question. (Peter) You're welcome. That's the answer.
(Sebastian) Garachi in Budapest. "This was definitely one of my best classes ever. I really enjoyed your big picture approach.
"Now it is high time to get my hands dirty programming some of the concepts I've learned.
"Well, after the exam period, that is, and of course, past the holidays, Christmas. Thanks for the awesome experience."
(Peter) You're welcome, too. (Sebastian) Yeah, it's great. Do get your hands dirty. We really regret we didn't
have a programming component, and it's going to happen in the future. (Peter) Yeah.