Here is the code for up heapify, right now it is blank.
Here we have a hip. Now suppose that we insert a
new element. For example, with value nine, this is
the current node. Since we insert in a new element,
the hip propriety may be belated. So to fix that, we
have to ask is the value of this node smaller than the
value of its parent. That’s the case. The property is
belated. So how do we fix that? We just interchange
the values, this becomes nine and this becomes
fourteen. To do this in Python code, we just write this
line to check the value of the current node is smaller
than the value of its parent, that’s true. We just
interchange the values like we did here. Since we
modified the value of this node, the hip property may
be now belated between this node and its parent. So
we set the current node to be this one and we can
do that in Python code like this. Now we again check,
is the value of this node is smaller than the value of
its parent, yes. So we just interchange those values.
Since we have already written code for doing that,
we just need to repeat the same process until this
condition is false or until we reach the red node.