Hi, here's an interview question.
Tell me about a time when
you showed initiative.
And this is how I might answer it.
So this is from back when I
was a senior in college and
working part time at
a software consultancy.
Now we were a bunch of young
engineers eager to get our
hands on real life code, and
we weren't doing a really good job of
documenting our day to day process.
There wasn't a defined rule in
the company for this purpose either.
So I tried to figure out what were
the best practices in terms of tracking
a large scale software project.
For instance,
drawing system design diagrams,
keeping track of functional
requirements, etc, and
making sure that those are in sync with
what was actually being implemented.
I started coordinating these
efforts among our team members, and
started assigning smaller bits
of tasks to different people.
My managers really liked this, and
I was, essentially, working as the team
lead for documentation for
the rest of my time there.
Now this helped us come up
with a better quality product,
avoid communication issues and make sure
that we had a complete documentation for
any future developers to come and
take over our work.
But most importantly, this was a very
enriching experience for me, and
I learned a lot which I probably
couldn't from any textbook or
any software engineering class.