Let's take a broader
view of what we just did.
We have two ingredients here that
are going to lead to an interesting and
crucial abstraction called map.
First we have a set of elements
that we'd like to process.
In our example of this set
is an array of 64 floats.
Second, we have the ability to write
an arbitrary function that runs on one
element in our example.
Our function squared each of its and put
elements producing an output element.
Generically, what we did was apply our
function to each element in the set.
This is a powerful parallel operation.
So, to be precise,
when we talk about this.
We say that we have
an abstraction named map.
It takes two arguments.
A set of elements and
a function that will be applied
to each of those elements.
Map is a key building
block of GPU computing.
Many of the problems you will
solve as a GPU programmer, and
certainly many of the ones in
this class use map operations.
GPUs are good at map for
two main reasons.
One, GPUs have many parallel processors.
The GPU is efficient at
delegating the computation of
individual elements to those processors.
We're going to find out
more about that soon.
Second, GPU is optimized for
throughput rather than latency.
So as a programmer you're probably more
interested in optimizing the rate at
which entire map
operations can complete.
Instead of the time it takes for
any individual element to complete.
And the GPU agrees with you.
Let's also take a look at
the communication pattern for
a map operation.
Maps model is straightforward.
One element in, one element out.
Of the computation of
output element number n,
only dependent on input
element number n.
This is a very simple and
straightforward communication pattern.
Other computations might require
a more complex communication pattern.
And we'll learn about those
patterns over the next few units.
So to make sure we understand
map let's do a little quiz.
Check the problems that can be solved
using a map operation on an input array.
Sort, add one to each element in
the array, sum up all the elements in
the array or compute the average of
the elements in the input array.