Alpha beta is a pruning technique that
allows us to ignore whole sections of
the game tree but still get
the same answer as with MiniMax.
>> So you're saying that alpha
beta never changes the answer but
is more efficient than MiniMax?
>> Precisely,
often it is much more efficient.
Let's take another look
at the MiniMax tree for
level three of the five
move isolation board.
We'll assume that our computer player
is evaluating the game tree from
left to right.
We have five sub trees
that we'll consider.
Looking at the left most one,
the first branch only has two nodes,
with values of one and
two, respectively.
It is the max level, so
we choose the two and
propagate it up to the min level.
>> Since the opponent x, will choose
a branch that minimizes the value,
we know this sub tree will
have a value of two or less.
So that means for any of the remaining
branches as soon as we see a two or more
we could ignore the rest of the nodes
because they will never be selected.
>> Precisely.
>> And we have two's in the left
most nodes of these three branches.
>> Yep.
>> Which means we can ignore
six of these 11 nodes.
Wow, that's going to save some time.
>> It gets even better.
Let's look at the next sub tree over.
And as soon as we get to this
two on the left hand branch,
we know that this whole sub tree
is going to return a two or less.
But we already know that we have
a two from the first sub tree.
So the highest node, we already
know that we'll get a two or more.
That means we can ignore all of
the remaining branches of the second
sub tree.
Going on to the middle sub tree, we
again get a two in the left most node.
We don't have any constraints
on the node above yet.
So we keep exploring and
get another two.
No other valid move is possible,
so this max node returns a two.
Now, the node above is a minimizing
node, so it must return a two or less.
Thus, because we know that the top
most level already has a branch
with a two value, we can ignore all
the rest of the nodes in the sub tree.
>> I see a pattern here.
With the fourth sub tree
we also get a two early on.
Which means we can ignore most of
the nodes in this sub tree as well.
>> And the same thing happens
in this last sub tree.
>> Hold it.
This sub tree's one of the bad moves.
It's value is actually one.
Don't we want our computer
player to know that?
>> Why? As long as we only care about
our computer player selecting the same
good move as it would with
the MiniMax algorithm we are okay.
Here, our computer selects
the left most branch
which is the same as
our MiniMax algorithm.
>> You're assuming that MiniMax
is valuing left to right and
takes the left most
branch in case of a tie.
>> Yep, we're assuming that
our goal was to play the game,
not keep a list of all the equally
good moves on a given level.
>> That's exciting,
looking at the entire tree it seems we
don't need to look at most of the nodes.
We only need to look at 29 of
the 78 nodes on the entire tree.
That will save a lot of time.
>> In fact, while our mini Max's
algorithm runs in b to the d time,
MiniMax with alpha beta pruning
can run b to the d over two time,
if the nodes are ordered optimally
with the best moves being first.
Even with random move ordering,
alpha beta pruning reduces the expected
run time to b to the three quarters d.