Of course, I don't want to just
show a bias towards Microsoft here.
They've done some amazing
stuff in this area.
But of course, Google has also played
into this area recently with all
of their Google Map stuff.
So here, for example,
I'm showing an example from Google Maps,
basically showing the Coliseum in Rome.
They have actually captured,
but more importantly,
citizens have captured and
put up and registered on the scene.
So, again, just looking at the coliseum,
there are lots of pictures available
using sites like
the outside Panoramio and
we can basically look
at different pictures.
And when I can click on it,
I can actually zoom in.
And of course, now I can browse
the scene in a lot of detail.
And of course, if you notice with
this interface as I move around,
it basically either finds a picture and
a best viewpoint for it or
lets me browse around
in the space itself.
And again, just browsing shows you
different images and you can kind of
again, do a little bit of touring
around and see interesting sights.
Now, I want to make sure that people
understand while in the old days,
this was important for
well known sites with a lot of pictures.
But with the growth of cameras,
something we've talked about before in
this class and the availability of,
you know systems like Google Maps,
where they're actually doing
allot of capture themselves.
We can actually do this for sites like
For example, the Georgia Tech campus.
So here now, let me show you a video.
Say, you want to come to Georgia Tech
campus and some of you, of course,
have not been able to.
You can basically now get a tour
of the Georgia Tech campus.
So here basically,
I'm going to first show
the Klaus Advanced Computing building.
If you notice there is a blue mark
where I was, that's my office.
And of course,
I clicked on one of the panoramas.
And now we can see the Clough
Undergraduate Learning Center,
the Van Leer building.
Zooming back out on the map.
Now, I'm going to show a little bit more
detail and actually get into something.
Again, you may have used
called street views.
The Clough's building,
I'm at this dot here in my office.
Loads of different types
of available images.
Here we're going to basically
get on to the first drive.
And again, I'm just going to
put myself on that street.
There.
And we're going to go for a little walk.
Here you basically see these are of
course, images captured by street views.
We'll talk about that in a bit.
But now,
I can actually start moving around.
Again, if you notice there
are lots of pictures here.
Now these pictures have been taken
by a street view camera system.
I'll show you that in a bit.
I'm going out on Ferst Drive, the
biomedical buildings are on this side.
Once I get to Ferst, what I want to do
is I want to have in down Ferst a little
bit more, but I want to actually
come back on Atlantic Drive.
And on Atlantic Drive, we can move up.
This is again Bandolier
from the other side.
Bandolier is of course,
where the electrical engineering and,
electrical and
computer engineering department is.
And this, of course is the College
of Computing building.
And this,
of course is where my office is.