The first thing to do here is to select the view controller by clicking on
this phone frame.
Now, you may have to lean in a little bit to see this tiny blue
border around the phone.
By the way, I could have done the same thing by opening up Document Outline, and
selecting View Controller here.
Okay, let me close Document Outline, and get back to my storyboard.
Okay so notice that there is an arrow that is pointing to our view controller.
Now this arrow means that this is the first or
starting view controller of our app.
Now you can see more information about this if you slide open
the Utilities tray.
Tray, and go to Attributes Inspector, and
in here you can see an option called Is initial view controller.
And that option is checked, which means that this view
controller is the initial or the starting view controller for our app.
If I uncheck this box, notice that the arrow goes away.
Now if I try to run my app, Xcode gives me an error.
It says, perhaps the designated entry point is not set.
How cultured of you Xcode.
Yes, the entry point is in fact not set.
To fix this error, all I have to do is check this box again.
Alright, I'm going to manage screen space so you can see my
story board a little bit better, by sliding out Utility and the debug area.
So after I've selected the view controller, I can go to the Editor menu and
then select Embed In > Navigation Controller.
And voila, we have something new on our screen.
Let me use the pen gesture on my mouse pad to align this properly.
I can also use the pinch gesture, to zoom in and out of the storyboard.
So it seems like the initial view controller has changed.
It is now this thing called the Navigation Controller.
Navigation controller, as its name suggests,
will help us navigate between two different screens on our app.
At this point however, I would love for
you to search for navigation controller in the documentation.
Read through the docs and identify somewhere between one to
three things that you've learned about this new idea.
Here is your challenge one more time.
You can share your ideas with us on the discussion forum, and
can check this box when you are done.