Now that we have our table,
we can start adding rows to the table,
as well as reading and
then manipulating data within it.
So the basic actions to
be performed on the table
can be summarized into one word, CRUD.
Now when I say CRUD,
I'm not referring to the crud on
Tommy's paws when he came in today.
Instead, CRUD is a database
related acronym standing for
create, read, update, and delete.
So let's visualize how these actions
can be taken on the spreadsheet, and
then we can take a look at how we can
use them on the actual table later on.
So starting off with the action create.
So say we have a pet come in,
it's a male seven kilogram
Terrier named Baxter.
He's brought into the shelter.
So to add him to the table,
we simply add another row to the table
containing all his information.
And so
this is considered a create action.
So next up is the read action.
So say the table has filled
up with quite a few pets, and
a client walks in wanting to know if
there are female pets in the shelter.
Well we can sort the column gender, and
then just search for the female pets.
So selecting the rows that we want,
with information that we want,
is considered a read action.
So next up is update.
Maybe we found out that
Baxter is not just a Terrier,
instead he's a Border Terrier.
So what we would do is go to his row,
change his breed entry,
updating that information.
And so this is an update action.
And lastly is our delete action.
If we find out that we've
added a pet by mistake, and
want to remove that pet from our current
list, we can simply delete that row.
So given that our table is
organized like this spreadsheet,
it can be easy to visualize the actions.
So next,
let's a quick look at the different
actions we'll take within our pets app.
And then we can decide which specific
SQLite actions we'll need to learn in
order to accomplish those.