All right, so now we're going to
take what we just learned, and
think about what generalized
MDPs might need.
Generalized Markoff Decision Processes.
So the Bellman Equation for
generalized MDPs looks like this.
Q*(s,a)=R(s,a)+Gamma times
kind of a summish thing
over s prime of a maxish
thing over a prime of Q
star s prime a prime.
So basically all I'm trying to say here,
is that we can take out,
we can substitute various things in for
this plus operator.
And this times operator and
we get different sequential decision
making problems that come out of it.
So just to make sure that you
understand what I'm talking about,
let's do the first one together here.
The first idea here is that
we're going to replace this plus
symbol with a sum over all
s prime of the probability
of reaching s prime times then
whatever function we're plus-ing.
Which in this case is the X thing,
applied to Q star so the X thing here
is written to be the max operator,
so max over all next actions.
Well, it says F S primate prime, but
here we're going to be substituting
in the Q star s prime a prime.
So, if we were actually to do
the substitution in the first line,
put this summation thing
instead of the plus thing, and
this max thing instead of
kind of the times or X thing,
what decision process sort of
thing would we get from that?
>> That's just a regular MDP.
>> Yes,
that's just how I would have said it.
So, it just gives us back the ordinary
Bellman equation for MDPs.
It's just, again, kind of a weird way of
writing it, but the point is that we're
going to allow different kinds of
operators to be substituted in here and
we're still going to get very reasonable
things out, things that we can run value
iteration on, things that we can
run q learning on and so forth.
So, if you think you get that let's
do the rest of this as a quiz.
Basically what I'd like you to do is for
each line here,
if we were to do the substitution,
where the plus operators define here and
the time operators define here,
what kind of decision process
would we get out of that?
>> I think I follow that.
I'm looking over these to make
certain it all makes sense to me.
I think I get what you are saying.
In the regular MDP we have
an expectation over maxes, and
so the first line is basically
an expectation over a max.
So that's what a regular MDP is.
So the next one is a min,
instead of an expectation, over a max.
And then in the third one's
an expectation over a peordida.
>> Oh yeah, sorry.
I just made up some notation there.
Let me explain what that means.
So, the basic idea is that we're
going to take a weighted combination of
all the actions and the weights
depend on the rank of the action.
And in particular we can have
a weight for the max and a weight for
the min and a weight for
the second largest,
the third largest, the fourth largest,
and those weights are consistent.
They're going to be just a constant.
>> Oh, okay.
Does that imply that we have,
no matter where we are,
we have the same number of actions?
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
Is there any relationship
between those weights?
They can be negative, they can be a
million, they can be anything you want?
>> Oh, sorry.
Yeah, good.
So the row of the weight for
a given rank should be It
should be a convex combination.
They should all sum to one and
be non-negative.
>> Okay, okay, okay.
Sure.
So it's like doing an expectation but
based on how good the action is.
Sort of.
>> Yeah where it falls in the list yeah.
So this actually generalizes
the first line max.
Because max is what we get if we put the
row of the largest rank to be one and
the row everything else to be zero.
But it also let's us get min right.
Where we have the row of
the smallest rank equal to one and
everything else zero.
And everything in between, like
uniform waiting over all the actions.
>> Okay, I think I've got it.
And let's see.
Let's double check the last one.
The last line,
certification over minimax.
I think I know what that means, okay.
>> Well, just to make sure.
So it's a little bit weird.
I'm kind of abusing notation here,
because minimax is usually defined when
you've got two different actors,
kind of a player one and a player two.
And here I'm just writing
it as if it were one actor.
But, you should think of it as,
this a prime represents a joint
action by the two players.
>> All right.
Okay, I think I got it or at least
got it enough to work it through.
>> All right.
Why don't you give it a shot, and
if you don't get exactly the way I
was thinking about it, that's okay.
It's mostly to just sort of get you
thinking about how we're substituting in
different pieces to get
this generalized MDP.
>> All right, I like it.
Okay, go.