Let's keep expanding the nodes in
order until we have fully expanded
level three of our tree.
As we see, some nodes have two children,
others have three.
Even so, we see that the exponential
growth of the children makes it
increasingly difficult to display
the full tree on the screen at once.
In level four it is x's turn.
Again we expand the tree completely.
Scrolling through the tree shows how
increasingly dense it is getting.
Level five gets a bit more interesting.
In the left node's branch
o has one final move.
However, in the next
branch x has blocked o in.
O has no move and the game ends.
To indicate that our computer
player has lost in this situation,
we will mark this node with a -1.
Expanding level five completely, we see
that one branch looks particularly dire
for our computer player,
as it has many losing situations.
Even worse, the opponent has control
of the board at the level above.
We have to find a way to
warn our computer player
from making a move that
leads to this branch.
By level six there are no moves
left anywhere on the board.
All games have ended.
The ones where o wins
we will mark with a +1.
The ones where o lost on level five,
we've already marked with a -1.
Now that we have seen all the possible
futures of the game, we'll back
propagate this knowledge to our computer
player so we can make a wise first move.