What is a camera or an imaging system?
So simple definition is,
it's some device that allows the projection of light from three dimensions,
three dimensional points, to some medium that will record the light pattern.
That medium can be film or it can be a sensor, etc.
But actually the key word to all of this is projection.
So here's a projection.
Some people walking on a sidewalk.
And there's this globe like thing in the middle.
And something that might convince you that something is a little strange might
be there's a tiny little guy standing on top of the world this was
a pre-clip for the movie Titanic.
That was a joke.
Tiny little guy.
Leonardo DiCaprio's not so big.
Okay anyway.
What's really in that picture is that.
Okay? And the reality is this picture wasn't actually the projection that
you thought it was.
At least some of you.
So you thought maybe it was like this ball thing that
you were looking at in an image.
And no, actually,
it was a flat thing that happened to be projecting into the camera.
And that gives you an idea that when you do projection somehow you're
losing information, you're losing three dimensions,
a third dimension you go from three to two.
And we have to figure out what went on in that third dimension