Here's a state space diagram for
a simple problem.
It involves a room with two locations,
the left we call A and
the right we call B.
And in that environment there's
a vacuum cleaner, and there may or
may not be dirt in either
of the two locations.
And so that gives us eight total states.
Dirt is here, or not here, or not, and
the vacuum cleaner is here or here.
So that's 2 times 2 times
2 is 8 possible states.
And I've drawn here the states based
diagram with all the transitions for
the three possible actions.
And the actions are moving right, so
we'd go from this state to this state.
Moving left,
go from this state to this state.
And sucking up dirt we go from this
state to this state, for example.
And in this state space diagram,
if we have a fully deterministic, fully
observable world, it's easy to plan.
Say we start in this state and
we want to end up in a goal state
where both sides are clean.
We can execute the suck dirt action and
get here, and then move right, and then
suck dirt again, and now we end up in
a goal state where everything is clean.
Now, suppose our robot vacuum
cleaner's sensors break down.
And so, the robot can no longer proceed
neither which location it's in or
whether there's any dirt.
So we now have an unobservable,
or centralist,
world rather than
a fully observable one.
And how does the agent then
represent the state of world?
Well, it could be in any
one of these eight states.
And so all we can do to represent
the current state is drop a circle or
box around everything, and say,
I know I'm somewhere inside here.
Now, that doesn't seem
like it helped very much.
What good is it to know that we
don't really know anything at all?
But the point is that we can search
in the state space of belief states
rather than in the state
space of actual spaces.
So we believe that we're in one
of these eight states, and now,
when we execute an action, we're
going to get to another belief state.
Let's take a look at how that works.
[BLANK_AUDIO]