So this is how I did it.
Inside get I am just using fetch,
in fact,
this whole object here with
method get is totally optional.
If there are no options fetch
assumes that you're doing a get, so
you can just get rid of it.
Here in getJSON, I simply then'd off
the get and then return response.json.
This whole response.json is
specific to the fetch API,
but it's basically
the same as json.pars.
To test I'm getting the json and then
if it's there, I'm adding the query to
the SearchHeader, if it's not I'm adding
unknown and console.log and the error.
Don't let me forget to console.log,
the response.
Let's see if it works.
So far so good,
I'm seeing earth-like planets.
And when I open up the console,
I see the response logged out with
the query and some more JSON files.
That's pretty cool but
I want to show you one more trick.
I just switched out the .catch for
another .then.
I could have left the .catch there,
actually but
I just got out of it to
keep this looking short.
Anyway, so from the original .then,
I am returning some results.
In fact, this is the first
URL in the search results.
Then, in this then, I am taking
the URL and console.logging it.
The cool thing here is
that I've got then and
then another then, which means
I'm chaining promises together.
So what happens here?
Now inside the console,
after the whole search object,
I'm seeing the URL of the first
planet in the response.
This whole idea of chaining
is incredibly important, and
that's what you'll be
doing next in the course.