Here, you can see my
GeofenceTransitionsIntentService and
this extends the base
IntentService class.
In it, I've defined a TAG, which is
just a string, called gfservice.
I've created a constructor,
which has the same name obviously,
GeofenceTransitionsIntentService.
And I super the TAG.
I've created an onCreate
override function, and in that,
I just called super.onCreate.
And then finally, I've created this
protected void, onHandleIntent,
and I'm passing it an intent called
Intent, and returning a void.
There's a lot of code in here and
we'll see how to build that in
the next steps and what that does, but
this is how you get started with your
GeofenceTransitionsIntentService.