In this problem, we're again in the 2-location vacuum world,
but this time around, we have local sensing,
meaning at each turn, we get input of what location we're at,
the left or the right, and whether there's dirt in that location.
But we don't know what's going on in the other location.
We have a dynamic world where dirt can appear anywhere.
As we move around, dirt can spontaneously appear
in the location we left or in the location we're going to visit.
However, if we're sucking, the dirt can't appear,
because if it did appear there, we would successfully suck it up.
And now in addition, the right and left moves
are stochastic in that they don't always succeed.
Sometimes when you try to go right, you do successfully go right,
and sometimes you stay in the same location, same for left.
The suck action is always successful.
It will always clean up dirt in the current location.
Now, when we start out, we get the percept
saying that we're in the leftmost location
and that location is clean, and that means our belief state
is that we're in either 5 or 7.
Now, the first thing I want you to answer is if we decide to move right,
what do we predict the possible belief state will be,
the possible set of states in our belief state will be
after we execute the right movement?