Lorenzo's first response
was pretty good.
He started out by listing all
the details that I provided to him and
noting down the base rule.
Now, in some sense you could solve this
problem without applying the full base
rule but it was a good decision in the
end for him to use it in full effect.
He did fumble in one place where
he used a slightly incorrect
form of the base rule but
he corrected himself quickly and
the mistake that he made could have led
him to a shorter route to the solution.
But it's important to note that these
shortcuts don't always work out so
it's safer to apply the full rule or
algorithm or formula, as you know it.