There are some other options you
can configure in your tracker
configuration file.
For example,
you could set the session timeout.
And the session is a pretty
integral concept to Analytics.
And the session timeout indicates how
long the app can be in the background
before Analytics consider
the current session to have ended.
I'm not going to go over all
these parameters now, but
you can read about them at your
leisure in the developer docs, and
the link to that is in
the instructor notes below.
One quick thing I do want to say is that
we already looked at the tracking ID,
but if you want to stop sending data to
Analytics, the easiest and quickest way
to do it is just to take your
analytics ID our of the tracking ID.
Now it's your turn to create
the tracking configuration file for
your app.
Create a new XML resource file called
tracker_app.xml in the res > xml folder.
Don't forget, you may need to create the
xml folder if it doesn't already exist.
And of course, you can call your
config file whatever you like.
It doesn't have to be tracker_app.xml.
That's just a good name.
And make sure that the root
element is resources.
Set your account ID, and you do that
with the ga_trackingId parameter.
And then enable auto tracking,
and you do that with
the ga_autoActivityTracking parameter.
And don't forget to set it to true.
And then finally, add the screen name
tags for the activities in your app.
And check off each of these boxes
when you've completed the tasks.