Hello and welcome to lesson Two of the programming in Java Course. We're
going to start a discussion with objects to understand why you might want to
know about objects. consider someone that is building a house. It used to be in
the olden days that a house was built from nothing but bricks and wood.
Nowadays, of course, a builder takes prefabricated components such as this
furnace or this water heater and puts them together. You can think of those as
the analogue of what an object would be in a programming language. An object is
a building block of a program. It is a component with some desired
functionality. Just as the water heater over here has some desired
functionality for the builder it heats water. In your programs you ask objects
to do work. You don't know how they do that and that's okay. Just like if you
really think about it do you actually know how a water heater does it's job? Or
for that matter, do you care? Here we have a different kind of water heater, a
solar water heater and it doesn't really matter how a water heater works as
long as it heats water. With an object what's important what it does, not how
it does it. That's all very abstract, and, the way one really learns about
objects, is to play with them. And I'll show you how you can play with some in
BlueJ.