Good question.
I would have to say my
favorite food is pancakes.
How about you, Tommy?
[SOUND].
I really like cheese too.
You know where they have
really good cheese?
The fridge at Udacity.
Don't worry, I can sneak you some later.
>> Catherine where have you been?
I've been looking for you all day.
>> Sorry I was just talking
with my new best friend Tommy,
we have a lot in common.
>> Okay that's great but Sue and I
are ready to get started on lesson four.
>> Yeah we still have to finish the app
sorry, what are we doing again?
>> In the previous lesson we
learned about content providers and
now we're getting ready
to start using them.
This lesson we're going to focus on
using CursorLoaders to load data from
the database on a background thread,
and this will keep our app responsive.
>> That kind of sounds hard.
>> Well, it won't be too bad.
Loaders remember Chris and Joe covered
them back with quick report app.
>> Yeah, so the student already
knows then that's fine.
>> Yep, and we'll also be covering
CursorAdapters to display results
from a cursor into the list view.
And this will give us a properly
formatted list of pets.
>> Okay good that catalog activity
was a real eye sore to look at.
>> What Catherine I
thought you liked it?
Well we'll also use CursorLoaders in the
editor activity and so for an existing
pet we can load their details from
the database directly onto the UI.
>> So then you can update the pet and
then save it in the database?
>> Mm-hm exactly.
>> Okay.
>> And lastly we'll figure
out how to delete a pet.
>> Nice, so then all of the features
of the app will be done?
>> Yep, that is the goal.
We have a lot to do.
Let's get started.
>> But I want to finish my coffee first.
>> Katherine.