When dealing with strings in Java,
an important concept to understand
is string concatenation.
Now that's a really big word, but
it just means we're joining character
strings together end to end.
If this is a string and
this is a string,
you can combine them by concatenating
them to make an even longer string.
To concatenate these strings together,
we use the plus operator.
This is the same addition
symbol that we know from math.
Just like you can add numbers together,
you can concatenate strings together.
Let's look at an example.
Say I have three different strings,
one string literal says I need,
another string literal
says 2 cups of coffee,
and another string
literal says on Monday.
I can use the plus symbol to
concatenate all these strings together.
That forms a ginormous string that
says I need2 cups of coffeeon Monday.
Whenever I see something like this,
I imagine the plus symbols are gone, and
I imagine the quotes are gone, and
I just imagine literally squishing
all of these things together.
And when I say squished,
we're really squishing them together.
There's even no extra space in
between this string and this string.
If you want to add a space here,
you would have to explicitly add a space
in this string literal at the end of it,
or you add a space at the beginning
of this string literal.
Same with coffeeon Monday.
I want a space here, so I'd have to
either add it at the end of this string
or the beginning of this string.
I added a space here and
a space here, so
when I concatenate all of this together,
I squish them together, and the sentence
comes out correct like this.
There's a space here and a space here.
Adding spaces in the right place is
a little bit tricky because you have
the quotation marks everywhere and
the plus symbols, and
there's even spaces
around the plus symbol.
But these spaces around the plus
symbol don't contribute
to the overall display string.
The space must be inside
the double quotes.
Here's an example of string
concatenation in our app.
I'm going to change the text so
that it says "Amount due " + "$10".
I'm concatenating this string
literal with this string literal.
When I run it on my device, and
then I hit the order button,
then I see Amount Due $10.
You can also concatenate strings
with integers like I have here.
Before, the ten was in quotes so
that was a string representation
of the number ten.
But here I just have 100 without quotes,
so this is the integer value for 100.
If I concatenate a string
with an integer,
then it immediately turns this
whole thing into a string.
If I hit the Order button, then I
see $100 showing up on the screen.
In a moment, I'll have you play around
with string concatenation to try
different values.
You could get compile errors,
so be careful of those.
If I forget a closing quote,
I could get an error.
In a moment, I'll have you play
around with string concatenation and
try different values.
According to Android
code style guidelines,
we should have a space before and
after each operator.
And this string concatenation
operator counts as an operator.
Now it's your turn to
practice in your app.
Experiment with combining different
strings using the plus operator.
You can also combine it with
integer literal values as well.
Once you feel comfortable
with string concatenation,
I want you to answer these questions.