So now that we have seen how Tomasulo's algorithm works and what the structures
are and so on, let's go through a long example that kind of helps you do things
on exams when we ask you kind of, do Tomasulo's algorithm for a few cycles,
let's see how to do that. I conveniently came up with tables like this so
that I don't have to draw everything by hand. Here we
have the characteristics of our processor basically this is that the load unit
takes two cycles to execute the load. Add takes two cycles to execute adds and
subtracts. Multiplication will take 10 cycles and divide will take 40 cycles and
they're done in the multiplication unit and the initial content of R2, R3, and
R4 are like this. This the table that gives us our
instructions in order like this so this is the very first instruction.
Here we will note in which cycle which instruction issues begin execution and
writes the result. This is basically a graph.
This is where we will say what cycle we are currently in and
this is our reservation stations. These are the two load reservation stations,
these are the three reservation stations for
the adders and this is the multiplication units reservation stations.
The load reservation stations are all really going to be our load queue so
they're going to be slightly different from the others.
Here we will just check when the instruction is in a reservation station.
This is going to be what the operation is. This is where we
restored the value that we have for this operand. This is the value for
the second operand. This is what we are waiting for in the first operand,
this is what we are waiting for for the second operand. And this is
whether the instruction has been dispatched, so that we can keep track of it.