Now the final step in the My Favorite
Movies app is adding the ability to
add and remove favorites.
And this is what'll happen when we
click this favorite button here.
If it's not selected and we click it,
then a movie will be added as a favorite
and if it's showing up as blue like for
this movie.
And we click it, it should remove
it from our Favorites list.
And this is going to require us to
use our first HTTP post request.
In the code, the button that we've
been clicking is connected to
the toggleFavorite action in
the movieDetail view controller.
Here at the top of the method we have
a constant that's commented out.
So let's uncomment this.
And it's called shouldFavorite.
This constant determines whether
the request that we're going to make
is going to set the favorite to true or
false, or add or
remove it from our favorites list.
Then we have the familiar seven
steps that you'll be implementing.
Also, at the bottom in a comment
section, I have the UI updates that
you'll want to perform after
the request is completed.
Now, because this is a post request,
some things are going to be different.
I highly recommend that you
look at the documentation for
the account id favorite method, and use
its example code as a starting point.
The changes aren't that drastic and
I think you'll be okay.
Also, I'll give you two other hints.
First, you'll need to use the movie
property of
the MovieDetailViewController.
This property is going to be important
as one of the parameters that you'll
send in the JSON body.
Second, when you parse the data for
this request, you'll need to check for
th status code.
And the status code is
returned in the results, and
this will help you determine whether
the request was successful or not.
If you are favoriting a movie,
then the status code you want
to see is either 1 or 12.
But if you're unfavoriting a movie
the status code you'll want is 13.
If you want to find out more information
about status codes like these,
I'll post a link in the instructor notes
because these are not the only status
codes that could be returned
by the movie database.
When you're finished implementing the
toggle favorite method check this box.