In our provider query code, let's write
the case for a single task with ID.
To select a row of data by its ID,
we'll use the selection and
selection args parameters
of the query method.
First we'll have to get
the row ID from the past MURI.
The URI will look similar
to the tasks directory URI.
It'll start with the same scheme
authority and tasks path.
But this time also with an ID
as the last part of the path.
And we can grab this ID by using a call
to get path segments on that URI.
And get with the index one passed in.
Index 0 would be the tasks
portion of the path.
And index 1 is the segment
right next to that.
And I'll store this ID in
a string variable named ID.
Then let's create our selection and
selection args for this ID.
I'll create variables mSelection and
mSelectionArgs to hold these values.
The selection will be the string _id=?.
And this is just the default name of
the ID column, _id, in our tasks table.
Followed by an equal sign and
a question mark.
The question mark indicates
that this is asking for
the rest of this equality from
the selection args parameter.
And the selection args should be the row
ID which we just got from the past NURI.
And selection args has to
be an array of strings,
even if it's an array with
just one value in it.
So again, our selection is the string of
the ID column followed by an equals and
a question mark.
And our selection args is an array
that holds the value of the row ID.
And finally we'll put this selection and
the selection args into the same
query code we used before.
This time with the desired
row ID criteria.
That completes this
task with ID case and
you can change the selection parameters
to filter any of the data you return.