So speaking of the algorithm, let's take a look at it.
So we're going to use the polar parameterization of the line,
the polar representation.
And something called a Hough Accumulator Array, which is just a fancy word for
the thing that's going to collect the votes.
You're basically going to have an array, two dimensions in this case, that where
the bins represent different values of d and different values of theta.
One of the things you'll have to decide, and
by the way you'll be implementing this, is how big are the bins?
How many of them are there?
So if it goes from 0 to let's say 0 to pi,
well if you have every one degree then there'd be 180 bins, if you had ever
10 degree there'd only be 18 so you have to decide how big the bins are.
So given this equation and the Hough Accumulator Array, here is the algorithm.
And I hope you appreciated that I tried to color code this.
It looks garishly ugly but it tries to keep everything clean.
So, the basic Hough algorithm is this.
You initialize your accumulator rate to zero everywhere, then, for
every edge point, aha, so we have to have a set of edge points.
That is, at every place in x, y,
we have to know whether it's an edge point, or we have a list of them.
Somehow, we know which points are edges, in fact, how do we know we know that?
Because we did that last time, right?
So you know how to do this in MATLAB or Octave or
your can write it in assembly code if you were really masochistic.
So for each edge point x, y, what we do is, so here I use theta from 0 to 180,
that's you know, supposed to be 1 degree increments.
All right, solve for d.
We just use that equation since we have x and y and
we have theta we can solve for d.
But notice, I'm not doing anything to restrict d being positive or
negative here, so it could be positive, could be negative.
And I have to then set H of d, theta, I have to increment its vote.
So if d is negative, what that means is, what I really mean is,
the bin of that d.
So maybe my d goes from minus 100 to 100.
So I would have 201 bins, if I do them by steps of 1, so
if I got a minus 20, I'd have to add 100, that'd be 80.
You, you get what I'm saying, right?
The, the d value goes into its bin, so
the bin of that D value gets incremented by one.
After you've done all the voting you find the values of d and
theta, where H of d of theta is a maximum.
So you want to find these peaks.
By the way, MATLAB there's a function called Hough Peaks, which by the way,
you're not going to be allowed to use,
because you're going to have to write your own peak finder.
All right.
Well anyway, let's assume you found just one d in theta, well the,
the line itself would be d is equal to x cosine theta minus y sine theta.
Get it? That's all there is to finding these lines given the edge points.