[Norvig] The answers are, in this case, only the second is a correct representation.
Any combination is possible to be dialed.
It's not the case that it's only possible to dial the correct combination.
Now, here we said that the lock button works at any point.
Whether it's open or not, the lock button will always lock it.
And so that's represented by the third option.
True implies it's possible to lock.
In this case the first one is a correct representation
of the successor state axiom for Open,
and the second one is not, because note what it says.
If we already have the lock open and then we execute some dialing action
that's not dialing the correct combination, X, we want it to remain open.
But this second axiom would make it be closed, which is not what we want.