Hold on, we said that end queens was
a constraint satisfaction problem, but
we covered that in the last lesson
using genetic algorithms, or
hill climbing algorithms,
to solve the problem.
>> That's right.
We can randomly assign
values to the variables and
iteratively improve the assignments
until we come to the solution.
>> Like our previous example with
four queens, while there were four to
the four, which equals 256 possible
states, we can quickly find
the solution by minimizing the number
of attacks with each improvement.
>> In fact,
this minimizing conflict method can
solve nqueens with n equals 10 million.
In the million queen's case,
this min-conflicts algorithm can solve
the problem in an average of 50 moves.
>> Wow!
I guess that's because there's a large
number of solutions to the problem.
>> Yup!
Iterative improvement algorithms work
well when they are many solutions and
where there are very few.
However, there are problems with the
number of constraints versus the number
of variables hit a certain ratio, and
the problem is very hard to solve.
>> Well,
then let's just stick to the easy one.