Alright, this one is going to be tough.
In this exercise we're going
to let Gigagal start jumping.
First, by making her fall.
Then, by making sure she
doesn't fall through the floor.
And finally,
the hardest part is deciding what to do
in response to the jump
key being pressed.
Should Gigagal start jumping,
continue a jump she already started or
is Gigagal falling and therefore
we shouldn't do anything at all?
Stick with it though,
because the result is way too much fun.
It's up to you now.
You've got the set up, the constants
that determine how jumping works
like how strong gravity is and
how high Gigagal should jump.
Set up the jump state enumeration
that determines whether Gigagal is
on the ground,
currently jumping, or falling.
Then sort out how to transition
amongst those states.
Finally, just jump around.