When we put an app on
the Google play store,
we'll have a whole range of users.
It's hard to anticipate what type of
device or app we'll be running on?
Maybe a phone or a tablet, maybe an
older version of the Android platform or
maybe a different language
than what we're using.
There are many best practices that you
can follow when building your app,
to make it work well for
all these types of users.
One best practice is
to localize your app.
There's a handy localization
checklist that you can refer to.
Localization means adapting your app to
different locales, meaning language and
country combinations to make it
a positive user experience for
all types of users.
At the surface level this can have
an impact on the design of your app
as well as the texturing
that appear in your app.
For now we're going to focus on how we
can make your app support different
languages.
First let look at the device
experience from a user's perspective.
If I prefer to use a different language
I can go into the settings app, and
then tap on the language and
input setting.
If I tap on language,
then I see the whole list of languages
that are supported on Android.
It includes character based languages,
like Chinese, and
right to left languages, like Arabic.
I'm going to change
the language to Spanish, and
just like that, all the text
is now showing up in Spanish.
You can see this across
the whole settings app.
If you check the others apps on the
device, those will appear in Spanish if
the developer chose to
support that language.
However, when you open
up our just Java app,
it's a jarring experience
because everything in this
app is still in English, while the other
apps on the device are in Spanish.
So how do we make our
app support Spanish?
So far, we know that our app can
contain Java files and resources.
We can provide default resources for our
app, but we can also provide alternate
resources depending on the user's
physical device size, language setting,
version of Android, or number of
pixels on the screen, to name a few.
In our dress Java app, we can provide
default text strings in English.
We can provide alternate text
strings in other languages.
So if someone has French as
a default language on their device,
the system will automatically
load the French translations
instead of the default English ones.
This article explains how you can
support multiple languages in an app.
Scrolling down you can look
at the project structure.
Within the res directory, you can add
another sub directory that contains
resources for a certain language.
This is a default values folder,
and we're choosing to put all
the English text strings here.
In the value's ES folder,
we have all the Spanish text strings.
In the value's FR folder,
we have all the French translations.
If the user chooses Spanish as
the language on their device,
then the system will load these
resources from the value's ES folder.
If this folder didn't exist,
then the system will just fall
back to the default resources.
If the user has French as default
language on their device,
than this system will
load these resources.
By the way, ES is the language code for
Spanish and FR is the language code for
French.
Android uses the ISO language codes.
Here's some examples of languages and
the two letter language codes
that correspond with them.
Let's go back to implementation details,
in order for
the system to switch out different
translations for the text in our app,
we need to isolate all the text from
all the other logic in our app.
We do this by creating a strings.xml
file in the values folder.
This is an xml resource file
that contains a list of
all the string resources that
are visible to the user.
This is the first time we're
seeing xml be used for
something other than defining a layout.
This is defining a list of resources.
This is one string resource, and
the name that we use to
refer to it is called title.
And the value of this
string is My Applications.
This is another string resource and
we refer to it using hello_world,
and actual value is hello world.
Then, in the values-es folder, we can
create a strings.xml file, but now,
these have the Spanish translations
of those same strings.
This string resource still goes
by the name of title like here.
But now, the value is Spanish
translation of my application.
The same applies for
the hello world string resource with
the Spanish translation here now.
And this is one more example
of the French translation of
the strings.xml file.
Once our strings
are declared as resources,
we can then refer to them in the XML or
Java using the appropriate syntax.
In the Java code,
we refer to strings like this.
In the Java code, this is how
we reference string resources.
First, we call the method getResources
to get the app's resources.
And then we call get string, and we pass
as input the resource ID of this string.
In this case it's R dot string
dot hello underscore world.
String is the resource type and
hello underscore world is
the name of the resource.
All of this on the right hand side ends
up becoming the hello world string and
it's stored in this string variable.
This whole expression evaluates to hello
world and gets stored in this variable.
By the way, this is similar to how we
refer to image resources in the Java
code using r.drawwell.photo, or
whatever the name of the image is.
In the XML, we can refer to the strings
using the @string notation and
then the name of the string resource.
Now the XML and
the Java code can stay the same,
regardless of what language the user
has chosen on their device.
We don't need a different layout file
that has the Spanish translation for
the text attribute here.
Android will load
the correct translations,
depending on the primary
language selected on the device.
Pretty awesome, huh?