Here's some code and
it's also from the Firebase
documentation on how to log a user in.
And you might notice that this is
incredibly similar to the code for
making a new user.
We start by making a reference.
We then call the authWithPassword method
on that reference, and we can pass in
data from the UI, such as the email
here and the password over here.
Now as our third parameter
we have a authResultHandler.
And instead of calling on Success or
on Error, we have onAuthenticated or
onAuthenticationError.
Now onAuthenticated gets called when
everything just sort of goes fine
with your authenticating.
The user gets signed in and
at this point you have access
to this fancy authData object.
And besides just having access
to the authData object,
Firebase also knows that you're
logged in, which is important for
the permissioning rules which
we'll talk about in version .5.
The AuthData object has a bunch
of really useful methods.
I'll talk about a few of them here.
You can use AuthData.getUid
to get a unique user ID
that is associated
with your user account.
The user ID is the first thing you
should think of if you're trying to
exactly identify who this user is.
Now, email is also good for the purposes
of identifying exactly who the user is,
at least in our case,
because both Google Login and
the email password provider accounts
will have emails associated with them.
So you might be wondering how you get a
hold of email from the AuthData object.
Well, the getProvider data method
returns a map of data specific to
the provider that you're using.
And for the email password provider,
that includes the email
the user inputted.
So you could get the email by doing
AuthData.getProviderData.getEmail.
So when you're using
the email password provider,
you can get the email by using
getProviderData.getEmail.
You can also get other things
from the getProvider data map,
such as a link to
a gravatar profile image.
I've included some information about
Gravatar images in the instructor
notes below.
But basically it'll give you a link to
a generic profile image of the user.
And it'll give a sort of pixelated
face if they haven't set a Gravatar
profile pic.
So in your app, if you ever
wanted to use profile pictures,
this would be a way to
get ahold of something.
And getProvider is another method
that you might need to use.
It tells you how the user logged in.
Right now you're going to be setting
up login through a email and
password provider.
But there's also Google,
Twitter, Facebook, and GitHub.
But you only get access to all
of this AuthData information
if your login went successfully.
If there was an error,
such as the extremely common one of
accidentally typing either your email or
password wrong, onAuthenticatedError
would get called instead.
And you can handle this in a similar
way to how you handled errors with
user creation.
What I'd like for the shopping list plus
plus app is that you do the same thing
where you call set error on one of
these input texts over here to instruct
the user how to correct
whatever they've done wrong.
Okay, I'm drafting up the spec and
we'll send it over right away.
But in the mean time,
could you do me a favor and
look up what Firebase error is returned
if the user mistypes their password?
Also, what errors return if
they mistype their email?
You can find a link to the Firebase
errors Java doc in the instructor notes.