So here we can see my app and a couple
of the modifications that I've done.
First of all,
there's the AndroidManifest.xml.
I've added the uses-feature for OpenGL.
I've added the meta-data for
the Google services.
I've also added the meta-data For
the API key.
As I scroll across you can see API_KEY,
and here's my API key that I got for
the Google developers console.
I can show in a moment where I
configured the Google developers console
for this app.
I've set my permissions, and you can see
them here, INTERNET, ACCESS_NETWORK, and
WRITE_EXTERNAL_STORAGE.
And that's pretty much it.
It's very straightforward.
In the Google developer's console, I can
look at the Google developer's console.
And if I click Edit
allowed applications.
And I scroll down.
I have a number of
applications that I've filled.
But this one is called maps3_6.
And I've just added the SHA1 key,
followed by a semicolon,
followed by the name of the application.
And when I did that,
I was given this API key, here.
You can see it begins with AIza and
ends with Drz8 and
when I go back to my manifest file I
can see that key is present right here,
beginning with AIza ending with Drz8.
So that's what I had to do to
set up the application to run.
Now in my activity.
Now in my layout I've added a fragment.
And it's typed
com.google.android.gms.maps.StreetViewP-
anorama.
And I've called it streetviewpanorama,
simply.
So next we're going to update
the code behind our main activity
to handle this fragment and
to draw the street view for us.