So, to conclude this sub-lecture,
let's look at what we looked at in the last few minutes.
Basically, introduced how sines and cosines can be used to reconstruct a signal.
Used that to construct and
characterize the whole concept of a Fourier Transform, and
talked about terms like frequency, amplitude, and phase.
Introduced the whole concept of frequency domain for a signal and an image.
And then identified the whole concept of how similar types of things,
convolution, and being able to look at different frequencies can be used to
actually use a Fourier Transform, doing the kinds of things we want to do.
Next, what we'd like to do is start looking at how we can merge and
blend different images together.
Remember our initial experiment with trying to do this?
We want to be able to take different images and merge and blend them together.
What we want to also do is start looking for how to do this at different
frequencies, so we can merge the frequencies of the image correctly for two
images, again, based on similarities of the frequencies for those two images.
You'll see examples of this in the next lecture.
And just to conclude again, some more information is available on these sites,
and it'll be made available also on the class website.
Thank you.