Now, what we are really interested in is finding within these two
images with all the transformations some features that
are common that would allow us to do any kind of matching.
So our goal is to find points in an image that can be found in other images.
Again, I've just showed you an example of this,
point being found in another one.
They need to found precisely, that means they need to
be well localized exactly where they would be across the two images.
But also, they need to be reliably found.
That they need to be, again, quite well matched.
If I was to take all of this neighborhood around the circle here,
they need to have the same neighborhood here.
So if I was to run different types of operations on both of them
we'd basically get similar answers.
So again, they need to be reliable, they need to be easily detectable.