Here is the answer, in an asymptotic
sense is basically just a constant, why?
First note that the algorithm does
n cubed work, what about transfers?
Start by considering the reads of A.
The read is a vector of length n
elements which you repeat n times.
So for A only that's n squared reads.
Next, let's look at C.
There's a read and
a write of one element each.
These are repeated a total
of N squared times.
So our tally of transfers now
increases to three N squared.
Lastly, there is B.
The algorithm reads N elements
of B N squared times.
That's N cubed reads.
Thus, it's the reads of B that
dominate the overall transfer cost.
And since the intensity is the ratio
of operations to transfers,
the intensity is constant.
An interesting question to ask yourself
at this point is, can you do better?
I hope your intuition says, yes.
in particular, there are n-cubed
operations but only n-squared data.
That suggests there might be
a factor of n reuse available.