Together we walk through how to add a
breakpoint for the increment method and
how to trigger that breakpoint.
Hopefully you were able to
reproduce that on your computer.
For the decrement method,
if we want to add a breakpoint,
I can just click here on
line 33 to add a breakpoint.
Then I click on this green bug icon
to launch the app in debug mode.
I'll see the Waiting For
Debugger message,
and then it will go away shortly.
To trigger this breakpoint,
I'm going to click on the minus button.
The app pauses at this line, and
I know that because the quantity
value hasn't updated to one yet.
I see the list of variables down here,
but
the quantity variable
hasn't shown up yet.
I click on this button to step over
this line to go to the next line.
Then I see that the quantity variable
shows up, and the current value is one.
At this point, I can step over this line
of code to the end of the method and
then just resume execution of the app.
Because I have two breakpoints in my
app, if I click on the plus button,
it triggers the breakpoint
in the increment method.
Then I can hit play to resume.
If I click on the minus button, it
triggers a breakpoint in the decrement
method, and I can hit play to resume.
If I don't want the app to stop
at either of those breakpoints,
I can just hit stop, and
it detaches the debugger.
Then the app just runs as normal where
it updates the screen immediately when I
click on the button.