In the introduction module,
you used canny edge detection
to find pixels that were likely
to be part of a line in an image.
Canny is great at finding all
possible lines in an image, but for
land detection, this gave us a lot
of edges on scenery, and cars, and
other objects that we
ended up discarding.
Realistically, with lane finding,
we know ahead of time that the lines we
are looking for are close to vertical.
So, how can we take
advantage of that fact?
Well, we can use gradients in
a smarter way to detect steep
edges that are more likely to
be lanes in the first place.
With Canny, we were actually taking
a derivative with respect to x and
y in the process of finding edges.
But let's stop and have a look at what
those individual derivatives look like
for an image of the road.