In the first lesson we discussed the
fact that there are two primary types of
experiments, randomized and
matched pair.
We covered randomized
experiments in detail, and
now we're going to dive into
matched pair design experiments.
Remember matched pair design experiments
are usually used when the volume of
observations or individuals is
fairly low, the concern for
bias is great, and the cost per
observation is high by comparison.
Matched pairing sets up treatment and
control groups for an experiment by
matching on a unit by unit basis
using a set of control variables.
The goal is to create two groups of
units that are as similar as possible to
each other, so that we can confidently
say that any changes during the test
are due to the introduction
of the experimental variable.
A mathematical algorithm is used to
create the treatment control groups
where for each treatment unit, one or
more control units is selected.
Before we dive into this process,
let's first discuss how to
select treatment units.