So here we are in our
functions playground.
Let's start by defining
Global Functions and Methods.
Global Functions are functions that
can be called from anywhere in an app.
Global Function syntax
is easy to recognize
because Global Functions aren't
called by a particular object.
They're just called sort
of floating in thin air.
One Global Function that you're
familiar with by now is print.
The min, max, and absolute value
functions are a few more examples.
Global Functions like print,
can be called from within any class.
Methods on the other hand,
are defined in and
associate with a particular class.
The vast majority of Swift functions
that you write and call will be Methods.
Here we have a method
called sum of strings,
it's defined within
the arithmetic class.
And is also called by an instance
of the arithmetic class.
So that's Global Functions and Methods.
To get to the next page in
the playground, just press Next.
And if you want to see all of
the pages in the playground,
you can go up here to the Navigate menu,
click on Reveal in Project Navigator.
And here on the left,
you can see how the playground is
organized and access any of the pages.