Let's now look at scheduling
on multi-CPU systems.
However, before we start
talking about scheduling,
let's look a little bit at
some architecture detail.
First we will look at shared
memory multiprocessors.
And then we will also take a look
at how this compares to multi-core
architectures.
In a shared memory multiprocessors,
or SMPs, there are multiple CPUs.
Each of them have their maybe own
private caches, like L1 and L2.
There are last level caches that may or
may not be shared among the CPUs.
And there is a system memory, DRAM,
that is shared across all of the CPUs.
Here we show just one memory component,
but
it is possible that there would
be multiple memory components.
But the point is that all of the memory
in the system is shared among all
of the CPUs.
In the current multicore world,
each of these CPUs can have
multiple internal cores, so
multiple CPUs internally.
Each of those cores will
have private caches, and
then overall the entire multicore CPU
will have some shared last level cache.
And then again,
there will be some shared system memory.
Here in this picture, we have a CPU
with two cores, so that's a dual-core
processor, and this is more common for
client devices like laptops, for
instance, or even cell phones
today can have two CPUs.
Whereas on the server and platforms,
it's more common to have CPUs
that have six or eight cores and
to also have multiple such CPUs, so
we'll have multiple multicore CPUs.
As far as the operating
system is concerned,
it sees all of these CPUs as
well as the cores in the CPU as
entities onto which it can schedule
all execution context, so threads.
All of these are, as far as
the operating system is concerned,
possible CPUs for
it can schedule some of its workload.
So to make our discussion more concrete,
we will first start talking about
scheduling on multi-CPU systems in
the context of SMP systems, and
a lot of these things will apply to
the multicore world because again,
the scheduler just
sees the cores as CPUs.
And we'll make some comments that
are more exclusively applied
to multicores towards
the end of this lesson.
We said in our earlier lectures
that the performance of threads and
processes is highly dependent on
whether the state that the thread needs
is in the cache or in memory.
Let's say a thread was
executing on CPU one first.
Over time this thread was slightly able
to bring a lot of the state that it
needs both into the last level of
cache that's associated with this CPU,
as well as in the private caches
that are available on the CPU.
And in this case, when the caches are
hot, this helps with the performance.
Now, the next time around,
if the thread is scheduled
to execute on the other CPU,
none of its state will be there so the
thread will operate with a cold cache.
We'll have to bring all
of the state back in and
that will affect performance.
Therefore, what we want to achieve
with a scheduling on multi-CPU systems
is to try to schedule the thread
back on the same CPU where it
executed before because it is more
likely that its cache will be hot.
We call this cache affinity and
that is clearly important.
To achieve this, we basically
want the scheduler to keep a task
on the same CPU as much as possible.
To achieve this, we can maintain
a hierarchical scheduler architecture,
where at the top level, a load balancing
component divides the tasks among CPUs.
And then a per-CPU scheduler with
a per CPU runqueue repeatedly
schedules those tasks on a given
CPU as much as possible.
To balance the load across the different
CPUs and their per-CPU runqueue, the top
level entity in the scheduler can look
at information such as the length of ea,
of each of these queues to decide
how to balance tasks across them.
Or potentially when a CPU is idle,
it can at that point start looking
at the other CPUs and
try to get some more work from them.
In addition to having
multiple processors,
it is possible to also have
multiple memory nodes.
The CPUs and
the memory nodes will be interconnected
via some type of interconnect.
For instance, on modern Intel platforms,
there is a interconnect that's called
QuickPath Interconnect, or QPI.
One way in which these memory nodes can
be configured is that a memory node
can be technically connected to some
subset of the CPU, so for instance,
to a socket that has
multiple processors.
If that is the case,
then the access from that set of CPUs
to the memory node will be faster
versus from that particular
processor to a memory node that's
associated with another set of CPUs.
Both types of accesses will be made
possible because of the interconnect
that's connecting all
of these components.
However, they will take
different amount of time.
We call these types of platforms
non-uniform memory access platforms, or
NUMA platforms.
So then clearly, from a scheduling
perspective, what would make sense is
for the scheduler to divide tasks in
such a way that tasks are bound to
those CPUs that are closer to the memory
node where the state of those tasks is.
We call this type of scheduling
NUMA-aware scheduling.