Okay, let's talk about the possible
values that can be on the right side of
our key value pairs.
We've already seen in the last note that
our keys can reference primitive data
types like numbers, booleans and
strings, but they can
also represent more complex chunks of
data in the form of objects and arrays.
That's right, a key can point
to other nested objects or
arrays of other objects.
Let's take a look at
our shoe example again.
You might suspect that the style
key maps to a nested object.
because the contents are enclosed in
curly braces, and you'd be right.
Okay, so
the value is a nested JSON object.
Well, how do I reverse it?
Well, if you look at its contents,
it just continues the same
key value pair structure.
You can read it the same
way you did before.
This time, we're just one level deeper.
So let's look at the key categories.
It has a value that starts with
a left bracket, has contents,
and then closes with a right bracket.
What do you think
the brackets represent?
This is the syntax for an array.
JSON arrays can contain primitive
data types or JSON objects.
Similar to arrays that
you've seen in Java,
you can navigate the contents
of an array using indices.
At the initial position, which is index
zero, we have the string value of boot.
At the following index position,
index one, we have winklepicker.
Then we have a key color, which maps
to the primitive string of black.
That completes our example,
JSON, describing a shoe.
But as you can probably imagine,
the nesting that we saw in the shoe
example can continue to compound.
That array could have contained more
objects and arrays inside of it,
and that means that the data
payload could get really,
really big, and that's absolutely true.
But the cool thing is
despite the potential size,
we've got a dead simple way
to navigate through it.
We just need to follow
the key value pairs.
Not sure what I mean?
In the next node,
we'll explore more complex examples and
get more practice
traversing larger JSON.
But first,
let's get some practice identifying
different JSON components in a quiz.
In the next quiz, you'll get to practice
distinguishing between a JSON object,
array, or primitive by looking at
a completely different JSON response.
This is an example from the Twitter API
where you can request the most
recent tweets that a user has liked.
This is the URL we query for the data,
and the response comes
back in JSON format.
It does require authentication, which
means you need to provide a username and
password to access the data.
You can't just copy
the URL into a browser and
see the results like we did for
the earthquake data.
Without getting bogged down into
the details of authentication,
the documentation gives us an example
request and example response.
This response looks similar to
the JSON we looked at earlier.
There are key value pairs, and some of
the values are JSON objects with braces,
and some of them are JSON
arrays with the brackets.
Other values that you'll see in here
include strings, booleans, numbers.
Cris and I did our own query to this
API and got back this response.
For the quiz, look at this response and
answer the questions.
In this quiz, I've asked you
about certain keys in the JSON
response that we got back form
the Twitter favorites API.
The link to my response and the original
documentation site is below.
Determine if the given key maps
to a value that is a JSON object,
a JSON array, or a JSON primitive.