Now that we've learned about
camera calibration and
correcting for distortion,
we can start to extract really useful
information from images of the road.
One really important piece of
information is lane curvature.
Think about how you drive on a highway,
you take a look at the road in
front of you and cars around you.
You press the gas or
break to go with the flow.
And based on how much
the lane is curving,
left or right, you turn the steering
wheel to stay in that lane.
Now, how does this work for
a self-driving car?
Self-driving cars need to be told the
correct steering angle to turn left or
right and we can calculate this angle if
we know a few things about the speed and
dynamics of the car and
how much the lane is curving.
To determine the curvature,
we'll go through the following steps.
First, we'll detect the lane
lines using some masking and
thresholding techniques.
Then, perform a perspective transform
to get a birds eye view of the lane.
This let's us fit a polynomial
to the lane lines.
Which we couldn't do very easily before.
Then, we can extract the curvature
the lines from this polynomial
with just a little math.
So let's start by learning more
about the perspective transform.