Map coloring is another classic
example of constraint satisfaction.
>> We are trying to color this map of
Australia using the minimum number of
colors possible, but making sure that no
neighboring regions have the same color.
>> I guess if they had the same color,
it'd be hard to tell where one territory
stopped and where the next began.
>> Exactly, we can set up the problem
more formally by first listing
all the variables,
in this case the territories.
>> And the possible colors of the
territories are listed as the domains
of the problem.
>> Finally the rules of the problem,
that no territory can be assigned the
same color as a neighboring territory,
are listed as the constraints.
>> We can do that explicitly by listing
all the possible pairwise constraints,
like how Western Australia's color can't
be the same as the Northern Territory.
Or we could list all
the allowable assignments for
each pair of territories.
>> A solution is an assignment of
colors to each of the territories that
satisfied all of the constraints.
>> I always wanted to
paint Australia red.