The answer can be seen directly from this formula over here.
In the first case we plug in X equals 10.
F over Z is 10 divided by 100.
We multiply 10 by 0.1, and we get 1.
It turns out all the units take care of themselves.
No matter which way we pose the question, we can effectively ignore those units,
because they're the same outside the camera as they are inside the camera.
For the second question, we transform this equation over here as follows:
We now plug in Z as 400, X as 20, lowercase x as 1,
to give us a focal length of 20 mm.
We can transform this equation further into this quotient over here.
F over x is 40 times uppercase X of 2 mm is 80 meters.
Finally we can write this expression over here, and we plug in x over f.
We get 100th times 300 is 3 meters over here.