There's a really nice little a graphical
illustration of tracking with
Kalman filters.
So let's suppose we have
some current estimate
of where we think things are, right.
And that's what's represented by this
little circle here in the x y plane.
Our prediction shifts and grows, and
that's why the, the size if you will.
And you can think of this as being
a a single, say, some number du,
of standard deviations of uncertainty.
So our, our uncertainty matrix
got significantly bigger, and
the mean may have shifted as well as,
also.
So that's our prediction.
We then take a measurement, and
you'll notice that the measurement
here is offset a little bit.
I mean, and it happens, you know, it's,
it's mean is right in the middle.
And it's actually tighter.
So it actually has a tighter
co-variance than the prediction, okay?
But the thing that's important
to realize is the correction
has a tighter co-variance
than either one of them.
So you'll see that the mean of
the final correction is somewhere
between the mean of the measurement and
the mean of the prediction.
Remember, it's going to be
a weighting between them.
And also notice that the co-variance
of the final corrected estimate
is smaller than either of the two,
all right?
And this might seem a little
weird when you look just at, say,
the, the co-variance of the measurement
and the co-variance of the prediction,
because they're both pretty big and
you might ask, how is it that
the co-variance goes down even
tighter than the measurement?
And again, the answer is, information
can only reduce your uncertainty.
So whether you think of as measurement
as reducing your uncertainty about
the prediction or
the prediction is reducing
the uncertainty about the measurement.
What that means is your final
co-variance will be less.
You'd be amazed at the number of PhD
qualifying students who when asked that
question standing in front of
the board kind of flunk through it.
So if you're thinking about doing a PhD
and I'm going to be on your qualifying
committee and
you're doing something in robotics.
Get to know and lerve,
love, your Kalman filters.