That was a really good question so
let's turn it into a quiz.
So here's some five different
examples of learning rate sequences.
That you might consider using in one
of these kinds of learning algorithms.
There's our friend 1/T which came
out of the analysis that we did to
get out the average.
So we're hoping that
one should really work.
But then let's look above and
below it so 1/T squared.
1 / T to the two-thirds.
1 over square root of T.
And actually,
it's sometimes pretty popular to use
learning rates that are just a constant.
Just a small number that just
stays constant over time.
And so what I'd like us to figure out is
which of these five rules
satisfy the two conditions?
In other words, that the sum of
the learning rates is infinite.
But the sum of the squares is finite.
>> Okay,
we can probably do that together.
>> Cool.
>> Okay, well go.