We will now look at NFS,
a very popular distributive file system.
In NFS, clients acts as
the remote server over a network.
And hence, the name Network File System.
It's another contribution
to computer science made
by the great systems researchers at Sun.
In fact, one of the reasons why
protocols like RPC were developed was to
help with the use of NFS.
Its architecture is
shown in this figure.
Client requests an access files using
the virtual file system interface and
using the same types of file descriptors
that they use to access files in their
local storage.
The VSF layer will determine whether the
file belongs to the local file system or
whether it needs to be
pushed to the NFS client, so
that it can pass it to
the remote file system.
The NFS client interacts via
RPC with they NFS server
that resides on a remote machine.
This is the machine that
actually stores the files.
The NFS server accepts the request,
forms them into a proper file system
operation that's then issued to
the local virtual file system and
from there, it gets passed to the local
file system on top of the local storage.
What that means is that on the server
machine, the requests that are coming
from the NFS server module are serviced
as any other file system operation that
comes from any application
running on this machine.
When an open request
comes from the client,
the NFS server will
create a file handle.
This will be a bite sequence that
encodes both the server machine as well
as the server local file information.
This will be returned back
to the client machine and
it will be maintained by the NFS client,
so whenever the client application
tries to access files that are stored
on the remote server on the NFS.
Internally, this file handle will be
passed with every single request.
If the files get deleted or
the server machine dies, using this
handle will result in an error,
because we're trying to use stale data.
Data that's no longer valid.
On client's right operations,
the data that needs to be written
to the file will be carried as part
of the RPC request from
the client to the server machine.
And in file read, the data blocks that
will be read from the file will be
the results from that RPC request that
was sent from the client to the server.
And as such, they will be
passed back to the NFS client.
And then ultimately,
back to the application that
issued the read operation.