So far you've used the API's Explorer
to test the functions in
the conference's API.
However the conference central
application also includes a full working
web UI.
Each of the pages in the web UI
sends calls into the backend API.
As you implement the backend
functionality the web pages in the app
will start to work.
So far the only page that will
work is the My Profile page.
This page calls get profile to get the
values of the logged in user's profile
and calls save profile when you
change values and update the profile.
Now, the goal of this course is to help
you learn how to develop app engine
applications not to
teach you JavaScript so
I'm not going to go into detail
on the code for the web UI.
However, I do want to point out the code
that makes the call to get profile.
This is located in static
slash js slash controllers.js,
and it's the init code for
the profile page.
You see here, there's a call to
gapi.client.conference.getProfile and
then a little bit further down,
here we have a saveProfile.
The Conference Central application
includes both a backend application that
defines endpoints functions and
a frontend application
that uses those functions.
We'll call the application that defines
the endpoints functions a backend API.
In this case,
the frontend application and
the backend API are combined in a single
application but they don't have to be.
You could have the front-end code in
a completely separate application.
Or you could even have multiple
applications that provide different
front-end interfaces to
the conference backend API.
In a way, app engine doesn't
care that the front-end and
the backend API in Conference Central
are the same application.
You still have to authorize the
front-end application to use the backend
API, even though they
are the same application and
share the same application ID.
So there are a few things you need to do
before you can start using the web pages
in the Conference Central application.
First, we need to tell the backend
API which clients apps are allowed to
use it.
You do that by specifying
the client id's,
we need to clear the endpoints.api.
So we've already granted access to
the API_EXPLORER_CLIENT_ID, but
now we're going to need to set
up this WEB_CLIENT_ ID as well.
It is a bit odd granting access
to ourself in a way, but
as far as the endpoint's API is
concerned it doesn't know the web UI is
in the same app.
So in settings.py here's where
the WEB_CLIENT_ID is set up.
And, how did I get this big
long alphanumerical value?
Well, it's just like what we did for
the Hello app back in lesson two.
We do it in the dev console.
So, our first step, go to APIs & auth,
and Consent screen, and make sure
the email address and product name are
set in the Consent screen, and hit Save.
Second, under APIs & auth,
select Credentials.
And under OAuth,
select Create new Client ID.
You are creating a web application,
and then under
AUTHORIZED JAVASCRIPT ORIGINS,
fill in your app id .appspot.com, and
also one for your local host including
the correct port like localhost:8080.
Once you do it it will show up over
here, then copy this client ID and
that's what you will
put into settings.py.
Another thing you'll need to do is add
the client ID to the JavaScript code
that runs the authentication
process on the client's site.
So far it hasn't mattered that the web
UI didn't have the correct client ID set
because we've only used
the API's Explorer.
But if you've tried logging
in using the webpages,
you've likely noticed
it didn't quite work.
So this code you'll find in static js,
app.js.
And right here under
oauth2Provider is a CLIENT_ID and
you'll paste that same
value in right here.
After you've set those things up and
saved and deployed, you should find that
you're now able to log in to
the Conference Central web app and
that My Profile will now allow you
to both see and save your profile.