Now let's see how we can compute the value of a state using these
two innovations to work on b and m.
I've modified our routine for value in two ways--
one, I've introduced a new line that says if we decide to cut off the search
at a particular depth then apply the evaluation function to the state and return that.
Then I've also added some bookkeeping variables.
One for the current depth, which will get increased as we go along,
and then two values called alpha and beta, which are the traditional names,
where alpha is the best value found so far for Max along the path
that we are currently exploring, and beta is the best value found so far for Min.
Then since we have these extra parameters when we start out,
we would make the call value of our initial state S0 and we're currently at depth zero
in the search tree, and we haven't found the best for Max yet so that would be minus infinity,
and the best for Min similarly we haven't found anything there so that would be plus infinity.
We call that and then each node we would chose one of these four cases.
Here's the new definition of maxValue taking the depth
and the alpha and beta parameters into account.
It's similar to what we had before.
We go through all the successors.
We take the maximum, and in this case we're incrementing the depth
as we call recursively for the value of each node.
We get the cutoff here if we exceed beta,
and otherwise we retain alpha as the maximum value to Max so far.
Then we return the final value.