Look at that a little more carefully in pqs space.
Let's assume that we've got some source pq that's right here, all right.
So if my surface normal were pointing right at that direction, so
the theta i is 0, cosine i is 1, then my value would be 1, all right.
But suppose cosine is 0.9, all right?
Well, that would be some, some curve.
Draw it around here, right.
This is some Iso-brightness contour, so
every one of those pqs would give a intensity of 0.9.
Going out a little further 0.8, 0.7.
Gets even further out, 0.6, 0.5, right?
Here's all the way down to 0.3.
And then finally, what happens when we get to a point where the surface normal,
is perpendicular to the light source?
Well if the surface normal's perpendicular to light source,
the cosine of theta i is 0.
So no light is being ref, is hitting that surface, okay?
And so that would be this line here all right, right there.
Where it says 0 value,
because that's the equation of a line in pqs phase, right?
P times ps plus q times qs plus 1 equals 0,
that's like a x plus b y plus c equals 0 in the p, but it's in pq space so
it's ap plus bq plus c equals 0, so it's a line.
So the perpendicular situation is a line in pq space.
So, and notice by the way, that p, q is a, the R of p, q is a maximum, right
when the surface normal lines up with the light source, as you might expect.
So that's our reflectance map in the Lambertian situation.