In this section, we explore Storm's multi-language capabilities by
readying a bolt in Python.
Due to implementation details Python is rarely used in
production Storm topologies due to Python's inefficiencies.
However, Python is useful as a prototype or low usage process.
And many of our
Udacity students are more comfortable with Python compared to Java.
Let's get started with basic usage.
In step 0, navigate to Lesson 3, Stage 1 and
remember to add your Twitter credentials into the TweetTopology.java file.
Also you'll need to install the Beautiful Soup python module in Ubuntu.
In your virtual machine run the following command sudo space apt-get
install python-bs4 this stands for super user do.
And install command for Ubuntu for the python module, beautiful soup.
You can simply copy and paste the command and after downloading,
you'll see your command prompt once again.
Next, in Step 1, maven requires a folder resources to contain the storm.py and
all python files.
We need to register in the folder location in the palm.xml file.
Scrolling up in the TweetTopology file,
you'll see the section, ADDING MAVEN RESOURCES FOR PYTHON SHELL.
Open your pom.xml file here and add in your Maven resources here.
Once you've added in the Maven resource file, in Step 2 in your text editor or
command line, add a Resources folder to /storm.
This new resources folder allows Maven to
package your python files in the resources directory within your final jar file.
You're now ready to write python bolts.
In Step 3 in your browser,
find the Storm multilang resources by following the link below.
In Step 4, create new files, copy and paste Storm.py and
split sentence py into your resources directory created in Step 2.
In step 5 you can review the usage of python bolts linked to
Java in WordCountTopology here.
And in Step 6 we see that the inner class SplitSentence extends
Shellbolt implements IRichBolt is needed.
In Step 7, create a new file in your Storm folder.
Not the resources folder.
And name the file SplitSentence.java.
Copy and paste the interclass SplitSentence into your new java file along with
the required import statements.
Remember as well that your package structure needs to change to Udacity.storm.
And to complete your split sentence class definition in step eight,
remove the static statement.
Since you are now defining a class instead of a static nested class.
In Step 9, update your topology to use the SplitSentence bolt that
internally calls the python program splitsentence.py.
You answer the implementation question, what grouping is needed for
this topology link.
Finally, in Step 10, package and run your topology.
When one's completed, you'll see the visualization will be the split sentence
word count using a python bolt.
Remember that your code should now match Lesson 2,
Stage 2 for reference, including file structure and Palm to XML file.
Good luck with the assignment