For this quiz, I want you to head over
to csstriggers.com and do some research.
I want you to find a CSS property
that triggers layout, paint, and
composite, and type it into this box.
Then find a CSS property that only
triggers paint and composite and
type it into this box.
And then lastly, find a CSS property
that only triggers composite and
type it into this box.
The reason you're checking out
csstriggers.com is because a, Paul made
it and he's forcing us to include it in
the course, and b, it's a super useful
resource for determining the amount
of work your CSS will trigger.
It's really important
to become familiar with
it if you want to write
performant websites.
Okay.
Well, good luck!