A running process is already executing, so
it should be marked as a correct answer.
Any of the processes that are in ready state, the CPU is able to execute them.
They're just waiting for
the operating system's scheduler to schedule them on the CPU.
You should remember that as soon as a ready process is scheduled on the CPU,
it will continue its execution from the very first instruction that's pointed by
the process program counter.
It is possible that this is the very first instruction in the process,
if the process entered the ready queue for
the first time after being newly created.
And the other option is that it's some other random instruction in the process
binary, depending on when the process was interrupted last time.
Either when it was interrupted by the scheduler or because it had to stop
executing since it had to wait on an I/O or some kind of external event.