This is the second part
of the two-parter quiz.
In the first part, you created
a store app with static content.
In this second phase of development,
you'll need to convert
the app to a dynamic one.
To do that, you'll need to create a JSON
file with all of the cookie data.
Make sure to store it
in the public folder so
that the route file can access it.
Once the JSON file exists
with the correct data,
update the cookies route
file to retrieve that data.
It should return an array of objects,
one for each cookie.
In the last step, you'll want to update
the cookie template to remove all
the hardcoded data.
The link to the starter code for
this project is in the instructor notes.
When you've finished, the feedback
extension will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.
Ember uses the QUnit testing framework,
and
I've created a number of tests
that you need to satisfy.
These tests help guide you through
completing the assignment.
Once all the tests have passed, the
feedback extension will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.
You can find a link to this project's
test page in the project's readme file.