But suppose you actually wanted to like do something useful.
What would be the easy way of doing that?
Well the easy way is I just give you the formula.
So, if M is equal to Q b as I said before, then, the center
is just found by taking this quantity above that quantity in a vector.
So this is a,
remember Q is a three by three, so minus Q inverse is a three by three,
b is a three by one, so this is a three by one, and then I add the one there,
that is the vector that is the camera center in the world coordinate frame.
So if I made, you know, the corner of that table that you can't see,
there's really a corner over there, if I said that's the origin, right, and this
way is x, and, this way is y, and that way is z, and then I have a camera here.
And I, took a look at a bunch of points here, and
I gave you the value of those points in this coordinate system, and
then I located those points, in my image plane.
And then I did all that math to compute that M vector, and that,
that M matrix, and then I pulled out the three by three and
called that Q and three by one and called that b.
And then I took minus Q inverse times b over one, that, vector would
be the actual location of this camera in that coord, world coordinate system.
Pretty, pretty cool.