Now before we go on, let's actually talk
a little bit about video stabilization.
Video stabilization is
an extremely important field and
anybody who's been doing work in video
knows that basically what we want to
do is try to keep as stable of
number of shots as possible.
This has actually resulted
in variety of innovations.
The most well known and most established
is the steady cam invented about 1975 by
you know, cameraman Garrett Brown.
He actually did some of this work
when the early Star Wars movies were
being filmed and in fact some of
the shots that were taken in the,
in the forest with the Ewoks and stuff.
If you notice lot of motions that were
going on were all relatively stabled,
captured by a camera like this.
I've had the privilege of meeting
Garrett Brown, he's an amazing person.
>> This is a steady cam.
Mine is a Master Series Elite.
The steady cam was invented
back in the 70s, and
it's revolutionized film and video,
by freeing the camera from the jib,
and the tripod and the dolly without
the bouncing and shaking of hand held.
Many people think it
works by gyroscopes but
in reality it's just balance and
the physics of the steady cam's arms
to isolate the body
movement from the camera.
While it makes the camera seem
weightless the rig is anything but,
and the operator needs a strong
back as well as a creative mind.
>> So I just showed you a small
video from YouTube about
what this whole steady cam is all about.
And if you notice one the interesting
things is basically it's got
a counterweight and it's the balance
of this counterweight on this you know,
counterlever from the camera that
basically keeps it stable and
of course removes it from
the motion of the user.
Widely used moti,
widely used camera system.
Of course, for those of you that
are interested you can look around on
the web and
you'll find even DIY versions.
Where you can actually make your
own setups to do something.
Not as well as this,
because this is a professional one, but
similar types of things yourselves.
Again, just like any
concept in photography and
videography there is a huge DIY
culture on these kinds of things.
I encourage you to look at that and
there are other solutions too.