The answers are pretty straightforward.
For the first question,
we know each machine can hold 100 files
in the replicated case, all files
are present on every single machine, so
regardless of the fact that
we have three machines,
we still can only hold 100 files.
In the partitioned case however, every
single machine can hold 100 different
files, and therefore the total
size of the file system is 300.
This illustrates one benefit
of the partitioned design,
because it can support larger
number of files in the file system.
For the second question, if we lose
one machine in the replicated case,
we will still have two other
machines that have all the files, so
we will lose zero percent
of the total files.
In the partitioned file system however,
33% of the files will be lost.
This is because when one machine fails,
all the files that were stored on
that particular machine will be lost.
This data point illustrates one case in
which the replicated design is better.
It provides greater fault tolerance
versus in the previous example,
the partitioned distributed file
system providing greater scalability
in terms of the number of files.
Also this is why a mixed approach
of using both replication and
partitioning types of techniques
will provide greater flexibility
in terms of achieving both size and
resiliency.