There a few key considerations
to consider when setting
up a randomized experiment.
These are the unit of diversion,
population, duration and size.
The unit of diversion refers to how you
will assign units to the control or
treatment groups.
You could randomly assign each visit to
the site to either control or treatment.
But then you may have the same user
seeing both versions of the site,
which could be confusing to them, and
complicate the interpretation
of the results.
What most experiments do is try
to split units at the user level.
So even if the user leaves the site and
comes back,
they'll see the same version.
This can be difficult with web data, but
most companies will use either a cookie,
device ID, IP address or
some other identifier as a proxy.
To learn more about the specifics of
how web experiments are designed,
see the link to the lesson below.
Next, you need to
determine your population.
In our website example,
this would be all visitors to the site
that don't already have the app.
Next, you'll want to
select the duration and
size of experiment in a way that
ensures that your control and
treatment groups are representative
of your population.
This is where the control
variables come in handy.
Let's take a look back at the three
control variables we identified.