Propositional logic, it's a powerful
language for what it does.
And there are very efficient inference
mechanisms for determining validity and
satisfiability, although
we haven't discussed them.
But propositional logic
has a few limitations.
First, it can only handle true and
false values.
No capability to handle uncertainty
like we did in probability theory.
And second, we can only talk
about events that are true or
false in the world.
We can't talk about objects that
have properties, such as size,
weight, color and so on, nor can we talk
about the relations between objects.
And third, there are no shortcuts
to succinctly talk about a lot
of different things happening.
Say, if we had a vacuum world
with 1,000 locations, and
we wanted to say that every
location is free of dirt,
we would need a conjunction
of 1,000 propositions.
There's no way to have a single
sentence saying that all
of the locations are clean all at once.
So, we will next cover
first order logic,
which addresses these two limitations