So now let's do a quiz on this.
So what we're going to do is I want
you to pick one of each type of
notification, regular activity,
always on activity or
watch face for
each of the questions here.
First question is how would you
implement an app that helps
the user go for
a run, in showing the current number of
steps in distance that they've covered?
The next question is what about helping
the user find out when the price of
a stock or commodity has
exceeded a threshold value?
Next, what about viewing a graph
of the history of the weather at
a particular location?
What about finding out if there
are any incoming emails or messages?
And tracking the number of steps and
distance walked each day by the user?
And finally, tracking the calendar
entries that you have
upcoming in the day?