Okay, excellent.
You've started to find and fix issues.
Now, hopefully,
you're JavaScript is behaving well,
but remember that it's only
a small part of making a frame.
>> In this lesson, you'll be tackling
styles or, as it's labeled in DevTools,
recalculate styles.
By the end of this lesson,
you'll be identifying and
solving performance issues
from style calculations.
But bear in mind that JavaScript
can often be the trigger for
the issues we're going to cover.
But it's not necessarily
JavaScript's fault.
Also, remember from the first
lesson that stout calculations will
take the DOM and
then for each element, figure out
what its visual properties should be.
>> Right, so the browser ends up with
a Render Tree which is like the DOM.
Only it's, the elements,
too, just need to be drawn.
So anything that shouldn't
be drawn won't be in there.
So if you set something to display-non,
it won't be there, but
if you have something like
pseudo-elements, like before or
after, they will be in this tree,
even though they don't exist in the DOM.