So it, it sounds like we want to, since we have two, two maybe big buckets.
>> Mm-hm. >> That we want to sort things.
Maybe three.
>> Mm-hm.
>> misinformation, panic mongering.
>> Reliable sources.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Maybe political stuff.
>> So each of those would be a separate sort of output bolt, is that?
>> Yes, because I, I think like because each set of
words that is characteristic, this computational bucket is different.
>> Mm-hm, right, yeah.
>> So, you might need a different kind of bolts for that.
So probably like you might you might have one single spout.
A spout which takes all the Twitter data, right.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Then,.
So then you might have one bolt that might be doing your panic stuff, right?
>> Mm-hm.
>> Then a little bolt which is doing that on this information.
And bolt with the current resources.
Right?
>> Mm-hm.
>> So now in the credible sources you might want to say, like,
now which data, so, this bolt is going to send the data [INAUDIBLE], right?
So now let us state the correct credible in bolt.
In this case, you must have [INAUDIBLE] credible accounts, right?
>> Right.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And this credible accounts are the ones that's going to.
I mean, if a lot of credible accounts are there, are probably,
if the accounts are too small, then all the bolts can carry those accounts.
>> Okay. >> All right, so
then you can use that survey by which, okay, I'm getting all these tweets and
the status from this account, okay, this is a credible source, right?
Then on the credible source, whatever you have to do, you have to,
if it requires further stage processing, yes, you need another bolt.
Right.
You can stage it and finally you can say something of a credible score or
whatever it is, right.
That is the output going to be right.
>> Yeah. >> And this information you already have whatever,
you can break up those words and like, like the credible accounts,
you have already input some kind of a, panic words, right?
>> Right. >> And then the you have to include the logic of
how many times this for a particular tweet you want to attach a score.
So the whole panic that tweet this.
>> Uh-huh. Yeah.
>> So, so like if more panic words are out,
again, then the degree of panic is much more higher than this one, right?
>> Right.
>> Come up with a score.
And, each tweet is assigned a certain code like that, right?
Then, at some point, then you would make another bolt, which is aggregating
those scores of the tweet, and slowly aggregating and coming up with one score.
So that you can have a, what is the panic score, or whatever that is, right?
>> Uh-huh, yeah.
>> That is another one, right?
So similarly here.
Then I think the misinformation.
How much is the degree of misinformation.
Again, for each tweet, what are the words that carry the misinformation.
Because let's say that you accumulate some characteristics of what Ebola is
not as compared to, and people are saying those things.
Compare it with Ebola, then find out how much is the degree of misinformation.
Then give the misinformation code.
Except having this, to follow the same pattern.
>> Yeah. >> Except the, the way you compute it will be different.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Okay. >> So because this is encapsulating computation logic, right?
So it will be very different in terms of this one.
So once you compute them, then all of the scores you can make available to
that is, then you over the dashboard and the dashboard will pick that from
where it is or whatever, and then display those scores.
And update the scores continuously.