For completeness,
let's briefly summarize where you stand,
with respect to sorting,
using bitonic ideas.
First, given an arbitrary input,
you have a procedure to
generate a bitonic sequence.
A pseudocode algorithm would
look something like this.
You can think of it in terms
of divide and conquer,
first you create two
bitonic subsequences.
Then you turn one into
an increasing sequence and
the other into a decreasing sequence.
The main thing you need are both plus
and minus variations on bitonic merge.
Now once you have this primitive,
sorting becomes really easy.
Use this routine to generate a bitonic
sequence from an arbitrary input,
then run a bitonicMerge on it.
Schematically, that's just glueing
the genBitonic circuit with
a bitonicMerge circuit.
You can show that the work in span,
a bitonic sorting is as follows,
notice that with respect to span,
it's polylogarithmic.
That's good, but what about work?
With respect to work,
this algorithm is not work optimal.
You know from CS101, that practical
comparison based algorithms
are possible with just
O of n log n work.
Of course, that begs the question
why bother with bitonic sorting?