All right, so
now we need to modify the word adapter
to store the background
color information.
So over here in the numbers activity
where we create a new word adapter in
this line, the third input will
need to be the color resource.
So R.color.category_numbers.
So go ahead and
modify your code to reflect this change.
Then go ahead and finish making
the code changes so that this works.
We'll need to modify
the WordAdapter constructor
to accept color as its third input.
And next, we'll also want to update the
WordAdapter logic to use the appropriate
color when setting up
the individual list item views.
So we'll make the WordAdapter change the
background color of the vertical in your
layout that contains the two text
views in the list item layout.
So once we've made those changes
to the WordAdapter constructor.
We'll need to make sure
our category activity
correctly calls this new
version of the constructor.
And lastly,
in the visual polish coding task.
We use the orange color
as a placeholder for
the background of the text
in each list item.
So once this new code is working,
we can remove that placeholder
color in the list_item.xml file.
So take a look at the notes provided
below the quiz for some hints as well.
Now this is the last coding task for
this lesson.
So good luck and when you're done,
check these boxes and continue on.