All right, so here we are back
in the shelter database and
I'm taking a look only at the ID, name
and weight columns from our pets table.
So say we get a word that Garfield has
been eating a little bit too much and
instead of being 14 kilograms,
he is now 20 kilograms.
So, how do we update that
information in our pets table?
Well, as the name implies,
we'd be using the UPDATE command.
So first off,
we start off with the UPDATE keyword,
followed by the name of the table which
is pets, followed by the SET keyword.
And after that, we want to set
the columns that we're interested in.
So, here we want to set
the weight column to 20.
Now, before I go ahead and enter here,
I need to pause and mention that if I
hit Enter now, this would set
the weight of all the pets to be 20.
So, in order to specify that we
only want Garfield to be updated,
we have our special WHERE clause.
So WHERE.
Afterwards we specify the id to be 2.
And that's because Garfield has id of 2.
So now I go ahead and hit Enter.
And if I want to see that it's been
updated, I can use SELECT again.
And notice here, the weight of Garfield
has been updated from 14 to 20.
So this UPDATE statement is
clearly pretty powerful, so
I'll be adding that to
our cheat sheet as well.
All right, so now we have the SQL
commands we need to view all our pets
as well as to be able to add new pets.
Well in our app, we'll also need
to be able to check on a pet,
and then change or
update their status if needed.
So this would be useful,
say if a pet gains weight, or
if maybe some DNA tests come back and we
finally know the exact breed of the dog.
So let's take a look at how exactly
we can update a single pet.
All right, so now is your chance to
practice using our update SQL command.
So try out these two scenarios.
So in this first situation, our
knowledgeable vet has identified that
Tommy isn't just a Pomeranian, but
in fact he's a Pomeranian Terrier mix.
So go ahead and write that SQL
statement that would update his breed
to be the correct breed.
And remember,
don't leave off the semicolon.
In the second scenario, so the scale of
the shelter was discovered to be broken.
And in order to mark all the pets
that need to be re-weighed,
the shelter wants to go ahead and just
set all the pets to have a weight of 0.
And then update them
one at a time later on.
So what I want you to do,
is you write the code that would
set all the pets weights to be 0.
And once again,
remember this punctuation at the end.
All right, best of luck.