Hopefully, all your JavaScript is
running at the right time in the frame.
And that's great.
But now, you need to make sure that
it's not taking too long to run.
Remember that to meet 60 frames a second
you have to fit all the work inside 16
milliseconds.
And that's not just JavaScript but
everything for our frame.
In reality, we have to be inside
of ten to 12 milliseconds to
leave the browser some time for
it's housekeeping.
It's easy for JavaScript to
take quite some time to run,
especially if you
are using frameworks and
libraries because they will need
some time to do their work.
Whether that's organizing views in your
app or handling callbacks or perhaps,
even analyzing data.
And now I'm back in Chrome's DevTools,
and
I'm going to take a look
at its JavaScript profiler.
This is going to tell us not just
that I spent time in JavaScript, but
which functions, where,
and for how long.
Normally, when we record and
interact with the site we don't get
a lot of information on JavaScript.
For example, here we can see that
I've called some JavaScript.
We don't know anymore about
what was called or why.
If I check this box,
in the UI, and then re-record.
And now you can see with
the JavaScript profiler on,
I get a lot more information.
And if I hit the W key
to zoom in a bit more,
we can see they called an expand
function followed by collect properties.
The JavaScript profiler is
a great tool to use when you know
that you have long-running JavaScript.
You shouldn't leave it on all the time.
You should really only look to use it
when you know you have a problem with
long-running JavaScript.
And now armed with
this extra information,
I can find my bottlenecks more easily.