So what would such a function look like?
Well, it would look something like this and
it would be, what's referred to as a Gaussian filter.
So here's our original image, here is our filter.
Now this is not a great Gaussian because it's only three by three.
But you'll notice it's higher in the middle, then falls off at the edges and
even falls off more at the corners.
And what that is is, that's a very sort of low representation,
very coarse representation, of a Gaussian function.
And our Gaussian function is written here.
This is the two-dimensional Gaussian in the u, v.
1 over 2 pi sigma squared,
e to the minus u squared plus v squared over sigma squared.
That's a circularly symmetric Gaussian function.
Get to know and love your circularly symmetric Gaussian functions.
All right, so here I have, that's in fact what that plot was, so
we're going to do smoothing proportional.
So this exponentially to the minus x squared plus y
squared over 2 sigma squared.
And the technical description of this,
is that it's a circularly symmetric fuzzy blob.
That's what the Gaussian is going to be.
So if we take that image,
that same high textured image that we had before, and we filter that,
with this now Gaussian blurring function, what are we going to get?
We get something that looks like that.
So much better, so much nicer, right?
I mean, compare smoothing with a Gaussian to the non-Gaussian.
Gaussian, non-Gaussian, right?
And you can see the difference.
In fact, in the non-Gaussian you see all these sharp edges,
now you really seem them because they're red, all right?
But when you do it with a Gaussian you get that nice smooth blurring.