The example for that decision making.
We did, I think couple years ago yeah,
almost like two years ago.
I went off to my clients
when I was the co-anchor.
I was helping one of
the biggest ticket app.
And then they want to run
the campaign in the middle of August.
So and then I start work
with them I think June, and
we start work on what's happening
in app, what is the takes
tools we're using them,
what is the finals we're tried to build.
I asked him what is your ideal customer
profile, they told me that you know what
over 25, male dominant,
the users who are really buying tickets.
I said this is not the right audience,
because you should definitely
tell me okay, 25, 55,
who has a car, and lives in the US and
they went to vacation last two weeks and
they are buying the coffee
every day from 7/11.
So that's what I want to hear, and
then I can redefine either those
are the finals or I can make a decision.
Obviously they didn't have any expert,
for it so it took me the two months,
16 hours per day, looking for
a different dashboard.
And then they told me that this is
like the money we'll want to give you,
around million dollar to
make art more visible.
But the problem is that, the time they
choose, because one of the marketing
guy, he really want to do
it in the middle of August.
I ask her,
what is the reason you want to do it?
Because she said, you know what,
it's the time for the people,
they really enjoy the summer and
they're probably going to buy tickets.
I said, is there any data is tell
us okay this is going to work out?
She said, I don't know, I felt it.
So I should think at that time
marketing should be based on data, and
the numbers and metrics.
So then I figured out
a instead of middle of August,
we should do the second
week of September.
And then at that time in the middle
of August, it was like Thursday I
said we should be do the campaign
on Saturday, the second Saturday.
And then they aren't choose any time
zone, I said 7 AM in Eastern Time.
And then after that,
I figure out it our user profile, and
I redefined the channels.
Because before my decision they
were running in ads in every place,
and then try to monetize those users.
But if you know what the right time,
right place, you probably going to save
a lot of money instead of spending.
You just figure out the right time, your
right audience, and the right moment.
So the second week of the September,
we spent I think 2% or
3% of the entire campaign and
the budget.
And then we successfully
hit the top charts, and
we stay couple months
without spending any money.
If we did that campaign August, we're
probably going to spend a lot of money.
And never going to hit
the right places or
right audience because we didn't
know who's going to be our buyer, or
who's going to be right user, can stay
and then can keep buying those tickets.
So I'm feeling that every marketers,
even indie developers who
are like doing everything as a fun,
they are the product owner.
They should be able to know,
okay, the timing,
building the right profile or
seasonality.
Which is another way you
can get more downloads and
more engaging loyal user pretty much for
free, because you're able to know
when it's the right time, for example,
send a push notification, right?
If it is a rainy day in Seattle you
should probably not say to people okay,
this is the best time for
buying the sun cream because
probably it's not going to work out.
But some companies they do,
because they don't really focus
on the specific user profile.
They just do the very general,
because they have a huge file.
They are huge users.
They don't really care.
But in the mobilizing,
it changed because mobile is getting
smarter every time, every day.
And then, I feeling that If
you are sending someone 11 PM
push notification, it sounds
like crazy but it can work out.
And I know some companies,
they're sending that time and
they're saying you know what?
A 20% discount for the night shoppers.
Because they know those user
keep checking their app
every night before going to sleep.
So then it is probably the best time for
sending push notification.
This old metrics, it tell you you don't
need to rediscover the United America,
you should only look at it, this is
the numbers and this is the user and
they are looking for something.