So that explains how that first
condition is satisfied that it's
basically taking care of
the averaging over noisy transitions.
This second condition is
going to turn out to be, well,
let's find out what it's
going to turn out to be.
So what we're doing here is we're
saying let's apply this operator,
this BTQ operator, or BTQW operator.
And the condition that we need to have
hold is that for any Q, U, S and A,
that if we hold this U fixed, which the
Q in the equation is going to turn out
to be the Q itself, and only vary how
we're computing our one step look ahead.
How we're estimating the Q
values of states that we
are moving to one step from now.
That the difference between those two
Q functions, in this case Q star and
Q, is going to get smaller after we
apply this operator than before,
which is an example of what property?
What is it about the operator
that we're counting on, for
this to be true, that before
we do the one step look ahead,
there are some distance apart,
but after they're closer.
>> Actually I'm not sure.
>> So however far apart the value that
we're using as a one step look ahead,
however far apart it was before,
that after we apply this rule
now it's closer together.
>> Right and it will be because you're
moving in the direction of what the one
step look ahead operator said.
>> Right and so
what property the one step operator,
what property of this
equation is giving us that?
It's the contraction property.
So the fact that this update has
the form of a contraction is what
gives us this property being true,
that after we apply an operator
things get closer together.
And then the third condition was just
the condition on the learning rates,
and we need that for
any kind of Q learning algorithm.
Anyway, at the end of the day,
by separating
the Q learning update equation
into using two different
Q functions in two different ways,
we can prove properties of both of them.
One is playing the role of averaging out
the stochasticity so that we're sort of
acting as if there are expected values
in here, even though there's not.
And then given that,
the other one is acting like the value
iteration operator, the one step backup,
and is contracting with respect to
the value function that you used.
So again the Q functions are being
used in two slightly different ways.
We proved that both of them hold,
and therefore this theorem
gives us that the whole iterative
algorithm is going to converge.
>> Right.
>> So this is all really just a long way
of saying hey, look, because Q learning
can be forced to fit into the scheme,
it's guaranteed to
converge in the limit.
>> So Q learning converges?
>> Q learning converges.
>> I guess we knew that.
>> Yeah, we knew that, and
in fact there's lot of literature
where people have proven
essentially this result over and
over again in slightly different
ways using different tools.
The thing that I like
about this proof is, well,
first of all I read it because
it's in a paper that I wrote.
>> [LAUGH]
>> But second of all,
it breaks things down in this sort of
modular way that we're going to be
able to reuse to prove the convergence
of other Q learning like algorithms.
And that turned out to be
important to prove, for
example, that Q learning in
game scenarios also converges.
>> Huh, but that's in the future?
>> That's in the future.
>> Are we going to re-prove this all
over again when we get to the future?
>> No, we don't have to, because the
generalized theorem holds in both cases.
>> Nice, nice.
>> That's the beauty of
the generalized theorem.
We never have to look at this again.
[LAUGH]
>> Well played, sir.
>> All that's going to matter is,
well it's going to matter that
the operators that we use for
updates are contraction mappings.
>> Okay.
>> And as long as we take care of that,
things are going to be great.
Oh, sorry, non-expansions, as long as
the thing in this position here is
a non-expansion, all will be well.
>> Good, good, so well played.
So we went through all of this so we
never have to go through it all again.
I like that.
>> That is exactly the thought, yeah.
And in fact,
even missing all the details of this,
I just wanted you to be aware of
the fact that these details exist.
The way that we actually use this is at
a much higher level of abstraction where
we just say, hey, we can write down
what we think the Bellman equation is.
We can prove that
the operators that we're using
here are non-expansions, and we're done.
>> And we inherit everything else?
Yeah, it's just like knowing that
the sum of the alphas should go to
infinity but the alpha squared
should not go to infinity.
Once we know that, then it helps us to
decide whether to choose this learning
rate or that learning rate.
It's the same thing, we can't just
substitute max with any arbitrary thing
we want to because it might be
expansive instead of non-expansive.
But so long as we're smart
about the things that we pick,
we know that things
are going to converge.
>> Exactly and so let's maybe go through
some examples of that as a quiz.
>> Sure.