To add Google Services you use a
meta-data tag in your app manifest.xml.
Here I've pasted it in and
you can see it's a meta-data tag
as a child of the application tag.
You're specifying that the name
is the gms.version and
the value is this
integer/google_play_services_version.
This will get replaced for your actual
run time or whenever you compile.
But just leave
integer/google_play_services_version,
and Android studio will do the rest.
In addition to that,
we want to specify find location, and
we do that using
the user's permission tag.
So the user's permission tag goes
here under the application and
above the closing manifest.
And again, we're just saying,
uses permission, and
the permission that we're going to
use is access find location.
If you're asked to do so, like I've
been asked here to do a grade all sync,
go ahead and do that.
And that's, once we're done,
we'll if everything compiles okay.
If you look closely at
the bottom of the screen,
that's where Gradle provides its
update of what it's actually doing.
We can see that it's synced and
everything worked.
We have no errors, so
let's go ahead and write our code.