Okay, so let's suppose that the domain name service
says that 72.14.248.239 is an IP we can use
for Udacity. Great. Now the OS is ready to
establish the connection with Udacity. The actual application data
will be empty at this point, so I'll just
leave this slot empty. This gets the TCP and
header attached to it, which includes the port numbers.
And this then gets the IP header attached to it,
which will include the source and destination IP addresses. The
routing table on my machine will point me toward the IP
address of my modem/router. If my computer doesn't have the
MAC address for the router cached, it could acquire it through
an ARP request. But this MAC address It is now
ready to put the IP packet in an ethernet frame, and
send it over the wire to the modem/router. When this
router receives the packet, he unpacks it from his ethernet frame.
Looking at the destination IP, he recognizes that
this packet is meant for the wide area
network. So he strips off the source IP
and the source port, and replaces them with
his own IP. And a new port number. This changing of the IP address and port
number, that the router does, is called what?
There's a three letter acronym for this too.