I'll walk you through
my implementations.
For getting the session ID we start
by specifying a dictionary of
parameters with just the RequestToken.
And then the API key will be
added by taskForGetMethod.
Then to make the request we'll use
the AuthenticationSessionNew constant.
From this point the rest of
the code is much like before.
We check for an error here.
Otherwise we're looking for
the session ID.
if we successfully find the sessionID,
then we return it as part
of the completion handler.
Okay, now let's look at get userID, it
takes the session ID as a parameter so
we've specified it here.
And we're going to call the task FerGET
method using the APIs account method.
Then in the resulting data,
we look for the ID key.
Let's check.
Is that ID?
Yeah, so the ID key, and
that'll give us the user ID, and
then we pass this back in
the completion handler, and for
this to work you may notice that we
need to cast this into an integer.
So let's go ahead and run this and
see if we make it to the main screen.
I'll click to authenticate,
and I'll click Allow.
And after everything
runs behind the scenes,
our main tab view controller appears.
Nice.
Now I know this may not seem
like a huge breakthrough,
but the big payoff is back in the code.
If we go back to
the LoginViewController,
look how nice the API client hides
away all the networking code.
This is literally all our log-in
view controller needs to see.
And we can go ahead and remove all
the existing functions that we had.
So let's get rid of those.