All right guys.
Fantastic.
Now, I think you've got
the tools you need to detect and
track vehicles in a video stream.
So Arpin.
Could you remind us again?
What are the steps we need to
do to get started on a project?
>> Sure.
First you need to decide
what features to use.
You'll want to try some combination
of color and gradient based features.
But keep in mind that this might
require some experimentation
to decide what works best.
Next, you'll need to choose and
train a classifier.
A linear SVM is probably your best bet
for an ideal combination of speed and
accuracy.
But you are encouraged to experiment
with other classifiers, as well.
Awesome.
So, Drew.
Maybe you could tell us,
then, what happens next.
We've chosen features and
trained a classifier.
Then what do we do?
>> Well, next, you'll implement
a sliding window technique to search for
vehicles in some test images.
You can try multiscale search or
different tiling schemes
to see what works best.
But keep in mind, you'd like to
minimize the number of search windows.
So, for example, you probably don't
need to search for cars in the sky and
the treetops.
Once you've got a working
detection pipeline,
you'll try it on a video stream.
And implement tracking to follow,
detect vehicles.
And reject spurious detections.
>> Awesome.
Well, alright then.
Let's get started on the project