After you've added the code from the
here's what else we need to add in order
to read the remaining attributes and
display them in our text field.
So first we need to
append read gender and
weight in the header,
so it looks like this.
So after ID and name here, let's add in
those last remaining three attributes.
So I'll end the header with this
new line special character.
Now next we want to find the index for
each column following the pattern that
we have here similar for
the idColumnIndex and nameColumnIndex.
So let's build that out.
So to recap, we use the getColumnIndex
method which takes in the name of
the column and returns back to
us the integer index value.
Then, inside the wall loop,
we can use these indices we just
got to extract the string or
integer value of the word at
the current row that the cursor is on.
So we already have that here for
the current ID and the current name.
So let's build it out for
breed, gender and weight.
So for breed, we can use getstring and
for gender and
weight, we used getint because
the values inside them were integers.
So lastly, in order to get our
values to display in the text view,
we're going to need to append them here.
So between each value,
I want to add a delimiter of the dash.
So let's go ahead and run it and
see what these changes look like.
Now all the values that I input
in appear on the screen, and
even my misspelling of poodle.