So every time a hit is sent
from your app to Analytics,
it includes certain
kinds of information.
You get to see which screens or
activities your users went to.
You get geo information,
like their language and their location.
You get device information.
What brands, models, OS.
And you get network info.
So every time a hit goes to Analytics it
carries all this information with it.
So now that we've got some
data in our dashboard,
I'm going to drill down into
the different parts just a bit.
I'm not going to give an exhaustive
tour of the dashboard.
There is like week-long
courses on how to
understand everything in the dashboard,
but I will take you to the key pages.
Let's look at the audience and
see the overview.
And the overview page shows
quite a bit of information.
You can drill down here,
see the country, the city.
Now you all know where I was,
probably no big surprise, the app name.
So you can just drill down through
these things and get the information.
Notice the screen resolution and
see that I went to 2.56 screens per
session at nine sessions and
the average session duration 27 seconds.
That was the overview for the audience.
You can look at the app versions.
Another one that's cool,
of course, is Geo,
which gives you information
about the languages.
In this case only one language.
The location.
You can actually drill
down into the location.
You can just keep drilling down.
At some point you won't be able
to drill down any further.
Another part of the dashboard that
you should get really familiar with
is the Behavior.
Through the Overview
gain a summary of things.
The screens, there's all
the screens the users went to.
And remember this will be
aggregated data for all your users.
because in our cases just the one user,
which is us.
And you can drill down a bit more,
get the average time on screen.
Percent exit is how,
what was the percentage of visits.
This was the last visit to the app.
So back in audiences too, of course,
you can go down into the devices,
Overview, my network operators,
I don't know what they were.
Anyway, you should drill down into
your own data, see what you can see.
So take some time to explore the
different pages in the reporting section
of the Analytics Dashboard,
then take this quiz.
What data do you get with auto
activity tracking is enabled?
Do you get to see users' locations,
their devices, what
buttons they clicked, who uses email
addresses, and do you get to see what
other apps they have on the devices,
whether they were running your app.
Check all that are true.