Let's take a closer look at gradient directions,
especially how they're computed and represented.
How about we use an image that has clearly defined edges and
distinct angles, like this?
Note that we convert the image to double type after reading and
scale it down to a 0 to 1 range.
This makes it easier to track down numerical issues that may crop up.
It also makes it convenient to display,
because imshow assumes a 0 to 1 range for double images.
MATLAB and Octave have a direct way of computing image gradients.
Imgradientxy is the function, it returns a pair of matrices, the first
one being the gradient in x direction and the second one in the y direction.
I'm pretty sure that the default filter used is Sobel, but
you can also mention it explicitly.
Let's try to visualize the gradient images.
But note that imgradientxy does not normalize the gradient
images therefore we must scale them to the appropriate range.
Now why do we need to add 4 and divide by 8?
To understand this, let us consider this a bell operator which looks like this.
Now what happens when this filter interacts with an image, or
an image region, that is black on the left hand side and white on the right?
All these negative coefficients, they get multiplied by 0 and cancel out.
Whereas these positive coefficients get multiplied by 1 and some to 4.
So the total response of the filter at that position would be 4.
Similarly, an image region which has white on the left hand side and
black on the right hand side would result in minus 4.
So our gradient values are in the range minus 4 to plus 4.
If we add 4 to each of these values, the range shifts to 0 to 8.
Hence, dividing by 8 gives us a 0, 1 range.
Enough with the math.
Now what does this look like?
As expected, in the x gradient image, you see the vertical edges show up.
Similarly, you can view the y gradient.
This time the horizontal edges show up more clearly.
Note that on your local machines, you should be able to simply pass in
the expected range and let imshow do the scaling.
If you leave out the limit values and pass in an empty vector,
then imshow will scale the image based on the actual minimum and
maximum values found in the image.
This can give slightly different results.
For instance, say the minimum magnitude found was minus 3.5.
This behavior is similar to what imgsc does,
although that has other options for setting the color map, et cetera.
Okay, now that we have the x and y gradients,
we are interested in computing the overall gradient magnitude and direction.
Fortunately there is a function to do this in one step.
The magnitude return is the Euclidian norm of the gradient in x and
y directions.
As we saw earlier, each of those could have an absolute value of 4.
So the total magnitude values can go from 0 up to 4 times root 2.
And that's what we used to scale it by.
This is what the gradient magnitude looks like.
The edge pixels are not super bright,
which kind of indicates that the edges were not as sharp, but that's okay.
The edges are still distinctly visible.
Remember that the gradient direction is an angle computed as
the tan inverse of y by x gradient values.
The result is returned in degrees ranging from minus 180 to plus 180.
Where 0 degree corresponds with the positive x-axis, and
increasing angle rotates counterclockwise.
The right edge has gradient pointing at 0 degrees.
Gradient values in the plain areas of the image are undefined.
Since they have to be set to some number, they're also 0,
which is why you can't see the gradient values along the right edge.
As I mentioned, angles go counter clockwise, so this is 45 degrees,
90, 135 interestingly,
gradient pointing to the left is at 180 degrees, which is the same as minus 180.
And here are the other angles for good measure.
Now I want you to write a function that finds pixels with
desired gradient direction.
The function should be called select_gdir.
The first couple of arguments are the gradient magnitude and direction images.
The third is the minimum magnitude value we want to consider.
This is to filter out noisy pixels that can have random gradient directions, but
usually low magnitude.
The last two arguments specify the desired gradient range, low to high.
For instance, here we want to look at gradients in the 45 degree angle,
with a plus minus 15 margin.
Note that you need to return a binary image that can be displayed with imshow.
Here's some code to get you started.