Octave is a free and
open source language for numerical and scientific computing.
It is mostly syntax and feature compatible with MATLAB.
You can download it from the GNU Octave website.
Follow the instructions for your corresponding system.
Linux is probably the easiest, and Windows is a bit of a pain.
I am on an OS X machine here.
There is a binary installer for OS X.
But I've had problems with it later on when trying to install packages.
So I prefer the Homebrew route.
If you don't have Homebrew set up already, first install XCode.
Then open up a terminal and
use the Xcode-select command to install command line tools.
Now you can install Homebrew.
You will also need a LaTeX distribution, like MacTeX.
This may take a while to download.
Once you have Xcode, its command line tools, Homebrew, and MapTech installed.
Continue with the instructions on the wiki.
Once you have Octave installed and
it's in your path you should be able to run it by simply typing Octave.
This is the Octave Interpreter.
Similar to the Math Lab command window.
You can type arithmetic expressions, create variables, and
even work with vectors and matrices.
To suppress the result of an expression showing up in the output,
use a semicolon at the end.
You can type exit to come out of the interpreter.
You can also run Octave in GUI-mode.
Note that this might still be an experimental feature, and
tends to break very easily.
You can carry out the same operations here as the console version.
In addition you have a work space which lists the variables currently in memory.
And a file browser showing contents of the current directory.
As in Matlab,
you can read images using the imread command and display them using imshow.
The base installation of Octave does not include any additional packages.
To install a package, we need to use the pkg install command.
The -forge option pulls packages from the online Octave-Forge repository.
Octave-Forge contains an extensive collection of packages.
We are interested in the image package.
Notice that this package has some dependencies.
We can install the image package, along with all its dependencies, namely,
general, control, and signal, in a single command.
Once installed, they should show up in the list of packages.
Now you can load the image package by typing pkg load image, and
then use functions from it like rgb2gray.
It converts a color RGB image into a gray scale or monochrome image.
For more information on the image package, check out it's Octave Forge page.
There is an extensive function reference that you'll need to use frequently.
The Octave Wiki is very useful as well.
It has installation instructions for a number of platforms,
as well as tutorials and examples to help you get started.
Play around with these to become more familiar with the Octave environment.