So, here I am in the command
prompt within the SQLite program,
inside the shelter database.
So, I want to see what tables
are in my database, and I can do so
using the .tables command.
So, as we expect,
it shows all zero of our tables,
because we haven't created any yet.
So, let's take a look at how to do that.
So, before I hit a table
within my shelter database,
I want to actually use
the headphone scenario from before.
And this is because later on,
I want you to come up with
the code to create the pets table.
So, for this example, let's take
a look at the headphone scenario.
So, let's quit out of
the SQLite program.
And then from here, I'm going to
create a new database called store.db.
Nice, so now I'm in SQLite again, but
I'm operating under the store.db.
And just to double check
what tables are under here,
it should be zero, as we expect.
So, before we go on to create the table
within the command prompt here,
let's discuss some details.
So, here'll be the names and
data types for
each of the columns from
our headphones table.
And this is the generic SQLite
instruction in order to create a table.
So, we have the table name,
the column names And
their corresponding data types.
Now, if we decide to call the table for
our headphones specifically,
headphones, we can modify the create
statement to look like this.
So, notice that the SQLite
keywords are capitalized,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And therefore, they're easy to identify.
So, we have create, text and integer.
So, similar to keywords in Java,
such as if, int, and
for, these keywords have special
meaning in the SQL language.
So, CREATE TABLE makes a table and
TEXT and
INTEGER are data types,
ones that we've just talked about.
Now here, headphones is
the name of our table, name,
price style, in_stock and
description are all column names.
So, before we head back into
the terminal, I'm going to go ahead and
add one more column to this table.
An integer called _id.
So, note that this is
another convention.
So, in every table, you should have an
ID that uniquely identifies the object.
And what do I mean by
uniquely identifies?
Well, let's think about it in
terms of our pets example.
So, say we have two pets,
both of them named Bear.
So, the first one is a 215 pound or
98 kilogram, English Mastiff named Bear.
And the second one is a tiny Pomeranian
only at 2 kilograms named Bear as well.
Now if we assume that the name
Bear is a unique identifier for
these dogs,
we would be absolutely wrong.
And say, an eager pet owner
named Sally came in and
wanted to adopt Bear, well Sally could
accidentally end up with a completely
different pet than she intended.
So, this is why, everywhere from deli
counters to say social security numbers,
we use uniquely numbered
entries in a system.
So, this is common practice
that helps us store
unique IDs to help identify products.
So, our headphones should and
will have IDs.
The name _id with underscore in the
beginning is a convention from Android.
So the _id column for
IDs in the SQLite tables for
Android are always called _id.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So, I'm going to be using this term
here, in order to prepare us for
our eventual usage of the SQL
code in the Android app.
All right, so now I'm sure you're
eagerly waiting to see what this
actually looks like when we enter
the command in the terminal.
So, let's go ahead and check that out.
All right, so
back in the command prompt.
I'm going to create the headphones
table now inside my store database.
I can do so
using the CREATE TABLE command.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And we can check that the table
is created using .tables.
Perfect, so it's returned to us
the name of the table, headphones.
Well, that didn't really give
us too much information.
But another command I can use,
is .schema and then headphones,
the name of the table I'm interested in.
And notice here, what this command does,
is it shows me the statement that
was used to create the table.
So now,
a hopeful SQL command that we could use,
would be PRAGMA and
then followed by TABLE_INFO,
followed by the name of the table
within the parentheses.
So, know here,
that this is an SQL command, whereas,
these dot commands here were
SQLite program commands.
So, this command here shows me some
useful information about the name and
type of all my columns, and
it's a pretty easy to read format.
So, now the opposite of creating
a table is dropping a table.
And this means that we're
completely erasing it.
So, this is a command that we'll
have to use with a lot of care.
So from here, if I type DROP TABLE
followed by the name of the table,
hit Enter.
And double check that
the table was removed.
By using our .tables command here.
And notice the headphones
table is just gone.
All right so now you've seen how to make
a table, view a list of all the tables,
as well as,
see what's inside your table.
And then lastly, we've talked
about how to delete that table.
And now since, the ultimate goal here
isn't to make the headphones store app
instead, we want to
make the shelters app.
I want you to go ahead and
write the statement needed to create
a table within your shelter database.
Before you do so, make sure that
your shelter database is open.
So remember, we can do .open and
then open up the shelter database.
And then from here, go ahead and create
the pets table with the correct columns.
Once you've done that, I want you to
use the PRAGMA TABLE_INFO command, and
make sure it matches the output that we
show you in the following quiz slide.
Afterwards, you should copy and
the paste the SQLite
statement that you used to generate
that table and paste it into the quiz.
And one last thing before you head off.
So, I kind of alluded to it earlier,
but you may have noticed the difference
between these capitalized commands,
such as DROP TABLE or CREATE TABLE,
these that end with the semicolon
versus these lowercase commands,
these dot commands that I was using,
such as .table or .open.
So, these dot commands are specific
to the SQLite program, whereas
these capitalized statements that end
with the semicolon are SQL commands,
remember, the structured query language.
So, try not to get these two
types of commands mixed up but
give this a try, and
I'll see you in the following exercise.