So let's take a look at
the solution to that exercise.
So first,
since we'll be using the database helper
throughout this catalog activity,
let's start by making an instance
variable for the database helper.
Let's do that up here, right,
under the catalog activity declaration.
So I might create a private
PetDbHelper instance.
I'm going to call that MdbHelper.
Now I need to instantiate it and
let's do that in the OnCreate method.
So down here,
let's have mdbHelper = new PetDbHelper.
And we'll pass in the context which will
be this, which is our current activity.
Now step 2, is I need to go ahead and
call both insert pet method and
our display database info method.
And I want to do that down here in
our onOptionsItemSeleted method.
So I already have the first
one inside this case and
then let's add the second one.
So that means when the user clicks
on the insert dummy data option.
Both of these methods will be triggered.
Now to actually build out
our insertPet method.
I'll start by getting
a writable database.
So what I've done here is create an
object of the SQLite database class and
we do so by calling this instance of
PetDbHelper and using this method.
Now next I'm going to
make the content values.
But first off let me create
a content values object.
So content values,
let's name the object just values.
And then call that instantiator.
Now next,
let's use the content values put method
to store each of the key value pairs.
As we discussed earlier, remember
that the key is the column header and
the value is whatever the correct
value information is for
the pet we want to enter.
In our case, notice here we're
hard-coding information specifically
about Toto our pet, so information about
his name, breed, gender, and weight.
After we've created our content values
object, we will actually insert
the information into database
by using the insert method.
So down below,
let's use our SQLite database object,
DB calling the insert method.
And the first parameter will
be the name of the table,
followed by null and
then the content values object.
Now I want to capture the value that's
returned by this insert method and
I want to capture it in
a variable called newRowId.
And let's have that be of type long.
So creating this variable allows
us to add an optional log message
at the end of our insert pet method.
And doing so
can help us catch any potential errors.
So with those steps completed,
let's run it on our device.
So with the app running on our device,
here in our catalog activity,
let's test it out.
Click on the overflow menu.
And then click
the Insert Dummy Data option.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Woot!
So notice here the number
of rows increased by one.
And in our log, we should be able to
see all the totals that we've added.
So the log message here that we put
into our insert pet method shows up.
Let's see if we can add a couple more.
So now I should have three
Toto's in my database.
All right, so if I click my heels three
times, let's go on to the next quiz.