One remaining challenge in making our
computer player are situations where it
is obvious to a human player that the
game will be decided in the next move,
but that the computer player cannot
search far enough into the future
to figure out the problem.
This situation is called
the Horizon Effect.
Take a look at this isolation board.
It's O's turn.
Which move should O take?
>> Well,
as soon as O moves diagonally down and
left one, X will only have six
moves as compared to O's seven.
Then O will win.
>> But that is 13 moves in the future.
How did you figure that out?
>> X will be blocked on the wrong
side of the partition and
not be able to reach O.
Both players will have to fill in
the rest of the game board efficiently
in order to have a chance of winning.
That's a great observation, but
our computer player may not see it.
Remember, when we started talking about
having only two seconds to make a move,
we said that our computer player
should only look ahead nine moves.
It won't see the end game coming.
>> But with iterative deepening,
it might be able to go deeper.
The branching factor towards the end
of the game is much smaller.
True, however, imagine that we have
already reached the next to last
depth of our search tree
in the time we have.
We have to evaluate the goodness
of the children of this node.
Which move would our my moves
evaluation function pick?
>> Well, certainly not the winning move.
The evaluation function will return
three for the winning move, but
I can see a couple moves
that would be preferred.
>> Going the whole way to
the right gives a five.
And going diagonally left and
down two spaces gives us six.
Yet both of these moves
will result in a loss.
>> Yep.
Going to the right will get O on
the wrong side of the partition.
Going to the left causes O to create
another partition with even less moves.