Let's look at the example
of image intensity.
Now most of the time, again, if you
remember our earlier work on looking at
image intensities in images,
mostly, if in fact, an image
intensity changes because we have more
bright pixels or less bright pixels.
So in essence, mostly this would require
us to be invariant to additive and
multiplicative changes
in image intensity.
And most of the time
the competition we're looking at,
since it's dependent on the gradient
information, would be invariant as long
as at any point within the neighborhood,
irrespective of the brightness at that
point, the invariance or the gradients
at that point are the same.
So again, essentially what
happens at any point in an image,
as long as we are working with
derivatives, we should be able to kind
of compute the information, the response
function, response function's purely
being dependent on the derivatives,
would not care if the image intensity of
the region that we're looking at is
much larger from one to the other.
So in essence,
what we're just repeating here is,
it would be invariance to
any kind of intensity shift,
if you add a constant derivatives
actually still won't care.
And similarly, if there was a scale
again the derivatives would not
be impacted, and all of that actually
still same results would appear.
And this is demonstrated by again,
our example.
Basically I look at
the response function r, and
depends on where our threshold, right.
Because if my threshold at that level,
and
if these two points are the ones that
I'm looking for, I'll still detect them.
But if I choose a threshold and
now somebody has scaled my intensity
variations, which will impact this.
Then it might actually cause a problem.
So then we basically would have to
have an adaptive threshold that
knows more about the scaling of
the intensities in an image.
But otherwise we still should be able to
find, because the shape of the response
one, response over the whole
sequence should still be the same.