So now let's actually start
understanding how to build
a simple stereo system.
Let's take our coordinate axis, here
I just put a simple left camera here.
I'm going to put them at coordinate
axis point 0.00, which is here.
Now let's imagine I can basically
translate this viewpoint by amount Tx
just in the X-axis,
no change in y to another location here.
So now, I have another camera, which
is located just Tx in this direction
farther from where the original
one was at zero, zero.
So both the cameras
are exactly the same.
They're just now translated
by a certain distance.
And I have of course, a new camera
which has its own coordinate axis.
So right camera is simply just looking
at the same view you just translated by
x along the x directions.
Everything else is the same.
In this case, the focal length is
the same orientation is the same,
everything is the same.
Let's look at this scene from the top.
Just looking at the X-Z plane.
So here again, I have a left camera.
Here now,
I have actually listed the focal length.
Right camera.
Again, we know the focal length here.
So, of course, the two cameras are
translated by distance Tx along x-axis.
Tx is also know as the baseline.
We have a point, X, Y, Z.
Of course, that point appears and
this viewpoint here we'll point,
call this Xl for the left image,
a location just an x-axis.
Looking down on X, Y is pointing
outwards, we're not change,
looking any changes in y on this one.
So then that point,
appears as Xr on this viewpoint here.
Question now of course is if I
know Xl and Xr, can I compute Z?
Which would basically be the depth
of this point here, right?
Now this is where actually we can
bring back simple geometry to help us.
So let's look at this again back
into our 3D simple stereo system.
I have a point in 3D,
that ray of light goes from this camera,
goes through this image and
hits that and
another one across just like we
saw in the previous example.
And of course, that's Xl and there
would be an X right here for this one.
Same kind of setup as before.
Now we can actually compute,
you link the same equations we looked
at at the beginning of this lecture.
That Xl basically would
be f X over Z and
yl would be Y over Z.
Right?
That's for this point here.
And in this case, of course,
you can also do the Y.
In this case of course,
yl is the same as yr.
The same point in the right camera,
Xr is different and Xl is not.
So here is one thing we can start doing.
Basically, we know that this
camera is moved by a distance Tx.
Well, that suggests something
to us we can actually use.
That basically, if I was to move
this point here by that same amount,
nothing else is changing,
the same point would appear.
So, in essence, the converse of me
moving the camera by distance Tx is
me moving this point in
the other direction minus Tx and
actually taking another picture.
So now basically saying is rather than
taking two pictures by moving the camera
by distance Tx, I'm just moving
the point minus Tx in the opposite
direction and taking another pictures.
So basically,
that means is now I have a point T,
a point here that should
be visible in this one.
So we don't have to look at this camera.
And of course,
now this ray is coming in this way,
implying that Xr is actually moved
there, same translation as minus Tx.
So now, I can basically compute Xr.
Again f,
X is now just this location x here minus
Tx in X direction divided by Z.
So that's basically, becomes my Xr.
Yr is the same,
we haven't changed anything in the Y.
So basically, this starts giving me
a very interesting way of comparing both
Xl and Xr which are now different
just by the top numerator.