After seeing the hash symbol, you might
be wondering what other kinds of symbols
a URIMatcher uses as special symbols.
URIMatchers have matching capabilities
similar to regex pattern matching, but
it's a quite bit simpler.
Regular expressions match a lot
of special characters, but
a URIMatcher recognizes only two
wildcard characters, an asterisk and
that hash symbol that you just saw.
The hash symbol can stand for
an integer of any length.
And the asterisk stands in for
a string of any length.
And these symbols can be
combined with each other or
specific URI path segments to
define a complete URI structure.
Here are some examples.
These are two specific
URIs that you've seen.
The first one points to
the complete directory of tasks.
And the second to a row in
the directory with ID 2.
In the next example, I'm using the #
symbol, which matches any number.
This path starts off with tasks.
And this could be followed by an
integer, whether that's the id 2, 3, or
9042.
Because of that hash symbol,
any number will fit this pattern.
There's also the asterisk,
which stands in for any string.
So for this URI,
the path again starts again with tasks.
Then it can be followed by,
well, any string.
For example,
you could have task's priority, or
this string could be a task description.
Or just some random letters.
Any string will fit this pattern.
And then finally, here's an example
where we combine these characters,
the hash and the asterisks, together.
This path structure will start with any
string, then a segment named other,
and then finally an integer at the end.
And these wildcard characters can
be combined in any path you need to
distinguish between
different types of URIs.
For the todo list app, we'll be
interested in displaying the contents of
a cursor that contains data for
all of our tasks.
So we'll need to define a URI that
identifies the entire tasks directory.
Then, for doing things like
deleting an individual task,
we'll also want to define a URI that
identifies a single row of data.
So in this next quiz, you'll be asked
to choose the best URI structures
to represent these two types of data.