Learning to code is hard and
you will feel confusion and
you will feel frustration.
But that is okay, that's to be expected.
What isn't okay is
when these confusion or
frustration is allowed to turn into
something worse like disappointment,
or anger, or terror, or
whatever, whatever that guy is.
Certainly doesn't look happy.
And since you're watching this right
now, you want to learn to code.
But if you start feeling
anything like this,
you're probably going to want to quit.
So, you should try your best to
avoid letting this, turn into this.
So, let me tell you some strategies for
how to stick with it.
When you start feeling frustrated or
confused, there are a few
things you can do.
First, you should always ask for help.
Typing your problem into a Google
search bar, will often solve it.
And, you can also go to
the Udacity discussion forums.
Your classmates
are an incredible resource.
The second thing you can
do is just take a break.
Press that pause button.
Try to learn when you're frustrated
can be really counterproductive.
Don't hesitate to stop and
come back the next day.
The third thing you can do, and this is
something a lot of people have trouble
with, but which is really useful,
is you can just keep going.
Look at answers when they're available.
Try to learn from them.
Go on without them if they're not.
Remember, you are not meant to be an
expert in this nanodegree, so sometimes
the best move will be to just go on and
accept a little temporary confusion.
To help you know when you should
feel comfortable continuing,
I'm going to occasionally be asking you
to rate yourself on the spectrum of
expertise from ignorance to fluency.
And then based on your responses,
I'm going to give you feedback
about what you should do next.
Let's try that out right now.