The first statement, a packet filtering
firewall is typically configured
to filter packets going
in both directions.
This is true.
In fact,
all firewalls regardless of which type
is configured to check
traffic in both directions.
The second statement, a prime
disadvantage of an application-level
gateway is the additional processing
overhead on each connection.
This is true.
We just discussed this.
The third statement, a packet filtering
firewall can decide if the current
packet is allowed based on another
packet that it has just examined.
This is false because a packet
filtering firewall makes decisions
based only on the current packet.
The fourth statement, a stateful
inspection firewall needs to keep track
of information of an active connection
in order to decide the current packet.
This is true, because a stateful
inspection firewall decides on a packet
based on the context of
the current connection.