All right, so
do you have an answer for this quiz?
>> I don't but
I think I know how to get one.
>> Let's go for it.
>> Okay, so basically your
asking me to estimate from data.
So you really, what your really doing is
asking me to do an expectation, right?
>> Right.
because that's what we're trying to
estimate is an expectation.
Uh-huh.
>> Right, and
the way you do that is
you just average things.
>> Yeah.
>> So I should just be able to do that.
So I can look at episode one and
I can see what the value for
S1 turned out to be.
And because you were so
nice and made gamma equal to 1,
I can basically just add up
the numbers on the arrows, right?
>> Yeah.
>> So the value to S1 in episode
one is 2.
>> Good.
>> And
the value to S1 in episode 2 is 11.
>> Good.
>> And
the value to S1 in episode 3 is 2 again.
>> Good.
>> All right.
So then if I wanted to know what
an appropriate estimate was after
3 episodes, I would just
average those three numbers.
I would get 5.
>> Is that right?
>> Yeah, so 15 over 3 which is 5.
>> Nice.
Okay, so then for 4 I see 2 again and
so that would be 17 over 4.
>> Good.
>> Which is a number.
[LAUGH] 4.25.
>> Good.
Yeah, that's what I was looking for,
nicely done.
>> Oh, so in fact I could do this for
one episode, or two episodes.
>> That's right, in fact what we're
going to work up to next is how we can
incrementally compute an estimate for
the value of a state,
given the previous estimate.
Given after 3 episodes, how do we get 4.
And 4 how do we get 5?
And 5 how do we get 6?
And then 10,000 how do we get 10,001?
>> Well, can I ask you a question?
>> Sure.
>> I'm curious how close we came.
You go from episode 3 to episode
4 you went from 5 to 4.25.
That's kind of a big jump.
So, do your remember from the last quiz,
what the last value of S1 was?
I think it was 2.
something.
>> 2.9, that's right.
>> Oh, it was 2.9.
>> Yeah, so in principle,
with an infinite amount of data,
that's what we should get.
We should get 2.9 as our estimate for
S1.
In this particular case,
we're actually a little bit high.
Why do you suppose we're
a little bit high?
>> Because we just haven't seen
enough data yet, we saw 11 once.
And, so it looks like for 3 episodes,
11 happens a third of the time
instead of a tenth of the time.
>> That's right.
Yeah, so
we have kind of an over-representation
of the higher reward.
So our estimate ends
up being skewed high.
>> Okay, that makes sense.
In the limit it should
all start to work out and
we'll get one-tenth plus elevens.
But in this case we got, I don't know.
Let's call it lucky.
We got a higher reward than
the expectation would predict.
>> Hm.
Okay.