Hi, my name is Dhruv.
I'm a full-stack engineer
here you know Udacity.
>> And I'm Philip.
I'm a coach in the full-stack team.
>> And
I'm going to be interviewing Philip for
a full-stack engineering position.
All right, with that let's get
started with the first question.
>> Mm-hm.
>> All right.
Are you comfortable with Python,
first of all, Philip?
>> Yeah, I am.
>> All right, perfect.
So our first question we're going to
be writing a simple Python method.
I want you to write a method
that takes in a string.
>> Okay.
>> And tells me whether or
not it's a palindrome.
>> Okay.
>> Do you know what a palindrome is?
>> Yeah it's just like a string that's
the same forwards or backwards.
>> Right.
So examples are-
>> Like race car was.
Yeah.
Do you care if it has spaces in it
or not?
>> To begin with let's
not worry about spaces.
We'll do that if we have time.
>> Cool, cool.
All right.
>> So yeah, let's get started.
>> All right.
Do you care what I name this
method or procedure?
>> No, no I don't.
>> All right then.
>> It should return
a boolean by the way.
>> Okay, got it.
So we'll call it is_palindrome.
>> Okay.
>> You know when I name a method, I
like to give it a name that's readable.
So yeah.
And it'll take in the string called s.
>> S.
Okay.
>> Okay, so we'll just go by the
definition of palindrome just to keep
things simple.
We'll just
say return s = =.
And what I'm doing here is I'm going to
use Python string slicing notation just
to reverse the string and see if
it's the same in either direction.
>> Okay.
Well that was quick.
Can you show me what it would look
like without this double colon syntax?
>> You mean like reverse
it in a different way?
>> Mm-hm.
>> Hm.
So, presumably strings have a reverse
method on them, I might try that.
>> Okay.
>> That might be more readable to people
who aren't Pythonistas.
>> Yeah exactly,
if I'm coming from a different language,
I might not know this immediately.
So what you're saying you would
do is you would first reverse it.
Let's assume strings have a reverse
method and go from there.
>> Okay.
>> So let's say Python
gives us a reverse method,
reverse of string gives us a new string.
>> Yeah.
>> And show me how you would
do it if you had that.
>> Okay.
So assuming we just have a method
called reverse, do you mean a method on
the string or just a function that you
call with the string as the parameter?
>> The function you call with
the string as a parameter.
>> Okay, cool.
So we just call it.
And so this presumably returns s,
it doesn't modify s, okay.
>> Okay, perfect.
Now let's take into the case
where you now have spaces.
So an example would be a sentence
like let's see can I get that.
>> Sure.
>> A man, a plan,
a canal, Panama.
>> Got it.
>> And so if we read this backwards,
a man, a P-L-A-N, plan,
a C-A-N-A-L, canal, P-A-N-A-M-A, Panama.
>> Okay.
So I guess another way to
phrase this question would be,
is it a palindrome if
you ignore the spaces?
>> Yes.
>> Okay, sure I can do that.
So the way I do it is,
before we do this check you've got
to keep this same basic structure.
But before we do this check what I'd
want to do is just remove the spaces
from the string s.
>> Okay.
>> So that would look like this.
S, I'll assign it to s.strip,
which is another one of, or one second.
Oops.
Let's keep our syntax correct.
But yeah, this is just a built-in
string method in Python so
it's super convenient.
Yeah, okay.
>> Okay.
Perfect.
Can you write me one or
two tests that would test this code to
make sure it's working as expected?
>> Yeah.
So what I would do?
I guess I would just, let's assume
this is like a Python file, right?
There's more code here.
So what I would do is I would just call
the function with a is_palindrome.
So an important thing to do is to guess
positive cases and negative cases so
you can see if it works correctly,
if it is a palindrome and
if it's not a palindrome.
>> Okay
>> So I'll do both of those.
So we'll start with the one we'd already
said from the beginning like racecar.
When I'm nervous my handwriting gets
bad so let me know if it's okay.
So I guess we'll just print this.
And we can say, well I guess if this
is a real example I'd do two print
statements like the first would
be like expected result, true.
And that way when I print the next line,
my output's really readable.
So yeah, we'll do that first.
So it would be like print,
test case one, Expected result is true.
Yeah, and so another case,
we'll do the Panama example.
>> Okay.
>> Just because that gets us
the case with the spaces.
>> Okay.
>> And, like I said, I want to
do some negative examples, too.
So I'd do the same thing but
my testing would be like abc.
And I guess you could do
like an edge case too.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So
also test with just an empty string.
>> Okay.
>> Which in this,
I guess we haven't defined it but
it should be a palindrome.
>> Yeah, fair enough.
Okay.
So can you tell
me what the runtime of
this method is now?
>> Let's see.
So starting from the top,
we'll go line by line.
So string.strip,
this is in the standard library I didn't
write it but I can guess how it works.
Like what I imagine it does is
it goes character by character,
and it kind of builds a new string.
So it probably has to go through
the entire string once, so
it's probably an o of n.
So I'll just write it over here kind of,
we have o of n.
That's the first step.
And then it compares the two strings
to see if they're equal for equal
which means it has to iterate through
the two strings at the same time.
That's also o of n on
the size of the string.
So o of n plus o of n equals o of n.
>> Okay perfect, and
what's the memory consumption?
>> Okay so in the beginning we
have the size of the string s,
which is I guess n.
Then we have to I guess have two
versions of it the reversed and
the normal string.
So two n, which I guess implies
down the end and big O.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> All right, perfect.