[Thrun] And the answer is simply 0, without much math.
The word "perfect" occurs in movie, but the word "storm" has never been seen before.
Therefore, the maximum likelihood estimate we will assign a 0 probability to the word "storm,"
which will make the total product of the various factors involved in "storm" just 0.
That is not the case for song.
There is a non-zero probability for "perfect" and a non-zero probability for "storm."
Hence, it will have a non-zero probability.
After normalization this will become 1 and this will become 0.
So without much math I can calculate the correct posterior
under the maximum likelihood model, which of course is disappointing
because Perfect Storm is actually a movie title.