At this point you
should have two things.
The first is the Droid Terms Example
app, downloaded onto your phone.
You're not downloading the code,
just the APK.
This app, which you did not create, will
just by downloading it onto your phone,
store all of this data onto the phone.
The second thing that you have is
code with which to create quiz app.
And right now that
code has a probation to
access the content provider
connected to Droid Terms Example.
And this is where it gives you the
ability to access Droid Terms Examples
app data.
Okay, so there are five steps to adding
content providers access to the app.
Like you've done the first one.
The next three steps are shown
here in these two lines of code.
This code accesses the correct content
provider and grabs some data from it.
We've got some new concepts
of vocabulary here, so
I'm going to break it down.
The first new concept
is the ContentResolver.
So our original diagram
is fairly simplistic.
Let's look at this drawing
that we saw before.
The more accurate version
of this drawing is this.
And this drawing involves
a content resolver.
So what's the purpose of having
this class sit between your app and
direct access to the content provider?
If you think about it, there
are multiple content providers on your
phone, and
you add more content providers
when you download apps that store local
data, which use content providers.
Besides the DroidTermsExample
content provider, you have a content
provider for contacts, your device
has one for user files of the device,
one that keeps track of user alarms,
the calendar provider, and some others.
Also, your app is not the only
app running on the device.
There are other apps that might also
be using content providers in parallel.
Managing what content providers
are talking to what apps, and
keeping all the data in sync,
could turn into a huge traffic jam.
That's where the content
resolver comes in.
The content resolver acts as
an intermediary between each app and
the content provider, or
providers, it wants to access.
It handles inter-process communication
and keeps everything in sync and
running smoothly.
Even if you have five processes
accessing two content providers.
So wherever you want to
use a Content Provider,
you'll need to do it
through a ContentResolver.
Okay, so now you know what
this first line is doing,
getting us a reference to
the system's Content Resolver.
This is the next step for
accessing the Content Provider.