Run your app on local host and
then use the API's explorer
to create a conference.
And then go to the Admin console to
check that the conference was created
as expected.
You can also use the create conference
page in the app to create and
save a conference.
The conference will be created
because the conference page sends
a call to the Save Conference function
which you've now implemented.
But the Show Conferences
page will not yet
work because you have not yet
implemented the function that it calls,
the functions to query
an output conference records.
So no matter whether you create your
conference in the API's explorer or
in the Create Conference page, you'll
need to use the data store viewer and
the Admin console to check that
the conference got created.