So let's match the activity
with the description.
First one, boy in the middle.
This means that covertly changing
a computer's network routing.
That's D.
Clickjacking, it means that it fool the
user into clicking something that is not
as it is portrayed.
So that's E.
Man in the browser.
It means that the APT can
modify the web pages covertly.
For example,
when the user enters data in a web form,
the APT can change the data
without the user knowing about it.
So that's B.
Man in the middle.
This means that the APT
can intercept traffic and
listen in on conversations,
so that's eavesdrops, A.
Keyloggers, this means that the APT can
covertly record keystrokes by the user.
So that's C.