Perhaps the traveling salesman problem
can't be approximated in general.
But if we insist that the cost function
obey the triangle inequality, as it does
in many practical applications,
then we can find an approximation.
The triangle inequality, by the way,
just says that it's never faster to go
from one vertex to another
via a third vertex.
Here's the approximation algorithm.
We start by building
a minimum spanning tree.
The usual approach here is to use one of
the greedy algorIthms, either of Kruskal
or Prim that are typically taught
in an undergraduate class.
In Kruskal's algorithm, the idea is to
simply take the cheapest edge between
two unconnected vertices and add that
to the graph until a tree is formed.
Thus we might start by adding this
edge here, then this edge here, and so
on and so forth.
Here I connected these two components.
And we just keep going
until we've formed a tree.
Next, we run a depth-first
search on the tree,
keeping track of the order in
which the vertices are discovered.
For this example, let's label
the vertices with the letters of
the alphabet, and
start from this vertex c over here.
Then the discovery order
would go something like this.
From c we go to b and then to e and
then to h and then to i and
we would record that like so.
At that point we'd turn back to h but
since we've already discovered it,
we don't write it down.
Instead we write down
the next vertex we visit j.
And this process continues.
We skip over h and e on the way to d,
and then we'd go to g and
f, and then skip over g and
d on our way up to a.
And then we skip over
all these vertices,
which we've already visited,
to get back to our original vertex c.
Finally, the algorithm
returns the list of vertices,
in this discovery order,
as the Hamiltonian cycle.
Note that this cycle follows
along the tree from c to b
to e to h to i, but
instead of going back to h,
it goes directly to j,
then it goes directly to d, and so on.
This cycle always seems
to be taking short cuts,
compared to the traversal that
the depth for search performed.
For the general traveling salesman
problem, we can't be sure that these
are in fact shortcuts, because we
can't assume the triangle inequality.
Where we do have the triangle
inequality, however, all of these will
be shortcuts, and as we'll see,
that will be the key to the analysis.