Consider a block row
partitioning of a matrix for
a sparse matrix-vector multiply.
Recall your two computational goals.
The first is to achieve load balance,
and
the second is to reduce communication.
So this is where we started,
then I introduced the graph
partitioning problem.
For this problem I said you want to
divide up the vertices into partitions
so that the partitions
are approximately balanced.
I also said you want to
minimize the edge cuts.
Here's my question.
Is the graph partitioning
problem as I formalized it,
the same thing as the goals for
a sparse matrix vector multiply?
Choose your answer, yes or no.
And then explain yourself in this box.