So, unfortunately.
Not unfortunately.
Necessarily we have to introduce a little bit of notation and mathematics in
order to make it easier to understand, what this reflectance map is.
So we're going to start by assuming we have a surface z of x, y.
Right? So here we have z in this direction.
X and y in that direction.
And you have some surface.
As you move in say, the x direction and the y direction.
Your z value changes and
in fact, you can talk about how z changes as you move an x and
y, that would be the partial derivatives of z with a spec to x and a spec to y.
And we are going to find two variables referred to as p and
q to represent these derivatives.
Now there is a little bit is ambiguity in the literature.
When I learned it from Burtoll, p was the partial of z with respect to x.
Q is the partial of z with respect to y.
As I was rummaging around the web to see how people talk about this all of
sudden sometimes people use the negative of the partial of
z with respect to x and the partial of z respect to y.
And it turns out when you do it as the negative it makes some
formulations a little bit easier.
So I'm going to use it as the negative, but
you can use it either way as long as you're consistent.