That question really put
your knowledge of for
loops, functions, lists, and a number
of other programming foundations you've
learned about to the test.
I hope you were able to figure this
one out but if not, no worries.
This was a pretty tough question.
Let's go over the solution now.
As we know,
we take in as inputs ml_string,
or the string which can contain
replacement words, and parts_of_speech,
or the list of acceptable
replacement words.
As we work through writing code for
this function,
here's an example ml_string and
parts_of_speech that we can reference.
The first thing we want to do is
convert ml_string into a list so
we can iterate over it, and we'll do
that by using the split function.
Now, we want to iterate over
each element in ml_string.
I set up this for-loop, which will
allow me to go through each word of
the newly converted list, ml_string.
Now, I assign this variable,
replacement, equal to the value of
word_in_pos called on the current word
we're looking at with the parts
of speech list passed in.
So if word contains a part of speech,
replacement will be equal to that.
So if place,
from the example ml_string was passed in
with the example parts of speech list,
replacement would be equal to place.
And if ADJECTIVE with an exclamation
mark, were passed with parts_of_speech,
it would be equal to just ADJECTIVE
with no exclamation mark.
Now, if the word wasn't in
parts_of_speech, for example is and
really, our variable replacement
would be set to the value None.
All right,
now that we have our replacement
variables set, let's use it in our code.
Here, we check if replacement
is not equal to None.
So, if replacement is equal to a part
of speech, like PLACE or ADJECTIVE,
we'll then replace the part of speech
in word with the string Corgi and
this will let us keep our punctuation.
Then, we'll add word to our
list replaced by using append,
because we want to build up our list
in the same order as ml_string.
All right, cool.
Now that we've added words that contain
parts of speech to our list replaced,
we just need to add code for
words that don't.
So if the word doesn't contain a parts
of speech we'll just add the word to
replaced.
Now, we just convert the newly replaced
list to a string and then return it.
That's it.
We've built a madlibs generator that
will replace instances of any word in
part of the speech with the string
Corgi, which will include punctuation.
Now, let's find out how to run this
program on our local machines with
user input rather than Corgi which,
as you'll see,
will involve just adding
one line of code.