So like I said, when you do this, you end up with this gradient function.
And of course, we do this both in the x direction and the y direction.
And, you know, we now have this problem of correlation versus convolution.
Well, if this is the x direction, if x goes positive this way,
this is a correlation filter.
By the way, this picture is what this looks like as an image.
Okay?
So these zero values on the outside, that's these gray, and
where it goes negative is negative and where it goes positive is positive.
In the y direction, which way is positive is always a problem because,
like we said, y can go up or y can go down.
You know, the main issue of course, is that it, it, it goes vertically.
So those are our two operators.
So that's how you would use a Gaussian in order to get some smooth derivatives.
But there is this question of how big a Gaussian should we use?
You might remember from filtering that we could pick different size Gaussians,
and here again is the fspecial being used, to get different sigmas.
And what happens is, you get more or less smooth versions of the image.
The same is true when we compute derivatives, right?
We can change the sigma, the size of the Gaussian.
And when you do that, you'll get sort of enhancing the, the magnitudes of these
derivatives as a function of sort of how quickly the image varies over space.
All right?
So with a small sigma,
all of this fine texture in here shows up everywhere in here.
In fact, even this little texture in here shows up in there.
But if I use a bigger sigma, okay?
So this area here you see there's a whole lot less going on there,
because we smoothed away most of that small variation.
So one way of thinking about this, smaller values, finer features are going to
be detected and larger values, only the larger scale edges will be detected.