Let's use the Ember CLI to
generate the service for us.
Now that the service exists,
we can move the data from
the individual routes into the service.
The instructions say to put
everything in a bricks property, so
I'll just move everything over.
So here's the data from
the bricks a bunch store.
And the blue and green brick data
is from the lots of brick store.
We're actually almost
all done with this quiz.
Now that the warehouse
manages all of the data,
each route just needs to be updated
to retrieve the data from here.
I've injected the brick warehouse
service into both route files, and
I'm referencing it as just warehouse.
Now instead of having all
of this hard coded data,
let's just get it from the warehouse.
In the bricks a bunch route,
I'm calling this method, that I need
to create on the warehouse, service.
This just returns the red
bricks from the list of bricks.
I'm making this method on the warehouse
instead of accessing the red bricks
directly, because we want our warehouse
to be in charge of handing out the data.
This way, if the service needs to record
whenever the red bricks are accessed,
we can just add a line to this function.
It's a separation of concerns.
The service is in charge of all the data
and the route just asks the service for
data, instead of accessing it directly.
Let's do the same thing with
the lots of bricks route.
Just like with bricks a bunch, I've
replaced all the hard coded data with
a call to a method on the warehouse.
This function needs to
be created over there.
So all this function does is return
the complete list of bricks.
So, visually speaking,
our app is the same to customers.
But architecturally it's more organized,
with a service being in charge of
all of the data, and the routes
are just accessing that service.
Now go forth and make your apps
more organized with services.