As I mentioned in the previous lesson,
because of my background, I'll be using
a retail scenario as an example for
working through the concepts.
But keep in mind that you should be able
to easily translate these concepts to
whatever area you work in.
For example, when we talk about
customers, you may be thinking of
students, employees, people visiting
a website, or responders to a survey.
When we talk about stores,
you can think school sites, hospitals,
airports, or
just about anything that has locations.
The point is that you will want to
gather whatever data is relevant
to your area of analysis.
In our case, we will look at what kinds
of data are typically available for
analyzing results for retail stores.
One thing to consider when you begin
your search for the right data
is to understand the objective for the
segmentation you're trying to create.
In the case of retail stores, we may
want to have segments that will help
management provide a benchmarking
system to understand and
evaluate the store performance.
Or we may want our segments to help make
marketing or product pricing decisions.
Or a third objective could be to
help managers determine the best
product allocation and
space planning for each store.
If you think about these objectives,
they are all a bit different.
And the final clustering solution
could look different for each one.
So if you think of what
data might be needed for
a specific objective versus all of
the data that might be available,
it will help you fine tune your search,
so
that you don't spend extra time getting
data together that you may not need.