So you've seen how to make projections,
selection and selection arguments, and
then add them to a query statement.
Now it's time to do that for
your pets app.
Remember, the visual here, and what
we'll be doing in the next exercise,
are not the final states of the app.
Instead, this visual corresponds with
what we'll see at the end of lesson two.
So later on in a future lesson, we'll
learn how to create a beautiful UI for
the pets catalog activity.
But for now I just want you to focus
on reading data from the database and
then putting that information
out into this text field.
In this case I want you to show just
basic information about the pets coming
from the pets database.
Let's move forward making incremental
steps building out a more detailed UI,
that will show more information about
the pets coming from the database table.
In our catalog activity we're going to
replace the sloppy raw query method call
with the correct call to the query
method of the SQLite database class.
Let's go ahead and delete this one.
To start writing the query method you
need to first write the projection and
any selection that's needed.
To help you with that,
take a look at the final app state.
Here's with the apps state will look
like by the end of this exercise.
Notice what shown in
the text output here.
Do you need to select any
specific rows or columns?
And if so, you should create a
projection and selections appropriately.
Next step, you need to call the query
method with the correct parameters.
Remember, if you don't
need to use a parameter,
you can simply pass in the value null.
So I've linked both the documentation
about the SQLite query method and
the tutorial example down below.
Now here's the state of the app
after this exercise, and
notice that nothing new appears on
the screen because we're just issuing
a query call, which is similar
to our old raw query call.
And you'll be learning how to
print out the values later on.
Here's what I'd like you to do for
this exercise.
Modify the catalog activity, so
that the result looks like this.
In order to do so,
replace the SQLite database,
rawQuery line with a call to
our query method instead.
If you need, specify a projection,
selection, and selection arguments as
well as any other variables that you'll
need in order to make this happen.
Final note,
the UI should stay the same as before.
Number of rows in your database table
may differ, but that's totally okay.