We've now looked at the central
challenges facing EMR designers.
And have considered some
innovative approaches,
particularly to the data
collection problems.
There's some additional material in
the text about data visualization you
should review.
In particular, view the medication
reconciliation video from Dr.
Shneiderman's group at
the University of Maryland.
New challenges arise as the
reimbursement system moves from pay for
procedure to pay for performance.
Novel informatics tools are required
to overcome these challenges.
And, as you'll see later on, are usually
provided by separate systems,
since virtually all EMRs were designed
for the historic payment model.
The Marshfield Clinic, the organization
whose exceptional performance in the PGP
demo we discussed earlier,
has historically developed its own EHR.
The latest version introduced
in HIMS 2015 features a fully
integrated set of these tools.