This is what we're going to cover and
in lesson two.
First, we're going to show
the quantity and then an order button.
Then, we're going to
show the price as well.
Next we're going to add a plus and
a minus button so
that when you tap on either of
these the quantity changes.
After that, we're going to take these
buttons and rotate them horizontally so
they show up like this for
the quantity picker.
And lastly, we're going to adjust
the way that the price is displayed and
we'll also move the order button
down to the bottom of the screen.
This is what the app is going to
look like by the end of Lesson two.
Along the way we're going to learn
about Java concepts like variables and
data types.
That way when we click on the plus or
the minus button we'll be able to
update the quantity or if click
on the order button we'll be able to
calculate and display the price here.
Now we're going to just focus on
the first stage of our app and
then slowly build up from there.
I'd like you to plan how you're
going to build up this layout.
The app displays quantity 0 and
then an order button.
If you're stuck try going,
through the three steps for
creating a layout that we went
over in the practice set.
Select the views you want, position
the view, and then style the views.
In this planning stage, I'll ask for
you to write a couple words for
each of these.
It's generally a good habit to plan out
how you're going to build something,
before you actually go and code it.
Otherwise, you might get lost
in all the details of the code.
Which views do we need here?
Do we need text views, image views, etc.
Step two.
For positioning the views,
which view group will be the root view?
Feel free to add other comments
about how to position these views.
Finally for
step three we need to style the views.
Is there anything we need to do here?
Write your comments below,
on how we need to change the view so
that they look like this.