But we would also want to
drill a little further down
into the details to confirm
this reasonableness.
Let's take a look at the single variable
growing season length by cluster.
Now as an aside,
I previously said it is best validate
your clusters using variables
that were not directly included
in the cluster modeling process.
In some cases though, the best
variables are the ones that you used.
In our example, since climate is really
built around just a few metrics,
we are using some that we have used
directly in creating the model.
Let's add a new sheet to Tableau.
And you can create the visualization
by dropping the cluster ID
into the columns.
In the growing season
length into the rows.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
It will sum these up by default,
which seems to show some distinctness
around a few of the clusters.
But since it's a sum,
that could be just because of
the number of stores in a cluster.
A better validation visualization would
be using the box-and-whisker plot type.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
You'll need to uncheck aggregate
measures to get it to show the clusters
separately.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>From this visualization,
we can easily see that the behavior
of the clusters is different.
Cluster one obviously has
the longest growing season.
And clusters four, five and
ten have the shortest.
By referring back to our map,
this makes total sense.
Since cluster one is in Florida and
four,
five and
ten are in the northern most states.