We typically report the results of one way ANOVA like this. Our F statistic as
a function of our two degrees of freedom, between and within, our p value, and
eta squared. Note that when we're doing ANOVA by hand, we can't find the exact
p value. This is the same as with the t test. We only know that our p value is
less than .05, our alpha level, because our f statistic is greater than the f
critical value. If we're using software, it'll be the same thing, except we can
calculate the exact p value. Notice that we frequently used small samples in
our examples and problem sets. However, we wouldn't normally use such small
samples, especially in real research. But if we use large samples, we can't do
ANOVA by hand. That would just take too long. We would use software instead.
When we use software, we don't care as much about the intermediate steps.
Really, we just want to compare the p value with alpha. We know that if p is
less than alpha, we'll reject the null. Since using software is so essential to
doing statistical tests. We're going to provide you with some software output
for you to see and analyze so that you get familiar with it. This is real data
that Doctor Laraway collected from his psychology students at San Jose
University. There are 188 students total, 90 of which were freshman, 44
sophomores, 23 juniors, and 31 seniors. And he asked them to self report how
many days every month they drink caffeine. You can already see that the number
of days that seniors drink caffeine is higher than any of the others. But it
also has a pretty large standard deviation, as does that for juniors. We
want to know if at least one group of college students drinks more caffeine
than the others. Dr. Laraway used the statistical program SPSS to answer this.
Here's his ANOVA table output. According to this, which of the following would
we do?