Okay, so like you've seen before,
we go ahead and
we click Start a new
Android Studio project.
So I'm going to do that.
Okay, and then we'll see
a screen that looks like this.
Now it said to name this
project Practice Set 2,
so I'm going to do that right now.
And I want to use the same company
domain that I've already been using for
all of my other projects,
which is android.example.com.
Now, as long as you didn't do anything
funny, this should have stayed the same,
so you probably don't need to change it.
Now just double-check that the project
is being saved wherever you want it to.
In my case I'm putting it on the
desktop, but you might want to put it in
your documents or
somewhere else on your computer.
All right, now I'll hit Next.
This screen looks pretty good.
I do want to make something for
a phone and a tablet and
I don't want to make something for a TV
or that I'm going to wear on a watch.
So I'm not checking these boxes and
I have this box checked.
In addition, I said that you should
be making something for API 15,
so I have API 15 selected.
If you don't,
you can always click here and change it.
I'm going to click Next.
Okay, and on this screen we're also
going to stick with what we know.
Go ahead and select Blank Activity and
then click Next to go to the next page.
And there's no need to customize
these or change these around.
You can just keep the defaults.
And once you're done with that,
go ahead and click Finish.
Okay, and after a little bit you should
see that your app loads up like this.
Good work.