Let's say you are an art gallery.
You've been staring at a painting that you really like, and
now you want to take a picture of it.
Your camera has a lens, and the sensor inside.
Now when taking the picture, you obviously want the painting to be in focus.
But say you also wanted frames such that,
the picture takes a exactly the image area, that is, you want to get the image,
when projected unto the sensor to match the sensor width.
Let's assume that your camera lens has a fixed focal length of 15 millimeters,
your sensor width, denoted by d is 35 millimeters, and
the width of the painting, w is 0.7 meters.
Now with your knowledge about field of view,
can you figure out how far the lens needs to be from the painting, and how far
the image plane needs to be from the lens to capture the desired image in focus.
Be mindful of units when calculating your answers.