Google strongly recommends
using a hybridized auth flow
in order to take advantage of all
the benefits of a Google Plus sign in.
Let's see how this flow works.
A user opts to log in with
the Google account, and
is redirected to a Google Portal for
granting access to your application.
The user authorizes your
app on the client side
using the JavaScript API client.
The Google server sends a one-time
code along with an access token
back to the client.
The client then sends this same special
one-time code back to your server.
Then your server relays this one-time
code back to the Google API server.
And in return, your server's given an
access token from Google, enabling it to
make its own API calls, which can be
done even when the user is offline.
This one-time code flow has a security
advantage over a pure server side flow.
This is because, with one-time codes,
Google provides tokens directly to your
server, without any intermediaries.
Even if a one time code is discovered,
it is extremely hard to use without
your application's client secret.
A client secret is a special code Google
issues to verify your application.
You will make a client secret in your
first app in just a few minutes.