All right, so the first two tasks of the
exercise were meant to catch you up to
the state of our code after you
watch me make those changes in
the previous video.
So in our first task, we're asked to
delete this block of log messages, so
I'm going to go ahead and
do that right now.
Nice.
Easy.
Our next task is to modify
the activity_numbers.xml to change it,
to use a linear layout
instead of a relatively out.
As well as changes
orientation to vertical
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then also add a view ID
which I want to call review.
Great so those are first two tasks.
So for the third task,
we need to modify the on create
method in the numbers activity.
We need to modify it so that it uses
a while loop to create a text view for
each element in the words list and then
displays the text view on the screen.
So here's our version of
the NumbersActivity.java that we've
posted online.
And the code that it uses here
to create the three text views
has a menu approach rather than
using the while loop approach.
So after starting this code and
understand how it works,
it will help us to write the while loop.
Now before we begin writing the while
loop, let's review the three guiding
questions that we discussed
earlier in the while loop lecture.
All right so now let's discuss how to
add text views to the screen using
the while loop more in depth.
And remember,
this is the general structure for
how we're going to write
our while loop and
the three questions that we'll talk
about will help us fill in these boxes.
So what task do we want to do each time?
Well, from the numbers activity code, it
looks like we want to create a new text
view, then set the text view to
a single word in the list, and
then add the text view to the review.
Second, so how many times do
we want to repeat this loop?
In this,
example we want to repeat it ten times.
So one iteration per word in the list.
And there are ten words
in this list right now.
The third question is,
what is the condition?
Well, we want to keep iterating through
the list until we reach the end of it.
So if we create an index
variable to keep
track of our current index position,
our condition can
be to keep looping until the index
variable is less than ten.
Which is currently this
length of the words list.
So this assumes that the index
variable starts at zero and
then increments by one each time.
All right so I'm back here
in the NumbersActivity.java.
The version where we've created
text views doing the manual way.
So I'm going to copy and paste this
block of code that allows us to do that.
And now in Android Studio,
in the NumbersActivity.java,
in onCreate method,
I'm going to add that block of code.
Now remember what we did here was
first we found the root view for
the whole layout then we created
a variable to keep track of
the current index position
in the words array list.
And then we created new text views
to display each of those words and
added those text views to our
root view to be displayed.
But this was a pretty mail approach.
So let's take a look at how
to change it to a while loop.
Starting with this first line
of finding the review for
the whole layout,
we do want to keep that.
I'll stay here even with
using are while loop.
Now next comes the parts of the while
loop, so I will write that out here.
Remember that the while loop requires
setting up the counter variable then
comes the while keyword and inside the
condition, followed by the braces and
inside these braces
contained instructions or
tasks as well as updating
the counter variable.
So here's a set up of our while loop.
So the first thing we need to do is
to set up the counter variable and
it looks like we actually
did that down here.
So I'm going to take that piece of
code and substitute it in here.
Now next we have the while keyword
followed by the parathesis and
inside we have the test condition.
And we're aware that our test condition
is that we need the index variable
to be less than ten in order
to continue this while loop.
However, instead of
using ten explicitly,
I want to use words.size method.
That way if the words
list ever does change,
we won't need to update
the test condition here.
It would allow us to automatically
get to the end of the list,
no matter how long it is.
All right, so now while this condition
is true, we want to create a text view
and set the text to be the word at
the current index in the words list.
And then we needed to display
the text views on the screen.
So since I already have the code for
this, let's move it in
the while statement.
So this will take
the place of instructions.
Nice, so it looks like we're
almost done all the while loop.
Last thing we need to do here is
to update the counter variable.
Remember that we need to update
the counter variable at the end of each
iteration, so that we can exit the loop
when we've reached the end of the list.
So, using the shorthand that we learned
earlier, I'm going to type in index++.
And remember, this is a shorthand
that's equivalent to index = index +1.
So I'll just make a comment
of that off to the side,
to help you guys remember that.
So now I can go ahead and remove the
rest of this whole I don't need anymore
since the while loop does all of that.
All right so we just made a number
of changes to our code and
implemented a brand new
concept the while loop.
So to recap what we just did,
remember that we remove the log messages
in the NumbersActivity onCreate method.
We also modified activity_numbers.xml,
change it to use a linear layout
instead of a relative layout.
We set the orientation
to be vertical and
then we added a view
ID called root view.
And lastly, an onCreate method
of the NumbersActivity,
we use the three guiding questions to
help us write a while loop to create and
display a text view for
each element in the words list.
All right, so earlier we talked a little
bit about kinds of short hands and
one common one that we saw was the
index++ that we used in the while loop.
And I mentioned that it was
shorthand for index = index +1.
There are a number of other
similar math shorthands.
For example,
a variable maybe such as j plus or
equals a number so 3 in this case.
And as a shorthand for that variable is
assigned that variable plus that number.
Additionally, we can have subtraction
shorthands such as taking a variable and
then add minus minus and
this is shorthand for i = i- 1.
And remember in all these cases we can
substitute different variables and
different numbers.
It's also really important to notice
that i++ is not just equal to
the i + 1 part, but it equals
the entire expression i = i + 1.
So, doing the calculation and
then assigning it back to that variable.