The answer is in-store name and
description.
Your game will first be
noticed in the app store so
that's when you need
the clearest communication.
So the most important thing to
translate for different audiences
is anything in the app store,
that includes the in-store name and
description and maybe the text
that goes to your screen shots.
But the name and description are the
most important because your screen shots
should mostly be visual and
not rely on text to communicate.
The names of in-app purchases and
leaderboards are less important, and
players should be able to get
an understanding of these features
just by playing your game.