There's a lot of interesting
questions we could answer.
Besides the questions I already
mentioned, we could look at how much
time the average student spends
taking classes on Udacity.
We could look how time spent
relates to the number of lessons or
projects students complete.
We could look at how student
engagement changes over time.
Or how many times students submit
projects before they pass and
whether this differs for
different projects.
I'm sure you thought of a lot of
interesting questions as well.
In this lesson, I'm going to focus on
how the numbers in the daily engagement
table differ for students who pass their
first project versus students who don't.
But feel free to explore any of
the other questions you've thought of
yourself and
share what you find on the forums.