You're almost done building Sunshine.
And now it's time to
work on the last step,
which is adding some visual polish.
Often, when developers start to build an
app, they focus on basic functionality.
But visual detail and
design is also really important.
So in this lesson, we're going to focus
on adding some layout pizzazz and
style to a simple app so
that it looks really good.
We'll be adding details like
custom colors, fonts and styles.
And we'll also learn how to make it look
great on all types of Android devices,
from the smallest of watches to
phones and larger tablet screens.
Then at the end of this lesson
you'll apply what you've learned
to put the finishing
touches on Sunshine.
Let's start by learning a little
more about the importance of design.