So that's IPv6.
Look for it in your near future or
maybe even in your present.
For most of the rest of this course,
we'll be in IPv4, which is a little
bit more widely used today.
Also, our hosting provider doesn't
natively support the v6 just yet.
But almost everything we talk about,
except the addresses,
will apply to v6 as well.
However, if you're building apps today
that care about IP addresses, even for
things like logging user requests,
you've got to expect them to be
deployed in a world with v6 present.
You can't expect that
addresses are 32 bits long, or
that their printed representation
looks like a classic v4 dotted quad.
To see if you have IPv6,
go to test-ipv6.com,
which is a site for testing whether
your computer has IPv6 access.
If you have a smartphone,
try it there as well,
and then mark whichever one
of these options is true.
Either that you've tested your devices
and at least one does have IPv6.
Or you've tested them and
none have IPv6 yet.