We can only speculate about
the real photo app code, but
it's probably something
like the array of structs.
But, for many tables, the dictionary
technique would work fine.
Note that in both answers, there is
an array of repeating data objects, and
each data object can be used to
build a single table view row.
We'll experiment with both
types of data structures and
we have a SWF session coming up
on array and dictionary syntax.
No matter the data structure,
the table view will need to
ask questions of its delegate in order
to access the data in the model.
Let's take a closer look at the delegate
methods that make this possible