All right, we're going to stop here.
We've taken a brief look at model fitting,
as really being a robust estimation problem.
So for transforms, you want to estimate the transform and you want to be
able to do that robustly, and we use robust error functions to help.
But what we're going to look at next time,
is a more algorithmic, approach to doing this.
Famous method actually invented by a very good friend of mine,
he's older than I am, so I'm not quite that old, that we'll talk about.
And what's cool is, it's a little bit more computer science oriented, and
this is a computer science class so that's great.
And it's nice to, you, we can use a little bit of combinatorial analysis to show
exactly how good it is.
And the other thing is, it is used all the time, so
you can say well finally is going to teach me something useful.
Come back next time.