In the previous morsel, we talked about the fact that the kernel and
the user-level library, don't have insight into each other's activities, and
let's talk about that a little bit more now.
In the kernel-level, the kernel sees all of the kernel-level threads, the CPUs,
and, the kernel-level scheduler is the one that's making decisions.
At the user-level, the user-level library sees the user-level threads that
are part of that process, and
the kernel-level threads that are assigned to that process.
If the user-level threads and the kernel-level threads are using the one-to-one
model, then every user-level thread will have a kernel-level thread associated
with it, so, the user-level library will also essentially see as many,
kernel-level threads, but it will be the kernel that will actually manage those.
Even if it's not a one-to-one model, the user-level library can
request that one of its, user-level threads be bound to a kernel-level thread.
This is similar of what we would want to perhaps to in a multi-CPU system,
if a particular kernel-level thread, is to be permanently associated with a CPU,
except in that case we call it thread pinning, and
the term that was introduced with the Solaris threads was
that a user-level thread is bound to a kernel-level thread.
And clearly, in a one-to-one model,
every user-level thread is bound to a kernel-level thread.
Now let's have the situation in which, one of the user-level threads has a lock,
and so that, basically the kernel-level thread is
now supporting the execution of that critical section code.
Now let's say, the kernel preempted this kernel-level thread from the CPU to
schedule the other one, so that means that the execution of
this user-level thread, the execution of this critical section cannot continue.
As the user-level library scheduler cycles through the rest of the user-level
threads, if they need the lock, none of them will be able to continue.
So only after the kernel-level, the schedule of this thread again,
will the critical section complete, the lock will be released, and so
subsequently the rest of the user-level threads will be able to execute.
So to reiterate, this problem that there is lack of visibility between
the kernel and the user level-thread management, is because at the user-level,
the library, makes scheduling decisions that the kernel is not aware of, and
that will change the user to kernel-level mappings.
And also data structures, like mutexes and
wait queues, that's also invisible to the kernel.
So the fact that this lack of visibility causes situations such as the one
that we described really leads us to the conclusion that we should look at
one-to-one models, to address some of these issues.
Since the user-level library plays such
an important role in how the user-level threads are managed,
we need to understand exactly, when does it get involved in the execution loop.
The user-level library is part of user process, part of its address space, and
occasionally the execution basically jumps to
the appropriate program counter into this address space.
There are multiple reasons why the control should be passed to the user-level
library scheduler, a user-level thread may explicitly yield, a timer that's set
by the user-level threading library may expire, also we jump into the user-level
library scheduler whenever some kind of synchronization operation takes place,
like, when we call a lock, clearly that thread may not be able to run if it
needs to be blocked, when we call an unlock operation, then we need to evaluate
what is then new runnable thread that the scheduler should allocate on the CPU.
And in general, whenever we have a situation where a blocking user-level thread
becomes runnable, we jump into the scheduler code, this is part of
the library implementation, this is not something that you will explicitly see.
In addition in being invoked on certain operations that
are triggered by the user-level threads,
the library scheduler is also triggered in response on certain events,
certain signals that come either from timer or directly from the kernel.
The next morsel should give you an illustration of these interactions.