Now in communicating with the provider,
you may have noticed that there was
a heavy reliance on setting
the correct URI as input.
And this is because we need to let
the provider know what data we need
to access or modified.
So let's take sometime to talk
more about your eyes right now.
In communicating with the provider, you
basically need to tell it two things.
First, what operation you want to do.
So, what action?
And secondly, what data you
want to use in that operation?
So, the method that you call here,
defines what action you're taking.
And these map to the methods
in your content provider.
And there should be ones that
you're pretty familiar with.
So, there's query, insert,
update, and delete.
Well, the URI helps define the data
that we want to do the operation on.
Well, what in the world is URI?
So URI stands for
Uniform Rsource Identifier.
And they're identifiers as the name
in place that tells the name,
location or potentially both of
something that we're interested in.
So you might have heard of URLs before.
For example, this one listed
here,: https://udacity.com.
So it looks like a common web address.
Well, URLs are actually
a subset of URIs.
And URLs stand for
Uniform Resource Locator.
And they specifically give us the
location of a file or data on the web.
So we're interested in using URIs to
identify the location of some data.
And in this case, the location is on a
an SQL like database file on our phone.
So we'll be particularly
interested in content URI's.
So these are URI's used to
identify data in a provider.
So they can point to part of a database.
So whether that's a single row, a table,
or maybe a combination of tables.
And they can also point to a file.
Perhaps a text, a photo,
or other media file.
So to give you an example,
here is some content URI's.
First is the sign here with
the contacts provider.
So notice that we're calling
into the contacts provider
with this content authority which
we kind of discussed earlier and
we're specifically interested in
the contacts information from it.
In this next example of the calendar
provider, we're particularly interested
in the events information
from this calendar provider.
Next, in this user dictionary provider,
we want to focus on the words
information from that provider.
Now can you spot something common
amongst all these content URIs?
Well, if you notice that they all
start with the same label here.
content:// then you're correct.
So all content URIs will
start with the same scheme.
And this leads us into a good discussion
about the structure of content URI's.
So content URI's are made
up of three parts.
So the scheme,
the content authority, and
lastly the information about the type
of data that we want to see.
So diving into the first part,
the scheme.
In this case, we're using content://
because like I had mentioned before,
it's a content URI.
So this is a standard way to
start URI's on an Android app.
Much like how we use HTTP:// or
HTTPS:// as the prefix of web URL's.
The next part is the critically
important bit of the URI
because it specifies what content
provider we need to use, and
it's called the content authority.
So, what it does is it specifies
which content provider class
we want to talk to.
So, think back to how in
the Android manifest file,
we setup the content providers
content authority and
set it to this,
com.example.android.pets.
Well, this has to match
the content authority for the URI.
So if this example were
to be the pets example.
This content authority would
have to be this line here.
So in our manifest,
we added a provider tag.
And this tag in the manifest
associates this content authority
with this provider Java class.
So our PetProvider Java class.
That means when our URI
uses this authority,
it's specifying that we want to
use this provider class.
Okay, so moving on to
the last portion of the URI,
is this section here, which specifies
the data we want to operate on.
So a common pattern that we'll follow in
our pets app is that you'll have a URI
that has just the name of the table and
that means we want to return
the data from the whole table.
So to give you more context,
here are some examples of URI's
from different tables in our
contacts provider table.
So notice that they all call
from the same contacts provider
because they're all using
the same content authority.
But they have different table
names listed at the end.
So it can be the contacts table,
the profiles table, the photo table or
the directories table but
they're all from the contacts provider.
So let's take a step back and
we want to know what data we
want to perform the action on.
But, how do we discuss between these two
cases of whether we want to operate on
the whole pets table or
just a single row of the pets table.
So we just saw how we can get
data from the whole table,
ending our URI with /table name.
But what if we need data from
a single row from the table?
Well, another URI we can use is to
have the name followed by a number
which specifies the ID of the specific
row that we're interested in.
So here's what I mean by that.
To specify a record from the table, we
can narrow down the last part of the URI
with the ID of a specific
row we're interested in.
So to reiterate those two situations,
in order to get all the rows from
the contacts table, we can format
our content URI to look like this.
Where it ends with contacts,
the name of the entire table
that we are interested in.
But, if we want to further specify
a single row of the table,
we can narrow the content URI based
on its ID, which we'll do here.
So, in addition to the contacts
table name, we end with slash id.
So let's go ahead and
recap those three parts of the content
URI with our contacts example.
So the first part is the scheme
which is the standard way to start
URIs in the Android app.
Remember it's content://.
So next up is the content authority
which specifies what content
provider to use.
And remember we set this up
in our Android manifest file.
And the file part of the URI specifies
the data that we want to operate on,
whether that's the entire table or
a single row from that table.
So, in the first line here,
we have a pattern of the URI that has
just the name of the table and that
returns the data in the entire table.
But, if we want to specify
a single row in the table,
we can include more information in
our URI using this, slash ID number.
Now, before we can move on,
we need to figure out what the URI's for
our pets table will look like.
So remember that the pet's table
can look something like this.
Now given the structure we just saw,
I want you to help design
the content URIs for our pets table.
And to help you along,
you can answer these two questions.
So first, what should the content
URI for an entire pets table be?
And secondly,
what should the content URI for
a single row from the pets table be?
And for this particular example,
I want you to find the content URI for
the second row of the table.
If you need some hints,
I've listed some down below,
where we're using
the ContactsProvider as an example.
So if we were to create the Content URI
for the Contacts table as a whole,
this is what that would look like.
And if we were to grab the Content URI
for a single row in the Contacts table,
here's what it is for
the fifth row of that table.