What makes a good feature?
So here, I have a picture just as an example.
The first thing is, it's called Repeatability/Precision.
The same feature should be found in several or
multiple images of the same scene.
Now, of course these aren't all the same picture.
Because, if I gave you 15 copies of the same picture.
This would be a really boring class, all right?
These are actually different pictures of the same scene, so
things change a little bit.
But despite those changes, I want to get the same points being identified, and
that's repeatability, and also.
I'd like it to be the active same point.
All right, so there's this little red dot on top of the camera,
there's one over here too.
I wonder which one I'm looking at.
See I'm going to make Megan cut back, and forth in her video.
Okay, the little red dot.
So that dot's a pretty good feature, because there's only two of them that I'm
looking at here, so I can find both of them, and
then matching will probably be easy to do and then they're very precise.
That is I'm not going to drift around,
I'm going to be able to find right on that dot.
The next thing is Salience or Matchability.
This is how distinctive the descriptor is.
So each feature should be able to be described uniquely enough
that it's easy to find it right.
So if I'm looking at a bunch of white dots on a black wall, and
they're all the same white dot.
That's really a problem, because that's the George, George, George, George,
George, right, everybody is named George, I can't find anybody, I just quit and
go home, all right?
So, you like to have a description that's different, about them.
Compactness and efficiency.
Another way of saying this is, don't get carried away.
You remember when we talked about computing the fundamental matrix,
we said well, I only need eight corresponding points, but
I mean maybe having a dozen or 20 of them might be better.
Maybe even 50, but 50 is much, much, much,
much, much, much, much, much smaller than the number of pixels in the image.
So, what I would really like to do is, in general, I don't want to have
a feature everywhere, although in this picture, there's a lot of them.
But you see, even here, it looks like there's a lot of them, but
I don't know, maybe there's a 100.
But there's tens of thousands of pixels here.
So, that's what it means by being compact and efficient.
And finally, Locality.
Locality is,
is not what you think if you think locality means exactly knowing where it is.
That was the precision.
Locality means that, the descriptor that I compute about the feature,
the description, the name, is based upon information that comes just.
From a pretty small area around the feature.
Now you might think that you know I'd like to take a nice big area
to describe it because that'll give me a nice very distinct description.
That's like a first name, and a second name, and
third name, and a fourth name would be giving me a very rich description.
The problem is and I'll try to find, oh yeah it's right over here.
So I'm looking at the side of this.
Now I'm I hope I'm still in the feed.
No, the camera moved!
I'm looking.
Okay, good.
Thank you.
So I'm looking at the side of the, of the lens over here, and
the problem is if I take too much of the lens to describe what's going on,
as I move over here, and I start to get occluded.
A bunch of that neighborhood goes away.
That's the same thing when we had,
you know, a finger getting occluded a little bit by the other.
So since I'm trying to find matching pixels from different views, and
different views will cause a little bit of occlusion to change,
I don't want the neighborhood that I use to describe the, the,
to make the description to be too large.
And that's what locality means.
It makes us more robust to sort of clutter, and occlusion.