Recall the 1-D block row algorithm and
its pseudocode.
You know that it's running
time is (2 tau n cubed) / P,
for flops, + alpha P + beta n squared,
for communication.
In fact, you can make this
code a little bit faster.
All you have to do is rearrange
the statements of the loop body.
Notice, I said rearrange
You don't have to actually change
the statements themselves.
In the best case, the rearrangement
I have in mind might improve
the performance by up to a factor of 2,
relative to this running time.
Your task is to show me how.
I will pre-fill this text box with these
statements, and I want you to rearrange
them to get this possible factor
of 2 improvement in speed.