I was able to get all of this
functionality in just 11 lines of code.
I'll show you what I did and
we'll see how your solution
matches up against mine.
Remember that the data is
stored in a model variable.
I'm going to get a copy of all of this,
so
I don't have to keep switching
back here to reference the data.
I switched in my code editor, and I have
the store handlebars template here, and
this scratch file with the data for
reference.
Read a section for
each one of these items.
Handlebars gives us the each block
to let us loop over information, but
what are we looping over?
Remember that this data
is stored in model.
So we're going to be looping over that.
The first time through the loop,
item will be this object.
The second time,
it'll be the blue bricks object, and
the third will be green.
Then it's just accessing
the properties off of the item object.
We also need to display
each of the bricks.
So that means another loop.
Notice that this is in each loop,
inside of another each loop.
Handlebars can handle some
pretty complicated structures.
To keep things organized, I put each
brick item in its own container div.
The template is now
displaying all content.
The last thing to do is handle
the bricks that are on sale.
Since not all of them are on sale,
we need to check which ones are on
sale before adding the class.
So we'll use the if
conditional expression.
So if the item is on sale,
we'll give it the on sale class.
If it's not, then we don't do anything.
And that's it.
Once you learn the basics,
handlebars is an easy to write and
easy to read templating engine.
And it's baked right
into ember templates.
Pretty neat?