First I look at the screen shot and
decide that since the,
these are in rows,
it looks like a vertical linear layout.
The second child though
is not a single view,
in fact that's a horizontal
linear layout of three views.
This is what the view hierarchy
diagram would look like.
We have a vertical linear layout as a
root view and five children under that.
The linear layout itself
has three children as well.
Once we have the diagram it's easy to
create this skeleton of XML code now.
The root view is a linear layout and
it contains a text view as its first
child followed by a linear layout
which has a button, text view,
and button inside of it.
And this is the closing tag for
the linear layout and
then we have the text view,
another text view, and a button.
Which are all children of
the parent linear layout.
From this XML we can go
in to Android Studio and
modify our existing layout
to look more like this.
In Android Studio I open up
activity main XML layout file.
We're going to make the changes
in place in this file so
that they match more closely
to our desired layout.
The first child is a TextView.
That we already have.
And it's supposed to be
the quantity header.
Next we should have
a nested linear layout
that contains three views inside of it.
We don't have that yet, so let's add it.
I'm going to hit Enter and
then just start typing LinearLayout.
It also shows up as one of
the auto complete options.
So I can just hit okay.
Then it auto populates the attributes
that I should fill in.
Because width and height are required.
I set the width to be match_parent,
which will in turn
match the width of it's parent, and
this will match the width of the screen.
For layout height, I don't want to
set match_parent, otherwise,
it will push the other views
off the screen vertically.
So I'm just going to
say wrap_content here.
That way the LinearLayout will only
be as tall as the two buttons and
TextView inside of it.
Now, this closing tag should be
moved after all the children
of the LinearLayout have been added.
So that will go down here.
When you have children
inside of a view group,
you should indent
the children by four spaces.
I'm going to add a space here too
because I like to have a blank line in
between each XML element.
One more thing we're missing is setting
the orientation of this LinearLayout.
Earlier we decided that the LinearLayout
should be horizontal so
that the buttons and
the TextView appear horizontally.
Cool.
Now that matches what we wanted.
Next we have, two TextViews and a Button
which we already have in our layout.
So I think we're done.
If you wanted to check the design pane,
this is what it would look like.
We have a vertical linear layout
with five direct children and
this linear layout has
three more children.
Let's run it on our device
to see what happens.
So, this looks close to what we want but
not quite.
The quantity picker is appearing
horizontally, which is a good sign.
But we want the minus button on
the left hand side and the plus button
to be on the right hand side, as shown
In the screenshot of the desired layout.
Also, these buttons are tightly squeezed
up against the edge of this TextView.
If I remember the screenshot correctly,
we also want eight dips of space on
the left-hand side and
right-hand side of this TextView.
So let's add that now.
Going back to the XML,
I'm going to move the plus
button to be after the TextView.
And then move the minus button
to be before the TextView.
In a horizontal row, we should have
the minus button, followed by the two,
followed by the plus button.
We also want to add padding
around this TextView.
We could either add it as margin or
padding, but
I'm just going to do padding.
And we'll set the value
to be eight dips.
Okay, great.
Now I have a hunch that there's
a bunch of extra white spaces and
the ordering of our
attributes may be incorrect,
according to the android
code style guidelines.
So, in the menu at the top of
your screen, click on code and
then click on reformat code.
And also rearrange code.
And that should rearrange
all the attributes and
fix up all the formatting for
you automatically.
Okay, great.
Let's run the app again.
There.
That's better.
Now there's space around the two and
the minus button is on the left-hand
side and the plus button
is on the right-hand side.
[SOUND] it looks good.
And then we also check
that it still works.
So, I'm going to pick an arbitrary
quantity and then order.
And that looks correct.
[SOUND] that was a long journey to get
this quantity picker on the screen.
All right.
The app is looking really good.
But so far, I've only showed you
how to show numbers on the screen.
What if you want to show
text on the screen?
Keep watching to find out.