So you now have everything to start
implementing more of the Pet Provider.
Well let's start off by reviewing some
key methods that you'll need to
implement in a ContentProvider.
And they are the ones listed down here.
So so far,
we have the onCreate method implemented,
which initializes the petDBHelper.
And we've also created a Url
matcher as a global variable.
And we're going to use that when we're
using the query, insert, update,
and delete methods.
And lastly we'll need to
implement our getType method.
So let's start off by focusing
just on the query method.
So previously, I mentioned that the
query method takes in as an input a Uri
but we notice here that it can also
take in a couple other inputs as well.
Now let's click on this link and check
out more details about the query method.
So in addition to the Uri's and input,
we see that we can have a projection,
selection, selection args and
a sort order as well.
So having these additional inputs allows
us so that when we query the provider.
If our content URI points to the whole
pets table, we can actually be more
specific about exactly what rows and
columns that we're interested in.
And this allows us to get
back a more specific row
instead of the entire pets
table in the cursor result.
So before we dive into the code,
let's actually review the end to
end diagram of the query method.
So to start when the Catalog Activity
calls the resolver query method,
we can pass in all these inputs.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
From there, the Content Resolver
passes on the request to the Provider.
And then the Uri Matcher helps us
determine what pattern the Uri matches.
From there, we query the pet's table.
And remember we need to apply the
projection, selection, selection args,
and sort order parameters that
we passed in if they apply.
So to resolve the query is a cursor
which contains some number of rows or
columns from this original table.
And then the cursor gets returned
by the pet provider query method
back to the resolver, and
then back to our catalog activity so
that it can be finally in the UI.
So this here is a complete end
to end flow of the query method.
Now to actually implement the query
method in the code of your pets app,
I'm going to help you out by
providing you some starter code.
So in this quiz, I'll be asking you to
replace your current blank query method
with this code, as well as finish
this to do under the PETS case.
So I know it looks like a lot
of code but don't worry.
I'll be walking through it line by line.
Now let's take a moment and
zoom out for a second.
And notice there are three major
parts of this query method.
So first off, we need to get
the database object and then,
we'll send the URI through
to the URI matcher
which helps us determine
which way to fork off into.
Whether to go down the path of
the pets case or the pets ID case.
So with those three steps in mind,
let's focus on how that
translates into the code here.
So first, we're going to access
the database using the mDb
helper variable that we initialized up
in the onCreate method of the provider.
So from there, we get the SQLI
object From the DB helper.
And remember that for the query method,
we won't be making any changes or any
writes to the database, so that's why we
can use a get readable database method.
So for the next step, that's when
we'll be using the URI matcher.
And that helps us find out what kind of
input URI was passed into us up here.
Now more specifically we're going to
call sUriMatcher.match giving
it the input Uri, this one here.
And from it we're going to
receive an integer code
that we can sort in this
variable called match.
Now after that, is when we have
to decide which path to go down.
So this is where the switch
case statements come in.
And this helps us to determine
whether it were in the pets case or
the pet id case.
Now, inside the switch statement,
if the URI matches the pets case,
then you'll need to perform
the query on the whole pets table.
Now as a hint when you're actually
doing this to do on your own,
you'll need to use the query method
on the SQLitedatabase object.
So this object up here.
And when you're doing the query
on the database table,
remember that you'll also
need to pas in a projection,
selection, selection args and
sortOrder that were given up here.
Now in the second case,
if the URI matches the pet ID situation,
then we need to perform
the query on a single pet.
So I filled in this node for
you already.
And since we know that we're operating
under a single row in the pets table.
We can see that the selection and
selectionArgs are pointing
us to a specific row here.
So then on the SQL database object.
This database here.
We want to call the query method,
passing in the pet Table_Name,
projection, selection,
selectionArgs, and any other inputs.
Now note that the query method can
accept in a lot of other inputs
to help customize the results.
But we'll be setting those to null.
So I know the syntax here can be
a little dense and hard to read.
And that's because we're using a lot
of Java constants, appended strings.
And then you were converting
some integers to strings.
But it might make more sense if
we take a look at an example.
So say the provider query method was
called with these example inputs.
So we pass in the URI and
the projection to the query method.
Well in this situation,
the URI ends with /pets/5 and
the projection gives us two columns,
ID and name.
Now given these two inputs, when we
enter into the switch case statement,
it's going to fall into
the PET_ID situation
because we have the number 5
appended at the end of our URI.
So we first set selection to be id=?.
And by the way, selection is a string so
that's why we're putting in quotes here.
And so that's what translates here.
So id=?.
So next is the selection
args variable and
that's going to be an array of strings
to be substituted wherever there was
a question mark up in
the selection string.
So if there were three question
marks in the selection strings,
then there should be three elements
here in the Selection Args array.
Well in our case,
we only have one question mark, so
the Selection Args should
only have one element.
Which should be the id 5
that we are interested in.
Now in the code, we're going to extract
out the 5 at the end of the URI,
so this is here by using our
ContentUris.parseId method.
And this will convert the last segment
of the URI path into a number for us.
And once we isolate that number 5,
we're going to turn it into a string
using our string.valueOf method.
And so now we can put 5 and
have it in quotes as the only
element in the selection args array.
So this translates to that.
So, I know that was a long explanation.
But now we see how this code here
translates into these codes here.
So, the reason we did all
of this work here was for
the propose of making the correct
query to the SQLite database.
So, when we call database.query
giving these inputs,
it helps us map to the correct
SQLite statements in purple here.
It's the statement that we translates,
gives us SELECT,
only the id and name from
the pets table, where the id=5.
Now, remember, the reason that we're
selecting only id and name here,
is that the projection that we're given
only had the columns id and name.
And the reason that the WHERE clause
here is id=5 is because we were
given that in the selection and
selection args here.
Now the result of this database query
should be a cursor only containing
the fifth row of the pets table.
And the cursor will get stored in
a variable here called cursor.
So for both the PETS and PETS ID case,
make sure that cursor available should
be set to the result from the database.
Now finally at the end of
the provider query method, so
end of all of this, we finally return
this cursor back to the color.
And this is how it all
connects In the diagram here.
So that completes the discussion
of how the query method works.
And I know that was not easy at all.
So congrats on surviving
all that with me.
Now it's your turn and
I want you to go ahead and
implement the query method
in your PetProvider class.
So start by replacing the query method
with the code linked in the just below.
Then I like you to complete
the TODO in the PETS case.
And do so to perform a query on
the database given the projection,
selection, selection args,
and sort order perimeters.
And lastly ensure that
the app still compiles.
Note that there should be no visible
changes to the app as expected.
If you need some help here, remember to
take a look at the pet's ID situation
that we've already provided in the Gist.