So how can you make sure that you will
have all of the indexes that your
queries will need?
Well, one way would be you could
manually edit index.yaml for
each index that you're going to need.
Another way is that you can run every
multi-property query on localhost
before you deploy to appspot.
That would also work.
You'd have to make sure you ran every
single one at possibly every path
through your application.
In that case the auto-generator would
write index.yaml which would get pushed
when you deploy your application.
Marking all your properties you need
indexed with index equals True,
that's not going to work.
That will not generate any
multi-property indexes.
But for single-property indexes,
you don't need to do anything.