To do this we're going to make
some simplifying assumptions.
The first assumption is
a Markovian assumption and
that's that only
the immediate past matters.
So what this says is,
if I know all of the states up through
t minus 1, and I want a prediction
of this state at time t.
That just depends on
the state of t minus 1.
Now these are Xs, not the Ys.
These are if I actually knew the state.
What this tells me is if I wanted to
predict the state on Wednesday, and
I knew the state on Tuesday,
Monday, Sunday, Saturday.
It's all the same as knowing
the state on Tuesday.
Okay?
I only have to know one prior state.
Now some of you might ask, but,
wait a minute, if I know Monday and
Tuesday, I might be able to estimate
the velocity for Wednesday.
>> If I know Monday and
Tuesday, I might be able to
estimate the velocity on Wednesday.
>> So that's right, except not, because.
Your state could also
include the velocity, right?
So, if I knew the position and the
velocity on Tuesday I make a prediction
about Wednesday, so
this is the Markovian assumption.
This probability of Xt given Xt minus 1,
that's what we refer to as the dynamics
model, that's how things are changing.
Second simplifying assumption.
We're going to assume
that the measurements,
the probability of the measurements,
remember, these are noisy measurements.
Given everything in the past, and
the current state,
only depends on the current state.
So this is where we say that
the probability of a measurement,
given a particular state and everything
else, only depends upon the state.
By the way this is called the
observation model and I will tell you,
it is this particular assumption
that is sometimes the most suspect.
One way you can think about this,
suppose you have some noise in your
sensor that is related to some
other processes going on.
And it changes in a particular way
that you might be able to estimate.
This thing says, well,
I don't look at my previous measurements
in order to make that prediction.
So for everything we're going to do,
we're going to make use of
this observation model,
where the likelihood of the measurement
depends only on the current state.
Just know that for more advanced things
like conditional random fields and
other, other approaches.
We'll actually be able to
make the current measurement
tied to previous measurements, but
we're not going to do that here.
I know some of you have taken various
machine learning courses, and
you're familiar with graphical models.
And, if I were to draw up this
set of simplifying assumptions
as a graphical model,
it would look like this.
And what this says is that some state X,
depends only on the state at time T,
depends only on the state
at time T minus 1.
And furthermore, it says that my
measurement depends only on the state.
And whenever I look at that,
I always think to myself, hm.
Okay, that's a joke.
Why?
because those of you who know what this
is, this is a hidden mark up model.
An HMM.
See, now Megan, who's helping with
the slides, she didn't know that, so
she didn't know how funny that was.
So she's now what is it?
ROTL?
No, ROTFL, sorry, I,
I left out the floor.
It's really hard to say emoticon things.
Not emoti, what do you call those thing,
whatever they are.
She's, now she's getting up.