You may have seen a recent news
story about a team of Japanese and
German researchers who wrote a program
to simulate the human brain.
Brains!
And in fact, their program didn't
simulate the entire brain,
just 1% of it over a short
period simulated time.
Now 1% of the brain is about 2 billion
neurons and 10 trillion synapses.
Very roughly speaking, neurons and
synapses form a kind of network
where neurons are like nodes,
and synapses are like edges.
The synapses serve as kinds of
communication channels connecting
the neurons.
Now as it happened in the simulation,
these synapses, because there are so
many more of them, accounted for
most of the storage and
computation in the model.
And in particular,
the reason these researchers needed to
run their simulation on a super computer
is because every synapse required
about 24 bytes of storage.
I think you can imagine that 24 bytes
times ten trillion is a lot of bytes.
Now, suppose I gave you a computer
work station with 16 gibibytes of
main memory.
If you don't know what a gibibytes is,
please see the instructor's notes.
Here's my question to you.
How many of these 16 gibibytes machines
would you need to store a full model?
That is, all 100% of the brain.
I want you to type your
answer in this box, and
please enter it to 2
significant figures.
So, for example,
if you thought the answer was 232.7,
you would just write 230.