We have Friendly Trap up and
running now, and it's great, but
it's pretty bare bones.
The basic interface is showing up,
but there's no real functionality yet.
But this is awesome, there's plenty
to do, so let's get to work.
To start,
let me give you a quick tour of the app.
Down here we have a text box and
a send button.
But when I type in a message and
press send, send clears the text box.
But our message isn't
really going anywhere.
On the left,
there's also this little image icon.
Clicking on this image icon should open
an ImagePicker so that we can choose
an image to send in the app, but
that doesn't quite work yet.
We've also got an overflow menu up here,
which has one option, sign out, but
the sign out button doesn't
do anything either.
You'll be working with me to make this
app a lot friendlier than it is now.
And of course to do that, we're
going to need to work with the code.
So let's jump over there.
I'm going to start by opening
up the AndroidManifest file.
We can see that the app has a single
activity, which is called MainActivity.
The MainActivity is what's
opened when you launch the app.
This is a pretty simple app, so
you'll be fully implementing
all of the features from this
single activity during this course.
Next, let's check out what we
currently have in the dependencies.
I'm going to open up this tab and
go over to our gradle files.
I'm going to check out
the app's build.gradle.
If I scroll down to the bottom,
I can see the place where all of our
app's library dependencies live.
Right now we have standard
ones like appcompat and
the design support library.
We've also included glide, which is an
image loading library that we'll use to
help us display images
in our message list.
You're going to learn more about
that during Sunday's lesson.
Next, let's head over to
the res directory and
take a look at our layouts.
Here we have two layout files.
I'll start by opening up
the main activity layout file,
this activity.main.xml.
This is the screen that we first see
when we run the app code at this moment.
We just don't see this
message list here and
that's because we haven't
implemented that functionality yet.
The layout is a relative layout made
up of a ListView to display all
the messages, an ImageButton to open
up the photo picker to send a picture,
an EditText, which is again the text box
that you send your message from, and
a button, which is our send button.
The second layout of importance to
us is this item_message.xml layout,
I'll open it up now.
This is the layout for
each individual message.
And scrolling down I can see that
it contains an ImageView for
photo messages and two TextViews.
One of these is a TextView for
a text message, and
the other one is a TextView for
the author of the message.
For each message in our app,
only the messageTextView or
the photoImageView will
be displayed at one time.
The logic for
whether to display an ImageView or
a TextView is done in the adapter which
we'll work with later in the course.
And speaking of the adapter,
let's go ahead and
take a look at those Java classes.
We have three classes in our project.
Let's open up the first one,
the FriendlyMessage class.
The FriendlyMessage class is a plain
Java object that just has three fields,
a text, a name, and a photoUrl.
We'll be using this
class when we actually
start to implement the database.
Next let's take a look
at the MainActivity.
Our MainActivity is
where the magic happens.
It's the class that handles the logic
for the main messages list screen.
Let's take a look at a couple
notable parts of this class.
Here I've defined a ListView for
the messages list and
if I scroll down to my onCreate, I see
that we're creating an ArrayList here
that's filled with those
FriendlyMessages objects.
And this ArrayList is going to be
the data source for our MessageAdapter,
which is called mMessageAdapter.
Right now the ArrayList is empty,
so we don't see any messages.
Another interesting part of
the MainActivity deals with the EditText
view.
Let me scroll down.
Here we have our EditText view and
we're adding something to
it called a TextWatcher.
This makes it so that we can't
press send for empty messages,
which is what we'd
expect from a chat app.
We don't want to fill up our database or
our messages list with blank messages.
Okay, so that was a very quick deep
dive into some of the starter code.
Again, we'll talk about
the adapter later.
Following this,
I have a quick quiz to make sure
that you were paying attention.
And then after that, you'll get to start
working on your first Firebase feature,
the real-time database.