Next, I want to make sure you're aware of the online wiki for this course.
It has information such as the class syllabus, lecture schedule,
project schedule, various resource links that are useful for the class.
It also has grading criteria and other policies that are valid for the course.
Let me now explain the grading policy in this class.
Your grade will roughly be split between the theoretical and the practical part.
The theoretical part, you will have two exams, a mid-term and a final.
The final will not be cumulative and
these will be worth 25 and 30% of your grade.
Your projects will be worth 40% of your grade, so
these are your programming assignments.
and you will have 5% of your grade come from class participation.
Given that the class is online, for class participation, we expect you to
participate in Piazza, the online forum that we'll use in this class.
How well you answer to questions posted by other students,
how often you raise an interesting and useful topics for
discussion in the forum, and also how well you do on the quizzes on
the Audacity platform that will be incorporated in the class lessons.
You can always monitor your grades in T-Square.
For the exams, we'll use an online service called ProcterU.
As the name suggests, this is a service that proctors you
during the examination and insures academic honesty.
The tests are to be taken individually, and
they will be closed notes, closed book exams.
For the projects, you can work in teams.
Across teams, you can have high level discussions about your design approach or
implementation approach.
But, you're not allowed to share code, results, text for the final report.
You should have these discussions thru Piazza, so
both the core staff, as well other students can help you.