All right, mag is short for magnitude.
And this is a decimal value that tells
us how strong the earthquake was.
Place is just the location of the
earthquake expressed in an abbreviated
English text string.
Time is the timestamp for
the earthquake event.
It is expressed in Unix Epoch time,
which we talked about earlier.
Felt might be a tricky one.
The USGS site includes a metric called,
did you feel it?
So the felt value
represents an aggregation
of website users that reported
that they felt the quake and
how strong they suspect
that it might have been.
Tsunami is another
potentially tricky one.
What the heck is this doing here?
Well, it's true that tsunamis are a
potential hazard when earthquakes occur
in the ocean or near coastal land areas.
So sometimes a tsunami alert
will be issued and used
by an emergency notification network
to warn people near the coastline.
This value registers a 1 if
there is a tsunami alert, and
0 if there is no alert.
This is a kind of way to say that
a value is true or false using numbers.
The title field is a concatenation
of the magnitude and place fields.
The architects of this feed realized
that it was probable that the people
might want to use these two values
together as a descriptive title
of an event, and
added it as a convenience.
The coordinates data might be a little
tough to understand at first because
it's not explicitly labeled, but
what it is is an array of three numbers.
The three numbers are, in this order,
longitude, latitude and depth.
These three numbers together describe
the exact location of the earthquake
within the crust of the planet.
It's pretty useful to understand
how the depth affects
how earthquakes are experienced.
The more shallow the quake,
the stronger it is felt on the surface.