By requiring that the passwords
are changed periodically we are sort of
ensuring that it's going to be less
likely that someone who is not
the right user is going to be able
to gain access to an account.
So, this is actually part of
the policy we're going to see later on.
And if there is a compromise, if
a computer is hacked, if a password is
stolen, then we have to report it
to somebody who's responsible for
cyber security at Georgia Tech, maybe
in your unit or could be the university
wide, but yes our policy does,
so this option is also there.
The third one says Georgia Tech
computers cannot be used to
download illegal content, example
of that here is child pornography.
It's absolutely a part of that