That ends our very long lesson on Harris corners.
I'm hoping Megan can do some, like video magic.
So you've actually just seen three magnificently edited, cut,
tight, get, you know, I hear she's friends with John Williams, so
there'll be a score in the background.
Anyway, but this notion of variation and gradients is very important in general.
It's used for feature detectors.
But it's, but this notion of gradients varying over a window will be
important when we do other issues having to do with motion and stuff like that.
But for now, we're just thinking of it as doing point detection.
And in the next couple lessons, we're going to take a look at some of
the properties of this detector and then we're going to build some descriptions,
some descriptors around those detected points.
Are you tired?
I'm tired.
All I've got to drink is water, I hope you can do better.