Well that's interesting stuff.
[LAUGH] What is an activity?
Well first, it's important to understand
what an Android application is.
A collection of components
that work with each other, and
with the Android framework.
There are four types of
components that make up apps.
Activities, services, broadcast
receivers and content providers.
Android knows about each of
these components because they
are registered in the Android manifest.
We'll ultimately cover all of these
components to some degree, but for
now, we'll focus on the activity.
An activity is the Android
component responsible for
most app user interaction.
The developer guide describes it using
almost a dictionary definition of
the word activity, as a single
focused thing that the user can do.
And that is a pretty
good design principle.
Since the user is doing something,
they're interacting with the device.
So activities are responsible for
creating the window that your
application uses to draw and
receive events,
such as touch events from the system.
>From a user perspective, a typical
application looks like a series
of linked activities beginning with
one that is started from the launcher.
The system maintains these activities
on a stack to help preserve context for
the users.
When you exit an activity using the back
button the system displays the previous
activity on the stack, or returns
the launcher if the stack is empty.
So, how does a Launcher fit in?
Well taking a look at the Android
Manifest, we can see a tag for
our application.
Inside that application tag
is the activity component.
And inside of our activity component is
an intent filter tag that contains a tag
mentioning the launcher.
We'll talk about intents,
intent filters,
and get in to lots more details
about activities in future lessons.
For now, the important thing
to know is this is how
your activity is registered
with the launcher.
The Android Framework has a large
toolkit to help build the user
interface, which is the visible part of
the application that the user interacts
with.
Each activity contains a layout that
provides the system with detailed
information about what to display and
how to display it, such as text views.
Let's go to the res folder.
That's where Android stores
application resources.
Separating out resources makes it easy
to update the way an application looks,
feels, and sounds, allowing you
to optimize the application for
different device configurations,
such as screen sizes and
languages without modifying code.
This is an important aspect of
developing Android applications
that are compatible on
different types of devices.
Resources contain things like images,
strings and
styles, as well as what we're
going to cover now, layouts.
The Android studio template
has created activity_main.xml.
Android stores all of its
layout files in XML format, and
these XML tags refer to types of view
objects in the Android UI framework.
As you can see, some view objects
can contain other view objects, and
their primary purpose is to
arrange other views on the screen.
Which is why they are called layout or
container views.
Looking at the onCreate function
inside of the activity,
we can see setContentView
with R.layout.activity.main.
Looking at the onCreate function
inside of the activity,
we can see setContentView
with R.layout.activity_main.
That will cause the XML layout
resource to be inflated,
converting everything in the XML file to
a hierarchy of view objects in memory.
[BLANK_AUDIO]