To understand Winter threats useful,
let's start to think about what
are the different ways to
provide concurrency and
what are the trade offs
among those implementation.
So far we've talked about
multi threaded applications.
But an application can
be implemented by having
multiple concurrently running processes.
We mentioned this in the earlier
lecture on Threads and Concurrency.
So let's start by
comparing these two models.
To make the discussion concrete we will
do this analysis in the context of
a web server.
And for a web server it's important to
be able to concurrently process client
requests.
So that is the concurrency
that we care for there.
Before we continue let's talk for a
second about what are the steps involved
in the operation of a simple web server.
At the very first, the client or
the browser needs to send a request
that the web server will accept.
So let's say this is a request
to www.contact.edu and
the web server at Georgia Tech
needs to accept that request.
After the request is accepted,
there are a number of processing steps
that the web server needs to perform
before finally responding with the file.
Now, we will talk about
a simple web server.
So if we take a look at what these
steps are, so we accept the connection,
we read the request that there is
an HTTP request that's received and
we need to parse that request.
We need to then find the file
in the local file system,
that's at the server side.
Once we have extracted the file,
we need to compute the header,
send out the header and then also send
out the file or potentially send out
an error message along with the header
that the file is not found.
So for the rest of this lesson we'll
really focus on this simple web server
processing.
One of the things that's worth pointing
out is that there's some differences
among these steps.
Some of them are more computational
intensive, so it's mostly,
the work is done by the CPU.
For instance, parsing the request or
computing the header.
This is mostly done by the CPU.
Other steps may require some
interaction with the network,
like accepting connection,
reading request, or sending the data.
Or the disk, for instance,
when finding the file and
then reading the file from the disk.
These steps may potentially block, but
whether or not they block will really
depend on what is the state of the
system at a particular point of time.
So for instance, the connection may
already be pending or the data for
the file may already be cached in memory
because of the previous request that
serviced that file.
So in those cases, these will not result
in an actual call to the device, so
an actual implication of the disk or
the network and
will be serviced much more quickly.
Once the file or potentially the error
message are sent out to the client,
then the processing is complete.