That really ends our conversation about shape from shading.
I'll say that and as I said with lightness,
it's still pretty a pretty under-solved problem.
Back in the 70s, and 80s where the view that the primary job of vision, or
one of the primary jobs of vision was to reconstruct geometry,
there was a lot of focus on how.
Geometry reflected itself in lightness and to try to undo that process.
Remember I talked about vision as being sort of inverse graphics.
That whole focus has diminished quite a bit, and the other thing is,
the idea of being able to take derivatives and
images with our current imaging systems where things are.
You know very it's all sorts of noise and kinds of things like that.
It just was yielding very brittle kinds of results, and like wise the types of
assumptions we had to make were sort of overly restricted.
So I don't think my colleagues would disagree and
say we basically can't do that right now, okay.
So you show us a nice, you know,
my coat lying over there, you guys can't see it, the chair, etc, whatever.
I can tell a lot of shading information, by integrating many multiple cues.
And, we don't really have good techniques for doing that.
There is a question, of whether machine learning is actually a play.
That is, maybe our system doesn't actually undo.
The physics of the image formation.
But instead it has learned,
the relationship between certain image patch appearance and shape.
And it just does that recognition or that mapping, without undoing the physics.
I would say the jury is still out on that.
And probably the truth is going to be somewhere.
In between I mean, Ted Adelson's demonstrations of that shadow casting,
clearly there's a global effect on sort of a local process.
And, exactly how we do that is still unknown.
So, shape from shading is a very old problem, but
we could probably use some very new solutions.
But at least now you have some idea of the,
sort of the nature of the problem and what we have done.