The answer is we can't achieve the goal.
We're just missing a nut so we can't do it.
But we're going to have to consider 4 factorial times 5 factorial paths
before we discover that.
The reason is because we start out, and we say in order to achieve inspected,
we need the precondition of being fastened.
In order to achieve fastened, we need some nut and some bolt.
We can try N1 and B1, but then we would also, when we end up back tracking,
have to try N2 against B1, N3 against B1, and so on, for all these and all these,
and we'd have to do that at every step in the back track.
So we end up trying all combinations of nuts and all combinations of bolts.
That seems silly, and so the idea of resources is to make the nuts and bolts
rather than make each one be distinct so we can handle them more efficiently.