As I mentioned, the core of the doing
of this class are the problem sets.
It says 8.
The first one is a very simple thing
just to make sure that you can get your
images in, do some basic manipulation
of the pixels, and submit them.
It's a way of making sure the mechanics
of everything are working for you.
Then problem sets one through seven
are actually to implement a variety of
the algorithms that we talk
about sometimes some simplified
versions of them.
Apply them to imagery
that we'll give you and
see what sort of results you can get.
A quick thing also,
we'll be using Piazza.
Piazza is a social network thing for
academics.
I've been using this for
a couple of years now in my
class here at Georgia Tech.
Is a great way for
students to communicate about
whatever's bothering them.
Now what's bothering them?
It's always the problem sets.
Every now and then it's the lecturer but
mostly it's the problem sets.
And you'll see, you know, Piazza used
and then all of the sudden the problem
set is due and Piazza use goes like
this and then it goes like that.
So I encourage you strongly
to use the forums.
If you have a question,
almost certainly somebody else
has that same question too.
So go ahead and post it, and
somebody's going to say,
man I'm glad you asked that question.
Or, you may find they already asked
that question, and either or I or
somebody else has already
answered that question.
So I encourage you to
actively use that forum.
Whenever you have a sharing system
like this, people always say, well,
how much exactly are we
allowed to share?
And it's always a challenge, and
here's what I tell students.
Full blackboard or
whiteboard collaboration is fine.
So if you guys want to stand or talk to
each other in front of a whiteboard and
sketch out how the code works and
what you had to do and how you had to
change the parameters, that's great.
What I want you to do, though,
is write your own code.
So, if you're posting an answer to
Piazza, don't post big chunks of code,
because it's just going to be too
tempting for somebody to just take that.
Post sort of what you had to do.
If you don't write your own code,
you won't understand why it is that
certain things make things happen.
I every now and
then get a complaint from people,
why is it that we're implementing
things that just exist in libraries?
And the real answer is,
"so when it doesn't work,
you'll know why." Because guess what?
It often won't work in the library
either or won't work as well.
And then you'll have no
understanding of what goes on.
So, yes some of what you will do
will say you're not allowed to use
now that function A, B or C.
We'll talk about that in a minute.
And it's not just because it's good for
your health right it's not
just like you're eating spinach,
it actually is important for
you to develop some understanding
as to how these algorithms work.
There will be a final exam.
It is not designed to be hard.
It is simply designed to force you to
go back and look at the material and
just for a second time get it into your
head, and it also allows us to ask some
questions about stuff that didn't
show up on the problem sets.
Normally when I give the exam
here it's a three-hour slot and
it takes people an hour.
But it just basically
covers the base material.
The grading, current rubric is
that 85% of the grade is based
upon the problem sets, which means 15%
of the grade is based upon the final,
and the other 10% of the grade
is based upon how I feel.