Now obviously you can answer this question without understanding anything about regression.
But what you find is this is different from classification as before.
This is not a binary concept anymore of like expensive and cheap.
It really is a relationship between two variables.
One you care about--the house price, and one that you can observe,
which is the house size in square feet.
And your goal is to fit a curve that best explains the data.
Once again, we have a case where we can play Occam's razor.
There clearly is a data fit that is not linear that might be better,
like this one over here.
And when you go to high non-linear curves,
you might even be inclined to draw a curve like this.
Now of course the curve I'm drawing right now is likely an overfit.
And you don't want to postulate that this is the general relationship
between the size of a house and the sales price.
So even though my black curve might describe the data better,
the blue curve or the dashed linear curve over here might be a better explanation overture of Occam's razor.
So let's look a little bit deeper into what we call regression.
As in all regression problems, our data will be comprised of
input vectors of length N that map to another continuous value.
And we might be given a total of M data points.
This is from the classification case, except this time the Ys are continuous.
Once again, we're looking for function f that maps our vector x into y.
In linear regression, the function has a particular form which is W1 times X plus W0.
In this case X is one dimensional which is N = 1.
Or in the high-dimensional space, we might just write W times X plus W0,
where W is a vector and X is a vector.
And this is the inner product of these 2 vectors over here.
Let's for now just consider the one-dimensional case.
In this quiz, I've given you a linear regression form with 2 unknown parameters, W1 and W0.
I've given you a data set.
And this data set happens to be fittable by a linear regression model without any residual error.
Without any math, can you look at this and find out to me what the 2 parameters, W0 and W1 are?