So what class would you think
keep is associated with?
Who's doing the keeping?
>> The pile is keeping parts.
The pile?
>> Well, it's keeping a pile.
Okay.
One way of answering the question is
who's doing the keeping here?
Okay, and in fact, its the system.
Its the solution that we're
building that's doing the keeping.
In general,
every system that you design,
you can think of the system itself
as a class, or an object in a class.
But usually you don't explicitly
represent that system class
in your class model.
Okay, so in this case, what
the system is keeping is a pile, and
so we're not going to worry about
keeping an operation of one of
the constituent classes.
It's an operation of the overall system,
okay?
And now count,
what is it that is doing the counting?
>> Counter is doing
the counting of leaves.
>> Okay.
And in the text, what does it say about
counted, in that first line at the end?
>> Have not been counted.
So-
>> So, the parts have not yet
been counted.
So, the operation is counting parts.
We can think of parts as being
an argument to the count's operation,
and the counter, as Jared said,
is going to be doing the counting.
How about get and put?
We'll lump those together.
>> This seems similar to
the system is getting and putting-
>> Well-
>> We're getting trees.
Once again, the trees
are the arguments to the operation.
Getting and putting or
taking them off of the pile.
So we're going to get them from
the pile and put them on the pile.
So in this case,
we're going to associate those
operations with the pile class.
Okay, how about is set to?
>> Is set to.
Leaves, count of the leaves is set to 0.
This seems to belong to the counter.
>> You're right on there.
Okay?
Take off is similar to get and
put, or taking it off of the pile.
>> How about examine?
>> Take a tree off the pile.
The pile could be examine it.
It seems like the pile and
the system are this overarching thing,
like they're the ones
driving this operation.
>> Well, the pile is going to be a part
of this system, but then again, so
is the counter.
And the counter is not the pile.
>> It sounds like the counter's
actions though are usually
on behalf of an operation maybe that
started with what the pile was doing,
which is examining parts of trees.
>> Okay.
And at this stage,
we're doing a static analysis.
The interplay of
the classes is more behavioral analysis,
which would come later.
Okay, so you're right that that's
an important element of understanding
the intended system.
But as far as this initial analysis,
we're going to do it and look for
the structural elements
that are involved.
Okay, here should be an easy one.
How about increment?
>> Counter is increment.
>> Okay, so we need an operation
to increment the counter.
How about throw away, or throw?
>> Increment the leaf counter and
throw away the tree.
So the counter increments and
then throws away the tree?
So it could be the counter
that's throwing it away.
>> Well, a synonym for
throw might be delete.
Okay, and
we're deleting it from the pile.
>> Correct.
>> So there might be an operation
in the pile class for
deleting or throwing away the element.
Okay, how about splitting?
>> Splitting?
The pile splits trees into trees and
sub-trees?
>> I don't think that
the pile does any splitting.
>> The pile's looking
at the split sub-trees.
>> That's correct.
Or storing them.
>> Correct.
Who is doing that?
>> The system?
The-
>> So it's an operation, your splitting.
Okay, who would you send instructions
to actually to do the split?
>> The tree.
Okay, so
we are going to have
an operation on a tree.
It says split thyself and
getting out two results from that.
How about display?
>> Display,
the counter's displaying its count.
>> Sure.
Okay, so you can see the back and
forth in trying to understand
these things that goes on.
All the process we saw before of
combining words together, stemming and
now trying to associate the various
operations with the classes.