So here's a tiny little example, so
let' say we're in this state here that
we know has a self loop of plus five.
And the discount factor is 0.5.
>> Okay.
>> So what's the value of actually
going around this self loop over
and over again?
>> Five times 1 over 1 times 0.5, so 10.
Good, and let's say the Rmax is 10.
And we know that the only other action
that we can take from this state
goes to this state which
has only one action.
And it takes us to this state and
we have no idea what happens from there.
So what do we assume?
>> Well, we assume that you can
always stay there forever doing 10.
>> And the value of that
at this state would be 20.
>> Right, for the same reasons.
>> And the value of that
at this state would be 10.
And the value of this action
At this state would be five.
So from this state,
from this bottom state here.
Even if this has the maximum
possible reward in the self loop,
the most value we can get out of that,
from this state, is five.
So, double discounted, ten loop.
So that means that we know that
the optimal action from this state
is this plus 5.
It's going to be better than even the
best that could possibly be out there,
so we're good.
It might be lower, it could be that
this unknown thing is even lower, but
that only strengthens our case,
that we were doing the right thing.
So the point is that we can
actually be in a loop that
uncovers no new unknown edges, it never
visits something that we haven't seen.
>> Mm-hm.
>> But we still are not making mistakes
and we know we're not making mistakes
because, if we're choosing this
path over something that uses these
optimistic estimates or
these optimistic assumptions.
Then, we're doing at least as
well as the best we could do.
>> Sure, I'll buy that.
I mean, although, that takes advantage
of something that's always bothered me.
>> What's that?
>> You set gamma to be one half right?
>> Yeah, it could be bigger,
I just didn't want to do the math.
>> No, I'm with you.
So, you set gamma to
be equal to one half.
And so, with the gamma one, that's true.
But in reality, when we keep track of
whether an algorithm is doing well or
not, we don't actually discount
the rewards that we see.
We just add them up.
So we are not going to go down
that philosophical rabbit hole.
We are going to accept
discount factors for now.
I agree with you that discount factors
are a little bit hard to swallow.
If we don't though,
I don't think we can make any progress.
>> No I agree.
It does make sense.
It just seemed like it
was worth mentioning.
That you have to take
the discount factors seriously.
That the future really is going to
be discounted from any given point
where you are.
Because otherwise, it actually
makes sense to get to that 10.
>> Yes.
Yes, you're absolutely right.
If we don't have a notion of
a discount or the discount is really,
really high, then it could be that
the highest this could be is going to
give us better than the repeated plus 5.
So yes, we are definitely leaning hard
on the notion of a discount factor.
>> Right.
And in fact, if the discount were 1 or
essentially 1 and
we know that our max is actually right.
Whatever our max is, is right.
You basically, unless you encounter
the actual self-loop, plus ten or Rmax.
Then you have to explore the entire MDP,
you must.
It'll just sort of force you to.
>> Well, okay, we'll do that
as step three of the analysis.
So let me finish this step two first.