Let's take the steps to
complete postToWatchList.
I'm going to start by
copying the code over
from postToFavorites since
they should be similar.
Now wait a minute, you may be thinking
to yourself, Jared's copying code again,
this means that we have duplication,
so should be abstracting this
away into something more elegant?
Well the answer's yes and no.
These methods do share some of the code
but it's really just indicative of
the fact that these two methods
use similar kinds of data.
Now think of it this way, if you're
going to abstract some of this code into
another method,
how often would that method be called?
Would it be reused as often as
something like task forget method or
would it only be called once?
This is the kind of thinking you're
going to have to do as a developer, and
that's the real beauty of design.
My advice would be to abstract away
functionality into methods as necessary,
but don't overdesign something.
You want to strike a balance.
Anyways, back to the code.
The first thing I need to change
is the method that's being used.
So in this case we want to
use the AccountID watchlist.
There we go.
Then I want to change the JSON body
to use the watch list key, and
the watch list value,
that's passed into this function.
There we go.
We'll also need to change over
the name of the completion handler.
And we may also want to
change our error string here.
Outside of this, the rest of
the code can remain the same.
So, lets give this one more run.
Click through to authenticate.
I'll go to my watch list and
let's go to the Lego movie.
Now let me pull it off my watch list,
that looks like it's working.
It's no longer there,
and let's add it back.
And I'll check our watch list.
And there it is.
If you've made it this far then
you're done with the Movie Manager.
Congratulations.