So in the last two
individuals coding tasks,
you implemented the content providers
query method, so this one down here and
modified the UI code to use
the provider query method.
Now in this task, you'll be implementing
the content provider insert method,
as well as update the UI
code in order to use it.
Now I know this might be
a little bit of a challenge but
you are definitely ready for it.
So before we get started,
let's take a look at the insert method.
So from this documentation,
let's click into here.
And we see that the insert method
takes in two parameters, so
it has the Uri and the ContentValues.
So let's explore those in more detail.
So here's a review of the end-to-end
diagram of the insert method
before we dive into coding it.
Now, when we start off and click
the Save button in the Editor Activity,
in order to save off a new pet,
we're going to call
the resolver's insert method.
Passing in the URI and
the ContentValues object.
Now the URI indicates where to
insert the data such as what table.
And the ContentValues indicates what
should be inserted into that row.
Then the Content Resolver over passes
on the request to our provider and
the Uri matcher, then helps us
determine what type of Uri it is.
From there, we decide that we want to
insert a new row into the pets table.
And so this new row gets added.
Now the result of all this is a pet
content Uri with the row ID of
the newly added pet.
And so this newly added row is
added at the end of the Uri.
The Uri will then get returned to
the pet provider's insert method.
Which gets returned by the resolver
back to our editor activity.
So this here is the end to end
flow of our insert method.
So the Uri and
content values goes in and
a new row gets added and
the Uri for that row comes out.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now to implement the insert method,
I'll be providing you some starter code.
As I did before with the query method
to help give you some structure.
And I'm going to give you
two methods this time.
So first, the insert method as well as
another helper method called insertPet.
So this insertPet is one
that we've created and
it's called by the insert
method inside of here.
Now in the quiz associated
with this video,
you will be adding this code
here to your pet provider.
As well as finishing out this to do,
which we have left behind.
So I know this might look
like a lot of code and
it might be a little bit scary,
but don't be intimidated.
Let's take a look at a high level
picture of what's going on here first,
and then dive into the details.
So what's happening is that we'll
be taking in the incoming URI and
using the URI matcher to figure
out what pattern matches.
So similar to what we
do at the query method.
However insertion won't be possible for
the PET_ID case in
this insert situation.
So this situation is not supported
in the URIMatcher insert method.
And this is because it doesn't
make sense to insert a new method
into a single row where
a pet already exists.
So hence, we'll only be inserting
a new pet in the pets case.
Because we're performing this
operation on the whole table.
Now within this case, we'll be
getting back a database object, and
then perform the insertion
on that object.
So with that high-level step in mind,
let's walk through the code.
Now, within the provider's
insert method,
we'll first use the URI matcher
to check if there's a match.
Next we're going to use the switch
statements to determine
which case it falls into.
Now, as I mentioned earlier, only the
PETS case is supported for insertion.
So any other match, or perhaps no match,
will just fall into the default case,
and an exception will be thrown.
So within the pets case, we'll be
calling the insert pet helper method.
Now we didn't necessarily need
an extra helper method out here.
We could've as easily put all this
logic up here inside the insert method,
inside the pets case.
But since we'll be adding
more code in this TODO line.
It's going to get pretty long in here.
So to make it easier to read,
we've pulled out this code
into a separate helper method,
and now we have two shorter methods
instead of just one long one.
Now within the insert pet method,
for this to do,
you're going to be responsible for
interacting with SQLite database to do
the insertion where the new pet will
have the attributes contained
within that contentValues subject.
Now the last sort of code of our
insertPet method will return to us
the URI for the newly inserted Pet.
Now let's walk through an example
to make all this clear.
So in this example, say the provider
insert( ) method Is called with
the General Pet URI, so ending in /pets.
As well as a content value subject.
Now say this content values object
contains these key value pairs.
Where the name is Tommy,
the breed is Pomeranian,
the gender is 1 and the weight is 4.
So note that we don't specify the ID
here because the row ID will be
auto-generated in increasing order as
we insert new pets into the table.
Now within the insert() method,
we're going to detect that
the Uri matches our pets case.
And from there we can proceed
with the database change.
So the Java code that you'll write in
the TODO section down in insert pet.
It will ultimately translate
into this SQLite statement.
Where we insert into pets for the
columns name, breed, gender, and weight.
And then we use the values Tommy,
Pomeranian, 1, and 4.
So the result of this database insertion
will be a new row ID which could be
6 for example if there are already
five pets already in the database.
Notice that the ID number is
automatically returned as the returned
value for our insert method.
Instead what we need to do is call
ContentUris.withAppendedId and
use this method to generate
the proper pet Uri for us.
So taking a closer look at
this line of code, see that
the contentUris.withAppendedId method
knows how to take our pet content URI.
So this here shown here in green and
add the number 6 shown in
purple at the end of it.
So the return value of this
method would be this URI.
So zooming back to this diagram,
we see that the return value is our URI.
And this will go all the way
back to our Editor Activity.
Now I want you to go ahead and
help implement the insert method
into your PetProvider class.
So start by replacing the insert
method already in there, but
the code link below in the Gist.
Also remember to add
the insert pet helper method
which we've provided in the Gist and
finish out the TODO marked in the code.
Also for the second half of this quiz,
I want you to update the UI code
to use the provider insert method.
And now what you can ensure that your
code from the first half of this quiz,
is acting correctly.
So by that I mean there
are two places with an app
that we need to insert a new
pet into the provider.
So the first one is in the catalog
activity where we insert dummy data via
the Insert Dummy Data menu item.
And second place is in our Editor
Activity when we hit the Save button to
save off a new pet.
So in this coding exercise,
you will need to modify both the catalog
activity and the editor activity to
take advantage of the provider's insert
functionality that you just added.
So to recap what I just said, remove
any old code in the two activities
that query the database directly.
And instead I want you to call the
ContentResolver's insert( ) method which
in turn calls the provider's
insert( ) method.
You may also want to update the text
message that gets displayed
in the EditorActivity,
letting the user know that the pet
has been successfully saved or not.
And it's because there's no need
to show the user the row ID or
the content URI of the new pet.
And lastly as a tip, move the user
visible friendly text in the text
message into the strings.xml
resource file.
Remember this is good practice, so
we're not hard coding this
information into the Java file.
So here's an example of what the updated
text message would look like.
So once the pet is entered
into the EditorActivity and
saved off, this new text message could
simply just say that the pet is saved.