So to help us go through this whole process of learning how to merge two images,
let's look at two specific example images.
Here I'm going to use, of course, a image like this and another image like this.
Both of skin of two different well known cats.
To help us with our analysis, let's just deal with black and
white images for now.
So what we're interested in is merging these two images together to
form one novel image.
What we can do is take one image, take the second one.
And, as we learned in one of our earlier lessons, just do some sort of
point arithmetic to combine these two images and come up with a weight of
taking one percentage of the other, and one percentage of the other.
So, for example, I could just take 50% of the pixel values from this image and
50% from the pixel values of this image and just do a simple pixel arithmetic.
Just add with the weight 50/50 between those two.
That would show us this blended image.
So of course, here you notice now real blending going on.
This part of the spot here, and
this part of the spot here are kind of now merged.
And of course there's transparency and
there's overlap of these types of spots from one image to the other.
Of course, we could play around with how we merge this thing,
get more information from this, less from that and
now actually, we can see that this spot is less visible, that spot is more.
So again, variety of ways we can do these blends.
Let's look at this again a little bit more carefully and
see what we can do with it.
My goal in this exercise is for us to now take this image and that image and
put them next to each other and blend them just around, in this region.
So for example, this is my boundary between those two images and
I want to be able to blend aspects of this image, this side and this side, and
basically I want to have a blended image right in the middle where the line is,
somewhere in this range, across the whole region.
So this box, let's say, you know, just a few pixels from the center here in
this here, I want to do all of the blending, so I want to actually have
this spot here, and not just have a sharp line, but merge over here, and
similarly, these two spots kind of also have a little bit of blending going on.
So that's our goal.