So to answer this question, let's look at each and one, each and
every one of them separately.
For example this one, if you notice there is no distinguishing mark here
anywhere that would allow me to kind of find this repeatable, any point here,
here, here would actually have the same characteristics but
this is definitely not a good feature.
Similarly, here if this was the feature anywhere along this line, and
with rotation anywhere along this line or this line would also match this.
So this is not a very good feature.
It's not easily matchable.
This one, the feature is here, and any point along this line, or
for example, even with rotation, anywhere along this point, and
many other points on this image, this would match exactly.
Not a good feature.
Same problem here.
Basically it's got a line here, and anywhere on this point and with rotation
around here and here, this would of match as a feature, not a good feature.
This one, again, a line anywhere across this one or
on the other side here, would match all of this point here, not a good feature.
So, so far, we've gone gone ahead and negated out one, two, three,
four, five of these features.
Now, let's look for what would be good features.
Here is a point.
If you notice, this is a corner.
Which basically is rather unique and yes, exactly this corner with blue and
the kind of the beige color doesn't really repeat anywhere else.
This actually would make for a good feature.
This one also has kind of a corner information here.
And in fact maybe would be one of the ideal ones again because just by looking
at it, I don’t find this picture again, in this locality here, a good feature.
This one also has a bit of repeating pattern.
And again, a very unique corner makes for a good feature.
So these three are good.
These, one, two, three, four, five are bad features.
Let’s look into, in more detail of what’s going on here