The two models are two extremes,
but in reality,
what makes sense is to
have something in between.
First, we should allow clients to
benefit from using their local memories
and their local disk, and
to store at least some parts of
the file they're working on.
For instance, it makes sense for
clients to download some blocks of
the file that they're accessing.
Or even to apply certain prefetching
techniques just like what regular file
systems do when they're trying to
prefetch blocks from disks into their
memory cache.
This will lead both to lower latencies
for those file operations that acts
as these locally stored or
cached portions of the file.
And by doing this, also some
load is removed from the server
since some operations can be fully
performed on the client machines.
And thus the server
becomes more scalable.
Now, once we allow the clients to store
portions of this file locally and
to perform operations on the file,
including modifications,
it becomes necessary for
the clients to start interacting
with the server for two reasons.
First, the clients need
to notify the server of
any modifications to the file
that they have made.
And also, the clients need to find out
from the server if any of the files that
they have locally cached has
been modified by someone else.
These interactions have to happen
with some reasonable frequency so
that it's not too late by the time
that we discover that certain changes
have been made.
This is beneficial because unlike
in the upload-download model,
with this,
the server is still in the loop.
It has insights into what exactly
are the clients doing, and
it has some control over which accesses
should be permitted versus not.
So it becomes easier to
maintain consistency.
However, the problem with this is that
it makes the file server more complex.
It means that the server would have to
perform additional tasks and maintain
additional state so as to make sure that
it can provide consistency guarantees.
And achieving a practical solution of
this model means that the clients would
have to understand somewhat
different file sharing semantics
compared to what they are used to
in a typical local file system.