Software developers use forums and
discussion boards all the time.
It turns out by a field that's
marked by constant learning,
evidently a life of learning means
a life of reading, and it's hard to
imagine that there's a profession
more steeped in online discussions.
>> Your cohort's forum will be another
indispensable resource during your time
in this nanodegree.
There, you can ask or answer questions
and contribute to discussions.
The Udacity team, as well as
other students in your cohort,
will be there to respond and help out.
Everyone, even the most experienced
of engineers get stuck sometimes when
trying to solve problems.
So please don't hesitate to
take advantage of the forum for
help if you're ever in this position.
You can search to see if someone has
already asked a question related to
yours, or
you can make a new post if no one has.
Chances are someone else is wondering
about the same thing you were,
so don't be shy.