Another problem with linear regression has to do with the regularization
or complexity control.
Just like before, we sometimes wish to have
a less complex model.
So in regularization, the loss function is either the sum
of the loss of a data function and a complexity control term,
which is often called the loss of the parameters.
The loss of the data is simply curvatic loss, as we discussed before.
The loss of parameters might just be a function that penalizes
the parameters to become large
up to some known P, where P is usually either 1 or 2.
If you draw this graphically,
in a parameter space comprised of 2 parameters,
your curvatic term for minimizing the data error
might look like this, where the minimum sits over here.
Your term for regularization might pull these parameters toward 0.
It pulls it toward 0, along the circle if you use curvatic error,
and it does it in a diamond-shaped way.
For L1 regularization--either one works well.
L1 has the advantage in that parameters tend to get really sparse.
If you look at this diagram, there is a tradeoff between W-0 and W-1.
In the L1 case, that allows one of them to be driven to 0.
In the L2 case, parameters tend not to be as sparse.
So L1 is often preferred.