So one question I usually get is, what are the requirements for
this class, and what is expected, and
specifically, what is expected of students who are enrolling in this class.
Let me try to outline some of those things now.
So just to re-emphasize, this is a computational photography class, and
we're interested in trying to understand the computational pipeline of how
an image is formed, how a camera captures an image, the rays of light.
And also, how do we actually process this information?
To do this, you will need to know things like linear algebra, calculus,
and probability.
Linear algebra, because as you will learn,
we will represent a whole lot of things as matrix, matrices, and vectors.
Calculus because we'll be looking at differential and
integration types of processes to understand the math.
Some of the concepts of what happens within an image, and probability because at
the end of the day there's a lot of sampling associated with it.
Look at these images and we need to be able to look at
from the statistics of this and probability distribution function of these.
Another thing that would be important is the comp,
the computational release associated and what happens when an image is formed.
To support this we're going to provide you with
tools one an experimental one within browser for
you to track images, but then to really do this kind of stuff in real,
you'll have to play around with a toolkit called or, or an API called openCV.
CV stands for computer vision.
Python and C++ are the languages associated with that.
We'll give you examples on how to get started on these types of things.
In fact, some of the same things will be used within a browser.
The good thing with this is you will be able to
put this on your own workstations and actually do the assignments.
And more importantly play around with the concepts we will be
discussing in class.
Another thing that is available to you would be things like Matlab and
Octave, where you can actually also do these types of things.
That are, actually we going to be covering in class.
One question I always get is do I need a high-end camera?
Well, having any kind of camera would be useful because you'll be
taking a few pictures and playing around with this on your own.
But really there's no need for high-end SLR camera or something like that.
Of course, if you feel like buying one.
Use this class as an excuse.
Feel free to.
We will also provide you with images of various types of you know, for
example, different exposure levels to do HDR and stuff like that,
that'll help you do your assignments and all the work that is needed.
But remember, the biggest goal of this class is start opening black boxes on
the kinds of things that you've been using with images and
photography all the time.
How does a camera work, what are the processes that go within a camera?
Your fave, favorite software that you use is Photoshop.
In this class, we learn how to open the black boxes and
how some of the tools that you've been using regularly.
What do they really do to images?
So that's really more about the technical aspects of photography that
we're going to be looking at.