Let me actually, showcase another interesting example.
This is an example from the landing,
the emergency landing of the US Air flight in the Hudson River in New York.
It's again, you know, the ability of this pilot to
land the airplane was amazing and he saved a lot of lives.
In this case, we've got several types of images.
First, before the plane landed,
many people from high rises up in New York City saw the plane and
took pictures, and these pictures were on Twitter worst, pretty fast.
These were participatory or citizen images.
Shortly after, when the the plane landed of course,
organizations like news agencies got there, and we got images like this.
Basically, showing where the plane was and how the rescue efforts were going on?
So, Participatory Citizen Data, Institutional Imagery.
What was interesting was next day, they went and found these videos.
Where you can actually, see the plane land.
So these were not videos or
these were not cameras placed there with that purpose in mind.
These were cameras placed there for security purposes.
And again, merging these types of things,
now we get a much different view of what's happening in that interesting event.
And again, thankfully many people were saved at this event.