In this example, your cursor contains
all of the words and definitions.
There are a variety of ways to get
information from your cursor object.
And working with cursors return from
the content provider is exactly the same
as working with cursors return for
the sequel like database.
To help out though,
I'm going to review a couple of key
methods that you should know about now.
I will also show how to iterate
through the rows inside of a cursor.
You'll need to know how to do some
of this to be able to finish out
the exercise.
The data of a cursor is tabular,
as seen here.
The data returned in your
cursor is pretty simple.
There are only three columns.
A cursor has a position, which is
the row it's currently pointing to.
When you first get your cursor
back from the query method,
in it's position at row negative one,
which is nothing.
When you call move to next, it moves
the cursor to the next row that it can.
And then it will either return true or
false depending on if the move
was successful or not.
So here, it would have returned true,
and then every time you call moveToNext
again, it will move
the cursor one more row down.
Again, here returning true each time.
Now once you get to the final row,
It won't be able to move the cursor
anymore, and then it will return false.
If you want to move the cursor somewhere
else besides the next position,
there are a few other move to methods.
This includes but
isn't limited to moveToFirst, which
moves the cursor back to the first row.
Each column in the cursor has an index.
When you're at a row and
you want to know some information
such as what word is at that row,
it's important to know the column index.
You can look up this column index by
using the getColumnIndex method, and
passing column heading.
The column heading is
found in the contract.
Then, you can use one of the get
methods to get the actual value.
Which get method you use depends
on the type of data that you're
expecting to get back.
For example, if you're getting a word,
you'd use get string.
If you're trying to get the ID,
you'd use get integer.
Again, you need to pass
in the column index.
Get count returns the number of
rows that are in the cursor.
And close should be called when you're
done interacting with your cursor.
If you don't do this you could create
a memory leak which will leave nobody
happy.
Your app might crash, so
just don't forget to do it.
Here's a handy code snippet for
iterating over all of the rows that
are cursor and then finally
printing out what was in the table.
It contains some of
the methods that we just saw.
Let's take a look at it in the code.
So here the code snippet
in our actual code.
I put it in the on
post execute method so
that I have the cursor available to me.
These two lines of code are simply
using the getColumnIndex method
to get the index of the word and
definition column.
I use constants from the contract class
to be able to actually loop this up.
This loop here will move
the cursor from row to row.
And for each row, it gets the value
of the word of the row and
the value of the definition of that row.
And then finally prints
it in a log message.
After that, we are a good Android
citizen and we close up our cursor.
Okay, lets see what
the output looks like.
Now the app UI on the cellphone actually
changed but if I go over here and
look at the log messages.
I'll see that for every single word that
was in the cursor, I have that word and
its definition.
Hopefully, this is enough about
cursors to get you started.
If you're looking for more information,
check out the links below.