The first statement.
The attacker does not have to use
his own computer in the attack.
As we just illustrated, the attacker
used botnets to launch such attack.
Second statement.
Since there are so
many computers involved in the attack,
it is difficult to distinguish
legitimate from malicious traffic.
This is true.
A victim, say, for
example, a web server,
receives traffic from computers all over
the internet, and it is difficult to
distinguish legitimate connection
requests from malicious ones.
The third statement.
The characteristics of DNS servers help
mitigate the effect of DDOS attacks.
And this is false.
Because DNS servers can send a lot
more traffic to a web server than
an individual computer.