What did you learn recently,
last week or last month,
that you thought was
particularly interesting?
>> Related to IOS development or just?
>> Let's do development general or
specifically IOS.
>> Sure.
So I do follow several
Like SwiftBlogs and
places that are constantly putting out
talks that people are giving on Swift.
And there's one in particular about
GameplayKit, which is new to iOS nine.
And it's talking about how you can
use things that are more tailored for
game applications for
non-game applications so.
In particular they talk about how games
play could has this concept of state
machines and state machines are good for
managing transitions between
different states of application and
this particular speaker is talking about
they use the state machine to manage
the state of his navigation stack
kind of how to quickly route from
a really deep part of the navigation
stack back to the View Controller to
a certain new controller using the state
machine and also using pathfinding.
So it was just an interesting
take on a gameplay kit in
kind of nontraditional uses of it.
>> Talking about blogs,
what blogs or websites do you,
technical ones,
>> Do you follow on a regular basis?
>> So for
a while I've been following NS hipster,
who writes good articles about different
parts of Apple frameworks and things.
I've also been following Tasha the
robot, she's a really great developer
and she does a lot of Swift so that's
good for anyone doing swift development.
I've also done my best here
recently to tune into when so
summits are happening another Swift
what's the word meet apps and
things like that to see what
people are talking about.
I think realm IO has a newsletter
that you can subscribe to or
they are releasing videos and
conferences and Speeches that
people are giving about Swift.
>> Have you been to any conference?
Or are you planning to go?
>> I haven't been to any
Swift Conferences before, no.
But I'm hoping to, so