Let's suppose we have a function, g, which is just f convolved with h.
Maybe h is a filter, f was the original image, doesn't matter,
it's f convolved with h, and suppose I want the Fourier transform of g.
All right, well, that's going to be written as follows, 'kay?
Our definition right, G of u, is just the Fourier Transform of g of x.
But g of x is just the convolution, so
that's sort of in here, this part here, of f with h.
Remember that was my definition of G, the convolution of f with h.
What I can do is I can rearrange this, and you'll see what I did here was,
this was u x, so here we have u tau, and here we have x minus tau.
All right, and so
if you multiply those together, you would just get u x, so it's the same thing.
But I've rearranged it, so all the tau stuff is here.
And all the x stuff is there, with this tau in there.
And so, we're going to make a quick change of variables, right?
I'm going to say, let's define a new variable of x minus tau is x prime.
So, now I've just, just converted that to x prime.
So, now I've got one integral here, and one integral there.
And if you stare at those, and you ask yourself, get ready.
What are those integrals?
>> What are those integrals?
>> Well, what are those integrals?
Well, let's take a look at just this integral.
That's the fourier transform of f, right?
You happen to use tau instead of x, but it's the same thing.
This is the Fourier transform of H, so
that can be written as just F u times H u.
Megan laughed when I said F u, by the way.
So G of u is just F u times H of u.
In other words, remember G was the convolution of F with H.
G of u, the frequency domain is just the product
of the Fourier transforms of F and H, okay?
So the idea here is that when you do convolution in the spatial domain,
you're essentially doing multiplication in the frequency domain.
And this is going to be really important, for
the next lesson when we talk about aliasing, and also for what we're going to
talk about here in terms of how convolution does frequency manipulation.
So this is just written here, is that if in if the spatial domain I
do convolution, in the frequency domain, I'm doing multiplication.
Also by the way, because of the symmetry of how the transforms work.
If I were to multiply in the spatial domain, that is, if I took two functions
and I multiply them together, I don't convolve it, I just multiply them.
The Fourier transform of that new function is going to be
the convolution of the Fourier transforms of each of the individuals, okay.
We're going to make use of that, both here, and
a little bit when we talk about aliasing.
So, in the spatial domain you do convolution in the,
in the frequency domain it's multiplication or vice-a-versa.