Here's how I came up with the answer. Since
the first 17 bits are fixed, that also means that
the first 16 are fixed. So I can go
ahead and write 130.58 in here. Now, there's one more
bit that's fixed. So, the one that represents a
128 here must also be 0. So the biggest that
I can make this eight bit address while sending
that top bit to zero is a 127, so I'll
write that. And then these bits are free, so the biggest I can make that is 255.
Actually, this IP would never get assigned to a
particular computer, because the highest in the range usually
indicates broadcast. That is to say this IP
means send the data to the whole subnet. Similarly,
the lowest address doesn't get assigned either. This is
used to refer to the subnet as a whole.