This notion of coherently
moving objects actually comes
from some very early work in vision that
was done by, the Gestalt psychologist.
Gestalt psychology,
which is really sort of the turn of,
I was about to say the turn of the
century, turn of the previous century,
really around 1900 or so, is when
they first started thinking about
the types of processes of the brains,
the brain does.
In terms of what actually has
to be constructed, if you will.
That is, what sort of processing
does the brain have to do.
Now, it, they didn't really have
computational models yet, so
it was very descriptive.
But it really was the precursor to
a lot of the computational stuff,
that we all do now.
So, one of the founders pictured
here is Max Wertheimer.
And if you, if you read, it says that
one of the things that really interested
him was, at a train station, you could
see a set of moving lights going.
You know, one, then another,
then another, then another,
and of course these lights
would just come on.
But his, he and everybody else,
saw it as moving, right?
Saw these sequence of lights as motion.
And his question was,
how does that happen?
What is the brain using?
And he took a bunch of his assistants,
who later went on to also become
famous Gestalt psychologists, and
they started looking at the way
the human system groups things together.
And they came up with a bunch of rules.
So up here we have the not grouped,
right?
We just have a bunch of black dots.
Well it turns out if you just
move them a little bit, right?
Proximity will cause you to say oh
I have three sets of two there.
Likewise appearance, though you see
that there's black, white, black.
All right?
Similarity also in shapes,
we've got a horizontal ellipsis and
vertical ellipsis.
But one of the ones that they
did that was kind of cool
was called common fate and
you can see what common fate here means
is that they're moving the same way.
And then this gets studied tremendously
by all sorts of people doing work in
psycho-physics and trying to understand
how far could a point move between
two frames for you to see it moving?
And then it turned out that they
were actually different things.
If you do it a very small amount, you
actually see the point moving, right?
You actually see that it went
through all those little stages.
And then, if I put the point further
away, it'd be off and then on.
You would get a sense of motion but
you didn't think you
actually saw the point move.
You would think it disappeared here and
reappeared there.
So you had this idea
that something move but
you didn't actually
see the things moving.
That was called a long range process.
I think these were done by Oliver
who was a famous psycho-physicist.
And so anyway, so this is, this idea of
how does the brain process such motion?
Sometimes, common fate is
the only cue you have.
So for example,
I'm showing you a random dot image.
You probably don't see very much there.
What do you see?
You see random dots.
Good.
All right?
Take it away.
Yawn.
[NOISE] Well don't yawn,
you'll go to sleep.
All right, put up another one.
There it is.
Is that the same random dot image?
You have no idea.
Okay?
But let me go to the next one.
This is a gif I made myself,
I'm very happy.
Now you're seeing two random dot images
sequenced right after the other.
So what you're probably
seeing is a square moving.
Back and forth, right and
left, all right.
You probably see a pretty
sharp boundary of that square.
You actually think there's
like an edge there.
Well, let me stop it, no edge, okay.
That edge was manufactured in your
head based upon the motion field.
Okay, and our goal is to understand this
computation of motion that would allow
a system to say there is a boundary
here based upon different motion.