All right, so now it's your turn
to implement an interstitial ad.
Here's a check list so you can keep
track of all the things you need to do.
First of all in the load
interstitial method, I want you to
create an interstitial ad object and
assign it to the member of the class.
Then set the ad unit id to
the test interstitial ad unit id
that we just looked at.
Create an ad listener that
inherits from toast listener and
overloads the following methods.
When onAdLoaded is called,
the show button should be enabled.
And when onAdFailedToLoad is called,
there should be an error message, and
the button should remain disabled.
Then create an AdRequest and
load the interstitial ad.
For the showInterstitial method check
to confirm that the ad is loaded and
then show it.
Then reset the button
by disabling it and
setting the text to loading
interstitial again.
Check this box when you are finished.