Congratulations, it's final project time.
For your final project, our boss needs a real-time,
dynamic visualization of tweets that contain worldwide top hashtags.
To implement this final project,
begin with a Storm Topology that calculates the TopN Hashtags.
Write a new Bolt that takes in TopN Hashtags
with a streaming join of real-time tweets.
Next, visualize only real-time Tweets that contain the TopN Hashtags.
If dynamically calculating and joining TopN Hashtags is difficult,
you may pre-calculate the TopN hashtags, halt your Topology, and
enter these statically into a new Spout.
However, you must use at least one new Bolt and
a streaming join to complete the basic implementation of your final project.
After this basic implementation is complete, update your screencast or
screenshot to the forum at the end of this lesson.
You may then add on as many extensions as you like,
including changing the entire project, using any number of data sources and
any visualization you either find or create.
You do not need to use the Tweet stream after you've implemented your
basic project.
We hope you continue on through this lesson as you work on your
final project to work alongside our hackathon participants.
See the types of questions come up, particularly around designing topologies.
Finally, at the end of this lesson when you see this screen, post your final
project basic implementation to the forum and comment on two additional posts.
If you like, Tweet out your image to your followers using Twitter.
Next, again, at the end of this lesson,
if you've worked on extensions throughout the hackathon along with our students,
post them at the final project extension forum and comment on two other posts.
Tweet your projects to your followers.
I hope you have fun exploring your final project, and good luck.
We can't wait to see your basic implementation and
any extension ideas that you come up with.