we're here with Kirsten from the Udacity
careers team Kristin and her team will
be providing you with career support
throughout the program in your effort to
find a job in self-driving car industry
will help to ensure your application
materials are polished you're ready for
interviews and you're connected to
employers in the field will also be
taking you behind-the-scenes that top
auto manufacturers to get an idea of
what they're looking for and how the
hiring process works in addition to this
or we're working with more than a dozen
hiring partners that are leaders in this
field such as mercedes-benz nvidia BMW
auto DD and many more
we're also working with software
company's radar and lidar manufacturers
and many others are searching for top
talent and it's growing field having
hiring partners like these means that
you as a student have direct and
preferential exposure at these companies
which will give you a significant
advantage in your job search
Kirsten is just one of the many
dedicated people here at Udacity that
you'll interact with throughout the
program will also have reviewers mentors
other students career staff hiring
partners and of course Ryan and to help
you along the way it's these people that
will help you make the most of your
Udacity experience and so on behalf of
all of us
welcome to the program