All right.
So in the last section, we optimized
our neural network to better find
the correlation of our data set by
removing some distracting noise.
And the neural network attended
the signal so much better.
It trained 83% accuracy
in the training data, and
the testing accuracy was up to 85%.
And this was just after one iteration.
So we probably could have kept training
it, and squeeze out a little more,
but we're going to keep looking
at this one iteration benchmark
to see how fast we can get
the neural net to train.
I mean, this is up from 60% before,
so this is a huge gain.
In accuracy and the speed of
training for our neural network, and
that was a lot of progress.
However, the actual raw
computational speed,
the number of seconds that it takes to
do a full pass is still pretty slow.
What I want to be able to do in here
is attack this network and say okay.
What is this thing doing that is
wasteful on the computation site.
So before we had kind
of a wasteful data and
now I want to say what is
wasteful inside this neural net.
Coz you know it's funny.
You could do a lot of things
on this theory side and
try to say okay how can it learn faster.
But truth is,
the other one before was the learning.
It was just taking a really long time.
So we also could of tied a optimize
the computational side so
that it's just train so
much more faster that it's still able to
learn what we want the other to learn.
The faster you can get your neural
to train then, to be honest.
The longer you'll let it
train before you get bored.
And you'll find more interesting stuff.
And people who train neural nets.
You can kind of just keep training.
There's no natural finish.
It's unlike probabilistic
graphical models.
Or many of them,
anyways, where you do a discrete
count of lots of different things.
And then when it's done, it's done.
In accuracy, neural nets can
kind of just keep training, right?
But the faster you can get it to train,
the more data that you can put into it,
the stronger it can be.
So what we're going to do here
is we're going to analyze
what's going on in our network and
look for things that we can
shave out that are going to allow
our neural net to go faster.
And now there's one first one
that kind of stands out to me.
We're creating a really big vector for
layer 0.
It's 74,000 and
70 something values, right?
And only a handful of them
are being turned onto 1.
Now why does this matter?
Well, this four propagation
step is a weighted sum.
We take this 1, we multiply it by
these weights, we add it into layer 1.
Then, we take the next one, 0,
we multiply it by these weights and
we add that into layer 1.
Woh, wait a minute.
We take a zero and
we multiple it by these weights, and
then we add the result of that.
That means every time there's a zero,
when we take this vector and
do a big matrix multiplication to
create our layer one, all these zeros
aren't doing anything, because zero
times anything is still just zero.
So, zero times this
vector added into layer
one doesn't change layer one
from what it was before.
So that, to me, is like the biggest
source of inefficiency in this network.
To kind of show you,
computationally, and
sort of prove to you that this
is the case, check this out.
So we have kind of a fake layer
0 that only has 10 values,
we're going to picture it here.
And then we're going to say,
okay, layer zero.
Layer 0, 4=1, layer, kind of pretend
that we put a few words in here.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now we're looking at layer zero again,
it looks like that, right?
So, weights 01, we're going to say
this is just a random write matrix.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then we're going to say,
okay, layer0.weights01.
Okay, so that's the output.
Now, what if instead we only summed
these vectors in here, right?
So we just said, okay,
1 times this goes in here.
So if we have these two indices,
4, 9, we have to have a new layer,
right?
So layer1 equals np.zeros, so
it's empty, and it's got 5 values.
And we're going to say,
for index in indices,
weights0 1, index, layer 1.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
+= 1 *, because one is
going in the data, layer one.
Boom.
Exactly the same values,
look at that and
the cool thing here is we only actually
worked with part of this matrix.
So if this, you know two words
out of 70,000 words then we
just saved not having to,
you know perform this operation in
this sum with the 69,000 other words.
That should be a pretty great savings.
Now, we'll see how much it actually
works out to in the end, but
that should be really positive.
I'll be curious to see how
that kind of works out.
Now let's take a look at the neural net
again, look for some more efficiency.
Now the other thing that's inefficient
is one times anything is just itself so
this whole one times
thing is kind of a waste.
So what if instead we change
this to just be a sum?
One times,
we can just eliminate that, right?
So [INAUDIBLE], pair one,
still the same thing.
Awesome.
So we got rid of this multiplication, we
got rid of doing these all together, and
we're still getting
the same hidden state.
That we were getting when we did this
full dot practice, this full matrix or
vector matrix multiplication.
I'm really liking this.
I think this is a ton to build upon.
And most of the weights are over here,
right?
There's only four weights that go
from the hidden to the output.
Well in our case it's hidden layer size.
I think we have a bigger layer, but
most of the computation is here.
74,000 by whatever hidden layer size,
this is the beefy part of training and
writing our neural net.
So that brings us to
kind of the next project.
So project five is about installing this
into the neural network from before.
So I'm going to go ahead and let you
take a stab at that and then we're
going to come back and talk about how
we can do that in a neural net before.
All right, best of luck.