So let me motivate the problem.
Remember stereo twice good.
All right, if you have two views of the scene, and these are two cameras that
are not necessarily going to have parallel image planes, just two views.
What is the relationship between the location of a scene point in one camera and
its location in the other camera.
That was what we wanted to know,
we wanted to know if we could know something about that relationship so
when we went looking for the matches, we could use it as a constraint.
Just to animate it a little bit, if we have of points, so
the idea is we have a point P, out there in the scene.
That point images to some location in the left image plane, center projection 1
here, and that line maps to a line in the center projection number two, and
that was what was referred to as an epipolar line with respect to that point.
So if you're looking for
that point, it's going to have to be somehow on that line.
Likewise the ray from the other center of projection maps to
the corresponding epipolar line in the other image, its center projection.
And those pair of epipolar lines, we showed before, that they're defined by
a plane called the epipolar plane, and that plane is defined, well, the simplest
way of thinking about it, is that it's defined by this base line vector.
So the translational vector between the two centers of projection and
this world point.
Or you could think of it as being defined by the three points,
P, CP2, CP1, that's the epipolar plane.
So we have a different epipolar plane for each point out in the world.
We then talked about what we call the epipolar constraint.
Right? The idea was, if I know about my epipolar lines or
I know about the epipolar planes.
The epipolar constraint means that if I have a point P
in the image on the left hand side.
There's only a one dimensional search in the right hand image to look along.
That was the epipolar line.
For the parallel image planes, everything lined up,
it was the same horizontal line.
But in general, if I have verged cameras we showed your
epipolar lines weren't going to be parallel.
And here was this example where we had converged cameras and
corresponding epipolar lines.
It also allowed us to define a couple of terms.
So the baseline was just the vector separating the two centers of projection.
The epipolar plane we just talked about, given a world point and
that baseline defines the plane.
The epipolar lines were the intersection of the epipolar plane and
each of the image planes, so that's a pair of corresponding epipolar lines.
The epipole of each image was the point in
the image plane that intersected the baseline.
And we said sometimes you don't actually see that, in fact if we, if we go
back to this pair of images here, all of these would have intersected over here.
So if this image had been huge, you would have been able to see the epipole, but
because it's in some sense cropped out, you can't always see the epipole.