[Thrun] So congratulations. You learned a lot about Bayes networks.
You learned about the graph structure of Bayes networks,
you understood how this is a compact representation,
you learned about conditional independence,
and we talked a little bit about application of Bayes network
to interesting reasoning problems.
But by all means this was a mostly theoretical unit of this class,
and in future classes we will talk more about applications.
The instrument of Bayes networks is really essential to a number of problems.
It really characterizes the sparse dependence that exists in many readable problems
like in robotics and computer vision and filtering and diagnostics and so on.
I really hope you enjoyed this class,
and I really hope you understood in depth how Bayes networks work.