So the goal of this lecture is to start,
for
us to start thinking about how we can
control the illumination in the scene.
So this was our projector system, and
using this I'll actually
showcase two different examples.
One, I'll actually talk
about the Lightstage,
where a light is shown on a subject
from these controllable light sources.
And, of course,
based on how this light are,
is illuminating the scene,
we can now create a model of
learning the illumination of this
person from different light sources.
And of course that will
allow us to do re-lighting.
Another example, that we've looked
at when we actually talked about
extracting depth
information from images,
was this concept of a trimensional
device on an iPhone, or
software for trimensional on an iPhone,
which let us basically take pictures
with different illuminations and
allowed us to capture a 3D model.
Let's look at them again just briefly
to help us understand the importance of
controllable light or
controllable illumination for
variety of applications.