It's time to connect to the internet.
To make this a bit easier,
we created a helper method called
getresponseFromHttpURL and network it
tells that performs the connection.
Lets' talk about how this works.
Believe it or not, you've already done
a big chunk of the work by creating
the URL object with
the appropriate query.
In order to get an http connection,
we just call an open connection on URL.
Note that this doesn't actually
talk to the network yet.
It just creates the http
URL connection object.
At this point, we could set the request
method, or add header fields, or
change properties of the connection.
We then get an input stream
from the open connection.
Next, we have to read the contents
of this input stream.
There are many ways to do this in Java,
but we've chosen to do using scanner.
Which is used to tokenize Streams,
because it's simple an relatively fast.
By setting the delimiter to \A,
beginning of the Stream.
We force the scanner to read
the entire contents of the stream into
the next token stream.
It's a bit of a sneaky trick, but
it does a number of things
automatically for us.
It buffers the data.
This means that it not only pulls the
data from the network in small chunks,
but because http isn't required
to give us a content size,
our code needs to be ready to
handle buffers of different sizes.
This code automatically allocates and
deallocates the buffers as needed.
It also handles the character
encoding for us.
Specifically, it translates from UTF-8
which is the default encoding for
json and JavaScript to UTF-16,
the format used by android.
There are lots of ways to do this and
we've added a link to stack overflow
where you can read about them.
Also there are some great libraries that
both simplify Android networking while
adding functionality to the http stack.
We've added information
on one of our favorites.
We're really close to achieving internet
connectivity but we need to do one more
thing before Android will let us grab
bits and bites from wherever we please.
We have to ask permission