Let's see how well you understand all
of the ideas we've discussed so far.
Here's a loop nest which implements
a matrix vector multiplication.
That is, suppose you're given a matrix
A which is of size n by n, and
two vectors, each of length n.
Then this loop nest
computes y = y + A times x.
Now the complexity of this operation is
O(n squared) since I have nested loops,
each with n iterations.
Here's my question.
There are two for-loops.
Which ones can I convert
into a parallel for-loop?
Your options are,
you can only safely convert loop 1 or
you can only convert loop 2.
Or you can convert both loops or
you can't convert either loop.
Choose one.