Okay, so that's called the essential matrix.
And it's maps between calibrated systems.
And what was really important about this whole operation is that we
converted the geometric constraint that we had talked about back in the stereo
days where we were talking about epipolar planes and, and looking for them.
We converted a geometric constraint into an algebraic constraint.
All right.
But, you ask, suppose I have uncalibrated cameras?
Geometrically, thinking about, if you gave me enough points that you told me,
this point corresponds to that and this point correspond to that.
It feels like I should be able to figure out
how the epipolar lines are constrained.
So what I need to do is to somehow figure out the algebraic relation between
images, given those correspondences, and that algebraic relation will give us
the relation between a point in one image and its epipolar line in the ima,
in the other image, if you gave me enough correspondences.
That's what's called a fundamental matrix, and
that's what we'll do in the next lesson.