This is going to be an improvement
upon our previous header design.
We have a form of text and
I want the text field to be all the same
size and they must also be aligned.
Seems pretty straight forward so
let's give it a try.
Let's layout the views first,
now let's stack this stuff into
three horizontal StackViews and
one StackView, a vertical
StackView that contains them all.
And let's give them names.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And now we're going to pin this
header to these three sizes.
Top, left, and right.
Not the bottom, otherwise it
would deform the StackView and
we don't need that.
Fix the misplacement.
Okay so once again it doesn't
look exactly the way we want.
However, some of the issues
are easy to fix.
We already know how to set a space here,
a space here, here, and
here between the stack views.
And also, we know how to make
these StackViews stretch
all the way horizontally.
So let's do this first.
Change the alignment to fill.
Let's add some spacing, eight, and
I'll add some spacing to
these StackViews too.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So internally it looks better but
it doesn't look exactly the way I want.
I want all of these text fields
to have the same size and
they should be aligned.
So let's go back to your commandments
and see if we find one that matches.
Number one,
tweak the properties of the stack view.
No.
The whole thing's about text views,
text fields.
Use another stack view,
that's number two.
No, not really.
Commandment number three.
Tweak the compression resistance or
at the hugging priority.
Mm-hm.
I don't think so.
Add constraints to the stat view?
Nope.
Absolutely not.
Add constraints to the views?
Close, but no cigar.
Number six, to connect views
within different StackViews,
use commandment number five.
This is the one.
What we need to do, is to relate views,
the text fields that are Within
different stack use.
So in that case we need
to use constraints.
What you jump ahead and
a bunch of constraints,
let's think what we
are really looking for.
We want the text fields to be
aligned and have the same size.
There's another way of putting this.
A way that makes it easier for
the sec view to do it's job.
Let me show you.
Editor.
Show layout rectangles.
What I really want.
If the labels should have the same size,
the size of the biggest one, this one.
The remaining space will
be given to the text field.
This is much better.
So lets go for it.
Press Ctrl drag and
move here equal width.
And now same thing.
Ctrl drag equal width.
This is what we want.
So the objective of this case study
is to practice connecting views
within different StackViews and
also understanding
that there's more than one way
of doing things in auto layout.
Always strive for
the one that requires less constraints.