Time for aside number two.
This one's kind of cool, actually.
It's more about cross products.
So you might remember, there's a simple formula for
how you can get, a cross product.
You basically do IJK, and then you do a1,
b1, c1, you, you do your first vector, second vector,
and then you do essentially the determinant, and that gave you the vector.
Remember that? Remember that?
Remember that?
Okay. Maybe you don't remember that.
That was the formula for cross product.
If you had been really smart,
you would say, you know, I can just write this as a matrix multiplication, okay.
So I just build this little matrix here from my a.
Okay, and I take my vector b here, and so
that says that the first component of c is going to be what?
Well, it's going to be minus a3 b2 plus a2 b3,
and that is the first component of the cross product of a and b.
Same thing for the second component and the third component.
So we can just write cross product as matrix multiplication.
So I'm going to define a little operator, and
this little operator is written here.
This x, that means cross product okay?
So when I do this little bracket a x cross, that means that I'm going to
substitute in this matrix, which is sort of the cross product in matrix of a.
So if I want to do a cross b I would just multiply this matrix times b.
So the notation as I wrote here is a cross b equals and just this bracket and,
and here the font's fixed.
It's just this bracket a x times b.
Something that we're going to make use of, not this lecture but
next lecture is and I'll, I'll leave, you know I love it,
I used to love it when professors said this, the proof is left to the reader.
Okay, but you can actually do this.
Figure out what the rank of this matrix is, and if you come out with
any number other than 2, try again, because the rank of this matrix is 2, okay.
So it's a three by three matrix, but the rank of the matrix is 2.
Now we're going to make use of that later, because as you may remember,
if you multiply matrices together, ranks can only get smaller.
I multiply a rank 2 matrix by some other matrix, I've got a rank 2 situation.