Consider the conventional matrix,
matrix multiply algorithm.
Suppose you compute it block by block.
That is let's conceptually divide A,
B and C into a little b by b blocks.
An algorithm might then look like this.
The algorithm iterates over blocks of C.
It then reads blocks of A and B.
Given the blocks, it multiplies them.
Finally it stores the block.
All these reads and writes of blocks are
basically slow fast memory transfers.
I want you to count them up.
After doing so, you should be able to
tell me the asymptotic intensity of this
blocked matrix matrix
multiply algorithm.
Before you start,
let's make some simplifying assumptions.
First, let's assume L=1.
Next, assume that b | n.
You can also assume that n | Z.
Lastly, since you need the blocks of A,
B, and
C to fit into fast memory
in order to multiply them,
let's also assume that the fast memory
size is 3 b squared plus a little.
Express your answer in terms of n,
little b, or z here.