[BLANK_AUDIO]
Live stream is starting soon.
It's starting soon, it's about to start.
It's about to go down.
Live stream is about to go down.
In fact it's probably
already going down.
There I am.
Hello world, it's Raj.
Good to see you guys.
ML Squad is in the building.
Let me shout out some names.
Egor, Glorious, Patchy, Mick,
Rodge, Chudumshu, Brandon.
Yo!
We got the whole machine running
squad in the house right now.
Who is ready to learn some TensorFlow.
I'm so excited for TensorFlow.
Asude, Gora, Spencer.
All right, all right,
all right, okay cool.
Hi everybody, hi, hi, hi, hi.
Okay, so let's get down to
business as they say in Mulan,
let's get down to business.
[SOUND] And
defeat [SOUND] the loss function.
Okay, so anyway, let's start
off with a five minute Q and A.
So hit me up with your most intense
machine learning questions, or
you just want to know anything.
I'm just, We'll go for it.
And then we're going to use TensorFlow
to classify housing prices.
Okay.
It's going to be dope.
It's going to be the first
time using TensorFlow from
scratch in a live session.
It's going to be awesome,
Okay, so here we go.
Hi, hi, hi, hi, let's begin.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I'm doing good, I'm doing good.
I'm so down, I do have a sore throat,
but I'm a human, I know, it's crazy,
but it's cool, it's cool.
What kind of method approach do
you use to manage your time?
Nick, great question.
So what do I use to manage my time?
I write down what I'm going to do for
the whole week, before the week starts.
So every Sunday I'll write
down the weekly goals.
So I have a weekly to-do, I have
a daily to-do, I have a monthly to-do,
I have a yearly to-do, and
then I have a five year to-do.
So I plan things out in
intervals like that.
I make sure that my goals
are accomplishable goals so
that I get that positive feed back so
I can get going.
Is google release its own OS?
Chrome OS yes.
Are there any recommended
books on computer science or
chritogrophy Yeah,
cryptography is so dope.
I wish I could just deep
dive into cryptography.
That is like some ancient Egyptian,
pharaoh, mummy,
you know what I'm saying,
like you have to.
A good book on cryptography is my book,
Decentralized Applications,
the best selling software
engineering book on Amazon for 2016.
And a good book for
machine learning is Machine Learning,
A Probabilistic Approach I
forgot the name.
But that's the name of it.
What do you think of Star Wars?
I love Star Wars.
I'm actually not like...
I love the old ones.
The new ones, like, I was kind of
disappointed by episode seven, so
it's like, whatever, it's kind of
conservative on Disney's part.
We have to make our own stories,
guys, we are a new generation.
We're going to make our own stories and
they're going to be as good,
if not better than Star Wars.
And we're going to have machine
learning, it's going to be dope.
When we make stories it's going to
be technically art accurate.
What if there are more [INAUDIBLE].
Great question.
So, it's like a 3D Graph with the value,
right?
We want to, remember what I talked about
last lecture, we want to drop a ball
into a bowl and see where it fits,
but what if we have multiple values?
Well then that's where a second order
optimization function comes in.
We have to find the local
minima that is closest to,
that is going to best
optimize our function.
We're going to talk about that later,
but the key words to remember is
a second order optimization function.
Tensor calculus,
that's exactly what we're going to do.
Not at a low level, but at a high level,
because TensorFlow is going to
do a little bit of magic for us.
Can you explain math behind TensorFlow?
I will absolutely explain
the math behind TensorFlow.
TensorFlow is better than
Torch exactly Hey Sraj,
are more layers always
better in a neural network?
Great question, Tamar.
No.M Not always, not always.
Usually it is.
So if you have a smaller data set,
you don't really need that many layers.
So remember, with machine learning,
there's always a tradeoff.
There's always a tradeoff.
Any engineering in general,
there's always In life,
there's a tradeoff as well.
But we want to, when we optimize for.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So when we increase the layers,
we increase the computational complexity
but we also increase the accuracy.
So there's a tradeoff.
How should I prepare for Google Brain
residency program interview?
Kaggle challenges are great.
And the tension flow intradocs.
Watch all my videos but
you probably already have.
If you do all that, if you apply
the code, you'll be good to go.
Essential.
Can you give new research idea
that can implement a tension flow?
Yeah, so here's an idea I've had for
a while.
Somebody should roll with this.
Take the synthetic radiance paper from.
Synthetic radiance.
So they stopped using that
propagation just for this paper.
And then take the idea
of one shot learning,
so probabilistic programming, and
then combine these two ideas together.
So, synthetic radiance and
one shot learning.
Boom, there's your landmark paper for
the year.
I don't have time to do it, so
someone just roll with that.
Is usable in Raspberry Pi?
Yeah, actually.
Somebody made a rap for our team now.
So two more questions and
then we're going to get started.
How did genetic algorithms
fit into machine running?
Genetic algorithms are good for
optimizing hyper parameters for us.
And let me talk about that for a second.
I've got some emails from some people
who are like, and also articles from
people who are like uneasy about this
where Google are using machinery.
Google's using machine running
to optimize machine running.
So what do we do?
Guys.
Machine running is not going
to take your jobs away.
Okay.
We will be.
Even if there's a job apocalypse,
machine running engineers will
be the last People to have jobs.
Not that that's going to happen,
we're going to create new
jobs in the big data economy.
And we're going to have basic income and
things like that.
Hopefully and crypt currency,
check out my post social point,
it's already possible,
and also Grant's point.
But Don't worry about
Machine Learning replacing
your job as a Machine Learning engineer.
If that actually happens, that we solve
intelligence and then there's no?
The idea of jobs and money and
scarcity all goes away anyway, okay?
So, let's just go ahead and get started.
The best way to start deep
warning is to start my course,
which is this course, okay?
Okay.
[COUGH] So that's the [INAUDIBLE],
here's what we're going to do.
We are going to use to
classify housing prices.
Okay so that's what we're going to do
and I'm going to use a notebook for
a while.
So let me go ahead and
start screen sharing immediately and
we'll get right on into this.
Here we go.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay.
So, let me move this chat window over
here so I can still see you guys.
I don't need to see myself though.
I just need to see you guys.
And then I'll also have,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
up so I can see myself.
All right, new movie recording.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
All right, and then that goes away and
I'm right here Okay.
Minimize myself.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Yeah, the one is kind of blurred.
I'm going to get a better one.
Okay, so here's what we're
going to do guys, okay?
So we have a housing data sets.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
One was the name, was the other thing.
Okay, so that someone knew that.
So and
just in general one shot learning.
So we need more one
shot learning progress,
because not everybody has huge data
sets and huge computing power.
I'm going to explain things
slowly this time, okay?
Thanks Alexander, much love.
So, I'm going to explain
things slowly this time, okay?
I want to start off by talking
about a neural network.
It's a lot.
Okay, we see this image a lot
of a neural network, right?
But the one thing I want to say
is you see all these circles?
We call them neurons.
They're not actually objects,
they're not classes.
These are just
representations of numbers.
Let me zoom in a little bit.
They just represent numbers, okay?
Because when we input data
into a neural network,
flow we call it a computation graph
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And these are not actually like neural,
they're not class objects.
When we take an input,
let's say like what we're going to do,
housing prices and
when we apply some matrix math to it,
it's going to take that value and
it's going to do.
So if it's a one value and we multiply
by a matrix of say, three values,
it's going to then become three or
four values.
Those values are what we represent as
neurons, they're not actually objects.
Then we take those values and apply
a set of matrix operations to them and
then, boom,
it's the next set of neurons.
But these neurons are not actually
classes, they are values.
Okay, so I just want to start
off with that, so that's that.
Now let me show you guys the data first.
So here's the data set.
Let me zoom in on this.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay, so
this is a set of housing prices, okay?
So the first one is the index, which is
the number, then next one is the area,
which is the size of the house,
the next one is the number of bathrooms,
then the price, and
then the price per square inch.
So, that's what that is.
What we want to do is we
want to classify this,
but we don't have labels right now.
We're going to add labels.
We're going to add labels where it's
going to be either a good buy or
bad buy, because what we want to
do is given one of these features
we're going to decide
which features to use.
But given one of these features,
we want to then classify the house as
either a good buy or a bad buy, okay?
So let me shut down my screen for
a second so
the bit rate goes up a little bit.
I want it to be not that laggy.
So that's what we're going to do,
okay, so that's our data.
So let's go ahead and
start doing this in a Jupyter notebook.
Okay, so I'm going to do
it in a Jupyter notebook.
All right, so
the first thing I want to do
is talk a little bit about, let me
just make sure that this works first.
Yo, let's see.
Yo.
Okay, it works, great.
Okay, so TensorFlow, why are we
using TensorFlow in the first place?
So, let me make the font bigger.
Actually, let me see.
We're using TensorFlow because
Google created it for,
this is going to be a supervise problem,
okay?
Yeah, it's price per square foot.
This is a supervised problem,
we're using TensorFlow because
TensorFlow is created by Google and
it was built to scale.
They've used it for many years.
They released it, it was kind of like
Zeus coming down from Olympus and
giving fire to the humans, right?
We know that TensorFlow can scale,
we know that it's reliable because
it's used in production by Google.
I mean,
Google search uses TensorFlow, okay?
So this is a reliable library.
Although, High Porch is pretty cool too.
It just came out this month, and
it introduces the concept of
dynamic computation graphs.
Usually, we have two interpreters,
right?
We have a python interpreter, and then
we have computation graph interpreter.
But what High Porch does is it has
one interpreter for everything.
Okay so Jupyter Notebook is
really is a great concept.
Basically, it allows us to view our
code and add mark down to our code.
It lets us add a bunch of
pretty things to our code.
Yes, Prometheus is the right
answer that I was looking for.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and
start by importing our dependencies.
Okay so,
we want to classify our problem.
And also let me show you guys
what our URL net looks like.
I didn't show you guys what
this is going to look like.
So this what it's going to look like.
Okay, so
we're going to feed in two inputs.
And we're going to apply
a set of weights and biases,
use the softmax function,
and then output the housing
price as well as the label,
which is good or bad.
Okay, so
we'll talk about that in a second.
Let's go ahead and
first import our dependencies.
All right, so
yes I'm focused on the content.
Thank you.
Hole watch.
Here we go.
Import pandas as pd.
Pandas is our beautiful library
to work with data s tables.
Work with data s tables.
That's our first library, okay?
So the next one is numpy.
Numpy is going to help
us use number matrices.
Both pandas and numpy need it,
so use number matrices, okay.
The next thing is natplot library
because we're going to show this graph.
We're going to show this
graph in this section.
And,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
What else?
We want natplotlib's pyplot as plt.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I prefer TensorFlow.
Pyplot to and finally tensorflow as tf.
Okay.
That's it.
Those are our four libraries.
Now we can go ahead and compile it.
Boom.
So because there are no errors,
we can keep going, right?
So that's the great thing about
jupyter/ipython notebooks is that
they let you compile as you go so
you can see what is happening.
Okay so that's what we did there.
Now we're going to load the data.
That was, Step 1 is to load data.
Load data, okay.
So let's go ahead and load data.
How are we going to load data?
Well we are going to use the pandas
library to help us do that.
So the first thing we're going to do is
we're going to use the pandas read csv
function because we have a csv file,
okay?
So we're going to read this
in as a dataframe object.
So what is a dataframe object?
A dataframe object is an object
in memory that pandas
creates from the csv file that
we can then easily parse, and
I'm going to show you what
I mean by easily parse.
So we're going to take this dataframe
variables, that we just created, and
we're going to list what we're going to
remove the columns we don't care about.
So how do we know which columns
we don't care about, right?
So let's go back to our data for
a second.
We have several columns here.
Which are the ones that we want to use
to predict if a house is good or bad?
Well, what we're going to do, we're
going to take out the index because
that's not going to
really give us anything.
It's just a numbering
of what each column is.
The next one is the,
let's say area and bathrooms, right?
So those are the two features that, like
We're going to use area and bathroom.
We're not going to use the price or
the sq_price.
Because when I look for a house,
I want to make sure that it has, and
that's just what I'm using, right?
Deciding which features to use is
its own discipline in and of itself.
What feature should we use?
And a good rule of thumb to go by, is
what feature would you personally
use to make a prediction, okay?
Now let me give you guys this data,
how I got this data.
I could create a gist.
So in a gist, I'll say,
let's just take all this.
I'm going to give you guys
this data real quick and
then I'll paste it into the chat so
you guys can see it.
So data.txt,
that will create a public gist, boom.
And I'll paste it into the chat, ready?
Get ready for this guys,
I'm going to paste it in.
Boom, there's your data.
That's the data file, all right?
So now you guys can do that along with.
All right, so, we are going to remove
the features we don't care about.
Okay, we're going to remove
We don't care about the price, we're
not going to care about the sq_price.
We only care about the number bathrooms
and what was the second thing?
The area, that's what we're
going to be using right now.
And axis is 1 because we're
only going to use the first
axis from the data sets.
All right, so dataframe.drop,
let me say what we just did here.
We removed the features
we don't care about.
So we removed the features
Now we're going to only use the first
ten rows of the data set in this
example.
So we only want to use the first
ten of these, right up to here.
Right up to here, okay?
No Oxford, I don't want to define that.
Okay, so how do we say that?
Well, easily enough,
the great thing about a dataframe
object is we can say,
I want from row 0 to row 10, boom.
So that's going to tell us that
we only use the first ten rows.
That's it, okay?
That's it, and so
now we have our dataframe object.
So let's go ahead and print this.
And here's a great thing about Python
notebooks, is we can now print this and
see what we have.
And it'll give us an error
if it doesn't work.
Okay, so there we go, invalid syntax.
So let's see what I did here.
So, on this line, dataframe.drop,
it's pointing to this axis = 1.
And the problem here is invalid syntax,
so we have index, sq_price, yes.
So, okay, so
this bracket actually goes here.
That's where the bracket goes.
Now let's compile.
Okay, so there we go.
There is our beautiful,
clean, formatted data.
And we're only using
the first ten columns, and
we're just using the area and
bathrooms as our features.
And remember, feature selection is
an entire discipline in and of itself.
And we could have used the square price,
and
we could have used
the price as features.
But what I'm looking for
are the area and bathrooms.
That's what I look for
when I try to predict if
a house is a good buy or
not for me, okay?
So now we have our features,
so let's introduce our labels.
So what we just did, so
step one was to load the data, and
step two is going to be
to introduce labels.
Because right now, there are no labels.
So we could just do a regression, right?
Because we could then
predict the next value.
And what do we use regression for?
For predicting the next
value in a continuous set.
So that's what we do for that.
But what we're going to do is
we're going to convert this into
a classification problem.
So add labels, so that's our step 2.
So we're going to take
a data print object, and
if anybody doesn't have the data,
go ahead and ask, and
someone's going to paste it into
the chat, the link to that gist.
All right, so what we're going to do
is we're to introduce the labels.
So we want to say, our labels are going
to be either a good buy or a bad buy.
And so how do we represent that?
Well, for simplicity's sake,
let's just use binary numbers, right?
So a good buy is a 1 and a bad buy is 0.
So let's just randomly add a set of,
for our ten values.
So we have to count ten, right?
So we want 1, 1, 1, 0 and
then we'll add some variety in there.
So let's see how many that is.
That's 3, 6, 9.
But we want, we have 1,1,0,0,1.
And then 0, and then 1.
Okay, so yeah, it's ten values.
So we're going to add our labels.
And so, 1 is good and 0 is bad.
So 1 is good buy and 0 is bad buy, okay?
So 1 is good buy and 0 is bad buy.
Now, you can't see
the first part of the code.
Let me repaste the link.
I'm going to repaste the link, boom.
Okay, [INAUDIBLE] paste the link.
Okay, so now you can't see
the first part of the code.
Let me go up.
I can't go back,
we have to keep going, okay?
So 1 is the good buy and 0 is a bad buy.
So we've defined our set of labels.
Now, the next step is to turn
TRUE/FALSE values into 1's and 0's.
So we're going to say,
that the location variable is
going to define those labels for us.
All right, so let's go ahead and
add the y2 values which will,
hold on a sec.
So Y2 and we're going to use
the dataframe( 'y1 ) == 0.
So what did we just do?
So what we just did is say
y2 is a negation of y1.
Right, so, we defined y2 as a negation,
as a y2 is a negation of y1.
It's the opposite, opposite, okay?
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Right, so axis 1 is the column, okay?
So y2 means we don't like a house.
Okay, so let's go ahead and define y2.
Okay, dataframe.loc, location.
And we're saying, okay, so
what is that value that we want?
[BLANK_AUDIO]
y2, and then we'll say, okay, so
we're going to convert it
to a int value, right?
So we want to remember that the type
we're converting to is an int.
So how do we convert it to a int value?
So we're going to take astype(int).
And so what this says is, it says turn
TRUE/FALSE values into 1s or 0's.
So turn TRUE/FALSE values
to ones and zeroes.
And now we've done that.
Now let's print out what we have here,
let's see what this looks like.
Thing about Python notebooks,
we can just print what we have here.
We definitely have a syntax error,
so there it is.
And I think Cyber
mentioned this earlier.
So we are going to add to line three.
So which one is that?
Our brackets, yes, just like that.
Okay, and so
now do we have an extra one?
Okay.
Okay, so what did we do?
So we added labels, but instead of
saying good or bad, we added two labels.
So this is just for simplicity's sake,
we don't want to convert
Text to integers.
We're just going to say a raw value.
So if y1 has a value,
that means that is a good bot.
And every time y1 has a value,
every time y1 is 1, y2 would be zero.
Every time y2 is one,
y1 would be zero, okay?
So that's just our way of of
labeling our data for now.
So we've added our labels.
That was step two, remember?
Step one was to load the data,
which we did into a data
frame object we parsed it.
And then step two was to add
the labels to the data, right.
Which makes this
a classification problem,
if we're going to classify this data.
Okay.
We're going to classify housing.
If a house is a good buy or
a bad buy based on the area and
the number of bathrooms, Okay?
Not bedrooms, right.
Well I guess the data didn't
have bedrooms, did it?
Okay, so, but yeah bedrooms would
probably be better if we have that.
So now we have all our
data in the dataframe,
we are to shape the end matrices that.
Now step three is to prepare data for
TensorFlow.
So depending on which machine
running library we're using,
we can,
we will prepare it a certain way.
But in general,
no matter what data we have we're
going to convert it into tensors.
So let me explain what tensors are.
So tensors are it's a high level,
tensors are a generic version
of vectors and matrices.
A vector is a list of numbers,
then Vector is.
We just write something.
This is important.
Because we see these worth a lot.
Is a list of numbers, then a matrix is
a list of lists of numbers, okay?
And so a vector would be a 1 D sensor,
Matrix would be a 2D tensor, and
then whatever a list of list, of list
of numbers is would be a 3D tensor.
And then that just continues, okay?
So a tensor is a very generic term for
both matrices and vectors.
And these tensors are how we
represent data in tensor flows.
And guys, machine learning,
neural networks.
It's all just matrix math.
It's a collection of operations
that we apply to some input matrix.
And we continually apply them
like a chain of these operations
until we get to an output.
And then we apply an optimization
function To minimize the loss.
And I'm going to talk
about that in a second.
We're going to do that.
But that's what this is.
So that was a little short,
the thing on tensors for a second.
But to get back to what we we're doing,
so we're going to take our data frame.
And we're going to say, Let's see.
We want to take the area and
the bathroom.
So we're going to take our features,
right, we're going to take our features
and we're going to convert
them into tensors.
We're going to convert our
features into tensors.
So, convert features to input tensor.
A simple gram.
We're going to convert our
features into a info sensor.
And this session with a few minutes or
probably an hour, we'll see.
As matrix and b.
We want to say as a matrix.
Now we're going to convert our
labels To input tensors as well.
So let me show you guys this energy gap,
okay?
All right, so see this right here.
These two purple circles, those are our
input sensors, our features and
our label.
So we're going to feed
that into a [INAUDIBLE].
We haven't created our weights yet,
If you just block out everything but
these two purple circles.
That's what we just created.
Okay.
So that's what we did for that.
Now we're going to convert our
Labels into features, okay?
So I'm sorry, our labels into tensors.
So we say out dataframe.loc.
Sometimes is probably going to happen.
So let's say, okay, so
we got location and
then we'll those labels that we created.
And then guys,
we can easily have One label as well.
Okay so, I gotta focus on this.
Let's see if this compiles.
Okay so syntax error,
what do we have here?
Right, so it's an extra bracket,
all right.
So area, bathrooms, We have location.
Okay, so this extra bracket here,
and then what else do I have here?
So for y1,
I have a bracket, I need another
bracket, and then we'll compile that.
Let's see what else we've got here.
Comma.
Aren't Jupyter Notebooks so great guys?
We can just compile as we go.
Input our location.
Y1, Y2.
What's the deal.
We're going to remove that.
We want to say, what is going on here?
We've got y1, y2 dot location,
and this is in brackets.
Boom.
Let's see.
Sh, okay,
let's see what's going on here.
Whoa, that's a lot.
None of the area bathrooms
are in the columns.
Hold on a second.
Area bathroom are in the columns.
Let's see what we did here.
So we said in dataframe.location we
converted area bathrooms as a matrix.
And then we said okay,
as_matrix, interesting, okay.
So we did have area bathrooms,
remove the closing brackets.
Remove the closing brackets on
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Or move this one and
we want to add, interesting.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Missing quotes, there it is, right
missing quotes, that's what it was.
My god, okay, yes, all right.
There we go.
Okay, you scared me for a second.
Let's print out what we had here.
So, what did we just create?
Boom.
So, what is this?
This is what our input
matrix looks like.
Okay.
So, we have the area and the bathrooms.
And this is what our
labels matrix looks like.
Let's print out our label matrix.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay.
So that's our input matrix and
that's our label matrix.
Guys, we have our inputs, now we're
going to prepare our parameters, and so
what step are we on now?
We're on step four.
So step three was to prepare
the data for tensor flow.
So we've formatted our data for
tensor flow and
now we're going to step four is
to write out our Hyperparameters.
Okay so what are our hyper parameters?
So the first one is going
to be our learning rate.
And so
when did we last see our learning rates?
We used the learning rates when we,
in the last live session
we summed that up we.
The learning rate controls
the rate at which we learn.
I know that's kind of.
So what's a better explanation?
The learning rate defines How fast we
reach convergence, to be technical.
Convergence is when our
model is at its optimal fit,
when we have that optimal fit
where the error is minimized.
And the learning rate defines
how fast we get to convergence.
We can't just say, can't just say,
make the learning rate a million and
just get there as fast as possible.
Because if you go too high,
then your model's not going to converge.
But if you go too low,
it's going to be too slow.
So remember, like all things,
it is a tradeoff.
That is the word of the day.
Machine learning is
a series of tradeoffs.
And epochs have tradeoffs as well.
Okay, so
the next thing is the training epoch.
We're going to train
this thing 2,000 times.
And why 2,000?
I don't know,
I mean we could try 10,000 in a second.
I don't know, you know what I'm saying?
And that's what we do.
We train for a number of epochs,
we see our results, and then we say,
well, is this prediction accurate or
not?
And then, if not, then we'll change,
we'll tune our hyper
parameter to this step again.
Okay, so then,
the number of display steps.
So how often do we want
to display the process
of trading and the number of samples?
Which is going to be the size
of number label which is 10.
Okay?
So those were our hyper parameters.
And now guys, we are ready to
compile and make sure that runs,
is to create our computation bracket.
So, a bit on computation.
Create our computation
graph/neural network, okay?
So computation graph,
neural network, are the same thing.
But before we get started, we do one
quick review, of what we've done so far.
We imported our dependencies, then we
loaded our data which is CSV file.
The data contained a bunch of features,
but we only wanted to use the area and
the bathrooms as our features.
We removed everything else.
Using those two things we're going to
predict if a housing price is good or
not.
But guess what?
There are no labels in our data,
so what did we do?
We added labels, because data frame
objects are really easy to parse,
add data from, remove data from,
and so we added labels.
Y1 is, when Y1 has a value 1,
it means it's a good buy.
When Y2 has good value that
is when it's not a good buy.
Then we prepare our data for
tensor flow.
How do we do that?
We look at our data print object and
we converted our features
into an input tensor.
And then we convert our labels
into input tensor as well.
We printed them out,
we defined our hyper parameters, and
now we're going to do, we're going to
write out our computation graph, okay?
So, let's go ahead and
write out our computation graph.
So let's go ahead and do this.
So the first thing I'm going to do is,
I'm going to create a placeholder for
our feature input tensor that
we just defined, input x.
And what this is doing is, so,
for our feature input tensors.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So the tensor flow will feed
it an array of examples.
Each example will be an array
of two flow values, area and
number of bathrooms.
And so
none means any number of examples,
which is usually the backsides.
So we're just going to say none,
so it's just generic.
We're going to say however many we want.
We allocated that number beforehand.
And this allows us to have
any number of examples.
And 32 because that's the size
of this input tensor.
Okay, so, I'm sorry, not 32, 2.
My mistake.
So, two because we have two features,
okay?
And it's a 2D matrix, right,
because we have two features.
So we've done that, and so the next
step is to now create our weights.
So create weight.
And so another thing,
placeholder objects are gateways.
So placeholders in tensor
flow are gateways for data.
It's how we feed data into
our computation graph.
Our gateway for
data into our computation graph.
All right, so
the next step is create weights.
So how are we going to
create our weights?
So we're going to define
our weights as W.
And we're going to say tf.variable, and
so it means- let me just write this out.
So we'll define our weights, and
it's going to start off as a set
of zeroes, because we haven't, and
that's how you should start off your
weights for a simple example like this.
Although it's transfer learning,
your weights aren't zero.
They've been trained beforehand.
So this is a 2x2 float matrix,
2x2 float matrix.
And we're going to keep updating that.
That will keep updating
through the training process.
That's what we're going to do.
Okay, why do we use a variable?
Well in tensor flow a variable is,
variables hold and update parameters.
So variables in tf hold and
update parameters.
And we have weights or
any other things we want to.
So they're basically in memory
buffers containing tensors,
okay, to be a little
more technical about it.
But these are our weights.
Okay, so
the next step is to add our biases.
So we're going to add our biases.
So, add biases.
And so, we want two biases, right?
Because we have two inputs.
We want two biases because
we have two inputs.
And this is also going
to be a tf variable.
And this is a 2x2 float matrix.
Okay, I already typed that out.
And, we're going to close the bracket
here and add a closing parentheses.
Okay, so let's see what this,
actually we're going to do one.
So let me show you guys what we have so
far.
So now what we've done is we've
created our input tensor.
We have, actually,
it uses the little square thing.
And we've created our weights.
And now we're going to add our biases.
This is what we're about to do.
So we're going to add these other
purple square looking dots.
So yes,
we're going to use back propagation
to update our weights in a second.
But first we have to define our biases.
And why do we use biases?
Well, biases are going to
help our model fit better.
So a good example is,
b in the y = mx + b equation.
B is the bias, like that.
So, right?
So, because b takes that line, and
it adds the y-intercept,
which makes it fit better.
So that's what biases do.
They're a part of a larger goal.
It's like if you didn't
have b in the y = mx +b,
the line wouldn't be the red line
that you're looking for, right?
So okay, and I'll go over everything
we've done at the end guys.
So right now we've added our biases.
And so the next step is to calculate.
We're going to perform
some matrix tasks.
So now we're going to multiply
our weights by our inputs.
So this is our first calculation
that's happening here, right?
Because weights are what we multiply,
weights are how we govern how
data flows in our compute.
Weights are how we govern how data
flows in our computation graph, okay?
Okay, so let's go ahead and
perform this.
We'll say,
we'll define this as y values.
And we'll say, and yes, we can
initialize weights as random as well.
And depending on what you're doing,
it can be different,
but right now we're
initializing them as zeroes.
And to perform this actual
matrix multiplication step,
the tensor flow has this great built-in
matrix multiplication function.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
That we can say, okay, so take our
[INAUDIBLE] and then our weights, and
then our biases and
what are we going to do here?
We're going to calculate the prediction
and to do that, we're going to multiply
the input matrix by the weight
matrix and then add the biases.
So let me write that out.
Multiply inputs by weights and
add biases, okay?
So, it's kind of like y = mx + b.
So similar, kind of operations.
Okay, so we've gone back, and now we're
going to do our softmax function,
which is our sigmoid.
Softmax is another word for sigmoid.
So we've done this part, right?
And now we're going to do this part,
which is we're going to take those
values, and
we're going to tie a softmax to it.
And what does softmax do?
Does anyone remember?
Shout it out in the comments and
I'm going to explain it in a second.
I'm going to type it out, and
If someone can shout that out
I will give you a shout out.
Tell me what the softmax function does?
We're going to say, softmax,
apply softmax to this value
that we created, right?
We going to apply our
softmax to the value input.
Apply,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Softmax to value we just created, okay?
It's an activation function.
So it's is our activation function.
And it does some things, shoot.
Okay, so let me go ahead and,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Yes, it normalizes our values.
So what softmax does is
it normalizes our value.
And what do I mean by that?
It takes our value and
it converts to a probability,
that we can then feed to our output.
So it's the last step before
we feed to our output.
So let me make sure that I have
typed all this ish out perfectly.
So on line 14, tf.Variable.zeros.
I said tf.Variable.zeros.
I need a bracket here, okay.
tf.zeros, be laser focused
on what I've done here.
Sp,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Let's see.
Interesting, so
there is an extra value here.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Let's see what's going down here?
tf.variable, tf.zeros.
Extra dot, okay.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay, so now the next step is to say-
It's good, you know what it is.
It's all good.
Okay, so I need to add a bracket there,
I think.
Right, yeah, so adding one there,
and once you add one here, and
then we're going to say compile.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And so then for the Y values,
it's telling me what I've done wrong.
So it's saying, hey,
Serraj, listen, buddy.
Listen, you need to apply your matrix
multiply, x w v tf.add, okay.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
What else we got here?
y values,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And let's see, maybe x is not defined.
x is not defined?
Because I didn't define it, yes.
So x is that value, okay?
Great, great.
And I hit Enter, so I need to
go ahead and add one more thing.
Okay, so what did we just do?
We added- the code is
going to go online, yes,
I'm going to post it in
the comments when I'm done.
We've got 15 minutes.
Okay, so what we're going to
do is we're going to say,
we've got that softmax value and
then we can get to our outputs.
So let me type that out.
So what are we doing here?
We're going to feed, so
we never did this part, so
we're going to say feed
in a matrix of labels.
So let me go over what
I've just done here.
Okay so,
these are our two placeholders right?
So x is up here and
y is down here, right?
So, one is our labels, and
then one is our set of features.
We created our weights,
we created our biases, and
this is our computation
stuff right here.
We multiplied our weights by our inputs,
and then we added our biases, and then
we used that value that we calculated
and we input it into an softmax player.
Which converted it into
a set of probabilities.
Okay, so there's that.
And now we're going to apply,
we're going to perform our training set,
perform training.
So we've done these steps.
And now step six is to perform training.
Step six is to perform training.
So let's go ahead and, so
this is the magic part flow.
So if you were here in the live section
last week, then we did this manually.
So let me just write out
what we're about to do.
What we're going to do is
create our cost function,
and the cost function we're going to
be using is the mean squared error.
All right, so
we did this last lab section.
One of the great things about
quartz is that we have continuity.
And so we can say, we can say minus y.
So this is going to be the equation.
Now I'm going to show
the equation in a second,
but what this does is it says,
we want to calculate the error.
So between our two y values, and we're
going to divide by the number of- So
the mean squared error is going to take
the average of the difference in values,
which is our error,
the square difference, and
that's what this is doing.
So reduce sum basically
computes the element,
the sum of elements across the matrix.
So let me write that out.
Reduce sum, computes the sum of elements
across dimensions of a tensor.
And so then, let me show the equation
for the ten seconds, but we missed it.
And so the two different
values we're using are the,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The two different values we are using
are the predictive values and
then the actual values for the outputs.
That is our cost function, we want to
minimize this cost function over time
and to do that we're going
to perform gradiant descent.
So, we're not, and
the great thing about textual flow,
we can just define gradient descent
as our optimization function.
We don't have to actually
write out every step.
And in gradient descent every
step means we're computing
the partial derivative,
with respect to our input variables,
which in our case would be the set
of weights and the y biases.
So, that's it.
We can just say,
we have a cost function.
We want to minimize that
cost using gradient descent,
and our learning rate will define
how fast we want to do that, okay.
So, do not call me
during a live session.
Okay, so let's see what we've got here.
We're going to say y is here, right?
And this should be y underscore,
so that's why that didn't work.
And so the next thing is you want to
make sure that Name wide is not defined.
How about now?
No, it is defined,
because I just updated it.
There we go.
Great.
I updated the white and
now we're going to create our section.
Let's initialize our section.
This is still part of the training.
We're going to initialize our
variables and tensorflow section.
So in ternsorflow we encapsulate
our computation graph.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We should re-encapsulate
our competition graph using
initialize_all_variables, using
a session object.
So in tensorflow, whenever you
want to do any kind of training,
you have to first initialize
all the variables.
And what initialize_all_variables does,
it just it does exactly what it says,
initializes every variable
you've declared beforehand.
That means those "tf dot" variables
we declared beforehand and
the placeholder objects
we did beforehand.
So every tensorflow,
generic variable that we
defined beforehand is initialized for
this section.
So this could be done under
the hood as well, but for
now we are going to have to define.
So we created our extension our
session and we just rerun it by
using the other variables that
we've initialized as our input.
Okay, and of course there's a so
no attributions of our variable.
So what was that?
So initialize all variables with a set
of parentheses, and then tf.Session.
Let's see what else we've got here,
tf.initialize.
I misspelled initialize, okay.
Initialize, great.
Okay, so here we go.
Let's do this.
This is the last bit
that we're going to do.
This is the actual training loop.
This is the training loop.
Okay, so let's go ahead and do this.
For every number, every epoch that
we have, for training epochs,
how many people do we have
in this live session?
300 people going, awesome.
So for every training epoch,
we're going to find this 300,
what was the number?
2,000?
We define as 2,000.
We're going to run our session given our
optimizer which is gradient descent.
So this is where we're
performing gradient descent.
And we're going to feed in.
This is were we actually feed into
the placeholders where we find earlier.
The first is going to be that x value
which is going to be our features.
R for x.
And the next is going to be for
thelabels,
which is going to be our r equal y.
So does that, and so that's it,
and so now that's it really, and
we can just write out
our debugging method.
Which is going to be write
out logs of training.
If I display_step = 0, and
then let's say, let's run this session,
given our cost function and
then we're going to.
And we actually already just did this,
but we're doing this so
we can print it out, just so
we can see what's
happening at each step.
Okay, so our input is going
to be that first tensor.
And our other input is going to be
that other tensor that we defined.
So then training stat.
It's going to be, now.
So, this part, I'm just going to,
it's this part right here.
Because we don't actually.
It's just logs.
That's it really.
So what we're doing is,
we're printing out the training stat.
And let me just go ahead and
run this now.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay, so
our first syntax error is going to be x.
It doesn't need that.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I do, what else we got here?
X, input x, y,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
feed_dict equals session.run feed_dict
equals, yo, okay, yes, okay.
Okay, awesome!
So, boom!
That's how fast it trains,
because it was only ten values.
Okay, it was only ten values.
And so what is happening here,
let's look at this.
The first column is our set
of training steps, right?
And the next one is our cost function,
and
the cost function is
minimized over time.
Okay, and
then eventually it's finished training.
So what is, so it ends up with a cost
function of .109 whatever, right?
So is this good or bad?
I don't really know, but it's better
than the first cost value, that's for
sure.
We don't know if it's a good cost
function or not because we kind of
arbitrarily defined what
those labels were ourselves.
So let's go ahead and test this out.
And how are we going to test it?
[SOUND] I have a cough, slash sore
throat and I'm also really sick.
Which is like,
I don't have time for that crap,
I'm teaching this dope ass court.
So we're going to feed in our input.
And we're going to test it now.
We're going to see what happens now.
So this is our output.
So what is it here?
So this is the prediction, right?
So we train our model and
now we're going to do our prediction.
And so it's guessing that
they're all good houses,
because these values are all above.
So remember I said we have y1 and y0?
So it's saying,
let me go back up for a second, so
you guys can see what
I'm talking about here.
So we defined, remember this y1 and y2?
That's what it's outputting as,
just the y1 and the y2.
It's saying these values rounded
are closest to one on the left side.
So that means it's all one.
And the values on the right
are all closest to zero.
Which means it's zero.
So what it's saying is it's saying,
all houses are a good buy.
But that's not the case.
So it's got seven out of ten correct.
But the actual thing is,
they weren't all good just
some of them were good, right?
So only three,
only some of them were good.
So seven out of ten
correct which is not bad.
How to improve?
Maybe we can add a hidden layer.
Add a hidden layer.
That's what I would do I
would add a hidden layer and
then I would try it again.
So that's my example for this, okay?
So let's go back to screen sharing,
okay?
Stop screen sharing.
Go back to me.
Hi, okay so that's what we did for that.
I'm going to add the code
to the GitHub link.
Five minute ending to an A,
then we're good to go.
Then I have a video for
you guys coming out for
you Friday which I'm
super excited about.
Hit me up with your questions, let's go.
Anything.
Why are you using Jupiter,
any special perks?
Jupiter because it allows you to compile
and see what you're doing in real time.
It's great for visually looking at,
especially for
data, it's great for
visually looking at what you're doing.
Exactly what Jake said.
How do you choose the number
of hidden layers or
not, of unites while trying
to develop a neural network?
It depends on how big your data is.
The more data you have,
generally the more hidden layers.
The more data you have the better it
is to add more hidden layers, Right?
Pieforce vs tensorflow for newcomer?
Absolutely tensorflow don't even trip,
but Pieforce has some great
architectural ideas that I think we can,
we'll see where that goes.
It's a really exciting space, guys.
It's only January, and we're already
seeing so much innovation in this field.
In fact, this pace of innovation is
accelerating itself, it's insane.
How many layers should we add?
For this case, I just mentioned that.
Can you say something about Google's
deep mind machine learning?
Well I mean they haven't
done anything this year yet.
Give them about two weeks I
expect to see some state of
the art something in
paper in like two weeks.
How to classify an image data set?
We are going to do that in
two episodes for this course.
High level.
A label data set a supervise
approach with labels,
I would look at Google's inception.
You don't even have
to train it yourself,
they've already trained
it on a million images.
And you can use transfer
learning to apply that, and
then add in whatever other
images you want to classify.
And because of transfer learning,
you don't need a backdated dataset to
train it, and I have video on that
called, build a TensorFlow Image
Classifier in five minutes.
How much coffee did you have?
I had a cup.
It is the same one as the one we
were doing with audacity, yes.
Anybody who is ever current on that
plan yes it's coming out in three days.
Do you think that will prepare me for
a deep learning job?
Yes.
What event, if you do the assignments.
Okay, that doesn't, copy that.
You have to do the assignment.
You can't just watch the video.
You have to do it.
Do it.
Like Shilo LeBuff.
I'm a huge Shilo LeBuff fan,
by the way guys.
Recently.
Because he does art for the sake of art.
Did you age?
I'm 25.
Did you study at university?
Yes.
What?
Computer Science.
Specifically robotics.
Anything on memory networks.
Yo, I want to do memory networks,
that's some advanced shit,
that's like generative
adversarial network,
shit that I find super interesting
at the bleeding edge of the field.
But we've gotta get our basics down.
If you should take something out
of this [INAUDIBLE] session,
what you should take out is,
are three things,
One, how to do gradient descent and
that propagation.
Two, a basic, an idea of what the main
variables are with tension flow.
That means place holders, tf variables,
the optimizer function, weights and
biases.
because everything's
going to build off of that.
If you get those simple things then
everything else is going to be much,
much easier.
The first thing is a softmax function.
Sorry, activation function.
An activation function is what we use
to convert numbers to probabilities.
There are several types
of activation functions.
In this case we use softmax.
Which university?
Columbia University.
But guys, I want to end this
with one piece of advice, and
then, we are good to go.
A lot of what we learn,
is, what we tell our selves we are
capable of doing, that what degrees are.
Degrees tells us,
they allow us to tell ourselves, hey,
I now know this, I can do it.
Well we have to inflict
that way of thinking.
It's not about, I have a degree,
now I'm a computer scientist.
I have a degree, now I can do X.
No, if you study something and
you do it, if you create the code and
it compiles and it runs and
gets you help with what you wanted,
you would now have
the ability to do that.
So don't be restricted by the dogma of,
I need to read this or
I need to this to get to this.
Think of something you want to build,
start building, and
along the way learn what
you need to to build it.
By the end you are going
to get really good.
Because if you've ever engineered
anything before then you know that
if anybody asks you a problem about it,
you will know every answer, why?
Because you had to deep dive into
it to be able to build that, okay.
So that's it.
All right, so
believe in yourself, basically.
Believe in yourselves,
the world needs you guys, okay?
We need you,
we are starting a revolution okay,
we are in the midst of a revolution
unlike anything the world has ever
seen before and we're going to
do some awesome shit, okay?
We're going to do some awesome shit,
okay.
That's it.
Thanks guys for watching.
The video is coming out on Friday.
It's going to be dope.
Continue the conversation
on site channel.
For now I'm going to do
the math tutorial in a second.
Okay.
For now I've gotta work
with Udacity on something,
I want to go down to Udacity and just
hang with them and see what we can do.
There's some really cool people.
For now, that's what I got to do,
so thanks for watching.
Love you guys.
[BLANK_AUDIO]