Now, how do we do Q Learning?
Well, we start off with this table of Q values--
and notice that there's more entries in this
table than there were in the utility table.
So for each state, I've divided it up
into different actions--so here's the action of going north, south, east or west
from this particular state.
They all start out with utility--
or rather Q utility, at zero.
But as we go, we start to update,
and we have an update formula that's very
similar to the formula for TD learning.
It has the same learning rate, Alpha,
and the same discount factor, Gamma;
and we just start applying that.
So we start tracking through the state space,
and when we get a transition--say we go
east from here,
and then east and then north and then north;
and then east--
and then we would back up this value;
and depending on what the values of Alpha and Gamma were,
we might update this to .6 or something;
and then the next time through,
we might update that to .7, and update this one to .4, and so on.
In each case, we'd be updating
only the action we took,
associated with that state, not the whole state.
We'd keep repeating that process until we had values filled in for all the action state pairs.