Learning a programming language is
a bit like learning a spoken language,
at least at first.
Take a look at this paragraph.
It's made up of multiple sentences,
which are,
in turn, made up of words and
punctuation marks.
We can reuse these elements in different
combinations to change the meanings of
these sentences.
Code isn't all that different.
All these symbols might seem like random
patterns that don't amount to much
right now, but that's just because
you haven't learned the words,
parts of speech, and
punctuation marks of this new language.
Let's take a look at some
of the basic elements that
make up a line of code in Ruby.