In the first lesson of this course I
will discuss some of the basic concepts
of web security.
Including the difference between
authentication and authorization, and
some of the related security
concerns that they address.
You will also learn the necessary
flow of information for all security.
And play with some of
Google's OAuth features
in the Google OAuth2 playground.
[SOUND] In lesson two we will go more in
depth on the different types of OAuth2
options for clients and servers,
implement logins and logouts, and
secure our menu pages for authenticated
users using Google Plus sign-in.
[SOUND].
In the third lesson you will
create a local permission system.
Protecting the data of each user
from being modified by other users.
[SOUND] And in lesson four, we will
explore other oauth2 providers such as
Facebook and GitHub to allow multiple
sign in options for our users.
[SOUND] [NOISE] To better understand
what you will be learning,
I would like to point out a few
similar topics that will be outside
the scope of this course.
Cybersecurity and cryptography are very
complex topics that form the foundation
of web security.
OAuth handles a lot of
this complexity for us.
Therefore, this course will
focus on implementation more so
than the mathematics and
theory behind this technology.
In a bit, we will see some of the
challenges of implementing your own web
security to better advocate the use
of trusted frameworks like OAuth 2.
In this course you will leverage
existing OAuth 2 providers
such as GitHub and
Google to allow users to securely
sign in to your web applications.
But we will not cover creating
your own OAuth 2 server.
If you're interested in more
details on these subject though,
please feel free to explore
the links in the instructor notes