Here's the 1-D Block Row algorithm for
matrix multiply.
Let tau be the time per floating
point operation, or flop for short.
In this case flop is a shorthand for
say a floating point multiply or
a floating point add.
It does not mean a terrible movie.
So if tau is the time per flop, then the
total time this algorithm spends doing
multiplies and
adds is 2 tau n cubed / p.
Pause to convince yourself that
this is true before you move on.
Here's my question.
What is the time spent on communication?
I want you to type your
answer symbolically here.
As usual, assume our alpha
beta model of communication.
Type a little a for alpha,
and little b for beta.