I mentioned these concepts briefly
earlier in the lesson, but
it's worthwhile to explore
them in some more depth.
We say that two vectors are parallel if
one is a scalar multiple of the other.
So if v is a vector,
then v and 2v are parallel,
as are v and one-half v,
as are v and -v.
In fact, since the 0 vector equals
0 times v, it follows that v and
the 0 vector are parallel too.
Also it's worth noting that v is
parallel to itself, since 1v=v.
Note that we consider two vectors to be
parallel even if they point in opposite
directions, such as
the case of the v and -v.
All that matters is that we can multiply
one by scalar to get the other.
In contrast, we say two vectors are
orthogonal if their dot product is 0.
Recall that if v dot w = 0,
then there are two possible cases.
Either one of the vectors v or
w is the 0 vector, or
else they're at right
angles to each other.
This is where we get
the terminology orthogonal.
Orthogonality is sometimes difficult
to imagine in higher dimensions, so
this algebraic definition comes
in handy when we lose our ability
to picture our vectors.
An interesting fact is that the 0
vector has the unique property
that it is parallel and
orthogonal to all other vectors.
In fact, the 0 vector is the only
vector that is orthogonal to itself.
To see why, suppose that v is a vector,
some vector, maybe not 0, but it has the
property that it's orthogonal to itself.
That means that v dot v = 0.
But recall that v dot v equals
the magnitude of v squared.
So that means the magnitude
of v squared equals 0.
In turn,
that means that the magnitude of v = 0.
Since the 0 vector is the only
vector with 0 magnitude,
that means the 0 vector is the only
vector that v could possibly be.
So if some vector is orthogonal to
itself, it must be the 0 vector.