So here's how I did it.
This first part should
look pretty familiar, but
there's one new line, this right here.
I went ahead and return the response
from the second getJSON.
This getJSON is getting
the URL of the first planet.
By returning it,
it will get past to the next .then
which happens to be right here.
When it receives the planetData,
it then creates a thumbnail with it.
Before we go on, I want to show you
a slightly different syntax here.
Instead of an anonymous function,
I can actually just pass this function,
createPlanetThumb, this function
will receive the same argument.
And as the argument that
the anonymous function was receiving
is the same one that createPlanetThumb
was receiving, this works totally fine.
I've also got two catches,
here and here.
I've got this first one here
in case there is an error with
the search results.
And I've got the second in
case anything else went wrong.
Your error handling strategy may
have looked slightly different and
that's totally fine.
So the real question is
does this code work?
Let's see.
And it sure does.
Very, very cool.
Okay, but that's about as far as we can
go just by manually chaining vents.
It's time to make chains
a little bit more interesting.