Okay, we're going to explain this pretty
quickly because this is a review from
the last course.
So if you need a refresher,
the link's below.
To achieve this desired screenshot,
we need to modify the list so
that each list item
shows more information.
Now, instead of using the simple list
item XML layout that's provided by
the framework, we'll need to
create our own XML layout for
a single list item that will
contain three TextViews.
Now in order to do this,
I created a new layout file
called earthquake_list_item.xml.
If we go over here to the TextView,
we can take a look at our XML layout.
Now in this list item file,
I have a horizontal LinearLayout
that contains three TextViews,
one for the magnitude, one for
the location, and one for the date.
We don't need to worry about
what it looks like now.
So I just evenly spaced out all the
views using a layout width of 0dp and
a layout weight of 1 for
all the children.
I also added 16 dips padding
on the list item layout so
that the list items won't
be too short in height.
Now if we switch to the design pane, we
can see our temporary placeholder data
to make sure that the layout
looks like the way we want.
Next, we add the XML tools namespace
to the root LinearLayout element,
under the line where we
declare the Android namespace.
Then we can use the tools:text
attribute on each TextView and
add some placeholder text.
What this does is add text that will
be shown in the Android Studio preview
pane, but not on our phone
when we actually run the app.
Cool, now our custom
list item layout is done.
Now we need a Java object to hold
all the earthquake information
that will be shown in each list item.
So now I'll hop back to our
Earthquake.java file, where we've
defined a new earthquake class that
represents a single earthquake.
Then we've defined three global
variables of type string,
one to hold the magnitude, the location,
and the date, because each
earthquake has these attributes.
Then in the public constructor for
the Earthquake class, we initialized
the three member variables
based on the values that were
passed into the constructor.
Since these global variables are
private, we need to create public getter
methods so that other classes can access
this information about the earthquake.
Now I'm going to go over to
our EarthquakeActivity class,
where we can actually create new
earthquake objects by calling
the constructor that we just created.
Now take a note to this line.
Instead of creating
an ArrayList of strings,
I want an ArrayList of
actual earthquake objects.
Then I created a new
earthquake object and
then added it to the list,
one at a time.
Now for each earthquake,
I made up some fake values for
the magnitude and for the date.
Then we had to create our
own EarthquakeAdapter,
which is customized to display
a list of earthquakes.
Now we define the EarthquakeAdapter as
extending from the ArrayAdapter super
class and
overriding the getView method so
that we control how the list
item views get created.
When getView is called, we can check
to see if we can use a recycled view.
Otherwise, we inflate a new
list item layout defined in
the earthquake_list_item XML file.
Then we can use the position parameter
passed in to get a reference to
the appropriate earthquake object
from the list of earthquakes.
Next, we can start binding the data from
the earthquake object to the views in
the list item layout.
We find each TextView in
the list based on the view ID and
set the corresponding data onto them.
Once the list item has the correct data
for a single earthquake at the given
position, then we can return
the view to the caller.
The caller in this case is the ListView,
who will take all these list items and
display them on the screen.
For a more thorough
explanation of ListView and
adapters, check out the last course
which has a whole lesson on this topic.
And the link is located below.
So let's go back to our
EarthquakeActivity.
We can create a new earthquake
adapter by passing in the list of
earthquakes and then setting
the adapter on the ListView.
Now let's run it on our device.
And this is what it looks like, cool.