Logging into a Unix system checks your
user name and password against a special
table of user names and passwords that
can only be read by the group user.
Group authenticates you as a user,
and logs you in to the machine.
Once you're logged in,
if you attempt to access a file,
this is when authorization is at play.
Before you can read or
write a file to a Unix system,
the operating system checks to see if
you are authorized access to that file.
This isn't authentication because
since you are already logged in,
you do not have to authenticate
yourself again to access the file.
If you have the right password to a zip
file, you are authorized to open it
without having to identify who you are,
so this is authorization.
When you cross a border into a country,
you must first present a passport to
identify who you are and
what country you are from.
So that's authentication.
Although, between some countries,
a passport is sufficient for
entry, many countries require a visa for
entering another country.
The visa can specify the things you
can do, like work or study, and
how long you're allowed
to stay in the country.
So this is definitely
an issue of authorization.