[Thrun] Well, the answer follows the exact same scheme as before,
with S being replaced by not S.
So this should be an easier question for you to answer.
P of R given H and not S can be inverted by Bayes' rule to be as follows.
Once we apply Bayes' rule, as indicated over here where we swapped H to the left side
and R to the right side, you can observe that this value over here
can be readily found in the table.
It's actually the 0.9 over there.
This value over here, the raise is independent of the weather
by virtue of our Bayes network, so it's just 0.01.
And as before, we apply total probability to the expression over here,
and we obtain off this quotient over here that these 2 expressions are the same.
P of H given not S, not R is the value over here,
and the 0.99 is the complement of probability of R taken from over here,
and that ends up to be 0.0833.
This would have been the right answer.