All right, so to modify word costs,
to support an image,
we're going to need to add two things.
So, first we need to add a private
integer variable in order to hold
our image resource ID.
Because this is a member variable,
I'm going to call it mImageResourceId so
that it matches the naming style
of our other member variables.
And secondly, we're going to need to
add a getter method for this variable.
So here we made it a private variable
but we'll need to access it from outside
so we're going to have to
write a public method.
I'm going to call my method
getImageResourceId and
notice that it takes no inputs and
it will return an int.
So within this method, I'm going to
say that it returns mImageResourceId.
All right, so those are all the changes
that we need to make to the word class.
All right, so run the app on your device
to make sure that this code change
didn't break anything.
So if we tap into a category, you'll
notice that there's no visible change in
the app, because we're not making use
of this new color variable just yet.
But we will be in the next coding quiz.