In the next few videos we'll cover the
code for working with scales, but for
now I'd like to stay at
a very high level and
use graphics to explain what's
happening when you use a scale.
The first thing you need to know is
that when working with an SVG canvas
the coordinates, in particular
the Y coordinates start at 0 and
then increase going down.
This is a little bit counterintuitive
to what you typically think of
when you think of a graph.
Usually the Y values start at 0 at
the bottom of an increase going up, but
the opposite is true for SVGs.
As you move to the right on an SVG
element, the X values increase.
And as you move down on an SVG element,
the Y values will increase.
This means that for our gapminder plot,
life expectancy values, which are really
high in the case for China's dot,
need to map to lower pixel values.
And conversely, countries for
which the life expectancy is low need
to map to higher Y pixel values.
This green bar represents the scale of
life expectancy on the gap minder plot.
At the bottom,
there's a minimum value of 15 years, and
at the top,
there's a maximum value of 90 years.
So what we'd like to do is map
all the values between 15 and
90 to pixel values between 0 and 250.
This blue bar will represent all
the pixel values that we'd like to map
our data into.
So our highest life expectancy value
of 90 needs to map to 0 pixels.
And our lowest life expectancy value
of 15 needs to map to 250 pixels.
D3 refers to the input values
as the domain of the data.
We'll use this when we
construct our d3 scale.
In d3, can be represented
by the minimum number and
the maximum value in terms in an array.
So we'll be using this when we
construct our life expectancy scale.
And note that we're not just
mapping the minimum and
the maximum value, we're also mapping
all the other values that are in between
two corresponding pixel values.
D3 refers to the pixel values you want
to map the input data to as the range.
This is also represented by
a minimum value and a maximum value.
You'll see this part of the code later.
In order to map or transform
our input data to pixel values,
we need to specify a function to take in
a data value and produce a pixel value.
In the case of life expectancy,
the scale that we want was
linear in the Gapminder plot.
Thinking mathematically about this
transform, we want to map our domain,
these values, into a range of pixel
values using some type of function.
Since we're using a linear scale,
the function is simply
the equation of a line.
Now, you don't need to worry
about the values of m and b,
since D3 can calculate
these two values for you.
Just know that you're
inputting some data value here
to get out some pixel value here.
D3 does this all behind the scenes for
you.
The only thing that you need to do,
is specify a minimum and
maximum for the domain and
a minimum and maximum for the range.
And also the type of scale
that you'll be using.
The D3 scale function figures out
the appropriate values or constants
to transform each life expectancy value
into its corresponding pixel value.
Now that we have some conceptual idea
of why D3 scales are important and
how they work, let's jump into some
live code to put scales into practice