So the two traditional
methods widely in used for
doing any kind of warping
are forward and inverse.
We briefly touched on
them in the last lecture,
I'm going to now just give
you more details on them.
So, to help us understand this, let's
start off by just having two images.
We'll call the first image
the source and the T, the target.
We want to be able to take information
pixels from the source, and
create a new image or a target image,
that would have the deformations or
the warps that we are interested in.
For simplicity's sake, let's imagine S
basically has a coordinates base u and
v, and the target has x and y.
Now this is slightly a different
notation than we've used so far.
In the previous ones,
we talked about S being basically x and
y, and the target being x prime and
y prime.
Just bear with me for a second, we'll
come back to that notation in a bit but
this is just to kind of help us
understand how we can do this simply.
So forward warping basically is taking,
generating a new x and
y by creating a warp on X,
which is applied to u and v here.
And warp and Y, which is also
taking u and v from this one.
And generating a new set of coordinates,
x and y.
So here, of course, the warp is X and
Y, apply to the values in here,
and generating this.
Backward or inverse is basically trying
to do the prediction of where things
are in the target based on what are
things or pixel values in the source.
So here, of course, we generating,
in essence, the u and v,
by doing a deformation or
a transformation, or a warp, U and V,
which takes values from here and
generates this image.
So in essence,
while we have this, we're trying to now
do the opposite of trying to figure out
how to go from pixel values in all of
the range values here into this one.
To help understand this,
let's take a simple example.
Now this was, of course,
what we want to accomplish for forward.
And this is what we want to
accomplish for inverse.
Here I'm basically showing an input and
output, for, basically,
the forward, and the input and output
for the backwards, or the inverse.
And the input and output for
the inverse warp.
Now, to help us along,
what we can actually start imaging is,
that this could be, u,
v could be completely integer values,
will become clear in a second.
While, the output has
to be in real values.
While in the case of the inverse warp,
the opposite is true.
If I have all of this in integer values,
I could actually now
have real values input.
Let me start off by finding a few
pixels in the original input here and
see what they would look
like in the output.
Here is one, and here's the other one.
When this pixel is moved over,
the information from this pixel is
moved over to the output,
of course, because of the warping,
it won't be just in the regular
grid pattern of this image anymore.
In fact, the intensity
value should be distributed
in the raster scan of this image, and
of course, what we now need to do is
generate a new image that would have
the values that came in from here.
And again, the warp would be
based on these two X and Y.
And imagine this, is now,
of course, moving here.
So, in essence, what we've got
is from here to there actually
we warped the image,
and from here to there,
we warped this part of the image,
this region, is now moved here.
So this is basically
the forward warping process.
In the case of the inverse,
the opposite is true.
We would have this region,
we want to move it here, and
we would have another one.
So again, let's take these two pixels
again, these are integer values and
all of the values that come from it and
we want to try to move into this range.
Now, let's talk about the problems.
The big problem when we do a forward
warp is, in this instance,
I moved all of the information
to a warped region here.
And of course, imagine if there
is another pixel or region here,
then I want to do it here.
Of course, if it moves here,
there might be a cause for an overlap.
Of course, it also is possible
that this region here,
that this region here next to it,
moves here.
And of course,
all of a sudden, I have no information
connecting these two parts here.
So of course, this would be a hole.
So overlap would, would mean they go
next to each other overlapping in
the information or, in this case, when
they're far away there would be a hole.
So this is one of the problems
when I go forward.
In the other end,
when I actually am going backwards,
that is doing the inverse warp,
I know that these pixels belong to here.
But the problem that comes in is,
when I actually start going for
something that becomes smaller or
the minification process.
I'll show that in a second.
That would result in
all kinds of artifacts.
One of the bigger artifacts in these
processes of course is aliasing or
blocking.