So the bottom line is, cameras are everywhere, and
they're having an impact on everything.
And this is why computational photography, which is in the area of trying to
understand the best possible ways to capture images,
is becoming relevant and important.
To summarize, I basically talked about the pervasiveness of
a camera in our society.
Basically talked about how computational photography builds on
other disciplines.
And basically talked about relationship between photography, and
traditional photography, and digital photography, implying again that
computational photography sits above all of them, and can encompass all of them,
primarily with the assumptions that computers are ubiquitous and
so are cameras and by combining them we are actually generating new ways of
capturing the environment and sharing them with each other.
Again, more information on this available on the web.
I'll be putting up a bunch of links on this stuff after the classes.
And basically I believe that there's a strong need for us to
continue working on computational photography, because of reasons like this and
also because it impacts how we capture our environment around us.
So now we will move to much more of the technical nuggets of this class.
We will study what is an image and
basically start thinking about making things computational, so
that we can process and interact with the information that's in an image.