Based on this workload analysis,
the author's made the following
design decisions in Sprite.
First, the Sprite will support caching
and it will use a write back policy.
First, every 30 seconds the client
will write back all the blocks.
That have not been modified
in the past 30 seconds.
The intuition behind this is that the
blocks that are more recently modified
will continue being modified,
that the client is still working
on that part of the data.
So it does not make sense to force to
write-back those particular blocks.
Instead, wait a little bit until
the client is done working on that
piece of the file.
And then right them back to the server.
This will avoid repeatedly
sending the same blocks over and
over back to the server.
Note that this 30 second threshold
is directly related to this value 30
seconds which is their observation that
a lot of the data will get deleted
within 30 seconds.
When a client comes along and wants
to open a file that's currently being
written by another client, the server
will contact this writer client and
will collect all of
the outstanding dirty blocks.
In the system, there is no explicitly
write-back on close, so it's possible
that a client has finished working on
a file completely, closed the file,
and there's still modified blocks
in that particular client cache.
Note that with this policy, Sprite
allows for a file to be open, modified,
closed, open, modified,
closed multiple times,
before any data actually gets
written back to the server, and
this is one way in which Sprite is able
to optimize this 33% of write accesses.
Now, note for this to work, every open
operation has to go to the server.
And what that really means is that
the directories cannot be cached
on the client.
So the client can not perform
a directories related operation,
that looks up a file, and opens a file,
and creates a file directly,
using its cache only.
It has to go to the server.
And finally, in the cases where these
rare concurrent writes do occur,
then Sprite will completely
disable the caching for that file.
And all of the writes will be
serialized at the server side.
In summary, Sprite distinguishes
between two situations.
When the files are accessed in a way
where the writes don't really happen
concurrently, instead over time
the clients take turns who's
writing to the file,
Sprite allows caching and
provides sequential semantics for
the file sharing.
In contrast when Sprite determines
that a file is shared concurrently for
write when multiple clients
want to write to that file,
then Sprite completely forbids caching.
It will disable caching.
Because this situation doesn't
happen frequently the penalty on
performance will not be significant.