Well for question one, how many outer most states?
There's two we've already said this dead and
alive states. Which button must be pressed to turn on the alarm clock feature?
That's button a. In the alive state how many current machines are running?
Well there's five. There's the main one, the power state, the light state and
the two that are labeled alarm-st and chime-st.
When the C button is pressed to set the time, which part is first,
that's, the user changes the second setting first. And then
the question about what unexpected side effect. When Harel was at Georgia Tech,
he told us about how when doing the modeling of his digital watch.
He found a bug in the way that it ran. Whenever you hit that B-button,
it turned on the light whether you needed the light turned or not.
Going back to the garage door opener for a minute, when I modeled the garage
door opener of my house, I found that there was a bug in its system as well.
The bug arose when I was going on vacation and I was hitting
the security feature. Now this wasn't in the example that I showed you, but.
The real state machine for the garage door opener has a security feature and
that turns off the remote the remote control so you can't open the garage on
the outside and what I was going to do was start the door go, door going down,
hit the security feature and duck out underneath. Okay the system had
not been designed to change that security feature as the door was going down and
I lock myself out. Okay, and it's another
indication that getting these reactive systems correct is quite difficult and
careful modeling of things is important. To make sure that you don't get
into these embarrassing or possibly situations that lead to safety problems.