So team Awesome thanks so much for
walking us through your really cool hackathon project.
And, I was wondering if you had any advice for
students as they are walking through their own final project.
>> I guess we benefited by working with other people.
So it always helps if you, have friends that could help on the,
you know, your project via, you know, first, we had some developers, and
modelers, and just a wide array of people.
So it he-,.
helped that everyone had different skill sets, so.
>> Also, just by the nature of Storm, VPI is actually not too complicated.
You only have a couple of things you have the spout, the topology, the bolts,
and then, you got your shuffle grouping, your fields grouping, and
maybe plus a couple of other things but that's basically it.
You have a bunch of little steps, that by themselves, are trivial, and
then you just add ten of them together and you come up
with something that's very nontrivial and actually looks pretty cool.
>> So, in the end my advice is basically to just learn what all those ten
commands do, and have some good design ideas of how to put them together.
[LAUGH]