[BLANK_AUDIO]
There's the standard fields that
supervised machine learning is
typically applied to,
including things like ads optimization,
ranking hotel research results for
Expedia and things along those lines.
All the use cases that we've read in
that area have been very successful.
We've also touched the large number of
use cases where it was unknown what
the current state of the art is or how
well machines could do in our problem.
Another one of my favorites touched
natural language processing.
We took a dataset of about
28,000 student written essays
from middle school and
high school students,
that were given a state standardized
exams across four different states.
And then we challenged our community to
develop automatic methods to grade these
essays.
So they can learn from training
stats how teacher grades
correspond to both the prompt and
the content in the essays and
then apply that to a new test of essays.
And it turns out that at the end of the
competition, we had two teachers grade
each essay, as well as the machine score
from each of those solutions submitted.
And for the top solutions the machine
scores as great as often with one
of the teachers as the other teacher
at grade with the first teacher.
One of the ones that we recently
hosted was around a cardiac
diagnostics problem,
where we had a dataset of about 500
patient MRI images that were
videos of their beating hearts.
And we've challenged participants to do
the same work that a cardiologist would
do in estimating certain properties
of the heart from the MRI images.
This is a task that takes a trained
cardiologist about 20 minutes.
And it's pretty much wasted time for the
cardiologist when they could be doing
more valuable things
in a clinical setting.
So this really enables the cardiologists
to help focus on higher leverage
activities instead of being able to do
the grunt work that machines can do
a very effective job at now.
The top Kaggle performance in this
competition for about the top 20 or
so teams approximated that
of a human cardiologist.