In the documentation for
GraphDefinedDomain,
we see that there is a static message,
returning a state object
called getState, which takes
a domain object as an argument and
an int representing the state
object from the domain to retrieve.
So we can call
GraphDefinedDomain.getState with
arguments this.domain, and 0.
In order to retrieve the zeroth state
for the domain we generated in line 14.
One thing to keep in mind is
that there isn't an intrinsic
notion of an initial state built
in to the domain object itself.
We are specifying the initial
state outside of the domain.
This allows us more flexibility
in building our MDP.
For example, we can specify
different initial states for
different runs of a planning algorithm.