The reason why we have to contact switch
among threads is because the CPU has
one set of registers to describe
the active execution context,
the thread that's currently
running on the CPU.
These include the stack pointer and
program counter, in particular.
Over time, however,
hardware architects have recognized that
they can do certain things to help hide
some of the overheads associated
with contact switching.
One way this has been achieved,
is to have CPUs that have multiple set
of registers, that each set of register
can describe the context of a separate
thread, of a separate execution entity.
One term that's used to refer
to this is hyper threading.
So, hyper threading refers to multiple
hardware-supported execution contexts,
so hyper threads.
There's still just one CPU, so on this
CPU only one of these threads can
execute at a particular moment of time.
However, the context switching
between these threads is very fast.
And just basically the CPU needs to
switch from using this set of registers
to another set of registers.
Nothing has to be saved or restored.
This mechanism is really
referred to by multiple names.
So in addition to hyperthreading a
common term is also to refer to this is
hardware multithreading,
or chip multithreading or
simultaneous multithreading, SMTs.
So, we will used basically these
two terms, hyperthreading and
SMTs, more dominantly than the others.
Hardware today frequently
supports two hardware threads.
However, there are multiple higher
end server designs to support up to
eight hardware threads.
And one of the features of today's
hardware is that you can enable or
disable this hardware
multithreading at boot time,
given that there's some trade-offs
associated with this as always.
If it is enabled, as far as
the operating system is concerned,
each of these hardware contexts
appears to the operating system's
scheduler as a separate context,
a separate virtual CPU, onto which.
Which it can schedule threads given that
it can load the registers with
the thread context concurrently.
So for instance in this figure
the scheduler will think that it has two
CPUs and it will load these registers
with the context of these two threads.
So one of the decisions that the
scheduler will need to make is which two
threads to schedule at the same time
to run on these hardware contexts.
To answer that question,
let's remind ourselves of what we
talked about when we talked about
the context switching time.
We said that it,
the time that a thread is idling,
that a thread has to wait on
something to happen is greater than
twice the time to perform a context
switch, then it makes sense to actually
do the context switch in order to hide
this waiting, this idling latency.
In SNT systems, the time to perform
a context switch among the two hardware
threads is in the order of cycles.
And the time to perform a memory
access operation, a memory log,
remains in the order of hundreds
of cycles, so it's much greater.
So given this,
then it means that it does
make sense to context switch
to the other hardware thread.
And in that way,
this technology hyperthreading
will help us even hide the memory access
latency that threads are experiencing.
Hyperthreading does have implication and
scheduling, in that it raises some
other requirements when we're trying to
decide what kinds of threads should we
co-schedule on the hardware
threads in the CPU.
We will discuss this question
in the context of the paper
Chip Multithreaded Processors Need
a New Operating System Scheduler
by Sasha Fedorova and others.