In this lecture, we will contrast several approaches for
structuring applications that require concurrency.
This will include and comparison between multi-process and multi-threaded
approaches, and we talked about both of these already in this course, and
in addition, we will present an alternative, a so-called event driven approach.
We will base the discussion of the event driven model on Vivek Pai's paper,
Flash: An Efficient and Portable Web Server.
This paper describes the event-driven architecture, and
it also includes detailed performance comparisons between a multi-process,
multi-threaded, and an event driven implementation of a web server application.
In addition, these results are put in contrast with Apache,
which is a popular open-source web server.
We will end this lecture with a more generic discussion on how to
structure good experiments.