For this first discussion
of scheduling algorithms
I want to focus on what we call
run-to-completion scheduling.
This type of scheduling assumes that
as soon as a task is assigned to a CPU,
it will run until it finishes or
until it completes.
Let me list first some of
the assumptions we will make.
We will consider that we have a group
of tasks that we need to schedule.
I'll refer to these also as threads and
jobs and similar terms.
Let me also, to start with,
assume that we will know exactly how
much time these threads need to execute.
So there will be no
preemption in the system.
Once a task starts running
it will run to completion,
it will not be interrupted or preempted
to start executing some other task.
And also to start with, let me assume
that we only have a single CPU.
We will relax these requirements
further as we go through this lesson.
Now since we will be talking about
different scheduling algorithms,
it will be important for
us to be able to compare them,
so we're going to think
about some useful metrics.
When it comes to comparing schedulers,
some of the metrics that can give
meaningful answers regarding those
comparisons include throughput.
The average time it took for tasks to
complete, the average time the tasks
spent waiting before they were
scheduled, overall CPU utilization.
We will use some of these metrics to
compare some of the algorithms that we
will talk about.
The first and
the simplest algorithm we'll talk
about is First-Come First-Serve.
In this algorithm,
tasks are scheduled on the cpu in
the same order in which they arrive.
Regarding of their execution time,
of loading the system, or anything else.
When a task completes,
the schedule will pick the next
task that arrived, in that order.
Clearly, a useful way to organize these
tasks, would be in a queue structure, so
that tasks can be picked up
from it in a FIFO manner.
Whenever a new task becomes ready, it
will be placed at the end of the queue.
And then whenever the scheduler needs
to pick the next task to execute,
it will pick from
the front of the queue.
To make this decision, all
the scheduler will need to know will be
the head of the queue structure, and
how to dequeue tasks from this queue.
So basically for
first come first serve scheduling
some FIFO like queue would be
a great run queue data structure.
Now let's take a look at this area
in which these three tasks T1 T2 and
T3 have the following execution times.
T1 is one second, T2 is ten seconds,
and T3 is also one second.
And let's assume they
arrive in this order.
So T1 followed by T2 followed by T3.
So this is how they'll be
placed in the runqueue.
Now let's look at through
put asymmetric for
this kind of system that uses
the first come first serve scheduler.
We have three tasks.
To execute them one after the other
we will take total of 12 seconds,
1 plus 10 plus 1.
So the scheduler on average achieves
a quarter of a task per second.
So 0.25 tasks per second.
If we are interested in the average
completion time of these tasks,
the first task will complete in one
second since it will start immediately.
The second task,
it will complete at time T11.
It will have to wait one second for
the first task to complete, and
then it will execute for ten seconds.
And then the third task it
will complete at time T12,
because it will have to wait for
the 11 tasks for T1 and
T2 to execute until it starts and
executes for one second.
So, if we compute the average completion
time in the system we see that it
is 8 seconds.
If we're interested in
the average wait time for
the three tasks in the system,
then the first task started immediately.
The second task started a second later,
because it had to wait for
T1 to complete, and
then the third task had to wait for
11 seconds before it started executing.
So, the average wait time for
these three tasks is four seconds.
So we have our simple
scheduling algorithm, however,
probably we can do a little bit better
in terms of the various metrics that
you're able to achieve with this
algorithm when we try something else.
So we see that first come first serve
is simple, but the wait time for
the tasks is poor even if
there is just one long
task in the system that has arrived
ahead of some shorter tasks.
So, to deal with this we can look at
another algorithm that's called shortest
job first, and the goal of this
algorithm is to schedule the tasks
in the order of their execution time.
Given the previous example
with tasks T1, T2 and T3,
the order in which we want to execute
them would be T1 followed by T3 and
then T2, the longest task, at the end.
And for tasks that take the same
amount of time to execute,
perhaps we break ties arbitrarily.
Now if we organize our run
queue the same way as before,
adding new tasks to the run
queue will be easy,
since it will just mean that we have
to add a task at the tail of the queue.
However when we need to schedule a new
task, we'll need to traverse the entire
queue until we find the one with
the shortest execution time.
So run queue won't really be a FIFO run
queue anymore, since we will need to
remove tasks from the queue in a very
specific order based on execution time.
One thing we can do is we can maintain
the run queue as an ordered queue so
that tasks,
when they're inserted into the queue,
are placed in the queue
in a specific order.
It will make the insertion of tasks into
the queue a little bit more complex, but
it will keep the selection of a new
task as short as it was before.
We just need to know
the head of the queue.
Or, our run queue doesn't
really have to be a queue.
It can be some treelike data structure,
in which the nodes in this tree are
ordered based on their execution time.
When inserting new nodes in the tree,
new tasks in this tree,
the tree may need to be rebalanced.
However, for the scheduler,
it will be easy, since it will
always have to select the left most note
in the stream, if the tree is ordered,
the left most note will have
the smallest execution time.
So we a queue, a tree,
this illustrates really that the run
queue doesn't really have to be a queue.
It can be other type of data structure,
and we'll see that it often is,
based on whatever is appropriate for
the scheduling algorithm