So for this quiz we're going to actually
derive a third Bellman equation
in addition to the V equation
that we talked about and
the Q equation which
we just talked about.
We're going to derive an equation,
we'll call it C, because we want to
make sure the front of the alphabet
gets a little bit of love.
So, just as Q here stands for this part
of the equation, starting from the R,
and V captures this part of
the equation starting from the max.
We want to express an equation
that starts essentially from where
the gamma is.
And so I've written four choices
that you can select among.
>> Okay, I think I got it.
So we're just doing the same thing we
did when you did that little clever
trick to derive Q.
We're going to do the same thing
by moving one step down this lot.
>> Exactly, yes.
>> Okay.
>> So we have b of s, and q of sa,
and we c of, I don't know, something.
>> So wait, wait here.
I don't think I can answer this question
until I get something resolved.
So the v stands for value.
The Q stands for quality so
the C stands for.
>> Quantity!
No, that's not right.
It stands for continuation.
The idea was introduced in a paper
by Tom Dietrich where he showed
that sometimes if the reward function
is really complicated it can help to to
derive, or re express the Bellman
equation in this form where the reward
gets left off and we only observe
the reward later in the flow.
So it has a little bit of usage, but
at the moment it's just to try and
get you to play around a little bit
with this idea of capturing different
quantities as it goes by.
>> Okay, I think that's a hint,
and I think I'm ready.
>> Go.