All right, so now that we
have a notion of contraction.
We should apply a contraction to our
favorite friend the Bellman operator.
>> I do not use contractions.
>> Oh, I see what you did there.
>> Thank you.
>> My spouse is an obstetrician, and so
sometimes she worries about
contractions as well.
>> I think we could probably do this for
an hour.
>> Let's say we contract it.
Nicely done.
So good.
So right, we want to apply this
notion of a contraction mapping
to the Bellman operator.
In other words, we want to show
that if we have a Q function Q and
we apply the Bellman operator to it.
Then, well in particular,
if we have 2 Q functions, Q1 and
Q2, the distance between them.
After applying the Bellman
operator is less than or
equal to gamma times
the distance before we apply it.
So by applying it we move these
two Q functions closer together.
Sure.
>> All right, so
the first thing we're going to do is
unpack the definition of the max norm.
And so in this case,
in the case of Q functions.
What that really means is we're going to
maximize, over all state-action pairs.
The Q value of each of those
state-action pairs' difference and
absolute value.
And that leaves us in a good position
to be able to unpack the definition of
the Bellman operator itself over these
two different Q functions Q1 and Q2.
So all I did here is substitute
it in for the Bellman operator.
The definition of the Bellman
operator as it's written up here.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Alright, since we're computing
the difference between Q values for
the same state action pair.
They're going to have the same reward
and then they're only going to differ
really in the value of
the resulting state.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So
we can cancel out these two rewards.
We can actually factor together
these gammas and summations,
which are the same in both cases.
And we get down to the maximum
difference over all the state
action pairs.
Or the absolute difference
between the discounted
expected value of the next state.
And the value of
the next state being for
Q1 the max over all actions of
the values of state s prime
at Q1 and for Q2
>> The maximum over reactions
of the values at state s prime for Q2.
>> Oh, because you can.
>> So
why can't we just keep factoring it?
Yeah.
>> because they're different a primes.
>> Right.
>> So do you see why I didn't
go one more step here and
actually combine these
two maxes together.
Even though we combined
these two sums together?
>> Yeah, because,
even though you wrote a prime both
times, they're two different a primes.
>> Right, right.
So this is the action that maximizes
the q value for Q1.
And this is the action that
maximizes the q value for Q2, and
they may have different max actions.
>> Right, even though they
both end up in this prime.
>> They start in s prime.
That's right.
>> Well, they start in s and
they end up in s prime.
>> And then we're choosing
the action in s prime.
>> That's right.
Okay, yeah, that makes sense.