So to build out this layout, I like
to first think about it conceptually
to make sure I have an idea of what
I'm going to do before I start coding.
First, we notice that it's a vertical
linear layout because the items
are in a vertical column.
We have three children views.
We have an image view,
a text view and a text view.
The first hint that I gave you was to
first determine the width of each view.
Since the whole layout takes up the full
width and height of the device,
this Vertical Linear Layout has
a width and height of match_parent.
Then for the image view, we want it
to also be as wide as the parent,
which in turn is as wide as the device.
So we set that to be match_parent.
Same for the two textviews.
We want them to match the full width
of the device, so it's match_parent.
Then we work on the height of each view.
These two textviews are easy because
they wrap to the content inside of them.
So we set wrap_content for
the height of each textview.
We also set the weight values to be zero
because we don't want these values to
change even if there's
available space in the parent.
Now the imageview was the hardest part.
We want the height of the image to grow
or shrink depending on the available
space in the parent, which depends on
the available screen size of the device.
We use weights to accomplish this.
We set the height of the image
view to start at zero dp but
we give it a weight of one.
Since none of the other
children have weight values
then any available space in the parent
will be given to this image view.
And the reason we set
the height to be zero dp
is because it's
a vertical linear layout.
So it fills itself vertically.
And we don't know the height yet
until the weight value determines it.
We gave you this link in
the instructor notes and
it had some code already in it.
The positioning of the views is
incorrect, though, so let's fix that.
Let's start with the text views
first because those are easy.
You can see that these text views
don't stretch across the whole width
of the device.
So we need to change that.
The width should be match_parent.
That's better.
So now the greenish-bluish background
goes across the whole
width of the device.
Same for
the bonfire at the beach textview.
Cool.
And the height
is that content which is correct.
Now we have all this extra vertical
space in the vertical linearlayout.
Oh, by the way, the width and
height of the linear layout is
set to be match parent so that
the layout will eventually extend the
whole height and width of the screen.
So to use this extra
height in the parent
we want to give it to a child
that has a weight value.
So let's change the imageview so
that it has a weight value.
First, we can set the width
to be match_parent so
that it also extends across
the width of the device.
Then we set the height to be 0dp and
the weight to be 1.
And that's the desired screenshot.
Good job.
Note that if I change the weight values
to be a really high number like seven or
ten, it doesn't really
change the device preview.
That's because this is the only
child with a weight so
it doesn't matter if it's a really
high weight or a really low weight.
All the extra height in the parent
will be given to this child.
So let's just change this to be one.
Okay, good job.