In this exercise you'll set
up a shape renderer and
use it to draw a stick figure.
At a minimum you'll need a circle for
the head, and five lines for
the torso, the two arms,
and the two legs.
Remember in order to set up a shape
renderer you need to declare it,
initialize it, and dispose of it.
Then to actually use the shape renderer,
you'll need to start a batch
of the appropriate type,
whether that's filled or lined, draw
your shapes, and then end the batch.
We don't really have
step-by-step to-dos for
this one since the aim is for
you to remember the steps for
setting up a shape renderer and
be able to set one up on your own.
Of course, the solution is
still available if you run
into anything confusing.
Give it a try.