So on our first scenario of our
Video Everywhere app we needed to store
the video segments.
Now, video segments are large media
files and they should probably be saved
using something like internal or
external storage in files.
So given that the videos
are specific to the app and
we don't want other apps
to be able to delete or
modify these videos,
using files would be our best choice.
So for our second app, the user
will likely quickly open up the app
to get a conversion when they need it.
So the user will need their
preferences for units stored.
Now because of this, using shared
preferences should be more than enough
just to store our unit preferences.
So our third case, the song app
was similar to our video app
in that songs are stored
on a user's device.
And their large media files.
So you might want to use
these songs on any app.
And in fact, remember the description
says that the songs should be useable
on any app.
So storing in files will make
perfect sense in this case.
So lastly we have our Pets app.
So it's likely that
the shelter organizes its data
in something like a giant
spreadsheet already.
So this method of data storage is
directly analogous to how the SQLite
database organizes its data.
So each row can have a pet.
And we'll store the most important
attributes of the pet in the columns.
So for that, our pets app,
we'll use our SQLite database.