We said that spinlocks are one of the
most basic synchronization primitives.
And that they're also used in creating
some more complex synchronization
constructs.
For that reason it makes sense to
focus the remainder of this lesson
on understanding how exactly
spinlocks can be implemented.
And what types of opportunities
are available for
their efficient implementation.
To do this, we will follow the paper The
Performance of Spin Lock Alternatives
on Shared Memory Multiprocessors
by Tom Anderson.
The paper discusses different
implementations of spinlocks and
this is relevant also for
other synchronization constructs
that use internally spinlocks.
Also some of the techniques that
are described in this paper that concern
the use of atomic instructions
generalize to other constructs and
other situations.