The goal for the first coding task of
this lesson will be to change the UI
from displaying a single text
view with all the pet data,
to displaying a list of pets.
This scrolling list view will be
a much better user experience for
viewing all the pets in the database.
It's a much easier to read
format with more white space and
divider lines as well.
Plus, we don't need to show unnecessary
information that the user doesn't
necessarily care about,
such as the database row IDs.
Each list item here will show two
pieces of relevant information.
Summaries of the pet, with its name in
bold, and then its breed down below.
In the last lesson, recall that we
discussed how this diagram represents
the current state of how we query
the database from the UI code.
So to display a list of pets,
the catalog activity will talk to
the resolver,
which then talks to the pet provider,
which then does the query
on the database.
After which, the cursor comes back,
as a result, all the way back
to our catalog activity.
Right now, we're going to zoom in on the
catalog activity and check in on how it
modifies logic around how to display
information from the cursor into the UI.
In earlier courses, we've learned
that you can easily display a list of
information using ListView.
And to populate the information
within the ListView,
we're going to need an adapter.
So essentially,
the adapter is responsible for
making the list item view for
each pet in the data source, and
then hands them off to
the ListView to show on-screen.
We first learned about ListViews and
adapters when building out
the MIWOK language app,
used to display a list of words.
Now, let's review how it was used and
then we can build on that concept
further for our pets use case.
We'll called out the ListView,
takes up the whole width and
height of the screen.
But, it starts off empty.
So know here, that the list is empty.
So the WordAdapter is what
holds on to the data source.
Here, we had a list of words, and
the WordAdapter also had an instructions
knowing how to make a list item for
each of these words.
So first, the ListView would need to
console with adapter to figure out
eventually how many words
we need to be displayed.
After which, it starts off by asking for
the list item at position zero.
The adapter, helps us identify
the zeroth worth in its data source,
constructs a list item for
that one word and
then passes this back to our ListView.
After the ListView has added this item
to the layout, it's going to ask for
the ListView at position one.
The adapter finds the corresponding
word, creates a proper list item and
then hands this back to the ListView.
So this back and
forth process will keep repeating.
The ListView will keep requesting list
items for each position in the list
until either there are no more words or
until this screen is full.
So for example, if there are ten words
in our list, but only seven can fit on
the screen, then we don't need to
request the eighth word just yet.
So this clever behavior of not
requesting views that aren't shown to
the user just yet,
is what makes the ListView and
Adapter combination such an efficient
use of memory resources.
For the views that are scrolled
off screen, we can go ahead and
recycle them and
simply swap out the text and
image, though it's going to be used for
a different word.
With a smaller number of
view objects to deal with,
scrolling performance in the ListView
can become very smooth and fast.
So as noted here,
the Adapter is responsible for
making a list item view for
each item in the data source.
For example, if our data source is
an ArrayList, such as an ArrayList of
words, then we're going to use
an ArrayAdapter to populate that list.
Now, if the data source is a Cursor,
such a Cursor of pets,
then we're going to be using
a CursorAdapter to populate that list.
Let's head back to the Pets app and
see all that in action.
In the catalog activity, we would be
defining a ListView that takes up
the full width and height of the screen.
And again, the list starts off empty.
Next, we are going to to set up
a CursorAdapter to hold on to the Cursor
pets, which we receive
from the provider.
We also want to make sure that
the CursorAdapter knows how to
create a list item view per pet.
So ListView starts off
by asking Adapter,
how many items will be
eventually be shown on the list?
Next, it starts off by asking for
each one of those items,
starting at position zero.
The Adapter moves the cursor to the
zeroth row and extracts out the column
values so that it can set up
a proper list item for this pet.
And then passes this list item
view back to our ListView.
Next, the ListView asks for
the item at position one.
The CursorAdapter moves the cursor
to row one, reads out its values.
And these values are used to create
the corresponding list item view,
which will get passed
back to our ListView.
This same process is repeated for
the next position, position two.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And the ListView will keep requesting
those items for each position,
either no more pets in the cursor or
until this screen is full.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So the next codeing task, we'll ask
you to modify the Catalog Activity to
have a ListView and
a custom CursorAdapter.
So let's walk through some of
the details of that code together.