Today was an embarrassing day. At 8 a.m., my boss sent
out an email to everyone in the company, asking for volunteers
to help him proofread some marketing documents. Since I had some
time available, I replied by saying, I can take a shot
at it. Or at least, that is what I wanted to
say. I misspelled one key word in that sentence. And instead,
wrote something really embarrassing. Why do the i and o keys
have to be so close to each other on my keyboard?
I was so embarrassed. I wish my spell checker caught
curse words to alert clumsy writers like myself. Let's write
a program that detects curse words in a text. But
before we do that, let me ask you, have you ever
been in a situation like this? Have you ever sent
or received a message that you felt was embarrassing? If so,
we would love to hear about it. You can share
your experience with us on the discussion forum. Check this box
after you've submitted your stories.