Thanks, Colt.
Let's take a look at our first tool.
Hierarchy Viewer is a tool that'll help
you visualize your entire UI structure
at a glance, and also provide you with
a better way to understand the relative
rendering performance of distinct views,
within that structure.
Here's what it looks like, so
let's go ahead and set it up.
You're actually going to need some
actual code to try this on, so
we're going to use Sunshine from
the Android fundamentals class.
You can find the details
on how to pick up this code
from the instructor notes down below.
When you're done,
click Continue to move on.
Oh, and one more note, if your phone is
rooted and running Android Jellybean or
newer, you're good to go, otherwise,
you're going to need to set up an
environment variable on your computer,
so that Hierarchy Viewer is able
to communicate with your device.
You can also find the details for
that, in the instructions as well.
All right, so let's go ahead and
start up Hierarchy Viewer,
the first thing you want to do
is hop into Android Studio.
Then, in order to get
the Hierarchy Viewer,
we're going to want to start
the Android Device Monitor.
Now, you can do that through a menu,
you can come up to the top here,
click Tools, go to Android, and
then select Android Device Monitor.
Or you can click this little
handy green little icon,
that also does the same thing.
So I'm going to go ahead and click that
to start the Android Device Monitor.
So here we are in the blank default
layout of Android Device Monitor,
now to get to Hierarchy Viewer, you're
going to want to open up a perspective.
So I'm going to do that,
by clicking this menu here, and
then clicking on Hierarchy view,
and then click OK to launch it.
All right, so here's the default
layout for Hierarchy Viewer.
If your screen looks
different than this,
you can go to the default view
by clicking the Window menu, and
click on Reset Perspective,
that'll reset things for you.
All right, so
let's talk about the different panes
that are available to you in the UI
layout for hierarchy viewer.
On the left here you're
going to find the windows tab,
you should see your phone and
a list of running applications in it.
Make sure you can see sunshine
amongst the list, and
then go ahead and
double-click to load it up.
Now as you can see, hierarchy viewer
shows you,your entire view structure for
the activity you selected,
in this case this was the main
activity of our sunshine app.
Now, if you hover over here this
is called the tree overview, and
it gives you a bird's eye view
of your entire UI structure.
Now you'll also see this view port,
which allows you to move around and
change what shows in
the detailed view on the left.
This is the detailed view.
As you can see when I
move the view port,
the details also change
in the detailed view.
This is a great way to zoom in
on portions of your hierarchy.
Now if you hopped over to the tree view,
there's this other zoom
control that allows you to zoom in and
out on your structure as well, like so.
I can also drag the layout to
move the position, zoom in and
out to get a little bit more context.
Now when you click on a view,
you can see all of its properties,
in the view properties tab, that
opens up here on the left hand side.
I'm going to go ahead and expand it, and
it's got these collapsible menus that
show you various details about the view.
For example, I can look at events and
other details related to
drawing on the screen.
Things like alpha, things like pivot,
things like rotation.
Now, double-click on a view to get a
preview of what's drawn to the screen of
this particular view,
that you've selected.
Now, let's move over
here to the lower right.
This is the Layout view.
Now, when you click on
a view on the hierarchy,
the Layout view highlights
the same view in that Layout view.
In other words, you can look at
this Layout view as a wireframe off
your device's screen markup.
So you can select items
in the detail view and
see where they will be laid
out on your device's screen.
You could also go the reverse
direction and click items here, and
see items light up in the tree
view on the top above it.
So for example,
if I click on this box right here,
this corresponds to this view over here,
and if I move the view pager, and
zoom in a little bit, I can drill
down into details about this view.
Now unfortunately you can't go directly
from hierarchy viewer to your source
code, because it's actually connected to
your running app, not the source itself.
But each node shows the type and the ID,
so that you can reference it later or
find it later in your source code.
All right, so
I want to step back for a second and
I want to make sure that you know that
hierarchy viewer is really useful in two
key ways.
The first, it's going to help you
understand your structure of your user
interface from Android's perspective.
And two, it can help you figure out,
where you might have superfluous views,
or opportunities to flatten your
view hierarchy to save memory,
and improve rendering performance.
But now some real performance insights
come from our per node profiling feature
and hierarchy viewer.
The tool models, the overall rendering
process of the entire user interface,
and provides rendering data for
a particular node relative to the other
nodes in that particular tree.
All right, so lets go back over
here to our detailed tree view.
Now click on a root node of a sub-tree
that you actually want to profile.
Just for test purposes right now.
I'm going to go ahead and
click on this action bar container.
Now in order to invoke the profiling
feature of hierarchy viewer,
you're going to want to click on
this Venn diagram icon, right here.
So, I'm going to go ahead and
do that right now.
Now, let's drill down a little
bit more specifically.
Now, as you may notice,
each view gets three distinct dots, and
they can be of different colors,
green yellow or red,
and we'll talk about what
that means in a little bit.
But, there's also a meaning
to the order of the dots.
Now the left most dot represents the
measure phase of the rendering pipeline,
the middle one, the layout phase, and
the right most one, the draw
phase of the rendering pipeline.
All right, so
lets talk about the colors now.
Now the colors of the dots indicates
the relative performance of this node,
in respect to all other profiled nodes.
So what do we mean by
relative performance?
Now let's take a look at this one.
Greens means that for
this phase of the pipeline,
this view renders faster than at
least half of the other views.
Now, if you see yellow,
it means it's in the bottom 50%.
Now, if you see red,
that means it's one of the slowest
nodes in your view hierarchy.
All right, so
here's a little bit of insight.
A red node is a potential problem in any
situation where you would not expect
slow performance.
For example, in a leaf node or
a view with only a few children,
that should be a red flag.
Now also remember, when dealing with
a large hierarchy something does need to
be the slowest node, so the question is,
is it the node that you expect it to be?
Also keep in mind that just because it's
performing relatively slow, it might not
be performing absolutely slow, that's
where the actual numbers are helpful.
All right, so now that you're
familiar with hierarchy viewer,
let's go ahead and try it on some
sample code for this lesson.