The first one says the query will fail
because the provided login is not
a correct user.
Okay?
So obviously what we're providing here
is not, doesn't match in any tuple, the
login value that is starting, restoring.
But let's look at it a bit more closely.
Although there isn't a match, but
then we're running into this or.
Okay?
This is a logical expression.
Boolean expression.
But if either is a match,
which will, you take a tuple,
the way you would do select is that
you look a row in the table or
a tuple, you look at the login field and
see if this value is going to match.
So what value are we
going to try to match?
Well, we only match
the value up to this point.
There is no match here.
So that's going to be false.
And then we continue on this, and
here we say there's an or, 1 = 1.
Now this is always true.
1 = 1, always evaluates to true.
So we're either saying there's a match,
or 1 = 1,
well together this is going to be true.
So, although the match fails,
but because of the or,
the full expression that we
have here is going to be true.
And we're actually not even
going to check for password and
PIN because whatever we put there or
did not, actually follows this two
dashes that we said,
actually is a common field, anyway.
So the query is actually only
going to select, be that select
accounts from users where
log in equals this, Okay?
That's what the query, that's going to
be submitted to the database.
That's what is going to get executed
when it's submitted to the database.
So the query actually will not fail,
and the reason for
that is that in this or expression,
although the match fails,
this side is going to be true, so the
overall expression is going to be true.
So the first one is not correct.
It will not fail because it doesn't,
login doesn't have to match.
1 = 1 is why this is going to be true.
So the first one is not
the correct answer.
The correct answer is the second one.
An injection attack will result In all
users' account data being returned.
This evaluates to true
which means that tuple
is one from which we should
be returning that request for
information, or
the information that's being selected.
Remember we return information
that is selected from all tuples,
for which this expression
evaluates to true.