So how can we change the MDP
reward function without changing
the optimal policy?
So in an MDP, we usually define
it with the states, the actions,
the rewards, the transitions,
and our friend gamma.
>> Mm-hm.
[LAUGH] What we're going to mess
with here is the R, but we're going
to leave everything else the same.
So what are some ways that we might be
able to change a reward function that
actually wouldn't change
what the agent would want to
do to maximize the reward function.
>> Well there's a couple of I think,
obvious ones.
So one is if you just take
the reward function and
multiply it by any positive constant.
Everything should be the same.
Right?
>> Yes, exactly so.
So in some sense the rewards
are kind of unit less, so
if you multiply them by 1,000,
it still encourages the same behavior.
It just seems like you're making
more reward points, but they're not,
it doesn't change the relative
strength of different behaviors.
So, good, good.
That's definitely one.
>> And I want to say this is true.
Just like by multiplying by a positive
constant doesn't make a difference,
it seems to me that if you just
shifted everything over by one or
by two or by three,
it would make a difference of adding
a constant to the reward function.
Adding a constant as opposed
to multiplying a constant.
>> Good, okay, good.
We'll talk about that one as well.
And there's a third one that we're
going to talk about, that may not be so
obvious.
But do you have any other guesses?
>> This makes me think it
desperately looks like what we did
in the other machine learning
class with clustering.
There has to be non-linear ways of
messing with the reward function to get
you the same answer.
But I can't think of a compact
way of saying what I'm thinking.
>> Okay, so that's, that's fair.
And we'll get into that in more detail.
Ultimately, we're going to call it
potential based modifications, or
potential based rewards.
And I'll define in a bit, but
first I want to go through the,
as you pointed out, the simpler cases
and develop a kind of methodology for
proving that we're not going
to change the optimal policy.
>> Okay.