Next, I want to use this definition
of an optimization problem
to define an approximation algorithm.
An algorithm is a factor
delta approximation algorithm
if on any instance I it
produces a solution S.
Such that the objective value
of the solution S on instance I,
is that most delta times the optimum for
the instance I.
Note that it's okay for delta to
be a function of the instant size.
Also, when we're working
with maximization problems
instead of minimization ones,
this inequality gets reversed.
Our previous results for
the min vertex cover problem then
can be stated in terms of
this definition by saying
that min vertex cover has a polynomial
time factor 2 approximation algorithm.
Or approximation scheme