Feeling up for a challenge?
In the instructor notes you'll
find a link to this site.
Pop open the timeline,
hit the big red button to record.
And then click the Click Me button.
Find the big Recalculate Style block in
the timeline, and then notice how it's
self time is going to be way too
long to hit 60 frames per second.
There are three things
you can do in this case.
You can either reduce the number
of affected elements,
you can reduce the selector complexity,
or you can do both.
Reducing the number of affected
elements means modifying fewer
nodes in the render tree.
Reducing selector complexity means that
you are going to using fewer tags and
class names to select your elements.
But hey, why not try to do both,
because that is a double whammy.
For this quiz, I want you to make
recalculate styles much more efficient.
If all goes well, you should be
able to get a five to ten x drop.
But before you start, I'm going to
give you a little bit of a hint.
This sample uses a class on the body
to change the style of all the boxes.
And this means that it has to check
the style of each and every box.
You can see that happening here with
this nth-child selector on class box.
An alternative would be to use
querySelectorAll to grab all of
the boxes on the page.
Once you have them,
toggle the style of every other
box by iterating through
this list using JavaScript.
Once you're seeing a five to ten x drop,
check this box to let us know you're
recalculating styles
much more efficiently.