So some of these lines
are pretty straight forward.
They start with a command prompt and
then there's a command
that I typed after it.
So those, all the ones that start
with a command prompt must be input.
This one right after the ls command
sure looks like output and it is.
Here though, I tried to get the shell
to wish you a Good St. Moose's Day.
But I forgot that the shell has a
special meaning for this single quote or
apostrophe character.
Like you saw earlier in the lesson,
the quote means that the argument and
therefore the command line that it's on
continue at least to the next
single quote, which is down here.
And that means this and this are both
also input lines, and these are output.
By the way, if you actually want to
see an apostrophe in the output.
You can do that.
The way you do that is to put
a backslash before the apostrophe.
You'd also need to put a backslash
before the exclamation mark as well.