So we also have talked about projective transformations, and for, remember for
3D, we said that we used 4D, four length vectors, and we had four by four.
Well for 2D images,
it's just a three by three matrix applied to a homogenous coordinates.
So here I've written this as I have an original vector, xyw,
w being the homogenous coordinate.
I apply my three by three, I get a new x prime, y prime, w prime.
And of course, to go to the nonhomogeneous,
I have to divide through by the w prime later.
So using this, sort of,
general framework, we can look at all of the transformations.
So let's go back to translations.
So translation in this framework is just the identity matrix up here,
the translation there, the 0, 0, 1 there.
And we go from xy1 to x prime y prime 1,
and in fact, we didn't have to do any division because we maintained that one.
And that's drawn with this cool little picture here, where we're just take this
square and we could just translate it around, nothing changes orientation size.
And translation preserves the lengths and areas of, of objects.
So as I move them around the angles stay the same.
Even the orientation stays the same.
And, because this is a, a projective transform, lines remain lines.
And lines remaining lines is going to be key to everything we do for
at least five lessons.
Well, four or five lessons.
All right, so that's translation.
A rigid body transformation could be represented this way as well.
It's called Euclidian or, or rigid body.
And now instead of having just a pure identity matrix, we
have this rotation matrix, so we can rotate in the plane and we can translate.
So we have three degrees of freedom here.
And again we've maintained a rigid body, so lengths and
areas are all preserved, angles are preserved.
Lines are preserves, but of course the location and the orientation can change.
Another one which people don't think of quite as much is a sim,
it's called a similarity transform.
In a similarity transform we have translation, here,
the rotation by the thetas, and you notice everything is scaled by a.
Okay.
So that's an expansion, that's a scale.
So this translation, rotation, and scale.
So how many degrees of freedom of that?
four.
Right?
Two for translation, a rotation, and a scale.
Now, one that we use actually a modest amount in computer vision is what's
referred to as an affine transform.
Okay, and in an affine transform you'll see that
we have six degrees of freedom here.
And I've just written them as a linear transformation.
A, b, c, d, e, f, okay?
And again, we go from xy1 to x prime y prime 1.
And what an affine transformation can do is essentially map.
And we'll look at this later.
Any three points to any other three points, all right?
And what you do is you're, you're essentially now being able to translate,
rotate, scale, and skew the image.
And there's skew in both directions.
So there's six degrees of, of freedom.
You still maintain parallel lines.
So the edges of the, this square becoming edges of a parallelogram.
Okay.
And ratios of areas remain the same.
So if I had one area here that was half the size of the area to the left,
then its transformation would be half the size over here.
But the area itself can change right through scaling.
All right. And again lines are mapped to lines.
Notice that we don't have to do the division still.