First of all, this answer and
that answer are definitely wrong.
It's totally reasonable to read and
modify layout properties and
styles with JavaScript.
In fact, that's why the language exists.
So don't be afraid of it,
even though for
synchronous layouts sometimes happen.
So that leaves these two answers.
And I want to take a look
at them individually.
And I will start with this one.
In loops, you should always
change your styles first and
then read layout properties.
Now this answer sounds somewhat
reasonable because you're
changing the styles first and
then hitting the layout properties.
The problem here is this keyword,
"loops".
Once you change the styles,
you have to run layout.
Okay, so if that happens
once that's not a big deal.
But if before the end of the frame
you have to recalculate styles and
then run layout again, you're putting
the browser in a situation where it's
redoing a lot of work and ultimately
creating a for synchronous layout.
So this answer is not correct.
So by the process of elimination,
this answer's right.
I'll show you why.
Reading the layout properties
first in the JavaScript phase
means that you'll be using
the layout from the previous frame.
Then if you do all of your
style changes afterwards,
right here in the pipeline,
the rest of it looks like normal.
The key word here.
Here is batch.
And then all of the style changes
will be batched up to happen after
JavaScript.
This means that recalculate style will
happen at the end of the frame and
in the right place for the pipeline.
So then, what does this strategy look
like with the example you just saw?
Let me show you.
This is the old janky code, and
this is the 60 frames per
second silky smooth code.
Notice that this frame only reads
a layout property once at the beginning
and then batch changes all
of the styles afterwards.
This is a pretty simple fix that
will give you a big performance win.