All right.
So you just created an intent
in the main activity of the Miwok app,
but
the code that we used to
create an intent in the Miwok
app looks different from the way we
create intent in the Just Java app.
So in the last course we
started to learn about intents.
But we didn't fully discuss
all the types of intents.
So there are actually two types of
intents, implicit and explicit intents.
Use an implicit intent when you
don't know which component or
even which app will handle your intent.
For example, in a social media app,
you can send an intent to
allow a user to take a photo.
It doesn't matter which camera
app receives the intent,
as long as the app can take a photo.
On the other hand, you should create
an explicit intent when you know exactly
which app component or
activity should handle the intent.
For example,
in the Miwok app from the main screen
when you click on a category,
we want to send an explicit intent
to the numbers activity within
our app to open that screen.
It doesn't make sense to let
any other activity handle this.
So now let's review each
case in more detail.
You can use an implicit
intent in the Just Java app
to open email app to send
off an order summary.
It didn't matter which email
app received the intent,
as long as it was an email app that
could take our message subject and
body and send it off as an email.
Remember that by specifying an intent
filter in their Android manifest file,
apps like this email app, announce which
intents they can receive and handle.
Another example of an implicit intent
is when you want to open
up a website in your app.
You can send an intent to
a browser app to show the website.
It doesn't matter which
browser up handles the intent.
They are all capable
of showing a website.
So this type of flexibility that we get
with intents is great when you aren't
sure what apps the user
has on their device.
Remember back to our
metaphor of throwing a ball
which represented our intent.
It didn't matter who we
were throwing it at,
as long as someone was there to catch it
and this represented an implicit intent.
Sometimes we want to be 100%
sure that when we send an intent
a particularly component
will receive it.
For example, within the Miwok app,
clicking on a category sends it explicit
intent that opens up a new activity
displaying vocab words in that category.
So, another example of this
is the Google Play Music app.
In the top level activity,
you see an overview of your music and
clicking on an album launches
the track container activity,
which contains a list of
tracks by a specific artist.
So this activity is within
the same music app.
In cases like these, we are using
an explicit intent, explicitly stating
exactly what activities should open when
intent is given to the Android system.
So back to the metaphor
of throwing a ball.
For explicit intents, it's like
we're shouting the name of a person
we know is on the other side and
no is open to catching the ball.
It's important to know that you should
almost never use explicit intents
to open a third party app because we
can't guarantee that the particular
third party app we intend to call is
actually installed on the device.
So, for this reason, explicit intents
are usually used within the same
application because the developer
knows what activities are available.
All right, so now we know
there's two types of intents and
let's review what's inside the ball
which represents our intent.
Implicit intents generally
need an action and a data URI.
We could also add in category,
components and extra information to help
the Android System determine which
app would best handle this request.
Implicit intents already know
where they need to go, so
it provides very specific information.
We usually just need to
pass the context and
component which is usually
the class we want to navigate to.
However, there are situations where
we may want to set the data URI so
that the other activity can
receive certain information.
Let's look at the code for
these two types of intents.
So this is an example of
an implicit intent and
an example of an explicit intent.
What similarities and
differences do you see?
For similarities, in both cases,
we create object instances of the intent
class and then we eventually pass the
intent as an input to the start activity
method and the two big differences are,
notice the different constructor inputs.
Implicit intent required an action
string such as action_view or
action_send to announce what
generic action the app is needing.
Explicit intents can directly name
the class component they need to open.
Secondly, for
implicit intents we have this resolve
activity if block which catches
cases where there aren't any apps in
the device to handle the intent request.
So to recap, for the implicit intent,
we need to create an object instance of
the intent class and in the constructor,
we pass in an action string and
in this case it's action sent to.
The implicit intent also has
this result activity if block.
On the other hand, to build and
fire off that explicit intent,
we make a new instance of the intent
class, passing in the context and
the activity we want to open.
Then we call startActivity, passing
in the intent instance we just built.
So as a disclaimer, I want to note that
this particular implicit intent example
uses intent extras, while this
explicit intent example doesn't.
But remember that both types of intents
are capable of handling intent extras.
So now let's practice
what you just learned.
In the following scenarios,
determine whether we use an implicit or
an explicit intent.
For each case, should we create
an explicit or implicit intent?
In case number one, popular group
texting apps allow users to
open video links they
receive in chat messages.
Should opening a video player use
an implicit or explicit intent?
In case number two, in a food ordering
app a user selects the dishes that she
wants to order and
clicks the submit order button.
The app then moves from the order
activity to the order summary activity.
Should moving to the order summary
activity use an implicit or
explicit intent?
And in case number three,
ride sharing apps allow users to contact
their drivers via text messaging.
Should accessing a text messaging
app on the phone use an implicit or
explicit intent?