So if someone in-between your user and
your server wants to stop them from
using your site, there are a lot
of ways they could mess with you.
So if the user can ping your IP address,
that means the blockage is not just
dropping all of their traffic to you.
So that can be a useful
thing to investigate.
Can a user access a different
domain on the same server?
Well, if they can't that suggests their
traffic isn't getting filtered by IP
address because normally two
different domains on the same server
would be on the same interface and
same IP address.
They might be getting DNS hijacked, but
this can definitely be
a good thing to investigate.
Can you send the email
from your Gmail account?
Well, when you send an email
with a service such as Gmail,
it's going to travel a very different
path from the traffic between a user and
your web server.
So this option is not
going to tell you very much.
Can they look up your server's
name using host or dig?
In other words, can they look up
your server's host name in DNS and
get back the IP address?
This can definitely distinguish certain
kinds of problems with the DNS, so
we should definitely investigate that.
And are all of the users with
the problem in the same country?
Well, that might indicate that
there is some kind of official
filtering being done.
So that's definitely a thing
to investigate as well