In this lesson,
we will review the memory management
mechanisms used in operating systems.
We will describe how operating
systems manage physical memory, and
also how they provide processes with
the illusion of virtual memory.
Let me remind you that
the intent of this course is for
us to review some of the basic
mechanisms in operating systems.
And also to serve as a refresher for
those of you who may have
forgotten some of this content
from your undergraduate classes.
My goal is for us to review some of the
key concepts, and to make it easier for
you to use additional references
like the books that I mentioned or
some online content,
in case you need to fill in any blanks