Now I could do the same thing for the
num_courses_visited field that I did for
the other two fields.
That is,
group the records by account key.
Then sum up the num_courses_visited
field for each account key.
However, if I did this, the results
would be a little bit strange.
For example, suppose this student
visited three courses their first day,
zero courses their second day,
and one course their third day.
Then the total for
this student would be four.
But that's not equal to the number of
days the student visited the classroom
at all, which is two.
And it's not equal to the number of
unique courses the student visited,
which is either three or
four, depending this was the same
course as one of these three.
Instead, I would prefer to
analyze the total number of days
each student visited
the classroom at all.
Regardless of how many courses
they visited that day.
There are a couple of ways
I could accomplish this.
First, I could change the code in
the sum_grouped_items function or
create a new similar function that
instead of adding each number up,
adds up the total number of records
where the number is greater than zero.
Alternatively, I could create a new
field in the data called has_visited,
that is either 1 or 0.
It's 1 if the student visits
the classroom at all on that day, and
0 otherwise.
If I do this, I could call the same
sum_grouped_items function that I've
already written to add up these numbers.
And what I would get is the total
number of days that the student visited
the classroom.
The second way is the way I would prefer
to use, but either one should work.
Using whichever these two methods
you prefer, calculate the mean,
standard deviation, minimum and maximum
for this number, the number of days
student visit any manner of degree
course during their first week.
Then enter your results in these boxes.