Now let's take a step back for a second, and I'm going to talk about
probabilistic letter models.
Here we have a sequence of letters,
and it looks like this sequence is rather infrequent in English.
But what can we do with letter models that we can't do
or that we can do in opposition to word models?
The answer is letter models are very good in cases
where we're going to be dealing with unique words that maybe we haven't seen before,
but they still give you properties of the language.
One very interesting task is language identification. Let's see how that would work.
Let's take some example phrases--"hello, world," "guten tag, welt," "salam dunya,"
and let's suppose you have the task of classifying these
into the language from which they were sampled from,
and we'll make this into a quiz, and we'll give you some choices--
English, German, French, Spanish, and Azerbaijani--
and tell me for each of these want your best guess is at the most likely language classification.