First, a reflection attack is
a form of man-in-the-middle attack.
This is true, because in reflection
attack, Trudy is the man in the middle.
In particular,
in order to impersonate Alice,
Trudy intercepts the message Bob sends
to Alice, and repay it back to Bob.
Second, to defeat a reflection attack,
we can use an odd number
as a challenge from the initiator and
even number from the responder.
This is true.
By doing so, Trudy cannot repay the
challenge that she received from Bob,
which is an even number, back to Bob,
because Bob is expecting an odd number.
Third, we can use signing with public
keys to achieve mutual authentication.
This is true.
We have discussed a mutual
authentication protocol
using encryption with public keys, but
you can easily modify the protocol
using signing with public keys.