Let me show this to you again.
This is exactly the same problem.
And this time, as I will traverse
the diagonal, I will find something,
jump off diagonal, come back to
the diagonal, jump off diagonal,
come back to the diagonal.
So, imagine this to be my diagonal, and
I'm jumping off, and creating loops.
There's one, of course,
I can do jumps forwards and backwards.
And now, you basically see
very simply that we can take
a video volume like this, and
traverse it in many different ways.
In essence, what we've done
is extended the time axis.
You're not bound to just the axis
of this we moved around a lot.
So, use exactly what I'm
going to show you here.
This is my diagonal, and in this way
we're going to traverse this axis, and
whenever off, you know, we find
something off diagonal we'll jump out of
this way, and keep on looping this way.
So, anytime I get these arcs
basically show possible pathways.
For example, here you notice these
jumps, and whenever the arc lights up
basically, it's going off diagonal,
and coming back to the diagonal.
So, now we've basically done
what we've set out to do,
we created infinitely
long video texture.