Hey, Catherine.
So for the numbers activity, we want to
be able to display the list of numbers
one through ten on the upstream.
Do you have any idea
how we should do this.
>> Yeah well in the last course we
talked about how you can store a single
piece of information in a variable.
>> That's right that's right.
So we can adjust.
We use an integer variable
quantity to store the number of
cups of coffee the over here.
>> Okay.
So
in this case why don't we
just use ten string variable.
Is this.
So we can have a string variable for the
number one for the number two and for
the number three and so on.
>> You have a good idea but there's
actually a better way we could do this.
>> What do you mean better.
>> There was something called an array.
>> Okay, what is that?
>> Or
it's the real hope to store a list of.
And help us maintain the order because
with a list of numbers like this,
it was easy to get mixed up in
display the information all wrong.
>> Okay that sounds good, but the since
haven't learned about a raise yet.
So we're going to need to explain that.
Do you have like an analogy or
something for that?
>> As a matter of fact I do
>> The pill box.
Where did you get that?
That totally looks like the one
my aunt has for vitamins.
>> Yeah know she might be calling soon.
>> Okay anyways.
How is the pill box like an array?
>> Well an array is like
a container of a fixed length.
So what is it created it
stays that length and so
this pill box has a length of seven.
And each slot stores a single value.
>> Wait so
I can store anything in that slot.
>> Well around storing
anything in there so
you can have your uncle's
pills in your aunt's pill box.
So once you create the ream all
about how to be of the same type.
So we have entire array of strings,
entire array Boolean,
entire array of integers.
Okay, but
what if I want to store the strings?
Like, one two and three.
>> Mmm, good point.
So, for
one you can store in the first index.
>> Okay, and then in the second slot
we would store the string two and
then third slot we would
store string three.
>> Yeah that's precisely
how the numbers go upwards
>> All right so
once we have the numbers in the slot.
We can pull all the values that we need.
>> Later on when we
need to display that.
>> Exactly.
>> Wait so
we discovered a really powerful concept.
If you want to store a list of
information you can just use an array.
Yeah, it's a good point.
But one important thing to
remember is that each element
of the array has to be
of the same data type.
>> Yeah.
And sometimes,
if you just want to store one thing,
like one string, then you can
just use an individual variable.
>> Nice.
Spot on, Kathryn.
Citing how to store your data
is known as choosing the right
data structures for your app.
When you need an array, and if you need
one, which type of array should it be?
Java is a strongly typed language.
This means that every time you
create a variable in Java you
need to specify what data type it is.
In the last course we work with basic
data types like integer and boolean but
will also work with more sophisticated
object up types like TextView
and ImageView.
You can only do certain operations
with certain data types for
example you can add two integers
With the plus operator.
But it doesn't make sense
to add two Booleans.
So when we have to set
text on a text view,
it expects a string as an input and
not an integer.
So Java will complain and
give you errors if you have
data mismatches in your code.
So to help you out we've
created this document
that discusses some primitive data
types and some object data types.
So you often hear primitive data types
referred to as the 8 basic data types
and you may recognize one such as
Int which is a whole number and
Boolean which has the values
either true or false.
So there are some new ones here that
you may not have used before, but
they may be helpful for
you to use in the future.
So for example, double is a decimal and
char is a single character.
Additionally, you'll see that string
is not listed under the Primitive
datatypes.
By now you should be familiar with
string as a text of any length.
It's actually an object of a type and
not a primitive one and
this is why we capitalize
the first letter s in string but
we don't capitalize C and Char or
b in Boolean for example.
even though string is an object data
type is treated in a special way in Java
you can automatically create a new
string by enclosing the text in quotes
instead of formally calling this
a constructor with the new keyword.
Now you can have an array
of any data type
from primitive types to object types.
So for example you can have
an array of integers And or
of characters or
even an array of floats.
Additionally we have
a right types of objects.
So we can have an array of strings or
even objects that are listed here
such as an array of TextView or
an array of buttons.
Keeping in mind what you just
learned about arrays and
what we've reviewed about data
types try to answer this quiz.
We've prepared a couple scenarios for
different apps that you may
run into as a developer.
And it's your task to decide how to
represent that information in your app.
Now given these scenarios,
what data structure would you use
to store the data in the app?
Integer, Boolean, String,
an array of integers, an array of
Strings, or maybe something else.
So the first scenario is for
a Travel app.
And you're storing items the pack for
traveling.
The second scenario is for
a YouTube app you want to know the
number of people who viewed that video.
The third scenario for
a Settings app and
you want to store the languages
supported on an Android device.
The fourth one, for a shopping app.
You want to know whether
a product is in stock or not.
For a fifth scenario, for a lottery app.
The winning combinations of five numbers
for a single round of the lottery.
I the last scenario for you to
determine what data structures to use.
For Health track app.
The number of miles or
kilometers walk for each day this week.