In the following quiz,
you'll write code for
a function called word_in_pos, which
stands for word in parts of speech.
The function takes in a string word, and
the list, parts_of_speech, as inputs.
If there is a word in parts_of_speech
that is a substring of word,
then you'll be asked to return
that word, else return none.
So if my word is equal to "NOUN", and my
parts_of_speech is a list that contains
the strings ["VERB", "NOUN",, and
"PLACE"], and pass both both of these
into my word_in_pos function, I’ll
be returned with the string, "NOUN".
However, if I were to pass in the same
list, but this time word would be
I would be returned with "PLACE".
We'll use this function in our final Mad
Libs generator by passing the current
iteration of Mad Lib Into this function
with the parts of speech
list that we're using.
If we receive none,
we know that the word we pass
in isn't in parts of speech, so
we can just add the iteration, or word
we're looking at, to our list replaced.
If it is, however,
we'll be returned with the part
of speech we want to replace.
So we'll replace the part of
speech with the user input so
we can keep the punctuation.
And then we'll add it
to our replaced list.
All right, good luck.