Let's walk through
each of these steps so
that you can see how to localize
the strings in your app.
First we want to extract all
the hardcoded strings from the XML and
Java files into a default
strings.xml file.
Then we're going to update the XML and
Java files to refer to
the appropriate string resources.
And then we're going to provide
alternate translations in another
language.
Let's start with step one.
In our activity_main layout,
let's look at the strings that
are currently hardcoded into our layout.
We have a TextView that displays
the word Toppings as a header in the UI.
Currently, the English word is
hardcoded into the layout, and
we even get a warning from
the Android Studio talking about it.
It recommends that we use a @string
resource, so let's do that now.
When I delete this, and
then type in @string/toppings
as the name of the resource.
But now I get an error saying that
Android Studio doesn't recognize
this resource.
I need to go into the strings.xml
file and define it.
Looking at the file
structure of our app,
I can go into the res values folder and
look for the strings.xml file.
There are a couple of strings that
are already populated here and
I'm going to add another one.
I just declared a new string
resource with the name toppings.
And the value is the English word for
toppings.
The name of the string resource
isn't going to change, but
the translated value will change
depending on the language.
Notice that I added a comment
here to describe where
the string is being used in the app.
This will help the translator, or the
translation service who's helping out,
to understand the context in which
this string is being used in our app.
We also specify a character limit.
This is also helpful for the translator
when space in the UI is limited.
For example, the translator won't
pick a really long translation
if they understand that we have
limited screen real estate.
Going back to our layout file,
now the error is gone because
this string resource exists.