When you buy a component from somebody else,
you're giving up your competitive advantage.
You didn't build it yourself, so you can't put into it the bells and
whistles that might give you that advantage.
On the other hand, the vendor can concentrate all their energy on that
particular component and come up with a super-specialized version.
So that's an, an advantage of buying.
Your development costs may also go down.
That is, the vendor can apply economies of scale,
thereby reducing the price you have to pay for that, that component.
However, dealing with a vendor is a third party relationship, and
the channels of communication that you have with the vendor may not be as
effective as the ones you would have if you did in-house development.