Let's look at this, and now with
a specific set of examples and images.
Here of course I have given you two
images, this comes from a very famous
data set that has been collected
by computer vision researchers for
years now to do real hardcore
analysis of stereo algorithms.
I'm basically showing you two images,
left and right.
Left image and the right image
basically are, you know, shown here and
now using this,
this depth could be computed.
I haven't told you how
to compute depth yet but
we'll get there in a bit,
specifically for images like this.
But you know how to do it if I
could find the same points and
do those two images, right?
To compute the disparity that is.
Here you see a couple
of interesting things.
You see, of course, a few dark
points here, this is where for
example no information was available.
Remember when I showed you
the images of the child earlier,
you just saw a lot of black image and
black points in those images.
Again, those were, again, but
there's no information available
partly because two images cannot just
actually see those points clearly.
Partly, the reason it can't see these
kinds of things is that each and
every pixel has to be
visible from both cameras.
This image basically is also
referred to as a disparity image or
disparity values.
And here basically we're showing
gray values form zero to 64.
Zero, of course, no information or
no disparity, 64 most.
And, of course, if you look at
it in this context it means that
basically anything that's
closer is you know, and
farther is lower values,
closer values are higher.