Now the final mystery is what
all of these arguments do.
You'll also notice I haven't really
told you how to specify what
content provider you actually
want to access or what table or
rows that you're changing,
inserting, or reading.
To specify what data you're
actually interested in reading or
manipulating, you need to learn about
an additional object called a URI.
URI stands for
Uniform Resource Identifier.
URLs are a subset of URIs that
are specifically met to identify network
locations such as websites and
files on the Web.
A URI is used to specifically identify
or give the location of some data.
In this case, on your phone.
Let's see how the URI encodes
the location of an exact
piece of data on your phone.
This object here in the code is a URI
and I'm getting it from the contract.
I'm going to then use a log statement to
see what this URI actually looks like.
Let's go ahead and run that.
So here the app is loaded up.
And if I look in here, I could see
what the value of the URI was.
This location is how you know exactly
what type of data you're querying for.
The first part, content://,
is the standard way to start
URIs in an Android app.
This is similar to how http:// or
https:// is a prefix for a Web URL.
The
com.example.udacity.droidtermsexample
is a critically important part of
the URI which specifies which content
provider to actually use.
It's called the content
authority of the URI.
And this is how the content resolver
knows which one of the many
content providers to
actually communicate with.
After the content:// and
the content authority,
is a string that identifies exactly
what data in the content provider that
you're interested in accessing.
The structure of this string,
known as the path,
will be specific to
the content provider.
And, in our case, what we
are trying to do is access all of
the terms which are stored
to the content provider.
So that's what's appended here.
So within the URI is
the following information.
It says, I'm a URI for
content providers on Android.
And I'm accessing this specific
droidtermexample provider and
I'm only interested in the list of
terms stored in droidtermsexample data.
Now you might be scuffing right now and
going, but Lila, how would I know what
the structure of these URIs is
even supposed to look like?
I'm not a mind reader,
and yes that is right.
You are not a mind reader,
which is why if the designer of the
content provider followed conventions,
which they hopefully did, they
should have created a contact class.
Here I am looking at the docs for
DroidTermsExample provider.
And here is documentation for
a DroidTermsExampleContract class.
This is the same type of contract class
like you make when you're working with
databases.
If we scroll down, we see that
along with all these constants for
the different columns in the database,
the contract also contains
information about URIs.
If we scroll down a little bit more,
we see this CONTENT_URI right here,
which is a premade URI that is
usually included in contract classes.
Here's the contract for
the CalendarContent provider.
And we can see that it
also has a CONTENT_URI.
I linked this contract to the notes,
and also the DroidTermsExampleContract.
Okay, so
let's review what all of this code does.
The first line gets the content
resolver for the query.
The second line calls the query
method on that resolver.
And using the query method is specifying
that we're performing a raid operation.
To that query method, you pass a URI.
The URI defines the exact data
you're trying to read or manipulate.
The rest of the query method, for now,
will take a bunch of null parameters.
We'll talk about these shortly.
In the meantime though, Susanna's
going to give you a few more quizzes for
review.