And finally this example based on 4-grams--
Now we're seeing an even longer structure.
Sometimes we have this generate something that makes sense like
"betwixt their two estates,"
and this is not something that appears in Shakespeare,
but it was just generated and it made sense.
Sometimes we get things that are actually quotes like "even to the frozen ridges of the alps."
The model chose to duplicate something that is actually in Shakespeare.
Certainly there were lots of traces it could have made.
"Alps" appears four or five times.
"Even" appears many, many times.
"Frozen" appears multiple times.
But it just happened to duplicate something that was a quotation from the original.
And then there's lots of examples of sentences and phrases that make a lot of sense--
"I know my duty," and "give me some little breath," and so on.
So it looks like even though all we know is a sequence of 4 woeds,
We're still capturing quite a bit of what it means to have coherent sentences but not everything.