2 treatment price points were tested,
87.99 and
76.99 versus the control price of 98.99.
Having done two tests,
we're going to analyze each price point.
The results of each will be compared
to each other focusing on gross margin
performance.
We're going to use the two datasets
that we previously created.
The control treatment pairs data will
be used to provide identification data
concerning which stores were
controller treatment units and
the store sales analysis data will
be used to provide performance data
associated with the control,
and treatment stores.
Using input data tools, let's bring both
data sets into a new Altiris workflow.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Since we conducted two tests,
one at 87.99 and the other 76.99, we
need to split the control treatment pair
data into 2 streams 1 for each test.
Let's drag a filter tool
on to the Canvas and
we'll use a basic filter
of test group equals 87.99.
This will result in the true output
streaming the data for the 87.99 test,
then the false output streaming data for
the 76.99 test.
Next, let's drag an A/B Analysis
tool onto the Canvas.
The A/B Analysis tool will provide
reports that detail how the treatment
units performed versus
the control units for a test.
First, connect the filter tool true
output to the A/B Analysis C and
T inputs.
The C input is the controls input
that provides the A/B Analysis tool
with a unique identifier for
each control unit.
The T input is a treatment input
that provides an identifier are for
treatment inputs.
The T input provides an identifier for
the treatment units.
Since all of the data for the treatment
and control stores is in the data
stream, we can connect the filter
output to both the C and T inputs.
First, we're going to setup the 87.99
analysis and we'll repeat the steps for
the 76.99 group.
So, let's connect the sales
data to the P input.
The P input provides
the A/B Analysis tool
with performance data associated with
the control and treatment units.
So let's configure
the A/B Analysis tool.
In the control section, select
the control's field for the control unit
identifier and the treatment's field for
the treatment unit mapping field.
In the treatment section,
select the treatment's field as
the treatment unit identifier.
In the performance data section,
will you store as the unit identifier?
Weekend is the reporting period date and
gross margin as the performance measure.
Clicking on the Test Dates tab,
we need to enter the dates of the test.
Note that this test refers to
the dates of the experiment and
not the dates of the data we have.
Since we ran the test from March 20th,
2014,
until May 28, 2014,
we'll enter those dates here.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The additional information tab can be
used to add text for the report output,
but we'll leave that blank for
this example.
And similarly, the graphics option tab
can be used to adjust the report and
automatically save it, but
we'll let you explore those features.
After repeating the steps for
the 7699 test,
we'll add a Browse tool to the I
output of both A/B Analysis tools.
The I output produces an HTML based
interactive dashboard
of the test results.
We'll also add a browse tool to the O
output of both A/B Analysis tools.
The O output produces a textual
summary of the test results,
basic summary statistics and a few
visualizations related to the results.
Now, we can run the workflow to
produce the textual and HTML reports.