Now that we have actually looked at how
we can estimate the camera paths, let's
talk about how we can go to figuring
out how to stabilize this camera path.
So, again, I'm just showing
you these paths as before.
What we're interested in now is
approximately find a path that as stable
is possible.
Here we refer back to some of
the simple cinematography principles.
That is what are the best properties
of a stable path of a camera?
Well, if I had a tripod and
this was my, you know,
degree of freedom etc,
of the path itself,
what I basically assume is that green
line here will keep the camera stable.
Right?
There would be no changes in the degrees
of freedom in x and y here,
so that would be my path.
So, I need to find
a smooth path like this.
Then the second one would basically be
I'm putting it on some sort of a railing
and moving it around, so
that would be a dolly or a pan.
This, in this case of differential,
it would be a linear segment.
So, again, we have the red
path is the original one.
We now added constraints to it and
found a path that has the yellows and
the greens.
And then basically, we need to
start dealing with the ease in and
outs, which would be this and this.
And here, it would be this here.
So these ease in and out with respect
to all of this kind of start giving me
a set of different constraints and
different paths moving functions
on the red line itself.
That's what we want to do in figuring
out how we want to smooth the path.
So what we basically do is look at
these different types of models and
use that as a constraint
on the path itself.
And again, we do this with various
types of smoothing algorithms.
Again, I refer you to the paper
that allows us to do this much more
efficiently.
So now, let's look at what this means.
Basically, what we are interested in is
finding a crop window within a frame,
which is for example, this.
And what that basically means
is that there's a path.
This whole window itself basically
is the envelope in this path
right here, right?
So for example,
I just made this small and
this is the whole region that I
can actually cover within it and
as long as I keep myself within this
region, I would be actually able to find
the best possible crop window that
traverses through this range.
Let's look at that again.
So here basically,
this size kind of defines the window,
the envelope in this thing.