[Norvig] So I've talked about the possibility axioms and the successor state axioms.
That's most of what's in situation calculus,
and that's used to describe an entire domain like the airport cargo domain.
And now we describe a particular problem within that domain by describing the initial state.
Typically we call that S0, the initial situation.
And in S0 we can make various types of assertions
of different types of predicates.
So we could say that plane P1 is at airport JFK in S0, so just a simple predicate.
And we could also make larger sentences, so we could say
for all C, if C is cargo, then that C is at JFK in situation S0.
So we have much more flexibility in situation calculus to say almost anything we want.
Anything that's a valid sentence in first order logic can be asserted about the initial state.
The goal state is similar.
We could have a goal of saying there exists some goal state S
such that for all C, if C is cargo, then we want that cargo to be at SFO in state S.
So this initial state and this goal says move all the cargo--
I don't care how much there is--from JFK to SFO.
The great thing about situation calculus is that once we've described this
in the ordinary language of first order logic,
we don't need any special programs to manipulate it and come up with the solution
because we already have theorem provers for first order logic
and we can just state this as a problem,
apply the normal theorem prover that we already had for other uses,
and it can come up with an answer of a path that satisfies this goal,
a situation which corresponds to a path which satisfies this
given the initial state and given the descriptions of the actions.
So the advantage of situation calculus is that we have the full power of first order logic.
We can represent anything we want.
Much more flexibility than in problem solving or classical planning.
So all together now, we've seen several ways of dealing with planning.
We started in deterministic, fully observable environments
and we moved into stochastic and partially observable environments.
We were able to distinguish between plans that can or cannot solve a problem,
but we had 1 weakness in all these different approaches.
It is that we weren't able to distinguish between probable and improbable solutions.
And that will be the subject of the next unit.