For the remainder of this unit,
I am going to talk about linear dimensionality reduction.
Where the idea is that the given data points like this,
and we seek to find a linear subspace in which to perfect the data.
In this case, I would submit this is probably the most suitable linear subspace.
So we remap the data onto the space over here, with x1 over here and x2 over here.
Then we can capture the data in just 1 dimension.
The algorithm is amazingly simple.
Number 1: Fit a gaussian; we now know how this works.
The gaussian will look something like this.
Number 2: Caluclate the eigenvalues and eigenvectors of this gaussian.
In this gaussian this would be the dominant eigenvector,
and this would be the 2nd eigenvector over here.
Step 3 is take those eigenvectors whose eigenvalues are the largest.
Step 4 is to project the data onto the subspace of eigenvectors you chose.
Now to understand this, you have to be familiar with eigenvectors and eigenvalues.
I give you an intuitive familiarity with those.
This is standard statistics material, and you will find this in many linear algebra classes.
So let me just go through this very quickly
and give you an intuition how to do linear dimensionality reduction.
Suppose you're given the following data points:
Your axes are 0, 1, 2, 3, and 4,
4 x1, and 1.9, 3.1, 4, 5.1, and 5.9.
These are essentially 2, 3, 4, 5, 6,
but slightly modified to define actual variance over this dimension.
So I draw this in here.
What I get is a set of points that doesn't quite fit a line, but almost.
There is a little error over here, a little error over here, and here and here.
The mean is easily calculated; it's 2 and 4.
The covairance matrix looks as follows.
Notice the slightly different covairance for the 1st variable, which is exactly 2,
to the 2nd variable, which is 2.008.
The eigenvectors happen to be 0.7064 and 0.7078 with an eigenvalue of 4.004,
and the 2nd one is orthogonal with an eigenvalue much smaller.
So obviously this is the eigenvector that dominates the spread of the data points.
If you look at this vector over here, it is centered around the mean,
which sits over here, and is exactly this vector shown over here.
Where this one is the orthogonal vector shown over here.
So this single dimension with a large weight explains the data relative to
any other dimension, which is a very small eidenvalue.
I should mention why these numerical examples might look confusing.
This is very standard linear algebra.
When you estimate covariance from data and try to understand which direction they point,
this kind of eigenvalue anylysis gives you the right answer.