You'll notice that when I
re ran the application,
it didn't require us to build again.
And that's because break points
are created by the debugger itself and
they're not part of your
application source.
On the main screen, I'll select
the break point debugging scene.
And then,
I'll tap the screen to create a spider.
As soon as I tap, we're immediately
redirected back to Xcode.
What's happening?
First, don't be alarmed, your
application's actually still running.
But the execution's been
paused at this break point.
With your app paused,
we can now use Xcode's debugging
tools to inspect our code.
At the bottom of Xcode,
the debug area is revealed, and
the bottom is split into two views.
We have the variables view on the left,
and the console on the right.
And you can re-veil the debug area
by clicking on this button here.
Like so, or
by using the hot key Shift + Cmd + Y.
Personally, I always like to reveal
the debug area when I'm running
applications.
To enable this feature, go back to
X code, and then go to preferences.
Go to behaviors, and in behaviors
you want to look for running,
the running section here, and then look
for the Starts option and select it.
And then check the box here
that says selection, show,
debugger with variables and
Console views.
So like it reads when your
application starts running,
we'll show the debugger
with these two views.
With the debug area revealed you can use
the two buttons in the bottom right hand
corner to hide the variables view,
and hide the console view.
In the variables view on the left,
we can see all the variables that
are visible in the current view mode.
The default view mode is Auto.
Auto shows variables that are currently
in scope that the debugger thinks you're
most likely interested in, given the
context and current line of execution.
The other view modes include local
variables and all variables, registers,
globals, and statics.
The local variables view
mode shows the variables and
arguments that have been declared
in the current function or
block, as well as
the special variable self.
Self is also usually displayed
in the auto mode and
it's an alias to the object whose
function or blocks been called.
So in this case, self refers to
a breakpoint bug viewController.
And it contains all the values and
properties of this breakpoint
bug view controller.
The last view mode displays everything.
This includes local variables,
globals, and even registers.
Typically, auto or
local view modes will be all that
you need when you're debugging.
However, this mode's
here if you need it.
So we'll go back to auto.
On the right is the console.
And right now the only thing in
the console are the letters LLDB
in parenthesis.
These letters refer to the LLDB
debugger or low level debugger.
Here, we're able to type
any valid LLDB commands.
And we'll talk more in depth about these
commands and LLDB later in the course.
Back in the main area,
we've already seen that we can
toggle our breakpoints on and off.
So this time let's set this breakpoint
inactive, and then click on this button
here in the debugging bar to
continue the program's execution.
Once the app becomes active, I'll tap
the screen, and this time the execution
doesn't pause when I tap on the screen
because the Breakpoint's disabled.
But you've probably also
noticed there's a problem.
Our spiders are not appearing
on the screen again.
And to figure out why we have this
problem, we'll make use of breakpoints,
the variables view, and
something called a stack frame next.