So far we have seen how OCL is used to specify invariants and
operations. There is another part of our analysis model that OCL can help with.
That's derive data. There were two places in the [UNKNOWN] model for
the library, where derive data, was used. The Patron's age and the amount of
the overdue fine. Remember that derive data are, they're attributes,
like any other attributes but, they're going to be computed along the way,
rather than something that is a, is a set piece of data. Okay?
And the, the situation here had to do, for example, with the, Patron's age,
which is changing on a day to day basis. So, at any moment when we need the age,
we compute the value. Okay, so we need to say what value is being computed. And
the same, the same holds true for the amount of fine which changes on a day to
day basis, and depending upon how long your book is overdue. So let's,
let's do a little exercise here.
See if you can come up with a constraint in OCL or a Patron's age.
And as a hint here, there's a keyword in, in OCL called derive, and
you use that instead of pre or post interim variant. See if you can express it.