Let's see if you can connect time,
energy, and
power as a function of the algorithm
a little bit more directly.
Here's the main high level
difference between time and energy.
You can reduce time by hiding it or
overlapping it using, for example,
parallelism.
Energy is different.
With respect to energy,
every operation has some energy cost and
you have to pay for
that cost for every operation.
Now let's go back to our
simplest model of parallelism.
That was the work-span or
multi-threaded DAG model.
In that model,
you had a bunch of abstract algorithmic
costs that you thought about.
Do you remember them?
One was work, another was span.
There was also the ratio
of work to span,
or the average available parallelism.
There was also the execution
time given P processors.
For time, we had both lower bounds and
upper bounds, the upper bound
coming from Brent's theorem.
And there was also Speedup.
Note, that this definition of
Speedup is a little bit relaxed
in the sense that it's (Self-) Speedup.
For (Self-) Speedup, I don't use the
best sequential time in the numerator.
Instead, I use the time of
the parallel algorithm when
run on a single processor.
But remember, if your algorithm is
work optimal, then self speed-up and
conventional speed-up relative
to the best sequential case
are basically the same, asymptotically.
Okay, my question is this.
Of these five five measures,
which one is the best metric
to use to quantify energy?
Now, think about these
informal definitions and
your options carefully
before you answer.
And I want you to
choose just one option.