Creating loaders is
actually pretty simple.
We start off by creating an integer
constant for a loader ID.
Then, we implement
the loader call backs.
Finally, we initialize the loader
with the loaderManager.
Let's take a look at what we
do to replace our async task
with an async task loader in
the second git hub query exercise.
The first task is to have
main activity implement
the LoaderManager.LoaderCallbacks,with
type string.
We'll import the class, and
then have Android Studio override
the rest of the LoaderCallbacks for us.
Then, we create the GITHUB_SEARCH_LOADER
constant int to uniquely identify
the loader.
Next, we remove the call
to execute the async task.
Since loader's taken
Android Bundle as their argument,
we'll create a bundle that contains our
search query as SEARCH_QUERY_URL_EXTRA.
Then, we fill in those LoaderCallbacks
beginning with onCreateLoader.
We'll return a new
AsyncTaskLoader with type String.
And let Android Studio import the class,
as well as override the required
loadInBackground for us.
We'll override onStartLoading.
If the argument bundle is null,
we'll just return.
We'll set the args to
final in onCreateLoader so
we can access them from
our inner class function.
Then we'll move the code from
onPreExecute to onStartLoading,
to set the LoadingIndicator to VISIBLE.
Next, we'll fill in loadInBackground
which I've already had
Android Studio override.
First, we'll get the string for
our URL from the bundle we just created.
And if the URL is null or
empty, we'll return null.
Next, we'll copy the try catch block
from the async task to do in background,
to loadInBackground.
And we'll fix things
up to make it compile.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Creating a new URL from our string,
And passing it to our
getResponse function.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Finally, if we get an exception,
we just return null.
Next, we copy the code from
onPostExecute, to onLoadFinished.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
After all, if the user didn't enter
anything, there's nothing to search for.
So we want the error message to
work the same way it did before.
Finally, we use the loaderManager to run
our loader within makeGithubSearchQuery.
We begin by getting the support
library version of the loaderManager.
Then, we try to get our loader.
If the loader doesn't exist,
we initialize it.
Otherwise, we restart it.
This is different from
the traditional loader flow,
because we only execute the loader
after the user hits the query button,
rather than when
the activity is created.
Also note that technically, we don't
have to do this because restartLoader
will create the loader if it doesn't yet
exist, but
this makes the code a bit clearer.
Finally, we remove the code
that retrieves and
displays the JSON from
the saved instance state.
And the code that persists to JSON,
then Solota will handle that for us.