Hey Asser.
>> Why are you wearing this weird coat?
>> Well funny you ask, I'm actually
traveling to Seattle to visit some
relatives and unlike here they
have this weird thing called rain.
Now I was actually able to use
Sunshine's location preference
to see that inclement
weather long in advance.
>> Right and I finally got my
temperature to show in Celsius degrees.
>> Cool,
now these are just some examples
of preferences you can implement.
The skills you learned in this lesson,
you can now quickly make preference
screens for your own apps.
>> You also learned about
shared preferences,
which is your first taste of
data persistence on Android.
Hopefully it tasted good because we
will be learning a lot more about data
persistence in the next lessons.
>> But for now take a break, stretch,
and maybe even enjoy the sunshine.
[SOUND]