So let's take a look at a diagram
of our current situation.
So right now our editor and catalog
activities are both directly calling
into PetDbHelper in order
to access the database.
So for example,
we can directly access the PetDbHelper
in order to insert a new pet which has
a weight of 7kg into the database.
And the PetDbHelper will help us insert
that pet directly into the database.
So this set up works well if we know the
information we're inserting is correct.
However, what if we have a typo and
say we accidentally insert
bad data into the activity.
So in this example,
if we enter a new pet.
But actually type in a negative
weight value of 10 kg,
well this direct interaction method
has a pitfall of inserting invalid
data directly into our database.
So we would end up inserting that
negative 10 value directly into
the database.
Now this is where the content
provider comes in.
We can centralize the accessing and
editing of the data via
the content provider.
So in this schema, our UI code will
then directly interact with the content
provider instead of directly
interacting with the database.
The content provider, as a layer of
data validation, which we saw we needed,
when we incorrectly entered
invalid weight values.
So, if there ends up being a bug,
we can catch it here.
So, the content provider, as this added
layer between the data source and
UI code, is called an abstraction layer.
And this is because the content
provider abstracts the way or
hides the details of
how the data is stored.
So the UI code just communicates with
the provider for any access to the data.
And it doesn't need to care about
the internals of how the provider is
getting this job done.
So in other words,
the content provider black-boxes
the underlying data from the UI.
Because the UI doesn't care if
the data is stored in a database or
in individual text files.
We could even store photo files,
and the content provider could
perfectly handle interacting with
the UI code in order to display those.
So in a later version of the app, if you
decided to swap out the database for
a different type of storage, the UI
code would still remain the same, and
continue talking to
the existing content provider.
So in addition to the database,
if we were to add photo files for
each pet, this could work as well.
Or even if the data were stored as text
files, instead of the database along
with photo files, our content
provider could handle that as well.
Now you might be thinking, wow,
the content provider sounds great, but
how does it go about
interacting with my UI?
So the UI code interacts
with the provider
by using various methods such
as query in order to get data.
There's insert as well as update, used
to update the existing rows of data.
And lastly delete,
used to delete rows of data.
Now, notice all these methods
are similar to database methods that we
used before.
In all these CRUD operations,
the UI code calls that
method to the content provider,
and that content provider itself,
calls its own form of the code
to the data source itself.
Now, let's take a moment to pause and
summarize what we've covered,
because it's big.
So first off,
the content provider helps us manage
access to a structured set of data.
So they can act as
a good abstraction layer
between the data source and the UI code.
Which can add data validation,
help us modify how the data is stored,
while the UI code
remaining is unaffected.
Now this brings me to the next big
advantage of counter providers I want to
discuss.
So what is it?
Well, they work well with
other framework classes.
So to explain what that means, so
take a look at this list of pets here.
So currently if pets are added or
removed, and
we want the latest information displayed
in the UI, we must call the query and
insert method each time.
Well, instead of doing
it that tedious method,
we can leverage the power of a framework
class called the Cursor Loader.
So when pets are added or
removed to this list, the list will
stay updated via our Cursor Loader.
Which will automatically check when any
changes have been made in the data, and
then automatically refresh the list
when that data does change.
So the Cursor Loader works in
conjunction with the ListView and
the Cursor Adapter,
which we covered in the last course.
And doing so, these display
the changes that are made in the list.
So implementing the Cursor Loader
requires use of the content provider.
So content providers and cursor
loaders make our lives a lot easier
because we don't need to
manually query the data over and
over again,
If any changes are made to it.
So to recap that second big advantage,
content providers work well
with other framework classes.
So we just saw an example of
how it helps automate how data
in a list is refreshed.
Well, it also works with
home screen widgets,
something called sync adapters
that sync our data to the cloud.
As well as provides search
suggestions in your app.
So the framework team wanted
to make content providers
a consistent way to manage access to
a structured set of data in android.
And without it, you'd have to admin
a lot of that functionality on your own.
So we'll be seeing more of how all
these plays out in lesson four.
After we have spent much
more time in lesson three,
setting up the content provider.
Now there's one more big
advantage I want to discuss, and
that's sharing data.
So when you have text data or
files inside your app,
currently no other apps can access it.
So in the case of our Pet shelter app,
this information is siloed and
say there's a vets app or
adoptions app or even a pet lovers app.
Well, they can't have access
to our existing database.
Well, we can expose our data to these
other apps using a content provider.
Doing so, other apps can access this
information by interacting with
the provider using the same query,
insert, update, and delete methods.
Well doing so
could be a security concern.
Because maybe you don't want
a particular app to access and
modify all your app data.
Potentially, a malicious app could
delete an entire database table.
So opening up your data to other apps,
could be dangerous if not done properly.
Well again,
the framework team has this covered.
The content provider manages
access to data in a secure way.
If you want other apps to prompt
the user to grant certain permission
to access the data, then the content
provider can help enforce this.
So, other apps without proper permission
won't be able to access the data.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So, to summarize the three points that
I want to call out of why content
providers are pretty awesome.
Is it they act as a good abstraction
layer between our data source and
our UI code,
helping us with data validation.
Secondly, they help us work well
with other framework classes.
And lastly, they help us easily
share data with other apps.
So for this exercise, I like you to
go ahead and check the boxes for
the accurate reasons of
using a content provider.
I've listed six here.
So do they help share data
more easily with other apps?
Do they directly improve
an app's performance?
Perhaps they provide a good
abstraction layer, or
maybe they only manage
access to text data.
Maybe they also work well with
other Android framework classes, or
maybe content providers are only written
in XML, and that might be good for us.