Okay, let's look at these guys.
Now remember,
these aren't instructions that are meant
to be followed together, they're
different ways that you can substantiate
the declare currentlyPlaying.
So, let's look at each
of them separately.
Okay, the first one,
everything is almost perfect but
there's one tiny thing missing and it's
the quote that matches this one here.
Much like our curly braces,
parentheses, and
XML tags, you always need to put
quotes at the ends of the string.
Okay, let's look at this next one.
As we discussed in the last problem,
capitalization matters.
And there's something wrong here.
String is always
a capitalized data type.
Now we'll discuss this a little
bit in the next lesson, but
String is not a primary
data type like int.
It's actually something called a object.
Again we'll talk about it more later,
but
with String you always
need it to be capitalized.
And once you capitalize String,
this would work fine.
And here, this one is almost fine,
there's just one tiny problem.
Can you see it?
All right.
Hopefully you caught it.
There should be a semicolon
at the end here.
As always, you should remember to finish
your Java statements with semicolons and
close all of your strings with quotes.
You don't want something bad to happen.