Conceptually, an Euler Tour
is fairly simple, but
there's some important details.
For example,
how should you store the tree, and
how should you compute the tour?
Here's one scheme.
Start with a version of the tree
in which you represent each
undirected edge by a pair
of directed edges.
For each node v,
we'll define its adjacency list to be
the set of its outgoing neighbors.
Here, d sub v is the number
of v's outgoing neighbors.
For example, here's the full
set of adjacency lists or
the adjacency table
representation of this tree.
Take vertex 1.
It points to 4, 5, 6 and 0.
Its out-degree is 4.
Its entry in the adjacency list or
adjacency table has these
four neighbors as well.
D sub v is 4 for this vertex.
Now to compute the Euler Tour, we're
going to define a special function.
That function is called
the Successor function.
Here's its formal definition.
Given an edge that goes from ui to v,
the Successor functions returns the next
neighbor in v's adjacency list.
Notice the modulo operation.
That operation effectively makes
the adjacency list circular.
Let's look at an example.
Consider the 0, 1 edge.
Let's apply the Successor
function to it.
Recall the definition of the Successor.
It tells you that applying s
to 0,1 is the same as this.
So what will the next edge be?
That's right, it will be v, u0.
In other words, the 1,4 edge.
To make sure you've got the hang of it,
let's do it once more.
Apply s to 1,4.
Remember the definition of s.
This gets you to the edge,
returning 2,1 from 4.
If you keep going, you'll end up
traversing the entire Euler circuit.
A good exercise is to prove this fact.
The key observation is that
this successor function
flips the relative positions of u and v.
If you get stuck trying to
convince yourself of this fact,
try heading to the online forums and
see if your peers can help you out.
Now one important
implementation detail remains.
Is the cost of applying
the Successor function constant?
Because if it's not,
then you can't claim that an Euler Tour
is possible in linear work.
Here's the problem that
should give you some doubts.
Suppose you recently
visited the 1,6 edge.
You want to apply
the Successor function.
That means you need a fast way
to jump from here to here.
Otherwise, you can't
apply the Successor.
An easy way to do this is to augment the
data structure with some extra pointers.
In fact, you can do that cheaply when
you're creating the adjacency list
data structure.
If you insert all these cross-edges,
you'll get something
that looks like this.
Egads, what a mess!
But anyway, I hope you're convinced
that it's at least doable.