The next step is to add a second
Horizontal Stack View, so that it can
hold buttons for playing the recorded
audio with high and low pitches.
With the Main.storyboard file open,
select the Play Sounds View Controller.
Let's search for “stack view” in the object library.
Drag a Horizontal Stack View
from the object library into the
Document Outline. Make sure that it's
embedded inside of the Vertical Stack View
our outermost stack view in the
Document Outline and under the first
Horizontal Stack View. Perfect.
Your Document Outline should look
similar to what you see here.
One more thing. With this new Horizontal Stack
View selected, change its Distribution
setting and the attributes inspector to
Fill Equally. There we go. Now let's add
some more buttons. Back in the object
library, start typing “button”.
Drag a button to the new Horizontal Stack View.
In the attributes inspector, remove the
buttons title text. So we'll delete that
and press Enter.
There we go. And change its image to HighPitch,
which is the chipmunk image.
It's all the same steps for the Low Pitch button.
Drag our new button below
the High Pitch button, remove its title
text and this time we'll change the
image to LowPitch which is an image of
Darth Vader. I’m also going to rename the
buttons to High Pitch button and
Low Pitch button. Once you're done, your
Document Outline should look similar to
this.
I should mention that the hierarchy and
order seen here is important. If I were
to rearrange the fast and slow button,
we'd see them change their position in
the stack view. With the Fast Button
positioned above the Slow Button and the
stack view laying things out
horizontally, now we see moving left to
right first the Fast Button and then the
Slow Button. So for horizontal stack views,
the order moves from left to right.
For Vertical Stack Views, the order moves
from top to bottom. So if I rearranged
these stack views, we could change the row’s
positioning. Right now the first row is the
Fast and Slow button. If I move the stack
view below, this now becomes the second
row and our first row now has the High
Pitch and Low Pitch buttons.
Let's return things back to what we had.
There we go. Now you have four buttons in
this view perfectly aligned, and we have
not had to add a single AutoLayout
Constraint. That's pretty awesome.