So earlier when I said
the CursorAdapter contains instructions
on how to make a list item view,
well, what exactly does that entail?
Well, let's dive in and
explore this area in more detail.
So let's assume that the list
view just requested for
the list item at position 0.
So now the Cursor Adapter needs to
first create a blank list item.
And this involves inflating
one from the XML Layout.
So the layout that we want
contains a vertical linear layout
with two text views.
One that looks like this.
Then we'll need to populate
these two text views
with the correct data from the cursor.
So since we're interested in
the pet at position zero,
we'll move the cursor to row zero.
And then we extract out the name column,
which turns out to be Tommy, and
set that to the first text view.
Afterwards, we'll extract
the breed column, and
get the breed to be Pomeranian, and
set that to our second text view.
Now in the list view requests for
the list item at position one,
we'll also need to create
another blank list item.
Then we'll also move
the cursor to position one and
then again bind the data from
this cursor on to the views.
So say we have a name of Garfield and
a breed of Tabby.
So in code, this two steps can
be separated into two methods,
first the newView method and
then the bindView method.
So the cursor adapter class is
actually an abstract class,
which means that not all
the methods are complete.
And that also means that we need
to create our own custom class.
So, for example, we could call
it the pet cursor adapter and
extend that from
the cursor adapter class.
Then we'll need to write code that
implements the logic for the newView and
bindView methods.
So sometimes the newView method
might not even be called.
And in those cases,
the bindView method is called using
an old view from a previous pet.
For example, the user may have scrolled
the Tommy list item view off the screen.
And that means that we can recycle
that list item view, and use it for
another pet in this list that is
about to be scrolled onto the screen.
So we set different values
onto these text views, and
then show this view on screen again.
And so that's why it's
useful to have a newView and
bindView method be two separate methods.
So in our case,
we're going to be creating a class
called the PetCursorAdapter class,
which, like I mentioned before, will
extend from the CursorAdapter class.
Notice that it contains a constructor,
which just calls
the superclass constructor in
order to initialize itself.
Then, we as developers need to fill in
the newView method, which creates and
returns a blank new list item for
the current row being
pointed to by the cursor.
And we also need to fill in the bindView
method in order to read data from
the current row in the cursor and set it
to the views within this list item view.
So the cursor adapter class
handles some of the logic for
us, such as moving the cursor to the
correct position, so that we don't need
to move the cursor to the correct
position within these two methods.
So to show you an example of
a fully implemented cursor adapter,
let's take a look at an online tutorial.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So this tutorial is from code path and
explains how to populate a list
view with a cursor adapter.
So the goal of the example
that will be shown below
is to show a to-do list
in the Adapter View.
So in this situation, the Adapter View
is a List View, and it's using
the Adapter to pool information from
a data source, which will be a cursor.
So let's assume that
the cursor looks like this.
So each to-do item has a body for
the task description,
as well as a numerical priority.
So to start, we need to find
what a list item looks like.
So we create a list item layout,
which here is referred to as a template,
in order to display a single to-do item.
We define the layout in
a file called itemtodo.xml,
and this is defined within
the resource's layout folder.
Now the convention is
to use the word Item
in the file name itself to indicate that
it's a layout for a single list item.
Now in the XML file,
we can see that this list item layout
consists of a horizontal linear layout,
so this outer view out here,
which contains two text views.
So one for the body, and
then one for the priority.
So here's a screenshot of what
the app will eventually look like.
We see that each list item, so
each row here, shows the task body and
the priority.
Now, to make all this work,
we need to find a custom cursor adapter,
which we're going to
call TodoCursorAdapter.
And this adapter will be responsible for
changing each row of the cursor
into a list item view
using the item to-do template
layout that we created in the file.
So now, let's take a look at the code
for the to-do cursor adapter class.
So let's scroll down here to
the defining the adapter section.
So we notice that the to-do cursor
adapter extends from the framework class
cursor adapter.
And notice there are two important
methods that are required
to be implemented, the newView
method and the bindView method.
So the newView method inflates,
which means that it creates
a new list item view object
from our item to-do XML file.
So the list view item it
creates is blank, and
it doesn't contain any information
about the to do item just yet.
Doing so
will be the job of the bindView method.
Instead, the newView method returns a
blank list item as its return value and
with that, we're done setting
up the newView method.
So the bindView method actually
takes the data from the cursor,
and then assigns it to the text
views within the list item view.
Now, notice that a cursor and
a list item view,
are passed into the bindView method.
So the view is the list item view which
is generated from our new view method.
And the cursor is a cursor that's
pointing to a particular row
you're interested in making a view for.
But for example, it might be
pointing at this row up here.
So the get milk body,
with a priority of 2.
Now, back down to the bindView method.
So the first thing I want to do in
this code is to find the two TextViews
using the findViewById method.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And into it we pass the view IDs.
From there, we have the references
to our two TextView objects.
Next, we want to get the value
of the priority and the body for
the current row from the cursor,
so these two lines.
After that, we take the text
views that we got up here,
and then set their text to
the values of the priority and
body from the cursor, so
these two lines here.
So after that, we have our cursor
adapter, list item layout, and
ListView all set up.
And now we need to
hook them all together.
So let's scroll down here to
the attaching the adapter
to a ListView section.
So doing so
will be done in the activity class.
And usually we set it up in the UI,
usually in the onCreate method.
So attaching the adapter to the ListView
requires these three steps.
So first, we need to get
a reference to the ListView.
And you need to have a ListView as
part of the layout for your activity.
Next, we need to create a new adapter by
calling the TodoAdaptor constructor and
then passing in the current activity
context, which we reference with this,
as well as the cursor
containing the to-do items.
And then finally, we set
the adapter on to the list view so
they can begin populating it with
this line here, set adapter.
Now, it's your turn to do the same for
the pets app.
So the first thing we need you to
do is to create a new layout file
called listitem.xml for
the list item layout.
And since you are already familiar with
creating layouts, I went ahead and
defined the item layout for
you in the code just linked below.
And that means you can just copy and
paste from there.
Afterwards, you need to create
a new pet cursor adapter class.
So the provided gist also
includes some starter code for
you as well for this task.
And be sure to fill in the logic for
the newView and the bindView methods.
So once you're done with that, I want
you to modify the CatalogActivity, so
that you can hook all
these pieces up together.
Start by modifying
the activity_catalog.xml layout file
to include a ListView instead
of the existing TextView.
Then in the displayDatabaseInfo method
of the catalog activity, you'll need to
setup a PetCursorAdapter using
the cursor returned from the provider.
Remember to set the adapter onto the
ListView, and at this time you can also
remove all code related to displaying
any pet information in the TextView.
Can use some help?
Feel free to reference the tutorial,
which we've linked down below.