But you can do more than just
display files in the terminal.
You can also edit files in the terminal.
This is really handy if you're
logged into a remote system and
you want to change a configuration
file or something.
Instead of pulling the file back to your
desktop and editing it with Sublime or
another graphically based text editor,
you can use an editor that
runs right in the terminal.
There are a heck of a lot of terminal
based text editors out there.
Like vim and emacs and
joe, and many others.
But one of the easiest ones is built
into ubuntu, and it's called nano.
You can run nano on any text file you
happen to have on your Linux box.
It takes the file to edit as
a command line parameter.
And here we are in nano.
You can move around with the arrow
keys and edit just like this.
Down at the bottom of
the terminal screen,
nano shows you a bunch of
commands that you can use.
The little carrot or
hat character means the control key.
For instance, ^J means Justify or
rewrap the text to fit on the screen.
And ^O means WriteOut which
is to say save the file.
If the file doesn't already have
a name it'll ask you for one.
Now open up nano on a file yourself.
Looking at the help that's right there,
what key stroke would
you used to exit nano?
Control-G, Alt-R, Control-Alt-Delete,
Control-X, Alt-X, or Escape :wq Enter?