Let me back up a step further,
and let's look at supervised learning more generally.
Our example so far was one of classification.
The characteristic of classifcation is
that the target labels or the target class is discrete.
In our case it was actually binary.
In many problems, we try to predict a continuous quantity.
For example, in the interval 0 to 1 or perhaps a real number.
Those machine learning problems are called regression problems.
Regression problems are fundamentally different from classification problems.
For example, our Bayes network doesn't afford us an answer
to a problem where the target value could be at 0,1.
A regression problem, for example, would be one to
predict the weather tomorrow.
Temperature is a continuous value. Our Bayes Network would not be able
to predict the temperature, it only can predict discrete classes.
A regression algorithm is able to give us a continuous prediction
about the temperature tomorrow.
So let's look at the regression next.
So here's my first quiz for you on regression.
This scatter plot shows for Berkeley California for a period of time
the data for each house that was sold.
Each dot is a sold house.
It graphs the size of the house in square feet
to the sales price in thousands of dollars.
As you can see, roughly speaking,
as the size of the house goes up,
so does the sales price.
I wonder, for a house of about 2500 square feet,
what is the approximate sales price you would assume
based just on the scatter plot data?
Is it 400k, 600k, 800k, or 1000k?