We've seen what search can do for
problem solving.
It can find the lowest cost path
to a goal and it can do that in
a way in which we never generate
more paths than we have to.
We can find the optimal number
of paths to generate and
we can do that with a heuristic
function that we generate on
our own by relaxing the existing
problem definition.
But let's be clear on
what search can't do.
All the solutions that we have found
consist of a fixed sequence of actions.
In other words,
the agent here in Arad thinks,
comes up with a plan
that it wants to execute.
And then essentially closes his eyes and
starts driving, never considering along
the way if something has gone wrong.
And that works fine for
this type of problem, but
it only works when we satisfy
the following conditions.
Problem-solving technology works when
the following set of conditions is true.
First, the domain must
be fully observable.
In other words, we must be able to see
what initial state we start out with.
Second, the domain must be known.
That is, we have to know the set
of available actions to us.
And third, the domain must be discrete.
There must be a finite number
of actions to choose from.
Fourth, the domain
must be deterministic.
We have to know the result
of taking an action.
And finally, domain must be static.
There must be nothing else in
the world that can change the world
except our own actions.
If all these conditions are true,
then we can search for
a plan which solves the problem and
is guaranteed to work.
In later units, we will see what to do
if any of these conditions fail to hold.