Let's take a look at our Styles and
Themes activity.
It's a mock email display that displays
a list of mail folders like Inbox,
Starred, and
Drafts with icons to the left.
Right now, this UI looks pretty wonky.
The spacing and
text size isn't consistent, and
you'll soon see that there's also a lot
of redundancy in the layout XML file.
So we'll want to add some styles
to get rid of that redundancy and
make this layout look cohesive and
more readable.
First, let's look at an existing style.
All of our apps themes and
styles are in the resources
values folder in styles.xml.
In styles.xml,
you can already see our app theme and
a style called ActivityLabelStyle.
This is actually applied to our list
of activities on the main screen.
And if you look in our
activity_main.xml,
you can see the style attribute
applied to all of our text views.
I wanted each of these items to look the
same, and so they use the same style.
In fact, I'm actually going to change
the background color to be our primary
light color in the styles.xml file.
So let's go back to styles.xml.
Right now the background
color is our primary color.
And I'll change it to
our primary light color.
This should change the color of all
the text views in the main activities.
I'll also change the text
color from white to black, so
it shows up on our light background.
Let's run our app and test if it worked.
It did all our views are now this
nice light purple with black text.
And I just had to change two
things in our styles.xml file
to change the style for all of these.
Now let's create a style of our
own to add to our mail folder text
in the style activity.
I'll create a new style by adding
another style tag and giving it a name.
This is for a mail folder text, so I'll
name this FolderStyle and close the tag.
Then, inside this style tag,
we can add items to describe
any style properties we want.
I want to add items for
any of the properties that all
of these views have in common.
So let's look at the style_activity.xml
to see what those properties are.
In our style_activity.xml,
we can look at each text view and
see what they have in common.
It looks like the layout width and
height are the same for each.
And let's use our first
view as a reference.
There's some drawable padding and
padding on the bottom and
top of the view.
There's also a text size and color, and
I want these values to repeat for
every view.
So instead of typing out each one,
I'm going to group
all of these in one style and
apply that style to each of these views.
So using this first text view as
a reference, let's add the properties we
want to apply to all of our text
views as items in our new style.
So let's go back to styles.xml.
For each property, I'll open an item tag
and I'll set the value for the property.
Let's start with the layout width and
height properties, since those stay
consistent as match_parent and
wrap_content respectively.
The name of each item should
match that property name in XML.
For example, our first item will
be named android:layout_width.
Then inside this tag we give the value,
which is match_parent.
Our next one is named
android:layout_height, and
that value is wrap_content.
We'll also add items for
drawable padding equal to 8dp,
which is the spacing between
the icon and the text.
Then I'll add padding top and padding
bottom, each 4dp to space out the views.
Finally, I'll add items for
text size equal to 28sp and
text color equal to black.
And all of these together
define the folder style.
Our next step is to apply this to those
text views in our style activity layout.
So back to our
style_activity layout file.
I can apply a style to
a view by writing style and
then referring to
the style we just made.
I'll say @style and then give
the name of our style, folderStyle.
And now I can delete the other
properties here that are now defined in
the style like our text color and
the layout width and height, so
let me delete those.
After we apply this style,
all that should left in the text view
is the text and icon properties
that are unique to this view.
This style will apply to all
the rest of the properties.
So lets do this to all our text views.
Now I've applied the style
to all our text views, and
deleted the unnecessary properties.
Now let's run our app, and
see how our style activity looks.
When we click into our styles and themes
activity, we can see that the text
is consistent, and it's nicely spaced
from the icons, since we added padding.
And most importantly,
adding our style has given each view
a consistent look that we defined.