As we said, when problem with
the O of 1 scheduler in Linux
is that once tasks are placed on the
expired list, they wouldn't be scheduled
until all remaining tasks from the
active list have a chance to execute for
whatever their timeslice
amount of time is.
As a result, the performance of
interactive tasks is affected.
There is a lot of jitter.
In addition, the scheduler in general
doesn't make any fairness guarantees.
There are multiple formal definitions of
fairness, but intuitively you can think
of it that in a given time interval, all
of the tasks should be able to run for
an amount of time that is
proportional to their priority.
And for the O of 1 scheduler, it's
really hard to make any claims that it
makes some kind of fairness guarantees.
As we said, Ingo Molnar proposed
the completely fair scheduler,
CFS, to address the problems
with the O of 1 scheduler.
And CFS is the default scheduler
in Linux since the 2.6.23 kernel.
It's the default scheduler for
all of the non-real time tasks.
The real time tasks are scheduled
by a real time scheduler.
The main idea behind
the Completely Fair Scheduler
is that it uses a so-called a Red-Black
Tree as a Runqueue structure.
Red-black trees belong to this family
of dynamic tree structures that have
a property that as nodes are added or
removed from the tree.
The tree will self balance itself,
so that all the paths from the root
to the leaves of the tree
are approximately of the same size.
You can look at the instructor notes for
a link for
more information about this
type of data structure.
Tasks are ordered in the tree based
on the amount of time that they spend
running on the CPU, and
that's called virtual runtime.
CFS tracks this virtual runtime
in a nanosecond granularity.
As we can see in this figure,
each of the internal nodes in
the tree corresponds to a task.
And the nodes to the left of
the task correspond to those tasks
which had less time on the CPU.
They had spent less virtual time.
And therefore,
they need to be scheduled sooner.
The children to the right of a node are
those that have consumed more virtual
time, more CPU time.
And therefore, they don't have to be
scheduled as quickly as the other ones.
The leaves in the tree, really don't
play any role in the scheduler.
The CFS scheduling algorithm
can be summarized as follows.
CFS always schedules the task which had
the least amount of time on the CPU, so
that typically would be
the left most node in the tree.
Periodically CFS will increment
the vruntime of the task that's
currently executing on the CPU.
And at that point, it will compare
the virtual runtime of the currently
running task to the vruntime of
the leftmost task in the tree.
If the currently running task has
a smaller vruntime compared to
the one that's in the leftmost
node in the tree,
the currently running task
will continue executing.
Otherwise, it will be preempted, and
it will be placed in the appropriate
location in the tree.
Obviously, the task that's corresponding
to the leftmost node in the tree will be
the one that will be
selected to run next.
To account for differences in the task
priorities or in their niceness value.
CFS changes the effective rate at which
the task's virtual time progresses.
For lower priority tasks,
time passes more quickly.
Their virtual run time
value progresses faster.
And therefore, they will likely lose
their CPU more quickly, because their
virtual run time will increase,
compared to other tasks in the system.
On the contrary, for high priority
tasks, time passes more slowly.
Their virtual runtime value will
progress at a much slower rate, and
therefore, they will get to
execute on the CPU longer.
You should take note of
the fact that CFS uses
really one run queue structure for
all of the priority levels,
unlike what we saw with some of
the other scheduler examples.
In summary, selecting a task from this
run queue to execute takes O of 1 time.
Takes constant amount of time since
it's typically just a matter of
selecting the leftmost node in the tree.
At the same time, adding a task to
the run queue takes logarithmic time
relative to the total number
of tasks in the system.
Given the typical levels
of load in current system,
this log of n time is acceptable.
However, as the computer capacity of
the nodes continues to increase and
systems are able to support more and
more tasks.
It is possible that at some point
the CFS scheduler will be replaced by
something else that
will be able to perform
better when it comes to this
second performance criteria.