As noted before, it's not necessary
to use only one kind of feature for
object detection.
You can combine both color-based and
shape-based features.
After all, they complement each other
in the information they capture about
a desired object.
In fact,
a variety of features can help you
design a more robust detection system.
However, you do need to be
careful about how you use them.
For example, assume that we are using
HSV values as one input feature
with the flatten vector
containing a elements.
And HOG as the other
feature with b elements.
The simplest way of combining
them is to concatenate the two.
HSV and
HOG into a long a + b element vector.
If you visualize this vector as
a simple bar plot, you might notice
a difference in magnitude between the
color-based and gradient-based features.
This is because they represent
different quantities.
A normalization step may prevent
one type from dominating the other
in later stages.
Also note that there might be a lot more
elements of one type than the other.
This may or may not be a problem in
itself, but it's generally a good idea
to see if there are any redundancies
in the combined feature vector.
For instance, you could use a decision
tree to analyze the relative importance
of features, and drop the ones
that are not contributing much.
But hey,
let's not get ahead of ourselves.
How you use this final
feature vector to look for
objects is the subject of our next
section on building a classifier.