First, each fragment must not share
a common fragment identification number.
This is false because each
fragment of the same IP packet
must share the same
identification number.
Second, each fragment must
say what it's place or
offset it is in the original
unfragmented packet.
This is true because
otherwise we cannot correctly
reassemble the fragments
into the original IP packet.
Third, each fragment must tell
the length of the data carried
in the fragment.
This is true.
Again, this has the correct assembly of
the fragments into the original packet.
Fourth, the fragment does not need
to know whether more fragments
follow this one.
This is false.
Because each fragment must know whether
there are more fragments to follow.
Again, this information is necessary for
correct reassembly of the fragments.