So let's actually start talking
about this whole concept.
We start with feature detection, again
we've looked at how we can do feature
detection using concepts like sift.
Something is also that
you're playing around with,
with the development environment
you're experimenting with right now.
Here basically means is I
take a bunch of images.
And again we have all
of these images here.
And now we're interested in basically,
is running a feature detector
on all of these images.
So here you basically kind of see
in a pictorial manner that each and
every image now has a bunch
of different features.
Now recall again what we learned
about feature detection,
that of course might have similarities
that would actually be dealing with both
illumination changes,
scale changes and rotation changes.
I'm here just showcasing
some simple examples.
These are not the actual features.
And again,
you can do this in your code yourself.
You can basically take
a bunch of pictures and
start dong feature detection on it.
Let me show you an example of what
this feature detection look like for
real images.
Here's an image.
And we run a feature detector.
Basically it identifies veracity
of different types of things at
different scales.
And this would allow me to
start kind of now finding
interesting features that we
can do of course matching with.
Recall we did this kind of stuff
already when we looked at panoramas.