[Thrun] So let's begin by taking the hidden out of the Markov model
and study Markov chains.
We're going to use an example for which I will quiz you.
Suppose there are 2 types of weather--rainy, which we call R,
and sunny, which we call S--
and suppose we have the following state transition diagram.
If it's rainy, it stays rainy with a 0.6 chance while with 0.4 it becomes sunny.
Sunny remains sunny with 0.8 chance but moves to rainy with 0.2 chance.
This is obviously a temporal sequence so the weather at time 1 will be called R1 or S1,
at time 2, R2 or S2.
Suppose in the beginning we happen to know it is rainy,
which means R times 0 when we begin.
We have the probability of rain equals 1 and the probably of sun, S times 0 equals 0.
I'd like to know from you what's the probability of rain on day 1, the same for day 2,
and the same for day 3.