So, after we have done
feature detection,
let's talk about matching images
that have similar features.
Again, something we have done before
when we talked about panoramas.
Remember, most of the pipeline of
this is similar to what we did for
panoramas, except in this time around,
we're not interested in putting those
images together in creating
a seamless larger image.
We just want to be able to model,
which images have similar content, so
we can say that they're
related to each other.
So for example,
I look at these features.
I basically say, okay, this image and
this two images have
something in feature.
We basically create a connection
between them and we do this for
each image with
relationship to each other.
And basically, create a graph structure,
which basically says,
this image is common with this,
this image is common with this.
So, in essence, what we do is take
one image, find the features and
match it with another image and
do this across for the whole database.
Yes, it takes computational time, but
this is something valuable for us to do.
And again, one of the contributions
of the original Photosynth paper was
a piece of software, the Bundler,
which is available from their site
that does it quite efficiently.
Now you may remember one of the ways of
doing this kind of matching that we have
talked about before and that was using
RANSAC random sampling and consensus.
Again, allows us to match different
types of images together based on
features that are within it.
And uses that to find images that are
well, similar and closer to each other.
This is what we use for
doing again, matching and
then using that to generate
a pattern same technique.
But in this instance, what we're
really interested in is finding out,
which images are related to each
other in a parallelized fashion.
And again,
something we know we can do quite
well if we have all of these tools.
This is a similar process to what,
of course, we talked about when
we talked about using recognizing
panoramas, which basically said is,
if I took a bunch of pictures,
that were not in order.
If I threw them into a process,
can they figure out which pictures will
actually use, be used to create
a panorama and which won't.
Same process applied here.