I guess it gave a very, when it says
it's still not very popular, of course,
a lot of people not
interested in buying it.
There are a variety of reasons actually.
People who are selling cyber
insurance have too may exclusions.
It's not really worth the cost.
You pay for it and
when you need it they say this this
is excluded and things like that.
So people are interested in insurance
when they think it's a good value for
them, which means there are not
too many exclusions and
the cost is low, and those things don't
hold when it comes to cyber insurance.
So not very popular not a lot of
people are actually asking for
it and buying it actually.
So that's what this link has
more information about it.
You should read it.