if you spent any amount of time in Xcode
you've likely handled warnings and
errors.
Warnings are issues identified by the
compiler that might cause problems or
have unintended side-effects
on your running application.
Now you're not required to fix
warnings before running your app but
it's highly recommended.
Errors, on the other hand,
are reported by the compiler and
must be fixed prior to running your app.
If you don't fix them, the next
code can't build your source and
can't run your code.
Both of these types of issues,
warnings, and errors,
are fundamentally different than the
kinds of bugs we solved in this course.
Before we talk about bugs,
let's take a look at the ways Xcode
shows warnings and errors to us.
The first place is here,
where my cursor is at the top toolbar.
Here Xcode displays the number
of warnings here and
the number of errors in your code.
As you can see, this project currently
has one warning and one error.
The next place that Xcode
reports warnings and
errors is in the issue navigator.
You can access it by clicking
on the issue navigator button
in the navigator panel here.
Or, if I were to go back, you just click
one of these icons on the top tool bar,
that'll also bring up
the issue navigator.
If the issue navigator is currently
hidden in your set-up you might not
have the navigator panel revealed.
Make sure that you click this button
to reveal the navigator panel
on the left side of Xcode.
In the issue navigator,
Xcode pinpoints each error and
the file where it originates.
If you are to click one of the errors,
it'll take you directly to the file,
and this is really useful.
I'll go ahead and resolve these errors,
this one error just looks like
an unwrapping problem, and there we go.
The second here is in the story board,
so View right here is inaccessible
because there's no segue.
Let's go ahead and fix that.
I'll control click, drag, and
add back the present modal segue and
let's run the project.
That was warnings and errors but
let's talk about the types of problems
you'll solve with the debugging tools.
That's runtime errors.
These errors are fundamentally different
from the compiler warnings and
errors we just saw.
Specifically, these errors
occur while the app is running.
Also, these are errors that
your users will see and
they're going to complain about
them if you don't fix them.
There are two types of runtime errors.
The first is a logic error
which occurs when your app or
program doesn't work as expected.
For example,
I'll go to the print debugging scene and
when I tap,
no spider appears on the screen.
Now, this is definitely a logic error.
When I tap, spiders should
be appearing on the screen.
As the second type of runtime error, a
fatal error, we also call these crashes.
To demonstrate one,
I'll click on the settings button,
then I'll try clicking on
one of the bug types here.
As soon as I click the button, the app
crashes, we're redirected back to Xcode,
and we're given a crash report.
At this point,
the app cannot continue any further but
clicking Stop should
not be your first move.
This is something that
I've commonly done before
as I was learning to program,
I panicked, my app stopped working,
I didn't know what was going on,
so I just assumed clicked Stop.
The problem with stopping after a crash
is that it get's rid of valuable
debugging information that
Xcode's trying to give us
to help us fix the problem.
So my first word of advice
about debugging is don't panic.
It'll only raise your blood pressure and
it doesn't actually get you any
closer to solving the problem.
Instead, it's better to take a clear
sequence of calculated steps when you
are debugging and we'll cover that next.