Next in our scenario, the modem wraps the packet in
the appropriate link layer frame and passes it on to the
wide area network. The packet will then make several hops across
the Internet. In each phase, the IP packet will be wrapped
in a link layer and sent on. A routing table
will be consulted to figure out where the packet should go
to next, and then the packet will be wrapped up again
in the appropriate link layer protocol before being sent along again.
Eventually the data will reach the Udacity site. Udacity will
say, of course I'm happy to establish a TCP connection.
So, it will send an acknowledgement. And my question to
you is, what is the destination port for this acknowledgment packet.