All right, so the last thing we have
to talk about are the logistics
of how you actually do the work.
And essentially,
there's going to be two places that
you're going to be doing the doing.
Well, three.
First,
there are these Arpin quizzes, where
you just have to click on the dots or
fill in the things, and usually those
are just going to be making sure that
you're not asleep while
watching the videos.
The real work's going to come in terms
of doing some computer vision work.
First, whenever we introduce
certain image processing or
computer vision types of new algorithms
or methods, as often as we can,
we'll produce some embedded
programming exercises,
which you can actually use while you're
doing the videos and work within them.
And in particular there, there may be a
function that Matlab already implements.
And so, you will play with the function
in the embedded system that you can just
use, so you might come to
understand the different, say,
the effect of the parameters.
But then,
when we get to the problem sets,
you'll actually be writing some
of these functions for your own.
So let's talk about your
own software environments.
Most of the examples
that I will describe and
talk about come from using Matlab.
I use Matlab normally when I teach here.
I use the base Matlab, plus what's
called the image processing toolbox.
By the way, there is a computer
vision toolbox also for Matlab.
I don't make use of that in this course.
It has some of the more advanced things.
For what we do, we just need Matlab and
the image processing toolbox.
By the way, for any of you that
are actual students with a student ID or
academic affiliation,
there is a student version of Matlab,
which costs less than most
computer vision textbooks.
If you go to a company and
you have to buy Matlab,
it is a relatively significant
piece of software to acquire.
The fact that you as a student can
get Matlab at a student discount, and
by the way, the license never expires,
you just get to use it, I highly
recommend you go out and do that.
And no, MathWorks has not
paid me anything to say that.
Really, honestly.
Honest, I wouldn't kid you.
But, if you don't want to do that, there
is an open source version of something
called Octave, and Octave is a open
source, sort of equivalent of Matlab.
And there's also image processing
toolbox equivalent available for Octave.
Arpin will give you a little more
detail about exactly how to get that,
in order to get that installed.
But that's the examples, that's the sort
of system that I'll be using as example.
For some of you, you might rather
do this using Python and OpenCV.
OpenCV is something that
originally came out of Intel,
took a winding path through Willow
Garage for a while, is now a part of,
I think the Open Source Robotics
something.
It's moved into a not-for-profit,
that's sustaining it.
OpenCV has really enabled people to do
a lot of image manipulation stuff in
a robust way, from either Python or C++.
When we give out the problem sets,
if there's something special that
you need to know about how to do
it in Python/OpenCV versus Matlab,
we'll describe both of them.
And you can use either one of
those programming environments.
Matlab tends to make
things a little easier,
things like plotting and clicking on
images and seeing what's going on.
Python and Open CV is a little more
connected to what you might actually
have to do out there in the job world,
to actually produce
computer vision code.