The idea is that if you have a signal,
the signal has as its building blocks these sinusoids.
And if you add enough of them, you could get whatever component you want.
So here we're adding up different,
this is, this was our target, these are the elements that we're adding.
We're going to show this more in a minute.
And this is the function that we're building up.
So before we look at that more carefully,
how many degrees of freedom are there in this signal, right here, okay?
There are three degrees of freedom.
What are they?
Well a here is just going to be the amplitude, that's going to be a scale,
all right?
And then there are these two numbers, omega and phi.
And omega is what's referred to as the frequency, and phi is the phase.
So which of these is most important?
Which of these encodes the, the notion of a coarse signal versus a fine signal?
Well it's going to be this one, the frequency.
All right? So as you change that frequency,
as that number gets bigger, essentially the thing wiggles more quickly.