If we want to build a linear classifier,
so we want to find some function
to separate the positive and negative
values, and the idea is that we want
a line x dot w plus b such that,
if the xi is positive, so if that value
is greater than zero we're going to
call it a positive, so that's here.
So if it's greater than zero we'll call
it positive, and if it's less than zero,
we'll call it negative.
But let's take a look at these data.
So here's a line that separates
the blues from the pinks.
That's a good line.
Good line?
Sure, it's a great line.
But here's another line, all right,
and here's another line, and
here's another line, and all of these
lines separate the blues from the pinks.
So the question is, of course,
which line is best?
All right?
And support vector machines
are a particular take
on how to decide which line is best.
And then we'll go to hyper planes and
higher dimensions there.
But it's basically having to do with
which classifying separator is best.
So, Support Vector Machines, SVMs,
are really this idea of the optimal or
the best possible separating line,
or in higher dimensions, plane.
And the way we do that is,
so you see this line here?
This line is drawn
down the middle there.
Well, sort of down the middle, okay.
Well, great, now it's a ribbon.
Okay, fine.
That line down the middle.
And the dotted lines here, right,
this is sort of the closest
distance of the, the points.
So those two lines are drawn such
that this line is the closest blue,
here's the closest red, and
this separator line is down the middle.
The idea, the Support Vector Machines,
is that we want to maximize this
distance between those dotted lines.
And that distance,
that's called the margin.
Okay, it's written in green here.
That's the margin between the positive
and negative training examples.
Right?
So, here, so it's from here to there,
okay, and the idea is to try to find
the line that gives us the best margin.