So the idea here, if something
goes wrong, then this is useful.
This one says, maybe nothing
goes wrong when there is a TCB,
when we're talking about
the trusted computing base.
The second option says, yes,
it is relevant because TCB only
provides high assurance and
not a 100% guarantee.
If you think about these two options,
we said TCB is also a system that is
fairly complex for a variety of reasons.
We're going to do our best and use the
design principals and do other thing for
analysis and so on,
but it's trustworthy.
It's not 100% secure.
So basically,
it gives us this high assurance, but
something could still go wrong.
It helps to have this design principle.
So if something can go wrong,
even if it's a small likelihood,
having this proves it's useful.
So I think, the idea here is that you
can't assume just because we have
the word trusted computed base in TCB,
that it is guaranteed secure.