View controllers are deinitialized when
they slide off the screen to the right.
DeInIt is invoked as view controllers
are popped off the navigation stack.
I'm overriding the deinit method in the
make your own adventure view controller,
and you can see that when
I press the back button
one print statement
appears in the console.
If I press the start over button, two
print statements appear in the console,
one for each view controller
that's popped off the stack.
This deinitializer is only
available in swift classes.
What else is specific to swift
classes as opposed to structs?
We've seen both classes and structs in
many of the apps we've built so far.
How does one know when to use
a struct and when to use a class?