Another multithreading pattern is what we call a layered pattern.
Let's return to the toy shop example.
Steps one, two and six, all of them deal with order processing,
accept the order, parse the order, ship the order.
Steps three and five deal with cutting and assembling the wooden pieces for
the toy.
Step four deals with decorating or painting the toy.
A layered model is one in which each layer is assigned a group of related tasks,
and the threads that are assigned to a layer can perform any one of
the subtasks that correspond to it.
End to end, though, a task must pass up and down through all the layers.
So, unlike in the pipeline pattern,
we must be able to go in both directions across the stages.
The benefit of the approach is that it provides for specialization and
locality, just like what we saw in the pipeline approach.
But it's less fine-grained than the pipeline, so it may become a little bit
easier to decide, how many threads should you allocate per layer?
The downsides are that this approach, this pattern, may not be suitable for
all applications since, in some cases, it may not make sense for the first and
the last step in the processing to be grouped together,
to be assigned to the same thread.
You may not be able to get any benefits from specialization in that case.
The other potential issue with the approach is that a synchronization it
requires is a little more complex than what we saw before,
since every single layer needs to coordinate with both the layers above and
below, to both receive inputs, as well as pass results.