So the second requirement talked
about being able to express
the address of a book.
It's phone number, library card,
how to reference it.
And that information was
apparent in the diagram.
You could see that those
attributes were supported.
So two seems like it's expressed,
at least already in the diagram and
then I said about requirements.
>> Okay, let's just stick with two for
the time.
>> Okay.
>> So, typically, in situations
where the requirements talk
about the availability of information,
such as with requirements two,
the UML notation is completely
adequate for describing that.
You were saying three partially.
>> Three partially.
There's mentioning of, based on the
functional stubs, that things could be
overdue, or that you could, I believe,
get the information about that.
But there's a lot that needs to be done
in order to fulfill that requirement
that I don't think the diagram
can actually do by itself.
>> Okay, I think you're exactly right.
And requirement three talked about
essentially some queries being made in
order to find out information about
items a patron has checked out for
example.
And a query is a kind of operation and
whenever the requirements indicate
that there's an operation,
you can in your UML diagram give
the signature of the operation.
But the actual details of what
the operation is supposed to compute,
UML can't deal with that.
So we're going to need OCL for that.
Was there another one that you thought
the diagram was sufficient for?
>> I listed both five and nine, and
requirement five talks about audio
visual materials, which there is
a class for that in the UML diagram.
And then for reference books,
I believe magazines
that can't be checked out,
they have classes in the UML diagram.
In that sense I think they're
kind of partially specify, or
they're partially taking care of the
requirement, but in terms of not being
able to check them out, that type
of functionality, it doesn't exist.
>> Okay, so recall in the diagram,
we invented some subclasses,
one for things that were loanable and
things that were not loanable.
So references and
magazines were not loanable.
>> Right.
>> So by the nature of the diagram
we were able to express that.
So that's requirement nine.
>> Right.
I guess I don't know if it was
enforceable by the diagram.
In terms of, functionally when you
actually try to check something out,
it seems like there's still something
you have to do as a programmer,
outside of the diagram.
>> Okay, so another thing to look at
in the diagram is the association line
between the patron and
it went only to loanable item.
It didn't go to the non-loanable item.
Okay?
So there's no association
expressed in the diagram
that supports checking out
references and and magazines.
Okay, so nine I think is covered.
The other one you mentioned was
requirement five which talks
about a patron checking out books and
audiovisual materials.
This is also an operation.
This is going to require
that the system,
ultimately implemented, do some
work at the time that that happens.
And that corresponds to an operation,
and
once again,
we need to say what that means, okay?
>> Mm-hm.
>> So for example,
if we were to talk about checking things
out, some record has to be kept of that.
We have to be able to ensure
the other requirement about
the kids only being able to check out
a limited number of books and so on.
So there's going to be work to do there,
and
we need to be able to express that work.
So five is something that is going to
require us to say a little bit more
about it.
>> Okay.