So our video, as shown here by this
candle that's flickering here,
basically it's nothing else but
a stack of images on top of each other
that are displayed to us over time.
So we still have the x and
y coordinates we had before.
And, of course,
the stack of images basically means
that we put them on top of each other.
And, of course,
as the next one comes, and
in this case I've actually also
layered them to kind of show you
that basically time is
progressing in this direction.
So this is basically the time axis.
Of course, they're offsetted here
to showcase the details of this.
So digital video essentially is,
same as an image in numeric
representation in two dimensions,
x and y, stacked in time t.
And, of course, just like we did with
images, now we actually will look at
a three dimensional data
structure where we can access any
information on this stacked image here
by traversing this in of course x and
y here and of course in time.
So this basically becomes accessing
things in a continuous function,
I(x,y,t) and a discreet function
(i,j,t) in a discrete formulation.
So, similar to what we've done for
images, except now we also want
to traverse for information in this
dimension, the time dimension.
In case of video, just like images,
we have to discuss
the concept of resolution.
It's expressed as a representation
of width and height of an image.
But, usually, and this is again more
standardization exists on video and
actually was much more
standard until recently, and
most of the videos you see are in
the aspect ratios of four by three.
So, most television footage that
you got in the old days when you
had bigger TVs was four by three,
much more standard definition.
As we move to higher definition, we
move to resolutions of sixteen by nine.
An important thing to note, even when
I'm showing here a video which is
square, most of the time, you never
actually saw videos that were square.
You always saw them in aspect ratios
of four by three or sixteen by nine.
Of course, only recently have we
started seeing videos that are actually
in portrait form, not landscape form.
And that is because again, the artifact
of using handheld cell phone cameras
which usually have this form
factor as opposed to this.
But mostly, and one of the things
that's standardized in video,
of course, both the resolution and
the aspect ratio.
And again, it's pretty much driven
again by the display mechanisms,
because most of the videos are watched
on televisions and they're, of course,
of specific resolutions.
Of course, these days, we're going away
from even just standard resolutions of
sixteen by nine, into real 4D or
4k videos and stuff like that which
have more resolution, the aspect ratios
are still being kind of made consistent.
But, a lot of changes
are coming in this discipline.
The other thing that is different
about images on a videos,
is basically again that it has
different types of file formats.
These file formats include the images,
and of course, what they also include is
information about what frame
rates to play these images at.
And additionally there is much more
information about, what kind of
compression code acts are being used and
what kind of wrappers are being used.
And of course, there are lots of
different file formats available for
videos.
I'm sure you've played around with
things like AVI, MPEG, MP4 and what not.
Again, we were not going to get into
any conversations about compression
in this class, but there's a lot of
literature out there you can look at.
But, overall we're interested in
being able to access the pixels
over time to be able to do the kinds
of processing we're interested in, and
that's what this whole lecture is about,
to get you thinking about that concept.