To start off,
I need to give credit to Jake Archibald,
who came up with the idea for this quiz,
and who also wrote this code.
There are two parts to the ready method.
It checks the ready state when
the readystatechange event fires, and
it also checks the ready
state immediately.
By checking it immediately,
this ready method will still work if
the ready state becomes interactive.
Before creating this promise,
so that's pretty useful.
And if the readyState is still
loading when the promise is created,
it'll call checkState every time
the readystatechange event fires.
Once the readyState is no
longer loading, it resolves.
So here's how I'll test it.
I simply call ready, and
then chain, then wrapperResolved.
Time to see how it looks.
To test this quiz it's
kind of hard to see but
I'm using to 2G so that the image
takes a little bit to load.
Remember this text should say
resolved before the image shows up.
Now, it already say resolved but
let see what happens when
the page get refreshed.
You can see that its resolved
immediately before the image even
finishes loading, that's pretty cool.
Okay.
Now it's time to try some air handling.