[BLANK_AUDIO]
One of the biggest hurdles that new
users to our platform run into is
something called overfitting, where
they're using only the feedback from
the public leaderboards to
evaluate how they're doing, and
to make modeling decisions.
So what this ends up being,
it works fine if you do it just once and
submit to the public leaderboard once.
If you're submitting a hundred times,
then you're inching your
score up on that leaderboard.
However, you start learning from
things that are byproducts instead of
related to the problem itself, and
that means that your public leaderboard
score no longer accurately
represents your performance.
One example for that, one of our
users early on had a blog post called
How To Drop 50 Places in One Minute
in a Kaggle competition.
He'd worked on one of our early
problems, got up to number
two on the public leaderboards by
creatively testing many ideas against
the leader board, submitting over and
over again, and making many submissions.
And then he was very eagerly,
our competitions end at 5
PM Pacific Time Midnight UTC.
At the 5 PM Pacific time, he was
hitting refresh on the leaderboard,
refresh on the leaderboard, and then
refresh on the leaderboard, waiting for
it to roll over.
And then he finally hit
the cutoff point in time,
it swapped over to
the private leaderboard.
He looked at the first place
hoping he'd be there and
hoping that it turned out
he'd win on that set.
Nope, not there.
He looked at the second place hoping
okay maybe I at least maintained my
position.
Nope, not there.
Then he started scrolling down and
scrolling down.
It turned out he dropped 50 places,
so the 52nd place in the competition,
because he over fit to
the public leaderboard.
And that is the single most powerful
way to learn about overfitting,
is the shock and
embarrassment of watching yourself drop
many many places in a competition
because of that mistake.
And then needless to say he's
never overfit another competition.
So our standard competition structure
involves actually two test sets.
One which we call the public leaderboard
set is used to create a real time
leaderboard that shown through
everyone throughout the competition.
And that is a powerful
incentive mechanism for
people participating in
the competition because
it shows people how they're
doing with respect to others.
And then the second set is what we
call the private leaderboard set,
which we only show the scores on it
once at the end of the competition, and
then we use that to determine
the final rankings and prize money.
And that's our protection
against overfitting.
Otherwise it becomes a game for
who can make the most submissions to
overfit to the public leaderboard.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
One of the hardest things when you're
competing in a Kaggle competition or
working on many other machine
learning projects is the failures
dramatically outnumber the successes.
So for every ten ideas that you try,
only one of them might actually work or
help improve the results.
So it's really important not to become
demoralised when you first take a crack
on the problem and it doesn't work
well at all or take another crack and
it still doesn't work well, but
instead to power on through and
keep trying different ideas and
where possible to learn
from why things didn't work out, and
then power through until you find the
couple things that really do work out.