Let's now look at another
distributed file system example,
the Sprite Distributed File System.
And also the decision it makes
regarding its consistency protocols.
We will base our discussion on
the Sprite Distributed File system
as described in the research
paper Caching in
the Sprite Network File System
by Nelson and others.
This is an older paper, and
it doesn't describe a production file
system like when we talked about NFS,
instead, Sprite was
a research-distributed file system.
But at the same time,
it was also actually built and
deployed at UC Berkeley,
and people were using it.
What's really nice about this
paper is that it has a lot of
detailed explanations of
what was the usage pattern,
the file access pattern, that motivated
the particular design that Sprite has.
The authors used trace data that
was gathered from users using
a real distributed filesystem to
understand something about the usage and
the file access patterns that
appeared in the real world.
And then based on that,
they understood what are the actual
design requirements for
a distributed filesystem?
So they were able to really justify
the decisions that they made in Sprite.