Before we conclude this lesson, let's discuss some useful
multithreading patterns for structuring applications that use threads.
We will look at the boss-workers pattern, the pipeline pattern, and
the layered pattern.
Before we start, let's take a look at the toy shop application.
We will describe these pattern in the context of this application.
In this application, for each toy order we receive, and let's say
we're sticking to wooden toy orders, we have to perform the following steps.
First, we have to accept the order from the customer.
Then, we have to parse the order to see what it's for.
Then, we have to start cutting the wooden parts for the toy.
Then, we need to paint and add decorations for the toy parts.
Then, all those parts need to be put together to assemble the wooden toy.
And finally, we need to ship the order.
Depending on the multithreading pattern,
these steps will be assigned differently to the workers in the workshop.