Let's recap what we've learned so
far about strings.
We saw how to define string
using a string literal.
We also learn that Swift strings
are encoded with Unicode scalars.
For this reason, we're able to
incorporate any Unicode character into
a Swift string including emojis.
Remember, to access the emoji keyboard,
you can press Ctrl+Cmd+spacebar.
The Swift string also has
many useful properties.
For example, the characters of a string
can be accessed through the characters
property.
We saw how the characters property
also gives us access to functions like
reversed, and
also makes it possible to loop through
all the characters in a string.
Here's what it looks like when you
print the characters of forwardString
backwards.