When building apps that use the API
Client, you have the usual onStart() and
onStop() methods that
need to be implemented.
Go ahead and do these now, and make
sure that you connect the API Client to
the onStart(), and
you disconnect it at the onStop().
You also need the onPause() and
the onResume() overrides, and
these are a little more
complicated in this case.
So an onPause(),
you should get a LocalBroadcastManager,
and use that to unregister our receiver.
For onResume( ),
you're going to do the opposite.
You get the LocalBroadcastManager and
you re-register the receiver.
But make sure when you re-register it,
you're going to use an IntentFilter.
And that IntentFilter should have
the same name as the one in the service.
In which case we called
it BROADCAST_ACTION.
Implement all these now
in the main activity, and
check this box when you're done.