I know exactly how many times I want to roll the die. In this case, it's four.
Now I get the die value from my generator, which was already defined up here.
The same way we did for the last question, and I remember to add a 1 because
this will generate numbers between 0 and 5. Now if the die value is 6, then I
know that he won. Initially, I was assuming that I hadn't seen any yet. So he
hadn't won yet. So he won would start out as false. And it's a Boolean. Now I
return whether he won or not. If any of the die values were ever 6, then he won
would be set to true. Otherwise, it'll just be left as false, the way it
started. Now for game 2. Game 2 has more stuff going on. I still know exactly
how many times I want to run, but this time I have to generate two die values.
Now, I only say that he won, if both are 6. So if first roll is 6, and second
roll is 6. Then 'heWon' is true and I started out assuming that he haven't won
and at the end I've returned the value of 'heWon'. Now, if I won the demo, I
should get something like this. It's hard to tell from this output what the
exact probability of winning would be. But if you're curious, you could run it
a whole lot more times. And use the algorithms that you've already worked with
to calculate the total number of wins and compare it between game 1 and game 2.
Good work on this problem.