Several design points are important to
consider when designing a distributed
shared memory system.
First is the granularity of sharing.
In S and P systems, the granularity
of sharing is a cache line.
The hardware tracks
concurrent memory accesses at
the granularity of a single cache line.
And triggers all the necessary
coherence actions like invalidations,
if it detects that a cache
line has been modified,
if that cache line has been
shared with other caches.
For distributed systems,
adopting a solution where every
single cache line sized write message
is being sent to nodes over a network
will potentially be too expensive.
And it will be hard to justify the use
of such system, the performance slowdown
will be significant, and
likely, it won't be very useful.
Instead, distributed shared
memory designs look at larger
granularities of sharing.
Some options include variables,
or pages of virtual memory, or
entire objects as defined by some
higher level programming language.
Variables are meaningful from
the programmer's perspective so
potentially DSM solutions can benefit.
Because the programmer can provide some
explicit support to tell the distributed
shared memory system how and when
individual variables should be shared.
However, this is still
potentially too fine granularity.
We have a lot of variables that
just few bytes long, like integers.
And in those settings, the DSM system
would still have very high overheads.
Using something larger,
like an entire page of content or
a larger object,
that begins to make more sense.
If the distributed shared memory system
is to be integrated at the operating
system level, the operating system
doesn't understand objects.
The only thing that it understands
is pages of virtual memory.
And then, the OS tries to map
those pages of virtual memory to
the underlying physical page frames.
So at the operating system level,
it makes sense to integrate
some page-based DSM solutions.
The OS would track when pages
are modified, and then,
it would trigger all of
the necessary messages
that need to be exchanged with
remote nodes on page modification.
Pages are larger.
We set a common page sizes for
kilobytes in many environments.
And so it is possible to then amortize
the cost of the remote access for
these larger granularities.
With some help from the compiler,
application level objects can be
laid out on different pages, and
then we can fully just rely on the page
base operating system level mechanism.
Or, we can have a distributed shared
memory solution that's actually
supported by the programming
language and the runtime,
where the runtime understands which
objects are local versus remote objects.
And for
those objects that are remote ones,
the run-time will generate all of
the necessary communications with remote
nodes and all the necessary operations
to provide distributed shared memory.
In that case,
the operating system doesn't really need
to know anything about the DSM solution.
So, the benefit of that is that
the operating system doesn't have to be
modified in this case, but
this is clearly going to
be a less general solution.
It will be applicable only for
those languages for
which there is such a DSM support.
Once we start increasing the granularity
of sharing, one important problem that
everyone has to be aware of is
what's called false sharing.
Consider a page or
even a higher level object that
internally has two variables, x and y.
A process in one node is exclusively
accessing and modifying x.
It doesn't completely
care about anything
that's stored in the variable y.
Similarly, a process on another node
is exclusively concerned with y.
And it has no reference whatsoever,
to the other variable, x.
Now when x and y are shared on the same
page, as in this example here,
the distributed shared memory system,
when it's using these larger
granularities, that's the only
thing that it understands.
So it understands a shared page.
So it will interpret these two write
accesses to that shared page as
some indication of concurrent
accesses to the same location.
And it will trigger any necessary
coherence operations, invalidations,
updates, or any of the other overheads
that are associated with maintaining
consistency among these two copies.
Such coherence overheads
won't benefit anyone.
P1 doesn't care what happened to y,
and also,
P2 doesn't care what happened to x.
In order to avoid these
kinds of situations,
the programmer must be careful how data
is allocated and laid out on pages, or
how it's grouped in
higher level objects.
Or the other alternative is to rely on
some smart compiler that will be able to
understand what is really shared state.
And then allocate it within a page or
within an object,
versus what is something that will
trigger these false sharing situations.