Another way of looking at that whole concept is this schematic here.
Let's assume I can put a light source that actually has a shape of
a plus sign here.
I have an opening with an aperture which is much bigger here.
When light goes through here, basically what's going to happen as we've
discussed in the case of the tree, it's going to get a little blurry.
Similarly, if the hole is small, it'll be less blurry.
Another hole instance of this would be is when we actually have a point
light source.
This is not a point light source.
These were, you know, if have different shapes in it.
A point light source basically is, has no dimension.
It's just a very high intensity beam.
When it hits this point here, because if it's a very small one,
it's going to go through correctly, and
of course there will be no kind of diffraction patterns here.
But if I made it even so much smaller, related to the wave length of
this light source, it's going to start creating diffraction patterns.
So of course we'll have another whole artifact on this image.
In essence, what it comes down to is, we need to figure out how to
control the various types of stains in this image, which basically suggests that
a larger pinhole, which is right here, creates geometric blur.
A smaller pinhole would create diffraction blur.
So this is geometric blur, a diffraction blur.
And a best pinhole, basically, would be an ideal in
creating other images that we want, but of course will let in a lot less light.
We haven't actually discussed the whole concept of amount of light, but
it should be obvious.
The smaller the hole, the less amount of light will pass through.
So again, let's look at the whole concept of pinhole size.
And let's try to study it with a little bit of math.
Let me get a few terms across.
First term is d, which is the diameter of the pinhole.
Again, we also refer to that as the aperture, the size of the opening.
because the amount of light goes through this one.
Another term we'll use is f, which is the focal length, which is the distance
from the obstruction where the pinhole is, and to the screen of the sensor.
How far away should that be?
because that's where everything is going to be focused and best produced.
Let's call that f, and it's also referred to as the focal length of a camera.
Another parameter we'll use is pi, which is basically the wavelength of light.
So in essence this captures, is the you know,
the physical characteristic of the light itself.
Using this, we can come up with an equation which suggests that
the the size of the hole depends on the focal lamp.
How far I want the subject to be or the, the image to be captured.
They'll be of length in this form of a equation here.