Now we've come to our first exercise.
You're going to open the first
exercise for the toy app.
You've hopefully placed our exercise and
solution code in an easy to find spot on
your development computer at this point.
If you haven't yet,
please download the source code now.
If you've synced with both repositories,
you should have separate directories for
both exercises and sunshine code.
Open up the first exercise in the first
lesson T1.1-exercise-createlayout.
You want to do this instead of continue
with the project you just created since
the code we provide contains valuable
to do items along with additional code
that will help guide you through the
exercise, eliminate unnecessary work and
prevent you from getting
too far off course.
Now it's your turn.
Time to get your first, albeit,
slightly boring Android layout set up.