Before we end, I wanted to now
actually talk a little bit about
some additional types of
things that are now known.
For example, there are many well-known
RGBD, that's the kind of a new camera,
because not only does it capture RGB,
but also depth information.
Perhaps the most widely used
these days is the Kinect camera.
This actually does have a VGA camera,
in addition has a infrared projector and
sensor.
It has lots of other types of things.
What it basically does is actually,
it projects from one of them,
a pattern of light, infrared light,
that this sensor picks up.
And, in essence, what it does is,
again, a pair, but
one part is illuminating a 3D surface.
The other one knows a little bit
about how to use that, again, and
it solves correspondence problems and
everything else.
How the light shape
is kind of coming in.
Here you kind of see this and
uses that to construct a depth in it.
So again, just by using a pair of this,
and then, of course, there's an RGBD
camera that also gives you the RGB
information, creating an RGBD camera.
So that's basically one of the very
well-known methods, and actually
a relatively cheap method if you know
the cost of these types of cameras,
that's been widely used to
now capture depth images.
There are other types of cameras
also coming onto the market.
Of course after the first Kinect
we now have a newer Kinect.
I'm just comparing the examples of the
Kinect image from Kinect 1 to Kinect 2.
So the big difference
between the Kinect 1,
which as I've said is basically an RGBD
camera, but it's using structured
light that actually is used
to reconstruct the scene.
The Kinect 2 is known to use
the time of flight sensor.
A time of flight sensor camera
is basically one that, basically
computes the range or the depth of an
image by measuring the time of flight of
the light signal between the camera and
the subject on each point of the image.
More details,
you can please look up yourselves, but
as you can see, the two big things that
actually were improvements on this one,
one was resolution, which actually
becomes much better in time of flight
types of cameras and also more detail.
Of course, these days,
additional cameras are also showing up.
This is a handheld camera from
Google called Project Tango.
Which actually basically lets
you extract depth sequences
in real time on a handheld
device like this.
And, of course,
if you paid attention these days,
the Amazon Fire phone actually
has five front-facing cameras.
And in fact, one of the applications
they have with these four of the cameras
around the corners to create basically
a way that when you move your camera,
it basically shows parallax
effects on the scene itself.
Again, a lotta computer vision and
face tracking goes into
all of this kind of stuff.
We're not going to talk much about
the kinds of face tracking or
stereo reconstruction
anymore in this class, but
I want you to everybody to think about
how you can leverage depth information
in computational photography.