Well, MacOS and Windows are the
commercial systems that most of you use.
Neither one of them
actually support BLP.
These vendors choose not do that,
for business reasons, or whatever.
So security enhanced Linux or
SELinux actually does do that.
The NSA was of course keen on having
operating systems that supported
BLP-like models because they have
information that is classified.
And if the vendors are not going to do,
they did support an open-source effort
to build security
enhanced Linux to include
the SELinux kernel module that actually
supports these kind of policies.
So, SELinux is out there now.
You can actually use it.
SCOMP is a system actually that
goes back to late 70s, early 80s.
This was an effort between Honeywell and
DOD and
the goal was to do sort of hardware.
So this is Secure Communications
Processor, that's what this stands for.
Was to build a system that
actually can get an A1.
So in a TCC criteria that we had,
the version a,
a1 it supports mandatory access control,
verified design, and things like that.
It's only the highest one, so that's
what this system aimed for, and so
it did obviously implement
mandatory access control and
in particular BLP-like models for it.