The next question I want to address is the one of resources.
Resources are things like this pile of nuts and bolts that are used somewhere in a plan.
Of course, resources could be handled just in the language of classical planning.
Here we have a description of a problem domain in classical planning language.
The goal is to get an assembly inspected,
and in order to do that, we have the action of inspecting,
which looks at an assembly which has five nuts and bolts
which each have to be fastened to each other.
If that precondition is satisfied, then the effect is that the assembly is inspected.
We have an action of fastening a nut and bolt to the assembly,
which requires a nut and a bolt, and the result is that they're fastened
and that the nut and bolt are no longer available for use.
Initially we have four nuts and five bolts.
Now the question is with this description of this problem can we achieve the goal?
Assuming that we have a depth-first tree search planner,
how many paths would that planner have to consider?
Would it be 1, 4, 5, 4 +5, 4 * 5, 4! + 5!, or 4! * 5!?