For a quiz, I would like you
to take a look at a paper,
Distributed Shared Memory: Concepts and
Systems.
This was an older survey paper that
describes several implementations
of distributed shared memory systems,
and
compares them along multiple dimensions
that we will discuss in this lesson.
The specific question you need
to answer is the following.
According to the paper
Distributed Shared Memory: Concepts and
Systems, what is a common task
that's implemented in software,
in hybrid, hardware plus software,
DSH implementations?
The choices are prefetch pages,
address translation, or
triggering invalidations.
As a hint go straight to page 76 of
the original paper PDF that's linked
in the instructor's notes and
start reading at the hybrid
DSM implementations heading.
So you don't have to read the entire
paper, but I do encourage you to do so
if you have a chance or at least to look
at it in a little bit more detail than
just jumping to this hybrid
DSM implementation section.