So basically what we're interested in is taking two images,
these two images are perfectly the, aligned, they're the same size, and so
in essence this basically means that each and
every pixel in between these two images is the same, except one gets the hand,
the one that is basically getting from the camera itself.
And the other one gets all of the stuff that's on the screen.
Since they're exactly the same size, and same aspect ratio and aligned.
What we basically, not,
need to do do is take the pixels from this one, and merge it with that one.
So this basically means is if I refer to this.
As image a, and this one as image b,
which basically means all pixels in this one would be referred to a and
therefore what basically means is I have a new function now which takes all
the elements of a and b and does various types of mathematical operations on it.
For example, it could be just a simple average, where I take a pixel from a,
take a pixel from b.
And divide it by 2, and give me a new value.
And this is what the output of that one would be.
So this one would be also where you basically kind of
see transparency artifacts.
That you already kind of know about.
Because in essence by doing this, you've kind of half the.
You know, creating half alpha, that is 0.5 alpha if we generate pixels from
this image, 0.5 of pixels from this image, added them together to generate this,
of course, that's why some things look transparent.
Here, of course, you see my hand is much lighter color, and
the, and the pen also looks a little lighter.
Of course, a normal form blend really would be just take the base layer,
b, and not actually part of anything from a.
But of course, you can now image this starts giving us lots of
additional tools how to do this.