You might be wondering if you can
add two vectors, can you subtract,
multiply or divide two vectors?
In NumPy the answer is yes.
You can vectorize almost any operation.
You can add two NumPy arrays with a plus
sign, subtract with a minus sign,
multiply with an asterisk,
divide with a slash and
exponentiate with a double asterisk.
These operations all work
with two NumPy arrays.
Or with a numpy array and
a single number.
You can also do logical operations.
If you have two arrays of
Booleans you can use ampersand
to take the logical and.
And you can use this vertical bar
symbol to take the logical or.
This is underneath the delete or
backspace key on most keyboards.
And finally you can use the tilde
to take the logical not.
Which is on the top
left of most keyboards.
Now make sure your arrays contain
Booleans if you're going to perform
these operations.
If your arrays have integers instead
then these symbols will do something
a bit surprising called bit wise and,
bit wise or, and bit wise not.
You can read about those operations in
the instructor notes if you're curious.
But it's not important for this course.
You can also use all the standard
comparison operations.
Now these vectorized operations make
a lot of data analysis code super clean.
And they're also usually faster
than doing the operations manually,
using a loop.
By the way, there's a cheat sheet
available in the downloadable section
that will help you
remember these operations.
As well as a bunch of other common
bits of NumPy in Panda's code.
On the next screen, you'll have a chance
to test out some vectorized operations
and see how they work.
You'll also write a function that uses
vectorized operations to calculate
the overall school completion
rate in each country
using the female school completion rate
and the male school completion rate.
To do this, assume that exactly half of
the population in each country is male,
and half is female.