So, for this one, we want to apply total probability.
This thing over here is the same as probability of test 2 to be positive,
which I'm going to abbreviate with a +2 over here,
conditioned on test 1 being positive and me having cancer
times the probability of me having cancer given test 1 was positive plus
the probability of test 2 being positive conditioned on test 1 being positive
and me not having cancer times the probability of me not having cancer
given that test 1 is positive.
That's the same as the theorem of total probability,
but now everything is conditioned on +1.
Take a moment to verify this.
Now, here I can plug in the numbers.
You already calculated this one before, which is approximately 0.043,
and this one over here is 1 minus that, which is 0.957 approximately.
And this term over here now exploits conditional independence,
which is given that I know C, knowledge of the first test
gives me no more information about the second test.
It only gives me information if C was unknown, as was the case over here.
So, I can rewrite this thing over here as follows:
P of +2 given that I have cancer.
I can drop the +1, and the same is true over here.
This is exploiting my conditional independence.
I knew that P of +1 or +2 conditioned on C
is the same as P of +2 conditioned on C and +1.
I can now read those off my table over here,
which is 0.9 times 0.043 plus 0.2,
which is 1 minus 0.8 over here times 0.957,
which gives me approximately 0.2301.
So, that says if my first test comes in positive,
I expect my second test to be positive with probably 0.2301.
That's an increased probability to the default probability,
which we calculated before, which is the probability of any test,
test 2 come in as positive before was the normalizer of Bayes rule which was 0.207.
So, my first test has a 20% chance of coming in positive.
My second test, after seeing a positive test,
has now an increased probability of about 23% of coming in positive.