Now that the housekeeping
is out of the way,
let's get back to drawing
things on the screen.
Let's draw the udacity logo in
the middle of our game world.
There's a number of things we're going
to have to do to make that happen.
First of all we need a sprite batch.
Sprite batch is pretty much like
the shape renderer we were using for
drawing simple shapes,
except it draws textures.
We also need to declare a texture
to hold onto the Udacity logo.
Remember that a texture is just
an in-memory representation of an image.
In the create callback of
our application listener,
we need to initialize the sprite batch,
and we also need to load up the texture.
If we open up the project pane,
and we go to android assets,
we can see the Udacity logo that
we're loading up and about to draw.
Down here in the render callback, when
we're getting ready to actually draw,
first we need to set the sprite
batch's projection matrix,
just like with the shape renderer,
and then begin the sprite batch.
The draw method of the sprite batch is
ridiculously overloaded, but in a way
that's actually very similar to the
rectangle methods on the shape renderer.
In this case, we are drawing the Udacity
logo with its bottom left corner at zero
zero with width logo size and
height logo size.
Just like with the shape renderer, we've
got to remember to end the sprite batch.
And there we go, we've successfully
drawn the Udacity logo.
I'll leave it up to you to figure
out how to center it in the world.
Follow the to-dos in the course
code to try loading and
drawing a texture for yourself.