What will happen to
shopping list plus plus.
What will happen to shopping list plus
plus.
>> Okay, that's the last of it.
I'm going to take this
box out to the curb now.
I got one more really hard thing to do.
>> Okay.
>> Hey there.
So, I've done great at
our Internet connections.
The video is a bit spotty.
I'm switching to voice.
I've got some bad news.
Shopping list plus plus
is officially bankrupt.
You know we had a good run.
But after we hit more than 100,000
users, we just couldn't keep up.
Even with your rock
solid coding abilities.
This is one of the hardest
calls I've had to make.
But I'm afraid I'm going
to have to let you go.
Seeing a shopping list plus
plus isn't the company anymore.
I know, I know it's terrible.
And I am so, so sorry.
But since we've got enough capital
to have you on for another week or
so, maybe you could spend a little bit
of time going into the engineering
specifics of why this all
happened in the first place.
Let's go over the data
schema one last time.
As you probably remember.
We had that big data redesign.
Now, unfortunately I was more
involved on the Android app side.
And I wasn't closely following what our
data engineers did to our database.
But here's a bit of example code for
the redesigned that shows
the basic data structure.
Obviously the production code was
a lot bigger than the small data
sample that I'm going
to show you right now.
Basically what the data team did,
was they stored the shopping lists that
the user owned within
the users themselves.
So here, under Walter,
we can see all the lists that he owns.
And each list has all of
its details including
all of its shopping list items.
Everything seemed to be going fine.
But when we had our big surge of users
in August, things just slowed to a halt.
Reviews of the app especially
complained about the shared pages and
the main shopping list page being very,
very slow.
So now ShoppingList++ is ruined.
Not to mention my personal finances.
J.P. is also looking into
what exactly happened.
But until then,
maybe you can give me your thoughts.
Looking at this data structure,
tell me what do you think happened?
What did we do wrong?