Great job connecting the random sentence spout to your topology.
Notice that we're emitting the sentences to redis-send our visualization twice.
The first time emits three exclamations appended to our sentence,
here in the exclamation bolt.
And the second adds three more, here in the second exclamation for
a total of six exclamations appended to the sentence.
In our visualization this is our random sentence spout here is exclaim one and
here is our exclaim two.
Finally they are connected with a shuffle grouping and the second is connected,
again, with a shuffle grouping with an exclaim one to an exclaim two.
And again in exclaim one we see three exclamation points, and
exclaim to three more appended for a total of six.
In part one of this exercise, I'd like you to modify your topology to
omit only sentences with three exclamation points.
Do not modify the exclamation bolt themselves, but instead modify the topology.
There are actually three ways to link your random sentence spout
to accomplish this.
I'd like you to implement all three.
So in order to append only three exclamation points, one solution is
to connect your random sentence spout, directly to exclaim one bolt.
And here we'll remain consistent and only use a shuffle grouping.
Once you've accomplished this and run your visualization.
The second apology is again to use the same random sentence spout.
Connect only to exclaim two and again using a shuffle grouping.
Finally the next way to emit only sentences with three exclamations is to
connect your spout to exclaim one and exclaim two using a shuffle grouping.
I'd like you to build and run each topology.
And remember that the sentences should only come out with three
exclamation points appended to the random sentences, not six.
Finally, choosing one of the topologies,
in part two I'd like you to navigate to stage two.
Into the spout and the random sentence spout.
Scroll down and remove the original sentences and
write new sentences that let us know how you're finding the class.
Or share your favorite song lyrics.
Take a screencast of your visualization and post this to the forum.
Remember that the visualization should have your personalized sentences,
appended with only three exclamation points.
Comment on two other posts, and optional if you already have a Twitter account,
why don't you tweet a screenshot to your followers?
And as an example, just remember that your sentence should have only three
exclamations at the end of it.
And these are the original sentences, but
we'd like these sentences to be personalized to let
us know what you think about the course or perhaps your favorite song lyrics.
Good luck with stage two and the end of lesson one.