Here's another company with problem.
Wind and
Shade Software makes a wildly popular,
distributed, weather-forecasting app.
They're getting ready
to build version 3,
a major upgrade from
last year's version 2.
But the whole company remembers the
problems that plagued the 2.0 release.
In the first meeting after the version
two launch all of the different groups
involves spent hours blaming
each other for the problems.
The product team was unhappy that they
didn't get to test the apps efficiently
before it was almost time to launch.
So it went out with bugs and
bad performance problems.
Version two is substantially
slower than version one.
The ops team was unhappy because when
they finally received the app to be
deployed in production they found
out that it used significantly
different software than version one.
Not all of the dependencies
were well documented.
There were also OS specific issues
because the developers were
using Windows while the production
servers were running Linux.
And the performance problems meant
that they had to stay up all weekend
deploying new servers
to handle the load.
It turned out the devs
had never tested it with more
than five simultaneous users.
And the dev team had been
struggling with deadlines.
In order to make their own process
faster, they were maintaining their own
dev server instances without
involvement from ops.
But their setup ended up being so
complicated that whenever they hired
a new developer it was nearly impossible
to give that person a consistent setup.
Especially when they tried following
ops suggestion of using Linux,
which they didn't know that well.
So, in the run up to version 3 they'd
really like to avoid another painful
debacle like the version 2 launch was.
But just pointing fingers and
laying blame just isn't going to help.
So the teams get together and
try to find some practical solutions
they can agree on to fix these problems.
Which of the following solutions
do you think might help Wind and
Shade's launch trouble?
Should they use agile
development practices?
Should they run production servers
using the dev's desktop OS?
Should they involve the ops
team earlier in development?
Should they implement
a suite of performance tests?
Should they buy some faster server
hardware to make the app faster?
Should they make smaller incremental
launches instead of big ones.
Or should they require devs to only
use technologies that have been
vetted at the start of the project.