The first one is, there is no market
demand for such certification.
Well, security has never been
more important than it is.
So if you can sell someone,
you can convince somebody that
you're selling more security or
higher level of trustworthiness,
there will be demand for it.
So I don't think the first
option is the right one.
The second one is cost/benefit
tradeoff is really the reason.
As you move up the certification chain,
of course, is you are to do more and
more things and
you have to do them in a better way.
And there's a cost for doing more and
doing extensive testing and
verification and
whatever that is required and that cost.
And so that the benefit
that comes from that cost,
those tradeoffs are the reason
that people don't choose to go for
the highest possible certification.