And another question I had, I guess.
One of my friends who can't be here now wanted to know
what are the use cases of, say, Storm versus Hadoop?
>> Mm-hm. >> You know, like I know, you know,
Storm and Hadoop can be used, like, at the same time.
I feel like Hadoop is more of like, you do batch processing, so
maybe store the Storm data in this, like, Hadoop cluster and
then, do some analysis there, but.
>> Yeah. >> If you could just list some stuff.
>> Yeah, I think the the Hadoop is generally used in param called store m query.
>> Uh-huh. >> Store m query in the sense like once the data comes in,
you store the data forever in that cluster.
>> Yeah.
>> And whenever you'd like to run analytics, you can run against it.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And so because the shared size of the data,
the amount of time it takes could be longer.
Or shored up depending upon the size of the data that you are looking at, right?
>> Mm-hm. >> And Hadoop storage system, and also an analytic system.
>> Yeah. >> Okay. On the other hand there the Storm is
essentially a streaming analytic system where you will.
As the data is being produced immediately you want to do the analysis.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Because if you don't do the other Storm does not have a way, but
which >> Yeah.
>> The whole idea is to as the data is flowing immediately do that out takes and
eye for the trans patterns whatever's happening on the data right away.
Unlike Hadoop there will just store the data, and
when you decide oh, I wanted know about these things.
>> Yeah. >> Then you can do it.
On the other hand in storm you ignore [INAUDIBLE] what you are looking for.
And you program it to look for what you want it to look for.
>> Are there some use cases where, say, Storm wouldn't be appropriate.
You know, for example based, because you have to do things in parallel.
>> Mm-hm. >> Or if you want to, like, do things and keep track of,
like, per user.
>> Mm-hm. >> And, like, show this graphically.
>> So make prod example the, take the example of top and tax.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And that is when I use Storm application.
>> Yeah. >> Because as the tweets are coming in a, what do you call it?
A real time fashion.
Then you're looking at continuously computing the top ten
hashtags because it might be changing.
Because suddenly something happens suddenly things will change, right?
>> Yeah. >> But if we look at
the lab that [INAUDIBLE] top ten trending hashtags, right?
>> Yeah.
>> And when you look at those hashtags, and that's kind
of changing depending upon what time of the day you open that, right?
So that is ideal Storm application.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And it because you got the, it's continuously changing.
It's looking at the data and all the.
Now, on the other hand, like if you wanted to look at something like,
by the way, I was interested in I mean, I have all this data, but
just couldn't for several years.
I wanted to know,
like, what were the hashtags that were trending for, like, two years?
>> Yeah.
>> The right?
So that is more a part of.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Because it's looking at a lot of data,
plus also looking at trending not of the last ten minutes or
five minutes, it's looking at over like a year, or months full of data, right?
>> Yeah. >> So that's not what our storm is made for.
>> Okay. >> Okay.
So that is that, that thing is like how real-time you want to be versus.
How lazy you want to be in that cardboard, right?
>> Mm-hm.
>> That is the distinction between the two.