The general methods of estimating shape from some queue,
shading, texture, focus, et cetera.
For a long time, that was a big deal in computer vision.
It was called Shape from X.
Sort of very popular in the late 70s,
early 80s, which I know is prehistoric history for most of you.
But the fundamental idea was that from an image and from some assumption about
the nature of the world, like that those houses are all the same.
And therefore, they're probably getting further away.
The brain could compute depth and
we wanted to build machines that could do that, as well.
But we, and a lot of other creatures have two eyes, so that recalls stereo.
And in stereo, the key is that the image from one eye is
just a little bit different than the image from the other eye.
Here I see the right side of Megan's nose and
I here, I see the straight part of Megan's nose.
Megan's, Megan's nose is pretty straight.
Mine's crooked.
Anyway, so you can think of stereo as recovering the shape from
the motion that's between the two different views.
And the idea is to infer that 3D shape.
Before talking about exactly how to do that, people have been looking at
this ability of the human brain to do this for a long time.
And in fact,
one of the things, cool things that showed up was stereo photography.
So Charles Wheatstone back in the early 1800s invented the first stereo viewer.
All right. Where you would take two pictures and then put
them through the lenses so that each eye saw a slightly different picture.
All right.
So what you've got here is this wooden thing that prevents the image in
the left eye from being seen by the right.
And likewise, the image in the right eye from being seen by left.
And there are these lenses here that essentially train the eye right on
the image that's right in front of them.
People were fascinated by this.
So here's a picture of Abraham Lincoln taken in 3D.
So, we went from 1838 to 1860.
So just 20 some odd years and
already you're doing 3D portraits of the President of the United States.
So it became a really compelling thing for people to see,
because you take this flat thing and all of a sudden, you would see depth.
Here's a stereo pair of Thomas Edison, most invent,
famous inventor of his age it says, probably true.
And you can view that through a stereo viewer or you could do
something really cool, you could make what was called anaglyph stereo.
An anaglyph stereo put down sort of red and blue imagery.
And what that did was imagine if you're looking at a white piece of
paper through a blue filter.
Well, everything's blue.
It throws away all the light except the blue and
the white, white light has blue in it.
So if you put blue stuff on there, it doesn't change anything.
So it basically, becomes invisible.
Whereas you put a red filter in it, the blue looks very dark.
Likewise, the you put the red image it becomes invisible to the red filter.
And so anaglyph stereo became popular for
a little while in cheap three-dimensional movies.
There's a picture of those stereo viewers and this is a great picture,
because it's a stereo image of kids looking at stereo pairs in the library and
this is in the early 1920s.
And the thing to realize is it gave you a certain sense of realism.
So people used to use it to experience far away places and
things that they couldn't see.
Otherwise, with a,
in, with a reality that they don't get when they just look at an image.
So for example, here's this picture of this bridge in India.
So all of a sudden, you could feel like you were in India,
which was different than just looking at a static picture.
And when I grew up, a lots of us had these View Master discs.
Okay?
Where, where you would put the discs into the little viewer and
you would slide it down and you would see the two different things.
And, you know, you, you, you've got educational stuff.
So when I was a kid, they landed on the moon and
they made stereo photographs of men on the moon, which is really cool.
Talk about some place you couldn't go.
Or much more importantly, you could get Spider-Man, which is really good.
And of course, if we had the internet then, we would have known that you
could have ordered stereo porn, but we didn't know that at the time.
Now you guys, you guys, you get three-dimensional television.
So for you, this is hardly new and compelling at all.
But it's basically the same principle of making sure that two
different images are shown to each of the eyes.