Okay, give me another one.
>> Okay,
tell me what find view by ID is?
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>> I feel like it has something to
do with finding a view by its ID?
>> Okay, but
try to define it without using its name.
>> Hey there.
We're actually fiddling around
with that app that you just made,
you know, Quiz Example.
>> Yeah, good job completing
it just in time to study up
on all the new terms you just learned in
this lesson, like Content Provider, URI,
and Content Authority.
>> But you did more in this lesson
than learn all these new terms.
You also used a preexisting
Content Provider.
By doing this, you grabbed another
developer's app data that was
already on the phone and employed it
in an entirely new app experience.
You can use the same steps to grab
things like the user's contact
information and their calendar events.
>> In addition, you now have insight
into when content providers are useful
and why you might want to make one.
So now if you do make a content provider
say, as part of your sunshine app,
you'll understand what the benefits
are for yourself and other developers.