So small size or reducing the size
of the trusted computing base,
will it help the testing?
Yes.
Remember, testing,
you need to have code coverage.
Larger the code you have, harder it
is going to be for you to cover.
All these possible execution paths.
So testing would be easier.
Verification we talked about state
space and explosional state space and
exponential.
Well, size is small,
that's going to be easier, too.
Finally, isolation of the TCB.
Depending on how isolation is being
done, in general if it's smaller,
fewer interactions with other
components and things like that.
So small size is actually good for
everything.
So I'm going to go ahead.
The details as they say,
the devil is in the details.
So you could say well what exactly how,
what isolation you talking about.
But in general, we say reducing
the size is a good thing.