Let's start by looking at what happens in a single threaded process.
The process is described with all of the process-related state,
that includes the address space or the virtual to physical address mappings,
its stack, its register since it has a single thread.
Whenever this process makes a system call,
it tracks into the kernel, executes in the context of a kernel thread.
All of the information about the state of this process we said is
contained in its process control block.
And let's, for now, assume that we're dealing with just one CPU.
Let's now make the process multithreaded, so this will look like our many-to-one
model, where many user-level threads are supported by one kernel level thread,
and that there is a user level threading library that manages these threads.
This user-level library will need some way to represent threads so
that it can track their resource use and
make decisions regarding scheduling and synchronization.
So it will have some user-level thread data structure.
If we wanted it to be multiple kernel level threads associated with
this process, we see that currently we have the process control block by
containing the, all the virtual address mappings,
as well as the execution state of the process thread.
We don't want to have to replicate this entire data structure with
all this information, just so as to represent different stack and
register values for the kernel-level entities.
So we will start splitting up this process control block structure to separate
the information that's specifically useful to represent the execution state of
the kernel-level threads, so their stack and register pointer.
And this will still have, the process control block will still have the virtual
address mappings, as well as some additional information that's relevant for
the entire process, so for all of the kernel-level threads.
Note that from the perspective of the user-level threading library,
the underlying kernel-level threads look sort of like virtual CPUs.
So the threading library looks at the user-level threads and
decides which one of the user-level threads will be scheduled onto
the underlying kernel-level threads.
Unix-based systems, for instance, have certain operations called set jump and
long jump which are useful when we need to save and
restore the context of the user-level thread.