As we said before, we have to figure out the dependencies.
Even though this problem has output [UNKNOWN] dependencies, again for
ILP all we care about is the true dependencies so
we could rename this program and give us the true dependencies or
we could just look at where the true dependencies are here. So we have here,
this is using R1,. This is using R2 and R1.
But it doesn't matter because this is going to be longer. R7 and
R8 are not depending on anything yet. R3 and R7, there is a dependence here.
R1 and R1, were dependant on this instruction here,
for both of them really. And then R7 and R7 we are not using any of them.
Again, we are overwriting R1 here. We are overwriting R1 here. And so on but
that doesn't matter because after renaming all of that will be gone. So,
now it's time to figure out what can execute in which cycle. In the first cycle
we can execute this one. We cannot execute this one because it depends on that.
We cannot execute this one because it has to wait for
the second instruction. We can execute this one, it doesn't depend on anything.
We cannot execute this one yet, because it has a dependence, this one also, but
this one can execute. So in the first cycle, we managed to do, 3 instructions.
Now this instruction only depends on instruction that is done after cycle 1, so
this can be done in second cycle. This one actually depends on instruction that
is done in second cycle so it will have to wait until the third cycle.
This one depends on an instruction that is done in the third cycle so
this is going to be executed in the fourth cycle. This one can actually execute
in the second cycle, depends on instruction that executes in the first cycle,
and that's it. So,it can be done in the second cycle.
So what we have is the last instruction that finishes in cycle 4 and
we managed to execute seven instructions over that time. So we have 7 over 4,
which if you want to calculate it out it's going to end up being 1.75.