There's some more cool applications.
There's a whole bunch of work in building up
structures from multiple images taken of that same structure.
And there's a system and a whole bunch of work that came out of the folks at
Microsoft Research and also University of Washington.
Here's an example published at SIGGRAPH.
And they built this system called Photosynth, and
what you can see here are a bunch of pictures that were taken of Notre Dame.
And, what these little things down here are meant to show,
are the locations of the image with respect to the structure.
And that has to do with relating between the views that you have things.
When you do that, you can do some really cool things.
They basically launched a site, this whole photo tourism,
this idea of that being able to put in your images and this is their Photosynth.
And I encourage you to check it out if, if, if,
when you're using this we still use computers.
In fact, here's a really cool demonstration done by Agarwal in,
back in 2009, isn't it.
So what you're seeing is, there's a whole bunch of these little dots,
these, those are camera view points of the Colosseum, in Rome.
You should go see that, see the, I mean, this is nice, see the real one,
it's really cool.
And this is just, flying you around the reconstruction of
all these points based upon the solution to where all these cameras were.
And this all relates to, first sun, solving fundamental matrix issues and
then getting the full 3D calibration.
I don't want to claim that you can do this with just the fundamental matrix,
because in fact you eventually end up getting full 3D reconstruction here.
But the idea is you have to know how the, the points correspond.