So let's look at that one now in a little more detail.
The step two of course is detecting and matching.
Here I'm just showing you two different examples.
And here we need to do is find features that are common between both.
Let's zoom in a little bit so
we can actually look at this detail a little bit more carefully.
So I'm zoomed in.
Now this should give you an interesting sense.
These are two different images.
Right, because as the game was progressing,
even when the camera was being panned from left to right, this megatron the kind
of the display of the stadium changed, so it went from lighter to darker.
The rest of the scene, of course, is still the same, but we want to
find matches between this and that for doing various types of alignment.
Looking at that a little bit more carefully,
let's look at these two examples again.
What I want to do is now find features.
Now, of course you see a bunch of numbers in both of these images.
So, the software I used already found those measures.
Now I'm going to find and connect, basically, specific examples of this.
So look at these circles.
I just put up five of them.
They need to match to other ones in the image, the corresponding next image.
So the same five ones and there and basically what you see is this feature and
this feature match, this feature and this feature match, this feature and
this feature are a match.
All five of these highlighted features have found a match from one to the other.
This is an important part of the matching of features from one to the other,
because that will be important to align these images together, and then,
of course, merge them.
We will cover the techniques of how to do this much later in the term, but
I just want to use this as an example of why you would want to do this.