At the top of the conference.py file,
you can see several imports
from models and settings.
Let's take a look at this.
First, let's take a look at models.py.
The profile class extends ndb.Model and
defines how the user
profile will look like.
The next classes,
extend ProtoRPC messages and
deal with sending data to and
from the endpoints app.
ProfileForm mirrors the fields
of the profile class.
ProfileMiniForm has only the two
fields that are editable by users and
TeeShirtSize holds enum values for
tee shirt sizes,
because we don't want users to be able
to enter free form values in that field.
Let's go back to conference.py.
Underneath all of these imports is
the definition of the endpoint.api.
After that we've provided a couple
helper functions for creating and
returning the profile object and
then we have the endpoint.methods.
Let's take a look first at
the getProfile function.
It's defined as an endpoints.method that
supports GET requests with no arguments.
So, its request type is
message_type set VoidMessage.
It's response type is ProfileForm and
it calls the private method
self._doProfile with no arguments.
What doProfile does if called with no
arguments is first, get the profile by
calling self._getProfileFromUser and
then returning self._copyProfileToForm.
We first want to develop and pass
the functionality of sending data to and
from endpoints and
this is what is implemented here.
We'll deal with indication and
saving data in data store later and for
testing purposes, get profile from user,
return some dummy data.
So getProfileFromUser creates an empty
profile object and returns it.
And copyProfileToForm, then goes over
the message fields in ProfileForm and
copies matching fields from
the provided profile object
to ProfileForm message fields.
You have to use getattr here,
you can't just get the values
from using the fields by name.
Also, note how the enum field
is handled slightly differently.
Now, if we look at the getProfile
method in API's explorer,
we'll see that it works
with the void request.
And it actually returns
a response containing two fields,
the ones that are defined
to have some sort of value.
DisplayName, value Test and teeShirtSize
with a value of Not_Specified.