The answer is, yes, there is.
There's a variety of possibilities.
I'll show you a somewhat complex one.
This one says we can look at the table and look at the chair.
Then if the color of the table and the color of the chair is the same, c,
then do nothing. We're done. We don't have to do any painting.
Otherwise, we can remove the lids from can one and look at it,
remove the lid from can two and look at it.
If the color of the table is the same as the color of the can,
then we can paint the chair with that can.
This is for any possible can, either can one or can two.
Otherwise, if the color of the chair and the color of the can match,
then we can paint the table, and otherwise we have to paint both of them.