Recall our overall template for
a merge sort on a two level
memory hierarchy machine.
Phase 1 has two parts,
partitioning the input into chunks, and
then sorting each chunk.
Phase 1 produces a bunch
of sorted chunks, or runs.
The goal of Phase 2 is then
to merge all of these runs.
Now suppose you implement phase two
using the the two way merging scheme.
What then become the overall asymptotic
costs of the entire merge sort.
I want you to give
symbolic answers here and
here for the number of comparisons and
the number of transfers respectively.
Express your answer symbolically
in terms of n, z, and L.
As usual, you can assume that
things always divide evenly, and
they're convenient powers of two, etc.,
etc., so your answer isn't too messy.