Let's check in with Jake and
see how he did this.
Did you get the service
worker registered?
>> I certainly did.
Here's how I did it.
I'm going to call
navigator.serviceWorker.register,
passing in the URL of the script.
I don't need to pass in the scope
because the default is correct here.
Of course this will throw an error
in browsers that don't support
service worker.
I could wrap this whole
thing in an if statement,
but instead I'm just going to return
if service worker isn't supported.
And since .register returns a promise,
I'm going to log a message
if everything worked out.
And just in case it didn't,
I'm going to log a failure message.
Of course if you did this differently,
that doesn't mean it's wrong as long as
the service worker is registered and
you avoid errors in older browsers.
That's it.
So once that's done, over in
the browser if I refresh the page,
yep, my service worker is registered.
We don't get any logging yet and
we'll find out why later on.
But if I refresh a second time,
yep, there they are.
I've got a log for
every request made by the page.
All the JavaScript, CSS, images,
including requests that go to other
origins such as this one for the font.
The scope of the service worker
restricts the pages it controls.
But it will intercept pretty much any
request made by controlled pages,
regardless of URL.
Not only that, but
as we'll start playing with soon,
you can mess around with these requests,
changing headers or
responding with something
entirely different.
This is pretty powerful, but with great
power comes great responsibility.
Because of this,
service workers are limited to HTTPS,
the securer form of HTTP.
Remember when we looked at the path
requests take through the network?
Well when you're serving
across plain unencrypted HTTP,
any one of these things in the middle
can remove, modify, or even add content.
This is bad, this is really bad.
You could request a news story
from a reputable source and
without encryption,
what you actually receive could be
very different from what
the journalist wrote.
Malicious scripts could also capture
data you input, alter databases,
read cookies,
entirely without your knowledge.
So all around,
not such a good thing really.
But service workers
live longer than pages.
So they could be used to persist
an attack like this, and
that would be really bad.
In fact, it's unacceptable to
let a potentially evil middleman
get control of your service worker.
And that's why it only runs on HTTPS.
Thankfully, localhost is
exempt from this rule,
which is why things work
fine on with his def server.
Although it did take two refreshes to
start seeing those console logs, and
that's actually by design.
The service worker has
a different life cycle to pages.
For example I'm going to change
this console log here to just
say hello world.
And if we look back in
the browser now and
hit refresh,
we're not getting those changes.
It's okay,
don't flip the table over just yet.
We need to learn more about
service worker's life cycle.