Now, let's say we've done all this learning,
we've applied our agent, and we've come up with a utility model;
and we have the estimates for the utility for every state.
Now what do we do when we want to act in the world?
Well, we now have out policy for the state,
which is determined by the expected value
and we compute the expected value
of each state by looking at the utility,
which we just learned.
But then, we have to multiply by the transition possibilities.
What's the probability of each resulting state that we have to look up the utility of?
And so, we need to know that--
and in some cases, we're given the transition model, and so we know all these probabilities.
But in other cases, we don't have it;
and so if we haven't learned it, we can'tapply
our policy, even though we know the utilities.
I want to talk, briefly, about this alternative method
called Q Learning, that I mentioned before.
Where in Q Learning, we don't learn U direclty,
and we don't need the transition model.
Instead, what we learned is a direct mapping,
Q, from states and actions
to utilities and so then, once we've learned Q,
we can determine the optimal policy of he state,
just by taking the maximum overall possible actions of this Q of S, A values.