Each type of hardware or
hardware architecture will support
a number of atomic instructions.
Some examples include test and set, or
read and increment, or compare and swap.
Different instructions may be supported
on different hardware platforms.
Not every architecture has to
support every single one of
the available atomic
instructions out there.
As you can tell from the names
of these instructions,
they all perform some multi-step,
multi-cycle operation.
But, because they're
atomic instructions,
the hardware makes
guarantees that the set
of operations that are included in these
instructions will happen atomically,
so not just halfway,
the entire operation or none of it.
That it will happen in mutual exclusion,
meaning that only one
instruction at a time will be allowed
to perform the appropriate operation.
And that the remaining ones will
be queued up, will have to wait.
So if we think about this, what this
means is that the atomic instructions
specify some operation, and
this operation is the critical section.
And the hardware supports all of the
synchronization-related mechanisms that
are required for that operation.
If you look at our spin lock example,
using the first atomic test and
set up operation, the spin lock
implementation can look as follows.
Here test is set to automatically
returns or tests the original value
of the memory locations that's past
this parameter, lock in this case.
And sets the new value of this
memory location to be one.
This happens automatically.
Remember, one, to us,
indicates that the lock is busy.
When we have multiple threads that
are contending for this lock,
when they are trying to execute
this spinlock operation,
only one needs to
successfully wire the lock.
The very first thread that comes
to execute the test and set.
For that thread, test and
set will return zero because
the original value of the lock was zero.
Originally, the lock was free.
That thread will
therefore exit the Y loop
because test_and_set will return zero,
read, and that is different than busy.
Why?
That is the only thread that
will acquire the log and
proceed with the execution.
All of the remaining threads that
try to execute test_and_set, or
then test_and_set will return one,
because this first thread already
set the value of lock to be one.
Therefore, those remaining threads
will just continue spinning
into this wild loop.
Notice that in the process,
these other threads,
they're repeatedly resetting
the value of the lock to one.
So as they're spinning
through the while loop,
every single time they try to
execute this test_and_set operation,
this sets the value of lock field
to be one again and to be busy.
However, that's okay.
The very first thread,
when it executed test_and_set,
they already set the value
of the log to be busy.
And these other threads are not
really changing the fact that the log
is indeed locked.
Which specific atomic instructions
are available on a given platform
varies from hardware to hardware.
Some operations like test and
set, others like read and
increment may not be
available on all platforms.
And in fact we may have versions of
this, where in some cases there is
availability of an atomic operation
that anatomically increments something
that does not necessarily
return the old value.
In other cases, there may be atomics
that support read_and_decrement as
opposed to read_and_increment.
In addition, there may be differences
in efficiencies with which
different atomic operations execute
on different architectures.
For this reason, software such
as synchronization constructs
that are built using certain atomic
constructions has to be ported.
We have to make sure that
the implementation actually uses
one of the atomic constructions that's
available on the target platform.
Also we have to make sure that
the implementation of software of
these synchronizations
constructs is optimized so
that use the most efficient
atomicity on our target platform.
And so that it uses them in
an efficient way to begin with.
Anderson's paper presents several
alternatives in how spinlocks can be
implemented using available
hardware atomics, and
we will discuss these in
the remainder of this lecture.