Next, in MainActivity,
define a method to load the container.
We're going to call
that loadGTMContainer.
It needs to get the TagManager
instance and load the container
using loadCondtainerPreferFresh and
pass in the ID You pass in
the TagManager account ID and the
default container that you downloaded.
And then you set the result callback.
And you do that using setResultCallback
on the result that was
returned by loadContainerPreferFresh,
and it takes a containerHolder.
And this callback is called when
the loading is finished, and it needs to
refresh the holder to make sure we
really have the latest container, and
save the holder, and
you would save it using
the setContainerHolder method you
defined on your application class.
Then we actually have to make sure
that loadGTMContainer gets called, so
call it in onCreate in MainActivity.
And check the boxes when you're done.