Don't worry if this doesn't
feel fast to you at first.
Learning to navigate your computer
from the command line takes time
and practice.
When I first learned to drive a car,
sitting in the driver's
seat was terrifying.
I remember stressing over
having to change lanes,
trying to keep track of all the steps.
Check ahead of you,
check the rear-view mirror,
check your shoulder, turn on the signal.
Gradually move into the new lane,
turn off the signal.
Whoo, it was a lot!
After some practice though,
driving became second nature.
I no longer have to think about
the steps needed to change lanes.
I just do it without consciously
thinking about each individual step.
The same idea applies to learning
how to use the command line.
At first you'll struggle to
remember which commands to
use in a given situation.
And then once you decide on a command,
it might feel clunky or
slow to type it out.
With enough practice, however,
it'll become second nature.
You won't have to stop and think about
which command you'll need to use.
You'll just know.