Every type of content that can be
transmitted on the Internet has a two
part identifier that describes it,
and that's called a media type.
You might see the more archaic name
sometimes, MIME type, which stands for
multipurpose Internet mail extensions.
When they were initially defined for
RFC 2046, media types
allowed you to have multi-part emails
with different types of attachments.
Media types are a reason why someone
can send a single email with images,
video, and
other file types as attachments, and
your email client knows exactly
how to interpret each file.
A media type string consists of a type,
a subtype, and optional parameters.
Here's an example media type that
describes most of the web pages on
the Internet.
The type of data is text,
specifically HTML text, and
it has a character set
encoding of UTF-8.
Here are a couple other
examples of plain text,
formatted RTF text,
and a PNG image file.
Here are a couple other examples.
Whenever you want to share data between
apps, you'll have to specify it's media
type so that Android can determine how
and if it can fulfill the request.