Or attacks can be considered a result
of violation of security policies,
therefore, as a prevention mechanism,
a firewall should be designed
to enforce security policies.
So what is a policy?
At a high level a security policy
specifies whats allowed and
whatever is not specified
is by default not allowed.
In other words,
what is allowed means what is good or
acceptable to the organization.
Obviously, policy is
organization specific, and
we will come back to this point later.
So specific to firewalls,
a firewall is designed to enforce
security policies on network traffic.
That is, all traffic, inbound and
outbound, meaning, from internal network
to the internet or vice versa,
must pass through the firewall.
And the firewall will
enforce policy on a traffic.
In other words, only traffic
authorized by the security policies
is allowed to pass through the firewall.
In addition to gravity enforcing
the security policies,
a firewall also must be dependable.
This means that the firewall
must not be easily to crash or
disabled by an attack.
The reason is obvious, because if
the firewall is disabled by an attack,
then all subsequent attacks
can get into our network.