Okay, here's our first technique.
It's called Eliminate,
and it works as follows.
Let's start with a simple board, and
let's say we have one box filled in.
For example,
this box is filled in with a seven.
So what do we know?
Well, we know that every row, column,
or three-by-three square must
contain exactly one seven.
So in particular, any box in
the same row can't contain a 7,
any box in the same column
also can't contain a 7.
And finally, any box in the same
3x3 square can't contain a 7.
So we've gathered some information on
the board just by looking at one box.
So let's see how to apply this in real
life, let's look at this Sudoku and
this highlighted box here.
And let's look at all the possibilities
for the values of this box.
We'll highlight in blue the boxes
in the same units as it.
First, we can see that the value
of this box cannot be a 1,
since there's a 1 in the same 3x3 box.
Same thing with 2,
since there's a 2 in the same column.
We continue this process for
3, 5, 6, 7, 8, and 9.
And we conclude that the only
available value for this box is 4.
Thus we assign the value 4 to this box.
This is called
the elimination technique.
You'll have the chance to code it below.