Before you can officially
choose an idea for you app,
you need to start thinking through
the features you might want to include.
But, how do you do that?
Consider the following questions.
Does your app have competitors?
What features do they use?
What about your users, who are they?
Why don't you ask them what they want?
And lastly, what are some features on
unrelated apps that you really love?
Do they have a place in your app?
Compile a list of features to include.
Don't worry about being
selective at this point.
Just jot down anything that you
might want to add to the app.
You'll refine it later, and then check
this box when you're ready to continue.