So now how do we generate the video
textures of the dynamic regions?
Again, those pixels that were just
the dynamic parts of the image
are the ones now we're going
to figure out how to basically
convert them into video textures.
So just to kind of start
thinking about it,
I'm now laying out this whole thing and
I'm basically kind of saying is,
this is the y axis, and
this is x and this is time.
So basically now we're
going to stack each and
every of these images in time and
just show the X and t.
So as time evolves, of course, we're
getting more and more of these frames.
So in this case, I'm basically kind of
saying is, this is one frame, second
frame, third frame and all of them kind
of create this video volume, right?
Let's think about it
a little differently.
And that basically
suggests is let's actually
only concentrate on the dynamic regions.
So here, this part of the frame,
not the whole frame,
this is the only part of the frame
where there is some dynamic.
And again as I go down in time,
there other frames come in.
Remember again, this is similar to
the whole part that we looked at before
which said that if I
had an image like this,
there's only a part of this
image where the dynamics is.
So, in essence that basically
means if this is my X,
I'm going to be only looking for small
parts in that image, not the whole part.
And in this case I'm basically
kind of suggesting for each and
every image in the region.
Only a part of it is the one that
is where the dynamics is, and
as I move further into time,
this part may have moved here.
And that's where I have other frames.
So, in essence,
this is the only part of the dynamics
that I actually want to model.
So how do we use that information?
Well, for example, what we can now start
doing is build video textures just for
those small regions.
So in essence what that basically means,
this is where the video texture is,
I don't actually have to do it for
the whole part of it.
I can find a sub part of this region and
use that to generate a video texture.
So the video volume in this instance
would simply be in time, in,
in the local coordinate X,
simply a part like this.
So this would be my small video region,
and again,
I have well defined slits here.
So this allows me to create now
a smoother transition from each and
every one of the frames and
generate a nicer,
smoother video volume to
represent this region here.
So, in this case what it basically
says we're going to map the continuous
diagonal slice of the input video
volume to the output panorama.
That's what we actually will do,
in outputting
the video textures onto panorama, again
in that region where the dynamics are.
Of course, in this case we will restrict
the boundaries to each and every frame.
So each and every frame basically is
kind of looking at just that frame and
you're going to find
a match the next frame.
And the problem with this is,
while it works fine,
actually creates some sort of
shearing motions across time.
Now remember we actually had these
issues when we talked about video
textures too, and we basically said,
match one frame to the other and
of course, either you'll get
a little bit of blurriness,
because it has not the best match.
Or you might actually
see unnecessary motions
that are impacted because how things are
matching from one frame to the other.
What does that mean?
Well, let's look at that example.
This is my original video frame or
sequence,
just from the part from the water
flow is happening and approximately
the same region, where we basically are
now doing a continuous diagonal slices.
So here's my original video,
you kind of see nicer motion, and
here you basically see a little bit
of you know, shearing going on.
Motion is not the most cleanest, and in
fact, basically its the first frame, and
it actually generates it, because it's
not actually doing a very good job
ungenerating the video volume, it's
actually keeping the boundaries stable.