Remember this crazy site?
For this quiz, you're going to be
improving its performance a little bit.
I've hit the Animate button to
start what could only be described
as somebody's spiral from
their worst nightmare.
There's something about
the Aren't I lovely?
part that makes it especially creepy.
In dev tools, I've hit the Show
paint rectangles button and
you can see that the entire page
is flashing green for every frame.
What you're seeing here is
really inefficient, so for
this quiz promote the box class
elements using will-change transform so
that they get isolated
to their own layers.
You could also hit the transform
button back on the site,
which uses a 3D transform.
And once you've used will-change
transform to let the browser know that
the box elements
are going to be changing,
you'll see a code appear on the screen.
Type that code into
this box to continue.