This project is in the same
state as we left off last time.
There's a Bricks A Bunch store and
a Lots O Brick store.
And both of them get their
data from a service.
What you need to do is add
a cart feature that will list
everything in the cart.
There won't be anything in
the cart by default, so
you'll also need to add a button to the
Lego brick items that lets a customer
add the brick to the cart.
Here's the specific information
that you need to follow,
the link to the starter code for
this project is in the instructor notes.
When you've finished the feedback
extension will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.
Ember uses the queue unit
testing framework and
I've created a number of tests
that you need to satisfy.
These tests help guide you through
completing the assignment.
Once all the tests have passed the
feedback extension will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page,
you can find a link to this project's
test page in the project's read me file.