So let me give you a little bit of a course overview.
To do that, let me explain sort of how the course is thought of, at least by me,
and Arpin thought this was really good, and Arpin's really smart, so
if he thought this was really good, maybe it's, it's good.
You can think of computer vision as being a relationship between sort of
three ways of thinking about what goes on.
At the top of the triangle is the computational model.
Often that's the math.
The, and I'll use an example from stereo.
So here we're showing you sort of the, the mathematics geometry behind, if you
have multiple views looking at a point out there, how you could reason about it,
and how what the math would be behind trying to find its actual depth, right?
The idea, you know, here's its center of one camera,
the center of another camera, here is some point, possibly here, here,
here, and by matching, we're going to be able to figure out what the depth is.
Once we have the math,
we can develop an algorithm, so here's an example of doing stereo by
what's called just correlating two patches along an epipolar line.
Don't worry, you're going to learn what these things are.
And computing say, the sum of square differences.
Just how well they match and you would measure that, and
the point at the minimum,
that's what this bottom point here is, that would be the right match.
And by knowing that match, I would know what the depth is.
So that's the algorithm.
And then the algorithm when we describe it to you in class or
in lecture, the algorithm always works.
But of course, the last point of the triangle are real images.
And when you apply these algorithms to real images, you're going to find that,
oh, you know, Professor Bobic, he just lied.
[LAUGH] Okay.
In particular, what you're going to find is that to make these things
work requires some reasonable amount of experimentation.
So we'll give you images in stereo, actually, we'll give you some scenes for
which there exists ground truth.
That is, you actually know what the right answer is.
And the question will be, how close is your result to the right answer?
The answer's going to be not really close.
[LAUGH] Because you're going to be implementing a relatively straightforward
stereo algorithm.
And the reason there are more complicated stereo algorithms out there is because
the straightforward one doesn't handle all the little issues that
show up in a real image.
This triangle of three ways of thinking about computer vision,
computational models, algorithm, and
real imagery, that's really, that triangle is how the course is structured.
What we'll do is, we'll develop the theory,
which will explain to you why it's possible to compute these things, and then,
we'll show some algorithms that implement that theory by
making certain assumptions or certain ways of going about handling the images.
And then, you'll actually apply them to real images,
which have all of their own mysterious properties.
That's going to be, will talk more about, in a minute about the problem sets.
The idea of the problem sets is to get you to understand sort of
the interplay between the theory, the algorithm, and the images.