Another big reason you need to join
the Google+ community is it's where
all of our career development
events take place.
Like we mentioned before, developing
your technically skills is of course
very important, but if you don't
know how to show case these skills,
no one else in the world
will know what you can do.
We'll help you learn how to market
yourself as a professional, so
you can advance your career.
These sessions will cover everything
from the basics of creating an awesome
LinkedIn profile, to how to use get and
get up in the real world.
Upcoming career development events will
be displayed in your student portal, but
it's important for you to watch ones
that recorded in the past as well.
You can find these in the past event
section of the Google+ community.