To avoid skewing our data, we only want
stores that have 68 weeks of data.
So we'll use a summarize tool to create
a count of weeks for each store.
We'll group by store and
then count the distinct number
of weeks related to each store.
Next, we can use the filter tool
to keep only those stores that
have 68 weeks of data.
Using a join tool, we'll add back in
the transaction data, but only for
those stores we identified
as having 68 weeks of data.
We'll join on the store field and
remove fields that we don't need.
We now have a data set with
all of the information, but
reduced to only stores that
have a full 68 weeks of data.
The day spa has a variety of services,
but
we're only interested in the sales
in gross margins for facials.
Since we are testing a change
in the price of facials.
However, we still want to use total
sales when calculating the store's sales
trends used to match control
in treatment stores.
This is commonly done because total
sales is a representative of foot
traffic for a store.
For this scenario, we'll be using
unique sales invoices as a proxy for
store traffic.
Invoices currently span multiple rows,
each row specifying a product or
service included in the transaction.
Using the summarize tool,
let's aggregate the data so
we have one invoice per row.
We want the total gross margin and
sales amount, per invoice, and
whether the invoice contained a facial,
or not.
So we'll start by grouping the regions'
store invoice number and date fields.
And we'll calculate the sum of
the gross margin and sales fields and
then we'll count the distinct non
null for the facial flag field.
The reason for
this is the facial flag will be
null if there is no facial involvement
in transaction and it'll be one for
each line item with a facial in it.
What the count distinct non null will
do is it'll give us one for an invoice
that had a facial, and a zero for
an invoice that didn't have a facial.
While a number of difference performance
measures could be used to calculate
trend and seasonality,
we'll be using store foot traffic
determined by calculating the number
of invoices per week for our analysis.
Again, we'll look to the Summarize
tool to help us out, and
count the number of invoices
per store per week.
We now have a data set that we wanted
that shows the invoices per store
per week,
along with the data information.
So let's drag an output data tool onto
the canvas, and save this file for
later use.