Now, just one more thing.
I can't help but describe what is probably the most famous probability problem of all.
It's called the Monty Hall Problem after the game show host.
And the idea is that you're on a game show, and there's 3 doors:
door #1, door #2, and door #3.
And behind each door is a prize, and you know that one of the doors
contains an expensive sports car, which you would find desirable,
and the other 2 doors contain a goat, which you would find less desirable.
Now, say you're given a choice, and let's say you choose door #1.
But according to the conventions of the game, the host, Monty Hall,
will now open one of the doors, knowing that the door that he opens
contains a goat, and he shows you door #3.
And he now gives you the opportunity to stick with your choice
or to switch to the other door.
What I want you to tell me is, what is your probability of winning
if you stick to door #1, and what is the probability of winning
if you switched to door #2?