There are a few different ways for
command to output its results.
Commands typically put there
output to the terminal.
For example, the uptime command prints
out a single line of information.
This single line of output
always has the same format.
First comes the current time, then comes
the computer's uptime in terms of days,
minutes, and hours,
next is how many users are logged in.
And the last item on the line is
the computer's current load average.
In this case, it looks like the computer
is running about 0.01 processes
at a time on average, so
it's not very busy right now.
Every time you run uptime,
you'll get output in this format.
Other programs can be a bit more
dynamic in their output, though.
The amount of information they
print depends on various factors.
For example,
the host command prints out one line for
each entry in a domain's DNS record.
System administrators can specify
lots of different things in their DNS
records, so the host command
needs to be flexible and
print out however much
information is available.
Here we see that Linux weekly news
has a simpler DNS configuration,
it only has two entries.
LS is another command
that works this way.
It prints the name of every
file in the current directory.
That means that LS will sometimes
output a lot of text, and
sometimes none at all.
Let's run LS again and see the result.
When we ran LS earlier,
there was no output.
Now we see there's one file, stuff.zip.
This kind of dynamically sized
output is pretty common.
A lot of commands work this way.
It can be disconcerting to run a command
and get no output or very little output,
but don't panic.
When using the shell,
no news is usually good news.
Now it's your turn to
interpret LS' output.
Let's switch to another terminal
running on another computer.
How many items are in this directory?