So, let's dig a little deeper into handedness.
So, let's review the answers on the quiz. The
one here that's correct, I really like this because
the touch targets are nice and big and they're
in a place that's really easy to touch
if you're using a phone with one hand. This
one here, on the right the touch targets are
really tiny so they're going to really hard to press.
>> Yeah, on phones you should try and have a 48dp minimum touch target and lots
of padding. Yeah, when users are on the
go, it's even harder for them to touch precise
little areas like that.
>> Yeah and these other two are not so good because if you look at the placement
of these buttons, they're actually in an area of
the screen which is not very easy to touch.
>> Just if you don't believe me, just pull out
your phone and try and touch those areas, it's not easy.
>> So, that brings us to something called the ow zone.
>> So here's some interesting statistics, fifty percent
of smartphone usage occurs with a single hand.
>> So this
diagram is really important to keep in mind
when you're building applications for people to use.
>> These red areas are the ones that
you should avoid they're called the ow zones.
>> What you really want to reach for is this green area, which is the temp zone.
>> If you put actions and buttons or any kind of interaction in that area.
>> It'll make your application much easier to use
with a single hand. So take out your smart phone
and see if you can identify where the natural
zones are and where the owl zones are for you.
This varies depending on what phone you have and how big your hand is.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> And one hand use is not the only way to hold your phone, there's also two
handed use. That's kind of like when I'm
sending an IM or a text to somebody, right?
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> And there's also what's called cradling,
which is hold with one hand and point
with the other. Yeah, I commonly do that when I'm like when browsing the web.
>> Yeah, so handedness and other ogle constraints
are all part of thinking about the user.
>> And making your application fit in their lives in a way
that they're comfortable performing tasks and
using your applications to achieve those tasks.
>> So, when you're building an application keep
the user in mind and make sure to
make the appropriate decisions, whether it's handedness or
respecting other constraints to deliver a compelling experience.