Here are a few different
kinds of elements and
you've seen most of these before.
I've added background color so
each one stands out.
Also notice that by default
each one is a different size.
Elements have to defaults styles which
are called User-Agent styles and
they often include the default
properties for box models.
For example, by default, headers have
a larger font size and font weight.
Plus margin on the top and bottom,
but they don't have padding.
And figures like the one you see here
have margin added to every side.
So how do you change their sizes?
Let's do a few demonstrations.
I've pulled back everything
from the previous example,
and just left the div with
some content inside it.
By default, the div is just tall
enough to fit the content and
takes up the full width of the page.
This time the extra white space
that you see around the div
is actually margin from the parent
element, which in this case is the body.
So, let's size it.
Notice how it changed with new values?
The div is now taller because I
set the height to 250 pixels,
and thinner because I set
the width to 200 pixels.
But what if I get rid of the height and
width and remove the content?
Check it out, it disappears.
Okay, so from this let's draw
some conclusions about divs and
block elements in general.
First, block elements take up
as much width as possible.
Remember, there's always the body,
which can be styled.
In this case, the body has a margin.
Elements are always going to be
constrained to the space given to them
by their parents.
So the fact that this div takes up as
much space as it can inside its parent
means that the width of block
elements are constraint-based.
By default they will be
as wide as possible.
Block elements also take up
as little height as possible.
See how the div ends at the top and
bottom of the text?
You can say the height of block
elements are content based, so
they are as short as possible.
Finally, if there is no content then
the block element has no height.
Inline elements follow different rules,
but we'll cover that in just a moment.
First, how about a quiz?