I used the functions that I wrote
earlier to calculate the same three
metrics that I already looked at,
but this time for
both passing and non-passing students.
First I used the group data
function to group the data for
passing students by account key.
And then I did the same for
non-passing students.
Next, I summed up the total
minutes visited for
non-passing students, and
described the results.
I also did the same thing for
passing students.
I decided to print the data for both
groups of students within the same cell
so that it would be easier
to compare the output.
And because of this,
I also added these print statements so
that I could differentiate which
output went to which group.
The first thing that I noticed about
this output is that the average time
spent in the classroom
is a lot higher for
passing students than for
non-passing students.
These means correspond to about six and
a half hours in the first week for
students who pass, and
two and a half hours for
students who don't pass,
which is quite a difference.
The standard deviation is also
a lot higher for students who pass.
This isn't surprising to me since
the mean is so much higher for
passing students.
And the more time students are spending,
the easier it is to have a lot
of variation among the times.
The minimum is zero for both,
which is as I expected.
I wouldn't guess that not visiting the
classroom during the first week makes it
impossible to pass your project.
And the maximum amount of time
spent is also a lot higher for
passing students, roughly 60 hours
a week compared to 30 hours a week.
Next I ran a very similar
piece of code for
the number of lessons
completed in the first week.
Again, I saw a much higher mean for
students who passed the first project.
I find it interesting that students
who pass are completing on
average two lessons per week,
since I would have guessed
that a reasonable pace might
be one lesson per week.
However, it is true that a problem set
counts as a lesson within this data,
so we might be seeing students
who are completing one lesson and
one problem set.
The maximum is also higher for students
who pass, although the difference here
isn't as dramatic as it was for
total minutes spent in the classroom.
And finally, I ran very similar coding
again to examine the has_visited field.
In this case, I saw that the minimum and
maximum days visited weren't different
between students who passed and
student who didn't pass.
They were zero and seven in both cases.
That's not really surprising since
there are hard limits on how many
days you can spend in your first week.
It has to be at least zero and
at most seven.
The mean again is noticeably higher for
passing students,
although possibly not as dramatic as in
the other two cases, at about three and
a third for passing students, and
a little less than two days in the first
week for non-passing students.
If I had to pick which of these
difference I found most interesting,
I would probably pick total number of
minutes visited, since the difference
between roughly six and a half hours
in the first week versus two and
half hours,
seems like the most striking difference.
But this is pretty subjective.