Recall the definition
of a Bitonic sequence.
I claim that once the sequence
is Bitonic, it's easy to sort.
Let's see how.
First, let's conceptually divide this
Bitonic sequence into its two halves.
That is, the half that goes up,
and the half that goes down.
For simplicity, let's assume that
this division happens in the middle,
though it doesn't have to in general.
In a moment, you'll see why.
Now after this logical splitting,
let's pair elements of one sub-sequence
with elements of the other.
Let's start by pairing the first
element in each sub-sequence.
Then pair the second elements
of each half, and so on.
Now, so
you can better see what just happened,
let me reorganize the elements by pair.
So the pairs are together now.
Here's a question for you.
What if for each pair you are to take,
say, the smallest element?
That would be the same as
taking the min of each pair.
What do you notice about these mins?
That's right, the minimum values
all form a Bitonic subsequence.
What if, instead, you took
the larger element of each pair?
That would be the same as
taking the max, and yes,
again you would get another Bitonic
subsequence within a circular shift.
What you just did has a special name.
It's called a Bitonic Split.
That is, a Bitonic Split is when
you pair the elements of a Bitonic
input sequence, and then you apply
the mins and the maxes to pairs.
The result is two Bitonic subsequences.
Did someone say split?
It gets even better.
All elements of the max
subsequence are greater than or
equal to all elements
of the min subsequence.
Naturally that suggests a divide and
conquer scheme.
I eat your freedom frites for
petit dejeuner.
I hope it's also not hard for
you to see that you can split in place,
that is without any extra storage.
So the end result of a Bitonic Split
would be two Bitonic subsequences,
visually that looks like this.