Awesome work configuring
the Java plugin.
Answering this question took some
real documentation hunting skills.
We need to hit the attributes method
of the manifest of the JAR task.
Let's check out how to find
that in the documentation.
We start at the Java plugin chapter of
the Gradle user guide, and a search for
JAR brings us this helpful
link to the DSL reference.
Here in the DSL reference of
the JAR task type, if we search for
manifest, we find that the JAR
task type has a method
called manifest that accepts
a configuration closure.
We also get a link to
the Gradle Java doc.
Finally, in the Gradle java
docs on the manifest interface,
we see that there's a method called
attributes that allows us to
add content to the attributes of
the manifest by passing a map.
Awesome!
That's what we were looking for.