What is a game?
The philosopher Wittgenstein said that there is no single set of necessary
and sufficient conditions that define all games.
Rather games have a set of features, and some games share some of them,
and other games share others of them.
It's a complex overlapping set rather than a simple criteria.
Here I've listed six different games and in some cases sets of games
like Chess and Go are similar, Robotic Soccer, Poker,
hide-and-go-seek played in the real world,
Cards Solitaire, and Minesweeper, the computer solitaire game.
I want to ask you, for each one, which of these properties they exhibit.
Are they stochastic? Are they partially observable?
Do they have an unknown environment? Are they adversarial?
For each game tell me all that apply.
Let me add that your answers may not be the same as mine,
because these very terms are not that precise.
Sometimes you can analyze a problem in two different ways
and flip from one of these attributes to another, depending on how you analyze it.