A lot of folks when they hear about SQL
features like order by, or limit and
offset, ask the question,
why do that in the database?
I already know how to sort
a list in Python, and
I already know how to do slices.
Why don't I just fetch the data back
to my application code unsorted, and
do the work there?
And it's true that count is
an awful lot like length.
And limit 100 offset ten is an awful lot
like taking a slice from elements
ten to a 110 of the result list.
And order by column is an awful lot
like, sorting by a a key that's
actually kind of complicated, but
there are a couple of big differences.
Speed and space.
The database can generally do these
things a lot faster than Python can.
Especially when you get to
tables with lots of rows or
complicated queues that
join several tables.
And you can easily have
a table with millions of rows,
sorting a million items in
Python can take around a second.
If you're writing a web app, that's
a second that you're user is staring at
their browser,
wondering why your app is so
freaking slow, and
it's taking up memory to do that too.
In contrast, a database can generally
do these operations much faster.
There are a number of tricks you
can use to make it faster still.
The big one is called indexing.
We won't deal with indexing
directly in this course, but
later on there will be some
notes on how to apply it.
In any event, doing restrictions and
aggregations in the database,
instead of in Python,
is a good practice to get in to.
So let's do more of that.