So the first statement,
can only infect Microsoft Windows.
This is clearly false.
The second statement,
can modify hidden and read-only files.
This is true.
You may ask, how can a malware find a
hidden file or modify a read-only files?
If you think about it, a malware can
be inserted into the operating system,
which has the highest privilege.
It can find any hidden file on a system,
and it can override any permissions,
such as read-only permission.
The third statement,
spread only on disks or in email.
This is clearly false.
The fourth statement,
cannot remain in memory after reboot.
This is a somewhat tricky question.
If this refers to the particular
instance of the virus,
then this statement is true.
Because after reboot, the memory
is wiped clean, and start over.
On the other hand, although we say that
the particular malware instance is gone,
after the system reboots,
we should know that if the virus
is part of a operating system,
then when the system reboots, the virus
will be loaded into the memory again.
So we really have to think about
this statement in a context.
The fifth statement,
cannot infect hardware.
This is true.
But we have to note that by hardware,
we mean,
that hardware that does not have any
software component, such as firmware.
The last statement,
can be malicious or benign.
Although this may appear
to be subjective,
I will say the answer is false.
The reason is that,
any malware that gets on your system
without your knowledge or authorization,
already violates security policy, and
therefore, it is already malicious.