All right, so let's start with case #1.
We asked about a group texting
app that opens up a video player.
Since the core part of
our app is about texting,
we probably won't be focused on
creating a world class video player.
It would probably be better
to leave it to another app
which has more expertise in the video
playback, such as the YouTube app.
We could send an implicit intent with
information on which video to play,
because it can be handled by any video
player app of the user's choice.
In case #2, we should use an explicit
intent, because we want to move from
the order activity to the order
summary activity within our app.
In this case, it's very clear which
activity to which we want to move next
in response to a user action.
In our last case, we again have a
general action, sending a text message.
We should use an implicit intent
to send the request to another app
that can handle sending a text message.