So here's if we were doing a homography, here would be our RANSAC loop.
Select four feature pairs at random.
Compute the homography H, that's the thing that moves it from one to the other.
And then, what this means is, take a look at the square distance between, some
point in the image, transformed by H, and it lands someplace, and take a look
at its distance from what it claimed was the putative match in the other image.
And count all the ones that are less than some threshold, just do that loop for
a while, and then you keep the one with the largest set of inliers.
You then compute, we don't use the old H,
you compute the least squares, the best H for
that set of inliers and that'll be a much more robust estimate of the transform.