Remember when we had our simple
five move isolation board and
we searched it to end game?
We found that player one would
always win unless it moved to one of
the center positions first.
>> I see where you're going.
The question is whether our
evaluation function of #my_ moves
predicts which branches will lead to
a win, and which ones lead to failure.
>> Exactly,
I always like to test my assumptions
because they are often wrong.
>> Okay, so here's the minimax tree,
where I've limited the depth to three
and applied the evaluation function.
I've also propagated the values
up the minimax tree to the top.
>> The result looks promising.
The two center positions have scores
of 1, while the rest of the branches,
which we know win, have higher scores.
Let's try another example.
What happens if we try the same thing,
but
assume we could only go two
levels deep on our search tree?