[BLANK_AUDIO]
Kaggle has a lot of different
benefits for students or
young professionals looking to
build a career in machine learning.
The first is that employers pay a lot
of attention to your Kaggle profile.
For a couple of examples of that,
I think Google DeepMind has now hired
about four competition winners from
people who've won computer
vision competitions.
And these are people that DeepMind
probably wouldn't have come across had
they not done a really good
job in Kaggle competitions.
So strong competition performances are a
really effective way to stand out from
the crowd and to demonstrate how
well they can do on a problem.
The second way that we help
people looking to find data
science jobs is running
their own jobs board,
where we highlight jobs from some of
the best companies around the world that
are hiring data scientists from
machine learning engineers.
The guidance that we typically
give companies who are hiring
from recruiting competitions that
we ran is to look at the top
two to three hundred out of a pull of about
a thousand people in those competitions.
And usually they use that as a starting
point and look at a number of other
factors from there,
when they're evaluating candidates.
There's actually a third way
that's really helpful for
people who are currently in a career and
either they want to
swap to doing more data science, machine
learning within their current company or
they want to swap, make switches.
If you participate a lot in Kaggle,
and do well in Kaggle and
it's a really effective way for finding
the most interesting projects and
getting access to the most interesting
projects within your company.
For example, one of our top users
is a chemical engineer by training.
But he's been pulled into pretty
much every special project around
the analytics machine
learning that his company's
done by virtue of his Kaggle profile.
And many executives four and five levels
higher than him in that company know who
he is and brag about his Kaggle
profile and Kaggle performance.
So it's a really great way for people
currently in large companies to get
greater visibility
within those companies.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The way to make your profile
more attractive to employers is
to showcase to the best of
your ability what you can do.
And the three mechanisms of doing that
are, the first is competitions and
having a strong competition performance.
Then the other two
touch on collaboration.
In enterprise data science teams or
commercial machine learning teams,
working collaboratively
is incredibly important.
And the two ways to showcase how you can
do that are, first, to write clean and
well-architected code which can be
published through Kaggle scripts.
And then secondly to participate
in discussion on the forums and
give helpful tips and advice,
share insights about the data, and
things along those lines.