Finally, Sunshine has
multiple activities, and
we can move between them using intents.
>> We also know how to use intents
to integrate multiple activities
within your app as well as
activities from other apps.
In this lesson,
we'll dive into just how the Android
framework deals with your activities.
In particular, how the activity
lifecycle may be different from what
you're used to from other platforms and
environments.
>> Don't worry, it's not all theory.
We'll work with parts of the framework
that help you handle this lifecycle,
such as loaders.
>> If you leverage the framework,
properly the users of your app
never have to think about things like
activity and process lifecycles.
Everything just works naturally.