So in this code example, I just want to
show you how we can do transformation f,
a specific form that is rotation.
First two lines, basically, are just
loading in computer vision and numpy,
then basically just load in
the image figure out the height and
width of the image,
of course show the original image.
Here we want to actually showcase
a rotation around the origin at zero and
zero, that is the point of
the image right at the top corner.
And of course, what we do is we
apply a rotation of 45 degrees.
So using that, of course, we have
now computed the rotation matrix.
We can print the rotation matrix here.
And that's shown here.
And of course, then we can apply
the transformation by this function cv
2 warpAffine.
Again, rotation matrix.
The image itself.
And that way we now can show the image
here with this line of code.
In this part of the code here, basically
now we apply the same transformation
except now that we are applying
at the center of the image.
Of course to achieve this we have
to transform the point to the half
the width and half the height of the
image, and again we are rotating this in
the other direction, minus 45 degrees,
and here one is still the scale.
We don't want to change the scale.
[SOUND] So, again, now we print out the
rotation matrix and apply it with new
new images transformation using the same
function above and display the image.
Let's see what this looks
like when we run it.
This is the rotation matrix when
we have the image at the origin.
That is the point top here,
of the image.
And the next one here is after
we've actually figured out
the center of the image.
That is we've basically moved to the
width half and half height of the image.
And then applied the same transformation
of basically rotating by 45 degrees.
Notice again this is minus 45 degrees.
This is plus 45 degrees and
therefore the signs are different.
This is our original image.
This is the image rotated
around the origin point.
And again as earlier stated I rotated
this image by 45 degrees, so of course,
now it's truncated or
cut at this top here, but
you can see that the image has
been rotated by 45 degrees.
This is the final one where again
this time around I've done the 45 degree
rotation at the center of the image.
That's why we actually
have put in this for
different terms in
the transformation matrix.
So actually our rotation
would be at this point.
And here you notice, of course,
the tech sign now has been
rotated this way 45 degrees and
shows a transformation of rotation by
45 degrees at the center of the image.