Now I want to describe the notation,
which we call classical planning, which
is a representation language for dealing
with states and actions and plans.
And it's also an approach for
dealing with the problem of complexity,
by factoring the world into variables.
So under classical planning,
a state space consists of all
the possible assignments
to k-Boolean variables.
And so that means they'll be 2 to
the k states in that state space.
And if we think about the two
location vacuum world,
we would have three Boolean Variables.
We could have dirt in location A,
dirt in location B, and
vacuum in location A.
And the vacuum has to be in either A or
B.
So these three variables will do and
there'll be eight possible
states in that world.
But they can be succinctly represented
through the three variables.
And then a world state consists of
a complete assignment of true and
false, through each of
the three variables.
And then a belief state, well,
just as in problem solving,
the belief state depends on what type
of environment you want to deal with.
Now, in the core classical planning,
the belief sate had to be a complete
assignment and that was useful for
dealing with deterministic,
fully observable domains.
But we can easily extend
classical planning and
we can deal with belief states that
are partial assignments, that is,
some of the variables have
values that others don't.
So we could have the belief state
consisting of vacuum in A is true and
the others are unknown and
that small formula represents
four possible world states.
And we can even have a belief state
which is an arbitrary formula
in Boolean logic.
And that can represent anything we want.
So that's what states look like, now we
have to figure out what actions look and
what the results of those
actions looks like.
And these are represented in classical
planning by something
called an action schema.
And it's called a schema,
because it represents many possible
actions that are similar to each other.
So, let's take an example of we want
to send cargo around the world and
we've got a bunch of planes in
airports and we have cargo and so on.
And I'll show you the action for
having a plane fly
from one location to another
here's on possible representation.
We say, it's an action schema, so we
write the word action, and then we write
the action operator, and
it's arguments, so it's a fly of p,
from x to y, and
then we list the preconditions.
What needs to be true in order to
be able to execute this action.
And we can say something like,
well, p better be a plane.
It's no good trying to fly a truck or
a submarine.
And we'll use the and formula
from Boolean propositional logic.
And x better be an airport.
You don't want to try to
take off from my back yard.
And similarly, y better be an airport.
And, most importantly,
p better be at airport x in
order to take off from there.
And then we represent the effects
of the action by saying,
well, what's going to happen?
Well, once we fly from x to y
the plane is no longer at x.
So we say not at p(x).
Plane's no longer at x.
And the plane is now at y.
So this is called an action schema.
It represents a set of actions for
all possible planes, for all x, and for
all y.
Represents all those
actions in one schema.
It says, but we need to know,
in order to apply the action.
And it says what will happen in terms
of the transition from state spaces.
This variable will become false,
and this one will become true.
Now when we look at this formula this
looks like a term in first order logic.
But we're actually dealing with
a completely propositional world.
It just looks like that
because this is a schema.
And we can apply this schema to specific
ground states, specific world states.
And then p and
x would have specific values.
And you can just think of it as
concatenating their names all together.
And that's just the name
of one variable.
The name just happens to have this
complex form with parentheses and
commas in it.
To make it easier to write one schema
that covers all
the individual fly actions.