The answer to the first question
is the TMDBAuthViewController.
We're going to cover how this class
handles step 2a of the authentication
flow in more detail
later in this lesson.
Next the only view class that
we have is the bordered button.
The next question should have introduced
you to the TMDBConstants.swift file.
This file contains stokes and
constants related to the movie database.
And the last answer is actually
derived from the TMDConstants file.
If you look at the method stroke,
there are a total of nine
methods that this app will use.
Hopefully these questions force
you to look at a few files.
But, if you haven't all ready,
I would recommend taking a quick look
through the project before moving on.