First, a common location for a network
intrusion detection system sensor
is just inside the external firewall.
This is true.
This is a very typical deployment
strategy of network IDS.
Second, a Honeypot can be a workstation
that a user uses for work.
This is false, because a Honeypot is not
a real system used by any real user.
Third, there's no benefit of
deploying a network IDS or
Honeypot outside of
the external firewall.
This is false.
Using a network IDS or Honeypot outside
of the external firewall will allow us
to see what attacks are coming from
Internet to the enterprise network.
In the case of Honeypot, because
attacks are trapped in the Honeypot,
it reduces the amount of traffic
that the firewall has to process.
In other words, the firewall does
not need to produce as many alerts.