This is a robot that points in the x direction, because θ equals zero.
We have a coordinate system over here where this is 24.
That's 18 in the y direction, and it moves forward for a while.
In fact we have 1 second, and it moves at 5 units per second, so this is 5.
Then it turns its heading into this direction over here, and this is π/8.
Again, the real robot would take a curve,
but in our approximation we assume it goes in a straight line
and then finally does a very discrete turn, which is an approximation,
but that's the question I have asked you here.
When you plug these values in, you'll find that the x extends by 5,
which is 29. Y doesn't change.
The final turn is π/8, which is about 0.3927.