Click on the View as button on
the bottom of the storyboard window.
This allows you to preview
your UI on different devices
as well as different orientations.
It also allows you to preview it when
the whole screen is not available
because it's being shared
with another scene.
This last part is a little
bit more advanced, so
we won't bother with it right now.
As you can see, the stack view remains
in the same corner of the screen.
The size of the stack view
doesn't change, however.
That's because it doesn't have to.
Now let's give the stack view
a little bit more work to do.
Can you think of a way
to force it to take
all of the available width on
any device and orientation?
Think about it.
We'll do it in the next video.