So, it actually winds up being helpful
to think of this continuum from novice
to expert as having
four distinct stages.
And I'm going to be referring to these
four stages throughout the NIM degree,
so you know to what extent you should
be mastering the material we cover.
In order to talk about these stages,
let's give them names.
On this end, I'm going to replace I
don't even know where to begin with
a title and that word is ignorance.
Now, ignorance sounds harsh,
but it isn't meant that way.
Ignorance about something just
means you just don't know yet
it exists and this is how every
journey towards expertise begins and
that's why we're calling it stage zero.
On the other end, let's replace why was
this ever hard with the word fluency.
Because when you're really fluent in
something, you've truly mastered it.
In between these two extremes,
there are two important stages.
First, comes awareness and
that is followed by ability.
To better explain what
these stages mean,
I'm going to share
a personal example with you.
As I do, try to connect
the stages I went through to
the example you just came up with for
yourself.
And the example I want to share is how
I learned to drive a stick shift car.
Because when I was a little kid,
I actually didn't know that different
cars could be driven in different ways.
I had no idea what stick shift was.
I was ignorant of its existence.
And then one day,
I asked my dad why he kept moving
the shifter around when he drove.
And he explained to me manual
transmissions and pretty quickly,
I at least had an awareness
that stick shift was a thing.
And even though that seems small,
this was an essential stage in my
journey towards becoming an expert.
The transition to this next
stage began on my 16th birthday.
I had gotten my driver's license and
I really wanted to drive.
So, I needed to learn
how to drive stick.
My dad gave me some lessons and
within just one or two of these lessons,
I could actually drive stick.
It was really hard, but
I was still driving.
I had to be very focused on what
I was doing with the clutch and
the break and the shifter and
the gas, but I can make the car go.
It was a big achievement.
And now, I've gotten to fluency.
When I drive,
I forget what I'm even doing.
I don't even think about driving
a stick, it just comes natural and
that's fine.
But let's talk about the most
empowering part of these stages.
To get from ignorance to awareness
took me a matter of minutes.
All my dad had to do was explain
to me that this thing existed.
Then to get from awareness to ability,
only took a matter of days.
And even though I was far
from being an expert,
after those two days of instruction
practice, I was driving a car.
It felt very cool.
Now getting from ability to fluency,
that required years of practice.
And I was constantly getting
closer to fluency over that time,
but it wasn't until a couple of years
of practice that I was actually at
the stage where I wasn't thinking
at all about what I was doing.
So think back to your example
of expertise that you have.
How did you make these transitions?
How long did each take?
If you'd like, feel free to share
your story on the discussion forum.
In the next video, I'm going to
explain why these stages are so
relevant to the educational journey to
learn to code that you are on right now.