Now lets take a look at the solution.
So each row in our table will represent
product information for a headphone.
So each headphone will have a name,
price, whether or
not it's in stock, a style,
and a description.
So we could see all this in our
webpage mockup, right here.
So we have the name,
the price, whether or
not it's in stock,
the description, and the style.
So like I mentioned in
the instructor's notes before,
we also have other information here
that you can see in the mock-up,
such as the customer's username or
the URL of the website.
But none of this has to do with
a single headphone in our table.
Similarly, the fact that there is a buy
one get one sale for this particular
headphone, doesn't change anything
inherent about this particular product.
Also the quantity of the headphone
that the user wants to order,
is definitely information
that we want to store.
But given that there might be
hundreds of users looking to buy
different amounts of this headphone,
it wouldn't be in the table that
we're interested in right now,
specifically about the product.
So likely,
we'd have another table in the database,
helping us keep track of user orders.