Okay, so let's drill down into the name compartment.
Obviously, the most important piece is the name, and that should be a noun.
After all, it describes a class of instances. For example,
you saw that Window was in italics. That's one way in which you can express
in UML that this particular class is an abstract class. Abstract classes,
if you're familiar with object oriented programming, are contracts which
describe the properties of sub-classes, and can never have instances themselves.
Besides using italics, you can also specify that a class is abstract using a tag
with the word abstract in it. Why might you want to use an abstract class?
Well, for one if you have some related sub-classes that have common features,
you can factor those features up into the abstract class.
Inside the name compartment, you can also have some other affordances.
You can for example have a stereotype. Stereotypes are a way
in UML of extending the base UML modeling language. You can also express some
optional properties inside of curly braces. For example abstract is one of
those key words you can use to give properties to the particular class.