You've already downloaded Vagrant in VirtualBox.
Two technologies used to provision, and
run Ubuntu 14.04 LTS virtual machine used throughout this course.
Follow along with the links provided in instructor notes and you'll see that
VirtualBox is virtualization software developed and maintained by Oracle.
Virtualization refers to the creation of a virtual machine that acts like
a real computer with an operating system.
For example, your computer could be running Microsoft Windows.
And for this course we've given you a virtual machine that
has the functionality of a computer with Ubuntu Linux.
This is possible using the virtualization software VirtualBox.
Next, we use Vagrant, a free and open source software, for creating and
configuring virtual development environments.
This can be seen as a wrapper around virtualization software such as
VirtualBox and around configuration management software such as Puppet or Chef.
In our setup we pull a base image or
virtual machine disc image from the Vagrant cloud and if you recall from
lesson 1 this step required about 15 to 20 minutes during your first run.
If you recall from lesson 1 I promised to demonstrate modifying the Vagrant
file and the privison.sh file to provision the machine for
the Python beautiful suit package.
Let's walk through this simple modification now.
From lesson 3, stage 3,
recall that we needed to enter a command, pseudo app get install Python BS4.
You may have noticed in lesson 3,
stage 2 that if you failed to do the install step and you submit your topology,
your process dies, where no module named bs4 exists on your machine.
To modify your box at the provisioning stage,
step 1 is to destroy your current box.
First close any connected web pages.
Next, stop your Python flat server, if you followed my directions for
setup you'll have another tab where your flat server exists.
Use Ctrl+Z, so Ctrl+Z to send it to the background, and
next kill %1, which will kill the program in the background.
Next, log out of your Ubuntu box in both tabs.
Log out and in your second tab, log out.
Now that you've logged out of your Ubuntu virtual machine,
in your local machine, make sure that you're still the original ud381 folder.
Type Vagrant destroy in your local machine.
Followed by yes.
And notice that the virtual machine is now destroyed.
Once your VirtualBox is destroyed, you can navigate to vagrantup.com and
follow along by clicking on the documentation.
Once in documentation, click on the Vagrantfile link.
In the Vagrantfile link, notice that the syntax of Vagrantfile is in Ruby.
Next, click on the Provisioning link.
And scroll down to the shell link.
We use a simple shell provisioner, and
scrolling down, and scrolling down you'll find the syntax for external script.
We use the Ruby syntax config.vm.provision with option shell, and
specify the path to our provision.sh instead of script.sh.
So, navigating to our text editor.
And navigating to the Vagrant file.
We simply add in the config.vm.provision with the shell option and
our path is provision.sh.
We then navigate to the provision.sh file and we see a number of Ubuntu
commands to install when the virtual machine is being provisioned.
We add in the python-bs4 package.
And remember to save your provision.sh file.
Once saved, we come back to our Vagrant up command in our terminal.
And notice now the new package of Python-ps4 is being updated.
We also see that our provisioning script fails because some of
the files already exist.
Notice that the provision machine only takes about 20 to 30 seconds to start up.
And this is much, much faster than the 15 or
20 minutes that it took during our initial run.
This is the because the base image has already been downloaded from Vagrant
cloud and now with our Vagrant and provision files we're simply provisioning or
installing our required software and starting services needed for the course.
After provisioning our machine we Vagrant SSH.
And now we can check if our Python bs4 package has been installed correctly.
We can do that dpkg-l and let's search for
python-* to look for all Python packages with a dash.
And scrolling up we see that the python-bs4 package,
the beautiful suit package, has been installed correctly.
Finally, if you're interested in building more virtual machines, or
playing around with provisioning machines.
I encourage you to explore the Vagrant documentation further, and
have some fun doing it.