So here’s my solution for problem 4.6, the CS215.
It’s hopefully quite a readable code, at the slight
expense of running time. I’ll take it over here while
I talk because it takes a while to run. So that’s going.
So if we look at the code here, first we have the
make link function from the lectures. There’s nothing
particularly exciting; it’s pretty much the same, just
with a few more comments in. And the next function
we have is the read graph function which reads the
graph from the IMDB files supplied on the Udacity
website. The movie names are not necessarily
unique, so we have changed this slightly from a
previous example in a lecture to append the year to
the movie name, so we get a unique string for each
movie. Also, we keep track of the actors and movies
we’ve come across so far in a dictionary to allow for
this media processing later. And this is the function
that calculates the centrality of each node. This is
very similar to the one shown in lectures, just with a
couple of small changes to make it slightly more
readable. For example, we’re converting the sum to
float here instead of adding 0.0. The rank function is
the same as we’ve seen in lectures. And finally, we
come to our find rank function. This takes the
dictionary out and finds the key that corresponds to
the ice biggest selling. This is very similar to the K
partitioning algorithm from the lectures, but returns a
single value only, instead of a list. And so whereas
here would be adding two lists together, we’re just
returning the value that it finds in these if statements
at the end. So this is where actually we run the
code. So first of all, we read in our graph and for
each actor, we calculate the centralities and select
the most popular actor before we finally output it to
the screen. So, it’s finished running. We can see that
Dustin Hoffman was the twentieth most central actor
and his centrality was 3.794. So if we now look at
the profiling code over here, we can see that the
centrality function takes most of the time, as we
expect. It is slightly more surprising that the pop
function that we use with centrality, that’s here.
It also takes a large amount of time. And so to start
optimizing, we could remove the cause to pop and
we could use Big Theta 1 algorithm to remove
values from the open list and put down. Also, the
map of potentiality function to all the actors is pretty
parallelizable, so threaded implementation could
save a large amount of actual time. As a lot of
people are trying this on the forums, it might be
worth checking that.