In this blank space, cell A26, we'll type equals sum
A2 colon A24. And we get that the total snowfall
was 122 inches in season one. For season two, we want the
sum from cell B2 all the way to cell B27. If
we type in this command and press Enter, we
get 173. Finally, in cell C28, I'll find the total
precipitation from season three. Which is from C2
to cell C26, and we get 129. So
it looks like it snowed the most in
season two. Great job. If this was tricky, don't
worry. You'll get better and better with using
Google Spreadsheets during this class, and by the
end, you'll be a pro. If you still
have questions, post in the forums. Your amazing peers
are always really quick to answer. But if this
was confusing, play around with Google Spreadsheets a little bit
more. It's important that you're comfortable with learning them,
because then you'll have a better experience throughout this course.