So the goal for the first coding task of
this lesson will be to change the UI
from displaying a single text view with
all the pet data to displaying all
these pets.
So this scrolling ListView will be a
much better user experience for viewing
all the pets in the database. It's much
easier to read format with more white
space and divider lines as well. Plus we
don't need to show unnecessary
information that the user doesn't
necessarily care about, such as the
database real IDs. So each list item here
will show two pieces of relevant
information, summaries of the pet with
its name in bold, and then it's breed down
below. So in the last lesson, recall that we
discussed how this diagram represents
the current state of how we query the
database from the UI code. So display a
list of pets, the catalog activity will
talk to the resolver, which then talk to
the provider, which then does the query
on the database. After which, the cursor
comes back as a result all the way back
to a catalog activity. So right now, we're
going to zoom in on the catalog activity,
and check in on how it modifies the
logic around how to display information
from the cursor into the UI. In earlier
courses we've learned that you can
easily display list information using a
ListView. And populate the information
within the ListView, we're going to need
an adapter. So essentially the adapter is
responsible for making the list item
view for each pet in the datasource, and
then hand them off to this view to show
on screen. so you first learned about
ListViews and adapters when building
out the Miwok language app used to
display a list of words. Now let's review
how is it used and then we can build on that
concept further for our pets use case. So
recall that the ListView takes up the
whole width and height of the screen, but
it starts off empty, so now here that the
list is empty. So the WordAdapter is
what holds onto the data source. Here, we
had a list of words, and the WordAdapter
also had instructions knowing how to
make a list item for each of these words.
So first the list you will need to
consult with the WordAdapter to figure out
eventually
how many words we need to be displayed,
after which it starts off by asking for
the list item at position zero. The
adapter helps us identify the zeroth
word in its data source, construct the
list item for that one word, and then
passes this back to our ListView. so
after the ListView has added this item
to the layout, is going to ask for
ListView at position 1, the adapter find
the corresponding word creates a proper
list item, and then hands it back to the
ListView. so this back-and-forth process
will keep repeating, so the ListView will
keep requesting list items for each
position in the list until either there
are no more words, or until the screen is
full. So for example if there are 10
words in our list but only 7 can fit on
the screen, then we don't need to request
the eighth word just yet. so this clever
behavior of not requesting views that
aren't shown to the user just yet is
what makes the ListView adapter
combination such an efficient use of
memory resources. So for the views that
are scrolled off-screen, we go ahead and
recycle them and simply swap out the
text and image, though it's gonna be used
for a different word so with a smaller
number of view objects to deal with
scrolling performance in a ListView can
become very smooth and fast, so is noted
here the adapter is responsible for
making a list item view for each item in
the data source, for example if our data
source is ArrayList such as an array
list of words, then we're going to use an
array adapter to populate that list. Now
if the data source is a cursor, such as a
cursor of pets, they were going to be
using a CursorAdapter to populate that
list. So let's head back to the pets app
and see all that in action. So the catalog
activity we wouldn't defining a ListView
that takes up the full width and height
of the screen, and again the list starts
off empty. Next we're going to set up a
CursorAdapter to hold onto the cursor
of pets, which will receive from the
provider, we also want to make sure that
the CursorAdapter knows how to create a
list item view per pet.
So ListView start off by asking
adapter how many items will eventually
be shown a list. Next
it starts off by asking for each one of
those items starting at position zero.
The adapter moves the cursor to the
zeroth row, and extracts out the column
values so that I can set up a proper
list item for this pet, and then passes
this list item you back to our ListView,
next the list you asked for the item at
position 1, the CursorAdapter moves the
cursor to row one, without this values,
and these values are used to create the
corresponding ListView which will
get past back to our ListView. This same
process is repeated for the next
position, position 2. ListView will
keep requesting these items for each
position until there are other no more
pets in the cursor, or until this screen
is full.
So the next coding task, we will ask you to
modify the catalog activity to have a
ListView and a custom CursorAdapter so
let's walk through some of the details
of that code together.