Once you're on the correct
branch go ahead and
open up the text fields project and
run it.
Type into all three fields and
watch for similarities and
differences in the behavior
of the three views.
Also if you need to dismiss
the simulator keyboard
you can do that in the Hardware menu.
Go to Hardware > Keyboard >
Toggle Software Keyboard.
You can also use the shortcut Cmd+k.
When you've picked out some
commonalities across the text fields.
Answer the quiz question.
Compare and contrast the following
features of the three text fields.
Presenting the keyboard.
Response to new characters being typed.
Rounded corners.
Reaction to the return button.
And behavior when editing begins.
Mark features that differ
between the three with a check.