Here's my approach of adding a spout to the topology.
In part one of the command line, we navigate to lesson 1 stage 2.
I can do that by cd dot dot, or cd space doe dot, ls, and cd stage2.
In part 2,
in stage 2, we navigate to the new ReporterExclamationTopology.java file.
Therefore in lesson one, stage two we go to source JVM udacity, storm and
the reporter exclamation topology.
Notice again, that this is the entire solution to stage 1,
if you ever run into problems.
In part 3 we see the added spout under the spout folder.
Random sentence spout, which is here in storm spout and random sentence spout.
We then enter the import statement,
with the package structure using package udacity dot storm as a hint.
Scrolling down to the begin stage two exercise part one of two
we import our random sentence spout.
And that's simply, udacity.storm.spout.RandomSentenceSpout, which
corresponds to the structure udacity storm spout RandomSentenceSpout.
You'll find throughout this course that I like to test often,
so, run mvn package, just to get in the habit.
Back at your command line, type mvn package in lesson one, stage two,
and we see a, we have a build success,
which means we imported our random sentence outcome correctly.
After our build success in Part Four,
we update the topology builder to first, ignore the TestWordSpout.
Back in our ReporterExclamationTopology, we scroll down to our TopologyBuilder,
and we want to ignore the TestWordSpout, which we can do by simply commenting.
In part B, we add the RandomSentenceSpout with an id rand-sentence,
using a parallelism of ten.
I'll use the test word spout as an example.
And I can copy and paste.
We want an ID of ran sentence.
And instead of a new test word spout, we want a new random sentence spout and
finally we leave the parallelism at ten.
In part C, we connect the exclaim one bolt to the random sentence spout
using the ID rand-sentence.
Back in our topology builder, you could either update the shuffle grouping
connection from word to rand-sentence, or you can simply common tab
that section, copy and paste and use the syntax of word, to link rand-sentence.
In this way we've connected our spout of rand-sentence to
the bolt exclaim1 using a shuffle grouping connection.
Next we see the bolt exclaim2,
is connected to exclaim1 using another shuffle grouping.
and in this way we can build up a topology.
Next, we package our program, using MVN package.
Next you can use the tree method, t-r-e-e, to see your file structure and
next we submit our program using storm jar target.
Remember you can use tab, Udacity, space jar with dependencies,
and the structure Udacity.storm ReporterExclamationTopology.
And hopefully with a built success and submitting your Storm program,
you are able to enjoy your visualization with random sentences and
exclamations appended at the end.
Preach on modifying your first topology.