So some of the most common things we
do with files are to move them around,
copy them, change their names,
things like that.
Let's see how to do some of
those things in the shell.
So the shell command to move files
is MV, which is short for move.
The simplest way to use it is to just
give it one file that you want to move
and the directory you
want to move it to.
You could also use it to rename files,
to move a file to a different name in
the same directory, or
to move several files into a directory.
Copying files is very similar.
The command is cp for copy.
As with mv, you give it the name of
the file that you want to copy and
where you want to copy it to.
And that can be a different file
name in the same directory, or
a file name in a different directory.
Or it could just be a directory that
you want to put the new copy in.
Both of these commands
support a lot of options.
You should read the manual pages for
both of them.
But here's something else
you might be wondering.
Mv, cp, rm, why do you think these
commands have such short names?
Put your answer here, and then we'll
share our thoughts on the matter.