For the last, part of the lesson, I want to talk about a much more
modern approach to using these Hough transform, displacement vectors.
In fact it was proposed as recently as 2004,
and subsequently, as a way of, locating a particular object.
What we're going to do now is, instead of using edges or
the idea of high, high value gradients as a, as a feature that you can find.
What we're going to use are little feature patches, all right?
And feature patches are just little chunks of an image that, for some reason,
for, for one reason or
another, you've decided, these are useful things to try to go find.
So, if you have those, this is the way that would work.
So we have a training image here, and
I'm going to assume for now that our feature patch is tire, and I'll tell you in
a minute about how we go about finding those feature patches, all right?
And so here I've located the tire in two different places, and so
in the same way as with the gradient, so when I first find it here,
I say, okay, there's a displacement vector to the right like that.
And I'll put that in a table that's indexed by the feature patch.
And then I find that, oop, I found it again, it's over here, and it's index, and
it, it has a displacement vector to the left, like that.
So I put that in a, in the same table, and
in fact it's indexed by the same feature type.
So, these features are referred to as visual codewords, which I'll describe in
just a minute, and the idea that I would have a table based upon the codewords.
And associated with each codeword is the set of displacement vectors that I
have to vote with every time I find that feature anywhere in the image.