So the first, second and
fifth of these are probably true.
Unless you work at google your
computer is probably not directly on
their network.
And just because computers is up and
running doesn't mean that it
has a web server running on it.
For instance the machine that
you're using to watch this course
has an IP address.
But it only has a web server
if you've started one on it.
But it's on some network, and
that network is somehow
connected through to Google's.
The reason that we know this is that
ping sent some traffic to this address,
8.8.8.8, and it got responses back.
So that means not only that we're on
a network and that they're on a network,
but that we're on a network
that can talk to theirs.