We'll be representing colors using
a color class provided by libGDX.
To find out how it works, let's
check out the libGDX documentation.
You can find the libGDX website
at libGDX.badlogicgames.com, or
just by searching of course.
There's a link to
the documentation in the nav bar.
Let's click it then,
if we scroll down a bit,
we find a whole bunch
of awesome resources.
But, what we're looking for is number 8.
Read the Javadocs.
And now,
to find information on the Color class.
We can just search the page for a color.
There we go.
Let's check it out.
Awesome.
We've got a color class holding the RGB
and alpha components as
floats in the range 0 to 1.
Scrolling down we see that there's
also a whole bunch of predefined color
constants.
Why don't you go check out
the libGDX color documentation and
see if you can figure out which of these
is not a predefined color constant?
Firebrick, periwinkle,
goldenrod or chartreuse.