Using the Memcache API is really simple.
You call the set, get or
delete commands supplying the key for
the Memcache entry.
In the case of the set method, you also
supply the string that you'd like to be
the value and the get method will return
the value for the key that you provide.
They key can be any string.
For our code, we'll make it a constant,
because we'll be using it repeatedly
when retrieving and
deleting announcements from Memcache.
You also need a method that queries
conferences to find if they're any you
want to put into the cache.
An if so,
setting an entry in the Memcache API.
You want to query for
conferences that are almost sold out,
that have seats less than or
equal to five, but more than zero.
You don't really want to expose this
functionality as an endpoint, so
this should be a private method.
Later, we'll talk about using
scheduled job or cron jobs.
We will need to find a way to call
this function via a regular, but
protected URL.
What we'll do is create a separate file,
main.py that will have a function there
that uses that
cacheAnnouncements function and
also sets ahead the furry URL.
We'll also add this to app.yaml
in the form of an entry forward
/crons/set_announcement.
Secured by having login: admin.
Login: admin means that cron and
application developers will be able to
access this URL, but not regular users.
And it'll let you test it just by going
to your app and adding this path.
You can implement this on your own or
take a look at the provided sample code.
The application logic in this
case is not that important.
Mostly, this is just to demonstrate
the use of the Memcache API.
So now there also has to be an endpoint
method for getting the announcement, so
it can be displayed
somewhere in the app.
You'll also have to
finish the code here.
And for endpoints, we'll also
need a simple message class for
the outgoing message announcement.
Because you can't just use
strings with endpoints,
you have to use ProtoRPC classes.
So let's call that class StringMessage
and have just one field in there,
which is required.
So there's quite a bit of work to do.
Take a look again at the TODO
in the provided code.
Remember, you can test your announcement
setting function by searching for
that Memcache key in
the developer console.
And you can see if your announcement
reading endpoint method works by testing
it in the APIs Explorer.
So, as you complete these steps, check
them off and then put your app id here.