The correct answer is, all of the above.
For instance, when we have multiple consumer threads,
one consumer thread is waiting.
It wakes up from the Wait statement because the list is full.
However, before it gets to actually process that list,
we acquired the mutex and processed that list.
Newly arriving other consumers, they will reacquire the mutex,
see that the list is actually full, and print and remove its contents.
So, the one consumer that was waiting on the list when the signal or
broadcast notification arrived, when it comes out of the wait, the list,
its state has already changed.
So, we need the while in order to deal with situations where there
are multiple of these consumer threads,
multiple threads that are waiting on the same condition.
This is related, also,
to the second statement in that when we signal a condition, we have
no way to guarantee the order in which the access to the mutex will be granted.
So, there may be other threads that will require this mutex before you
get to respond on the fact that a condition has been signaled.
And so in that regard, if you cannot control the access to the mutex and
guarantee it, you have no way to guarantee that the value of this list
variable will not change before the consumer gets to have access to it again.
So, all of these three factors contribute to the fact that we have to
use while in order to make sure that when we wake up from a while statement,
indeed this condition that we were waiting on, it is met.