Now we're getting somewhere.
We've got data from the Internet
showing up in Sunshine, but
let's make it a bit easier to test.
We'll add a menu that allows for us to
refresh the view with new weather data.
This is especially cool if you're
using the random weather server.
Open S02-02-Exercise Menus.
Look at your to dos.
This is going to look a lot like what
you did to add that menu to the get up
query app earlier.
First, add a Refresh string
called action_refresh.
Then, create a new menu
resource called forecast.
We then inflate our new menu
in onCreateOptionsMenu and
we handle the menu actions
in onOptionItemSelected.
A good idea to make it clear that
things are working is to clear
the weatherTextView immediately and
call loadWeatherData.
You can do this by setting
the text view to empty text.