To answer this first question,
let's take a look at the database.
As JP showed us,
I can actually click here on list name,
which is the specific piece of
data that I'm interested in.
And up here, I can actually see
the URL that is specifically related
to the list name piece of data.
Here I've got the name
of my shopping list app,
shoppinglistplspls.firebasedio.com, and
then we have the name of the key,
which is just listName.
So I can copy this, okay, and the next
question is, when the listener that's
attached to the list name is triggered,
what will you do with the data.
We're going to want to
update the UI here.
It has a couple of text views in here,
which we'll probably want to
change using set text, and
we can update that text view
using whatever the user entered.
All right, let's get to it.