We can see this going on in images.
So here's a nicer picture showing you aliasing in images.
So you can see what's happening is that this is a radial sine wave,
and you can see as you get closer and
closer, the pixels are supposed to be wiggling faster and faster.
And eventually I run out of pixels.
Okay, I don't have enough samples to get how quickly the thing varies.
And so that is an example of aliasing here.
So, what is its impact on you?
Well, its impact on you is you have to be a little careful how you treat your
images, for example, and this comes from Steve, all right?
Suppose I've got this image, a beautiful Van Gogh picture.
Suppose it's too big to fit on a screen.
I want a smaller version of it.
How can we reduce it?
I don't know. Make it half the size or quarter of its size to do that.
Well, one obvious way would be to throw away every other column and
every other row, all right?
Just throw those away.
And that's called image sub-sampling.
Now by the way here it says by half,
what it means is I throw away half the columns and
half the rows, which of course is actually a quarter size smaller, right.
But half meaning, half the rows, half the columns.
If I did that again, I would now have one quarter of the total rows,
one quarter of the total columns, one-sixteenth the size.
I could do it again, one-eighth.
In fact, you might start to notice this is already looking a little ugly.
And in fact, to make it clear exactly how ugly it is, let me blow up the half,
the quarter and
the eighth by zooming in on both of them just blowing up the pixels.
And you'll notice, this is atrocious, okay.
The, the one-half one doesn't look too bad, but remember here we've only
taken one out of every eight columns and one out of every eight rows.
And then we blow, blew the thing back up.
And you can see that this does not look like a blurry version of
the original, okay.
And the reason is we have aliasing.
We have sampled too infrequently for the amount of variation that there is.
Essentially, things wiggling here more often than one out of every eight.
And so if I just take one eighth, right, I'm not capturing all the wiggles.
So what's the right thing to do?
Well, we need to do that anti-aliasing, we just learned that.
So, a simple one is to do Gaussian, okay?
So, what we'll do is we'll filter, right, so we'll take the Gaussian and
then take every other row, all right?
And then if you want to be not so clever about this, you could do a Gaussian of
that, and take every other row of that, to get the one quarter.
And you could do the Gaussian again, and do that.
Or, what you could do is you do a much bigger Gaussian to begin with, and
take one out of every eight.
You can convince yourself that mathematically these are going to be equivalent.
When I do that, and I blow up the Gaussian one-eighth, you'll see
that this actually looks pretty much like a blurry version of that, right?
Compare this to what we did with the subsampling, right?
So here's sort of our original.
Here is the Gaussian eighth 4x zoom.
And here is the subsample 4x zoom.
And you can see that the Gaussian does a much better job doing the reduction and
that's because it's been anti-aliased.
So if you're doing Computer Vision and you decide, you know, what I've got
this huge 1920 by 1080 image coming in, but I'm just trying to recognize faces,
all right, and my faces are going to be, you know, 100 pixels big let's say.
And you say, you know what?
What I can do is, it's going to be expensive to do that face recognition.
We're going to talk about face recognition towards the end of the class.
It's expensive to do that over the entire image, when it's so big.
Let me make the image, you know, one-eighth its size this way,
one-eighth its size that way.
And, I'll make my faces smaller, and look for them that way.
You know what?
That will work pretty well, if you do this, if you do anti-aliasing.
If you just pull out the arbitrary pixels right,
you're going to make a mess of the whole thing.
You'll get aliasing, and then the faces won't look right.
So that's why doing this kind of stuff matters even in computer vision.