Now you've seen how to query for
all of your data.
But in Sunshine, you'll also
want the ability to query for
just one day of weather to display.
So let's look at how you can modify
your query code to retrieve just
one row of data.
Let's think about this
in terms of SQL code.
To select all the data in a table,
you write a select all query.
And to narrow down the number
of rows that are returned,
you can use a WHERE clause.
A WHERE clause retrieves data
only when it fits some criteria.
For tasks, this could be only
tasks with priority equal to one.
Or that fit a certain description.
And to retrieve a single row of data,
you have to ask for
it with a unique criteria
which is its id.
This is all well and good,
but how can do the same thing
using only our provider query?
Well, a provider will translate method
calls into the correct SQL code
to interact with data.
And to construct a WHERE clause,
it uses the selection and
selectionArgs parameters
of its query method.
Let's see how this looks in code.