So to quickly summarize in this lecture,
I just wanted to get you started
thinking about what is video and
what are the representations, videos,
building off the concept that we have
studied extensively, that is images.
The concept of persistence of vision
plays an important role in this one for
both capturing and then, of course,
visualizing and playing videos back.
We talked about how we can basically
take the same concepts of filtering and
processing images, everything we
learned, except now we will do it
in three dimensions,
not just X and Y, but X, Y, and T.
And then we talked about,
we can actually apply some of
the point the detection feature,
detection methods, and use that to track
interesting information across videos.
Of course same kinds of techniques
are used to do people tracking and
stuff like that.
Again, we won't get into this kind
of stuff in this class, but for
those of you who are taking
the computer vision class some time,
will learn a lot more about it.
Please find additional information
both in the Rick Szeliski book, but
also just look at my website.
There's a lot of fun
stuff about on videos.
My group, as I said, works extensively
in the area of videos, and we have loads
of examples and I'm going to be showing
you a whole lot of them in this class.