The most important thing
about a bitonic sort is that
everything boils down to by doing
bitonic merges efficiently.
Let's start with an network for
a 16-element bitonic merge.
I'm going to draw it in
a simplified form as follows.
The left-hand set of
dots are the inputs.
Now remember that the first step of
the algorithm is a bitonic split
which is computed in place.
I'll represent the split using
this next column of dots.
So for example, this dot is the part
of the split that computes the min
of this input and this input.
The max you would,
of course, compute here.
So these edges indicate the dependencies
between these two outputs and
these two inputs.
Now the remaining pairs of
dependencies would look the same.
The result is two bitonic
subsequences at stage one.
So here is one bitonic subsequence and
here's the other.
Now remember we're talking
about a bitonic merge so
the computation in dependencies will
repeat within each subsequence.
For instance, here's the first
pair from the first subsequence.
Within this first subsequence,
the pattern repeats.
And we will see the same thing
within this second subsequence.
Let me fill out the rest to the end.
So this picture of a bitonic merge
shows us where the inputs are,
where the outputs are, and
the pattern of dependencies.
So what does a distributed
algorithm look like?
For the distributed case, let's divide
the elements among processing nodes.
For example, here's one division.
So in this example there
are four processing nodes and
I've divided them by assigning
consecutive sets of inputs to each node.
So let's think about this.
Where does communication happen?
Well, anywhere a dependence edge
crosses a process boundary,
there has to be some
sort of communication.
For example, consider these edges.
According to this picture,
this process has to send these
elements to this process.
Similarly, the same process has to
send data back to the first process.
This pattern is sometimes
called a binary exchange,
as there are two processes
swapping data with one another.
Okay, you ready for something cool?
Notice that edges cross process
boundaries only up until this point.
In fact, there are just log P
stages in this first block,
which means only log P
rounds of communication.
In the remaining log n over P stages,
no edges cross process boundaries,
meaning there is no communication.
So from this analysis I
hope you can see how to
estimate the communication time for
bitonic merge.
Now, this isn't the only way
to distribute data and work.
Here's another scheme.
Here I've assigned each row of
the network to a different process in
a round-robin fashion.
The scheme is sometimes called a cyclic
distribution or cyclic assignment.
Although it's a little bit harder
to see, the communication versus
local computation phases are similar to
the previous block distribution scheme.
For example, consider this input.
Let's follow its outgoing
dependences at every stage.
During the first log n over P stages,
there's only local computation.
The remaining log P rounds
require non-local exchanges.
The patterns you've seen so far tell you
something about the number of messages
that need to be sent, but
what about the volume of communication?
Again, let's ask how much data
does the first process send?
You can verify that in each stage,
this first process needs
to send n over P words.
This is the same as the block
distributed scheme.