All right, welcome back to computer vision.
We're going to to continue our discussion about frequency analysis and
how to study images with notion of frequency components.
If you remember last time we talked about the idea of
decomposing images based upon frequency.
And we motivated it by showing you this picture.
This is that famous Dali picture which when you allow the high frequency imagery
in there, you see a picture of a woman admiring the, the Mediterranean or
something like that.
But when you blur it, that is when you remove the high frequency you just
have the low frequency, it becomes a picture of Lincoln.
And this idea of how do we decompose images into thinking about what was
going to be a basis set of that involved frequency and
the idea that a basis set was going to be some set of functions that
we're going to linearly span our possible signal.
So the idea is that we should build and make any possible signal out of
this set, and that they are linearly independent so
I can ebb which basically allows me to do this summation.
We're also going to end up within our Foginal basis set so that when you
change the amount of one basis element you don't get any change in the others.
And the basis set that we were talking about was this Fourier set, right?
And the Fourier set basically decomposed things into sinusoids and they were
sinusoids here of increasing frequency that were sort of moving vertically and
horizontally, and the idea is that we could construct images doing this.
So related to that idea was this notion of what we call the Fourier Transform,
and the Fourier Transform was that you would put in a signal, showing it here in
1D, but also talk about it in 2D, and what you would get out was instead of f
as a function of x, that is the intensities of function of location,
you got out a F, cap F, as a function of I L Mayer, omega was frequency.
And the idea is that cap F would decompose into an even component and
an odd component being represented by complex numbers, and so this would
allow us to represent both the magnitude and the phase for a given frequency.
And if you wanted to, you could recover that magnitude and phase.
The magnitude is just the square root of the sum of the squares of each of
the real and imaginary component, and
the phase was just this arc tan of this relation.
To do the Fourier Transform is represented by this
sort of ugly looking integral.
Here I'm showing it to you in 1D, we'll do it again in a minute in 2D.
But the idea was you took your function and
you integrate from minus infinity to infinity.
And you multiplied it by sinusoids of whatever frequency and
sometimes frequencies omega.
When we're going to do it for two dimensions u and v,
so here's it's written as u.
And even though this does not look like a sinusoid,
you had to remember that e to the i k was cosine k plus i sine k.
So this is what allowed us to go from the spatial domain to
the frequency domain.
We also mentioned that you could inverse this, if you wanted to, right?
So if you give me the Fourier transform f of
u of a signal thereby just changing whether that's plus or
minus, I can do the integral and get back the original signal.
But now we have both u and v.
We also talked about the discrete version.
And we showed some examples here where you're taking the sums instead of
the integrals.
And most of the time, we're mostly interested in the power.
Remember, the square root of the sum of the squares?
And that's represented here.
So I might have a,
a signal that has a certain amount of even part and an odd part, or
the real, imaginary, you take the square root of the sum of the squares and
you got the magnitude, and the magnitude of the power is what we'll typically be
talking about when we talk about the presence of frequency with any given image.
We want to know the power of it.
The phase is important for doing reconstruction but
in general, we're not going to be doing a reconstruction.
So today, what we're going to do is in this lesson,
is we're just going to relate the Fourier transform to convolution.
And in particular, how it's,
how convolution in space is multiplication in frequency.
And let me show you how that works.