Hey, Peter here. Time for another office hours, and unfortunately this week, again, Sebastian can't be with us.
He's gotten a little bit sick and has lost his voice.
However, we went over the questions together and answered them together in written form.
So I'm going to discuss that now.
So for half the questions, just imagine I have a German accent and I'm a little bit more handsome.
So the first question is, "Can you discuss common filters, their importance, usage and algorithms?"
And particle filters were discussed, but common filters were only mentioned briefly.
And yes, it's true, common filters are an important form of filtering, and they existed before they were popular in AI.
They were important in control theory. They've been used in a lot of engineering applications.
One of the first was at NASA Ames, where they were used in the Apollo Program, that was before my time at Ames.
But were historically important.
It's only in recent years that particle filters have been used in more applications.
The difference, I think, is that common filters are great if the state is largely known, and we're just trying to track it more exactly.
For example, if you have a spacecraft or an airplane that's flying in mostly a straight line,
but you want to know precisely where it is, common filter is a great way to go.
But if you got something with a more erratic movement, something that's making kind of binary decisions
and going right or left, like say a person walking through a crowd, then particle filters are better than common filters
at representing that kind of movement.
Now, next question is from Jamie in Oxford, Ohio:
"This is just a clarification on Laplacian smoothing. In the lecture videos, the K parameter is assumed to be one.
"In real-life applications, how exactly would K be determined?"
And Sebastian says for the application he knows having to do with robotics and so on, K is usually one.
In some natural language applications, different values of K are chosen.
It really has to do with how much you trust the accumulated evidence, versus how much you want to look towards the future.
So you can just set it by hand to one. I think that's the important step, is to do anything at all,
if you have, especially in cases with high dimensional data, using some value of K greater than zero
is usually much better than not using it, which corresponds to the maximum likelihood estimator.
If you're nervous about choosing a particular value, then you can always try to learn it
using some of the machine learning techniques that we've talked about.
For example, cross-validation could be a good way to go.
Take out some of the data, try it with K=1, try it with K=2, and so on,
and then choose the one that performs the best on the held out data.
Next question is, "I wonder how HMMs are used for speech recognition? Regarding speech as noise,
"and noise as the addition of sine waves, what are the hidden Marcobian states in a wave?"
Well, usually speech recognition represents the sine or the sound wave in a set of features in some transform space.
Sometimes a (Foyer) space, or what's called a (Mell Hebstrom) space, which is similar.
So you extract some of the features, you represent each state with that.
And so you're breaking it out in that domain, and then you're also breaking it out in the time domain--
Maybe ten or so frames per second. So each one of those would be a state linked to the previous state.
And there's usually not that much hidden state at each node.
You could have some hidden state corresponding to different types of speakers, different dialects,
male versus female and so on.
Then the output from each state is the phoneme or part of the phoneme that the sound represents,
and the process of speech recognition is then finding a best path through your network that outputs those phonemes
and string those phonemes together to make words and string the words together to make a sentence.
Next question is from Frederick Johnson in Stockholm.
"I just heard about Markov chain Monte Carlo or MCMC. It would be interesting to hear a bit about that."
So this is an advanced topic for estimating a probability density for a Bayesian network.
And rather than propagating exact values throughout the graph like we did with variable elimination,
MCMC is an approximation technique. So something like particle filters are a very basic way of performing MCMC.
But there are other techniques as well. So anything that making a selection and making an approximation
would count as an MCMC algorithm.
Next comes from MJL in Vienna. "The mind mapping robot uses particle filters for location,
"yet it only builds the map as it goes along. How can I use particle filters without a map? Isn't that a chicken and egg?
"You cannot locate because you have no map, and you cannot build an exact map because you have zero location (amount)."
So that's a great question, and it is a real problem. It's a separate problem from treating one of them alone.
And the problem has been known as SLAM, which stands for Simultaneous Localization and Mapping.
And there's an algorithm called FastSLAM in the literature, that's a great one, that uses particle filtering.
So if you're into building, if you're building a map as a robot moves, you need to attach a map to each particle filter,
and that's basically the trick. So each filter has a location, and then it also has a map associated with it.
And the theory is a little bit complicated. It actually turns out that Mike Montemerlo, who wrote a Ph.D. thesis
on this FastSLAM algorithm, Mike was a software lead for Sebastian's project that won the DARPA Grand Challenge
with his car, and Mike now works at Google.
Next question is from Monty. "Hi. As you know, due to lack of programming homeworks, can you provide a quick guide
"as to how we could start programming or recommend a book or site for this issue? Thanks."
Well, I have a textbook on A.I. programming, but it's almost 20 years old now, so maybe that's not the best first place to start.
I'd say probably the best more recent book on A.I. programming doesn't sound like it--
doesn't sound like it's an A.I. programming book, but it is, which is Toby Segaran, "Programming Collective Intelligence."
If you want to go beyond books, if you like A.I. in games, you can check out the website aiwisdom.com.
If you like natural language, try The Natural Language Toolkit, which is NLTK.com.
And related question: "Can you recommend a program or two to simulate robots physically,
"and another program other than Nero," the neuro evolving site that we've told you about, "to train agents?"
And that's from Noreldon in Cairo.
Well, I haven't kept up with all of the options there, but one I really like is called Pyro Robotics--
PyroRobotics.org. And that has a number of simulators where you can simulate robots,
and the great thing about them is that if you actually have a physical robot as well, you can run the simulation,
and then they have a method for hooking up the same code to the actual physical robot.
Here's another question about particle filters, this is from Trainor in Rome:
"Sorry, I find the description of particle filters quite confusing. Could you please clarify the meaning of U in sampling part?"
So the U is the controls. That is how the movement of the agent or the actions of the agents are going to change.
And sometimes we give specific action commands to a robot,
and whatever happens next is a function of those commands, and we call that U.
"Could you please clarify why particle filters are not good in situations where uncertainty of measurements or controls is very low?"
And that's from Andrei in Russia. So these are extreme cases, and when measurements have no uncertainty,
then it's quite unlikely to guess a state that corresponds exactly to any given measurement.
And take for example range sensors. If the ranges are measured exactly, without any noise whatsoever,
then only states that meet those measurements exactly will have non-zero importance weights.
And so it's a bit of a problem, as in practice all the guesses would be wrong.
Now, if there is uncertainty in measurements, then pretty much any state could have a small non-zero probability.
And it's the same with actions. So if actions and controls are perfect, we never really spread out the particles
in the next state prediction, and this means we can never generate particle outside the set of initial particles.
Or put differently, if we fail to guess the exact initial state with at least one particle, we can't get a good solution.
And those are all extreme cases because it's really only in an artificial game or something that you have no uncertainty at all.
So it's a little academic. In real life there's plenty of uncertainty and there's no problem.
I guess maybe a metaphor to think about it is trying to shine a flashlight out to figure out where you are:
With any real flashlight, the beam spreads out and you have a variety and you can see a pretty big distance,
you see a large circle for the flashlight's beam.
If you had a laser instead of a flashlight, then you'd only see a little dot. So the laser corresponds to having no uncertainty,
you see this little dot, you can never spread out and explore more.
But in real life it's like the flashlight: You're spreading out as you go out into the future, and you usually have no trouble.
"Can we use a particle filter if the environment is changing? Like in the room example, if furniture's being moved around,
"can a robot still navigate?" Yes, that can be done, but it's not trivial because you need this map that has sort of time as a function,
needs to have some idea of what can change and not change.
The environment change introduces systematic noise in this case, and that can have bad side effects,
so it's difficult to get that right.
"Unit 11.2 looks like a batch update on all the particles. Will this method still work if we do a sequential particle update of S instead?
"That is, update our working copy of S rather than keeping it separate, S prime, and then swapping them over?"
That's from John in Singapore. And the best suggestion I can come up with is, yes, we think that that will work,
and that it will converge. But it's not commonly done.
And basically, it's just not a difficulty to keep two separate states and swap them back and forth,
and modern machines have plenty of memory, it's easy to do that, and the math is worked out, so we understand how that works,
so that's just how it's usually done.
Next question is from Gefetti in Turin. "Is it possible to use A.I. in production scheduling?
"I know of cases where I feel a stochastic approach would be really helpful, and usually we just work with mean time between failure.
"It seems better to use A.I." So yes, A.I. is used in real-world production scheduling.
For example, we used it in the Deep Space One spacecraft, which was controlled by an on-board planning and scheduling program.
Scheduling was an important part of it. The majority of real world scheduling is done by techniques from operations research,
which has a large overlap with A.I. techniques. For example, constraint programming started out in A.I.,
but now has shifted largely over into the operations research community. And so it's sort of a combination there of A.I.
and kind of linear programming-type techniques. And broadly used in industry.
And last question is from Mitchy in the UK. "In HMMs, how would you deal with multiple independent hidden states?
"We saw an example of rain/sun with happy/grumpy measurements. What if it was rain and pay rise and illness and so on,
"sort of many states in a month?" That just means the internal hidden state would grow exponentially.
And we can do that either by multiplying out and having one state variable that has all the values,
or by using something called a dynamic Bayesian network, which was actually introduced by my officemate, Tom Dean,
where each individual state, rather than being a single state variable, has a little Bayesian network,
but they're linked together just like a normal HMM.
Okay. So that's it for this week. Thanks for all the great questions, and we'll see you again soon.