Here's a list of the major things you've done so far. The z-test, t-test,
ANOVA, or f-test, correlation and regression. And all of this has used
numerical data. We've been able to take the average and standard deviation.
Calculate our test statistics and do hypothesis testing. To start off this
lesson, we're going to go a little deeper into numerical data. There are three
different kinds that we want you to pay attention to. So I'm going to ask you a
few questions just to get you thinking. Here are three examples of data:
percentage correct on a test, finishing order in a race and temperature in
degree Celsius. So, just imagine for example that we had 100 values for each.
We have 100 students, and we know what percent each of them got on a particular
test. Or we had 100 runners, and we notes who finished first, second, third,
etcetera, all the way to 100. And then we have, let's say, 100 different cities
around the world, and we note their average daily temperature and degree
Celsius. For each of these data examples, indicate which characteristic fits.
Are the data a simple rank. Or are they ranks with equal intervals? Meaning
that the distance between a value of five and six, let's say, is the same as
the difference between eight and nine. Or, are they ranks with equal intervals
and an absolute zero? Meaning that there can never be a value less than zero.
This is kind of a tricky question, and hopefully I explained it adequately
without giving away the answers. Give it some thought and make your best guess.