Up until now, we've been declaring lots
of variables with the keyword var.
Now, I want to talk about its companion,
the keyword let.
In Swift, there are two different
ways to assign a name to a value.
They are constants and variables.
Constants are defined
using the keyword let, and
variables are defined
using the keyword var.
Not surprisingly, once the value of a
constant is set, it can't be reassigned.
The value remains constant.
So one should use let when assigning
a value that's not expected to change.
Variables, on the other hand,
can be reassigned.
So one should use var when assigning
a value that's expected to change.
And if we output our personalized
encouragement we see that it
takes the change.
So it started as, you can do it,
Stephanie and then we changed it to,
you can do it, Ryder.
Here's another example, the constant
birthYear doesn't change but
as time progresses forward
the current year changes, so
at first it's 2016 and
then maybe it changes to 2016.
And therefore the age also changes and
we could see printed at the bottom
our age was initially seven and
then after the year changed to 2016,
the age became eight.
But notice that context matters as well.
This example assumes that
the variable age is going to
be calculated multiple times.
If age were only intended
to be calculated once,
then we could go ahead and declare age
and even current year as constants.
When in doubt,
declare constants over variables.
Any time a value is altered,
it should be explicit.
And this protects our code from
inadvertently changing values that we
don't want changed.