We're ready to start
building Flick Finder.
Here, I have the starter code project,
which you can download from
the link in the instructor notes.
Let's run it to see what we have.
The UI's fairly simple, we have a title,
a place where our image will go here
in the middle, and then we have UI to
support the different text search,
and a latitude and longitude search.
There's also some space left
below the text fields so
we can display the image's title or
error information.
If we open up the ViewController.swift
file, we can see that actions have
already been connected for
both of our search buttons.
We have the searchByPhrase action and
the searchByLatLon action.
We also have this method called
displayImageFromFlickrBySearch
that takes a dictionary of parameters,
and
this is where we'll make our
search request to Flickr.
We left some comments in the search
actions that say we need
to add the necessary parameters for
the methodParameters dictionary.
So there's one there and one here.
And this is similar to the approach
we took in Sleeping In The Library,
where we're going to build our
methodParameters dictionary and
then we'll pass it to
displayImageFromFlickrBySearch.
And there we'll construct our URL and
make our request.
Now the rest of the code in this view
controller is primarily for the showing
and hiding of the keyboards that come up
when we have our text field selected.
And also it has some code for
the checking of, did we enter
a valid latitude or longitude?
Is the string empty when
we're trying to search for?
I'm sorry.
Is the text empty when we're trying to
do the text search?
And all those little edge cases.
But there is one more method that I
want to show that we provided for
your convenience.
It's called flickerURLFromParameters.
This method uses the classes
we just discussed.
NSURLComponents and NSURLQueryItem.
And what this method does is it takes
in parameters that you pass it, and
then it constructs a URL for
the Flickr request.
So, no more escapeParameters method.
Just pass this method, a dictionary of
the name value parameter pairs, and
it'll construct a URL for
the Flickr API.
Now let's take a peek at
the constant.swift file.
Here, like before in
the Sleeping In The Library app,
we've defined some useful
constants that you can use as
you're writing the networking code for
this app.
Okay, now to the exercise.
What I want you to do is
correctly add the parameters for
the methodParameters dictionary so that
it contains all the arguments needed to
perform a text search using
the flicker.photos.search method.
Now remember, at your disposal,
you have the constants that we've
defined in constants.swift,
and you'll also need to adjust your
API key, make sure you do that.
And then the only other odd ball
parameter is that you'll need to
include the text that's
provided by the user.
And then,
when displayImageFromFlickrBySearch is
called, print the URL that's constructed
by our flickrURLFromParameters
method into the debug area.
And if you do everything correctly you
should end up with a URL that looks
like this one,
assuming of course that the user inputs
the text oranges in their search.
And you'll also want to have your
api_key and not this little placeholder.
So take some time to code this up.
And when you're done, check this box.