So this basic idea of finding corners in, in thinking about it this way.
I don't know if I would say that it was first introduced.
But I'll say that it was most well known introduced way back in 1988.
I know some of you guys were, like, in diapers.
And some of you were, a dream in your parents' eyes.
And some of you were a nightmare in your, no, whatever.
It's a long time ago, all right?
And, the picture here down below is just showing you sort of a mess of corners.
And they don't all look like corners, but
they, they're places where the gradient varies.
And it was created, this paper, the Alvey Vision Conference is what later I
believe became the British Machine Vision Conference.
And it was done by this, by Harris and Stephens.
Now.
If you ask anybody, about the corner detector I'm about to tell you about,
they'll you that they're Harris corners.
Because that's what everybody remembers.
I know an awful lot of people in Computer Vision, I don't know who Stephens is.
So this tells you something.
That if you're doing a paper with somebody, try to get your name first.
Unless of course it's your advisor and he's paying, he or
she's paying for your education in which case then you know.
But, anyway, so I'm it's, it's actually Harris and Stephens and you can impress
somebody by saying, Harris and Stephens corners but it's, it's Harris corners.
All right. So let's learn about Harris corners.
So, Harris corners are.
Based on a approximation, model and an error model.
And here's how we do.
Let's assume, that we've got an image L and right here, right and
I is the intensity image.
And what we're going to do is we're going to say, if I shift that I by
a little bit, by a u and a v and I were to sum up the square over some window.
How much error, would i get?
K thats thats thats the game we're going to play.
So stepping through that, I is our image intensity, so
I of x y is just the orignal image.
The u and the v is some small shift, so
if I were to pick up my window and move it over a little bit,
I would now get some different image just shifted by a little bit.
I subtract them and
square them, and then I, going to, I'm going to sum them up over some window.
Okay? So the window is going to be some area, around some point.
So that's written here as w of xy.
The total value here, E, is sort of for error.
You really could think of it as sum of the change where E for error or energy.
But the idea is that we're going to sum it up.
Around that window.
Now of course your window can typically be a square window,
like in my house, or if you want to actually work a little bit, or, on a,
on a slow computer you make it be a square window.
But if you actually want to weight the pixels near the point you're thinking
about, more then the pixels that are far away, you would use a window that
falls off in intensity, intensity So like a Gaussian window would be an example.
So.
Typically your windows can be square, if you need to be really fast, or
smooth, if you need to be really good.
So, are you fast, or you good?