Here's a short quiz for you.
Imagine that you've had an association between classes for
students and classes for courses.
The association was called Take and
the implication was that a student is taking a particular course.
I have four options for you in how to implement this association, and
I'd like you to give me a reason for each one which might be thought of as
a disadvantage of that particular approach.
The first approach would be a reference in each Student
object to a Course the student is taking.
Second option is a vector of references to students in each course.
Third is to do a, an association class containing two attributes, one for
a Student and the other for a Course.
And the fourth possibility is symmetric vectors in Student and, and
Courses pointing back to the other class.