So let's look at the code that we added.
Let's look at the OrderDinnerActivity.
See I added the inputs for
the View class.
I added variables for
the selected Dinner and the DinnerId.
I updated onStart() to store
the selected dinner and
the selected dinner's Id.
I wrote a to-do note for myself,
to re-factor sendViewProductHit,
since it can now get the dinner and
dinner Id out of class fields.
I leave you to do that if you like,
it won't change the functionality.
It will just make your
code a bit cleaner.
Here's the definition for
addDinnerToCart.
It takes a single argument of the view
which is passed automatically
when the user clicks a view
that activates the method.
And I just pop up Toast
as a placeholder code for
actually putting the dinner in the cart.
And then the method calls
the sendAddToCartHit
to send the hit to Analytics.
This new method SendAddToCartHit, is
very similar to the sendViewProductHit
method we already defined.
So we get the dinner and the dinner Id
from the relevant global variables.
Make sure you fix this code if you copy
and paste it from the other method.
So here I create the product action,
which is ACTION_ADD.
And again, if you copy and
paste it from the other method,
make sure you change this.
Then we get the tracker.
We use EventBuilder to build the hit.
We set the category to Shopping steps.
We set the action, we set the label to
the selected Dinner, and we build and
send the hit.
Let's take a quick look at
the layout file, order_dinner.xml,
to make sure the Add to cart button
calls the addDinnerToCart method.
So this is the button, and yes it does,
addDinnerToCart, excellent.