Both Panda's and
NumPy have special data structures,
made to represent one-dimensional data.
By the way, NumPy stands for
Numerical Python.
In Pandas, this data structure
is called a series, and
in NumPy it is called an array.
Pandas and
NumPy also both have structures for
two-dimensional data, which you'll
learn about in the next lesson.
I typically prefer to
use Pandas' series,
since they have more
features than NumPy arrays.
But NumPy arrays are simpler, so
I'm going to cover those first.
Panda series are built on
top of NumPy arrays, so
it will be important to understand NumPy
arrays when you move on to using series.
In many ways, a NumPy array
is similar to a Python list.
It contains a sequence of elements and
those can be anything.
But suppose you had a Numpy
array of US state codes.
So here's Alabama, Alaska, Arizona,
Arkansas, California, and so on.
I included quotes around these
states because they are strings.
Like lists, the elements of
a NumPy array are in order, and
you can access elements
by their position.
In this NumPy array,
Alaska is at position 0,
Arkansas is at position 1, and so on.
So if you had a NumPy array named a,
then a[0] would return the string AL for
Alaska.
Also like lists, you can access a range
of elements from a NumPy array using
something called slicing.
Again, the syntax is the same as for
lists.
So, a[1:3], would return an NumPy
array containing Alaska and Arizona.
Note that just like for lists, the upper
bound is not inclusive, so I got
the element at position 1 and position
2, but not the element at position 3.
And finally you can use for
loops with NumPy arrays using code like,
for x in a:.
So, what are the differences between
a NumPy array and a Python list?
First, NumPy arrays are designed for
each element to have the same data type.
So, either each element should be
a string, each element should be an int,
each element should be a boolean or
something else.
You can create a Python list
that contains some strings,
some ints, some booleans, and
so on, all mixed together.
And you can still do that in NumPy, but
it was designed for
each array to have a single data type.
Second, NumPy includes a bunch
of convenient functions.
For example, the functions to take
the mean into standard deviation.
Now you saw last lesson that you
can also use these functions on
Python lists.
But, if your data is in NumPy array
then these functions will be faster.
Now this is one place that
the type of the elements matters,
since it only makes sense to take the
mean of the array if all of the elements
are numerical.
Another difference is that NumPy
arrays can be multidimensional.
You'll learn more about this
in the next lesson, but
it's similar to making
a list of lists in Python.
On the next screen you'll be given
a chance to play around with some NumPy
code, and see what it does.
I recommend that you read each section
of code, and predict what will be
printed, then change false to true, and
use Test Run to see if you were right.
If you're not sure what will be
printed just use Test Run to find out.
You can also add your own code and
try out other things if you're curious.
At the bottom of the code,
there's a function for
you to write called max_employment
to check your understanding.
It take these arguments to NumPy arrays.
The first one contains country names and
the second one contains
employment data for each country.
The country names are in the same
order as the employment data.
The function should return the name of
the country with the highest employment,
and the corresponding maximum employment
value based on the given data.
When you click Test Run, in addition to
seeing the output of any code you write,
you'll also see the result of running
your function on the full employment
data set for a few different years.
If you click Submit, the grader will
check whether your function is correct.
If you want to test your function on
something smaller than the full data
set, I recommend testing it out on
the arrays provided at the top of this
section of code.
This one contains the first 20
countries in the data set, and
this one contains employment data for
those countries in the year, 2007.
Since those arrays are named
countries and employment,
you can test your function on those
arrays by using the line print,
max_employment(countries, employment).