So let's also spend a bit of a time looking at the evolution of a camera.
Historically again, seeing where the camera, you know, how long has it
been since the earliest definition of what a camera was to what it is now.
While the earliest concepts camera has been known to existed from times of
Plato in the in the Greek philosophers time, but, the earliest
embodiment of a camera came about in the mid-1800s, with a device like this,
where basically, there was a lens associated with it and,
of course, you could put some sort of chemical at the back, 1839, you know, or
roundabouts was when these cameras were being, and used for photography.
1907 has been the basic theme of the technology to start saving them into prints
like this.1948 is perhaps when a smaller handheld types of cameras like this,
starting coming about.
1986 is the instamatic, disposable types of cameras,
you take a picture, throw this out and take the film and use it.
1991 is the first con, first concept camera for digital SLRs,
this was actually, I believe the resolution of this was about less than two
megapixels, when I started my research career, I tried to get one of these, for
various types of projects I wanted to work on, and they cost more than $20,000,
and I was allowed access to it so I could take a few pictures if I
go to the labs of some of the manufacturers of these cameras, but,
the bottom line is this is the kind of camera almost all of us have now.
2000 is the first mobile cell phone camera that came out, so and
again you notice the evolution from 1839 to 2000, and
of course since 2000, we've even make leaps and bounds in this one.
Now cameras are getting smaller, and smaller like these.
And, more importantly, they're only going to get smaller, so
these are concept designs of cameras that could just be an lens.