Almost all of these are great examples of applications that are used everyday,
and are primarily based on word models.
We've seen classification before for spam and other types of categories,
language ID and so on.
There's also the idea of clustering, where we don't have categories ahead of time.
Yes, you can take news stories and classify them into, say, sports or weather,
but you can also cluster them to say here's a cluster of stories
that are all related about the latest topic that has maybe never occurred before.
There's also input correction of various kinds such as spelling correction,
sentiment analysis--taking reviews of products and trying to decide
if they're favorable or unfavorable and rate products that way,
information retrieval--web search is a problem that I've worked on
and is primarily addressed with word models,
question answer such as IBM's Watson did in playing the game of Jeopardy.
They use a variety of techniques.
Much of them are based around word models, but there are other techniques as well.
Machine translation--we saw the example of Chinese menus and translating to English from examples.
The examples are primarily dealt with by phrases and individual words
and some augmentation to that as well.
Speech recognition--as similar story.
And then finally I threw in one that is no primarily a question for word models.
Driving a car is autonomously is primarily a question in perception and localization.
Yes, you might want to be able to talk to the car to direct it to do something,
but that wouldn't be part of the autonomous part.