Up to this point, we mentioned
synchronization multiple times while
discussing other operating
system concepts.
In this lesson, we will primarily
focus on synchronization.
We will discuss several
synchronization constructs,
what are the benefits of
using those constructs.
And also we will discuss what is the
hardware level support that's necessary
in order for those synchronization
primitives to be implemented.
As we cover these concepts,
we will use the paper,
The Performance of Spin Lock
Alternatives by Thomas Anderson.
This paper will give you a deeper
understanding of how are synchronization
constructs implemented on top
of the underlying hardware, and
why they exhibits certain
performance strengths.
There is a link to the paper
available in the instructors notes.