Operating systems support
devices via device drivers.
Here's a chart that shows where device
drivers sit with respect to the rest of
the operating system and
the actual hardware they manage.
Device drivers are device-specific
software components.
And so, the operating system has
to include a device driver for
every type of different hardware devices
that are incorporated in the system.
Device drivers are responsible for
all aspects of device access,
management, and control.
This includes logic that determines
how can requests be passed from
the higher levels of the system software
applications to the actual device,
how can the system respond to
device-level events like errors, or
response notifications, or
other status change information.
Or in general,
any device-specific details regarding
the device configuration or operation.
The manufacturers or the designers of
the actual hardware devices are the ones
that are responsible for making sure
that their device drivers available for
the different operating systems or
versions of operating systems
where that particular type of
device needs to be available.
For instance you may have
had to download drivers for
printers from a manufacturer like HP.
Operating systems in turn standardize
their interfaces to a device driver's.
Typically this is done by providing some
device driver framework so that device
manufacturers can develop the specific
device drivers within that framework,
given specific interfaces that
that operating system supports.
In this way both device driver
developers know exactly what is expected
from the ways the rest of the operating
system will interact with their device.
And also the operating system does
not depend on one particular device,
one specific device if there
are multiple options for
devices that provide
the same functionality.
For instance, for storage you may
have different types of hard disk
devices from different manufacturers.
Or from networks, you may have different
types of network interconnect cards.
And switching the hardware components
will require switching the device driver
but the rest of the operating system,
the rest of the applications
will not be affected.
So there's standardized
interfaces both in terms of
the interaction with those devices as
well as in terms of the development and
integration of the device drivers.
In this way we achieve
both device independence.
The operating system does not
have to be specialized or
to integrate this particular type of
functionality for each specific device.
And also device diversity.
It's an easy way for
the operating system to support
arbitrarily different types of devices.
We just need another device driver.