welcome to the first module here you're
going to learn how to use one of the
most exciting tools and self-driving car
development deep neural networks at the
end of this module you'll create a
project that demonstrates real-world
application of the skills you need to
become a self-driving car engineer
that's right in the project you'll train
a deep neural network to drive a car in
a simulator first you'll drive and
record training laps and simulation and
then you'll build and train a deep
neural network that learns from the way
you drive a deep neural network is just
a term that describes a big multi-layer
neural network and a neural network is a
machine learning algorithm that you can
train using input like camera images or
sensor readings and generate output like
what steering angle the car should take
or how fast it should go
the idea is that the neural network
learns from observing the world you
don't have to teach it anything specific
deep learning is just another term for
using deep neural networks to solve
problems and it's become really
important for self-driving cars but deep
learning is relatively new until the
last few years computer simply weren't
fast enough to train deep neural
networks effectively now however
automotive manufacturers can apply deep
learning techniques to drive cars in
real time because deep learning is so
new automotive engineers and researchers
are still experimenting with just how
far it can take us but deep learning has
already were revolutionize segments of
autonomous driving like computer vision
and it has the potential to entirely
change the way we develop self-driving
cars