So let's take a quick look at the code,
I put my code in
the ShowAllDinnersActivity and
the first thing you're going to need
to do is import these couple things.
Tracker and the HitBuilders.
And then I put my timing
code in the OnCreate method.
because that's where
we display the list.
I put my startTime down here,
actually after I set the ContentView.
You may have put it above,
it doesn't matter.
So I start recording the time here,
I get all the dinners,
I create the ArrayAdapter,
I set the Adapter, and
then down here I record the stop time.
So now we've got the start and
the stop time,
we need to calculate the elapsed time.
And I've converted from
nanoseconds to milliseconds and
then I have defined a new function
to report the timing hit.
So I have my method, send
AnalyticsTimingHit, got the tracker.
I use TimingBuilder to build the hit.
I set the category to
list all the dinners.
I passed in the elapsed time,
which is t and here I set
the value to the elapsed time.
Set the labels, set the variable and I
build the tracker and that sends a hit.
And that's all there is to it.