Hello everyone.
Today I'm going to talk to you about
a question you might be faced with in
an interview.
Please tell me about a problem or
challenge you encountered and
how you dealt with it.
So how I would respond to that
question is in a previous company,
we had a particular challenge
where we had a large user base.
And a large portion of that user
base were our very loyal users and
they were frustrated because
we would iterate quickly
on the UI that they had to interact with
on a daily basis with their students.
So we brought together
a cross functional team,
someone from marketing,
product, engineering, and
the support team to sort of discuss how
we would go about approaching this.
A lot of great ideas came out
of that collaboration, and
what we found was we had another
challenge that was somewhat similar.
Because metallurgy user base,
our support team at the time was
only about 20, 25 people and
it was difficult for
them to keep up on the demand especially
when we released the a project product.
A lot of questions would come in and
a lot of challenges a lot of bugs and
do it over though the team.
So what we ended up doing was
putting together a program where we
sort of deputized our teachers,
the most loyal teachers, and
gave them some insight into our
product development process.
And would give them first look at
our product before it was released.
Now, we wouldn't give them access to
that product until we were confident it
was 90, 95% out of the way there.
And that it would be released for
three or four weeks.
So when this did was it
allows those loyal users to feel
a part of the development process.
It also gave them enough information
ahead of time that they could figure out
strategic ways they can incorporate
the new design into their workflow.
And in turn they can share
those ideas with teachers that
might be facing similar
frustrations when the product
would be released into
the general user base.
We also incentivize them,
we gave them some swag,
we gave them some opportunities
to contribute in very
specific meet up type groups
that we would have online and
we started the program with
about 30 to 50 teachers.
I think it was 50 teachers.
And during that first year and
I believe now today they
have over 150 teachers that are in
that program all over the world.
So we are able to have those teachers
respond to support questions.
We have those teachers able to alert.
The teachers in their communities and
in their schools and
their online communities.
About potential on changes to the
product and how it would affect them.
It was quite an effective program.
I think we are user base grew
even more because of it, and
it really allowed our users to feel like
they were a part of this larger team,
this larger effort, that was working
hard to put together a quality product.
They exhibited tremendous
ownership of the product, and
felt very defensive if someone
would attack it without a cause.
Very successful program and
a very successful collaboration
amongst not only my team but
with the users as well.
And so, I think the product today
is a lot better because of it.
So that's how I'd answer that question.
Good luck and see you soon.