For a distributive shared
memory solution to be useful,
it must provide good
performance to applications.
If we think about the core service
that's provided by distributive shared
memory systems,
accessing memory locations,
then it's obvious that the performance
metric that's relevant for
DSM systems is what is
the latency with which processes
running on any one of these nodes can
perform such remote memory accesses.
Clearly, accessing local memory
is faster than remote memory.
So, what can we do in order
to maximize the number of
cases where local memory's
accessed versus remote?
One way to maximize the number
of local accesses and
achieve low latency is to use
a technique called migration.
Whenever a process on another node
needs to access remote state,
we literally copy that state
over to the other node.
This makes sense for situations where
we have a single reader, single writer.
Since only one node at a time
will be accessing this state, so
it does make sense to move the state
over to where that single entity is.
However, this requires moving the data,
copying the data over to the remote
node, and that incurs some overheads.
So even for these single reader, single
writer cases, we should be careful when
we trigger these types of mechanisms
because if it's only going to be
a single access that will be performed
in this other location, then migrating,
copying over the entire state over
to node four, it won't be amortized.
We won't get much in terms
of low latency improvements
if we have to copy all this data just
for a single read or write access.
For the more general case, however,
when there are multiple readers and
multiple writers, migrating the state
all over the place doesn't make any
sense since it needs to be accessed
by multiple nodes at the same time.
So, a mechanism such as replication
where the state is copied on multiple
nodes, potentially on all nodes,
is a more general mechanism.
Use of caching techniques,
which create a copy of the state on
each node where the state was accessed,
can lead to some similar behavior
as what's seen with replication.
One problem with this is that it
requires consistency management.
Now this state will be accessed
concurrently on multiple nodes.
And we have to make sure we coordinate
those operations, as we said,
to order all of the writes,
propagate the most recent write
operation to wherever or whomever is
performing the next read operation.
This is some overhead.
One way to control the overhead is to
perhaps limit the number of replicas,
the number of copies that can exist in
this system at any given point of time
since the consistency management has
overhead that's proportional with
the number of copies that need
to be maintained consistently.