We've covered a handful of new
concepts related to networks, so
let's take a second to make
sure we remember what's what.
For each term listed here, I want you to
match it with the correct description.
The description's are an HTTP request
where a client requests a specified
resource from a server, another term for
the type of HTTP request specifies
a location for retrieving data over the
network, a number returned in response
to a HTTP request that indicates
the results of the request, and
finally, the role that an iPhone plays
is accessing data from the network.
For example,
it's downloading images from Facebook.
Now for each description,
match the number for
the term that correctly describes it.