Since the launch of Android Jelly Bean,
notifications can take up to
three action buttons,
which appear in the notification itself.
Each action button can launch
a different pending intent and
perform different actions on your app.
Even though actions are optional, you
should at least set the notification to
allow the users to launch the app so
that they can look at the event that
caused this notification to
show up in the first place.
To add actions to a notification,
you call
the addAction as many as three times
when creating the notification builder.
The addAction method takes an input
parameter of type Notification.Action.
To create such an action, you post in
an image resource, the label text and
a pending intent that will be fired
when the action button is pressed.
Cool, okay.
So let's see how to code these two
action buttons into our notification.
One that will simply dismiss
the notification and
the other that will increment
the count for us.