Before we can discuss some of the design
and implementation challenges
with the models of remote services that
we described in the previous videos,
we need to distinguish among
stateless and stateful file servers.
First, the stateless server is
one which doesn't maintain any
information regarding which
clients access which files,
how many different clients are serviced,
nothing.
Every request has to be self-described,
self-contained, so that it has
all of the parameters regarding
the filings being accessed, the absolute
offset within that file, along with
any data that needs to be written.
This model is suitable for
the upload-download model, or
the other extreme,
true remote file access service.
But, it cannot be used for
the more practical model,
which relies on caching,
because without state,
we cannot achieve consistency management
in the distributed file system.
This is one of the biggest
negatives of this approach.
It prevents the use of caching,
which is an important performance
optimization technique.
The other downside is,
because all of the requests have to be
self-contained, there will be more bits
that will need to be transferred
in order to describe each request.
There are benefits to
the approach as well.
For instance, since there is no state
that's maintained on the file server,
no resources will be consumed on
the server side to maintain that state.
No memory will be used,
no CPU will be spent,
in order to make sure that the state
is consistent, so that's one benefit.
The most important benefit
of the approach is that,
because it is stateless, and
because the requests are self-contained,
this leads to a very resilient
design in terms of failures.
If the server crashes, it just needs
to be restarted, and it can continue to
service all of the future client
requests without any potential errors.
Sure, the clients will need to reissue
any of the requests that have timed out,
but they will ultimately receive
the exact same type of answers,
regardless of the fact that
the server has failed.
Neither the clients, nor the server,
will need to do anything else special
in order to recover from this failure,
just restart.
In contrast to this, a stateful server
is one that maintains information
about the clients in the system,
what are the files they're accessing,
what types of accesses they're
performing, reads versus writes.
For instance, for each file,
the file system may track information,
who has portions of the file cached,
who has read or written to it recently,
or similar information.
Because of this state, it becomes
possible for the file server to allow
data to be cached and at the same
time to guarantee consistency.
Something that wasn't possible
with the stateless server.
And also to provide other benefits,
like locking.
We need state to make sure that we can
keep track of who has locked the file,
and whether or not the file is locked.
Incremental operations is another
thing that can be supported
by having some state.
A client can issue a request,
I want to read the next kilobyte
of data from this file.
With a stateless design,
there is no concept of what
the next kilobyte would be.
You have to describe every
single request fully,
with the offset of the file, with the
specific file handle, and everything.
The problem with this
is that on failure,
all that state that the server
maintains needs to be recovered, so
that the file system overall is
still in a consistent state.
That requires some more complex
mechanisms, for instance,
the state needs to be checkpointed.
We have to have to
some way to rebuild it
in order to have a good
representation of
what it is that the clients were
doing before the failure occurred.
And of course, the runtime
overheads with the stateful server
because it needs to maintain this state,
and
also execute all of the necessary
consistency protocols.
Exactly what those overheads will be,
will depend on the details of how
caching is enabled, when and how it can
occur, and then what are the consistency
requirements that the distributed
file system needs to support.
We will look at what are some
of the options in this space
in the next videos.