For this quiz, I'm giving you this
site with these three buttons.
I want you to load it on your touch
capable devices, like my phone here, and
I want you to do some research.
Eudo just explain until you can use
pseudo-classes to make your your UI feel
more reactive.
These three buttons have active,
focus and
hover pseudo-classes applied to them.
When a button is active,
it's background will be Aqua.
When it's in focus,
it's background will be FireBrick and
when it's hover it's
background will be HotPink.
See how the first letters match?
Clever anyway, take a look at this
site on your touchscreen devices and
answer this question.
Which pseudo-class does not
get applied on mobile devices?
That means,
never gets applied on mobile devices.
Does active never show up,
does focus never show up or
does hover never show up?
Take a minute,
play around with the site and
then select one of these three answers.