So this is an app called Trimensional.
Grant Schindler did PhD,
with us at Georgia Tech and
here we notice a couple
of things he's doing.
Just by an app like this, and he
basically puts it in front of himself in
a dark room and, of course, the app
turns on different types of lights.
And, based on how the face is lit,
it actually can generate a, well,
interesting 3D mesh.
Now, it's not the most accurate mesh or
anything like that, but
you can see that it
does a pretty good job.
And all it does is basically
changes how the face is lit.
This is a whole concept that actually
also sometimes is referred to as
photometric stereo.
That is, how do you photometrically
change the properties of the environment
and capture the variations that
are coming in because of that,
to extract the shape of something?
So in this case of course,
it was done for faces,
just like I showed you in the previous
example of shape from shading.