I'm about to walk you through
an efficient way to implement scatter as
well as other collectives.
I learned these techniques from
a terrific colleague of mine,
Robert Van Deguine.
I can't do his presentation justice,
but I'll do my best.
So, here was my first
implementation of scatter.
It's fairly naive because
the root does all the sending.
That made the communication
time linear in p.
And that's sub-optimal.
Remember that our goal was to
find an alpha log p algorithm.
Here's a different approach.
Suppose this is the root.
Let's start by logically dividing
the network in two pieces.
Then let's send the lower
half of the data, and
we'll just pick some process over here
to the destination, let's say this one.
So we'll pack up this half,
and then we'll send it.
Surprise, surprise,
you are dividing and conquering.
Did someone say conquering?
I think you can imagine that you
would continue this process.
Voila.
So what is the cost of this scheme?
Pick any round of communication,
little i.
The rounds go from 1 to log p
assuming p is a power of 2.
Now in round i, this scheme sends
a message of size n over 2 to the i.
So the time for round i is
alpha plus beta times n sub i.
So we just need to substitute and
then sum over all the rounds.
Plug some stuff in.
Simplify.
So if you work it out, you should
get something that looks like this.
Notice how awesome you are.
You've attained the lower bound,
both with respect to latency and
with respect to bandwidth.
Nice job, you.
In fact, at this point,
I can let you teach the class while
I retire to a beach community,
sipping pina coladas and
rolling naked in my wads of OMSCS cash.
Now, since gather is a dual if scatter,
running the same technique backwards,
at least conceptually,
gives you another good algorithm.