You should get out and network.
My parents must have told me this 100
times when I started looking for jobs.
For the same reason of getting a job,
your apps should get out and
network, too.
Because networking is such a key
feature in so many iOS apps.
Now the networking over here,
this really isn't my forte.
But you're in luck.
I'm good at iOS networking, and
I'm going to show you how to do it.
If you've never heard about
networks before, that's okay.
In this course, the main prerequisite
is that you're comfortable with UIkit,
you've built a few apps, and
that you're ready to learn.
Throughout this course we're going to
build four small apps
that use networking.
These apps will prepare you to build
a portfolio app called, On The Map.
Among other things, On The Map will
allow you the Udacity student,
to share your location and something
awesome about you on a map with other
Udacity students from around the world.
To build On The Map, we'll need to learn
how networking works, how to send and
receive data over the network, and how
to display that data that we receive.
My name is Jared Parks and I'm going to
be the instructor for this course.
For now let's get to the point.
You should go out and network.