So now, of course,
that begs the question.
How do I define similarity?
So here I'm just showing you a few
frames, f1, f2, f3, 4 and so forth.
And, as we know we have 90 of them.
First, I can basically think about
computing the Euclidean distance
between two frames.
So here basically,
let's consider just two frames.
And we can try to do this
mathematically very simply.
That first frame here is p, and it has
all of these pixels up to n pixels,
and q all of these
pixels up to n pixels.
Again, they have to be the same size,
as we know, right?
So of course, now we want to know how to
compute the Euclidean distance here, and
I'm referring, that basically is d2
from p to q, which basically, kind of,
now takes the square of
difference from each and
every one of the two similar pixels, p1
minus q1, p2 minus q2, for all of them.
This, of course, can be made into
a simple equation, which is shown here.
Summation across from 1 to N,
all of the pixels, and
subtracting one element by the other,
and of course,
we're taking the square difference,
which is the Euclidean difference here.
This distance metric is
referred to as an L2 norm.
And, of course, this is a way of kind of
computing the distance between each and
every one of the frames.
I can do this again, as I said, for
each and every f1 to the other 90, f2,
the other 90, and all that stuff.