Now, we already learned something really interesting,
which is the special case of a linear filter.
We took an image, and we applied a small kernel.
The application of a kernel is often denoted
with a special symbol over here.
And we received a new image
that was slightly smaller, and we don't really worry
about the fact that it's smaller.
There's ways to keep it the same size
by assuming everything around the original image is zero.
But we did receive a new image that was part of the kernel over here.
And the general math of the new image,
for any pixel accorded x and y, is obtained by summing
over all layers in the kernel, u and v,
of the original image shifted by u and v
times the kernel itself.
Now, this will take some time to digest,
but what it really does is it does exactly what we did before.
We take our kernel, which in this case might be a 2 x 1 kernel.
We go over both of these fields
or any number of fields that exists over here.
We look at the corresponding image field and shift it a little bit.
We did this before. We shifted it by 0, 1 pixels.
We multiply these 2 things.
There was a +1 here and a -1 here before.
And we add all these things up
to arrive at the resulting image.
Think for a moment to realize that this function over here
implements what we just did.
It's a nice and elegant function.
It's called a linear filter.
And the reason is the math inside this sum is linear.
It's a multiplication.
And so is the sum, and the convolution operation itself
is often called the linear operation.