Firewalls have limitations.
That is, there are situations where
a firewall provides no protection.
If traffic does not pass
through a firewall,
then a firewall cannot examine said
traffic and provide protection.
For example, if traffic is routing
around the firewall, meaning that
the traffic does not pass through the
firewall, then there is no protection.
Or for traffic that's internal to the
network meaning that the traffic does
not go across the boundary between
internal and external networks,
then there's no protection by the
firewall that sits between internal and
external networks.
If the firewall is misconfigured,
the traffic that passes through, the
firewall cannot examine it correctly.