I am now asking a hidden markov model question.
In the given, the following hidden markov models with 2 internal states,
with a property of transitioning to either side is 0.5,
and the probability of staying is therefore, 0.5.
This Hidden Markov Model has 2 possible measurements or observations, X and Y.
The probability of observing X and Y depends on what state
the hidden markov model is in.
For A, it's 0.1 for X and 0.9 for Y.
For B, it's 0.8 for X and 0.2 for Y.
Let's assume that the initial probability of distribution at time 0 is 1/2 for either of the 2 states.
I would like to know what's the posterior probability of being A at time 0 given that we observed
X at time 0 and not Y, what's the posterior probability of state A at time 1 given the observation of X at time 0,
and what's the posterior probability of A1 given the observations X at time 0 and X at time 1.
That means two consecutive Xs.