The answer to our storage
issues relies on the fact that
we don't really design page tables
in this flat manner anymore.
Instead, page tables have
evolved from a flat page map
to a more hierarchical
multi-level structure.
This figure here shows
a two level page table.
The outer level here is referred
to as a page table directory.
Its elements are not pointers
to actual pages, as in here.
Instead, they're
pointers to page tables.
The internal page table has proper
page tables as its components that
actually point to page tables.
Their entries have the page frame number
and all the protection that's for
the physical addresses that
are referenced by the corresponding
virtual address.
An important thing to note is that
the internal page tables exist only for
those virtual memory regions
that are actually valid.
So any kinds of holes in
the virtual memory space
will result in lack of
internal page tables, so
for those holes, there won't be internal
page tables allocated for them.
If a process requests via malloc
additional virtual memory to be
allocated to it, the OS will check and
if necessary it will allocate an
additional internal page table element
and set the appropriate page table
directory to correspond to that entry.
That new internal page table entry
will correspond to some portion of
the newly allocated virtual memory
region that the process has requested.
To find the right element in
this page table structure,
the virtual address is split into yet
another component.
Using this address format,
this is what we need to perform to
determine the correct physical address.
First the last portion of
the address is still the offset so
that's going to be used to compute
the offset within the actual page,
within the actual physical page.
The first two components of the address
are used as indices into the page
tables, into the different levels
of the page table hierarchy.
And they're ultimately going to
produce the physical frame number
that's the starting address
of the physical region.
The first portion is used as in
index into the outer page table.
So, that will determine
the page table directory entry
that points to the actual page table.
And then the second index is used
as an index into this page table,
into the internal page table.
This will produce the page table entry
that consists of the physical frame
number and then we add that with
the offset just like before,
and compute the physical address.
In this page the address format
is such that it uses ten bits for
the internal page table offset.
That means that this internal page table
can address two to the tenth elements.
So two to the tenth pages can be
addressed in the internal page table.
Since we used ten bits as the offset
into the actual page that means
that the page itself is also
two to the tenth in size.
Therefore, if we do the math, we see
that every single internal page table
can address two to the tenth, the number
of entries, times the page size,
that's another two to the tenth,
so one megabyte of memory.
What that means is that whenever
there is a gap in the virtual memory
that's one megabyte size.
We don't need to allocate
that internal page table, so
that will reduce the overall size of
the page table that's required for
a particular process.
This is in contrast with the single
leve page table design where the page
table has to be able to translate
every single virtual address and
it has entries for
every single virtual page number.
So clearly the hierarchical page table
model helps in reducing the space
requirements for a page table.
The skin can be further extended
to use additional layers using
the same principle.
For instance, we can add another,
third level that can consist of
pointers to page table directories.
Adding yet another fourth level to this,
which consists of a map of pointers
to page table directories.
This technique is particularly
important on 64 bit architectures.
There, not only that the page
table requirements are larger,
it's also the fact, is that the virtual
address spaces of processes on
these 64 bit architectures
tend to be more sparse.
If it's more sparse,
that means that it will have larger gaps
in the virtual address space region.
And the larger the gaps,
the larger the number of internal page
table components that won't be
necessary as a result of that gap.
In fact, with a four level addressing,
we may end up saving entire page
table directories as a result of certain
gaps in the virtual address space.
Let's look at a quick example.
These two figures show how a 64-bit
virtual address can be interpreted
to determine which indices are used into
the different levels of the page table
hierarchy.
The top figure has two
page table layers,
whereas the bottom one has
three page table layers.
In both of these figures,
the offset field is the actual intext
into the actual physical page table.
There is a trade-off
in supporting multiple
levels in the page table hierarchy.
As we add multiple levels,
the internal page tables and page table
directories end up covering smaller
regions of the virtual address space.
As a result, it is more likely
that the virtual address space
will have gaps that will
match that granularity and
we will be able to reduce
the size of the page table.
The down side of adding multiple
levels in the page table
is that there will be more memory
accesses that will be required for
translation since we'll have to access
each of the page table components
before we ultimately produce
the physical address.
Therefore, the translation
latency will be increased.