Brands use Klout to reach out to the influencers for word of mass marketing. So
for example Audi has this test drive campaign that they offer to
influencers in San Francisco. They basically invited all those opinion leaders
in different vectors of the industry to come in and test drive one of this
newest model, and get a sense of how they feel about this new model. That's what
Audi do. And Virgin America for example offered this VIP service for those,
who are even just a Klout user, when they come to the airport terminals, they
invite those influences over to their VIP lounge, just for all the pros they have
there. Because you know, they think having a Klout score is a good indicator of
you being influential and savvy was this social media thing that's coming up. So,
and people has different ways of using Klout scores across different domains. I've
also heard of some dating sites using Klout score as a signal to match people up.
>> Cool, are there any other ways that you can think of often top of your head. >> Some
CMOs - chief marketing officers uses Klout to just filter their candidates with.
Because a lot of the bigger, more traditional companies, when they try to adapt
to their social media era, they're trying to hire someone with social media
background. To be able to help with their branding and, and, and the picture of
their company. And for those jobs, having a Klout score is a must. I've heard. I think
Barrack Obama, the President, has the highest Klout score of 99. And San
Francisco Giants just recently after they won the World's Series, they had
a share that same score for a month. >> Wow, and Justin Bieber? >> Justin Bieber
has a very high Klout score of 92. And a lot of celebrities and media
celebrities are a whiz in their range. And but he's one of, definitely one of
the highest Klout score.