My answer is everything but the TLB.
Here's the condition
that you need to check,
does the cache have more
lines than words per line?
For instance,
let's take the register file.
A cache line is just a register,
and the line width is 16 bytes.
So the number of lines is 16,
and the words per line is 16
Bytes divided by 8 Bytes, or 2.
So the register file is indeed tall.
Now let's take the L1 cache example.
The number of lines is 2,048.
That's 32 kiB divided by 64 bytes.
The number of words per line is 8.
So it's also tall.
Now let's skip to the TLB.
The number of lines is just the number
of TLB entries, which is 256.
But that's actually less than
the number of words per line,
which in this case is 1,024.
Thus, this quote-unquote cache is short.
So here are the final answers again.
The main conclusion of this exercise is
that most levels of the memory hierarchy
are indeed tall, but
not all of them are.