Now let's discuss botnet command and
control.
This is the most important
aspect of botnets.
Recall that the definition of botnet
is that a botnet is a network of
compromised computers that the botmaster
uses for malicious purposes.
Here, by botmaster,
we mean the attacker behind the botnet.
Because the botmaster needs to
make use of the network of bots,
he needs to communicate with the bots.
In other words, there needs to
be command control, or C&C for
short, from the botmaster to the bots.
For example the bot should report to
the botmaster its current status and
the bot may be directed by the botmaster
to another site to download
the latest malware version.
And the bot may receive instructions for
spamming, phishing and DDoS, and
so on, from the botmaster.
In short, we can see that without C&C,
a botnet is not a network, but
just a collection of
isolated infected machines.
And as a result, the botmaster
cannot utilize the aggregate
competition of power of
all the bots available.