Here I want to show you another example, where we can do same kinds of things.
Except, we want to use this approach to take the scenes that are the most
similar, either out or put them back in to extend the size of this image.
So here the goal is, I have this image.
What happens if I want to shrink it, so
I want to get rid of some information in the horizontal, or
I want to increase the size so the aspect ratio is much wider here.
And I want to add frame.
This is a method called scene carving, and
again, you can look at more details on the papers listed below.
Here's how the dissolve looks like.
So here I'm basically shrinking them,
what's really happening is some of the, you know, seam is being removed.
Or, when I'm stretching it out,
more seams are added based on the sample space between them.
And this is allow used, allows you to kind of generate a much larger
aspect ratio or a small aspect ratio.
These kinds of approaches are very common and also available in
standard Photoshop tools like content aware fills and stuff like that.
They are widely available in a variety of photo apps these days.