First it uses repeating key letters.
As we have shown in the example, the key
stream is as long as the plain text and
the key letters will be
repeated in a key stream.
For example, the key stream can be
lemon, lemon, lemon, and so on.
Because the key letters are repeated,
think even a long plaintext message.
The same letters may be mapped
to the same cipher text,
because they have the same
repeated key letters.
For example, if the plaintext letters
A-T-T appear multiple times in
the plaintext, and the key
letters L-E-M are being repeated,
then there high probability
that the same cipher text,
L-X-F will also appears multiple
times in the cipher text.
Then using knowledge of
the English language or
the context of the communication,
the attacker can guess what other words
that may be repeated multiple times.
Therefore, by searching for
the repeated cipher text words,
the attacker can then compare
the cipher text words and
the plaintext words to
uncover the key letters.
So this is a weakness
that can be exploited.
Second, require security for
the key, not the message.
This is, in fact,
a strength of the cipher.
Third, the length of the key can be
determined using frequency analysis.
This is also a weakness
that can be exploited.
For example,
using knowledge of the English language,
the attacker can look
at the cipher text and
determine that the most frequently
used three letter word is the, T-H-E,
and then by looking at the distance
between the two occurrences of there,
the calculator can then
guess the length of the key.
Knowing the length of a key would help
the attacker uncover the whole key
instead of just a few key letters.
So therefore,
this is a weakness that can be
exploited to break the Vigenere Cipher.