So back in the source code for
our Tsunami app, let's go ahead and
open up the MainActivity and
look at the makeHttpRequest method.
Now this is the method that performs the
actual HTTP request to the server and
takes as input a URL object.
A few lines in,
inside our try catch block,
you can see that we call the
openConnection method on the URL object.
Then we cast the return value into
this HttpURLConnection object and
stored in the variable
called urlConnection.
So the answers to the quiz were
the data type of the return value of
url.openConnection is the data
type HttpUrlConnection.
If you looked at the documentation for
the URL class and
then looked at the Public methods
section, then you may have said that
the return value of the openConnection
method is a URLConnection object.
Now for this quiz,
we actually accepted either answer
because HttpURLConnection is actually
a subclass of URLConnection.
It inherits all the behavior
of URLConnection and
adds more functionality on top of that.
In our case, we're going to be working
within HttpUrlConnection object,
and nor a URLConnection.
Let's discuss this more next.