You've got your building blocks
in place for your app, and
you're almost ready to jump back
into Xcode and start writing it.
But, by now,
you should be able to give an estimate
of how long it's going to
take you to complete it.
Which is good for whatever career path
you might decide to pursue, whether
you're going to work for a company or
you're going to be a freelancer.
For companies, project managers, like
myself, are very grateful for those that
can accurately estimate how much time it
will take them to complete something.
And if you're a freelancer,
you need to be able to
accurately estimate how long its
going to take you to do something or
else you're going to get totally
screwed and not get paid enough.
Go through the list of features
that you plan to use in your app.
How long do you think it will
take you to implement each one?
Be generous with your estimates here,
and
make sure that you're
including debugging time.
It's actually where you'll probably
spend the majority of your time.
And here's a hint.
It will take you about twice as
long as you think it's going to.
But, if you're not sure at all how long
it's going to take you to complete this
app, think back to the portfolio apps.
How long did it take you to implement
features for MemeMe, or OntheMap, or
VirtualTourist?
You're doing something
very similar here.
You, essentially, have a specification,
you know what APIs you're implementing,
you know what features
you want to include,
and you're going to build your
app to that specification.
So use past experience as a guide.