The first statement,
the one-way hash function is important
not only in message authentication but
also in digital signatures.
The one-way property of
hash function says that
it is very efficient to compute a hash
value of a given input message.
On the other hand, given a hash value,
it is computationally infeasible to
find the original input message.
Hash function can be used
in message authentication.
For example, if Alice and
Bob share a secret key,
then Alice can authenticate herself
by sending a hello message and
hash the hello message along
with a share secret key.
And when Bob received this hash value,
along with a hello message
in plain text, Bob can hash the hello
message along with a shared key and
see whether that hash value matches with
the hash value that he just received.
And if they match, then Bob knows
that this message is from Alice.
In other words, Alice is authenticated.
Now if the one-way property of
hash function does not hold.
That means the attacker
intercepting the hello message and
the hash value can then
reverse the hash function and
find that the secret key that was used
to hash along with the hello message.
Therefore, the attacker would
able to obtain the share key.
Therefore, the one way property
of hash function is important for
message authentication.
Now what about digital signatures?
Here's typically how
digital signature works.
Alice can create a digital signature for
message, say m.
She first hashes m, and then sign
the hash value of m using a product key.
Then she sends the message m in
plain text along with a signature,
therefore the one way property of hash
function is not important here because
the input plain text
message is sent anyway.
To recap, this statement is not true
because the one way property is
important for message authentication but
not in digital signatures.
Second statement, SHA processes
the input one block at a time but
each block goes through
the same processing.
This is true because
this is how SHA works.
Third, HMAC is secure provided
that the embedded hash function
has good cryptographic strengths, such
as one-way, and collision resistant.
This is true, that is,
if the underlying has function is not
secure, the HMAC would not be secure.
On the other hand, as we have discussed,
HMAC is more secure
than a cryptographic hash function
because of the use of a secret key.