Hey, welcome back.
So while you were taking a break,
our designer provided us updated designs
of what the app should look like.
And here they are.
We could leave the app as is, but
as it stands,
the audio feature is hard to discover.
Now, we want to provide
some indication to the user
that the list items are clickable, and
that by clicking it, they can here
the pronunciation of each word.
So our designer provided these designs.
And notice that each list item
now displays a play arrow icon
to indicate that the item is clickable.
So in this task,
you will make your version of
the Miwok app look like these designs.
I'd like you to add
the play icon to the app.
Our designer also requested that
the icon be 24 dps by 24 dps,
have it be vertically centered
within the list item and
also position 16 dps from
the right edge of the screen.
Now, as a heads out, you might need to
make some significant changes to your
layout in order to make
this new layout work.
So as for the icon,
you can download it from this free
library of material design icons here.
So this library was created by
the Google design team for you to use
in your own apps in order to comply
with the material design guidelines.
So this is a valuable resource if you
want to go on to create other apps but
don't have a designer to
create icons for you.
Now, if you scroll down
here to the AB section,
there's a play icon that we can use.
So click on it, and
it will give you options for
how you can download the icon.
So you want to choose the 24
dp version of the icon
as requested by your designer.
Then, I want to choose the white version
as opposed to the black version, and
then download PNGs.
So the file is downloaded as
a zip file onto my desktop, and
then I unzipped it right here.
So let's open that up.
So we got different versions of the app,
so let's open up the Android folder.
So we organize these Java folders for
the various density buckets.
Now, inside this drawable HDPI folder,
we have the HDPI version
of the play arrow.
Now, I'd like you to go into
each of these folders and
copy over the image into your version
of the MiWok app in Android Studio.
So that means the HDPI icon goes into
the existing drawable HDPI folder in
our app.
The drawable MDPI icon goes into the
drawable MDPI folder in Android Studio,
and so on and so on.
And you can also rename the file as
well so that they have a shorter name.
So something like ic_play_arrow.
Remember where ic stands for icon.
Now, remember that we should include all
versions of the assets in our app so
that the icon doesn't appear
blurry on certain devices.
And once you're done with this tasks,
I'd like you to check
this box to continue.