To solve this first equation, we can subtract 1 from both sides and get 2x
equals 3x minus 6. Next, we can subtract negative 2x from both sides to keep
our x variable positive. So, I'll have 0 equals x minus 6. Be really careful at
this step. You know positive 2x and negative 2x sum to 0, so we need to make
sure we have a place value over here. So if this left side is 0, that must mean
x would have to equal positive 6. Since 6 minus 6 does make 0. We also see that
by just adding 6 to both sides. So 6 is equal to x, or x is equal to 6. For the
right equation, we want to distribute the negative 1 first. So we'll have 2x
plus 1 equals negative 3x plus 5. I'm going to move my x terms to one side by
adding 3x. This also gives me a positive X variable on the left. So if I have x
plus 1 is equal to 5 and then can subtract 1 to get 5x is equal to 4. If we
divide both sides by 5 you get x is equal to 4 5ths. So here's my solution set.
X could equal 4 5ths or x could equal 6. Either one of these would work. Let's
make sure. We can check this first x value by plugging it in for x. 2 times 4
5ths is 8 5ths. And then I can just change 1 to 5 divided by 5. So this makes
13 5ths on the left side. Notice that I still have absolute value the entire
way down my problem. Now I'm going to take the absolute value of this number.
And I get positive 13 5ths. That's the distance from 0. For the right hand
side, I'll have 3 times 4 5ths, which is 12 5ths. And then I'm going to change
negative 5 into negative 25 5ths. This term is still really negative 5. I
subtract my fractions, and I get negative 13 5ths, or the absolute value of
negative 13 5ths. The absolute value is always positive, so 13 5ths is equal to
13 5ths. So yes, this checks. I can do the same for the positive 6. I'll
substitute it in for x to check my equation. 2 times 6 is 12, plus 1 is 13. I
notice I still have the absolute value. So the absolute value of positive 13 is
13. On the right hand side I have 3 times 6, which is 18. And the absolute
value of 18 minus 5 is the absolute value of 13. And hey, look at that, 13 is
equal to 13. That checks as well. You might have gotten stuck with the negative
sign when distributing or perhaps with this fraction. Think about the types of
mistakes you might be making if you are making any, and try and write them
down. This would be a good reference for you later.