So this quiz asks us to write code for
the random_noun function, and we'll do
that by using the randint function we
learned about to generate a number from
0 to 1, and return the string sofa if
the number is zero, else we return lama.
So the first thing we need to do is
generate this random number from zero to
one, and the way we would do that, is of
course, by using the randint function.
So I'm setting a variable
random_num = randint(0,1).
And that's because the randint function
will return a random number from
the first to the second argument, but
with both arguments
included in that range.
So now that we have our
random number figured out,
we need to implement
some logic around it.
Since we returned sofa at
the random number of 0,
a check of random number 0, and
return the string sofa if it is.
And since random_num can
only be one of two numbers,
we don't need to write another
comparison checking if num is 1.
We'll just return
the string "llama" instead.
And that's all there is to it.
We can now generate random_nouns.
You can see how we can expand
this function to generate more
random_nouns by increasing
the range our randint function.
In the next quiz,
there will be generating random verbs,
so we're going to start creating
some really interesting math glibs.