Now let's set up our app so that we
have the proper classes to display more
attributes about each earthquake.
In the next coding task,
modify the app so
that we can store more information then
just the location about each earthquake.
We should keep track of the magnitude,
the location and the date for
each earthquake.
When you're done,
it should look like this screenshot.
Continue to use fake data,
also known as place holder data
because we're setting up the key parts
of the app that are needed later.
You can make up any details you want for
each earthquake, it doesn't need
to match our fake data exactly.
There will be a fair amount
of code changes required,
which can be challenging.
If you find this task too hard, you can
review the content from the last course,
where Jessica walked you through,
step by step, on how to display
a list of data in the Me Walk app.
Otherwise, give this a try,
I'll offer you two hints below the quiz.
I also linked the Android Flavor
app from the last course,
if you want to use that for reference.
Good luck, when you're done
check this box and continue.