I hope you enjoyed learning about neural
networks and convolutions so far you've
been learning about deep neural networks
at the conceptual level and applying
these techniques to a range of image
classification tasks in the next project
you're going to return to autonomous
driving that's right
next you're going to build a deep neural
network to classify traffic signs your
network should be able to take an image
and decide if it's a stop sign a yield
sign a different type of sign or maybe
no sign at all this will be a terrific
portfolio project to demonstrate for
employers to your hands on practical
experience with deep neural networks