So Walter, building off the developer
just said, the problem was with the many
to many relationship between the users
who were on a shared shopping list and
those shared shopping lists.
We needed some way to
represent this relationship.
Shopping lists could have a bunch of
different people associated with them
and users themselves could be associated
with a bunch of her shopping lists.
In this example here, A has three
different users associated with it, and,
JP, for example,
has three different shopping
lists that he's associated with.
And what we needed was for
the data that's associated with
the shopping list, for example, shopping
list A, to have some sort of reference
to these people that are shared.
And what we needed was some way to
be looking at a shopping list And
know the people who had
access to that list.
And also be able to look at a user and
know all the lists that
were associated with them.
The decision that we made about our
database was that we would store
the shared members as part
of the shopping list itself.
For example,
you can see them right here for
the shopping list,
the Wilderness Survival List.
This made looking up whether a user had
access to a particular list very easy.
There are problems, though, that arose
when we had to deal with displaying
the shopping list fragment for
a user that had a huge
amount of shopping lists.
There are two main issues.
First was the amount of data
that we were manipulating.
Now FarBase provides some methods for
sorting and
filtering data and
they work very efficiently.
We were able to use these methods to
go through the hundreds of thousands of
shopping lists and
grab the lists that were specifically
owned by the user in question.
We were also able to use
these methods to go in and
filter out only the lists that
were shared with the user.
Again, these were speeding
queries when we had less data.
But with hundreds of thousands of
shopping lists to sift through,
even Firebase's lightning fast
query language began to slow down.
And we did the search twice once for
trying to find out if the user
was an owner of a list.
And again to try to find out if
the user was shared with the list.
So that was the first issue.
The second issue was that it was tricky
and annoying to combine the results
from these two different
queries in Firebase UI.
These two listings should be combined
to make a master list of all
the shopping lists that
a user had access to, and
this required some sub-classing
of the fire base list adapter.
We had to rewrite a lot of code,
and it just wasn't very clean.
>> You know, after the fact, they found
out that issues involving two way many
to many relationships are common.
So, I did a little bit of research on
my free time, since my retirement I've
got a little example using a chat
app that you might find informative.
Here, let me see that tablet.
It's important at this point
to emphasize that many to many
relationships are important
to get correct.
Consider how users can belong to a group
and groups can contain a list of users.
For reasons such as these a two
way relationship must exist and
needs to be accounted for
in your database design.
Let's look at this model in
the fire based dashboard.
Here is a first attempt at
producing two way relationships.
But when it comes time to decide
which groups a user belongs to,
things get complicated.
We can monitor all the groups and
iterate them every time there is
a change, but this is costly and slow.
Even worse, what if Walter isn't
allowed to see all of these groups?
When we try to fetch the entire list,
we'll get an error telling us
the operation wasn't allowed.
What we would like instead is an elegant
way to list the groups Walter belongs to
and fetch only data for those groups.
An index of Walter's groups,
can help a great deal here.
Didn't we just duplicate some data by
storing the relationship under both
Walter's record and under the group?
Yes, this is a necessary redundancy for
to a relationships.
It allows us to quickly and
efficiently fetch memberships.
Even when the list of users or
groups scales into the millions.
Or when security and firebase rules will
prevent access to some of the records.
When in doubt remember data storage
is cheap, the user's time is not.
>> That's fascinating.
Actually, while you were talking
I took the liberty of drafting up
a couple of different ways that we could
have dealt with that tricky to many
many relationship that
you were talking about.
What do you think we should have done.
And into these five I've come up with
another tip which basically is that
data storage is pretty cheap but
the user's time is not cheap.
As just mentioned, if you find yourself
in a situation where Where duplicating
data can make reading and writing
to the database more efficient for
the client app you should do it.
It's better to duplicate data than to
create more Firebase back end traffic.
Now we're actually already
doing this in our code.
For example with our user data.
Here we have some user data for Walter.
And we copy again all of this user
data into our user shopping list.
Now this might seem somewhat
unnatural to developers.
Usually, developers for their best
not to create duplicated data.
But let's get to the root
of why you do that.
Well you usually do that
because it's easy for
duplicated data to get out of
sync if you're not careful.
To deal with this, Firebase makes it
easy to keep duplicated data consistent.
By using deep path updates.
Here is some code for actually doing
one of those fancy deep path updates.
And you should note that it's using
the method updateChildren to deal with
that duplicated data.
What you do is you simply make
a hash map with all of the changes
that you need to make bundled together.
So for example let's say that the Walter
user object appears two different places
in the database.
And just for
this example, let's say that you can
change Walter's name around, and
if you do change Walter's name, you want
to change it in both of these places.
In that case we take the hash map and
we put each of the locations and
the new updated name value.
So, this location and updated name is
for this location in the database And
this location and updated name is for
this location in the database.
And we update his name to the exact
same thing in both places.
And because we use
the updateChildren method,
either all of these updates are going
to occur or none of them will occur.
This approach though does make
it easy to make a mistake.
If you're sleepy and let's say forget
to add all the correct places in
the code that a user needs to update.
Then you'll still get into
an inconsistent state.
One approach to deal with this
is to create helper method for
each collection of objects that
needs to be updated at once.
So for example for the user object,
you could create one such helper method.
And then the entire job of this helper
method is to take in as a parameter
the property of the object
that you want to change.
And then that helper method
will create a hash map
that adds all of the different
places of the database.
That that property would
need to be changed.
Okay So with all of that in mind I
want you to take a look at the five
alternative database options that I
put in the instructor notes below.
And I want you to pick which
of these database structures
you think is the best for
ShoppingList++.
And here are the screens if
you need them for reference.