In your iPython notebook you'll find
a function that says MahalanobisDist.
It takes in two variable, x and y.
It calculates the covariant matrix
as well as the difference arrays for
each of the variables from their means.
It returns the Mahalanobis distance.
Lets execute the scope.
Once this is done running,
we can use the MahalanobisDist function
to calculate the distances between
all the points in x and x bar.
Let's run this line of code.
The next function implements
an outlier detector.
In this case, we call the previous
MahalanobisDist function
between the two variables x and y.
We set a threshold of
-2 times log of 1-p.
Here p is the probability with
which I believe that a point is
in the distribution of x and y together.
Let's run this code.
Now that we have defined
the function FindOutliers,
we can call it with our variables.
We use x,xbar and a probability
of 2.43 times 10 to the -6.
This corresponds to a five sigma
significance in a normal distribution.
Let's see if we can find outliers
with five sigma significance.
The FindOutliers function returns
the outliers in an array.
We want to plot the outliers and see
what the indices of these outliers are.
Use the PlotOutliers
function to do that.
Once it's done running,
you will see the following output.
Total Outliers found : 4.
The indices of the variables for
the outliers are given here.
The plot here shows the values where
the outliers lie in the x x-bar PDF.