First, let's look at
this helper function
that turns the detected activity
type code into a string.
It's a very simple switch statement
that just looks at the different codes,
be they in_vehicle,
on_bicycle, on_foot, etc.
And then returns a string from our
resources file that matches this.
So if I have detected
activity in_vehicle,
I'm returning the string for
r.string.in_vehicle.
And if you remember earlier on,
when we pasted into our strings file,
I had put those codes in there.
So if I come back down to my strings
file, here you can see I have
things such as in vehicle, in a vehicle
on bicycle, there's on a bicycle, etc.
So I've just set up those
strings in my strings file.
And then back on my main activity,
whenever I detect that code,
I'm just returning
the equivalent string.
So now, let's take a look at what
we've done in the on receive function.
Now if you remember, you created it
earlier on and it received a context and
an intent.
So what do we do?
Well, first of all we create a new
array list of detected activity.
I call this updated activities and
we just get the value of this
from the getParcelableArrayListExtra
that we spoke about.
Now if you remember when we pushed
the detected activity array list
onto the intent, in the intent service,
we called it by a name,
which was Constants.ACTIVITY_EXTRA.
So we just use that name to address
it to get it right back out.
So now we have the array
list of detected activities
in our main activity, or at least in the
nested class within the main activity.
So now we can just go through and
update the status string as a result.
And because this is a nested class, I
can actually call mStatusText directly.
So now all I have to do it I say String
strStatus equals empty to empty it.
And then for each activity,
for each DetectedActivity
within this updatedActivities,
I now just update my status
to be the string that corresponds to
the actual code returned by getType().
And then the actual
confidence as a percentage.
So the confidence is
returned as a percentage.
So I just put the percent character
afterwards on a new line.
And that's where we were able
to get all of the activities
that we saw on the demo
earlier on on new lines and
a rough estimate of what of
the accuracy of that activity.
Now there's one more step that we
need to do, and we have to declare
this receiver class on the main activity
and make sure that we're using it.
This is pretty simple.
Let's go ahead and do that right now.
So first of all,
on my MainActivity class where I've
declared these other member variables,
I'm going to declare one for
our broadcast receiver, and here it is.
I'm just saying protected
ActivityDetectionBroadcastReceiver and
I'm going to call it mBroadcastReceiver.
Then in my onCreate function, as I
create all the other member variables,
I'm just going to come in here and
paste in that mBroadcastReceiver is a
new ActivityDetectionBroadcastReceiver.
We're almost there now.
We just need to finish the last part,
and that's to hook up the buttons.