Let's take a look at inline elements.
Inline elements such as spans, treat
height the same way as block elements.
However, the width is
treated differently.
It is content based, that means,
an inline element will only be as
wide as the content inside it.
Also, unlike block elements,
you cannot set the width and
height of inline elements.
The box will simply take on the size
of the content, no more, no less.
So, you might be thinking to yourself,
well, what happens when the content in
an inline element is wider
than the space available?
That's a great question.
The content wraps.
Each one of these is called a line box,
and
they're all part of
the same inline element.
You can think of this one element,
as being broken up into different lines.
Notice that each line box has a top and
bottom border.
But the left border only get's drawn at
the beginning of the first line box and
the right border only get's drawn
at the end of the last line box.
Another interesting behavior, is inline
elements can accept margin And padding.
When added, margin will push elements
away horizontally but not vertically.
In the next video,
you'll have a chance to look at
a wide variety of inline elements.