The reason I ask this question
is because of something called
Occam's Razor.
Occam can be spelled in
many different ways.
And what Occam says is that
everything else being equal,
choose the less complex hypothesis.
Now in practice there's actually
a trade-off between really good data fit
and low complexity.
Let me illustrate this to you
by a hypothetical example.
Consider the following graph where
the horizontal axis graphs complexity
of the solution.
For example,
if you've used polynomials this might be
a high degree polynomial over here, and
maybe a linear function over here,
which is low degree polynomial.
The training data error
tends to go like this.
The more complex a hypothesis you allow,
the more you can just fit your data.
However, in reality your
generalization error on unknown data
tends to go like this.
It is the sum of the training
data error in another function,
which is called the overfitting error.
Not surprisingly the best complexity is
attained where the generalization error
is minimum.
And there are some of those methods
to calculate the overfitting error.
They go into a statistical field under
the name, bias variance methods.
However in practice, you're often
just given the training data error.
You find, if you don't find the model
that minimizes the training data error,
but instead pushed back on complexity
your algorithm tends to perform better.
And that is something we will
studying a little bit in this class.
However, this slide this
is really important for
anybody doing machine
learning in practice.
If you deal with data and have ways to
fit your data, be aware that overfitting
is a major source of poor performance
of machine learning algorithms.
And I'll give you examples
in just one second.