Now that we know how to organize our
tests, let's start writing our own.
You already wrote your first
test in a previous lesson, but
we'll now break that test down and
explain each part.
Each test starts with a call to expect.
You can think of this as
the launching point of any test.
It's what starts the process.
The expect function accepts
a single value called the actual
that we want to test.
In this example,
the actual is add 0.1, 0.2.
We then need to tell
the testing framework
what kind of comparison we want
to use against the actual.
The comparison method is
called the matcher and
is a method chained after
the call to expect.
Jasmine includes a lot of matcher
functions and you can even add your own.
In this example our matcher is toBe
which is the equivalent of a strict
equals comparison.
Finally, we pass the expected value to
our matcher, in this case the value 0.3
which is what we would expect
the add 0.1, 0.2 to return.
All in all, you can think of this
test to look something like this
once it has been evaluated
by the framework.
Add 0.1, 0.2 equal, equals, equals 0.3.
If that expression returns true,
this test passes.
Otherwise, it fails.
You can also negate a test by chaining
the word not, before the matcher.
For example,
this test would evaluate to true,
since add 0.1, 0.2 does not equal 0.1.