Now that we have validated that
our theory, that individual words
instead of review are predictive of that
review's positive or negative label.
Now it's time to transform our
datasets into numbers in a way that
respects this theory and this belief, so
that our neural network can search for
correlation in this particular way.
So what we want to be able to do is we
want to present the words as input into
the neural network in such a way
that it can look for correlation and
make the correct positive or
negative prediction of the output.
So the most natural way to start
here is simply count each word and
input those counts as inputs
to the neural network.
Pretty simple, well defined and
I think that should have correlation
with what you want to predict.
Now as far as predicting and
positive and negative,
obviously neural nets can't
predict the word positive.
Well, some more advanced ones can but
that's not what we're trying to do here.
Instead, we're going to
represent positiveness and
negativeness as a number where positive
is the number 1 and negative is the 0.
Now the reason that we're
doing this in one neuron and
kind of giving it two sides that the
network has to decide between is that we
know that positive and
negative are mutually exclusive.
But we're not going to train our
network to ever say that a review is
both positive and negative.
And by modeling it this way,
we can make these two different
labels mutually exclusive.
This reduces the number of ways that
a neural network can make a mistake.
Which reduces the amount
it has to learn and
actually helps it learn
this particular pattern.
In some ways some other [INAUDIBLE] for
example,
have five different output labels for
different granularities.
So for example, can have five stars,
you can pick one star to
three stars to five stars.
And it turns out that sometimes it
can actually hurt the neural net and
make it more difficult to predict if it
actually has to predict which star was
most likely.
Because it allows it to sort of
make double positive predictions,
a three and a four where the four is
incorrect and the three is correct.
But they share a lot of signals,
it creates ambiguity in the network.
But in this case,
because you only have two labels,
we can force the network to have to
choose between the two of them thus
reducing the number of ways
that it can make an escape.
One of the themes throughout
this computorial is going to be
making the prediction
as easy as possible.
And framing the problem in such a way
where it's as easy as possible for
the neural net to make this prediction.
What do we need and
what was Project 2 going to be about?
Project 2 is about setting up two
functions that take our input and
output data and transform them into the
appropriate 1 0 binary representation or
I guess on the output and
then the count's on the input.
So in this case, the first function
I want you to build takes a review,
extracts the words from the review.
And then counts them and
it puts those counts into a vector.
Now that vector has to
be constant length,
it needs to be the length
of the vocabulary.
And then I want you to create another
function that just maps positive,
negative to a 1 or 0.
So go ahead and
create those functions and
then I'll show you how I create them and
we can compare notes.
See you then.