RPC is intended to simplify
the development of cross-address space
and/or cross-machine interactions.
So what are the benefits?
RPC offers a higher-level interface
that captures all aspects of data
movement and communications, including
communication establishment, requests,
responses, acknowledgements, et cetera.
What this also allows it permits for
RPC's to capture a lot of
the error handling and automated,
and the programmer doesn't
really have to worry about that.
Or at least the programmer doesn't have
to explicitly reimplement the handling
of all types of errors.
And finally, another benefit from RPC
is that it hides the complexities of
cross-machines interactions, so the fact
that machines may be of different types,
that the network between them may fail,
that the machines themselves may fail.
That will be hidden from the developer.
So as a programmer, when using RPC,
we don't have to worry
about those differences.