The first statement applies to threads.
Each thread belonging to a process shares the virtual address space with
other threads in that process.
And because threads share an address space,
the context switch among them happens faster than processes.
So, processes take longer to context switch.
Both threads and
processes have their execution context described with stack and registers.
Because threads share the virtual address space, it is more likely that when
multiple threads execute concurrently, the data that's needed by
one thread is already in the cache, brought in by another thread.
So, they typically result in hotter caches.
Among processes, such sharing is really not possible.
And then the last answer is B.
We already saw that for processes, it makes sense for
the operating system to support certain interprocess communication mechanisms.
And we'll see that there are mechanisms for threads to communicate and
coordinate and synchronize amongst each other.