Most of those are answerable without truth tables.
The first one is satisfiable. If A is false then not A is true,
but it could also be false, which is if A is true.
So it's not valid, and it's not unsatisfiable. We can make it either true or false.
The second one is always true.
If you look carefully, A or not A, no matter what is set for A, one of those two things will be true.
The same is true for the next one,
and it comes with this funny thing about the implies relationship.
A and not A is always false,
and we know that if the condition of an implies is false
then we consider the entire statement as true no matter what is on the right side over here.
That means because the left hand condition is always false,
because it is always valid.
The next one is satisfiable.
It is easy to see if we look for examples for it becoming true or false.
If I find one of each, of course, I show that it can't be valid, and it can't be unsatisfiable.
If A and B and C are all true, then this statement will naturally be true.
If we flip B to false, then this expression becomes false
whereas the others will remain true,
but the conjunction of those will become false.
I have just given you an example for making it true or making it false.
Hence it is satisfiable.
The next one is tricky, and I'm going to use my truth table
to show that it is actually unsatisfiable.
Let me write down the combinations for A and B.
There are four combinations in total.
A implies B is true as long as we don't have that A is true or B is false.
This is the false version. Everything else will be true.
Not A or B is true as long as B is true,
and also true if not A is true, which means A is false.
We find that these two expressions are identical.
But because we negate the second expression and with this expression,
the negation over here is just the opposite--false, true, false, false.
There is no way to make any of these come true.
Hence it is unsatisfiable.
The final one is a simple counterexample.
This is always true if all A, B, and C are true.
It is at least satisfiable, but it is not valid,
because if I flip B to false then the expression on the left becomes false,
but the right expression is not affected.
Hence it is just satisfiable.