Now, this gives us exactly what we wanted to describe quantitative at
the beginning.
Recall the problem, with the random variable X that takes on value X1 and X2,
and we ask the question, what's the probability distribution between X1 and X2?
And further, does this probability distribution,
become more skewed to one side or the other, when we know that Y1 happened?
So now we know, that this schemeness, is precisely captured by the entropy,
before and after conditioning on Y1.
Specifically, we want to look at H of X and H of X given that Y equals Y1.
If the entropy, went down as a result of Y1 happening,
then we know that Y has an impact on X.
Now, the amount that H went down due to Y
being Y1 is H of X minus H of X given Y equals Y1).
Similarly, the amount that H went down,
due to Y being Y2 is H of X minus H of X given Y equals Y2.
The impact, from Y1 and
Y2 are averaged to form what's called Conditional entropy.
As you can see, Conditional entropy,
is simply the expected value of H given the value of Y.
And thus, the expected value of reduction to entropy on X
due to knowing Y is H of X minus H of X given Y.
Finally, this tells us what we need to know about selecting features.
It we're interested in the random variable X.
And we've been collecting other variables, A, B, C, and so on.
The variable with the maximum influence over X, is the one for
which the reduction and entropy is the largest.
More precisely, the variable which has the biggest impact on X,
is the arg min of this expression.
In the next video we will apply this to identify important
features influencing enter tweet time.