What we're going to do is we're going to step through the geometry for
a pretty simple stereo system.
The first thing that we're going to do,
is assume that the optical axes are parallel.
That's these right here, and because the optical axes are perpendicular to
the image planes, it means the image planes are parallel.
In fact, we're going to assume that they're exactly coplanar.
So this image drawn here is as if we were looking down on our camera rig system,
all right?
The cameras are looking out, okay, and this is the image plane right here,
so we're looking down on the plane, and that will let us take a look at
how things shift left to right in the stereo imagery.
For our geometry here,
we're going to assume our cameras are separated by Baseline B and
that both cameras have a focal length of f, so f is on both sides.
So for the two cameras, they both have the same focal length.
Now, let's assume that we have some Point P in this scene, okay.
And it's located at a distance Z in the camera coordinate systems.
Now remember, the Z is the distance all the way down to the centers of
projection, okay?
So that's Z not to the image plane, but to the center of projection.
And if you remember, just for mathematical convenience, we put the image plane
in front of the center of projection so things don't get inverted.
So, that point P projects into both the left and the right images.
Now, just to make sure you're paying attention, on the left image,
the distance is going to be positive.
And on the right image, the distance is going to be negative because our
origins are right in the middle.
Zero is here is in the middle of the image plane, got it?
So, distance is positive in the left and negative in the right.
These quantities, xl and xr, are meant to be distances, so they're positive
values, but whether they move plus or minus depends upon which image we're in.
So here's our point pl, and there's our point pr, and pl, is as I said,
this distance xl to the right of the optical axis, so
it's positive, and the point pr is to the left.
So it's negative xr to the left of zero, all right?
So now we can do some simple geometry to figure out the relationships between
xs, ps, bs, ps and everything else that happens to be in the picture.
We want to find an expression for z, so we start by using similar triangles,
just like we did for projection, but these are different triangles.
The one's looking down.
We have the first triangle, which is based upon the point p and
each of the projections.
That triangle's shown in yellow.
And then there is another triangle that's based upon the center of projections,
and the point P.
And that one is shown here in blue.
See how it faded in.
Let me back it up.
There it is. That's the other triangle.
Well, we now have two similar triangles.
So we can write down what the relationship is between the edges.
Namely that B minus these distances,
so that's going to be this distance, okay, is to this distance,
which is just Z minus f, that's same proportion as
the total baseline B, I'll draw it here, is to the total Z.
Okay, those similar triangles give us that relationship, so
very little bit of rearranging gives us an expression for Z that says that
Z is equal to f times B over xl minus xr, okay?
And that difference between the left and
the right amount, that's called the disparity.
The cool thing here is that we're computing the distance in
the scene based upon a difference between these two.
Now you should ask yourself a little question here.
What happens when disparity is zero?
Well when disparity is zero, that means that some point in the scene
projected to the same point in the left image as the right image.
In other words, as I moved my, from my left to my right camera,
that point didn't appear to move.
Well remember, we had a quiz on this.
We talked about how come the moon follows you.
Well, the moon follows you because Z is so
far away that you get, no change in the left and the right.
So the disparity is zero, so the depth is what?
It's infinite, okay.
And that's the inverse relationship between disparity and depth.