Let's go over the question again.
We're supposed to use string slicing
to store everything before NOUN in
substring1, everything after NOUN and
before a VERB in substring2,
and everything after
VERB in subsstring3.
Let's find the indices that will
give us everything before NOUN
by taking a look at the sentence
variables' index values.
The beginning of the string,
or index 0, has a value of A.
So let's write that down.
Index 1, as we see, is a space.
And index 2, is N, and
also the beginning of NOUN.
So, as we see, everything before
NOUN is before the second index.
Let's use our findings in substring1.
So now substring1 is complete.
When the left hand side
of a colon is blank,
it means to start from the beginning.
And when there's a number in the right
hand side of a colon, it means the slice
will include everything up to,
but not including, that index.
So this will be equal to A with
space next to it, and not A space N.
Let's now move on to
substring2's indices, or
everything after NOUN and before VERB.
From finding substring1's indices,
we know that NOUN starts at index 2,
and since NOUN is four characters long,
we'll begin our substring2 at index 6.
So let's write that down.
Now we need to find where VERB begins.
I don't feel like counting all
these characters over here, so
I'll take a guess as to
what index VERB is at.
I don't know, let's say 26.
I'm now going to switch over to
my Python interpreter to see
what the value is.
All right, so
here I am in my Python interpreter, and
let's start by declaring
the sentence variable.
Now that we have our
sentence variable declared,
let's take a look at
what the 26th index has.
All right, cool.
So the 26th index of sentence is c.
Since I don't see that letter
anywhere else in the sentence,
it's a safe bet that it's
the beginning of can.
Let's write that down in
our list of index values.
Now that we know the 26th index
value is the character "c",
we can count up from there until
we find the beginning of VERB.
Counting from index 26, or c,
we found that four spaces over,
at index 30, we have V,
or the start of VERB.
So this is where we're
going to end substring2.
Let's fill that in.
And last but not least, we need to
fill in the substring indices for
substring3, or everything after VERB.
To get the beginning slice index,
we'll add the length of the word, VERB,
which is 4, to 30, or
the index we found VERB at to get 34,
and we'll leave the right
hand side of the colon blank.
Awesome, we now split out
sentence into three substrings.
We'll now be able to add our own
NOUN and VERB replacements to these
substrings so we can create our
own Mad Lib-style sentence.