So now, I’m going to give you a very concrete example to suggest the importance
of pinhole size and its relationship to pe, eh, the image quality.
Let’s start off with our simple example, our tree again.
This time around again, we have an obstruction and a screen, a sensor.
What we will do, of course, is we will create this quote,
unquote, the eye to the world, a pinhole in this obstruction.
So then, we can actually capture what's been actually visible at
this point here, to the screen there.
Of course, as we expect, all rays of light going from this point will go and
form on the other side here.
And all rays from here, and of course all rays in
between will actually use that to create a inward a tree on the other side.
Just for sake of explanation I'm basically showcasing a example image here,
this is not exactly the same tree here just showing what's going on.
That this would be a nice crisp image if this was a nice crisp hole
because everything would be going through perfectly.
And it would get a nice crisp image on the other side.
Now let's look at another example of the same situation,
again a screen a tree and obstruction.
Here I'm actually,
going to create a little bit of a bigger one hole than this one.
And we going to just do same kinds of tracing of rays.
So for example, I take tree of light.
And now, the hole is bigger of course the're is one going form the top of
the hole and another one from the bottom of the hole, when it gets here.
And in this case also, one ray is going to the top and to the bottom.
Because again, the hole is bigger here.
I showed you just one that in assume, it assumed that only, you know,
the hole was small enough that not many rays would go through it.
You know, just by looking at the triangles here.
If this size is bigger, you can expect this to be much,
you know, getting bigger as you get farther away from this point.
And, of course, what would happen in this instance is,
because of these two rays.
The trees would kind of start cut into,
you know, inter, interfering with each other as they form on the surface.
And as I put more of them there, you would see that, of course,
on the screen we have a blurry image.
Basically putting in more and
more these and the tree, of course, is looking blurry.
And again, basically think of it as nothing else as the, because of the size of
this the triangles are getting bigger and this is the blur point here.
Of course, the resulting example could be something like this where now,
of course, it's much more blurry.
So this basically starts implying is, that this size of
the pinhole is an important parameter in how well we can capture images.
Now, one thing we haven't start calling is,
we want to start actually referring to this opening as of the pinhole,
as the aperture.
Again, remember what we looked at when we looked at the insides of a camera.
The size of the aperture was basically the opening.
because that is the amount of light that was allowed into the camera before it
reached the sensor.
Well in essence, this is what it is.
Right?
It's the aperture.
And the size of this aperture is extremely important parameter for
us to know as we move towards capturing light into a camera.
Just as a note, these images are simulated just to kind of showcase this point.