Here's the F table and we'd need to use the degrees of freedom that you found
earlier. Since there are three groups, remember that there were two degrees of
freedom, and there were three cows per group who consumed the food. There were
nine total values and the degrees of freedom within group variability was 6.
They intersect here at 5.1433. Our F statistic, 27, is much greater than our F
critical value. It's out here somewhere in the critical region, probably way
out there. Therefore, we would accept the alternative. At least one pair of
significant differences exists between the amount of food that cows ate. We
summarize our results in our ANOVA table. This is how the results are typically
presented even when we use software.