Let's take a look at the solution.
Like getFavoriteMovies,our first step
will be to specify the session ID
as one of the parameters.
Then because the method contains the ID
that we need to substitute with the user
ID, we can use this
substituteKeyInMethod.
If we follow the constant
that we used here,
you can see that there's the ID
that will end up being substituted.
The next step is to
make the git request.
Then we check for an error.
Otherwise, we have our results.
Now the results in this case is
an array of dictionaries, so
we can use this moviesFromResults
method that's part of the TMDBMovie
to create an array of TMDBMovies
from the array of dictionaries.
And then we return them in
the completion handler.
Okay, let's see if this works.
I'll run the app,
we'll click through to authenticate, and
then, let's go to the watch list.
And here, in the watch list,
I see some movies that are on my watch
list and I can check the movie database
website to verify that these movies
are indeed on my watch list.