I think this quiz is slightly
challenging because,
though the logic is very simple,
it's easy to accidentally get lost in
a nasty series of nested if
statements if you're not careful.
It was my goal to keep my
code as clean as possible.
I'd love to see your code if
you think you did better.
Because this is by no
means the best answer.
Okay, let's get started.
When you look into the script
tag at the end of the body,
one of the first things that you'll come
across is this, the IssueTracker object.
I'm using it to collect and
then format the validation
messages that I want to show.
The idea is that I'll eventually call
retrieve, which returns a string.
And this string is the validation
message that I want to pass to
setCustomValidity.
And remember that if there are no
issues with the validation,
then setCustomValidity
expects an empty string.
Which is what this case is doing.
Next up,
there is the onclick handler for submit.
I start by grabbing the values
on both of the inputs and
then creating two
different IssueTrackers.
One for the first input and
one for the second input.
The reason is that sometimes I
might want a message to show up
on the first input, and
then sometimes on the second.
After that there is
the checkRequirements method, and
it's a pretty legible
series of if statements.
There's no nesting with these if
statements so, I'm pretty happy.
And this is where all of the regular
expressions are coming into play.
The only complicated if statement is
this last one where i'm looking for
illegal characters.
Or those symbols that aren't
explicitly allowed in the password.
It's only a little complex because I
wanted to inform the users exactly
which characters they
use that are illegal.
So I have to loop through
the regex match group to create
all the different validation messages.
Here's where checkRequirements
actually gets called.
And it only happens after I know
that the first password and
the second password match.
After that, it's just a matter of
retrieving the two messages and
then setting them on each
input with setCustomValidity.
All right, not too bad,
let's see this in action.
Okay, now you can see that these
are now password types, so
you can't see what I'm typing.
So let me fix that real quick.
There, I switched from password to text,
so now you can see what I'm doing.
I'll try to submit this, and
I see that they don't match.
Okay, that's obvious.
All right, and these two are too short,
they're missing an uppercase character,
they're missing a number and
they don't have any symbols.
So when i hit submit, I see all of that.
Cool, okay so now I added some
uppercase letters, some numbers, and
some symbols and
I'm pretty sure these match.
Nope, and now they're still too short,
less than 16 characters.
Okay, now these two should
be long enough now, cool.
And my password was
successfully changed.
All right now I hope you didn't pay too
much attention to that because that was
my real password.
No, I'm just joking.
All right, anyway,
I hope you had as much fun
validating these inputs as I did.
In the next lesson you'll
start designing forms with
all of the inputs you've
practiced with so far.
With designing comes testing.
So in the next video watch Luke
describe how he likes to test forms.