Hopefully you typed it in all right.
A common mistake is to forget the
semicolon at the end of each statement.
Or you may have misspelled the quantity
variable in subsequent lines of code.
The variable name must match
the same spelling and capitalization
as the very first time that
the variable was originally declared.
Also int has to be spelled
specifically in this way.
Otherwise java won't recognize that this
is supposed to be an integer variable.
For best practice, remember that
we always add a space before and
after any operators.
In this case,
we only have a sign operator, so
we add a space here and
here, in all these cases.
Thanks for
making some observations about the code.
There's no right or wrong answer here.
One of the observations you may have
made is that int is only used on
the very first line of code, right here,
but not on subsequent lines of code.
Let's talk more about that next.