once again we're in the fortunate
position to be able to bring a world
expert into the classroom Vincent van
hook is the principal scientist of
Google's deep learning team and he'll
teach you the fundamentals of deep
neural networks Vincent will cover the
jump from machine learning to deep
learning the architecture of multi-layer
deep neural networks and the concepts
underpinning convolutional neural
networks a convolutional neural network
is a specialized type of deep neural
network that turns out to be
particularly important for self-driving
cars at the end of this section you'll
use the tensorflow deep learning library
to build your own convolutional neural
network within the course you'll see
optional assignments which are designed
to familiarize you with tensorflow these
assignments are a great way to get more
practice and stand out to employers
first things first let's learn from
Vincent about how to take what you know
about machine learning and use it as an
entry point to deep learning will see
you when you finish