Well, this is one of these funny things.
Hm.
Well, these certainly true.
Okay.
Yes, I could remove the noise if you told me what the noise is.
But nobody ever tells you what the noise is.
Because if they did, they would have removed it in the first place.
So you don't know what the noise is.
You just know the statistics of the noise.
And then, here is one that's interesting.
False, because additive noise destroys information.
Well, if you have just plain addition, and
the addition works, then that statement is not true.
And so, C would be wrong.
But, suppose you have a limit between 0 and 255 or even 0 to 1.
If your noise pushes you beyond the limits and you clip.
You've lost that information.
So sometimes when you add noise you get these nonlinearities.
But in general,
we can't remove the noise because we don't know what the noise was.
If we did, we could just subtract it.