Let's go through these one by one. Under a light
load, CSMA/CD will be efficient, because when a frame is
ready, it will be sent. And then you shouldn't expect
many collisions. The same holds for switched ethernet. Token ring on
the other hand, is not efficient, as a node might
have for the token to pass all the way around the
ring before he can send his frame. CSMA/CD suffers under
heavy load. As we are likely to see repeated collisions and
long back offs, much of which will be wasted. Token
Ring, on the other hand, will continue to operate as
usual because of strict rules on whose turn it is
to access the medium. Switched Ethernet is resilient because the collisions
are either avoided altogether at the port routing or the
switch can queue up messages and send them when the machine
is ready. As to being fair, CSMA/CD is susceptible to
hogging. From one node continues to succeed and sending its frames,
while the others backoff longer and longer, because of the exponential
backoff. Token is designed for fairness, that is basically everyone gets
asked before someone can send another frame. Switched Ethernet is fair,
because pretty much everyone gets what they want all the time