You remember our problem solving work.
We have a state space like this and
we're given a start space and
a goal to reach and
then we'd search for a path to find
that goal and maybe we find this path.
Now, the way a problem solving agent
would work is first it does all the work
to figure out the path to
the goal just doing by thinking.
And then start to execute
that path to drive or
walk or however you want to get there
from the start state to the end state.
But think about what would happen
if you did that in real life?
If you did all planning ahead of time,
you have to complete goal and
then, without interacting
with the world,
without sensing it at all you
started to execute that path.
Well, this has in fact been studied.
People have gone out and blind folded,
walkers put them in the field and
told them to walk in a straight line and
the results are not pretty.
Here are the GPS tracks to prove it.
So we take a hiker, we put him at
a start location, say here, and
we blindfold him so that he can't
see anything in the horizon, but
just has enough to see his or
her feet so that they
won't stumble over something, and tell
them, execute the plan of going forward.
Put one step in front of each other and
walk forward in a straight line.
And these are the typical paths we see.
Start out going straight for awhile,
but then go in loopty-loops and
end up not on a straight path at all.
These ones over here, starting in this
location, are even more convoluted,
going straight for a little bit and
then going very tight loops.
So people are incapable of
walking a straight line
without any feedback
from the environment.
Now here on this yellow path,
this one did much better.
Why was that?
Well it's because these paths
were on overcast days and so
there was no input to make sense of.
Whereas this path was
on a very sunny day.
So even though the hiker couldn't see
farther than a few feet in front of him.
He could see shadows and
say, as long as I keep the shadows
pointing in the right direction.
Then it can go in
a relatively straight line.
So more or less, we need some
feedback from the environment.
We can't just plan ahead and
come up with a whole plan.
We've got to intervene planning and
executing.