But there is one problem,
what if there's a critical part of the
solution that is none of the parents?
>> That could be an issue.
Could also imagine that a critical piece
might be in a board that never
gets selected as a parent.
Like poor number 4 here, and
that critical piece gets bred out in
the early stages and never comes back.
How do we handle it?
>> More randomness.
>> How so?
>> Just like we have
mutations in biology,
we're going to use mutations
in genetic algorithms.
For each digit,
I'm going to have a small but
significant chance that the digit
will mutate into some other digit.
In the first child,
the five changes into a one.
The second child does not
have any mutations and
the third and
fourth children each have one mutation.
>> So this mutation step is like
occasionally choosing a random direction
and simulated annealing
>> Or
the randomness in
stochastic beam search.
>> Exactly.
>> And given enough generations and
mutations,
we expect to get the desired answer?
>> Yep.
And one of the things often reported
in genetic algorithms papers
is how many generations are needed
until we get a good answer.
>> Okay.
Now that we've seen all the components
of genetic algorithms,
it seems like a good time for a quiz.