The goal of this course is for
you to start building your first
iOS app as soon as possible.
To that end, we will teach you the
minimum amount of Swift Syntax you need
to build Silly Song!.
Silly Song!
is a single screen app that prompts
the user to enter their name and
creates a Silly Song based on the input.
In order to build Silly Song!, you will
need to be able to manipulate strings,
which we will learn in lesson one, and
define and call functions,
which we'll learn in lesson two.
In lesson three, you'll build
the logic for silly song, and
in lesson four,
you'll learn how to use X code,
the integrated development
environment for iOS.
Then you'll finish up the app and
submit it for your first project review.
Throughout the course we'll be
working through examples together and
the first lesson will begin with
a set of exercises on strings
to get you writing Swift code ASAP.
That's it for the road map,
let's check out the first exercise to
see what Swift strings are all about.