Before I dive into mathematical detail about
value functions, let me just give you a tutorial.
The value function is a potential function
that leads from the goal location--in this case, the 100 in the upper right--
all the way into the space so that hill climbing
in this potential function leads you on the shortest path to the goal.
The algorithm is a recursive algorithm.
It spreads the value through the space, as you can see in this animation,
and after a number of iterations, it converges,
and you have a grayscale value
that really corresponds to the best way of getting to the goal.
Hill climbing in that function gets you to the goal.
You can simplify.
Think about this as pouring a glass of milk
into the 100th state and having the milk
descend through the maze, and later on,
when you go in the gradient of the milk flow,
you will reach the goal in the optimal possible way.