Let's look closer at how block devices
are used, using the similar diagram.
Block devices, like disks,
are typically used for storage.
And the typical
storage-related abstraction,
used by applications, is a file.
The file is a logical storage unit,
and it is mapped to some underlying
physical storage location.
What that means is that
at the top-most level,
applications don't
think about the disks.
They don't issue operations on disks for
seeking blocks and sectors, etc.
Instead, they think about files, and
they request operations
to be performed on files.
Below this file-based interface used by
applications will be the file system.
The file system will have the
information how to take these reads and
writes that are coming
from the application, and
to then determine where exactly
is the file, how to access it,
what is the particular portion of
that file that needs to be accessed,
what are any permission checks
that need to be performed, and
to ultimately initiate
the actual access.
One thing that's useful to have is for
operating systems provide some
flexibility in the actual details
that a file system has in terms of
how it lays out files in disk,
how it performs these access operations.
In order to do that, operating systems
allow for a file system to be modified
or completely replaced with
a different file system.
To make this easy,
operating systems specify something
about the file system interfaces.
This includes both the interfaces that
are used by applications to interact
with the file system, and there,
the norm is the POSIX API that includes
the read and write and open file system
calls that we've mentioned so far.
Also, standardizing
the file system interfaces
means that there would be certain
standard APIs in terms of
how these file systems interact with
the underlying storage devices,
as well as with other operating system
components they need to interact with.
If the files are indeed
stored on block devices,
clearly at the lowest level, the file
system will need to interact with
these block devices near
their device drivers.
We can have different types of block
devices where the files could be stored,
SCSI ID disk, hard disk,
USB drive, solid state disks.
And the actual interaction
with them will require certain
protocol specific APIs.
Now, in spite of the fact that all
of these may be block devices,
there still may be certain
differences among them.
For instance, what are the types
of errors they report or
how they report the errors.
So, in order to mask all of that,
the block device stack introduces
another layer, and
that is the generic block layer.
The intent of this layer is
to provide a standard for
a particular operating system
to all types of block devices.
The full device features
are still available and
unaccessible through the device driver.
However, if used by the file system
stack some of these will be abstracted
underneath this generic
block device interface.
So then what happens when the user
process wants to perform an access,
a read or write operation in the file,
it invokes that read/write operation for
the POSIX API and
the kernel level file system will then,
based on the information that it
maintains, will determine what is
the exact device that needs to be
accessed, and what is the exact
block on that device that supports
that particular region of the file.
That in turn will result
in some generic read block,
write block operations that are passed
to the generic block layer and
this layer will know how exactly to
interact with a particular driver,
so how to pass those operations
to the particular driver and
how to interpret the error messages,
or notifications,
or responses that
are generated by that driver.
Any lower-level differences
among the devices,
like the protocols that they use, et
cetera, will be handled by the driver.
It will speak the specific
protocol that's necessary for
the particular device.