So during leaf counting we
talk about a tree having or
consisting of a left and right sub-tree.
>> Sounds right, anything else?
>> There's parts of a pile which
is tree as parts so that's.
>> Okay.
>> kind of that left and
right sub-tree kind of
going back to that.
>> So you've got it.
In our diagram now,
we're going to have an aggregation
relationship between pile and tree.
This means there's a line between
the two and at the pile end of the line,
is this open diamond indicating that
a pile is a collection of trees.
Likewise if we have sub-trees
being parts of trees,
we have an aggregation relationship
between a tree and itself.
Okay, so we'll have a line,
a looped line going from tree to itself,
and at one end of that line,
we'll have the diamond indicating that
tree is a recursive data structure,
as you might expect, okay?
Consisting of parts which are trees.