Hi, I'm Mike Wales, the web
curriculum manager here at Udacity.
In a past life,
I built web applications for
three-letter intelligence agencies
you've probably heard of.
There was no room for
error with these applications.
They had to function as intended
all the time, every time.
More importantly, we needed a way to
add new features to these applications,
while making sure we
didn't break anything.
You're probably already doing
this in your own web apps.
You refresh the browser,
click around and
just watch to make sure
everything is working correctly.
Although this works, it's a pretty
slow and inaccurate process.
What if I told you there was
a way you could programmatically
check your application's functionality?
In this course I'll show
you how to do just that.
You'll learn how to write your very own
unit tests which are suites of functions
that check if parts of your application
are functioning as you expect.
In fact, I'll even show you a whole new
way to go about application development
called test-driven development
where you write tests for
your features before you even
write the feature itself.
So what is a test anyway?