So the application not responsive error
is something that doesn't have one
correct answer.
If you think about it there
could be a ton of reasons why.
And I think again it's
important to follow up with,
what does your application do?
I think if Sam was able to ask
a couple more questions about,
okay well is it a music app?
What runs in the background?
Starting to probe into why
it's not responding, and
kind of figuring that out because it's
either what my application is doing or
how it's structured, is important.
So again, with these type of questions,
they're very broad and
there's not one right answer.
It's just important for you to kind
of talk to your interviewer and
nail a very specific area.