Let me actually introduce to you some
concepts on, how we can get depth?
If somebody gave me a single image
like this, how would you compute that?
Well, an interesting
thing in this image is,
there's perspective in this image
that is, if I was to let's say,
draw a line let's just draw
a line connecting all these
points here or I can draw a line
connecting all these points here.
And I can draw a line connecting
all these points here.
In essence, if you look at them, each
and every one of the lines that I would
draw is basically pointing that
these are vanishing lines.
They get closer and closer, and
converging to a same point
at the distance away.
So, in real scenes you will always find
that there are pre-determined, well
defined vanishing lines and points that
an image in a real scene will point to.
And that basically start showing
is of course there's depth.
Things that are farther
away are smaller,
things that are closer up are larger,
and by disconstructing it
as you go farther into the scene
they get smaller and smaller.
So this is an important cue,
the perspective and
basically just looking at
vanishing lines and points.
Now one thing I want to remind you is,
this is actually true for
mostly real images and photographs.
Just as an exercise I recommend trying
to do the same exercise on paintings and
seeing, you might actually
find that sometimes
vanishing lines do not converge.
Here is another perspective
to look at depth, right.
Here I'm basically sharing an image.
Again it's hard to,
in this instance find vanishing lines.
There is horizon and everything, but the
vanishing lines are hard to determine.
But, I know what humans usually are or
what size.
So by looking at this and
noticing the fact that,
as you go further, this same humans are,
are different people.
They're getting smaller and smaller.
That also starts giving
me the sense of the depth
as I move further down this way.
Right, so
just objects of known sizes help me
understand how I'm going to
be able to perceive that.
Another high level cue, and when I mean
high level is it requires a lot more
kind of analysis of a scene is something
which could be called occlusions, right?
These two people well,
he's in front of this lady here.
She's in front of all
of the shopping stuff.
She's in front of the,uh, you know,
materials and this market here.
Which basically starts saying, is I
can't see any of this because she's in
front of it, I can't see anything
behind her because she's occluding it.
And there's a whole lot of
information on how the occlusions
are kind of manifesting it selves.
And this kind of starts telling
me more about the scene, so
occlusions are also an important cue
that could be used to analyze scenes.
A really well known method in
the computer vision is extracting
information of shape of a object
by just seeing how well or
how differently it's lit?
So here is an example of just by
looking at the lighting variations on
the surface, you can actually
extract the shape and the depth.
As I said depth as you go
into the image of this face.
This is an interesting example of
how we can actually start looking at
depth of different types of scenes,
and just to showcase this,
I'm going to show you something fun and
interesting that one of our alums
Grant Schindler worked on, and
which is an app on the App Store now.