Okay, that first quiz was
a little bit on the simple side.
This one's going to be more useful.
You'll be matching jQuery's.ready
feature by wrapping a check for
document.readyState in a Promise.
You are now in the thening
stage of the course.
I want you to use then to perform
an action after a promised result.
Document.readystate has
three possible states.
Loading, interactive, and complete.
Loading means the document
is still loading.
Interactive means the document
has loaded and been parsed.
But subresources like images and
style sheets have yet to load.
This is equivalent to
the dom content loaded event.
Lastly there's the complete state,
and that means that
all the subresources including
images and style sheets have loaded.
Every time the document's
ready state changes
a ready state change event fires.
Creating a promise to run on interactive
is really useful if you want to run
some code as soon as all of the initial
dom elements have been loaded.
For this quiz I'm giving you an event
handler for ready state change.
I want you to wrap it in a promise so
that it resolves when
the dom is interactive.
Or, in other words,
I want it to resolve when the ready
state is no longer loading.
Like the last quiz, you don't need to
worry about air handling because if
the dom is never ready then
the page won't display anyway.
Make sure you test, too.
Do so by using .then to chain
the method wrapperResolved when
the document is ready.
Make sure you check out
the Instructor Notes for
help getting started, and good luck.