All right so
now we're going to get started on some
technical coding tech questions okay?
>> [CROSSTALK] All right.
>> So I'm going to erase the board here.
All right, so let's imagine
that we're building a website.
And this website,
let's say this is our viewport here.
This website will present
a slideshow of images.
>> Got it.
>> All right so this is the web site and
this is also the viewport.
And here's an image and on top of this
image there will be buttons going left
or right allowing you to cycle through
the images and then kind of off here.
Tthis is the first image
that's outside the viewport,
you're looking at this one and then
you have on and on and on over here.
Let's say five images in total.
>> Right.
>> I would like you to write
the HTML markup you would use.
Don't worry about styling.
Just the HTML you would
use to build this out.
>> Got it.
>> Don't worry about HTML, the head tag,
the body tag, just assume all that's
provided, and just what you need
to do this year to set it up.
>> And I assume I'll use JavaScript
to flush this out later, right?
>> Yeah we'll move into that.
>> We'll move into that okay.
>> Right now just focus on the HTML
that you would use to build this.
>> Right so first thing I really
don't understand, was okay I
want to make sure I have all my
variables and all my constraints right.
It's that I need to make a carousel and
then I need to have pictures,
right, that show up.
And right now here's the viewport.
And it looks like to me it looks
like there's a section here.
So this is a box so what I'm going to
do is actually define that box first,
in my viewport.
So I'm going to use,
most likely I'm going to use,
I like to use semantic tags so
I'm going to use section.
And probably class, carousel?
Probably define that.
And section here.
So this will define this here.
>> Okay.
>> So within the section.
How we are going to do this is
I'm actually going to create.
I need buttons here, so
probably I'm going to have buttons.
So I'm going to actually want to
expand this a little more, Section.
I'll probably see,
since I'll probably make some
sort of span, Here.
Class equals button.
Left, and
then I'll have another span here.
And a span here.
Because then I'll use CSS to
style my buttons later on but
this is how I would set up my structure.
Class equals button right.
Okay, within here, again,
I actually want the main picture.
So I'll have an image tag here.
Class equals I'll probably
name this carousel me,
pic, right here.
Now and how we would like set up
these other things off the view port,
I would probably have some
sort of JavaScript that would
like load within the section here.
At the end here.
Probably have some JavaScript
that would like load.
JavaScript.
To preload.
Take these images and
then I click.
If I click on the button then like
I would preload these images all.
And I want to get a clarification
like if I click on this button here.
That the image will actually animate and
shift.
>> We're not worried about animations.
>> Okay.
>> We would just want if you were to
click this button,
this picture would go away and
this picture would be in it's place.
>> Okay.
>> And so
if you were to click obviously the right
button the opposite would happen this
picture would they move this
way because semantically and
structurally that's what would happen.
>> Okay.
>> But not animation wise.
So if you would equate the right button
you would end up having two images out
of view somehow.
>> Okay.
>> And
then this third image
would be in the view.
>> Okay, got it.
Then, so thanks for the clarification.
So then, I would probably
have an image here, class,
carousel, like off left.
Left here?
>> Mm-hm.
>> And then I will have a image here,
class carousel off rights.
And that's how it was set up
because basically these two.
I will set up my CSS and
these two will be off the field for
using some sort of like width to make
sure that we need to make sure that
the viewport there so
you know what you look this will be.
This will show up.
This will just show up here in
the viewport, this will show up here.
And this will show up here.
>> Right.
>> And that's how I would set
up just a pure structure.
>> Okay.
>> Right now.
So a few questions.
In choosing these spans here.
You said that these
are essentially buttons.
>> Yeah.
>> But you're using the span tag.
>> Are there any negative consequences
from using that span as opposed to
using something like an anchor tag?
Or a button itself?
>> The negative consequence that I
see is that, the span takes up space.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Though this space will be guided by
whatever background image I give it.
>> Okay.
>> So, I think it's, if i'm correct,
this span tag will actually take
up space versus an anchor tag,
and anchor tag you can use a anchor tag.
>> There's a specific advantage for
using a anchor tag or a button.
Let's assume the user
does not have a mouse.
>> Okay for accessibility concerns yeah.
You're right,
I would op to think about accessibility.
I would actually change
my span to anchor tag.
>> Okay.