First, an IKE SA needs to be established
before IPSec SAs can be negotiated.
This is true, because the purpose of an
ISA is to use it to negotiate IPSec SAs.
Second, the identity
of the responder and
receiver and the messages they have
exchanged need to be authenticated.
This is true.
This is the last step of
the Phase One protocol.
Third, with perfect forward secrecy,
the IPsec SA keys
are based on the IKE shared
secret established in Phase One.
This is false.
With perfect forward secrecy,
the IPsec SA keys are not based on
the shared secret keys
established in Phase One.
So that if the phase one
keys are compromised,
the IPSec SA keys are not compromised.