So to get us started,
let's recall the basic elements
of computational photography and
the various stages that we actually
have looked at many times in this class.
Basically we have a 3D scene,
which is illuminated.
We want to actually
take the illumination,
use the optics to focus
it onto a sensor.
Sensor gives us information,
allows us to create images and
pixels that we can process
to improve the quality,
which is sent to a display and
then used by a user.
And this has basically been the pipeline
we have been looking at for
computational photography
throughout the class.
Let's look at it much more pictorially.
Again, we're trying to remember
what we have already looked at
previously in this class.
We can actually take a 3D scene like
this and illuminate it with a projector.
In this case projector
is a light source.
And to control this light source we can
put some sort of a controllable aperture
or modulator in front of it that,
basically, opens a different
regions here, or different regions of
this thing to illuminate the scene.
So, in essence, we can now control how
the light is actually being entered
into the scene and
illuminating the scene.
On the other hand, we can do the same by
actually having a camera in the scene,
which is now capturing the light
illuminated by this light source.
And, of course,
we can also put a modulator,
a controllable aperture in front of
the camera which only allows a specific
light to go through in
different parts of this region.
Again, both of those
are controllable things.
And this was basically the idea we
had before of how we can control and
computationally control each and
every aspect of how light is shining
on a scene and how it can be
captured to create an image of different
types, a novel image sometimes.
So this has been something
we've looked at before.