So to set break points in the command
line we'll use the LLDB's breakpoint
command.
And for the first question,
which sets a line breakpoint,
I've used breakpoint set and
then I specified the file option and for
the file, BugFactory.swift, and
for the line option, line 26.
So the whole command looks like this.
Next to set a breakpoint
using a selector,
we use the breakpoint set command again
but this time we use a selector option
and for the selector option we're
passing the value viewDidLoad.
This as we'll see shortly creates
what's known as a symbolic breakpoint,
because it matches on a symbol In this
case a selector instead of a line.
And the selector we are interested
in is viewDidLoad so
the full command looks like this.
And note that because viewDidLoad
does not take any arguments,
we're just writing the name by itself.
However for a method like
viewWillAppear, which takes a parameter.
The selector is going
to include a colon, so
it would be like you will appear colon
and that's because it has a parameter.
That's what the selector would look
like for that particular method.
And if you're unsure at all about how to
specify selector then you can always go
to Apple's documentation because
they use the selectors everywhere
in the documentation.
So for example I"m in the UI view
controller classes documentation and
we can see, go up a little bit
here's our viewDidLoad selector.
And notice it does not have a color or
anything it's just viewDidLoad.
This minus symbol here represents
that it is an instance
method belong to an instance of UI View
controllers, not a class method.
And if we scroll further down we'd
see for instance view will appear.
And it takes a colon and that colon
exists because it has a parameter for
animated or
if you have a method that's got multiple
arguments, see if you can find one.
Here we go, begin appearance
transition we can see that it's
selector has two colons,
it's got a colon for
the first parameter Is appearing and
a con for the second parameter animated.
Next, a list all breakpoints,
we use breakpoint lists.
And to show the stack trace for
all threads we use thread backtrace all.
Let's go ahead and
see these commands in action.