In order to build a UI in Android,
we use Views.
Views are just rectangles that
appear on the screen, and you may or
may not see the boarders
of those rectangles.
Essentially, a View handles drawing and
event handling and all the basic widgets
in Android extend from this base class.
The Android developer's website has
visual guides on how to use those basic
widgets.
For example, the text field which allows
the user to input text to your app,
can be configured to either
single line or multi-line.
It also offers something,
text selection for copying and
pasting and text auto-completion.
You get to also specify the keyboard
type between just normal text or
a phone number or an email address.
Another common view is the Button.
And the website comes with instructions
on how to use the OnClickListener
along with some styling recommendations.
Other input widgets
include Radio Buttons,
Checkboxes, as well as date and
time Pickers.
And also,
Spinners which act like drop down menus.
When it comes down to the style and
design of those widgets,
you should absolutely check out
this Android material design guide.
This will be covered in more
depth in the next lesson.
So for now, let's focus on
building a functional UI first.
Now, if you want to display multiple
views together, you need a ViewGroup.
A ViewGroup is a container for
children views and
its the base class for
all the layouts in Android.
Let's have a look at some of
the most commonly used layouts.
The first time is the FrameLayout.
A child that gets added
to the FrameLayout
will be placed into the default
position at the top left corner.
If you add another view, it will be
placed on top of that first one.
So typically, FrameLayouts are used
to block out an area on the screen to
just display one single item.
Next we have the LinearLayout,
which simply organizes its children
either vertically or horizontally.
You can also specify a weight for
each child,
giving it more or
less space than others.
And then, we have the RelativeLayout,
where you can specify that a view should
be aligned to the parents, left,
top, right, or bottom edge.
You can also specify that one view
should be relative to another view.
It doesn't fill up the space as nicely,
compared to a linear layout.
But there's pros and cons to each.
There is also a GridLayout where the
views just fills up cells in a grid and
you could also have views
that span multiple cells.
It's worth mentioning here that a view
group enhanced all the layouts extend
from the base view class, which means
that any layout is a view in itself.
That means you can nest view groups and
layouts within each other, opening up
tons of possibilities of designing any
layouts you can imagine but be careful.
Nesting too many layouts in one another,
may effect the overall
performance when rendered.
That's why Android offers one more
layout type called the constraint
layout.
The constraint layout just
like the relative layout
allows you to place child views
relative to the parent or each other.
However, the constraint layout
uses constraints to specify how
each view should be positioned and
scaled relative to the other views.
This offers the ability to create
pretty complicated layouts
as we will see later on without having
to nest layouts within each other.
The reason we care much about
parent child view relationships
is because the way a child gets
laid out depends on its parent.
The simplest example of this is
specifying the view's, width and height.
This diagram shows all possible
combinations of using wrap_content or
match_parent.
However, if you ran this on a device,
all of these would look
visually the same, simply because
you won't be seeing the boundaries.
So, why does it matter
which one we pick?
Well, it matters when there are other
children placed next to these ones.
And another reason would be,
if you want to specify gravity.
Say for example, you have this
text view within a frame layout.
By default, the text is left aligned and
in this case, no gravity is set.
If we specify gravity to be center,
then it will center the content
within the textview itself.
Vertically, it can move because the text
is already centered inside the textview
but horizontally it does shift
over to be in the middle.
Instead of this, if we specify a layer
gravity to be center, that will center
the entire textview horizontally and
vertically within the parent.
Since this text view with the center
match parent, it can't really move
sideways, so it would only move it down
towards the center of the entire layout.
But say, if the text view
was set to wrap content,
then it would move to align itself
in the center horizontally as well.
You can also specify padding and
margin on views.
Padding tends to shift the content
inside the textview itself.
Expanding the border, if you said
the the layout margin to be x and
the parent will be the one
interpreting this parameter
adding a margin of x
around the entire view.
Again, when you render both of these,
they will visually look the same.
But there will be an obvious difference,
if there was any background color for
example, for these views or
of the text slightly getting longer and
they were wrapped differently.
All views have a visibility property.
For this image here,
it could be visible, invisible or gone.
If it's invisible,
then it's not shown but
it's still got a placeholder that
affects the entire views around it.
If it's set to gone,
then it will be no longer in the layout.
It's as if it didn't even
exist in the XML at all.
You can also toggle the visibility of
a view dynamically during run time.
The developer website lists all the
possible XML attributes that you could
set for each view class.
It also shows the Inherited
attribute from its base class,
all that along with
the corresponding Java methods.
So that was a brief rundown
to help us get started but
definitely do check out the developer
website for more details later.