Before we get started coding, we must
first create a client ID and client
secret with Google in order to be able
to communicate with its API libraries.
In your browser,
visit console.developers.google.com.
And log into your Google account and
follow along.
Once you're logged in, go ahead and
click the Create Project button.
Let's name our project
Restaurant Menu App.
Google automatically creates
a project ID for you.
You can change this project ID,
but it needs to be unique.
So let's go ahead and
leave it as is for now.
Let's click Create.
And when Google's created your project,
it'll automatically take you
to the Project Dashboard.
Go ahead and click APIs and
auth on the left-hand menu.
Then select Credentials.
In the OAuth 2.0 section go ahead and
click Create new Client ID.
Make sure Web application is selected
and then click Configure consent screen.
The consent screen is the screen
that will be displayed
when my app tries to connect
to a user's Google account.
I must specify at least my email and
a name for the product.
Let's go ahead and
put restaurant menu app.
Let's save our changes, and
then click Create Client ID.
Now that we see that our web application
has a client ID complete with email
address, client secret, redirect URIs,
and JavaScript origins.
Now let's go ahead and
click Edit Settings.
In our authorized JavaScript origins,
let's go ahead and
add http://localhost:5000.
This is needed for
our local version of code to work.
If you've been using the IP
representation of localhost,
127.0.0.1, this should also
be included in the JavaScript
origins if you want that URL to work.
Let's go ahead and click Update.
And we're ready to use our client ID and
client secret to add
OAuth to our application.