So here in the order_dinner.xml
layout file, you should have button,
Start checkout.
Notice that initially we set
the visibility to "invisible,"
because we don't want the button to
show up until after the user presses
the Add to cart button.
Now looking at the order_dinner_activity
java file, we need to import the button,
because we are going to be hiding and
showing buttons.
We added the startCheckout() method.
We show a toast instead of actually
implementing the checkout process, and
then we call
the sendStartCheckoutHit method.
And then in the sendStartCheckoutHit
method, we're going to send a hit to
Analytics to report that
the user started checkout.
And for
this we're going to fake the cart and
just assume that the currently
selected dinner is what's in the cart.
So we create the product.
We set the ProductAction
to ACTION_CHECKOUT.
Set the category.
I'm setting mine to Shopping steps.
We set the action, the label,
we build a hit, and we send it.
So one other thing we need to do is
to update the addDinnerToCart method
to show the button for checking out,
and to hide the button for
adding the dinner to the cart.