Now that we know about how Unity
handles colliders and rigidbodies,
let's dive into how we can use
physics to detect if we're
looking at a specific
object in the island scene.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
For that we need to
talk about raycasting.
Raycasting is like the name
suggests shooting a ray out
from a given point in the hopes of
getting a collider in our scene.
Raycasting has a lot of applications but
one of the biggest use cases is for
detecting what someone
in VR is looking at.
A ray requires two
pieces of information.
The position it's located at and
the direction it's traveling in.
In VR, we're fortunate to always
know both of those details,
which makes it really
easy to cast a ray.
So let's do that.
First thing we need to do is add
a collateral to all the objects we want
to detect.
In this case, let's make sure
there's one on our treasure chest.
Once we do that, let's create a C#
script and call it, Detect Treasure.
Now before we dive into writing code,
let's first take a look at
the documentation for Raycasting.
If we scroll down a bit,
we can see that there's some
sample code that we can use.
Even though there aren't many
lines to do a simple raycast,
there's quite a lot going on here.
For starters, instead of using update,
the sample uses fixed update.
Fixed update is a method in Unity that
works very similarly to the update
method, but is the proper place to write
code that deals with rigidbodies, and
the Unity physics engine.
Since Raycasting uses physics,
we should be using fixed update.
Next, the code defines a forward vector.
This is the direction that our object
is facing and in the Unity editor,
it's represented by this
blue arrow right here.
After that, we have this line here
that actually does the Raycasting.
So let's break that down,
starting from the middle.
So first,
we have this call to raycast, and
we provide it the position,
our forward vector and
how far we want the ray to travel,
which in this case is ten meters.
Then, outside of our raycast, we have if
conditional which checks to see if our
ray actually hit anything or not.
If we do hit an object, then we get
to print this little message here and
that's the power of just
a few lines of codes.
Let's go ahead and copy this and put
that into our detect treasure script.
And at this point, let's just add
the component to our main camera and
then test it out.
Once we hit Play and look at
the treasure chest in the center of our
vision, we'll see that we get
the message here in the console.
And if we look away, then we
don't get these messages anymore.
So now that we know that we're
correctly detecting our treasure chest,
let's have the treasure chest open.
But first, we need to create an
animation for it, which we'll do next.