Many problems in artificial
intelligence are exponential in time or
space, or both.
In fact, NP hard problems are so
common in AI that researchers joke,
half seriously,
that AI is the study of finding
clever hacks to exponential problems.
Often when a clever hack is finally
found, or when computers finally get
fast enough to address that particular
problem successfully, the world
no longer thinks of the problem as one
belonging to artificial intelligence.
How many people think about the system
that helps consumers choose
plane flights as an AI?
Or the system that helps determine
when to deploy an airbag on an SUV?
Yet at one point,
these types of problems were
considered to be part of AI.
That idea leads me to another
joke definition of AI.
Artificial intelligence consists of all
the NP hard problems that have not yet
been solved.
What matters to me are the problems
that the field of AI tackles.
On the way here, I was practicing
this lecture with my taxi driver,
Dilbur, when I realized he was
using AI while we were talking.
To get me to Udacity headquarters,
the navigation program on his smartphone
had plotted a path that was better
than the one I would have told him.
And was communicating with him
in a way that he was getting
the information as he needed it.
That's what is exciting about AI,
you get a chance to work on
everyday problems that can
improve people's lives.