AsyncTask allows you to run a task on
a background thread while publishing
results to the UI thread.
The UI thread has a message queue and
a handler that allows you to send
a process runnable objects and
messages, often from other threads.
AsyncTask wraps this behavior with
a reasonably straightforward interface.
AsyncTask is a generic class.
Meaning that it takes parameterized
types in its constructor.
Each one of these generic parameters
is to find as a Java variable argument
with the three dots,
which means that it is technically
passed as an array in Java world.
The three types used by
an AsyncTask are the following.
Params, the parameter type sent
to the task upon execution.
Progress, the type published to
update progress using the background
computation.
And result, the type of the result
of the background computation.
These three parameters
correspond to three
primary functions you can
override in AsyncTask.
doinBackground, onProgressUpdate and
onPostExecute.
There is also an onPreExecute function
to help complete the pattern.
In order to execute an AsyncTask,
you call Execute with the parameters
to be set to the background task.
The AsyncTask then runs
through several steps.
First, it calls onPreExecute
on the UI thread.
So, you can initialize anything
you might want to in the UI thread
before your background tasks starts.
Then, it calls a doInBackground
on another thread,
which is where your long
running task will run.
It's the only method that must
be overridden to use the class.
And it is called with parameters
you pass to the execute function.
If you want to update some UI with the
progress from your long-running task,
you call publishProgress with
the progress parameters.
This causes onProgressUpdate
to be called on the UI thread
with your progress parameters.
You can call publshProgress as many
times as you'd like from doinBackground.
Finally, you return the result
when you're tasking running in
doinBackground is complete.
This causes the OnPost Execute
function to get
called on the UI thread with
the result you returned.
AsyncTask is a useful abstraction for
threading and
messaging between threads on Android.
It's not right in every circumstance,
but
it's a good start to get you coding
in a multi-threaded environment.