I think the only correct answer here can be
the last one;
it's some combination of the above criteria,
because there's always counter examples if you just take a single one of them.
So for example, if software does something that the user doesn't want,
if the software enforces copyright protection,
some people might call that malware, actually,
but there are of course cases where
software does something that the user doesn't want
and it's still for a good purpose.
Software that deletes files, no way,
because you can delete files on your computer using
the normal delete command,
and that is not malware.
Gathering information from your computer, not as a stand-alone criterion,
because there might be software that you actually want to
gather information from your computer.
Disrupting other programs;
well, sounds like malware, but on the other hand,
if for example you have an anti-malware program
that disrupts malware, that will definitely disrupt,
or hopefully disrupt the computer virus
that is trying to infect your system.
It doesn't have to be malware
just because it interrupts other programsl.
Installs without asking; well, with most software
having automated updates,
I don't think that classifies as malware alone.