For this quiz you'll be wrapping
set.Timeout with a Promise.
There won't be any error handling yet
because I want to keep
this first quiz simple.
I'm giving you a sample
page to work with,
and inside of it you'll find
a function called wait.
Wait should simply wait a set number
of milliseconds before resolving.
That means that you'll need to
call resolve when setTimeout
executes its callback.
While you're working on this function,
I want you to console.log(this)
inside the Promise.
The reason is that I have a question for
you about the scope of this inside
Promises when you finish working on it.
I also want you to return
the Promise from wait.
The reason is that,
after you finish your work,
you will be able to uncomment
these two lines to test your code.
If there are no errors,
and this text changes,
you'll know you've done it right.
And like I said, when you're done,
I have a question for you.
What is the scope of
this inside the Promise?
Type your answer into this box.
Don't forget, you can find
a link to more quiz instructions
in the instructor notes, and good luck.