Now there are a number of different
ways to solve this quiz, so
don't worry if yours doesn't
match up exactly with mine.
I set up the event
tracker function here.
Each object keeps track
of a list of events and
a list of other objects to notify.
Then I extend the function's prototype.
Just like backbones on,
this function add the callback to
the event's list of callbacks.
Very similar to on,
notify adds a list of objects it
needs to notify for each event.
Trigger loops through all of
the callbacks and invokes them.
It also loops through the list of
objects it needs to notify and
triggers them too.
And that's it.
So, an event tracker object
can manage its own events.
It can also let other objects register
with them to get notified when an event
happens.
Pretty neat?