All right, so let's rememb, remind ourselves of the overall strategy for
doing feature-based alignment to affine transforms.
We know how to compute features.
That involves both detection, remember all that Harris, that Harris Laplace
stuff, for finding feature points, and for generating descriptors.
We talked about SIFT where we generate descriptions around the little local
neighborhoods of the points.
Second, we know how to find some pau, plausible, or
what we're soon going to call putative matches.
We talked about doing the vari, the variation on Kd-trees,
the Best-Bin hashing methods.
Basically ways of saying,
well which features are likely to match which other features?
I might make some mistakes, but
at least they get me some, some reasonable matches.
Then we would have to compute a transform that aligns one image to the next.
So for we talked about doing homographies or affine transforms.
And then finally you would apply that transform.
Great.
All right, so the algorithm follows this pretty carefully, but
you'll see in a minute, we're going to get to a point where we don't,
there's a step that we don't know actually how to do.
So the first is extract the features, fine, we do that.
Second, is compute these putative matches.
That's the term that's used.
This is that, what I was talking about doing this kd-tree or the best bin.
And what you see drawn here, all those red arrows, those are going from
some feature in the left to the best feature matching it on the right.
Now if this was nice, if this,
if everything was right, you'd see this nice smooth transition.
But of course what you see here is a lot of stuff.
In fact you can see, you know, some of these things tend to be all lined up
the same direction, but here's one right, it goes from here to there.
That is clearly, I think the technical word is, wrong.
So what we'd like to do is, somehow figure out a solution to this that makes it
clear that we're going to ignore that one and pay attention to another.
So after we find the putative matches,
then we have the loop until happy routine.
Okay, so loop until happy says,
hypothesize some transform T from some of the matches.
Actually, this is what's going to be interesting.
This sum of the matches, okay?
And then we're going to verify the transform.
We'll talk about what that means in a minute, and
we keep doing this until we think we found a solution that's really good.
That's what it means loop until happy.
At least today and then you apply the transform.