So far we've looked at the state space of cities in Romania--
a 2-dimensional, physical space.
But the technology for problem solving through search
can deal with many types of state spaces,
dealing with abstract properties, not just x-y position in a plane.
Here I introduce another state space--the vacuum world.
It's a very simple world in which there are only 2 positions
as opposed to the many positions in the Romania state space.
But there are additional properties to deal with as well.
The robot vacuum cleaner can be in either of the 2 conditions,
but as well as that each of the positions
can either have dirt in it or not have dirt in it.
Now the question is to represent this as a state space
how many states do we need?
The number of states can fill in this box here.