Now I'm going to give you some sentences
or axioms in first-order logic.
And I want you to tell
me if they correctly or
incorrectly represent the English
that I'm asking about.
So tell me yes or no,
are these good representations?
And the first, I want to represent
the English sentence Sam has two jobs.
And the first order logic sentence
is there exists an x and
y such that job of Sam,
x and job of Sam, y and not x=y.
And so tell me yes, that correctly
represents Sam has two jobs or
no, there's a problem.
And secondly, I want to represent
the idea of set membership.
Now assume I've already defined
a notion of adding an element to a set.
Can I define set membership for
these two axioms?
For all x and s,
x is a member of the result of adding x
to any set s and for all x and
s, x is a member of s implies that for
all y,
x is a member of the set that
you get when you add y to s.
And third,
I'm going to try to define the notion of
adjacent squares on say, a checkerboard.
Where the squares are numbered
with x and y coordinates and
we want to just talk about adjacency in
the horizontal and vertical directions.
Can I define that as follows?
For all x and y, the square x,
y is adjacent to the square + x,
1, y and the square x,
y is adjacent to the square x + y, 1.
And assume that we've defined
the notion of + somewhere.
And that the character set allows + to
occur as the character for a function.
Tell me yes or
no, is that a good representation
of the notion of adjacency?