In this section we'll move on to simple storm topology submission.
Well, you'll submit the program that you just built in Maven.
The topology you just built takes in a TestWordSpout linked to
an ExclamationBolt using a shuffleGrouping linked to
the same ExclamationBolt using another shuffleGrouping.
We'll be exploring the design of topologies and
the syntax, including groupings, throughout this course.
So for now, let's simply submit the storm topology that we just built.
Step one is to view your files by typing ls.
And again, all of these directions are in the written directions, and
you see the pom.xml file.
We'll speak about the POM more in later lessons, but
it stands for the project object model.
Here's our source files and we see a new class file, target.
Again with tree, T-R-E-E, and
we see the compiled class including the jar and jar with dependencies.
In Storm we will be using the jar with dependencies.
Finally, to submit our first topology,
we use this class structure to run our first program.
Remember to use the Tab shortcut to help fill in the following command.
Also note the space between storm and
jar, and jar and target, and finally target and our ExclamationTopology.
And also remember there is no .java after our ExclamationTopology since
we're submitting the compiled class.
First type storm jar second target, and
again target with a tab we'll find this target directory.
Next, we want this jar file.
So we can type in udacity tab, and remember that we have two jar files,
we actually want.
We actually need the jar-with-dependencies, so
hit the hyphen, and the hyphen tab will get us the jar-with-dependencies.
Finally, we want udacity.storm, and
we're going to submit our ExclamationTopology.
Once again, that's udacity.storm.ExclamationTopology.
And remember there's no .class when we submit.
Hit enter and you'll be running your first storm program.
Storm runs for a while and then shuts down.
And we can scroll up to see some of the output.
We see that there's a word and exclaim1 and exclaim2.
And we see that there are names followed by exclamation points.
We'll explore this further.
But for now, great job on submitting your first Storm program.