So a lot of really exciting things
are happening in the world of web
development right now.
We have new API's,
new features coming down in
the browsers, that kind of thing.
What most excites you about
where things are headed?
>> Where things are headed right
now is one is web components.
I think it's really cool because when
I was learning like HTML 4, HTML 5.
I always had to like kind of
reinvent the wheel of like,
all these little components these models
and all these little moving features.
Wouldn't it be great if you could just,
in other programming languages,
like some sort of GUID framework,
in .net or
in our programming language
wouldn't it be great for
me to just take a component that's
been fleshed out already and
then I just add it on to my site and
make it my own then I can just really
concentrate on making
my own application and
not have to worry about all the mundane
things that I need to make.
Like, need to make sure that
the JavaScript is working fine.
Need to make sure that the backend's
like communicating fine.
But, that's one of
the most exciting things.
It really will empower me and
other feature developers, you know,
make things quicker, make things faster,
and also, just really.
At the end make the experience
a whole lot better for users.
>> Have you had an opportunity yet
to actually play with web components and
use them yourself because the browsers
are starting to get there, but
not quite.
Have you played with that at all?
>> Not so much right now, [CROSSTALK]
just excited about what's coming about
cause I was looking at Google IO,
like events, and I was thinking wow,
this is really cool.
And I need to play around with
palmer because that's Google's own
implementation in Chrome so.
Because I know right now if
I were to really do it for
a real project it's going to be hard.
>> Right.
Natively right because like I need
to make sure that safari will work,
firefox will work,
mobile tablet I need to make sure that
my web components that I'm using works.
There's a lot more headaches.
>> [CROSSTALK] It's not quite there yet.
>> [CROSSTALK] Not quite there yet, but
that's where I'm going
really excited for.
>> Cool.