Now that we have the order summary,
we need to send it off in an email so
that we can actually get our coffee.
This is what it would look like
when we hit the Order button.
It opens up an email app on the device
with a prepopulated message
containing the coffee order and
a custom subject line.
In order to accomplish this,
we need to understand a new
topic in Android called intent.
And intent is a message that requests
some type of action to be performed
by another app component,
such as an activity in another app.
This is a powerful part
of the Android framework.
Because our app can leverage
functionality that other apps provide
like sending an email,
opening the camera, reviewing a map.
It lets us be efficient and
smart as developers,
because we're not reinventing
what other apps already do well.
Think of sending intents like
tossing a ball to someone.
In the same way that a person can
toss a ball to another person,
an app component can send an intent
to another app component.
Here are some examples from
apps that you might recognize.
In the Google Keep note taking app,
a user can hit the camera
icon to take a photo.
While the Google Keep team could have
written their own camera functionality,
instead they get it for
free by sending an intent to open
up the camera app on the device.
Similarly, in the Yelp app,
clicking on the location of a business
sends an intent to open up a maps app
on the device to provide turn by turn
navigation instructions to the user.
And lastly, for a restaurant
page in the Google Maps app,
clicking on the Call button sends
an intent to launch the Dialer app so
that the user can make a phone
call to the restaurant.
The coolest part about sending intents
is that you don't have to know precisely
which app is capable of handling it.
There could be multiple apps on the
device that could handle the intent, but
ultimately only one needs to handle it.
Using our analogy, when you throw
the ball, you don't have to know
who you're throwing it at,
as long as someone catches it.
Let me show you what I mean.
For a restaurant listing
in the Google Maps apps,
clicking on Websites sends an intent
to display the restaurant website.
Now, the Maps app actually doesn't care
which web browser handles the request.
If the user only has one web
browser installed on their device,
then that app will automatically
handle the request.
However, if the user has four web
browsers installed on their device,
then the Android framework will pop up a
window to ask the user to just pick one.
This is what it looks like.
The pop-up window is known
as a disambiguation dialog.
Once the user makes a choice,
then the system sends the intent to
the selected app to handle the action.
And in this case the restaurant
website is displayed.
Now let's move on to talking about
what's contained inside this ball
that represent an intent.
You can think of an intent as a message
specifying some operation to be
performed.
It contains two primary things,
the general action and
some data to act upon.
You can also specify additional
information such as category, component,
and extras,
which is literally extra information.
All of these things are used
by Android to determine which
app component can actually
handle the intent.
For example a maps intent would
contain the action ACTION_VIEW,
and the data would be the latitude and
longitude coordinates of
the location that we want to see.
The rest of the fields can be blank.
Then, any app that's capable
of displaying latitude and
longitude coordinates can be
used to handle the request,
which is probably any maps application.
Another example is to use
an intent to dial a phone number.
In this case, you would compose an
intent where the action is ACTION_DIAL
and the corresponding data is
the telephone number to call.
Notice that the format is in the form
tel, colon, followed by the number.
This formatted string is called a URI,
short for uniform resource identifier.
This is a standardized
way to structure data so
that it can be properly
processed on the receiving end.
Think about it like a mailing address,
it follows a structure so
that it can be delivered properly.
In case of sending an intent,
a URI is needed so
that the data can be properly passed
to the receiving app component.
Depending on the data encoded in
the intent the scheme may change,
such as this case or
the geo case that we saw earlier.