If you start to add too many
things to the order form,
then the content can get
cut off at the bottom.
Like this could get
pushed off the screen and
then you wouldn't be able to see it.
A vertical linear layout
doesn't scroll if it extends
beyond the edge of the screen.
You need to add something specific
in your app to make it vertically
scrollable.
This is a silly example, but I basically
copied the views that we have in our
layout and
then pasted it right after each other.
And you can see that even
though there's more content
beyond the edge of this screen,
it still doesn't scroll.
This is especially a common problem
when you switch your phone to landscape
mode and the screen is shorter
compared to in portrait mode.
That's where it'd be really
convenient if this could scroll.
And now I'll leave it to you
to figure out how to do this.
When you're done,
you can describe how you did it here.
You can write it with your feather
quill, or just use your keyboard.