So what I'm arguing for, is basically that computation photography is
extending any kind of traditional photography, either it be film or
digital, and basically, has better specification.
Control and
support for some of the aspects of photography that we've known for a while.
For example, dynamic range is excellent on film or traditional cameras, but
now, even with the small handheld cameras, by changing the process on
how the sensor and the optics could be changed using a control manner.
We can actually generate dynamic range images on our cellphone cameras.
Which don't have all of the fancy optics and
controls a traditional camera like this would one, this one would have.
Traditional cameras allowed you to do a lot of focus point by
point kinds of things.
But now we can control them,
again, with computation in a much smaller packaging and again to
a lot different types of things directly on board with a non-board computer.
We can play around with, you know, field of view and resolution.
Again with a traditional camera or
digital camera, you are stuck with it from day one.
But, this could be changed approximately and
directly on the camera with variety of controls.
Of course similar things like exposure time and
frame rate can also be controlled.
And these types of control right now are available on most cell
phone cameras with camera software associated both on the Androids and IOS.
Again, people are using these abilities apps.
Another thing that's coming up is burst photography.
Now of course traditional cameras could actually capture a lot of
images at one time by just keeping the shutter button down.
This kind of stuff is not showing up in your standard cell phone cameras, and
burst photography, and auto gifs are becoming really popular.