Of course, these days this whole concept
of video textures is coming back and
it's now coming back as
referred to as cinemagrams.
So here I just show two examples.
This is using the Microsoft
Research Cliplets software.
And of course here you notice,
it's a static scene except there is only
one thing moving, and that's the train.
All the people are still.
This gives a very nice rendition
of kind of showing motion and
emphasizing only one bit of motion.
You might want to try out the Microsoft
Research Cliplets software, interested
in developing these types of things have
provided a nice toolkit for doing this.
There is of course a whole lot of
additional stuff also coming up, for
example.
There's another example, where basically
if you notice the whole scene is static.
The only thing that's moving is
the water from the, from the tap here.
Again, showing you the emphasis of
just one specific dynamic motion and
keeping the rest stable.
We'll talk a little about these kind of
things also in one of my other lectures.
We're going to talk about video
stabilization, but again,
there are lots of techniques out there
and you can play around with this.