Now the first plan might fail.
If we go from S to A and attempt to go from A to G, a flood might be in the way,
and the flood will never go away. Therefore this is the correct answer over here.
The second succeeds.
We go from S to B, and if the traffic light is red, we wait until it finally turns green.
Then we go from B to G.
However, we can't say in advance in how many steps the traffic light turns green.
Therefore, the solution will be unbounded. It can't really be bounded it in advance.
The third one also may fail under the same condition as the first.
We go from S to A. If there is a flood, we just try again.
Finally, if the flood goes away, we go from A to G.
However, a flood never goes away. Therefore if there is a flood we will actually fail here.
The fourth one always succeeds in a bounded number of steps.
We go from S to A. If there is a flood we go from A to D and then to G.
Otherwise we go from A to G.
As you can see, the number of steps might be either 3 or 2,
but I can bound it by 3.
There won't be more than 3 steps in total.
The same is true for this plan over here.
We go to B. If we find a stoplight, we go back to S, then to A, to D, and then to G.
However, if the stoplight is green, we go straight to G,
and you can see that this is going to succeed.
The final plan--[SA, AD, DG]--avoids all the floods and the stoplight
and will therefore always succeed in 3 steps, which is bounded.