As I already hinted, memory management
isn't currently done by the operating
system alone, in order to make these
tasks efficient, over the last
decades the hardware has evolved to
integrate a number of mechanisms
that make it easier, faster, or
more reliable to perform allocation and
arbitration tasks regarding
the memory management.
First every CPU package is equipped
with a memory management unit.
This CPU is used virtual address
as to the memory management unit.
And it's responsible for
translating them into
the appropriate physical address.
Or potentially the MMU
can generate a fault.
The faults are an exception or
signal that's generated by the MMU that
can indicate one of several things.
For instance,
it can say that the access is illegal.
Like, for instance,
that the memory address that's
requested hasn't been allocated at all.
Or it can indicate that they're
inadequate permissions to perform
a particular access.
For instance, the memory reference
may be part of a store instruction,
so the process is trying to override
a particular memory allocation.
However, it doesn't have a write
permission for that particular access.
That page is what we
call write protected.
Or another type of fault may be
an indication that the particular
page that's being referenced,
isn't present in memory, and
must be fetched from disk.
Another way hardware supports memory
management is by using designated
registers during the address
translation process.
For instance in a page based system,
there are registers that are used to
point to the currently active
page table, or in a segment based
memory management the registers that
are used to indicate the base address of
the segment potentially it's limit,
so its overall size of the segment,
maybe the total number of segments and
similar information.
Since the memory address translation
happens on pretty much every memory
reference, most memory
management units would integrate
a small cache of valid virtual to
physical address translations.
This is called
the Translation Lookaside Buffer or TLB.
The presence of a TLB will make the
entire translation process much faster.
Since, if this translation is
present in this cache then,
there's no need to perform
any additional operations to
access the page table or the segment and
to interpret the validity of the access.
And finally,
the actual generation of the physical
address from the virtual address.
So the translation process,
that's done by the hardware.
The operating system will
maintain certain data structures,
such as the page tables, to maintain
certain information that's necessary for
the translation process.
However, the actual translation,
the hardware performs it.
This also implies that the hardware
will dictate what type of
memory management modes are supported.
Can you support paging?
Can you support segmentation, or both?
So basically, are there any
kinds of registers of this sort?
It will also potentially imply
what kinds of pages can there be?
What is the virtual address format,
as well as the physical address format?
Since the hardware needs to
understand both of these.
There are other aspects of memory
management that are more flexible in
terms of their design since
they're performed in software.
For instance, the actual allocation.
Basically determining which portions of
the main memory will be used by which
process.
That's done by software or
the replacement policies that determine
which portions of state will be
in main memory versus on disk.
So we will focus our discussion on those
software aspects of memory management,
since that's more relevant from
an operating systems course perspective.