Here's our first simple app,
which we're calling Click Counter.
It has one button and one label.
When you tap the button, the label
shows an integer value that increments.
This app is extremely simple.
In fact, you might think you
could build it in your sleep.
But we want you to get in to the habit
of diagraming all the objects used to
create an app.
Let's give this a try for
each of the objects in Click Counter.
We can draw each of the objects
we're interested in as a rectangle.
And we'll represent object
properties with circles like this.
All ViewControllers
inherit a view property.
This points to the root view of a page.
In this case, the view that
paints the white background.
Our diagram needs two more view objects,
a button to click and
a label to show the click count.
We will draw objects that
paint the view in blue.
These view objects contain
the complex code required to get
all the pixels painted
in the right colors.
These are UIKit objects
that we use off the shelf
as they've been written by Apple.
Do we need a model object?
In this case, our app only
needs to remember one number so
that it can increment.
Let's make an int property
in our ViewController.
We'll call it count.
This is the basic
architecture of our app.
We've got our model that stores the
click count, our view objects that paint
the screen ,and our ViewController
that ties everything together.
These objects get created and connected
right before this page is displayed.
Now let's say the user clicks
the button after the page is displayed.
Those button tabs turn into events, so
we'll indicate that in
our diagram as well.
So what else will these objects
need in order for the app to work?
Let's think through the sequence of
events that happens as the user taps
the screen.
The user taps a button on the screen and
that button interprets that
tap as an event, invoking
an action in the ViewController.
Now we're in our control code,
our custom code.
Here the Viewcvontroller
updates the model.
After updating the model,
the ViewController needs to also
update the text of this label.
But right now, the ViewController
doesn't have a way to access that text.
In order to accomplish this last step,
we need to add a label property
to the ViewController.
All right.
Now that we got a plan,
let's go recreate these objects
in the viewcontroller.swift file