Most things are not, that are shiny are not perfect mirrors, but
we can think of them as being glossy.
Okay and what the glossy means is, if we have our illuminate here and
we're coming out some angle.
It means I don't have light just at the mirror point, but
it's spread out a little bit.
Okay. And that's what this lobe here, is meant to show.
Okay, and the more gloss as opposed to being specular.
Right? Blurrier, I make that lobe a little bit fatter.
Okay.
And that's written as this equation which
says that basically now instead of doing that delta function.
I just take co sign, of the angle between them.
All right, and dot V, raise to some exponent.
Okay?
Cause that's the angle between them and I raise some exponent.
Now, if the angle between them is zero, that means it's a perfect mirror angle.
Right, then dot product is one.
Raised to K it stays one and I get a perfect reflection.
But, as the.
The angle falls off a little bit, co sign becomes a little bit less than one,
and when I raise a less than one to the K,
well as K gets bigger, that falls off faster.
Okay.
And, in fact, you can see that illustrated here these are some
artificially generated images, so here it's just, you know,
moving a light source to different directions.
Okay, not so exciting.
Here, you can see that the specular component is getting tight and tighter and
tighter, all right?
And so it's getting more like a mirror, that's the raising of that K, okay?
And so that's, the specular component.