Let's explain the problem with some of
these problematic instructions a little
more via quiz.
So we said that in the earlier
x86 architectures, the CPU flags
privileged register was accessed
via instructions POPF and PUSHF.
And these instructions failed
silently if they're not accessed
from the most privileged ring,
ring zero.
This is where the hypervisor
would reside.
What do you think can occur as
a result of this situation?
The options are, the guest VM could
not request interrupts to be enabled,
the guest VM could not request
interrupts to be disabled,
the guest VM could not find out
what is the state of the interrupts
enabled/disabled bit,
or all of the above.