Here's the solution.
At this point, I hope the steps for
each task are becoming more familiar.
I'll start again with the parameters,
which for
this request are the API key and
the request token.
Then to build the URL, we'll use
the /authentication/session/new method.
Next I repeat the steps that we've
been taking to create the task here,
then we have this displayError function
and then we check for error cases, so
one, two, three different
error cases here, these guys.
And here we convert the JSON
data into a useable dictionary.
And then, we grab our session ID,
so we look in the results and
we look for
the value of the session ID key.
We store the session ID in the app
delegate and then we print it out.
And don't forget we need to start
the task using task dot resume.
Now let's go ahead and run this.
I'll enter my credentials again.
And there we go, and there's the value
we've been looking for all along,
a session ID.