Since all of these changes
depend on UI router,
I installed that first and added as
a dependency to the apps module.
I set up the configuration for the
module and injected state provider and
URL router provider.
Next I added a home state and
made sure that any unknown states
redirected to the root floating bricks
slash red is supposed to show us all
the red bricks so I set up a state for
that, this loads the bricks template and
uses the red bricks controller.
I did the same thing for
the blue and green bricks.
Notice that i use the same template for
each, but
each one has a different controller.
I was able to do this because I set
the variable name for each one to brick.
And finally i added the current state.
With all the states that have added
navigation links to the index file.
The links use the UIS ref directive and
point to the appropriate state name.
Each item now has its own page.
But i still need to add the cart to
each item page as a nested view.
Remember that a nested view uses
the name of the parent a dot and
then its name, so I used redBrick.cart.
Since this is displaying the same
information as the cart page.
I gave it the same template and
controller.
Then I created nested card pages for
both the blue brick and
the green brick pages.
For the cart to display on the item
page, I used ui-view again.
And then I added a link to
navigate to the nested state.
Since all brick items share this view,
I couldn't make this red brick.cart.
Because that would load the nested
cart view only on the Red Bricks page.
So I left the main state
dynamic by not providing it.
So this will load redBrick.cart
on the Red Brick page,
blueBrick.cart on the Blue Brick page.
And greenBrick.cart on
the Green Brick page and we're done.
For a bonus though there's a lot
of duplication going on between
the red brick, blue brick and
green brick states.
Instead I created one brick state
that determines the controller to
use by the URL.
Since we only have one brick state now,
I can clean up all the nested
card states down to just one.
Since there are no longer
individual states for the items.
I needed to update the links to
pass along the data in the URL.
This is a much more organized
state management structure.