So I promised that we would
do stochastic bandit arms,
deterministic MDPs, and
then ultimately combine ideas together
and handle general stochastic MDPs.
So I think we can do
efficient exploration of deterministic
MDPs relatively simply actually.
Here's a little randomly generated MDP.
Randomly generated in that I
drew a bunch of arrows and
I have absolutely no idea
what the solution to this is.
But if we were doing reinforcement
learning in this MDP,
all we would know at any moment in
time is which state we were in.
And which action we were choosing.
And so, an action, in this case,
would just have a label,
like action one and action two.
I made two actions for
each of these states.
We know how to solve a deterministic MDP
to figure out the optimal policy for it.
But we can't solve it in the beginning,
because we don't actually
know any of this stuff.
Right, all these numbers.
Where do the arrows go and
what reward do we get on an arrow?
We don't know any of
that at the beginning.
>> Right.
So, two observations.
One, you don't have two
actions at every state.
>> Oh, what do you mean?
>> Well, the one that has
the three coming out of it,
there's only one action that comes out.
You don't have a self action.
>> This one?
>> Yes.
>> Dope.
All right, there's just two things,
then they both can have a plus three.
But, you're right.
I thought I got them all, but
I missed that one.
>> It doesn't really matter.
So, that's one observation.
One observation is one does
not always equal to two.
The second observation.
Is that if we know it's deterministic,
then all we have to do is,
in every state, try every action once.
>> Yeah, that's true.
>> And then we know everything we know
about which action is best or whatever,
magic.
Something like that.
Shouldn't that work?
>> [LAUGH]
Okay,
well you're kind of onto something.
It's certainly the case that once
we've tried each action in each state
then we can actually build
the entire MDP and solve it.
>> Right.
>> The question is what do we do
along the way?
What do we do when we don't
have the whole MDP yet?
Maybe it's not entirely clear.
I mean if we could just teleport
ourselves to any state that we wanted to
be in and take the action at that state,
then that would be fine.
But that's not how the world
is in reinforcement learning.
Right?
All we can do is choose actions.
We can't choose which state to be in.
>> Well, we could track every
state that we've ever been in and
every action ever taken.
>> That's true.
>> And then just do things
that seem reasonable.
Explore a little bit randomly so that
we make certain we get to every state.
And get a chance to take every
action and then kind of go.
>> All right.
So you're thinking explore randomly so
that we hit everything.
That could work, but we can make
MDPs where that's problematic
because if we choose actions randomly we
keep, for example, getting reset to some
beginning state and
actually not choosing things randomly so
that we visit all of
the states can be challenging.
>> So, that's true, Michael,
but if we don't know anything about the
MDP then I can always construct an MDP
that's going to mess with whatever
exploration strategy you have, right.
Because I'll just always there will
be some state with some action that
puts you into some state
you can never get out of.
So, unless you can do random restarts or
be able to get to some state.
Press a button and do a reboot.
You could always get unlucky and
never be able to explore the MDP.
>> Okay, all right.
Well, that is a fair point.
We have to be very careful about
what we think our criterion is.
Now, we went through it pretty
carefully in the case of bandits, but
I kind of jumped to deterministic MDPs
without revisiting this question.
So I'm going to propose
a particular optimization criteria,
and then we'll talk about why
it needs to be like that.
>> Okay, that seems fair.