[Thrun] Here is the application of HMM to a real robot localization example.
This robot is in a world that's 1-dimensional and it is lost.
It has initial uncertainty about where it is,
and it is actually located next to a door but it doesn't know.
It's also given a map of the world,
and the distribution of all possible states, here noted as s, is given by this histogram.
We bin the world into small bins, and for each bin we assign a single numerical probability
of the robot being there.
The fact they have all the same height means that the robot is maximally uncertain
as to where it is.
Let's assume this robot is going to sense
and it senses to be next to a door.
The red graph over here is the probability of seeing a door
for different locations in the environment.
There are 3 different doors, and seeing a door is more likely here
than it is in between.
It might still see a door here, but it's just less likely.
We now apply Bayes rule.
We multiply the prior with this measurement probability to obtain the posterior.
That was our measurement update. It's that simple.
So you can see how all these uniform values over here become nonuniform values over here
multiplied by this curve over here.
The story progresses by the robot taking an action to the right,
and this is now the next state prediction part, the what we call convolution part
or state transition part, where these little bumps over here get shifted along with the robot
and they are flattened out a little bit just because robot motion has used uncertainty.
Again, it's a really simple operation.
You shift those to the right and you smooth them out a little bit
to account for the control noise in the robot's actuators.
And now we get to the point that the robot senses again,
and this robot senses a door again.
And see what happens. It multiplies.
It's now a nonuniform prior over here with the same measurement probability as before,
but now we get a distribution that's peaked over here
and has smaller bumps at various other places,
the reason being the only place where my prior has a higher probability
and my measurement probability is also high probability is the second door,
and as a result of our distribution over here, it assumes a much larger value.
If you look at that picture, that is really easy to implement,
and that's what we did all along when we talked about rain and sun and so on.
It's really a very simple algorithm.
Measurements are multiplications, and motion become essentially convolutions
which are shifts with added noise.