So overall I believe, the field of Computational Photography is exciting and
emerging area.
Which requires a lot of research and development and study.
Now, questions that at least, I would like us to think about in the future.
But not during the class perhaps, is what will a camera look like in 10 years or
20 years from now?
What other types of novel images can we capture?
And what would their uses be?
How will the next billion cameras change the social culture?
Again, I show the example of images in news.
How availability of the beast with billion eyes is changing our way to
kind of see things.
Much more globally.
And actually this is playing a real important role in the social context.
Well, this is going to become even more important.
One of the bigger questions remains is, of course with, so many images and
videos being captured and not put on the network or in a database of some sort.
The image search problem is going to be get even bigger.
So question is, how can we actually think about changing computational
photography pipeline to help with image search?
An example of this, of course, is the use of metadata like Geotagging.
That is becoming widely used, to search or at least classifying cluster images.
Another question comes up, is how will the high-speed chain cameras or
high-resolution cameras change how we use them?
Again we should be able to see more, more details, more clarity and
other types of things.
That'll lead us to understand more about, how we visualize things.
More and more these days has been a growth of robotic cameras, or
autonomous cameras.
These are going to also have an impact,
on how we perce, how we capture the environment?
And how we use that kind of content for a variety of things?
>> [LAUGH] >> Again more and more with, built-on this concept.
Also there's going to be more and
more abilities to pervasively capture our environment.
Also capture them from our first person perspective and capture our experiences.
Many science fiction stories have written about these types of things.
And now actually, you may want to think about them more because as
technology gets better, we are getting closer to those things.
And more importantly, again, the availability of these types of cameras is
changing how we both have user-generated content showing up on the internet.
And also how is changing how for the videography and
photography is done at the professional level.
And also impacting the things like, reporting news.