Here is the illustration
of a computer system we
used in our introductory
lesson in operating systems.
As you can see,
the execution of applications
doesn't rely only on the CPU and
memory, but relies on many other
different types of hardware components.
Some of these components are
specifically tied to providing inputs or
directing outputs.
And these are referred
to as I/O devices.
Examples include keyboards and
microphones, displays,
speakers, mice,
also network interface hard disk.
So there are a number of different
types of input/output devices that
operating systems integrate into
the overall computing system.