Within sunshine if you tap on
a list in the main activity,
it opens up the detail activity.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
But the main activity
remains on the back stack.
Ready to reappear as
soon as you hit back.
Now in that example both activities
are within the same app.
But as we learned in lesson three,
you can also launch the browser or
maps app from sunshine.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Or for
that matter the user can hit Home.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Or launch apps from there or
they can use the recent key or
switch to another app
using notifications.
All these options mean you can end up
with a lot of apps on your back stack.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now keep in mind that our resources
on devices are extremely limited.
So it's not a good idea to have dozens
of apps sitting idle in the background.
Android solves this for us, so
you don't have to use those
awful task killer apps.
So how does it do that?
Well it kills low priority applications
that you haven't used in a while.
We'll go into detail on exactly how
it figures out which app needs to die
in lesson six.
But for
now it's important to realize that your
app isn't in control of its own destiny.
It can be killed at any time.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So you need to know
how to deal with that.
And that means understanding the life
cycle of an activity and the signals we
get from the framework to indicate
it's progress through the lifetime.