Summary slides, I love summary slides.
For 2-views and we learned at the beginning, there's a geometric relationship
that defines the relation between rays in one view and rays in the other view.
And we were referring to that about the epipolar geometry.
These relations can be captured algebraically besides geometrically.
For the calibrated camera case that was referred to as the essential matrix.
For the uncalibrated camera case, it's the fundamental matrix.
And the math that we've been going through has been talking about how you can
find these matrices.
How you can find these relations by just giving me
the correspondences between points from one image to the next.
All right.
This ends the lesson on fundamental matrices.
In fact, it ends the entire unit on calibration in stereo.
I hope you realize that from these relationships,
you can capture the geometry of the scene.
That is given some camera views,
you can eventually figure out the three-dimensional locations of the points.
So this is not image processing, right?
This is actually vision where we recover a 3D structure.
And if you're taking the OMS version of this, of this class and
you're doing the OMS problem sets, you're going to get to know and love these.
Well, you're going to get to know.
I hope you'll love these processes pretty well.
That's it for this unit.