With just basic support from
an interconnect like PCI and
the corresponding PCI controllers on
the device, a system can access or
request an operation from a device
using a method called programmed I/O.
This method requires no
additional hardware support.
It involves the CPU issuing
constructions by writing into
the command registers of the device and
also controlling
the data movement by accessing
the data registers of the device.
So either the data will be written to
these data registers or read from them.
For instance, let's look at
a network interface card or
a NIC as a simple device that's
accessed via programmed I/O or PIO.
Here in the NIC case,
when a process that's running from the
CPU wants to transmit some data that has
been formatted into an network packet,
the following steps need to take place.
First, the CPU needs to write to
a command register on the device.
And this command needs to instruct
the device that it needs to
perform a transmission of the data
that the CPU will provide.
The CPU also needs to copy this
packet into the data registers and
then the whole thing will be repeated
as many times as it's necessary for
the entire packets to be sent out.
Given that the size of this register
space that's available on the device
may be smaller than the network packet.
For instance if they have a 1500-byte
packet and the device data registers or
the bus that connects the device
with the PCU are 8 bytes long,
then the whole operation of performing
programmed I/O will require
one CPU access to the device
registers to write out the command,
and then another 188 accesses, so
1500 divided by 8, approximately 188.
In total, there will be 189 CPU accesses
to the device-specific registers.
And, we said that these look
like CPU store instruction.
This gives us some idea about the costs
associated with programmed I/O.
Let's now look at the alternative.