Welcome to the machine learning unit.
Machine learning is a fascinating area.
The world has become immeasurably data-rich.
The world wide web has come up over the last decade.
The human genome is being sequenced.
Vast chemical databases, pharmaceutical databases,
and financial databases are now available
on a scale unthinkable even 5 years ago.
To make sense out of the data,
to extract information from the data,
machine learning is the discipline to go.
Machine learning is an important subfeed of artificial intelligence,
it's my personal favorite next to robotics
because I believe it has a huge impact on society
and is absolutely necessary as we move forward.
So in this class, I teach you some of the very basics of
machine learning, and in our next unit
Peter will tell you some more about machine learning.
We'll talk about supervised learning, which is one side of machine learning,
and Peter will tell you about unsupervised learning,
which is a different style.
Later in this class we will also encounter reinforcement learning,
which is yet another set of machine learning.
Anyhow, let's just dive in.