This was a complex but, in my opinion, authentic exercise using open
source bolts to implement some pretty cool functionality.
I hope the process was useful, and I walk through my solution.
I broke my approach up into 3 major stages, imports or
Part 1 of the written instructions.
Linking to Topology, which is also Part 1 of the routine instructions, and
incorporates a lot of the syntax hints.
And finally, filtering and emitting.
Which is Part 2 through 5.
You can skip ahead to solution sections that you had difficulties with.
And let's begin with imports for my approach.
In part zero of the written instructions we simply add our credentials to
the TweeTopology, and rename to TopNTweeTopology.
So we navigate to lesson three stage four.
Rename TweetTopology to TopNTweetTopology and
remember to change your class name to TopNTweetTopology.
In Part 1, we remove the rolling count bolt and use the count bolt.
And in code we can simply comment out our rolling count,
un-comment our count-bolt and
remember to update the connection to count-bolt instead of rolling count-bolt.
And once your visualization's working, you can move on to importing and
connecting the total ranking's bolt to the required dependencies.
Once we're at this stage,
we simply navigate to the total rankings bolt using the link.
And this will begin the process of a fairly tedious cycle to.
copy>create>update import statements,
build using Maven, which leads to more copying, creating, updating and building.
So, let's get started.
We first copy the TotalRankingsBolt.
We navigate to the storm folder, not the tools and
create our file name TotalRankingsBolt.java.
We then look at the package structure and update.
And our package structure again is udacity.storm, because udacity and storm.
We see that there's another dependency from storm, starter,
tools rankings, and we update the import statement and plan to.
Copy Rankings into Tools.
We navigate to storm starter tools, and find Rankings.
We copy and past the Rankings.java file, create them in our Tools folder,
paste and remember to update again.
Now at this point without looking too deeply at the code,
we might be ready to build.
I'll just walk through this to show the types of errors that come up,
and how you can use these errors to then repeat this entire cycle.
We first Maven package.
And we see a build failure.
And build failure is that Rankable is not in our dependencies.
And if we search for
Rankable in our Rankings file, we see that we're creating a list of Rankables.
Therefore Rankable should be in our dependencies.
And we'll go through the process again of copy > create > update,
using these build failures.
We find rankable, copy > create > update, and finally try to build again.
And now when we see the BUILD FAILURE,
we see that there's an abstract ranker bolt that we're also missing.
Navigating to the total rankings bolt.
We see that TotalRankings extends an AbstractRankerBolt.
We could have discovered this dependency if we walk through the code more in
detail, which you could have done, but this approach is simply using the Maven
life cycle, and build-cycle, in order to discover our dependencies.
We navigate to storm > starter > bolt.
And we find the AbstractRankerBolt.
Again we copy > create in storm folder not tools.
And paste the AbstractRankerBolt, in the AbstractRankerBolt file.
We then update our package, and again check our dependencies and
see that we have Rankings and TupletteHelpers.
Which we already have as ranking and TupletteHelpers.
But remember to update this import statement as well.
And notice that I put TupletteHelpers not in util but in tools.
An after our Maven package, we finally get our BUILD SUCCESS.
So, great job importing.
Next, let's check our connections, and
notice that we haven't yet connected any of our components to our topology.
Since our aim is to connect the TotalRankingsBolt to our topology,
let's navigate there now.
And if you've seen in hint two, or
simply read the documentation, or the comments really.
We see the intermediate rankings is necessary, and
we configure this bolt with a GlobalGrouping.
Therefor, we'll need to import intermediate rankings.
We navigate to Storm Starter Bolt, and see intermediate rankings.
We copy, create again in Storm, and
not Storm tools, create IntermediateRankingsBolt.java.
Update our package, and again look at our input statements.
We see that we have Rankable.
But we don't have RankableObjectWithFields.
So let's first update our import statement, and once updated, let's go and
get RankableObjectWithFields.
This is in Stormstarter tools.
And Rankableobjects with fields.
We complete our cycle again by copy, creating, and
updating with RankableObjects with field.java.
Paste, and finally update the package structure.
And notice that we don't have any further dependencies.
Finally let's build, and hope this works.
Great, and now that we have a BUILD SUCCESS.
We should be done with imports, and we can move on to Linking to Topology.