For our first question, our Sunshine
database had two tables which you could
see from the fact that they were two
innerclasses with the name Blank Entry.
Now here's what we find it in the code.
So as a sidenote, this is the same code
that we saw from the GitHub link below.
I've just removed the comments so
that we can more easily see
everything on one slide, so
here are the two entry classes.
So, LocationEntry and
further down we see WeatherEntry.
So, for our second question,
the table that is represented
by the WeatherEntry class, the name
of that table is simply weather.
In this case, the weather contract
has two tables, a table for
weather data and
a table for location data.
So, the weather data table contents
were stored in our WeatherEntry class.
In the code here,
here's our WeatherEntry inner class, and
inside it, we have a constant name,
table name,
and that constant is associated with
the name of the table which is weather.
So for the third question of how many
columns does the weather table have,
not including the ID and count columns.
Well, that table would
have ten columns and
then for our last question
What's the constant name for
the column that's a short description
of the weather condition?
Well, we'll see in the code
the name of the constant is
COLUMN_SHORT_DESC, and
here's those two answers in the code.
So inside her, weather entry class
we have the name of our ten columns.
And to find the name of
the short description constant,
well we could see it from here.