Depending on what address you chose,
you might see some different results.
But for www.udacity.com, or Google,
or a bunch of other sites,
it's going to to be the first option.
What's happening is that NC
tells the operating system,
connect to that address.
And the OS is trying,
trying very hard, but
it can't get through because
that port's not open.
All that traffic is
just getting dropped.
But as it's trying to get through,
it sends these packets slower and
slower until finally it gives up.
The reason for the slowing down is
because one of the common causes of
packet loss is congestion.
And the one thing you don't want to do
in case of congestion is send faster.
So the answer we observed
here is number one.