The question about the MVC,
that's to understand how
solid is his knowledge.
I don't expect him to know a lot, but
whatever he knows must be crystal clear.
So the MVC is the base
of any iOS application,
or even OSN and many other applications.
So, I want to be absolutely sure that
he knows where to put those three
types of bricks before letting him
build a house and maybe crumble down.
It looks like he has
a pretty good understanding
of what are the responsibilities of
the model, the controller, and the view.
I was expecting something
of a broad overview.
He got into more details.
That's not a problem at all, as long
as you don't get lost in the details,
and you show that you
understand the big picture.
That's good for me.