So I got three evictions.
Since the cache is empty,
the first five instructions,
which contain four unique addresses,
yield the following state.
Notice that the fifth instruction
is actually a cache hit.
So what about the next instruction,
which accesses a new address, hex AB8D?
LRU evicts the least
recently used address.
So for this program,
that would be hex BEEF.
In other words of the cached addresses,
it was the first one to be loaded,
and hasn't been touched since.
So out with the beef.
And if watching from Texas or
Argentina, lo siento.
And so, in with AB8D,
which I'd been waiting with bated, but
not abated, breath.
Now notice what happens.
All but one of the remaining
instructions is a cache miss.
It seems that the least recently used
heuristic evicted exactly the addresses
we would have preferred to have kept.
The result is three evictions,
compared to just one from
the optimal replacement policy.
Of course, this is just one example.
A natural and interesting question to
ask at this point is, what can you say
in general about the gap between,
say, LRU and optimal replacement?