You saw a lot of examples of
data types in lesson one.
It may come as no surprise that data
types are kind of complicated in SQL.
Types in SQL often have different names
from types in Python or other languages.
And sometimes,
there are distinctions made in SQL
that other languages don't make.
We'll be working with only a few of
these types in this course though.
For a whole bunch more types and
links to some documentation with
even more types, see the next page.
SQL has several different string types.
In this course,
we'll just use the text type, which is
basically the same as a Python string.
Same goes for numbers.
SQL has number types for
many different purposes.
But in this course,
we'll mainly be using the integer type,
which is roughly the same
as Python's int.
And how about our animals' birth dates?
SQL has date and time types as well.
We'll be using date columns for
birth dates since we don't
care about the time of day.
One thing that's really important
to keep in mind about date and
time values in SQL is that you have
to put single quotes around them
as if they were strings.
If you write 2012-11-23
inside single quotes,
SQL can interpret that as a date or
as a piece of text.
But if you write 2012-11-23
with no quotes around it,
it can only interpret it
as an integer expression.
It will think you mean
2,012 minus 11 minus 23,
which equals 1,978,
which is probably not what you wanted.