[Thrun] It's really interesting to compare this to the situation over here.
In both cases I'm happy, as shown over here,
and I ask the same question, which is whether I got a raise at work, as R over here.
But in one case I observe that the weather is sunny; in the other one it isn't.
And look what it does to my probability of having received a raise.
The sunniness perfectly well explains my happiness,
and my probability of having received a raise ends up to be a mere 1.4%, or 0.014.
However, if my wife observes it to be non-sunny, then it is much more likely
that the cause of my happiness is related to a raise at work,
and now the probability is 8.3%, which is significantly higher than the 1.4% before.
This is a Bayes network of which S and R are independent
but H adds a dependence between S and R.
Let me talk about this in a little bit more detail on the next paper.
So here is our Bayes network again.
In our previous exercises, we computed for this network
that the probability of a raise of R given any of these variables shown here was as follows.
The really interesting thing is that in the absence of information about H,
which is the middle case over here,
the probability of R is unaffected by knowledge of S--
that is, R and S are independent.
This is the same as probability of R,
and R and S are independent.
However, if I know something about the variable H,
then S and R become dependent--
that is, knowing about my happiness over here renders S and R dependent.
This is not the same as probability of just R given H.
Obviously, it isn't because if I now vary S from S to not S,
it affects my probability for the variable R.
That is a really unusual situation
where we have R and S are independent
but given the variable H, R and S are not independent anymore.
So knowledge of H makes 2 variables that previously were independent non-independent.
Offered differently, 2 variables that are independent may not be in certain cases
conditionally independent.
Independence does not imply conditional independence.