Here are the changes that we made
to the makeHttpRequest method
in the Tsunami app.
If the response code is not 200,
then we log the error response
code using the log.e method call.
Should this happen, we'll see the error
logged in logcat with the log tag
main activity, followed by
the message Error response code: and
then the numeric response code.
We also do similar in
the doInBackground method,
which may throw an I/O exception when
trying to close the InputStream.
We can verify that this log message
statement will be created by
intentionally creating
a bad request URL.
Notice these miscellaneous
characters here.
When we run the app,
we'll get an error when we try
to connect to the invalid URL.
As you can see here,
we see a red error message appear in
the logs with the response code 400.
Okay, great,
we verified that the log message gets
called when the request is unsuccessful.
The second task was to log the error
when we catch an I/O exception.
We can verify that this code path gets
executed by putting our phone into
airplane mode.
That will definitely cause an exception
when we try to connect to the Internet
to get results.
When we run the app,
no earthquake information shows up.
However in the logs,
now we see our error message stating,
problem retrieving
the earthquake JSON results.
So we know that an I/O exception
was thrown and caught.
Great work with logging errors.
It's a good practice to
follow as a developer.
If you want to reference the final
state of the Tsunami app code,
see the GitHub link below.