Good job completing lesson two stage two.
Now, we're going to modify the distributed sentence count topology that you
just created, by creating a new sentence word count topology.
What we're going to do is count the words in the sentences,
that you're now inventing.
In part one, navigate to lesson two stage three.
And duplicate the sentence count topology, and
call it the sentence word count topology.
Following the Java convention, you'll need to update the required class and
constructor names again to match the file name.
In part two,
implement a new bolt SplitSentenceBolt that extends the base ritual.
Your SplitSentenceBolt takes in a tupal,
with a sentence at position zero, extracts the sentence.
And splits the sentence into words, and emits the words in tuple.
My suggestion is to copy and
paste a similar bolt such as the count bolt, update the class name, and
implement the prepare, execute, and declare output field method.
To clear the new field, sentence dash word.
I also list a few helpful Syntax hints in the written instructions.
In part three, scroll down again to your topology builder, and
update the topology to make a random sentence.
Split the sentence using your new Split Sentence Bolt and
send the output to with the Count Bolt.
One implementation question to consider.
What stream method should you use,
to connect a sentence to the split sentence bolt?
Do sentences need to be sorted by field in order to be split?
Finally, in part four build, and run your new topology.
Once that's running correctly notice that the report bolt is already
connect to the count.
Again personalize your random sentences, take a screenshot, or
screencast in video, and upload it to the forum.
And comment onto other posts.
Finally, your sentence,
word count topology should now match less than two stage four.
When you're on your final storm solution, you'll see that the random
sentences are going to be split, and the words are going to be counted.
So now, the words instead of the sentences are going to show up in
our visualization.
As the topology is running, you see that word seven grows,
because my sentences have two sentences with the word seven, four score and
seven years ago and Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs.
And good luck with the assignment!