So did you fall into the trap?
Let's look at the distribution
again without the clutter.
If you were to approximate this with
an ellipse, what would it look like?
Well, something like that.
Which is the major axis here?
That's right, horizontal.
And that would be the first
principle component.
As odd as it may look,
the second principle component would
be orthogonal or perpendicular to this.
So, this is one and this is two.
Intuitively, this doesn't look right,
does it?
But it's exactly what
you told PCA to find.
The axis with the most variance
would be the first competent and
the one orthogonal to
it would be the second.
PCA is good for characterizing
a single class of instances.
It can reduce the effective number
of dimensions need significantly.
But, what if your data came
from two classes or sources?
If you wanted to characterize two or
more classes at the same time
PCA might not be a good choice.
This is especially true if
the axis of most variants for
the source distributions
are not perpendicular.
There are some other approaches for
characterizing multiple non-octagonal
classes such as ICA or
independent component analysis.
One big difference here is that ICA
does not require the components or
basis vectors to be orthogonal.
Anyways, this is probably going off
track from the current discussion.
Let's focus back on PCA and
see how we can apply it to images.