I would argue that the global grouping is needed here because we
want the entire stream to be sent to a single bolt, the ReportBolt.
Because we have a parallelism of one for
the ReportBolt, technically a shuffle grouping would also work.
All streams are shuffled to one ReportBolt, but
this adds computational overhead for one bolt.
Finally the fields grouping means we hash or
bin on a subset of the tuple attributes or fields.
For our use case then this is also not the best solution due to
computational overhead for one bolt.
Hopefully you chose the global grouping to connect the report bolt
to the count bolt.
Great job.