Welcome back to Computer Vision.
With this lesson, we're actually starting a new unit,
which I've nominally titled Features in Matching.
But really, the, the whole idea of this is to find reliably detectable and
discriminable locations in different images.
That is, I'd like to figure out a way that,
if I have some points in one image of a scene, I'd like to
figure out which points are the same points in another image of the scene.
Now, you might say wait a minute,
we just did that in stereo, but no, you didn't.
You see in stereo, the idea was that we
were going to have these epipolar lines along which we would search.
But remember we talked about that in order to find those epipolar lines,
we need to know the fundamental matrix, and in order to do that,
we'd need the correspondences, so this is a way of finding correspondences.
That's one way of thinking about it.
Couple of resources, Forsyth and
Ponce do cover this nicely here in section 5.3 and 4.
And Szeliski, which is that other textbook that we pointed you to,
also does this well in, chapter 4.