Let's fix one of our earlier toy
applications to better work with
the Android life cycle.
Our GitHub query application.
Open up exercise 5b, part 1,
and type in the query android.
When we rotate the device the word
android from the added text is
preserved, but the euro and
query results are thrown away.
Because edit text can be edited by
users, they are preserved automatically
by the Android framework during
a configuration change such as rotation.
Regular text views are not.
So how can we fix this?
We can again use a saved instant state.
We'll create a static
final string key for
storing the query URL, as well as a key
to store the raw JSON from the result.
Then we'll override onSave instant
state to store the query URL and
search results into
the saved state bundle.
Finally, in onCreate if the save
state bundle is not null
we retrieve the values and
restore the text to both views.
And here's how that app works now.