It seems like the simplest thing
we could do from our Android app.
Would be to add a single piece of
data to the Firebase database.
If you remember,
here's my shopping list screen, and
I got this floating
action bar button here.
It's supposed to add a shopping list.
When you press it you've got the nice
dialogue, you can enter a name.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
But when you press
Create it does nothing.
Let's have it store the name for the
shopping list I enter here, in Firebase.
Whenever we interact
with our Firebase data,
we need to create a Firebase object.
This object,
here, is tied to a specific Firebase
database that's specified by this URL.
Right before this,
you should have saved your URL in
a constant that we called FIREBASE_URL.
So for us, we can use the FIREBASE_URL
constant as a argument, here.
Now this Firebase ref object here has a
lot of methods that you can call on it.
Many of these methods we're going to
go over in detail and they're all
referenced in the Firebase DOCs which
I've linked in the instructor notes.
The two that we're interested
in right now are the child and
the .setValue method.
Your online Firebase database stores
everything as key value pairs.
What this code will do is make
whatever is put here the key and
whatever is put here the value.
So, if we were to type "listname"
right here, we'd be making a new
data entry in Firebase, or node,
that had the key of "listname", and
then we'd set it to
whatever value it has here.
I'm going to go ahead and
do this in the code.
The code that I'm interested in
is inside AddLIstDialogFragment.
Specifically, when you
hit the "Create" button,
it calls this addShoppingList method,
which is currently blank.
So, what I'm going to do is
make a new Firebase reference.
And I'm going to pass in the constant
that I made for the Firebase_URL.
And then I'm going to
take that reference.
And I'm going to say,
go to a child called ListName.
That's going to be our key.
And I'm going to say
set the value there.
And what I'm going to set it to is
what the user entered in the text
view of that dialog.
And if I scroll up.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We already have an instance
variable up here,
storing in reference to
the EditText in that dialogue.
So scrolling back down,
I'm going to set this string to
what's stored in the EditText.
And then I'm going to pass
that string in right here.
Okay, let's run this code.
Okay, so I've got the code up and
running.
I'm also going to go ahead and
open up my Firebase dashboard.
Okay, now moment of truth,
I'm going to click the plus button.
And I'm going to type in a list name,
and well, I
don't want to ruin the surprise of what
happens when I click that create button.
So go ahead and try this yourself and
tell me, what do you see on
the Firebase dashboard here?