When we use numbers as network
addresses, we don't care about adding or
subtracting them.
You never multiply one
address by another.
Just like street addresses or
postal codes, they may be numbers but
they don't really represent
quantities or amounts.
Rather, IP addresses,
like these other sorts of addresses,
represent difference.
Each address has to be different from
every other address on the same network.
With a given number of bits you can
only make a certain number of distinct
values.
Like with one bit, you can only
make two distinct values, 0 and 1.
With two bits you can make four values,
and with three bits, you can make eight.
So if you had a network that only
had three bit long addresses,
you could only have as many as
eight machines on the network.
So okay.
How about four bits?
How many distinct four
bit values are there?
Put your answer here.