If you experimented a lot
with the knock back we added,
you may have noticed that while being
flung through the air you could still
kind of control your movement left or
right.
You could either slow down or
speed up, how fast you're flung away.
Also, if you're so lucky as to be
knocked back in such a way that you
landed on a platform,
you just slid right off it.
Neither of those behaviors make
much sense, so let's fix them.
First, we need to set GigaGal's
horizontal velocity to zero when she
lands on a platform.
There we go.
Second, we need to add a new
jump state called recoiling
that disables the left and right
controls while GigaGal is flying through
the air after being hit by an enemy.
Check out the to do's in the course
code, first to make sure that GigaGal
doesn't just slide off of
platforms when she lands on them.
And second to disable
the arrow keys when GigaGal is
flying through the air after
being hit by an enemy.