So here we are on the Jenkins console,
and this is a build pipeline with
a bunch of automatic steps in it.
If this build, starts whether
automatically or manually,
it will run each of
these steps in order.
But let's say we want to add
a manual step, for instance,
this might a be a point at which
a human QA tester will need
to approve a particular build for
release.
To do that,
we'll need to do a few things.
First, we need to decide where that step
will be inserted into this pipeline.
We might decide, for instance,
that we want it to after tasks
are run but before their release.
Second, we need to
write the step itself.
We'll set it up to just echo a message
to the logs, just as a demonstration.
So in the new step,
in the build trigger section, well,
we want this to be a manual step,
so it isn't triggered by anything.
Then we go to the step that we
want to be before the manual step.
And we set it to have
a post build action,
which will build other
projects manual step, and
we specify the downstream
project as being our new step.
Now, in the pipeline view, we can see
the new step, but we want the release
step to be after the manual QA step,
so let's change that too.
Instead of being triggered
by the Test step,
the release will now be
triggered by the ManualQA.
Save that.
Go back to the Pipeline.
And now we have them in the right order.
And when we run it, well,
let's see what happens.
So you can see, the later steps turn
blue and the first one turns yellow,
then green, and
the colors change on down the pipeline.
And when it gets to the manual step,
it'll wait for
us to manually run it,
and it's all green.
So, now it's your turn.
In your Jenkins instance, add a step
to a pipeline, set the preceding step
to have it as a post-build manual step,
change the following step
to have the manual step as a build
trigger, and then run the pipeline.
What do you think all those
different colors actually mean?