In most programming languages,
you have to declare a function
before you can call it.
Basically the idea is that code's
read from top to bottom, so
there's no way that we should be able
to call this findAverage function
if it hasn't even been declared yet.
Like literally, how can we call
findAverage when the function
is being declared lower than when
the call's happening in the code.
So this shouldn't work, right?
Well, actually it does and
this is because of one really corky
feature in JavaScript called hoisting.
And it has to do with how JavaScript
code is being interpreted.
Basically before any code is executed,
all function declarations are hoisted
to the top of the current scope.
I know, this is weird, right?
Now just to be clear, the code you
write is actually not going to change.
The code's still going to look
exactly how you wrote it.
Its just when the code is being
interpreted when the function of
declaration is actually
getting hoisted to the top.
So still going to look the same and this
function is actually going to get called
and its going to return
back the correct value.
Hoisting also happens with
variable declarations,
let's take a look at
this simple example.
If we call the sayGreeting function
the way that it exists now,
we're going to get back
a reference error and
that's because the variable greeting has
not been defined or declared anywhere.
How can we print out greeting
if it doesn't exist?
To fix this error, we can declare
greeting pretty much anywhere in
the function because ultimately,
we know that it's going to get hoisted
to the top of the function scope.
For example, if I was to
declare greeting on line three,
we know that ultimately when
the code gets interpreted,
it's going to get hoisted
to the top of the function.
Of course, when this code is ran it
would still look the exact same way as I
wrote it, but now this time
it's printing out undefined.
So I guess that makes sense because
we haven't really given
greeting a value yet.
So let's try to give it a value and
then see what happens.
So instead of just greeting by itself,
let's assign the greeting and
the string hello.
Okay, so we get it undefined again.
This is actually a bug
because of hoisting.
The variable greeting is getting hoisted
to the top of the function scope, but
the assignment is staying
exactly where it is.
Because the variable declaration
is getting hosted to the top,
gets declared here but
the value's still undefined.
And then when we print it,
it's giving us back undefined.
So the moral of the story here is that
to avoid bugs like this JavaScript
programmers usually declare functions
at the top of their scripts, and
variables at the top of their functions.
That way the way the code looks,
and the way the code behaves,
are consistent with each other.