Now you're ready for
your next challenge app.
And this random color app the colorizer
text field has been changed so
that it randomly changes color
every time the text changes.
This is achieved with the random
color text field delegate.
I'm going to walk you through the steps
to create the random color text
field delegate.
Then you can run through the steps on
your own to see the random color app
in action.
The first step is to create an empty
random text field delegate class.
To do this just control click on
the folder where you want to put it.
Then go to New File.
Choose swift file and then name it.
Next you'll want to import UI kit,
define your class,
subclassing NS Object and declare
the UI text field delegate protocol.
Inside your new delegate class,
you'll need to create a method
that will return a random color.
If you need some help
writing this method,
there are some helpful suggestions
in the next reading node.
You'll also want to implement the method
textField shouldChangeCharactersInRange.
This is where you'll set
the color of your text.
And then the last two steps are in
the viewController.swift file.
You'll need a variable for
your new delegate.
And then assign that delegate
to one of the text fields.
After you've completed those steps, run
the simulator and verify that it works.