Along your journey to becoming an iOS developer,
your Udacity support team will
be with you every step of the way.
You can schedule one-on-one meetings with
our mentors and visit our discussion
forms, which are monitored around the clock.
When you submit a project, you'll
get line-by-line feedback on your code
from professional coder viewers.
If you stay on schedule, you'll submit your
first project and see your first review this week.
While you build projects that
will become the basis for your app portfolio,
our careers team will help you
assemble your professional profile,
ensure you're prepared for your interviews,
and offer personalized support
one-on-one to answer any questions you
might have regarding your job search.
And not talk. Let's write some code