Your conference central application
is now fully functional, and
you can save and get profile and
conference entities whenever you want.
But it's not very efficient yet.
Every time your code makes a call to
get an entity from the data store,
that entity can be fetched from disk.
That's slow for you users, and
it also counts against your daily quota.
And that's why App Engine
offers Memcache
as a way to automatically
cache your data.
In this lesson you'll learn how NDB
takes care of caching entities.
And because that's really too easy,
we'll also take a look at how to use
the underlying Memcache Python API
to put entries into the Memcache and
get them back.
Let's suppose you want to run an ad
encouraging people to sign up for
conferences that are nearly sold out.
You can store those
announcements in Memcache.
There's no need to save them in
datastore because they are very
transient in nature, and
it doesn't really matter if an
announcement gets evicted from Memcache.
Another feature of App Engine
that we'll explore in this lesson
is how to deal with long-running
tasks by using task queues.
And to do that, we'll use task queues to
set a confirmation email when someone
creates a conference.
And we'll wrap up the lesson by creating
a cron job, that periodically checks for
conferences that are nearly sold out and
updates the announcement in Memcache.