An image template is useful for
detecting things that do not
vary in their appearance much.
For instance, icons or
emojis on the screen.
But for most real world objects that do
appear in different forms, orientation,
sizes, this technique
doesn't work quite well.
In template matching, you depend on raw
color values laid out in a specific
order, and that can vary a lot,
so you need to find some
transformations that are robust
to changes in appearance.
Once a transform is to compute the
histogram of color values in an image.
When you compare the histogram of
a known object with regions of a test
image, locations with similar color
distributions will reveal a close match.
Here, we have removed our
dependents on structure, that is,
we are no longer sensitive to
a perfect arrangement of pixels.
Therefore, objects that appear in
slightly different aspects and
orientations will still be matched.
Variations and
image size can also be accommodated
by normalizing the histograms.
However, note that you are now solely
relying on the distribution of color
values which might match
some unwanted regions.