Now that you're familiar with NumPy
arrays, let's move on to pandas series.
A series is similar to a NumPy array,
but
it has a little
additional functionality.
For example, if you have a series named
s, then the function s.describe will
print out the mean standard deviation,
median, and some other statistics about
your series as this function
isn't available for NumPy arrays.
There are also some other benefits
of series over arrays which I'll go
over in a minute.
For now though, I want to focus on the
similarities between series and arrays.
All the things you just learned
how to do on Numpy arrays
will also work on Pandas series.
You can access elements using the square
bracket notation to get either a single
element or a slice of elements.
You can still loop over your series.
You can call the same convenient
functions you just saw such as mean and
max, and you can still used
vectorized operations.
And just like NumPy,
pandas series are implemented in C, and
thus are much faster
than using Python lists.
On the following screen,
you'll see some test code you
can try out using Pandas series.
I'd also like you to write a function
that takes in two series as arguments,
for example, life expectancy in 2007 and
GDP in 2007.
The countries will be in
the same order for each.
The function should perform
the following simple heuristic
to check whether these
variables seem to be related.
The function will look at the question,
when a country has a life
expectancy above the mean,
is the GDP above the mean also?
Or vice versa.
If the life expectancy is below
the mean, is the GDP below the mean?
Your function should return two numbers.
The first number is
the number of countries where
both values are above the mean or
both values are below the mean.
The second number should be the number
of countries where one value is above
the mean and
the other is below the mean.
So these two numbers should add up
to the total number of countries.
Like I mentioned, the inputs will be
panned as a series, but you should
be able to write the same code to solve
this as you would for NumPy arrays.
Here's a hint you can use to
make your code a little shorter.
In Python,
you can actually add booleans up.
True will be treated as one and
false will be treated as zero.
So in Python true + true = 2.
So how I would approach this problem is,
first create an array of booleans.
The boolean is true if both
numbers are both below the mean or
both are above, and false otherwise.
Then I would take the sum of this array
to find out how many countries meet
that condition.