Here's another particle filter question.
Now we're looking at the state position,
beginning with the same state position as before and the same 3 particles--
1 over here, 1 over here, 1 over here,
and to give the states names, you're going to call this one a1, a2, b1, and b2.
Let's assume we take a single random particle with uniform distribution,
and we emulate a next state.
The state position works as follows: A particle will move with property 1 to an adjacent state
but adjacent is either north, south, east, or west, but not diagonal,
because every particle has 2 adjacent states, it'll break ties at random
so you're going to pick 1 of the 2 with 50% probability.
So with this 1 particle that you've drawn random,
and it's in the random single position,
what's the probability that finds itself in a1, a2, b1, and b2?