[Thrun] And surprisingly, the answer is 7.
You cannot recover the absolute location and orientation of the coordinate system,
which are 6 of those parameters,
but you can also not recover scale.
For example, take a situation like this where you have 3 points over here
and now make this situation twice as large
with the points spread out twice as widely.
Because of perspective math, this over here will be the same answer
as this guy over here.
So this is 1 scale parameter that you can't recover,
so you can only recover 6m plus 3n minus 7 parameters.
And as long as this is smaller than 2mn, you have a solution
of the structure from motion problem.
This was entirely nontrivial.
If you got this wrong, I would have gotten this wrong if I hadn't known the solution.
But it's fun to think about these things.
A lot of computer vision people care about whether the problem is well posed,
and you need a certain number of features and a certain number of images
to make this equation hold true.