So here, I have just I think this is a figure from Forsythe and Ponds.
Maybe it's from Salinski.
I hope their lawyers aren't watching.
It's somebody.
And basically, it talks about how you can transform an image.
And so on the bottom left hand corner, you have a square.
And you can see, you could just translate it.
They, they call it Euclidean, but
that's just a rigid transformation where you have the rotation translation.
You have similarity, affine, and projective, and
we're going to talk about each of those in terms of the mathematics.
So let's take the simplest example.
So the simpi, the simplest example here is translation.
So we have an x and, and by the way in, in this cool little figure.
So the original x and y is the green box, and take our x and
we just add some translation vector to it.
And we saw that it was an easy way to describe this using
homogeneous coordinates where we just do xy and 1, and we add 1 to the end.
And then we can just have a transformation matrix here, which is just made up of
an identity plus the translation vector that we add from over here.
And to keep the whole thing in homogeneous coordinates, we would just say we
would make a, instead of a 2 by 3, would make this a 3 by 3.
So that 0 vector now is on the bottom row.
And what we do is we get from one homogeneous vector to another.
Okay?
So that would be translation.
By the way, because these are now just matrix multiplications,
we could chain these transformations.