So looking at the same
stereo system again.
So all information that
we are searching for
this likelihood of all the points
corresponding would be on the same line.
So we actually need to just look for
images on the same line.
This can be demonstrated by simply
looking at the same example we have
looked at before.
Basically find the patch
on the left image.
In this case here,
find this polar line constraint.
And take this and match it to all
the regions just on that line.
One by one, it reduces the computational
complexity quite a bit.
And now I can actually come
up with matches on this one,
use that to create a match score value.
Again, could be somewhat
square differences, or normal,
normalized cross correlation.
And if you notice this starts
giving you a very high score,
in this case high being good of a match.
And this basically tells
me this is a match to this,
and this gives me correspondence.
And of course that could be used to find
the matches that could be used to do
disparity computations.