Now, let's use a simple two by three
version of isolation to illustrate how
to make a game tree that shows all
the moves possible during a game.
We will use this game
tree to select moves,
which give the best
guarantee of winning.
Consider any filled spot on
the game board as unavailable.
We will start with one filled spot,
we'll call the beginning game
level zero in our game tree.
Assume that O is the computer player.
O is the first to move, so the computer
has five choices in the beginning.
We draw out all the possible boards for
level one of the game tree.
X goes next and
can put its piece anywhere on the game
board that has not been taken by O.
So no matter which position O occupied
for it's first move, X has four choices.
We can quickly draw the nodes for
level two of our tree.
>From then on, the number of choices for
each player becomes smaller
as the pieces are limited to
moves like a queen in chess.
O goes next.
The left most leaf,
O can move straight down,
diagonally down to the right,
but it can't move through X.