So if you add the timer.timedFunction
decorator to the sumUp function,
it's the same as if we had reassigned
sumUp to be this wrapped up version.
And when the code called
the sumUp function afterwards,
it returned the sum of
the numbers from 0 to 10 million.
But it also printed out how
long it took to add up.
That timing feature was
added by this decorator.
The details of how decorators work,
are rooted in functional programming.
I've put a couple of links
in the instructor notes,
that go into much more depth.
And just like other functions,
decorators can appear in Python modules.
You'll be seeing an example
right up ahead in this course.