Paul just showed you something
ridiculously awesome.
With the timeline, you can watch how
one piece of work causes another.
I mean, that's just amazing,
and so for this quiz,
I want you to load a timeline.
What?
Load a timeline you say?
You can do it pretty easily.
Simply right-click in the timeline and
go to Save As to save one, or
Load to load a timeline.
Loading a timeline is a super easy
way to share and compare timelines.
In the downloadable section,
you can find this timeline.
Once you've got it,
simply right-click in any timeline and
then load it for yourself.
Once you've loaded the timeline,
see if you can figure out which function
caused initWebGLObjects() to run.
Type it into this box.
And finally, if this JavaScript
was called during an animation,
would it still be possible for the
animation to reach 60 frames per second?
Yes or no.