Here are the answers for this quiz.
First off, the answer for Pipe and Filter is C, increased coupling.
This is because some changes, like the format of the data going through
the pipeline could affect all of the filters, reflecting their tight coupling.
The answer for Blackboard is D, can promote spread of bad data.
Because the blackboard is a common repository accessible by all components,
if it somehow gets contaminated this bad data could readily spread to
other components.
The answer for object orientation is A, increased system fragmentation.
Object orientation can increase system fragmentation because of
the many relatively small independent objects that may exist.
And finally the answer for
implicit invocation is B, reduced system understanding.
This happens because server components are not aware of clients which can
change dynamically.