There are some cool things that you can do when you
find the fundamental matrices that relate different views to each other, okay?
Because essentially,
you can figure out which points correspond to which other points.
One, which is really kind of interesting, is, suppose I've
got a pair of views of a scene, and what I'd like to do is do some stereo.
And I know that if I solve for the fundamental matrix, I could, for every point,
I could find the epipole that's along and search along that.
But of course, every point lands on different epipolar line.
What you can do is what's called image rectification or stereo rectification.
Where you take your original image and be, if you find the fundamental matrix,
you can essentially unwarp, maybe that's not the right word.
Just rectify is the right word.
So, it's as if the two images were
taken with parallel image planes that are aligned.
And why is that good?
Because it makes me happy.
No, it's good because you can get publi, no, it's good because then it
means your stereo solution now is just moving along the, the horizontal line.
So your search is not just 1D, because it was 1D before.
But it's a particular known one dimensional search.
Namely, every point here corresponds somewhere along the corresponding scan line
of the other image.
And that was done nicely comes from this paper here shown in 1999,
showing you a real example that they did that comes from their paper.
Here you see two images taken from
radically different views of this very weird sculpture.
The lines that are drawn on there are the epipolar lines, and
you'll notice they're skewed, and they they go off this way.
All right, after you do the stereo rectification by finding the fundamental
matrix, you get horizontal epipolar lines, which was the whole point, and
allows you to do the stereo algorithm.