To get ready for creating the tag,
we first need to create two triggers.
I'll start with the trigger
of the open screen event.
So, go to triggers, new.
I'm going to call my
trigger open screen, and
I want it to fire on an event.
So, you choose event from fire on.
I want it to fire when the event equals
openScreen because that's
what we put in our code.
So you see here in the code
it was openScreen, so
I want the event to equal openScreen.
So the mapOf method
defines the values for
DataLayer variables and the name of
the event is the first argument here.
And don't forget to save the trigger.
So we've defined the trigger for
the openScreen event.
But we don't have a trigger yet
specifically for
the show daily specials screen.
So I'm going to create that now.
New trigger, I'm going to
call it Daily Special Screen.
And I want it to fire when
the screen name equals,
whatever it was I put in my code,
which was Show Daily Special.
And in fact, I'm just going to copy and
paste it from here.
Now we could have created one trigger
that was fired by the two
separate conditions.
But keeping the triggers
separated like this allows for
more flexibility when
we're creating our tags.
Okay, now we're ready to create the tag
was fired by the open screen event for
the show daily special activity.
Create a tag.
New.
Okay, we want this tag to
send an Analytics hit, so
I'm just going to be fairly
explicit in my name.
Call it Send Daily Special Screen Hit.
You can call it what you like.
Choose product, must be Analytics.
And then you're going to need the
tracking ID for your analytics account.
There's two ways to get it.
You can go to the Admin tab in Google
analytics, go to your Tracking Code and
then you get your Tracking ID from here,
or in Android Studio in your
tracking configuration file for
analytics, you get the ga_trackingId.
Assuming you set it correctly that is.
Anyway, whichever way you do it, get
the value and go back to tag manager.
Now you could just copy it right in
here, but we're not going to do that.
Instead, we're going to
create a variable so
that we don't have to look it
up again next time we need it.
So we click on the building brick,
scroll down to new, choose constant
because this time our variable is
a constant, give it an appropriate name.
And set the value.
And then create the variable.
And there, the variable's created.
And you notice now here we're back
in the create the tag screen.
And you've got the variable
My Tracking ID.
And notice that the variable begins and
ends with curly braces.
And anywhere you see this
building block, you can insert or
create a variable.
Anyway, back to creating our new tag.
So the default track type for analytics
is App View and that's what we want.
So just make sure that
you see App View here.
An App View hit sends
a Screen View hit to analytics.
The only parameter it takes is
the screen name, which is required.
So you need to click More settings
> Fields to Set > Add Field.
And then click not on the brick but
in the field itself.
And select screenName.
This is not the variable enclosed in
double braces, it's just screenName.
This is required for
App view or screen View hits.
And then the value, click on
the brick and choose screenName.
This one is the variable
that you defined.
And continue and then you need to
decide when you want it to fire.
So click Custom and there's two
conditions that we want it to fire.
We want it to fire when the event
equals open screen which would
be the open screen trigger.
And we want it to fire when the screen
name equals Show Daily Special.
So we'll choose that one.
And we'll save and we'll create the tag.
Save the tag and that's it we're done.
>> You forgot something.
>> What, what did I forget?
Oops, yes it's easy to forget.
You have to publish your changes
before they can take effect.
Go ahead and create a tag to send the
hits to analytics when someone goes to
the daily specials screen in the act.
You'll need to create the open
screen trigger and a trigger for
when the screen name is daily special.
And then you'll need to create
the tag to send the hit to analytics.
And while you're creating a tag go ahead
and create a variable to hold your
analytics account I.D. Publish your
changes and restart and run the App.
So if you've got your phone for your
tablet whatever device you are using.
Connected to Android studio,
you can look in the logs
to see the hits being sent.
And for that you must have bugging for
tag manager enabled.
And search for hits, and here we see
that an, the application name is
What's for dinner, cd stands for
content description.
In this case it's Show Daily Special.
The language is English,
and t equals appview, and
that's a type of hit that's being sent.
And then you should also see the t ID,
which is the account ID.
As you try out your app and
particularly as you go through the show
daily special activity, you should be
able to see the data showing up in
a real-time dashboard in analytics.
You see I've got my top screen
name as Show Daily Special.
So, go ahead and do these things,
create the triggers, create the tag,
create the variable, restart and
run the app, check the logs,
check real time analytics and
check the boxes as your done.