The steps of putting data in the data
layer are, get the tag manager instance
and you do that calling get
instance on the tag manager.
Then, get the data layer and
you do that calling getDataLayer
on your tag manager instance.
And then you put a key/value
pair in the Data Layer.
And you do that calling push on the Data
Layer, specifying the key and the value.
For example,
if the key is food_pref, And
values "vegan",
this is how you would do it.
That's all fairly simple.
And when the values in the data layer,
you get it out using "dataLayer.get".
For example, you just call "get",
specifying "food_pref" as the key.
When the values in the data layer can
also be used in tag manager triggers.
And we're going to look
into how to do that.
In lesson one, we use the what's for
dinner button to display the users food
preferences before suggesting a dinner.
You're now going to use a similar
menu to set the food preferences.
The daily special.
Your tasks are in main activity,
to find a new method putFoodPref in
Data Layer, which takes a menu item.
And this method puts a value for
food pref in the data layer.
And this table shows the menu item value
and the data layer value to put in.
And the key is always food pref.
And then update the existing
show daily special method
to display the food pref's pop up menu.
And then you'll need to set
the old click listener to call
the putFoodPrefin DataLayer method and
to start the ShowDailySpecialActivity.
You can find the code for
creating the PopupMenu
in the showFoodPrefsMenu
method in MainActivity.
This method pops up
the food preferences menu.
And then uses the food preference
to get dinner suggestion.
However, we want to get the daily
special, not the dinner suggestion.
So you'll need to copy and
modify the code to suit your needs.
So go ahead and do these steps now and
then deploy your app.
You won't see any changes in
the way the app behaves yet.
Next we'll add triggers in tag manager
to make use of the data layer variable,
and that's when you'll see
the changes in your app.