So we wanted to find out
what was the highest and
lowest ports so
we could listen on using Netcat.
Let's start with the lowest.
Let's try 2048.
It looks like listening on
port 2048 works just fine.
Let's try a much lower port 100,
permission denied, okay,
that's interesting.
If we do a little searching in this
direction, we'll find out that we
can't listen on port 1023 but
we can listen on port 1024, cool.
What happens in the other direction?
Suppose we'd heard listening on
port 9999 Looks like that works.
How about port 65535?
That works, too.
How about 128000?
Says here nc, port number too large,
when we went to connect to it.
So regardless of what
happened over here,
it doesn't look like we're actually
able to usefully listen on port 128000.
If we kept on experimenting, we'd find
that actually 65535 is the largest
port number we can listen on usefully.
But it's interesting that
the error that we got at 65536 and
the error that we got at
1023 were not the same.
They didn't even show
up in the same window.
Plus, with this 1023 being too low,
that's kind of odd because we know that
the SSH server in the web server listen
on ports below 1024, like 22 and 80.
So how come they can but nc can't?
Let's look into that.