Now that you've finished coding, let's
take a look at the code that I wrote.
For the multiply_coefficient_and_row
function,
I have to make sure to multiply both
the coefficients of the variables in
the equation represented by
the plane's normal_vector and
the constant_term by the same
multiplicative factor.
Notice that I make a new plane
object here instead of just altering
the normal_vector and constant_term
of the current plane object.
If I had altered the existing plane,
I'd need to reset the plane's base point
attribute as well or
else I would introduce some subtle bugs.
Finally, for the
add_multiple_times_row_to_row function,
I again make sure to add the appropriate
amount to both the normal vector and
the constant term.
Finally, I make a new plane to
replace the plane currently existing
in the slot, row to be added to.
When I scroll down to the test code and
run it, I get no output from the tests,
since the tests only output
anything if they fail,
that means my code passed all the tests.