The next module is when we start getting into more analysis of the image itself.
Here we'll actually learn more about the digital image representations,
how you represent images to make them computable objects.
We will learn about pixel and point processes of images.
Again, doing some mathematics on these images or computation on them.
We will learn things like, how do you smooth and filter images?
And again, learn the basic principles, the intuition behind these.
We will learn more about how we can extract different types of information from
images for analysis.
And in this timeframe, we'll actually do experiments where you'll actually learn
more about image filtering and also feature detection.