This code makes a reference
to R.drawable.bg and
this references a bg.png
file in res/drawable-hdpi.
So what we'll do is we're just
going to copy our new dog.jpg into
the same directory.
So here we're going to
copy the image over and
now we can see it here
in the project viewer.
This here shows that I used
a 320 by 320 jpeg image.
I changed bg to dog here in the code.
Now if you look at where the drawBitmap
call is made, it draws it all the time.
We need to only draw the bitmap
when not in ambient mode.
So we add this if statement
to check the ambient state.
Also, we need to clear the canvas to
black if we don't draw the background.
If you forget to do this then
the canvas will show the previous one
before ambient mode and you will
incorrectly see the second hand.
So that's it.
We're done with the changes.
When we run the watch
face in interactive mode,
we can see the dog picture
in the background.
When we go into ambient mode,
the background is black.
Congratulations!
You now have your own customized
Android Wear watch face.