This map is taken from these three.
We found that previous side has example of you know,
there is these three visualizations and we already decide that you know,
visualizing the sentiment across the United States is a very cool idea.
So we took you know, a map that we can make some interactive display.
This map is broken up by counties, and each county has a color and
the color is a sentiment of those tweets that we got for that county.
And also if you see,
when you hover over the county you'll see the tweet message of the county.
Other grey area are the places where we haven't seen tweet yet.
>> And so yellow is very happy and dark blue is unhappy and so with
the World Series going on right now we see the some yellow around San Fransisco.
>> Okay, well, let's take a look at your code.
And so and a lot of the logic here is basically you've
modified the app.py that we gave you.
You created a map.html, so how about we start with the app.yi.
>> Okay.
So Juan all ready got this.
There are already a couple, you know, applications all ready filled out for
us, you know, the basic and the stream.
So what we did is we added a map.html and
the way to send any data to it is by adding this app.route.
And that's the only thing that'll add to the app.python.
>> So it's pretty simple.
>> Yeah, very simple.
>> Mm-hm. >> So this is a map.html.
And we originally took a template that already exists.
And we- >> That's from the datamaps.github.
>> Yeah. The datamap.github.
Yup. That's the place.
And this JavaScript file has the map or data.
So the java script renders all the information in this file and
create this map that you see on this display.
And we added a JavaScript that physical just does a county lookup.
It, it a reads the county id and
then give us the id that corresponds to this map we see here.
>> And I see it's in the static county, the static\countyLookup.
There it is.
Cool.
>> We have a couple colors on this map and
we're trying to really show, you know, the sentiment pretty continuous scale.
Well, of course, we cannot put all the colors on there so chose ten levels.
And those ten levels are, you know, kind of a gradient from blue to yellow.
And that's, you know, how we created that, those color code.
Over here we have the source.onmessage, and
this is the part that takes the information, the Storm pass to Redis.
So it reads the event data, and split it by the delimiter, and
gets the county id, the sentence, the tweet and then a sentiment.
So that's the three things that we decided to pass to the map.
Of course there used to be a lot more fields but
that's the thing that we ended up using.
>> How about we skip really quickly to the report bolt just to
make that connection.
So we've basically, I see that you've,
you've changed the bar type character that I was using.
And provided the class.
And you have created a delimeter.
And so basically what we're doing is Redis.publish to the word
count topology stream and you're publishing the count id, delimeter the tweet,
the delimeter, and the sentiment with another delimeter.
And So you've stuffed this into a large string.
>> Right.
>> And then parsed it out.
>> Right. >> Very cool.
>> Yeah.
RIght, so, we had to up, because we had to update the map,
the color in real time, so what we did is that we created a hash,
kind of an associative array in JavaScript.
And in here we update a counting id with the most frequent sentence that we
pass in.
And also the kind of running average sentence that we pass in.
So every time there's something new, we pass into this hash structure.
And then we have this window.setInterval function.
This is, this is saying, let's update a map every second.
This is millisecond unit.
And we call this function updateViz.
And in here we are looking at okay,
let's look at all the keys in hashSentiment and we're going to update.
All the sentiment that we received was in that one second interval and
here we're seeing if the sentiment we get the color, put the color into this
data of structure and the map will take this data and update it accordingly.
So this, [INAUDIBLE] you know by, in the D3 package.
So we didn't have to do much with that.
I know it's very complicated.
Yeah.
And then we reset hashSentiment.
>> Cool. >> So we can see it, you know, updating in real-time.
I think this is super cool.
>> Yeah. We're getting only 1% of tweets, so
the map is not, you know, populating very quickly.
>> Right.
>> But if we have a lot more data, then we will be seeing a lot of,
you know, blinking.
>> Mm-hm. >> And.
A lot more colors.
>> Cool.
All right, thanks a lot.