So we see now that there are a lot
security concerns to address regarding
authentication if we
implement it ourselves.
But, chances are, someone else has
already solved these problems before.
Developers have created free and open
solutions we can use to authenticate
users on our web applications,
simplifying the process of adding web
security without having to reinvent
the wheel with each web application.
Instead of authenticating the user
by yourself, you could ask a trusted
third party to take care of
the complexities of user authentication.
Then the third party can communication
back to your application that the user
was authenticated against their
third party security system,
allowing your application to not only
securely interact with the user but
share data between your app and
the third party authenticator for
a more streamlined user experience.
As an app developer, this allows you
to worry less about the authentication
part, and spend more time and effort
on your application logic instead.
Here, let's do a quick example about
how third-party authentication works.
Let's say I created a web application
and want to allow my users to be able to
log in with an existing third-party
profile, like Facebook or Google.
So I don't have to create
another username and
password just to use my site.
By implementing third-party
authentication,
communication between all
involved parties must happen.
As a user, you must first
communicate with my application,
which will then take you to the third
party's login to verify your identity.
My application also verifies it's
identity with the third party app and
waits for
a confirmation of user trying to log in.
The third-party app requests to share
your information with my application,
and then allows my application to
access your third-party account.
Once my application receives
confirmation from the third-party app,
you are now logged into my site.
My application may also have access
to certain things in your profile,
like your profile pic or
latest status updates,
to make your user experience
even more complete on my site.
But wait a second, you might be
thinking, hey, not so fast, web app.
Just because I want to log into your
site, doesn't mean I want you to have
access to my entire Facebook profile,
especially without my knowledge or
permission of what you're using and
when.
And you'd be absolutely right.
Clearly, if there's some third
party involved you want to know
what kind of information
is being shared about you.
This is where the concept
of authorization comes in.
Let's talk about that now.