Well it turns out that most of the different kinds of UML diagrams could be so
used. Of the 14 diagrams I've listed here nine of them that might be,
might be appropriate. Of course a given diagram, like a class model diagram,
might be useful at a very low level that we wouldn't even call architectural.
What it also could be used for lending out what the major classes of a system
are. As with some of the other diagrams they can convey the structural elements,
but also some of the UML diagrams can convey the behavioral aspect. For example,
sequence diagrams and communication diagrams. And
at a most abstract level in terms of dealing with a systems overall usage and
how its going to be broken out into different aspects of functionality,
use case diagram could be useful for those circumstances.