[Narrator] Planning under uncertainty.
In this class so far
we talked a good deal about planning.
We talked about uncertainty and probabilities,
and we also talked about learning,
but all 3 items were discussed separately.
We never brought planning and uncertainty together,
uncertainty and learning, or planning and learning.
So the class today, we'll fuse planning and uncertainty
using techniques known as Markov decision processes or MDPs,
and partial observer Markov decision processes or POMDPs.
We also have a class coming up on reinforcement learning
which combines all 3 of his aspects,
planning, uncertainty, and machine learning.
You might remember in the very first class
we distinguished very different characteristics of agent tasks,
and here are some of those.
We distinguished deterministic was the casting environments,
and we also talked about photos as partial observable.
In the area of planning so far
all of our evidence falls into this field over here,
like A*, depth first, right first and so on.
The MDP algorithms
which I will talk about first
fall into the intersection of fully observable
yet stochastic, and just to remind us
what the difference was,
stochastic is an environment where the outcome of an action is somewhat random.
Whereas an environment that's deterministic
where the outcome of an action is predictable
and always the same.
An environment is fully observable if you can
see the state of the environment which means if you can make all decisions
based on the momentary sensory input.
Whereas if you need memory,
it's partially observable.
Planning in the partially observable case
is called POMDP, and towards the end of this class,
I'll briefly talk about POMDPs but not in any depth.
So most of this class focuses on Markov decision processes
as opposed to partially observable Markov decision processes.
So what is a Markov decision process?
One way you can specify a Markov decision process by a graph.
Suppose you have states S1, S2, and S3,
and you have actions A1 and A2.
In a state transition graph, like this,
is a finite state machine,
and it becomes Markov if the outcomes of actions are somewhat random.
So for example if A1 over here, with a 50% probability, leads to
state S2 but with another 50% probability
leads to state S3.
So put differently, a Markov decision process of
states, actions, a state's transition matrix,
often written of the following form
which is just about the same as
a conditional state transition probability
that a state is prime
is the correct posterior state
after executing action A in a state S,
and the missing thing is the objective for the Markov decision process.
What do we want to achieve?
For that we often define a reward function,
and for the sake of this lecture,
I will attach rewards just to states.
So each state will have a function R attached
that tells me how good the state is.
So for example it might be worth $10
to be in the state over here,
$0 to be in the state over here,
and $100 to be in a state over here.
So the planning problem is now the problem
which relies on an action to each possible state.
So that we maximize our total reward.