The overall SIFT procedure to recognition was originally defined to
have sort of four components.
The first two were finding these extrema these,
those are those maximums the difference in Gaussians that we looked at.
And to detect, you know, localize exactly where they were.
So, these days as I mentioned this before,
a lot of people use the Harris-Laplace method of doing this instead.
Where you do Laplace in scale and Harris in space, whatever it is.
Use some method to find your keypoints, and
also to determine the scale of the keypoints in the image.
Then what you have to do, there are two more things related to SIFT and
we're going to do them today.
The first is, we're going to define an orientation.
That is, we don't know how the image has been transformed and
of our little local neighborhood, we want to know what the orientation is.
And then, once we have an orientation, we can think of
that feature with a spectator orientation and build a descriptor.
And by the way, I'm using the phrase here, Keypoint.
Keypoint was the terminology used in SIFT.
What we're talking about is these detected interest points and, and
you're going to use them as keypoints, you're going to use them as features.
Keypoint description is the descriptor we're going to use.
All right.
Here is a, a, a picture taken out of again the original SIFT work.
Here is just a, a small image of a house on the left.
And what this incredibly ugly graphic on the right is, is just.
And, and we've got better ones in a minute, but this was the original.
Is just there were all these little keypoints, and
you can see these direction arrows.
Okay?
And those directions are going to be the little local orientation that
we're talking about.