Here's my lazy answer to the lazy quiz.
Just B-trees.
Rather than telling you why
the others aren't I/O efficient,
let me tell you why a B-tree
can be I/O efficient.
Briefly, and hopefully by way of review,
let's quickly go over what a B-tree is.
Dang union artists. Let's try this
again. Briefly, and hopefully
by way of review, this is a B-tree.
Each node contains a set of keys and
a set of child pointers.
The branching factor at
each node can vary, but
it must lie within a specific range.
The keys are sorted.
Sorry, that's sorted, not sordid.
Let's look at one of the nodes.
Let's call it X.
A moment ago I said the branching factor
has to lie within a certain interval.
that interval is between B + 1 and
2B- 1 for some B that's at least 2.
B is a user-defined parameter.
Consider the ith key value at x.
Let's call that key case of i.
Now consider any key within the subtree
rooted at the ith child of x.
Let's call that key c sub i.
A B-tree data structure maintains
the following invariant.
The key k sub i lies between
the key values of its children to
the left and right.
It's not too hard to show that the
height of this tree is log base b of n.
So, in order for B tree search to attain
the lower bound on slow fast memory
transfers, you just need
to pick B appropriately.
Namely, pick B to be proportional
to the transfer size L.
Now the key point is that a B
tree can be made to IO optimal,
but only if you choose
the right branching factor.
In particular,
you have to make the branching
factor specific to the machine.
So much for
algorithmic portability, or is it?
[SOUND]