Now that we've learned about placing
objects in 3D space and how to give them
color using materials, how we go
about bringing these objects to life?
&gt;&gt; Well,
that's where animations come into play.
At it's most basic level, we can rotate
the hands of a clock just like this or
at a more advanced level, we can
actually create some 3D characters and
animate them just like these guys.
&gt;&gt; Wow, that's cool.
Animations are a great way
to bring your scene to life,
and they're also are really good
way the director uses attention,
because as humans we're very sensitive
to movement in our peripheral vision.
&gt;&gt; Absolutely, and
unity action makes it really easy with
the built in tool called mecanim.
So, let's learn how to use it.