I now have a stereo question.
For a valid calibrated stereo rig, we're given two pinhole cameras
whose displacement is B, and we observe a point out in the scene.
The distance of this point to the image plane up uppercase Z.
Our cameras have a focal length of f.
Of course, this point is being projected into two different locations
for the two different images--x2 and x1.
For the sake of this question, we're going to just consider delta x, which is x2 minus x1--
the displacement in the corresponding images.
We measure delta x in millimeters, same with the focal length f.
B is in meters and so is Z,
and I use meters for B and Z so that the units effectively fall out.
You don't really have to consider them.
Suppose the measured delta x is 4 mm
with a focal length of 40, and our displacement is 0.1.
How far away is the object in meters?
Suppose we have a displacement of 0.05 mm for a focal length of 50.
We now care about the baseline B, if we happen to know the object is 100 meters away.
Next we have a displacement of 0.1 mm. We don't know our focal length.
We know that the baseline is 0.2 mm, and the object is 50 meters away.
Finally we don't know the displacement, but we do know that the focal length is 200 mm.
We have a baseline of 1 m and the object is 50 meters away.
Can you fill in the missing numbers?