So that sort of talks about the energy and now what we have to do is we
have to talk about what is the relationship between the light coming in and
the light going out.
Because the light going out is
the light that's going to go into your sensor, right?
And to model that,
we use what's called the Bidirectional Reflectance Distribution Function
or BRDF.
Okay?
And the idea of the BRDF is that I've got a little surface patch that has
a normal.
And my light comes in at some angle and
I'm going to be viewing it at some other angle, all right?
And I want to talk about the amount of, sort of the proportion of
this light that comes in as, as sort of what proportion of this light coming in,
in this direction, goes out in some other particular direction.
By the way, this angle theta here, that's the tilt angle.
That is the amount that you're off of the normal.
And then there's a rotation around the normal that's the Okay?
And for some surfaces, we actually have to worry about both of those angles.
All right.
And so the irradiance is the amount, just like we said before,
it's the light per unit area that's coming onto the surface.
And now it's radiance, because now it's not the radiance from the light source,
it's the radiance back from the reflecting surface.
Okay.
Remember, radiance is the stuff coming out.
Irradiance is the stuff landing on it.
So now we have the,
before, the radiance was the stuff coming out of the light source.
Now the radiance is the light coming up off the reflective surface.
So we'll just write this as E of the irradiance of the surface in
some particular direction.
The L is, I don't know.
I don't know why we, I guess we use L for radiance sometimes,
because it's the lightness of what you're going to be seeing.
That's the radiance from the surface in some particular direction going out.
And the BRDF, the Bidirectional Reflectance Distribution Function is
just the ratio of those two things.
Right?
So it's the percentage of the light reflected as a function of
the light coming in, okay?
A couple things about it is that obviously, you can't reflect more light than
came in, so that ratio is going to be less than one.
Now you might get a very bright spot in some direction,
if it were to integrate over all these different lights.
But from one particular direction, the most I can do is send back all the light,
I can't, I can't manufacture light.
This is a, a passive system here.