An agent interacts with the environment
by sensing its properties.
This is known as perception and
by producing useful output or
actions that typically change
the state of the environment.
The process by which an agent
decides what action to take
based on its perceived
inputs is called cognition.
Much of our discussion of AI will focus
on cognition, especially reasoning and
decision making.
Perception and action become more
relevant in systems that react with
the real world, such as robots and
self-driving cars.
>> Now some agents directly associate
their actions with what is perceived or
have very simple
pre-programmed behaviors.
>> [SOUND] Like an automated
trashcan that opens when
it senses something in front of it.
>> These are referred to as,
reactive or behavior based agents.
Now it's possible to accomplish
surprisingly complex behavior
by layering simple reactive
control in a hierarchy.
Now, on the other end of the spectrum,
some agents are more deliberate and
perform some non trivial processing
such as game playing agents, or
path planners.
We can further classify these agents
depending on the kind of processing they
do like knowledge based agents, planning
agents, learning agents, and so on.