[SOUND] All right,
we just wrote a lot of lines of code.
So now, I'm actually going to show you
another way we could've written that
clickListener without
writing that many lines.
And as developers,
we like to be as concise as possible,
which makes the code easier for
other people to read.
Now, I here at the MainActivity.java.
Notice that we created
the OnClickListener variable here, but
only use it once here.
So I'm going to show you a new way that
we can create that object in line.
So I'm going to cut that part out and
replace the object here.
Nice.
Now, I can go ahead and
delete this line.
And now the code is simplified and
looks like this.
So less lines of code,
right, looks better.
I want to show you how we can
make it even more concise.
So instead of creating an entirely
new NumbersClickListener class
in a completely new file,
we can actually declare it in line
when we're calling the set
OnClickListener method.
So now I'm going to replace
what I just put in here,
this new NumbersClickListener
with OnClickListener and remember
the NumbersClickListener implemented
from the OnClickListener class.
Now, I'm going to add an open brace and
go ahead and
implement the OnClick method,
right here in line.
So no extra Java class would be needed.
Now I can put anything I
want in the onClick method.
I can display a toast or make it open
the numbers activity or anything else.
So given that, let's add some code
to open the numbers activity.
And if you remember the code from
before, we can create a new intent and
call start activity on that intent.
And let's see what that looks like,
remember to pay close attention
to the closing braces, parenthesis and
semicolons at the end of each sentence.
So it's very common place to
miss one but luckily in studio,
remember that if you click on a brace,
it'll highlighted its brace partner.
Now I'm going to go back and
delete the NumbersClickListener file
because it's not going
to be used anywhere now.
I've essentially moved that
code into my main activity.
What we learned before is equivalent
to this new way of creating click
listeners, and hear the same three steps
in a shorter number of lines of code.
For the most part,
I always set up my click listeners
this way, in line as they're needed.
It makes the code easier to read
because the logic of the click listener
is close by the view as
opposed to in a separate file.
Of course, there are always cases
when this isn't that ideal.
But if you have a click listener that is
used in many places across your code,
then you don't have to keep copy and
pasting the same block of code
in different files in your app.
Now, it's your turn.
Within the main activity file, attach
click listeners to each of the category
views for numbers, phrases,
colors and family members.
The to click listeners in line,
as we showed you most recently, and
we've included the code for
you to use as a reference.
Good luck.