Having done this, what we,
let's see, what have we done so far?
Well what we've done is,
we've figured out the best possible
line in sort of two dimensions.
Okay?
Well great except what if, a, suppose
my features are not in two dimensions?
Okay.
And also,
I've been sort of assuming that
I could actually draw a line.
Well, what if my categories
are not linearly separable?
All right, and hm, what if I have
more than just two categories?
Well, what we're going to do is,
we're going to knock down
those questions one at a time,
going forward for SBMs.
So we're going to start with, what if
the features are not two-dimensional?
Okay?
Well actually,
nothing about what I showed you in
the math required that it be 2D, right?
W.X. I didn't tell you that
X has to be two dimensional.
No, it can be any dimensional.
Or D dimensional, N dimensional,
whatever you want.
It just basically,
you're now instead of using a line
you're creating a hyperplane.
The math is exactly the same because
remember a plane is set, remember how
a line was defined, in fact so,
in 2D a line was defined by the normal.
Well in 3D,
oh this is going to be priceless,
a plane is defined by the normal, right.
So as long as they have this normal W,
I'm getting a plane.
In 3D, it's a real plane.
In ND, it's an M minus one hyper plane.
But other than that all
the math is the same.
And in fact, using just that
machinery you can actually do some
pretty cool stuff in computer vision.