Next, you'll learn about
querying conferences and
it's helpful to have several
conferences to query.
So, I'm going to create a few and
you can do the same.
So the only required field for a
conference is Name, but we'll generally
specify other fields, so that we have
more interesting things to query.
So far, we haven't an implement that
any functionality to true conferences.
We can use the data store admin
interface to check that our conferences
got created.
Next, will be implementing the query
conferences function to get conferences.
You already know how to get an entity
out of the datastore by key,
but for conferences,
we don't know the key,
because we let app engine
allocate the key for us.
So we'll be querying for conferences.
So, one thing you can do
is you can query by kind.
In which case,
you'll get all entities of that kind.
Note that this q here, this variable
is actually a query object and
not the result of a query.
To fetch a single result out of
a query object, you call q.get.
To fetch all the results,
you call q.fetch.
And to fetch say, only five results,
you called q.fetch 5.
You can also use a query object
as a standard iterator in Python.
Another thing you can do is put an order
on the query instance by naming
a particular field.
You can also add filters
before you fetch the results.
So for instance, if we wanted to fetch
only conferences occurring in February,
we could do it just like that.
So let's first, implement this simple
way to display all conferences and
worry about the filters later when
you get this first step done.
First, you will need to add a new end
point definition for query conferences.
And as you hopefully remember from
the getProfile on setProfile endpoints,
you'll need ProtoRPC message classes for
the request and the response.
There are some big differences, though.
With get and set profile, you're
always working with just one entity,
one user's profile.
But when you're dealing
with conferences,
you can have several filters and a query
can return a list of conferences.
So you already have an outgoing
ConferenceForm ProtoRPC message class
for single conference.
But since you need to send several
conferences, we'll also need
a ConferenceForms message with
a repeated field to contain them.
The same applies to query filters.
A single filter will go into
ConferenceQueryForm and
several in ConferenceQueryForms for
response.
So, I've provided some code
to help you implement this.
Take a look in lesson slash four
Additions in the files marked TODO_2.
After you've successfully implemented
the query conference's endpoint,
you should both be able to use
it in the APS explorer and
in the web front-end as well as
long as you don't use filters.
So check off each of these
steps as you complete them and
then put in your app ID here.