All right, you're done!
Let me show you what I did.
So the first thing I did
was create some new themes.
I created an AppTheme.Main and
AppTheme.Details.
And those are both
derived from AppTheme.
And I have put them in the main
styles just so I can keep them there.
And I'm mostly keeping this stuff out
just because it's nice to keep all this
v21 stuff out of the old,
old Android Stuff.
So then we go to v21, and
I have actually created
these styles now with name.
Just turning
windowContentTransitions on, and
then details referencing these enter and
return transitions.
Which look a lot like
the ones that I showed you.
So if we look at our transitions we
actually now have transition resources.
As you can see we have two different
kinds of transitions, one for
v21 and one for
landscape v21 which is pretty cool.
So, in the case that we are in
non-landscape it's
pretty straight forward.
It's exactly what I showed you before.
We're ordering them together.
It's a half second long,
we're going to fade everything that's
not the status bar and nav bar.
We're going to slide
the toolbar from the top,
and we're going to slide the additional
pane in from the bottom.
So very, very straightforward.
And for landscape, the only difference
is we're going to slide the additional
pane in from the right,
because that looks a lot nicer.
Then for the return transition,
we slide that one out from
the bottom in the case of portrait.
And in landscape, we slide it off right.
So, very, very straightforward there,
in terms of adding the transition set.
And then the only question really is,
where do we actually go to
kick off our animation?
And, of course, a good spot for
that is in MainActivity.
MainActivity knows a lot
about what's going on, but
it also is a thing that actually
is responsible for launching this.
MainActivity, if we're
not in two pane mode,
is actually responsible for
launching that next activity.
And we just call ActivityOptionsCompat,
makeSceneTransitionAnimation and
then start the activity.
And we are done.
And we have a very,
very simple transition.