So, we actually just learned some interesting lessons.
The probability of any random variable Y can be written as
probability of Y given that some other random variable X assumes value i
times probability of X equals i,
sums over all possible outcomes i for the (inaudible) variable X.
This is called total probability.
The second thing we learned has to do with negation of probabilities.
We found that probability of not X given Y is 1 minus probability of X given Y.
Now, you might be tempted to say "What about the probability of X given not Y?"
"Is this the same as 1 minus probability of X given Y?"
And the answer is absolutely no.
That's not the case.
If you condition on something that has a certain probability value,
you can take the event you're looking at and negate this,
but you can never negate your conditional variable
and assume these values add up to 1.