Here are my answers for
the function names.
And as you can see, most of these are
named in a pretty straightforward way.
It's almost a one-to-one
mapping with the requirements
that we saw in the interactions here.
As for the return types, getRequestToken
should return the request token,
which is a string, and
the same applies for getSessionID.
Then for getting the UserID we should
return an integer because that's what
the UserID is represented as.
For getting movies by search String or
getting favorite movies, or
even getting our watchlist movies,
each of these three functions
all return an array of movies, and
so you can see the brackets here and
then the TMBDMovie object
is what should be returned.
And then in final two POST functions,
postToFavorites and postToWatchlist,
we should return the status code
indicating whether the post succeeded or
not, and the status code is
represented as an integer.
Again, all these answers
are not absolute.
This is just my design
approach to the API methods.
We'll use these functions as we
implement the Movie Manager, but
as you build apps, feel free to create
and to tweak API clients over time,
until you have something
that's usable and awesome.