>> One thing that comes up when doing filtering is what to do
about the boundaries,
because you might ask what happens when your filter falls off the edge.
>> What happens when your filter falls off the edge?
>> Meghan has been rehearsing this all week, outstanding.
Well, basically it's undefined until you define it.
All right?
So you have to think about what size operation you want, so
that can be illustrated like this.
Okay?
And here we're going to use a little bit of old MatLab nomenclature,
they've changed it, because the old MatLab nomenclature actually makes it clear.
So, here I've got a function f and I'm filtering it with g.
And you might try to think about well, what's the size output that I want.
And there's sort of three different possible sizes.
One is when g just touches that corner, I start to get a response.
So if I think of the center point of g as the reference,
I would actually get a box that's bigger than the original function.
Okay.
The flip side is if I want to make sure that all of g is actually touching f,
then I'm going to, again using the center point,
I end up with a smaller output than the original.
And that, that's used to be referred to as valid,
since all those points were in fact correct.
But the problem is when I filter a 55 by 55 image,
I'd really want to get back a 55 by 55.
I don't want to get back a 58 by 58 or a 52 by 52.
What I want is referred to as the same.
So here you see that we put that filter with its middle at the corners and
we get back the same size.
So the problem of course,
is what's underneath these pixels here that are sticking out?
And basically when you do filtering,
you have to tell the system what you want there.