So let's recap our current knowledge
schema of where you're are and
how we got here.
So we started off by defining a schema
and then creating the contract class.
And then using this contract class
you are able to write the PetDbHelper
which is a class that provides
a connection to a database by returning
this database object.
This class also helps create a database
if one doesn't already exist.
Using the SQLiteDatabase object we learn
that we can call various CRUD methods,
so the create, read,
update, and delete methods.
So far you've learned about the insert
method which is used to update data and
the query method,
which is used to read out data.
So the query method takes
in quite a few parameters.
And the three that we focused on were
projection, selection and selectionArgs.
You remember,
projection allows us to specify
what columns we're interested in.
And the selection and
selectionArgs helped us to specify
what rows we're interested in.
In our query method returned
back to us this cursor.
So let's see how the query method and
cursor object of returns fits into
our existing knowledge schema.
So the SQLiteDatabase object
can call the query method,
which we learned returns the cursor.
And this cursor can be passed back
the UI to be used or displayed.
So given what we just learned
about the query method and
the cursor object looking at
the current set of the app,
we notice that it's not printing out
any of that information we got back.
Well, this is because we've
only received the cursor, but
we haven't set up any way to display
any information from it just yet.
So our goal at the end of lesson 2 is
to be able to print out the information
about the pets in your database in
a text view in the catalog activity.
So, to get started,
let's take a look at an example of how
to get information from that cursor.
And I've written out some code
linked in there just below and
let's take a closer look at that.
So, if we will take that block of while
code and execute it on our pets table,
here's what that would look like.
Now, by default,
the cursor starts at Position -1,
then when we enter the while loop,
the first call moveToNext and
this moves cursor to position 0.
So this takes us to the first row of the
database and move to next, we'll return
back to as true, because the cursor
has moved to a valid position.
Now once we are in the body of the loop,
we can do some operations
on the values in the row.
So we do so using our two different
get type methods here, our getIn and
getString and both of these take in
column indices which we saw explained in
an earlier video.
So in this case we're using both of
these methods to get the idea and
the name from this row.
So getting back 1 and Toto.
And then once you're done with this row,
the loop will move out and repeat itself
calling moveToNext again and
visually, this is what it looks like.
So the cursor will continue to
move on to the next row until all
the statements in the loop repeat for
that row.
So here again, moving down.
Move to next will return true because
the cursor could again move to a valid
position.
And you can see as the while loop
continues to move through all
the rows in our cursor.
So the while loop continued to move
our cursor through the positions and
executing these lines of code until
we get to this last row here.
Now after the statement is
complete on this last row
moveToNext is called one more time and
the cursor will try to move, but notice
that it moves to an invalid position.
And when this happens,
moveToNext returns false because
there is no next row to move to.
And this means the loop can stop.
So I removed the old try finally block,
the one right below the query method,
and replaced it with
the code from the gist.
Now what this code essentially
does is first it gets a text view,
then it prints out how many pets
there are and then it prints ID and
pet name as headers.
Afterwards it cycles through all the
pets in the cursor to get their ID and
names and then appends the information
to the text in the text view.
Lastly, it makes sure that
the cursor is closed and
it does so to avoid any memory leaks.
Now here's what the app looks
like when it's running.
And I've gone ahead and
input at four different pets already in.
Notice that it just shows the id and
name of each pet.
So let's see exactly how this
was accomplished in the code So
that you can go ahead and
complete the exercise for this topic.
So starting off, you already have
a text view in the catalogue activity.
The one that we have here in res
layout and catalogue activity.
So this text view here.
And we can go ahead and
find it using find view by id to
get a reference to that text view.
Next, we set the text of the text view
to show how many pets are stored in
the cursor, in this line here.
And then after this,
we use the pen command in order to
keep adding text to the text view.
So, what we add to it,
is the name column and id column.
So common pattern we're
looking through cursors is to
use a while loop like
the one we have here.
Doing so, helps us move through all
the information in the cursor and
let see exactly how that's done now.
So in this code, outside the while loop,
we first get the column indices for
the idColumn and the nameColumn.
Now in the while loop,
I use getString and
getID in order to get the name and
the ID.
After which I append these
values to the text view.
As I noted before,
you should always close your cursor.
So this is the purpose
of using this try block.
So it surrounds the code
that uses the cursor.
And once this codes completes,
this finally clause here is called and
the cursor is closed.
Now if for some reason a code crashes,
the cursor will also be closed.
And this is because with
the try-catch block
the finally clause always happens
whether or not the program crashes.
So what we've set up here is not the
complete UI for this lesson just yet.
I want you to practice using
the cursor and complete the UI for
this lesson by printing the rest of
the pet information that we see.
So I want you to print out the remaining
breed, gender, and weight.
So let's put all that to
practice in this exercise.
I'd like you to modify the catalog
activity by replacing the code that
displays the cursor count with
the code provide in the gist below.
So once you call
the SQLite query method,
read the pet attributes from
from the cursor returned and
then display the pet attributes in
a text view in the catalog activity.
All attributes of the pet should
be shown in the text view.
And it's okay if you have different pets
in your database compared to what you
see here.
So to recap, you're going to
update your catalog activity so
that rather then just displaying
the number of rows in our database,
the code provided in the gist will allow
us to see information about the pets
from each row.