Now there's a small problem when
I actually try to rub this code.
Let me write a message.
I'm going to go ahead and press send.
Now, over here in the database,
I'm going to click on the database tab.
If everything worked out,
I should be seeing my message here.
But there's still nothing.
Nada, no.
Okay, so something's wrong.
If you go back to your app and
look at the Android monitor,
it'll provide a clue I'm looking
here at the Warn level of messages.
So if we look at this last
message here it says,
it tries to set the value at this
point that's seems reasonable.
But database error permission denied.
Looking back at our database
there's another clue up here.
It tells me that the default security
rules require users to be authenticated.
Now this is referring to
the security rules field for
our database,
which can be access right here.
This rules here,
are used to determine which users can
access what information in the database.
There´s a rule for handling who
can read from the database and
a rule for
who can write to the database.
Now, by default, the rules are set so
that users can read and write from
the database, only if they are
authenticated, also known as logged in.
But you haven't even implemented
the login functionality yet, so
it's actually impossible to
get to a state of the app
where your user can read or write.
Now we're going to talk quite a bit
more about authentication and
these rules later on.
For now, I'm going to change these
rules so that we can experiment and
actually get a write working.
So I'm going to set my read and
write to true.
And I'll go ahead and press publish.
This allows anyone using the app
to read and write to the database.
Okay, I want to emphasize that you
should never set these rules to true for
a production application.
Setting these rules to true makes
it possible for a savvy user
with a bit of programming experience to
basically do anything to your database.
That includes reading the entire
database, which might have
sensitive information about users,
or erasing all of the data in it.
So because of that, setting read and
write to true is for
development purposes only.
And we could see here
that after publishing,
Firebase is giving me a little warning.
But for now let's see if changing these
rules allowed me to actually write to
the database.
I'm going to go ahead and
try to send another message.
Okay so I set my message and
now going over to the database tab
I can see that I actually have
a message's location, and
I can expand that out and
see that my message was saved.
Congratulations, you just wrote
your first data to the database,
isn't that cool.
>From now on this messages
node will exist and
it'll contain a list of
individual message notes.
This messages node here, is the database
reference that we are referencing here.
And if I go and
make a few more messages,
we can see here at the database, they
are listed out under the messages note.
And if we're using Firebase Vocabulary,
each of these messages could be
considered a child of the messages and
you'll also notice that there is
a random sequence of letters and
numbers associated with each message.
Recall that every time data
is pushed to the database.
A unique ID is created as a key for
that data.
This allows me to type
the same message twice and
then, in the database, be able to
differentiate between the two messages.
Now, under these unique keys, you'll
find the actual message data itself.
Each message consists of a text key
value pair and a name key value pair.
Right now,
all messages show our name as anonymous,
because we haven't been
authenticating users.
You'll learn how to
authenticate users shortly,
when we actually talk
about authentication.
For now,
we'll just have to remain anonymous.
So right now, you're effectively sending
messages from the app to the database.
The next task is actually to read these
messages and display them in the app.