A bitonic split gives us a natural
divide and conquer scheme for
sorting any bitonic sequence.
Let's see how.
Given an input sequence, split it.
That means you pair
elements from each half.
In this case there are 32 inputs, so
you'll pair elements that
are 16 away from one another.
Here's the logical pairing.
Here are the mins and
here are the maxes.
That ends the first splitting step.
The result is two bitonic
subsequences each of length 16.
You can then repeat this
process on each subsequence.
Start the splitting by pairing elements
that are eight away from each other.
First pair, then take mins,
then take maxs.
That leaves you with four bitonic
subsequences, each of length eight.
And you'll just repeat this
process until you run out of pairs
What you just did is
called a bitonic merge.
That is you started with a bitonic
sequence as input and you sorted it.
Let's write out some pseudo code.
You're given a bitonic sequence,
let's say it's of length n.
If there were at least two elements
then you do the following, again for
simplicity, let's assume that n is even.
You start by splitting the sequence.
This will give you two
bitonic subsequences.
You then merged each
of those subsequences.
Now remember that all elements of
one subsequence are less than or
equal to all elements of the other.
That makes them independent.
Therefore you can spawn one of them.