I hope you found this
calculation to be a no brainer.
[NOISE] Okay, so
here's the answer that I came up with.
1.4 million computers.
So, how did I get that?
Well, 10 trillion is ten to the 13th.
That's the number of synapses.
Each synapse needs 24 bytes.
And that's for 1% of the brain, so
to get 100% we multiply by 100 so
that's the total storage
required by the model.
Now each workstation had 16 GiB of RAM,
and 16 GiB, as it turns out,
is 2 to the 34th bytes, so
dividing this by 2 to the 34th,
you should get something
like 1.4 million machines.
So, how many computers is that?
A heck of a lot.
The super computer with the largest
number of compute nodes is probably
Sequoia, which is an IBM machine
at Lawrence Livermore lab.
That's of June 2014.
The sequoia machine has
about 98,000 nodes.
So what if we took
a look at data centers.
According to a 2012 analysis of Google's
data centers using satellite maps.
Someone with a lot of time on
their hands estimated that
all of Google's data centers might
have about 1.8 million servers.
Again that's of 2012.
So, they probably have more.
1.8 million just barely big
enough to hold the whole problem.
Hey that's huge.