As you might have guessed, we want to use normalized cross correlation.
This correlates the template t over the signal s and
returns a normalized set of values.
You can find out the maximum value in this result set using the max function.
This corresponds to the best match location.
When given two output arguments max can actually return the index of
the max value as well.
Isn't that what we wanted?
Let's look at the result.
So we see that the returned index is seven.
But the correct answer should be five.
What happened?
The correlation function actually starts comparing from the first point of
overlap between the template and the signal.
Here the template has three elements.
So comparison starts where the third element overlaps with
the first element of the signal.
And the window moves from that point forward til the end and beyond.
The operation stops at the last point of overlap.
Let's look at the values of c to figure out if this is really the case.
We use the same trick here to display column numbers, and
let's comment out other output code for clarity.
As we can see here, we have 16 values.
Our signal had 14.
The first two coefficients are from positions where the template was
partially outside the signal.
Therefore, index three, which is the length of the template corresponds to
the first position in the signal.
We have to account for this offset when returning index value.
One way to think about this is that the index value returned by
max is the rawIndex.
In order to get the correct index,
we need to subtract the size of the template and add one.
Let us restore our original output lines and look at the output.
Now we have the correct index, five.
This is the starting position of the template found in the signal.
Let's try a different template.
All right.
As expected, the template is found at position seven.
Note that we are not constrained by templates that have exact matches.
For instance, we can try a template that only partially occurs in the signal.
Quite impressive.
The template is found in the correct position, even though there is a mismatch.
A partial mismatch would result in a correlation coefficient that is
less than one.
But it might still be the maximum across all other elements.