So here is the example of dual photography we looked at before where,
illuminated a scene with the computer controlled projector that
basically opened the aperture in different ways, and
then we got a modulated aperture in front of the camera to figure out how which
which light source was related to what parts of the image will be updated.
Now remember again, these are the elements of photography,
we have a 3D scene and a user, and these are the five phases in between,
where we have Illumination, optics, sensor, processing, and display.
In the case of dual photography,
what basically we know that we control the illumination, so that's what
computational is involved, optics are controlled a bit here and basically how
we control the aperture, both sides, but more on the camera side here.
Sensor is being used as is right now, but you can control that also, and
then of course image that is actually computed from a series of
things as process and then displayed to [INAUDIBLE] limit.