want to see something cool?
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
Let me show you how come they got their
paper on the cover, I think It was
the ACM, I think it was the journal,
the journal of ACM, but I forget.
They had the cover picture
of a journal and here's why.
Here's a picture of an apple, okay?
Beautiful picture of an apple.
Here's a picture of an orange and
I'm going to tell you it's not
just any picture of an orange.
You'll notice that this apple
is in front of some pencils.
This orange is in front
of some other pencils.
kind of same colored background, and
you'll notice they're the same size, and
that's because they've been
scaled to be the same size.
Using the Laplacian pyramid stuff,
I can make this picture.
Okay, now if Megan could see this
picture, Megan would be going, wow,
how did they do that?
>> Wow, how did they do that?
>> Okay, first of all,
I hope you are too, it's pretty cool.
It's half orange, half apple,
and it blends, and
you can't see any seams, all right?
And the way they did that is,
they built a Laplacian pyramid, so
this is the coarser scales,
this is the original Laplace scale.
The coarser, coarser, and they just seam
together, each one of the, the pyramids,
by just a single pixel, but at the small
size, not at the, not at the expanded
size, so at the very small one, they
took half of the left, the left half of
the apple, the right half of the orange
and they just blended the middle row.
Then they expand that, okay?
Take the Laplacian here,
Laplacian there, combine that,
add in with single row,
you do that all the way down,
and what you've done is you've blended
the, the low frequencies over a larger
range of the image, and the high
frequencies over a smaller range and
you make this magic apple orange thing,
and that's how you get yourself on
the cover of the transactions
on ACM Transactions on graphics.
Cool, right?