But there's a problem with rejection sampling.
If the evidence is unlikely, you end up rejecting a lot of the samples.
Let's go back to the alarm network where we had variables for burglary and for an alarm
and say when arrested, in computing the probability of a burglary,
given that the alarm goes off.
The problem is that burglaries are very infrequent,
so most of the samples we would get would end up being--
we start with generating a B, and we get a -b and then a -a.
We go back and say does this match?
No, we have to reject this sample,
so we generate another sample, and we get another -b, -a.
We reject that. We get another -b, -a.
And we keep rejecting, and eventually we get a +b,
but we'd end up spending a lot of time rejecting samples.
So, we're going to introduce a new method called likelihood weighting
that generates samples so that we can keep every one.
With likelihood weighting, we fix the evidence variables.
That is, we say that A will always be positive,
and then we sample the rest of the variables,
so then we get samples that we want.
We would get a list like -b, +a,
-b, +a,
+b, +a.
We get to keep every sample, but we have a problem.
The resulting set of samples is inconsistent.
We can fix that, however, by assigning a probability
to each sample and weighing them correctly.