When we put an app on
the Google Play store.
We'll have a whole range of users.
It's hard to anticipate, what type of
device our app will be running on.
Maybe a phone or a tablet, maybe an
older version of the Android platform,
or maybe a different language
than what we're using.
There are many best practices that you
can follow when building your app.
To make it work well for
all these types of users.
One best practice,
is to localize your app.
There's a handy localization
checklist that you can refer to.
Localization means, adapting your
app to different locales else.
Meaning language and country
combinations to make it a positive
user experience for all types of users.
At the surface level, this can have
an impact on the design of your app,
as well, as the texturing
that appear in your app.
For now, we're going to focus
on how we can make your
app support different languages.
First, let's look at the device
experience from a user's perspective.
If I prefer to use a different language,
I can go into the Settings app and
then tap on the Language
an Input setting.
If I tap on Language,
then I see the whole list of languages
that are supported on Android.
It includes character based
language,s like Chinese and
right to left languages like Arabic.
I'm going to change
the language to Spanish, and
just like that all the text
is now showing up in Spanish.
You can see this across
the whole Settings app.
If you check the other apps on
the device those will appear in Spanish,
if the developer chose to
support that language.
However, when you open
up our Just Java app,
it's a jarring experience
because everything in this
app is still in English, while the other
apps in the device are in Spanish.
So how do we make our
app support Spanish?
So far, we know that our app can
contain Java files and Resources.
We can provide default resources for our
app, but we can also provide alternate
resources depending on the user's
physical device size, language setting,
version of Android, or number of
pixels on the screen, to name a few.
In our gesture shove app, we can
provide default text rings in English.
We can provide alternate text
strings in other languages.
So if someone has French as
a default language on their device,
the system will automatically
load the French Translations
instead of the default English ones.
This article explains how you can
support multiple languages in an app.
Scrolling down we can look
at the project structure.
Within the res directory you can
add another subdirectory that
contains resources for
a certain language.
This is the default values folder and
when choosing to put all
the English text strings here.
In the values es folder,
we have all the Spanish text strings.
In the values dash fr folder,
we have all the French translations.
If the user chooses Spanish as
a language on their device,
then the system will load these
resources from the values es folder.
If this folder don't exist,
then the system which is fallback
to the default resources.
If the user has French as a default
language on their device,
then the system will
load these resources.
By the way es is the language code for
Spanish and fr is the language code for
French.
Android uses the ISO language codes.
Here are some examples of languages.
And the two letter language
codes that correspond with them.
Let's go back to implementation details.
In order for the system to switch out
different translations for the text in
our app, we need to isolate all the text
from all the other logic in our app.
We do this by creating a string
set XML file in the values folder.
This is an XML resource file
that contains a list of
all the string resources that
are visible to the user.
This is the first time we're
seeing XML be used for
something other than defining a layout.
This is defining a list of resources.
This is one string resource, and
the name that we used to refer to it
is called Title and the value of
this string is my application.
This is another string resource and
we referred to it using,
hello underscore world and
the actual value is hello world.
Then in the values es folder we can
create a strings dot xml file, but
now these have the Spanish
translations of those same strings.
This string resource still goes by
the name of title, like here, but
now the value is the Spanish
translation of my application.
The same applies for
the hello world string resource with
the Spanish translation here now.
And this is one more example of the
French translations of the strings dot
xml file.
Once our strings
are declared as resources,
we can then refer to them in the XML or
Java using the appropriate syntax.
In the Java code,
we refer to strings like this.
In the Java code, this is how
we reference string resources.
Firs,t we call the method getResources
to get the apps resources.
And then, we call getString and we pass
as input the resource ID of the string.
In this case, it's R dot string
dot hello underscore world.
String is a resource type and
hello underscore world is
the name of the resource.
All of these on the right hand side,
ends up becoming the hello world string
and it's stored in this string variable.
This whole expression evaluates to hello
world and gets stored in this variable.
By the way,
this is similar to how we refer to
image resources in the Java code.
You can add dot drawable dot photo or
whatever, the name of the image is.
In the XML, we can refer to the strings
using the add string notation and
then the name of the string resource.
Now, the XML and
the Java code can stay the same,
regardless of what language the user
has chosen on their device.
We don't need a different layout file
that has the Spanish translation for
the text attribute here.
Android will load the correct
translations depending on the primary
language selected on the device.
It's pretty awesome?
Let's walk through each of these steps,
so
that you can see how to localize
the strings in your app.
First, we want to extract all
the hardcoded strings from the XML and
Java files into a default
strings dot xml file.
Then we're going to update the XML and
Java files to refer to
the appropriate string resources.
And then, we're going to provide
alternate translations in
another language.
Let's start with step one:
interactivity main layout.
Let's look at the strings that are
currently hard coded into our layout.
We have a text view that displays
the word toppings as a header in the ui.
Currently the English word is
hard coded into the layout, and
we even get a warning from
Android studio talking about it.
And it recommends that we use a at
string resource, so let's do that now.
When I delete this and
then type in @string/toppings
as the name of the resource.
But now, I get an error saying that
Android Studio doesn't recognize
this resource.
I need to go into the strings
dot xml file and define it.
Looking at the file
structure of our app,
I can go into the res values folder and
look for the strings dot xml file.
There are a couple of strings that
are already populated here and
I'm going to add another one.
I just declared a new string
resource with the name toppings and
the value is the English word for
toppings.
The name of the string resource
isn't going to change.
But that chance added value will
change depending on the language.
Notice, that I added a comment here to
describe where the string is being used
in app.
This will help the translator or the
translation service who's helping out,
to understand the context in which
this string is being used in our app.
We also specify a character limit.
This is also helpful for the translator,
when space in the UI is limited.
For example, the translator won't
pick a really long translation
if they understand that we have
limited screen real estate.
Going back to our layout file,
now the error is gone because
the string resource exists.
Now, how about hard coded
strings within our Java files?
Let's take a look at our
create order summary method,
which has a bunch of English
strings hard coded in.
Let's start by moving the phrase,
thank you to the strings dot xml file.
And, here's a new string resource
with the name thank underscore you.
Then we can update the Java statement,
to refer to the new string
resource by its name.
We're using the getString method
within the activity class,
which takes as input a string
resource and returns a string.
The thank you string is then
added on to this whole message.
In certain cases, you might not want
to translate part of a text string.
For example,
you might want to create a string and
then leave spots that can be
filled in later with variables.
In that case, you want to mark off
the spots that shouldn't be translated
with an x lift tag.
It wouldn't make sense to
translate the user's name, but
it would make sense to translate name.
S,o when used properly this whole string
resource would show up as named colon
and then the person's name like Amy.
With the x lift tag,
you give it an id which is name and
then you can specify
an example like Amy.
Inside the xliff tags, you would put
the string that shouldn't be translated.
In this case, where using
the percent s formatter symbol,
which specifies that a string will
be substituted in here later.
If you're wondering why we don't just
add the strings using the plus symbol in
the Java code.
The reason is because declaring
it as a string resource
allows the translator to decide if
this is the right format for the text.
The translator may decide to flip
the order of some of these words so
that it makes more sense
in the local context.
The translator only has control over
the words in the strings dot xml file.
They don't have control
over the Java code.
For the xliff tag to be
recognized you also want to
add this thing to the resources
tag in your strings dot xml file.
Now, the Java code we're going to
replace this part of the order summary
with our string resource.
Now, we're using the order
summary name string resource and
we're filling in the blank
using the name variable.
Normally, this gets string
method in the activity
would take as argument one input,
which is just the string resource.
But now it takes into arguments, because
we want to pass in the name variable and
have that be inserted into
the blank spot in this string.
If your string resource had two
spots that needs to be filled and
then you would pass in two
additional inputs here, so
that would be a total of three
inputs to the method call.
And so on from there.
If you want any more clarification on
how to use xliff tags, you can check
the Localization Checklist, which is
linked in the instructor notes below.
So far, we've covered these two steps,
and now we're going to look at providing
alternate translations
in another language.
So in Android Studio,
there's actually a neat little tool
called the translations editor.
You can access it by clicking on
Open editor or you can right click
on the strings dot xml file and
then click on open translations editor.
There's a column for
the name of the string resource, and
then the default value, which is
the English translation right now.
Each row corresponds to another string
resource that we defined in our strings
dot xml file.
If we click on the globe icon here,
we can add a new language.
I type Spanish and add Spanish.
You can click on the cell here to
provide the Spanish translation for
the string resource thank you.
I'm going to type in gracias,
which means thank you in
my terrible Spanish accent.
We can do the same for
our toppings header, and
this is the Spanish translation.
I'm not even going to
try to pronounce that.
Now, let's rebuild our app.
My device still has Spanish
as a default language.
And when I open up our app,
wow I see that the toppings
header is translated in Spanish.
The rest is still in English
because I haven't finished it yet.
And then, when I click on the order
button, then I see Gracias.
It's awesome, that it worked.
Behind the scenes the translation
editor did a couple of things for us.
It created the Spanish version
of the strings dot xml file.
When you click on that you can
see that it automatically added
the translations in.
If we didn't provide
Spanish translations,
then it doesn't appear here.
As a developer, you have the option of
modifying the strings file directly or
using the translations editor.
If you want to add more languages, you
can simply click on the globe icon here.
Cool you have just finished
all three steps for
localizing a couple of
strings into Spanish.
Now, there are a few other hard
coded strings that we missed, but
this time, I'd like you to take
the lead in localizing them.
You'll find Spanish translations for
these text strings in
the instructor notes below.
But you're welcome to pick
another language of your choice.
At the end, your app should look like
this assuming that you chose Spanish.
And then when you hit the order button,
the email subject line and
the message body are both in Spanish.