Now that Friendly Chat is
connected to the database,
let's write code to
send a message to it.
If we think when our app is running,
the best time to send a message would be
as soon as the send
message button is tapped.
There's already an action wired up for
this called, did send message.
That's what I'm looking at
now in the FCViewController.
This function calls text
field should return, and
it resets the message
text field back to empty.
All right, there's our starting point.
Let's go a little bit deeper by diving
into the text field should return
function and see what's happening there.
In text field should return,
assuming the text field isn't empty.
We see the messages packaged
into a data dictionary.
And then passed along to another
function called send message.
Our data dictionary consists of
a key which identifies the text
we're wanting to send.
And then the value is the actual string
itself contained in our text field.
Let's keep following along
the path through the code and
see what send message is doing.
Aha, the send message function is empty.
This is where we need to add the code
to push the message to the database.
To do this, we'll use the database
reference that we made earlier.
If we think about the database
structure, the reference that we've made
starts at the topmost part,
or the root of the JSON.
We're able to walk on in the JSON
by using the child method.
For example, if I were to call
ref.child and past messages,
that's like specifying the node
of the path /messages.
If we recall the example
structure we saw earlier,
we want to store each message
as a child of messages,
using some kind of unique
identifying string for each message.
So how would we achieve this?
Let me go ahead and remove that code.
And let's focus in on the mechanism for
achieving this, childByAutoId.
This function generates a unique key
that's prefixed with the time stamp, so
the resulting list of messages that we
have, will be chronologically sorted.
So in our case, we'd be specifying
a path that looks like /messages/ some
auto generated unique id.
And that's exactly what we want.
It ensures that the path is unique,
and that the database will be able to
distinguish between messages,
even if they contain the same text.
And then once we have
our path constructed,
we can set a value at the path
using the set value function.
For this, we could pass in
the data argument directly, but
let's tweak the data a little bit first.
Let's also add a display
name to the data, so
that when we set the value at this path,
it includes the actual
text of the message, plus the display
name of the user who sent it.
So to do this, we've created a copy
of our data called end-data.
And then we've added a key value
pair where the key is name,
and the value is our display name.
And then we pass M data to
the set value function.
And this is what writes
the message to the database.
Okay, let's run the app again to see
if our message will actually send.
I'll send hello as our test message.
Well, that didn't work.
In the debug error,
we see that the app has been denied
permission to set value or remove value.
We're not permitted to
write to the database.
That's not good.
What's the problem?
If you go to the Database
tab in the Firebase Console,
which we selected over here.
You'll notice that the message also
didn't populate in the database.
So what do we do?
Well, it's just so happens that the
database uses a set of rules to control
how the database can be viewed and
changed.
And this is for our own good.
We'll look how to
modify this rules next.