Here's the number I came up with.
3200 gigaops, or
3.2 trillion operations per second.
Let's see how I got there.
In 10 years there will be 5 doublings.
5 doublings is a 2 to the 5th,
or 32x increase in performance.
So a 2025 processor,
relative to a 2015 processor will
run at 32x100 or 3,200 gigaops.
Wow, that is fast.
I mean really fast.
As a point of reference,
suppose I gave you three
trillion pennies, head to tail.
Those would go around
the Earth about 30 times.
That's a [BLEEP] ton of pennies.
In fact, you might already know or have
experience with specialized processors
that, even in 2015, are capable of
trillions of operations per second.
The point of this exercise is to
give you an intuitive feel for
peak performance and the rate of
growth that exponential trends bring.
When you think about it, the numbers and
scale we're talking about
should really blow your mind.