In lesson three, we wrote
the rock paper scissors app, and
we used three different techniques to
present the ResultsViewController.
One for each of these three options.
For rock it was all in Code,
for paper it was a named
Storyboard Segue, triggered using Code.
And for scissors it was a triggered
Segue attached to the button in
Storyboard.
In the Make Your Own Adventure app, the
segues have all been of this third kind.
We've attached the segues directly to
the buttons using a pop-up connections
menu and storyboard.
Automatically triggered
segues are great, but
all three of the segue techniques
are available in navigation,
the same way they are in
mobile presentation.
What would it take to reproduce the
three segues in rock, paper, scissors.
Using a NavigationController
instead of modal presentation.
In this segment,
we're asking you to do just that,
the next reading note will walk
you through the steps to do so.