So now, you've defined the code in your
application class to start tracking.
But so far, there's nothing that
triggers the startTracking method.
But, all you need to do to activate
tracking is to call the start tracking
method that you just wrote.
You can call it in
onCreate in MainActivity.
And, Activity can call getApplication
to get the application singleton for
the running app.
However, since you're using your
own subclass of application,
you need to cast the result
to your subclass.
Once you've got
the application instance,
it's a simple matter of calling
startTracking to kick off tracking.
And, you have to get your parens right.
So, go ahead and
add the code to onCreate in MainActivity
to start analytics tracking.
And, make sure your project compiles.