Here's the answer.
For the height,
if you had the top padding, content, and
bottom padding, you get 175 pixels.
For padding,
you only need to specify 50 pixels.
This cover's adding the padding
to not only the top and
bottom of the element, but
also the left and right.
Getting familiar with the short hand way
of writing CSS will help you save time
and make your code a little cleaner.
Short hand doesn't work for
every property, so
do some research on your own to
figure out when it's okay to use.
Finally, for margin,
you only need to specify 20 pixels.
Just like padding, margin behaves
the same way when writing it shorthand.
This takes care of adding 20
pixels in all four directions.
Top, bottom, left, and right.