Many phones have currency conversion
apps which are pretty useful when
you're traveling.
This exercise deals with an example one.
In this case, we're converting
US dollars into Japanese Yen.
And the rate is 1 US dollar
to 119 Japanese Yen.
And we're going to assume that
we're converting 40 dollars.
Okay.
Let's hand simulate to see if it
does what we expect.
In the first line, we're declaring and
initializing a variable called dollars,
and we're setting the value to 40.
This variable is probably storing
the amount that we're trying to convert.
Okay.
On this next line,
we have a variable called dollarsToYen.
And we're setting that to 119.
This variable probably represents
this conversion rate up here,
that $1 is 119 yen.
Next we're declaring and
initializing a variable called yen.
Now let's calculate the value
that we're initializing it to.
So here we have dollarsToYen,
which is 119.
And we're multiplying it by dollars,
which is 40.
I used a calculator for this one.
The result here is 4,760.
In the next line,
that's what we display 4,760.
So, did this do the right thing?
Well we know that $1 is 119 yen and
if we have $2 it's going to
be two times whatever $1 was.
So it'd be two times 119 and
if we had $40 it would be 40 times 119.
Which is the exact
calculation that we do here.
So it looks like, yes, this is correctly
calculating the number of yen.