Now, you just learned how to
use the SQL update command.
And using the where clause,
we saw that we can set
constraints on the objects that we
want to read or select out of a table.
And using that same where clause,
we can specify a single pet
that we want to update.
In our case,
we want to specify the pet via its id.
Now the final database operation
you need to know, involves
deleting all the pets who have been
entered into the database incorrectly.
Now a word of warning here.
It's shocking how easy it can be to
remove all the pets from the database.
So be very careful when
using this command.
So here's the code for
the delete SQL command.
And this single code here will
delete everything from the table.
So, that here reads DELETE FROM and
the table-name.
So, this is the specific
command that we'll be using for
deleting all othepets for
our pets table.
And I'll be adding it to our cheat
sheet, so that we can refer to it later
when we're building out our delete
all button for our pets app.
And to reiterate, be very careful
when you're using this command,
because it deletes all
the pets from our table.
Now if we just want to remove a single
pet that's been incorrectly entered,
we can make the command more specific
once again by using our where clause.
So just as updating, if we want to
specify a specific pet to delete,
here we use the where clause,
followed by id and
the id of the pet in the database
that we're interested in.
[BLANK_AUDIO]