So the first we're
going to look at is Load.
Whatever it is,
users want it to load quickly, and
it's super important that we optimize
for the critical rendering path.
Earlier in Cam's course, and this is
the fourth plug I've given it now,
oh I should be on some kind
of commission, seriously.
Anyway it's linked in
the instructor notes and
it will take you through
the fine details of that.
I took you through a quick tour of the
rendering process in the first lesson,
but essentially you want your initial
load to be done in one second.
Okay, I'm going to switch across
to Chrome, and I'm going to load
Google Play Music, and I suspect
it'll load in about one second.
There we go.
Now after an app's loaded,
it's normally idle, it's waiting for
a user to interact.
And this is our opportunity to
deal with things that we deferred
to meet that one second load time.
Normally, these idle blocks
are around 50 milliseconds long,
although you may several
of them in one go.
These idle blocks are fantastic times
to get some heavy lifting done so
that when the user interacts
things are nice and snappy.
I'll stop for a second and
let you think through the best way
to approach an app's idle time.