There are two primary ways of
rendering 3D environments.
You can write code, or you can use
a graphical editor based environment.
Or you could do some combination
of the two approaches.
For this nano degree, we'll be
writing code and using an editor.
For the first part, we'll be
a using a game engine called Unity.
A game engine is a software framework
that makes it easier to develop games.
The goal is to reduce iteration time.
And overhead as much as possible.
You need short iteration times.
Because so much of virtual reality
requires quick experimentation.
We simply don't know
everything about this medium.
It's too new.
Game engines often provide 3D rendering,
physics, sound,
scripting, animation asset management,
and a whole lot more.
In short, there are packages of tools
that make it easier to build games and
VR apps.
But Unity isn't the only game in town.
It's just a popular choice.
Some of the other big game
engines are Unreal Engine,
CryEngine, Lumberyard,
and many many more.
Okay, so to contrast game engines,
you can also build VR
apps using native development tools
like C++, Open GL, and DirectX.
When you pick these tools, you are
building your VR software using the raw
materials of the computer
graphics world.
Instead of using a bunch
of prepackaged tools and
a game engine, Native Development
requires you to integrate
every component you want to use.
The result is that you get much
more flexibility and it's often
with some increased performance, but
you have much longer development times.
You may choose to build a native
app when you need an extremely high
performance data intensive
simulation like Occulus Medium.
Or you might build a native app when
you need to build a framework that
others will use to build
their own VR apps, but for
most VR Developers, a game engine is
the right choice for their project.
There's also one other VR Development
option out there, web browsers.
I think the web could eventually
be a huge platform for VR.
Unfortunately, WebVR isn't currently
good enough for production use.
It's possible that in
the future this will be one
of the dominant VR platforms.
But for now, as a VR developer, our main
choice is between native development,
and using a game engine.
And for this course, we'll be
using a game engine called Unity.
Let's dive right in.