Let's look at the different ways that
a remote file service can be provided.
We will assume that there is
one client and one server.
Whereas that one extreme we have what
it is called the Upload/Download model.
This means that when the client
wants to access the file,
it downloads the entire file,
performs locally the operations and
then when done,
it uploads the file back to the server.
This is less similar to
proper file system but
it's more similar to the way
FTP servers behave or
even the way version management
systems like SVN servers behave.
The benefit of this model is that
once the client has the file,
it can perform all of the operations
locally so that can be done fast.
One downside of this model is that the
client needs to download the entire file
even for a small file access for
a small file modification.
A second downside with
this model is that it
takes away file access
control from the server.
Once the server gives
the file to the client,
it has no idea what the client is doing
with it, or when will it get it back.
This makes some operations
related to sharing files
a little bit difficult to execute.
At the other extreme,
we have a model that's called
the true remote file access.
In this model, the file remains on
the server and every single operation,
every read or every write,
has to go to the server.
In this model, the client makes
no attempt whatsoever to leverage
any kind of local buffer cache,
local disks, or anything like that.
Everything has to go to the server.
The benefits of this extreme is that
the server has full control and
knowledge of how the clients
are accessing and
modifying the shared state and
the shared files.
This makes it easier to ensure that the
state of the file system is consistent,
and that there are no situations where
multiple clients are overwriting
the same portions of the single
file at the same time.
The down side of this model is
that every single file operation
has to incur the cost of
remote network latency.
In this model,
the latency costs are suffered
even when clients are only reading
repeatedly from a read-only file.
This model will bypass any resources
that the client has locally,
to cache that file.
Also, since every single file
operation goes to the server,
the server will get
overloaded more quickly,
meaning that the single server will not
be able to support as many clients.
This limits the scalability
of the file system solution.