In Linux, you can define a reader
writer lock by using the provided
data type for reader writer locks.
To access a shared resource
using this reader writer lock,
you use the appropriate interface,
read lock or write lock.
Which one you use will clearly
depend on the kind of operation that
you want to perform in
the shared resource.
The reader writer API also provides the
corresponding unlock counterparts for
both read and write.
A few other operations are supported
on reader writer locks, but
these are the primary ones.
And if you would like to explore more,
then take a look at the .h file.
We are providing a link to it
in the instructor's notes.
Reader writer locks are supported
in many operating systems and
language run times.
In some of these contexts, the reader
writer operations are referred to as
shared locks and exclusive locks.
However, certain aspects of
the behavior of the reader writer locks
are different in terms
of their semantics.
For instance,
it makes sense to permit a recursive
read_lock operations to be invoked.
But then,
it differs across implementations, and
exactly what happens on read_unlock.
In some cases, a single read_unlock may
unlock every single one of the read_lock
operations that have recursively been
invoked from within the same thread.
Whereas in other implementations,
a separate read_unlock is required for
every single read_lock operation.
Another way in which implementations
of reader writer locks differ is
in their treatment of priorities.
For instance in some cases, a reader,
so an owner of a shared lock,
may be given a priority
to upgrade the lock.
So from a reader lock to
convert to a writer lock.
Compared to a newly arriving request for
a write lock, or an exclusive lock.
In other implementations,
that's not the case.
So the owner of a read lock
will first release it and
then try to re-acquire it with
write access permissions.
And contend with any other thread that's
trying to perform the same operation.
Another priority related
difference across
reader writer lock implementations
is what kind of interaction is there
between the state of the lock,
the priority of the threads, and the
scheduling policy in the system overall.
For instance it could block a reader so
a thread that otherwise would
have been allowed to proceed.
If there is already a writer
that has higher priority and
that is waiting on that lock.
In this case the writer is waiting
because there are other threads that
already have read access to the lock.
And if there is a coupling
between the scheduling policy and
the synchronization mechanisms,
it's possible that a newly
arriving reader will be blocked.
It will not be allowed to join the other
readers in the critical section.
Because of the fact that the waiting
writer has higher priority.