How do we actually do this?
Well, let's talk about this.
Here is a simple example,
I have a video clip here and
I'm going to use this to
generate a video texture.
Playing this video you kind of
notice that basically it
is got a lot of dynamic nature, and
of course, I'm intentionally simp,
taking simpler examples of these flames.
But you can see that this is actually
a very interesting, you know,
dynamic scene.
A video texture basically
builds from this and
it identifies transitions in
time which it loops over.
So in essence the red bar here is
showing you something interesting.
This was the time axis from zero,
to let's say whatever,
however long the video frame was.
It basically jumps from
one to the other, and
it can keep doing this in this space
to generate a Infinitely long video.
So this red dark,
basically in the time axis,
is basically flickering from one to
the other, and it's showing that it can
actually search and seek out
other examples and keep looping.
How do we generate that is what
we're going to try to get next