Let's dive into Firebase storage and
security rules by learning
about the keyword match.
The match of a rule matches
a specific storage path so
that you can apply
a rule to that location.
Every path starts with a forward slash.
Followed by a path segment.
And there are three
types of path segments.
Here's the first type of path segment.
It's called a single segment.
A single segment is a literal
reference to a single path name.
For example,
this images/profilePhoto.png matches
the specific file named profilephoto.png
in the images directory.
The second type of path segment is
called a single segment wild card.
This is a variable that can refer
to any path at that path level.
The variable name is
surrounded by curly braces.
This is often used to
match multiple file pads.
For example if you wanted to match all
files that were stored directly within
the images path you could use
this match statement here.
Two notes,
first the variable name can be anything.
Second, storage rules do not cascade
in the same way database roles do.
So for example, this rule here
would match images/lyla.jpg.
But it would not match
images/profilepictures/lyla.jpg which is
why we have the next match option which
is called the multisegment wildcard.
The multisegment wildcard matches
any number of past segments at or
below the specified path.
The syntax is almost the same as
the single segment wildcard but
it ends with a =**.
The multi-segment wildcard rule
is handy because it does
cascade to everything below it.
A multi-segment wildcard let's
you declare cascading explicitly.
In this case, if you wanted to
match both images/jarrod.jpg and
images/profilePics/lyla.jpg.
The multi segment wildcard
is the way to go.
It would even match
images/profliePics/January/User1/Puf.-
jpg.
The only constraint for matching is that
it has to start with this images path,
after that the multicard segment
wildcard will match everything.
Now that you know a little
bit more about matching and
Firebase Storage,
let's play matchmaker in this next quiz.