You've previously analyzed Phases 1 and
2.
For Phase 1 the comparisons grow like
n log Z and the transfers like n/L.
For Phase 2 the comparisons
grow like n log n/Z and
the transfers like n/L log n/Z.
Let's combine these.
The comparison terms
combine to just n log n.
That's good news.
It means the mergesort
scheme is work optimal,
relative to any other
comparison based algorithm.
What about the number
of memory transfers?
Basically, Phase 2 dominates and
you get n/L log n/z.
That's not too shabby.
To see how far you have to go it's good
to cook up some numbers for n, L, and
Z and
compare them to the known lower bound.
That lower bound turns out to be this.
I'll leave this last bit
as an exercise for you.