So far we have actually looked at
a variety of different topics, like for
example, how to use a panorama to give
you a better sense of space, actually
have a view which is much larger field
of view than usual images that you get.
We've also looked at how
to analyze videos, and
one of the specific things we've
looked at is video textures.
In this lecture, we're going to combine
both the concepts of video textures and
panorama building to create what is
referred to as panoramic video textures.
We're going to look at how we
can take a video of a scene,
use that to generate a larger
field of view of that scene, but
also incorporate in it
the dynamics of the scene,
specifically the kind of dynamics
that's captured through video textures.