So now we will look at the things
involved when registering
an AdMob account.
This type of account is needed when you
show real ads, but it's not required
during test and development,
as we've talked about before.
So this is the registration page for
an AdMob account, and
the first thing we want to do is to
sign in with our Google account.
So we sign in with our email address,
and then our password.
So now we're signed in
with our Google account.
The next thing we need to do is
to provide the information for
an AdSense and AdWords account.
These are Google products that
AdMob uses, so when you sign up for
AdMob, you also need to sign up for
these products.
So for
AdSense we will fill out the country and
territory, and whether we want
a individual or business account.
And observe that this
cannot be changed later on.
The Payee name which must
match a bank account name.
This field you may not be
able to change either, so
it's important to get it right,
and then the address
And then we click Continue.
Then we have the AdWords information.
And here we only need to fill out
the time zone and the billing currency.
And then we click Continue.
Now you need to read the program
policies and the terms and conditions.
I have already read these documents, so
I can immediately accept
these conditions.
Now, we're ready to
create our AdMob account.
And then click Get Started.
So this should now be your landing page.
And as you can see,
you now have a Publisher ID.
This ID is a unique identifier for your
AdMob account that you may use when you,
for example, contact support.