Hi there.
My name's Lyla and I'm a course developer here at Udacity.
Today I'm going to be walking you through an example of how to use a content
provider to access data from your Android device.
Of course you might be wondering what exactly is a content provider, so
before we start any of that I'm going to tell you a little bit about the joys of
content providers and
why application developers actually take the time to create them.
After that, we're going to learn how to use a standard Android content provider
to pull data from our Android device and put it on the UI.
Once we're done,
you're going to know how to use this important Android framework feature, so
let's get coding.