So here is a demonstration of
the skeleton app that was just created.
So here is our main window, and if I
click on the Interstitial Ad button,
I will launch
the Interstitial Ad activity.
You can now see that we have the two
buttons here, Load Interstitial and
Interstitial Not Ready.
The Interstitial Not Ready button
is our mShowButton member of
the Interstitial activity.
And as you can see, this is disabled
since we disabled it in our code.
Now, when I click on Load Interstitial,
you'll see that the text of this button
changes to Loading Interstitial.
Now it's your turn to implement this.
Let's see what we did.
We created two buttons in the layout
file of InterstitialActivity,
Load Interstitial and
Interstitial Not Ready.
We defined a callback for Load
Interstitial to be loadInterstitial.
And in this callback we disable
the button Interstitial Not Ready, and
we change the text of Interstitial
Not Ready to Loading Interstitial.
To be able to disable and change the
text of this button programmatically,
we need to define it as a Property or
a member of our
InterstitialActivity class.
This member had the name mShowButton.
We define the callback for
this button to be showInterstitial.
And for now, we left the implementation
of this callback empty.
We also disable this button in onCreate.
And finally, we defined the
interstitial_ad_unit_id to be this value
in our string resource file.
And remember, this value is to test
ad unit ID for interstitial ads.
Now it's your turn to
do all of these things.
And check here when you're finished.