So now let's look at the whole concept of how we can actually use
a pyramid representation.
And specifically in this form, we'll look at a Gaussian Pyramid.
That'll allow us to encode the frequencies at different levels and
let us do blending or other types of operations that basically look at
different frequencies differently.
So just to start off, let's start off with this simple eight by eight image.
All right?
So this is just a simple representation.
I'll use this to showcase what we can do with this.
But let's now go back the concept of doing simple filtering.
I'm going to run a small Gaussian kernel over this.
Let's say it's a three by three.
And my goal is to, let's take the information from the filtering process here,
for this one, and create a new image.
Except that I will just do this, to kind of replace it,
make a smaller image out of this.
So my goal is to generate a four by four image out of this.
Of course, what we can do is, now look at this, for
example, three by three neighborhood.
Run a Gaussian kernel on it, get a new value that encodes all of
the information there, and replace it in my newer image.
So using this, I can now generate a four by four image.
So in essence, what I've done is, I've basically taken every other value.
These are pointed here.
So I've basically taken these 16 values and put them here.
Except what I'd rather do is basically run a small convolution with the Gaussian
and take the value that's the resultant of all of the convolution here and
replace it in this one.
So in essence, that's what we've done here is,
we've gone from a eight by eight and generated a four by four.
We can, of course, cyclically repeat this and
generate a two by two, which is shown here.
And of course, at the end of it, what I can now do is run a kernel and
find the value at this point here, which would be the, you know,
the Gaussian kernel of these four values.
And generate a value here.
So if you notice, what we've done is, we've gone from eight by eight to four by
four, two by two, and of course, one by one.
We can of course do this for real images too.
Here is my Einstein image.
Let me refer to this as g0, basically the Gaussian at level zero.
And of course, the first one, I'm running basically a Gaussian kernel,
now actually generating an image like this.
I refer to this as g0, to refer, basically, to the concept.
This is a Gaussian at level 0, this is a Gaussian at level 1,
here of course, run through the same process, and
now this 512 by 512 image is converted into a 256 by 256 image.
And we can keep doing this.
Generate g2 with level two.
This is, of course, now a half of 256 by 256, so 128 by 128.
And then go on all the way to a small image like this.
So each one of them is referred to now as a Gaussian.
At different levels, two, three, and four.
So let's see what this representation looks like.
What I'm basically doing now is moving the smaller ones on top of
the original image.
And if I was to just draw, for example, this point here we can actually see that
in essence, what we have is a pyramid with the bottom, the highest resolution,
followed by the next higher resolution, going all the way up to this point here,
and by connecting these lines,
we basically can see that now we have is a pyramid representation.
And that's what the pyramid looks like.
So we've basically gone from information that actually was very high
resolution to low resolution and by actually doing Gaussian filtering to kind of
now scale these things up, we basically have different levels.
This was, of course, the zero, original, one, two, and three.