So I've got, I've got a question about the collector.
>> Mm-hm. >> And so I just kind of wanted to ask in more detail how it works.
>> Mm-hm. >> And, and what, for example, would be the difference for it to just,
instead of having a collector just to return a tuple for that function and.
>> If you, I mean, output collector is the only way Storm knows which to put to.
Put it into the, pass it on to the next stage.
>> So, so how does it pass it on, exactly?
>> So, like the data, the way the, when you do an image-
>> Mm-hm.
>> So once you have the image, then internally, it captures into the queues.
I mean, [INAUDIBLE] remember, I was talking about the destructive queues, and
all the various other things.
When you do an code you're doing all those queues or whatever it did.
And again then the tuples on those queues are doubly collected by
the center thread and assembled into a global send thread.
And which in turn goes to the appropriate destination.
>> And this is all within a Java virtual machine.
>> With it all running in the Storm worker JVM process.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
So that's, that is the connect begin, the collector and
how it goes underneath, right.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So, under collect results.
Also, in addition to that,
I believe that you can do even something about stats collections, too.
So collec, output collectors already collecting the output tuples.
But also it can collect some stats also.
>> And so can you emit anything?
Like, what's, what's kind of the restrictions on what can you emit?
>> Collectors, I think they do a bunch of methods, right?
I mean, I mean I known all the image methods, and they make a particular tuple.
They make a ten set of columns, or whatever it is.
So there are, these all order emits that you can do,
to emit different ways and different forms.
>> Well, I mean, within the tuple, you emit values, right?
>> Mm-hm.
>> And then the value takes a bunch of arguments.
>> Yes. >> Can those arguments be any object?
>> Yeah, it can be any objects.
Yes, it can be any objects.
And in the schema where the declare outputs field or whatever, right?
There's another layer third or low, right?
You can say column one is named word, column two is sentiments col,
like something like that, right?
So then whenever you do Emmet you deal with only the columns,
the number of columns.
You don't deal with key value kind of thing where word is this one and
this one, right?
>> Mm-hm.
>> So, so what the thing is like it's kind of like an [INAUDIBLE] to
put any kind of object that's powerful enough.
Because ultimately, we do serialization, right.
So either Java serialization or the serialization or whatever.
So that objects are all serialized, then again deserialized on the don't stream.
>> What's the best programming method for
when you emit, to make sure that the order, because you access by offset, right?
Zero, one and two?
Of the tuple? But you don't know-
>> The offset is nothing but column number.
>> I see.
>> Columnal, it's a column like we don't say that going So for
example, let us say you are emitting a tuple which has four columns.
>> Right.
>> Like Word 1, Word 2, Word 3, Word 4, an offset of zero means you are one.
Offsets of one means you are two.
>> But in the emitter, you emit, you emit by position, so
it's position dependent.
It's just a programming question, if I switch the order in the emitter then,
I have to tell everybody downstream that's looking that they have to.
>> They aren't looking, yeah.
You always stick to the scheme of whatever you are providing,
because that is the only contract that you have, right?
Because if you don't stick to the schema, whatever >> Right.
>> In the wrong >> Yeah.
>> So.
>> Just over time I noticed when I added something, you know.
>> Mm-hm.
>> You always had to add it at the end or I'd break everything.
>> Yes.
>> Which was, which was a little troublesome.