What linearity is going to allow us to do is to build up a signal or
a function, remember an image, a piece at a time and
then be able to say how a linear operator affects that whole image.
Right? Because, basically the way both linearity allows us to say is if I
could sum up a bunch of things to make an image,
then if I apply a linear operator to that whole image, it's going to be
the same as the sum of applying that linear operator to each of the pieces.
And it let's us talk about things in an effective way.
So, to do that we need sort of these building blocks of a function.
And the building block of functions is what's referred to as an impulse.
And the impulse function in a discrete world is very easy to talk about.
It's a single point with a value 1, and it looks just like an impulse.
In the continuous world, an impulse is a little bit trickier because what
does it mean to be sort of at a single point width, you know,
it would have some amount 1, and that's where you have to turn on your calculus
hats just a little bit, no, I guess you put on your calculus hats, right?
And an impulse is actually a small, little signal whose area is 1.
Okay? So, and as the thing gets narrower and narrower in width,
it has to get taller in height in order to maintain that same area.
And in the limit what you get is an impulse.
So it's got 0 width and infinite height, but it's,
it's integral, it's area is 1, and that's what's referred to as an impulse.
We're going to mostly stay in the discrete world, so
we won't have to worry too much about that.
So the, the cool thing about an impulse is the following.
Suppose I've got some sort of a system, a black box.
So it's a function H, right?
So, sorry, it's an operator H.
And we don't know, actually, anything about it.
But if I put in an impulse, okay, so
I put an impulse into the system, I can see what comes out.
By the way, that response is called the impulse response.
Not, not all that clever, right?
So what's really cool is, if I know what the impulse response
of some black box H is, maybe we'll call that h of x, okay.
I can describe what this operators going to do by h of x.
The reason that works is the following.
Since any sequence of pulses here, and we're going to do this in 2D in a minute,
can be described by just adding in a shifted set and
scaled set of those single impulses.
If I know how this black box effects just the single impulse.
I'll be able to say how it affects the entire image.
Okay?
And that's why impulse responses matter.