Okay, let's find the traversal paths for
the image filter used on
the given media file.
From scanning the response, we can
see that there's a filter key here
which maps to the string
value of Sierra.
If you've ever used Instagram,
Sierra is the name of one of the filters
that you can apply to your
images to give it a cool effect.
To get down to this key value pair,
we need to start at the root JSONObject,
find the JSONObject with
the key of data, and
then down to the string value for
the key of filter.
Here's the path written out.
This one's pretty straightforward.
Root, JSONObject with key data, and then
get String value for the key filter.
Next, let's find the path
to get the website URL for
the thumbnail version of this image.
All right, for this one, I gotta scroll
around a little bit and look around.
And indeed, I see there's
the word thumbnail here, so
that's probably the key I'm looking for.
After studying the response for a little
bit, I found the thumbnail here,
along with other images for
this particular media file,
including low resolution,
thumbnail, and standard resolution.
The path to get to this value
is to start at the root object,
then to go to the data JSONObject,
then find the images JSONObject.
Then we care about the key thumbnail,
which is a JSONObject with information
about the thumbnail image.
And lastly, we find the URL key, where
we can find the thumbnail image's path.
So back on the quiz,
here's what the path looks like.
Root, JSON object with key data,
JSON object with key images,
JSON object with key thumbnail, and
then get String value for the key url.
Now let's work on the last question,
finding the first hashtag for the image.
Looking at this response,
we see the tags list, which contains
the list of hashtags for the image.
Then we see the first and
only hashtag, which is hammocklife.
I wish I was living my
hammock life right now.
Anyways, let's find the path
of this first hashtag.
We start at the root object as always,
then we go to the data JSONObject and
look for
the key tags, which maps to a JSON
array because of the square brackets.
Then we look at the first element
in the array, which is hammocklife.
And here's the path
that we just discussed.
Root JSONobject with key data,
JSON array with key tags, then look
at the first element in the array.
Hooray, great work with this quiz.