This is a particle filter question where we start with a single particle over here facing east.
The particle has an X, a Y, and a heading direction,
and this particle is on a checker board with black squares and white squares.
Let's assume we draw 5 new particles from this particle for the motion of going right,
and they end up as indicated over here.
Each of these 5 new particles--1 of which falling into a2, 2 of which falling into b2,
1 into c2, and 1 into b3--
each of these particles will obtain an importance weight,
as now that what we'll measure is on a black square.
So the measurement is black.
To calculate the importance weight, let me tell you that the probability of seeing black
on a black square = 0.8,
whereas the probability of seeing black on a white square is only 0.1.
So I want you to tell me the total importance weight that falls to a2--
here we just have a single particle--
into b2--please add the importance weight of both particles--
c2, and b3.
Please add your numbers over here.