All right, now,
it's time to play with some textures.
Let's hop back into the Unity editor.
First let's make a new material by
clicking on the Create button and
then going to Material.
Let's call this material Chessboard,
okay.
Let's go ahead and set the albedo
to a nice light tan color.
Something like this, great.
Now right-click on the hierarchy,
go to 3D Object, and Cube.
Over in the Transform component,
set the cube's position to -3,
0.5, and 1, great.
Now, let's rename our cube to be
something like Checkerboard Cube.
And let's drag and
drop our new chessboard material
onto our Checkerboard Cube.
Okay, so now we have a tan cube but
it doesn't look much like a chessboard.
If you look at the material that you
created, you'll notice little boxes
besides many of the rows, here,
here, here and all the rest of these.
You can drag and drop textures
into these boxes to assign them.
Each row represents a different type of
material property like albedo, depth,
light emission and more.
Go to the project pane and
find the search bar, and search for
an image called checkerboard.
Now, drag and
drop your checkerboard image right into
that slot beside the word albedo,
awesome.
You just assigned the texture
to this material.
And you'll notice your box is starting
to look a lot more like a chessboard.
But to finish things off,
let's scale down the box a bit.
Go to the Scale tool, select your cube
and then scale it down along the y axis.
Let's also scale the whole
thing down quite a bit, great.
Now, go to the Move tool and
move the chessboard onto
the kitchen counter,
something like that.
It looks great.
Okay, who wants to play some chess?