So, we've seen that it's easy to figure out the solution to a game
if there's a dominant strategy or if there's a Pareto-optimal equilibrium.
Now let's look at a harder game for which such solutions don't exist.
This game is called Two Finger Morra,
and it's a betting game, and we're going to show a simplified version of it.
Again, we have a simple 4-state outcome matrix,
and there are 2 players called even and odd.
And they both simultaneously show either
1 or 2 fingers.
And then if the result of the total number of fingers is even,
then the even player wins that many dollars from the odd player.
And if the total number of fingers is odd,
then the odd player wins that number of dollars from the even player.
So, if 1 and 1 is 2, so that's even,
so even gets +2, and we won't bother writing odd getting -2
because it's a zero-sum game, and it will always be the opposite.
Similarly, 2 and 2 is 4,
so even gets +4 and odd gets -4.
2 and 1 is 3, so even loses 3 dollars
and pays it to odd and similarly up here.
Now, there's no dominant strategy, and it seems kind of tricky
to figure out what the right strategy is.
We're going to need more complicated techniques,
and it turns out that there is no single move
that's the best strategy for either player.
But there is what's called a mixed strategy,
so a single strategy of always playing one or the other
is called a pure strategy, and a mixed strategy
is when you have a probability distribution over the possible moves.