When you create an application
that uses Location Services,
there are a number of steps
that you'll typically follow.
I'm going to list the six steps here.
And you're going to have to fill in
the blanks as to what you're going to do
in each step.
The first step is,
you're going to create a something
that uses the Location Services API.
Think about what that is.
The second step is that you're
going to extend your activity
with the number of callbacks.
What do you think those
callbacks might be?
The third step is that you
then extend your activity
with a particular listener in
case the connection fails.
Do you remember what that listener is?
The fourth step will be that you
continue to extend your activity and
you extend it with another listener.
This time it's a listener for
location updates.
Again, think about what that is.
The fifth step is,
after you've connected,
there's something will wait for
the something callback.
What do you think that is and what
callback do you think it's waiting for?
And then finally, in this callback,
you'll set up something, and
it's another callback, and in this you
can capture your location information.
These are all the steps that
you'll typically follow.
Can you fill in the blanks?