Now that we've covered exponential
smoothing models in detail, let's begin
construction on a model to forecast
bookings for Bates Hotel using Alteryx.
We'll begin by dragging and dropping
an Input Data tool onto the canvas and
loading in the Bookings xlsx.
We'll be using this data to forecast
the next six months of room bookings.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Next, bring in a Record ID tool.
All this does is number our records,
but doing this will allow us to
filter out a holdout sample.
We'll get more in depth on holdout
samples later in the course.
For now, we'll filter out the last six
records in our time series to use as
the holdout sample, by setting our
filter to include records less than or
equal to RecordID 114.
Now that we've prepared our time series
data for model construction, we can take
a look at the time series plots to
determine how we should apply our trend,
seasonal and error components
in our model calculation.
We'll connect a Record ID
tool to a TS Plot tool.
In the TS Plot tool configuration, we'll
select Bookings as the target field,
Monthly for our target field frequency,
and Time series plot as our plot type.
Now, add a Browse tool to the
interactive node of the TS Plot tool.
You can do this by
right-clicking on the tool and
selecting Add Browse After
(Interactive).
Now hit Run.
The interactive output for the TS Plot
shows us a vast amount of information.
Let's take a look at
the decomposition plot.
From this plot, we can tell our
trend moves in a linear fashion,
suggesting applying trend additively.
The seasonality within our time series
data looks to be about the same
every year.
But is it?
The seasonal portion of our
decomposition plot allows us to that
confirm is this is true.
Looking at the seasonal peaks and
valleys,
we can see that seasonality increases
in volume each seasonal period.
This suggests applying seasonality
in a multiplicative manner.
Lastly, our remainder, or error,
shows changing variance as
the time series moves along.
This means we should use
error multiplicatively.
The next step after determining
the fashion of how to apply our trend,
seasonal, and error components, will
be to build a model using the ETS tool.
Let's drag and
drop an ETS tool onto the canvas.
We'll name our model MAM, to show how
we're applying the different components.
Next, select Bookings as
the target field, and
Monthly as target field frequency.
On the Model type tab, we can set
the different component types.
Set Error to Multiplicative, Trend to
Additive, Trend dampening to No, and
Seasonal type to Multiplicative.
On the Other options tab, let's input 6
as the number of periods to include in
the forecast, and set the series
starting point to 2006 period one.
Let's also test if trend dampening will
have a positive effect on our model.
So, copy and
paste the ETS tool on the canvas, and
make sure the configuration is
the same as our first ETS model.
Except now,
set Trend dampening to Yes, and
also make sure to add
dampened to the model name so
we can tell the difference when
referencing the final output.
Our alpha, or smoothing value
is calculated automatically by
Alteryx to maximize error reduction,
so we'll not have to set this.
Before we hit Run, auto-browse to
the R or report node of the ETS tools.
We can click on the Play
button to build our models.
The output from our ETS tool will
show us important information such as
in-sample error measures, information
criteria, and the selected alpha value.
We'll discuss how to compare,
forecast, and
visualize these results in lesson four.
For now, save this workflow,
as we will come back to reference
it later on in the course.
[BLANK_AUDIO]