So the correct answers are here.
First of all, you'll create a Google API
client that uses your desired API.
In the example I showed earlier,
I was using the location services
API with a Google API client.
With others, you may be doing login,
you may be doing maps, you may be
doing other things, but you'll still
be using a GoogleApiClient for that.
You'll next extend your activity
with the ConnectionCallbacks.
These are the heart of
the asynchronous programming model,
where the services can call you back
whenever something important happens.
You'll also need to extend your activity
with the OnConnectionFailedListener.
In case the connection fails, so
that you can handle it gracefully.
And then, finally, after connecting
the GoogleApiClient that you
created earlier on, you wait for
the onConnected callback.
Once you get the onConnected callback,
you know that your ApiClient
is connected to the services.
And you're able to make
the calls on those services.
And then once you've done that,
you can follow the requirements
of your specific API.
Like for example, as you saw earlier on,
I was doing location work, so
I also had an on location
changed method, that was firing
whenever the location changed,
as a result of the location request.
You'll see all of this in much more
detail in the location services module,
as well as all of the other modules.
This sequence will be used in every
app that you build and you'll
want to be sure that you know it as you
move through the rest of the class.
Since this sequence is so important,
take some time to think of a good way to
remember these steps and then maybe
go post in the forum about it.
Also take some time to read
what other people have said.
You might find a methodology
that works for you.