I'll use the generate command
to create a new component.
Remember that Ember requires a component
to have a dash in its name, so
it has to be lego-brick, not just brick
or lego, or lego brick without a dash.
It has to have that dash in there.
I like taking things step by step, so
let's extract all of this inner loop
data over to the components template.
Now to have this code show up,
all we need to do is call the component.
Remember that variables in a component
are blocked from the outer scope.
So these have no meaning.
So for the brick value in here to
be equal to this one out here,
we need to make that connection.
Now the inner brick value is
equal to this outer brick value.
Remember that, by default, the component
wraps all of its content in a div.
Since this div is also here we
have an extra unneeded layer.
We can remove this div, but
then we'll lose our styles.
To fix this, we'll apply a class to
the component in the components file.
I'll move these classes to
the components className property.
But how do we work with this class?
To handle this, we need to use
the classNameBindings property.
This checks a property and
then applies a class.
To have it check the item's sale value,
we need to pass this
value into the component.
Inside the component, the sale property
is the value stored in item.onSale.
Back in the component file
we can check this value.
If it's true then we can
add the class on-sale and
now we can delete this
wrapping div element.
We still have the same
end visual result, but
now all of the brick content
is located in one place.
So we've separated our concerns and
have a dedicated file to update
when things need to change.
Great job.