Now that we're logged in, the next two
steps are to get the Session ID and
the User ID.
Each of these steps will closely mimic
what we did to get the Request Token.
In code we already called getSessionID
here, and getUserID here.
So all you need to do is correctly
implement both of these convenience
methods.
If you implement these correctly
then the completionHandlerForAuth
closure will be called, where success is
true, and we don't have any errorString.
This should cause the main
tab view to be presented and
we're ready to use the app.
Okay, so now it's your turn.
When you're done implementing
getSessionID, and
getUserID, check this box.