Commuters in the US spend an average
of one hour a day in their car.
And a person checks their smart phone
an average of 125 times per day.
Our cars get us where we're going
while our phones keep us connected.
But using your phone while driving
can be distracting and dangerous.
But what if you could stay connected
using your phone but in a safer and
more convenient way that's
integrated in the car?
And better yet, what if developing for
this new platform was easy and familiar?
Welcome to Android Auto,
bringing Android to the car.
It's the same platform you already
use for phones, tablets, televisions,
watches, and more!
In fact, all these experiences
will often be in the same APK.
But now your app can also extend to
the car in a way that's safer and
more efficient for the driver.
So they can stay connected, but
with their hands on the wheel and
eyes on the road.