Let's do a quiz in which we analyze
the performance metrics for
shortest job first.
To do this, let's assume first that
shortest job first is used to schedule
three tasks, T1, T2, and T3.
Also, let's make
the following assumptions.
The scheduler will not preempt the task,
so
this will be the run to completion type
of model that we discussed so far.
We'll assume that we know the execution
times of these tasks, and
we'll use the same values
as we used before.
So, T1 and T3 are 1 second and
T2 is ten seconds.
And, let's assume that they're
all arrive at the same time.
So, we will start analyzing
this system from some time, T0,
when all of these tasks
are actually in the system already.
Per this system, calculate the
throughput, the average completion time,
and the average wait time,
using the shortest job first algorithm.