So before you made that change,
I asked you to think about whether it
would be better to clean bad stuff out
of posts as soon as the user sends them,
before we put them in the database or
whether we should put them
into the database as they are and
clean them up before we display them.
It turns out that there
are arguments both ways.
Usually you'll hear programmers talk
about input sanitization, meaning that
we clean bad stuff out of user input,
before we do anything at all with it,
that way if someone later displays
the stored posts using another app.
They don't have to worry about bad
stuff hiding, in the database.
But on the other hand, if we wanted
an accurate record of what users have
sent to us, maybe we want to preserve
bad input in the database, and
do output sanitization instead.
People have different opinions,
about which of these is best.
Right now, since we already have
live bad stuff in the database,
we definitely need to sanitize output.
But we could sanitize input as well.