So to understand this project,
this perpendicular relationship, let's look at the projective space.
So what does a line in the image correspond to in projective space?
Well, a line really is defined by this plane of rays that's intersecting
the image plane and that plane's defined, like all planes are by a normal.
And this is that same normal, a, b, c.
So all the rays that are perpendicular to that normal form the line,
because the line is really just a plane in
this projected space intersecting the image plane.
Cool, right?
It gets better.
Oh, and we can write this very simply in the same vector notation I
was showing you before.
So essentially, in fact, you know, what, let's, let's say,
l transpose p if I wanted to write it that way.
Right? So that's in vector notation.
And the thing to think about is that in projective geometry and
in this homogenous coordinate system, a line is also a homogenous 3-vector.
So a point is a homogenous 3-vector, but a line is also a homogenous 3-vector.
In fact, this relationship that a point is a 3-vector and a line is
a 3-vector is what's going to get to this duality between points and lines.
And as we've said, a line is a homogeneous 3-vector,
which is defined by that normal to the plane and
it is perpendicular to every point p that's on that plane.
And what does it mean to be perpendicular to a point?
Well, in projective geometry, being perpendicular to a point means that
you're actually perpendicular to the ray that defines that point.
And that's what gives us some of that duality.
Given these points and lines are both three vectors and we have this duality.
Suppose I have two points, p1 and p2.
Now remember, points are actually these rays, p1 and p2.
How would you solve for the line that goes between them?
Okay. So you know in algebra, if I gave you two points,
you would figure out your formula for line.
Well, in projective geometry, it's actually pretty easy.
Since l here is just perpendicular to both p1 and p2.
Well, you remember how to get a perpendicular vector given two other vectors?
You just take their cross product, okay?
So l is equal to p1 cross p2, that's it.
No problem, okay?
And l is the normal to the plane.
So that plane is the line, so
the way I get that line is I just cross the two points.
Very easy.
Let's just keep going.
What is the inner section of two lines?
Okay.
So remember now, I've got a line l1 and l2 and remember that
they're actually planes and what I'm showing you here are the lines that
are made up of the planes where the planes intersect the image planes.
So the l1 plane gives you this.
The L2 plane gives you that, okay?
Well, just a little bit of thinking here and you realize if the point p
is perpendicular to l1 and point p is perpendicular to l2, okay?
Then what I need is a line that is perpendicular or, or, and
need a point whose ray is perpendicular to l1 and l2.
All right?
Well, that's easy.
So just as we had before in order to find the intersection,
in order to find the line that spans the two points.
We took that cross product to find the line.
In order to find the point that's the intersection of two lines,
I just take the cross product again.
So the points and lines as I said, they form a dual in projective space and
that means really given any formula, I can sort of switch back and
forth between what are the points and what are the lines.
So when I showed you that l transpose p equal 0.
And I said, l was the line and p was the point.
Well, that's just because l is for line and p is point.
If this was some other language where l stood for point and p stood for
line, you'd all be really confused.
But basically, what it would mean is that I was thinking of 1 as the line and
the other as the point.
We're going to make use of this not in the next lesson, but
in the one later when we talk about fundame, fundamental matrices.
Where just to, to give you forward looking a little.
Remember that if I have a point in a stereo image,
it has to appear somewhere on a line.
In the other, that's the epipolar line and vice versa.
These pair of epipolar lines.
So projective geometry will make it real easy to go between points in lines.