So we have two threads, T1 and T2.
They need to perform some operation involving some variables, A and B.
And, in fact, the two threads don't even need to perform the same
operation on A and B.
But let's say they both need to access these shared variables, A and B.
Before performing these operations,
they must lock mutexes that protect the shared variables A and B.
And let's say T1 first locks the mutex for A and then locks the mutex for B.
And in the case of T2,
T2 first locks the mutex for B and then locks the mutex for A.
And this is where the problem is.
The two threads are waiting on each other in a cycle.
Neither one of them will be able to get to the foo operation.
Neither one of them, in fact,
will be able to execute this second lock operation.
They'll keep waiting on each other.
And we'll have a dead lock.
So how can we avoid these situations?
One way to avoid this situation would be to unlock the mutex for
A before locking the mutex for B, or the other way around.
We would call this fine-grained locking.
The problem with this is that,
it won't work in this case since the threads need both A and B.
So, they have to have both locks.
They need both variables, after all.
Another possibility would be to get all the locks up front and
then release them at the very end.
Or maybe we just end up using one mega-lock, some mutex m sub A,B.
This solution may work for some applications.
However, in other cases it can be very restrictive because it
limits the level of parallelism that can exist in the system, and the last and
the really most accepted solution is to maintain a lock order.
If we force everyone to first get the mutex for A and then the lock for
B, the problem will not occur.
If we investigate this a little bit more,
we see that the problem is that T1 is waiting on something that T2 has.
And T2's waiting on something that T1 has.
So we have a cycle basically.
And in this case, we have two threads, so
it's easy to reason about the situation and to determine that the order
in which these locks are being acquired can result potentially in a cycle.
In principle, this type of analysis is a little bit more difficult to illustrate
than to determine, but what we're trying to really show is that if there is
a cycle in this kind of wave graph in which we draw a line between two threads.
If one thread is waiting on a resource that the other thread has,
then a cycle indicates a dead lock.
Maintaining a lock order will prevent such cycles from occurring.
So will ensure that there will be no deadlocks in the code.
So to enforce this kind of maintain lock order principle in the example before,
T2 would have to get the mutexes, the mutex for A first and then the mutex for
B, and there no way that in that, in this code a cycle would occur.
There's no way that a deadlock can happen.
So, consider this.
If thread 1 is waiting on the lock, is about to execute the operation lock
m of B, it means it already has acquire the mutex m of A.
If thread 1 already has this mutex then thread two cannot have it.
So, thread two must be somewhere before this lock operation and its execution.
That also means that thread 2 could not have acquired the m_b mutex,
it doesn't have it, and therefore there's no cycle.
Thread 1 is not going to end up in a situation in which it has to
wait on thread 2 for that particular lock.
So it will be able to acquire it and continue.
So this type of technique will always work.
The only potential challenge is that in complex programs that
use many shared variables and potentially many synchronization variables, so
lots of mutexes, take some effort to make sure that these are indeed ordered.
And everywhere used in the same order.
But as a technique this is foolproof.
And it guarantees that it will prevent deadlocks from happening.