You've already learned how
to activate auto tracking so
that every time any user goes
to any screen in your app,
a hit is recorded and
sent to Google Analytics.
While you're learning how to
add analytics to your app,
it's fine to have auto tracking enabled.
It's gratifying to see the hits
coming in the dashboard.
But if your app gets wildly popular and
if you've got auto tracking enabled,
then that's going to be a lot
of screen hits that get sent.
In fact, it could be too many hits,
and you might run into quota limits.
If your app exceeds its quota limits,
excess hits will not be counted.
You can read about quota
limits in the developer docs.
The main point to understand
is that it's often better to
specifically track
what you want to track
rather than enabling auto
tracking across all activities.
It's easy enough to disable auto
tracking for all activities.
Simply set ga_autoActivityTracking
to false in the config file for
your tracker.
And then, instead, to track when
users go to a specific screen,
you can send a screen view hit,
like this.
You add the code to onStart.
Then you get the tracker.
Hopefully you know how to do that now.
You can set the screen name on
the tracker with setScreenName.
And then you send the hit, calling
build on HitBuilders.ScreenViewBuilder.
And you'll need to make sure that
your app has the right imports.
You're going to need the Tracker class.
And you're going to need
the HitBuilders class.
For all hits that are sent,
you still get the geo information,
the device info, the engagement details,
and all that other good stuff.
Okay, go ahead and try it now.
In the tracker config file,
set ga_autoActivityTracking to false.
Then pick an activity in your app, and
add the code to the onStart()
method to send a hit.
So, here,
I'm tracking hits to ShowRecipe.
So I'm in the ShowRecipeActivity
with my onStart method.
And you can see I set my screen
name to Show recipe screen.
And here's the code to send the hit.
And then, of course,
run your app and try it out.
You can look in the logs to
see that your hit gets sent
when you go to that screen.
See there's my hit, but not when
you do anything else in the app.
And then of course, don't forget to
check your analytics dashboard and
then come here and check the boxes.