So now that we've seen how
regular notifications work,
how do we go about extending this
application to work with Android Auto?
These are the same steps
you would have to take,
if you had an existing messaging
app that you wanted to modify.
So this would be very useful for
you to understand.
When a user connects their phone
to an Android Auto head unit,
a companion app runs on the phone which
implements the Android Auto experience.
Shown here.
This Auto Companion app looks for
apps on the device, such as these here,
that declare Android Auto support, and
so our messaging app needs to declare
this in the AndroidManifest.xml file.
So let's open that file up.
So we go to manifests,
AndroidManfest.xml, and here it is.
We need to declare an XML file that will
contain the Android Auto information.
So let's add something like this
inside of the application tag.
Now we need to create
this reference file.
So if we go over here and select res,
you won't have an XML directory so
we need to create that.
So right click New, Directory,
type the word XML and hit OK.
Right click on the XML directory,
select New File,
and type in automotive_app_desc.xml,
and hit OK.
Inside this new file,
you then need to declare support for
notifications, like this.
The next step is to create broadcast
receivers that will be called,
whenever an Android auto message has
been heard by the user or replied to.
So we can use Android Studio to
create these receivers very easily.
And it'll up the AndroidManfest.xml
file for us as well.
So to do this, click on File,
New, Other, Broadcast Receiver,
and for the name, we're going to
type my message heard receiver and
we'll leave all the defaults
as they are, and hit finish.
You can see now,
we have sub class created for us.
And you can see the AndroidManifest.xml
changes here, as well.
You need to add an intent filter, so
that this receiver will only
respond to specific actions.
Note that we include
the package name here.
You should change this package
name to whatever the name is for
your application.
Ours is defined here, at the top
of the AndroidManifest.xml and so
we're going to use that here, too.
We also need to create a receiver for
message replies as well, so
let's do the same thing File,
New, Other,
Broadcast Receiver, and this time we're
going to use MyMessageReplyReceiver.
Once again with the same default and
then finish.
If we go back to
the AndroidManifest.xml file,
we need to make sure we add
a similar intent-filter as before.
And so we put that in like this.
You'll see here that
the action is a reply,
instead of heard like we used before.
We also need to double check that
we're including the Android support
library as well.
This is defined in the build.gradle
file for the application module.
We can find that here.
Here, and then we load it up.
And if we scroll here,
you can see that we're already including
the support-v4 library here,
so we're good to go.