[Thrun] One of the remaining open questions pertains to the number of clusters.
So far I've assumed it's simply constant and you know it.
But in reality, you don't know it.
Practical implementations often guess the number of clusters along with the parameters.
And the way this works is that you periodically evaluate which data is poorly covered
by the existing mixture, you generate new cluster centers
at random near unexplained points, and then you run the algorithm for a while
to see whether the existence of your clusters is still justified.
And the justification test is based on a memorization of a criterion
that combines the negative log likelihood of your data itself
and a penalty for each cluster.
In particular, you're going to minimize the negative log likelihood of your data
given the model plus a constant penalty per cluster.
If we look at this expression, this is the expression that EM already minimizes.
We maximized the posterior probability of data
logarithmic is a monotonic function, and I put a minus sign over here
so the optimization problem becomes a minimization problem.
This one over here, we have a constant cost per cluster is new.
If you increase the number of clusters, you would pay a penalty
that is in the way of your attempted minimization.
Typically, this expression balances out at a certain number of clusters,
and it is generically the best explanation for your data.
So the algorithm looks as follows.
Guess an initial K, run EM, remove unnecessary clusters
that will make this quote over here go up,
create some new random clusters, and go back and run EM.
There is all kinds of variants of this algorithm.
One of the nice things here is this algorithm also overcomes local minima problems
to some extent.
If, for example, 2 clusters end up grabbing the same data,
then your tests would show you that 1 of the clusters can be omitted;
thereby the score can be improved.
That cluster can later be restarted somewhere else,
and by randomly restarting clusters, you tend to get a much, much better solution
than if you run EM just once with a fixed number of clusters.
So this trick is highly recommended for any implementation of expectation maximization.