So given that little bit of information,
we can now talk about image reprojection.
Here's the basic question.
How do we relate two images, so I have two images, projective plane one,
projective plane two, where the center of projection of the camera was the same.
'Kay, so I've got the camera, and
it's center projection is fixed, and I take two images.
So the question is,
how do I map from projective plane one to projective plane two?
Well here's the answer, basically think of that image or the point on
the image as we said is it's actually a ray in space, and it's a ray from
the center projection, through the image plane intersecting the image plane.
And then in order to figure out how to map
from projective plane one to projective plane two, I basically have to
figure out where that same ray intersects projective plane two.
So if I knew where that plane was,
then I could just figure out where that point is.
All right?
And so that would be, you know, right here.
'Kay?
So what should be clear is,
that in order to figure out where this ray was intersecting projective plane
two, I didn't actually have to know where in the world that ray hit.
I just need to know the camera center,
the location of the point in image plane one that defines the ray, and
then I intersect the ray with projective plane two.
Where it hits in the world is irrelevant.
What that means is, instead of thinking of this as a reprojection from
3D to 2D in figuring out how it projects to some other 2D plane,
when I'm going from two planes that are from the same center,
I really want to think of this as a 2D image transformation.
A 2D, it says here, image warp from one image plane to the other.
I don't have to worry about the third dimension, the 3D world.
So a very cool application of this is what's referred to as image mosaics, or
sometimes called image panoramas.
So would you like to know how to make an image panorama, sometimes called
an image mosaic, which is way easier to say than panoram, ra, pa, pan, panama.
Maybe they make them in Panama.
I don't know.
We're going to make panoramas, and we're going to use homographies to do this.
All right, so here's the basic procedure of how to make a panorama.
You're going to take a sequence of images from the same position.
So you might say, you might ask,
well if it's from the same position, don't I get the same picture?
No, you're going to rotate the camera about its optical center.
So the position stays the same, but
the direction that the camera's pointing can change.
Then what you're going to do is you compute a transform between the second image
and the first, or the first and
the second, and then what you do is you transform that second image to
overlap with the first according to the, the, the correct transformation.
And then what you'll have to do is you'll have to
blend those two pictures together to make the mosaic.
And of course, if there are more images then you have to repeat.
But wait a minute.
How come I don't have to worry about the 3D world in order to
put together a panorama of images that are taken of
this whole big world that's got different depths etc.
What about the 3D, 3D geometry of the scene?
Why aren't we using it?
Well, you can probably guess it's that thing that we said before.
About that the, when you're projecting from one image plane to the next,
if they're taken from the same camera center, the 3D world is irrelevant.
So I don't actually have to know the scene structure in order to
paste together these pictures to make a panorama.