Here's the game tree for another stochastic game.
This game involves flipping a coin.
The chance nodes have two results: heads or tails.
Then the player Max has two possible moves, A and B,
and the player Min has two possible moves, C and D.
This game is too small to have any alpha-beta pruning involved,
but I've listed all the terminal values for the terminal states of the game.
What I want you to do is fill in the non-terminal values
for the chances nodes, the max nodes, and the min nodes
according to the rules of minimum value and maximum value and expected value.
I should say that the probability of the coin flip is 50% heads and 50% tails.