All right for our implementation, I'll
start by attempting to set latitude and
longitude constants using their
corresponding text fields.
Technically, this if let statement
should always pass because if we scroll
up here, there's this isTextFieldValid
method that's being called on
both of them and it's going to ensure
that we actually have valid, double, or
floating point numbers.
But this extra check that we're making
in the if let statement is nice in case
we want to call this method without
assuming any prior checks were made, but
if the check does fail, let's return
a valid string, but with all zeros.
Now, after the latitude and
longitude constants are created,
we need to create a value for
each item that shows up in the list.
For the minimum longitude,
let's take the longitude and
subtract away half the width,
the SearchBBoxHalfWidth.
Now normally this statement would
work fine, but what if I try to
subtract beyond a negative 180
degree minimum for longitude?
Well, if that happens, maybe it would
be best to just return negative
180 instead because there could
be the case where a user puts in,
say, negative 179.6, and
we set our HalfWidth here to ones.
So if we were to subtract that away we
would be at, what, negative 180.6, which
is outside of the accepted range but,
to the user, they wouldn't know that.
They'd be entering valid longitude,
so, yeah,
returning negative 180 in that
particular edge case would be nice.
So, what I'm going to use
is the max function and
we want to return
the maximum of this value.
Or we'll need our constant.
Very good, okay.
So if we subtract beyond negative
180 then just return negative 180.
Similarly, for the minimum latitude,
we'll subtract away HalfHeight
of the BBox which we have
here in this constant.
And we're using max again and
in this case we're using the minimum for
latitude which is -90.
Then for the maximum longitude and
latitude we just do the reverse.
We add HalfWidth and HalfHeight and then
we use the minimum function to ensure
that we don't go over the maximum value
in our LonRange and our LatRange.
With these created, we can use a little
string interpolation and we're done.
And let's build and run to check.
And there we go.
There's our URL.