Hey Jessica,
I just had a chat with Tommy, and
he's wondering where the app is.
>> Well, we don't have it just yet,
but there's a good reason for that.
>> Okay.
>> So,
first we had to lay the foundation for
our students, teaching them SQLite
statements in the command line.
And now we're ready to take what
they learned in the command line and
move it into the pet's app.
So in lesson two right now, we'll focus
on how to create a database in the app,
and then learn how to insert and
then query data from it.
>> Okay, sounds like you've
got it all under control.
>> Yeah.
>> All right, good,
because we don't want to make Tommy mad.
>> That's true,
he's really scary when he's mad.
>> Yeah.
>> Actually how about in the mean
time we give him this snack?
>> Okay, good idea.
Hey Tommy, do you want a snack?
Good boy.
What pet's app?