Now to tie everything together, we will look at an implementation of
the classic producer-consumer problem that uses the pthreads library.
We will look at the source code section by section.
In this first, for instance, section this is the global scope where all of
the different variables are defined.
If you happen to get lost as I trace through this code, then please
reference the source code link that’s provided in the instructor’s notes.
So let’s take a look at this.
In this producer-consumer example,
we have a shared buffer of size buffer size, and it happens to be three.
There are three also shared variables where num refers to the number of
elements in the buffer, and then add and
rem refer to the indices that point to the element in this buffer
where we need to add the next element or to remove the next element from.
For instance if this is our shared buffer initially all of
these variables would be zero.
When we add one element, that means that the total number of elements is one.
Adding new elements will have to happen in the next field in the buffer array.
And removing an element still remains to be zero,
because this is the element we need to remove.
Adding a second element changes the values of these shared variables as follows.
So the total number will be two.
And then new additions should be placed in the buffers of two element.
And we still haven't removed anything.
When we remove one element from the buffer, the x,
that means that the total number of elements in the buffer is now one.
Still, the next available slot in the buffer,
that we can use to add an element, is two.
And the slot that contains the next valid entry in the buffer that we
should be removing next is one, the y.
So, this illustrates how this buffer and
these three shared variables are used to manage the producer consumer data.
The shared variables are used in conjunction with a mutex, and we use this mutex
initializer statement, that this basically automatically initializes the mutex.
So it does the function of attribute init, essentially.
And we're going to use two condition variables.
One, c_cons, which will be used by the consumers, so
the consumers will be waiting on this condition variable.
And then the other one, c_prod, and this one will be used by the producers.
The producers will be waiting on this variable.
There are also two functions, two procedures,
the producer operation that will be executed by our producer threads, and
the consumer operation and that will be executed by our consumer threads.