(Sebastian) Okay. Here's from Custer Kriptis in Greece.
"Thanks a lot for this class. Are you providing a downloadable form of this course for people that completed it?
"I would personally want to archive the lectures, given that I might want to refer to it in the future. Thank you, professors."
(Peter) Yes, I think we covered that before. I think they'll always be there on YouTube. But we should package them up
in a way to make it easy to gather them all together at once. So we'll look into trying to get that done.
(Sebastian) Yeah. I also hope that the website will just stay up, and then people can just always go back.
I find that the course the way we lay it out is not meant to be an encyclopedia or a reference book,
so if you want to go back, it might be hard to find stuff, as you probably experienced.
It's really meant to be for one-time consumption, you just go through it for the experience.
So we might, in future months and years, add more information on how to find things and how to access things
very quickly once you've learned it and just want to refresh it. That's clearly, I think, a deficiency of the current system.
Evo from Houston, Texas says, "I agree with you to try things out instead of just reading books.
"However, could you say a bit about types of materials you should/could study in order to get a broader foundation
"in the field of A.I.? And thanks a bunch for this great initiative. Evo."
Well, obviously there's one book that stands out among all others, one book that captures 95% of the marketplace,
one book that has been translated into more languages than any other book,
and clearly, chapter 26 is the best chapter, because I wrote it. (laughter) But this book so happens to be written
by a person that sits on my left, you wouldn't believe it. And I highly recommend it.
Peter, you said that you would take the proceeds of the sales this quarter and donate them?
(Peter) That's right, and donate them to charity. My publisher did notice that the sales were going up
because you all were buying books, so thank you. (Sebastian) That's really generous of you.
(Peter) Yeah, well, it's generous of all you to buy the book, and I hope you got some good use out of it.
(Sebastian) So you can tell I'm not doing this for Peter's personal profit, but that's actually a really good book,
and I think Peter put a lot of work into the third edition. (Peter) Yeah. (Sebastian) I think more than the first two editions.
(Peter) That's right. (Sebastian) It's amazing how the later editions consume more work.
(Peter) The first edition was easiest, because Stuart Russell and I were doing it, and we just said,
"We'll put what we put into our class when we teach it, and if you don't like it, too bad," and so it was easy--
We just wrote it down. (Sebastian) And then all the professors (unintelligible).
(Peter) Yeah. And then we felt like we were doing this for the world and not for ourselves, and that made it much harder.
And we had to sort of double-check everything. (Sebastian) Yeah. But I've taught from this book many times,
and I find it amazingly well-researched. It is a big book. It's not 500 pages, it's... can you tell how many pages it is?
(Peter) 1,100, I think. (Sebastian) Oh my God, 1,100 pages. Well, it's going to keep you busy for a while.
(Peter) Yeah. (Sebastian) The other thing that's nice about it is there's lots of references in there to other texts.
I also wrote a book that isn't quite as popular as Peter's. It's more specific, on probabilistic robotics,
so it looks into robotics from Bayes network perspective.
And if, after this, you care about robotics and perception and real world systems, you can buy it.
The sales didn't go up as a result of this class. We didn't use it as text at all.
So if I teach a future robotics class, I might use that as a text.
(Peter) And to answer Evo, I think you should also look into reading journal articles.
Once you start getting into a field, then you should become competent to read the current research,
and that's really where things are happening. And if you want to keep up with where the field is going,
going to have to be able to learn to read those as well as read the textbooks.
(Sebastian) Anul Lorena from Mexico City--hi, Mexico City--says, "Dear professors, you talked about
"top-notch lists of students. Do you think it would be possible to know, after giving us the final score,
"the overall place you got among the 40 or 80,000 students? That would be encouraging for future courses."
And the answer is absolutely yes, we'll let you know your rank. We're kind of dabbling with the idea of
contacting our top-notch students to solicit--for those of you who want to do it--to send us your c.v.
We have good connections to a local search engine company and they're always looking for great people.
It'd be a pleasure, actually, to assist some of you in finding you jobs, to be honest.
I have to admit, I've been impressed by some of you, many of you, and the amazing high-quality answers
you've given to a really challenging set of exam questions. At some point we looked at the number of--
the ratio of top-notch students in this class outpaced the ratio of top-notch students at Stanford.
So it would be a pleasure. So please stay tuned, and if you are doing really well, you might receive email by me.
(Peter) And we'll be careful to respect your privacy and not spam you too much, and let you make the contact
if you want to, but we may be able to help-- (Sebastian) Absolutely. (Peter) --make that connection.
(Sebastian) This is really meant just as an assistance if you care about it; if not, just ignore us, please.
Vicki in Brazil. "Hi, I just wanted to thank you, professors, for this excellent opportunity that I had.
"I really appreciate the subject and the challenges it has brought. Please let us know of any incoming classes.
"Professor Thrun and Professor Norvig, your passion is contagious."
(Peter) Well, you're welcome again, Vicki. It's too easy. There aren't any hard questions this week.
(Sebastian) Yeah, no one says, "This course sucks." Except once you said you didn't sleep much.
(Peter) That's true. (laughter) (Sebastian) Well, I have to admit, these comments are moving me, honestly,
they make me really emotional about this class, and make me feel really close to you guys.
So here's one last question I'd like to ask, and I tried to find one that's a little bit less about the wonderful experience.
Here's one by Neco from Moscow. "I want to ask about neural nets, evolution in programming, genetic algorithms,
"fuzzy logic, fuzzy time series. The professors never mentioned these topics at all over the class. Why is this?
"And will these topics be covered next classes?" And he actually hopes that they will.
And the answer is that we only had ten weeks, and so we can't cover everything.
Like Sebastian said, my book is 1,100 pages. That was too many, and all of A.I. is even larger than that.
So we had to come up with a sampling. And in each area we chose a couple examples, and we left out other examples.
So, like why didn't we do genetic algorithms? So genetic algorithms are certainly very popular, they're a big part of A.I.
It's a commonly used tool. But the way we see it, genetic algorithms are another type of search algorithm.
And we introduced a couple search algorithms, and since it wasn't a class just about those,
we didn't want to exhaustively cover all of them. And so we covered what we could in the amount of time we had.
(Sebastian) One of the most popular tools right now are probabilities. And of course, probabilities in machine learning,
probabilities for inference, and probabilities and uncertainty. So for example, when it comes to fuzzy,
I think these days probability has become somewhat more popular than fuzzy logic, which tries to achieve similar things--
not exactly the same thing, but it's often used to represent uncertainty.
And as Peter said, I think there's many topics we had to leave out. We did want to go in-depth in some topics
and really teach you the skill of using it. We didn't just want to make an overview class.
And you can take my word for it, we also left them out at Stanford. So Stanford students have no clue about these things, either.
And these are important concepts and they're worth studying, and I think a lot of interesting stuff is happening in these fields.
And so our apologies for not dragging this class on for another eight weeks or so.
Well, I think that's our last office hour. (Peter) That's it. So, thank you all for watching and participating in the class.
Good luck on the final exam. I know you'll all do great.
You've done great so far, and it's been a pleasure working with you.
(Sebastian) So it was great having you in class. We've been blown away by the wonderful feedback we received.
I think it was one of the best ways to spend my time, and I'm so glad I could reach so many of you.
When I was a student, I couldn't get access to good education at the scale that we aspire to provide to you for free.
So thank you so much, and I hope you stay tuned for possible future classes.
(Peter) And it's been a great experiment, I've learned a lot from doing it. I hope you've learned.
And I hope the field of A.I. and the field of education and online education can take some lessons from this.
There's still a lot we have to analyze to kind of understand what went on.
We know we worked really hard and didn't sleep very much. We don't quite understand all the lessons
from what worked and what doesn't work. We're going to go back and analyze that and try to figure it out,
and then try to figure out what the next steps are in the next class.
And I hear, Peter, you're going to do a TED Talk, right? (Peter) I am. (Sebastian) That's wonderful.
So Ted is this big conference that takes place in February--technology, entertainment, design.
It's a meeting where the brightest and the best in the world report on their experiences,
and Peter's going to be the person doing it. (Peter) So by February I have to understand what just happened.
(Sebastian) Yeah, I'm happy to help you. All right. Goodbye. (Peter) Goodbye and thank you.