When an I/O request is made the user
process typically requires some
type of a response from the device
even if it's just a status that,
yes I got it I'll do this for you, so
what happens with the user process or
the user thread once
the I/O call is made?
What will happen to the thread will
depend on whether the I/O operations
are synchronous or asynchronous,
for synchronous I/O operations,
the process or the calling
thread at least will be blocked.
The OS kernel will place that thread on
the wait queue that's associated with
the corresponding device and then the
thread will eventually become runable
when the response from this
request becomes available so
in the mean time it will be blocked,
it will be waiting,
it will not be able to
perform anything else.
But asynchronous operations the user
process is allowed to continue
as soon as it issues the I/O call,
at some later time
the user process can be allowed to come
in and check are the results ready for
this operation and at that point
it will retrieve the results.
Or perhaps at a later point the process
itself will be notified by the device,
or by the operating system,
that the operation has completed and
that any results are ready and are
available at the particular location.
The benefit of this is that the process
doesn't have to go and periodically
check to see whether the results are
available, this is somewhat analogous
to the polling versus interrupt base
interface that we talked about earlier.
Remember that we talked about the
asynchronous I operations when we talked
about the flash paper in the lesson
on thread performance consideration.
In there, the solution was for
the kernel to avoid blocking the user
process by creating separate threads
that will perform I/O operations,
in that case synchronous
operations that will block.
Here, we're really talking about
asynchronous I/O operations
truly being supported within
the operating system.