Before we dive deeper
into this orientation,
we should probably start
with some introductions.
I'm Cheng-Han, the data analyst
curriculum manager here at Udacity.
I studied a lot about mission learning
when I was a student in school, and
I most recently worked as Program
Manager at Microsoft before coming here
to Udacity.
I have worked with our industry
partners and with course helpers here,
at Udacity, to create all the courses
and the project in this nanodegree.
>> And, I'm Miriam Swords Kalk.
I work on community and
student experience for nanodegrees.
I started out here at Udacity as
a course developer, helping plan and
create new courses.
And then, I moved over towards student
services team to get more direct
interaction with students.
I really, really love learning to
understand what our students, like you,
want and need.
And that's exactly what I'm
doing in this nanodegree.
I'm here to be your number one advocate,
your voice within our company.
I can't wait to hear the feedback you
have for us throughout the nanodegree.
>> There are a lot of other people
as well working on this nanodegree.
You will talk to Udacity coaches and
course developers.
These people have all
worked on the courses and
the project in the nanodegree.
They have backgrounds ranging
from math PhDs to engineers and
people working in natural sciences and
more.
They're all very excited to work with
you and other aspiring data analysts.
>> On top of that,
they're professional educators.
They understand how to
help you learn best and
are here to help make that happen.