The reason why I gave you all this is because I want you to apply it now
to a slightly more complicated problem, which is the 2-test cancer example.
In this example, we again might have our unobservable cancer C,
but now we're running 2 tests, test 1 and test 2.
As before, the prior probability of cancer is 0.01.
The probability of receiving a positive test result for either test is 0.9.
The probability of getting a negative result given they're cancer free is 0.8.
And from those, we were able to compute all the other probabilities,
and we're just going to write them down over here.
So, take a moment to just verify those.
Now, let's assume both of my tests come back positive,
so T1 = + and T2 = +.
What's the probability of cancer now written in short form probability of
C given ++?
I want you to tell me what that is, and this is a non-trivial question.