So, we need to swap out the root
page for the skeleton page, but
continue to make everything
work offline first.
I guess this is a job for you,
because the phone lines are lighting up.
We have a Mike dialing in.
Think they're up for this one, Mike?
>> I do.
>> Then go for it.
>> If you completed the previous task,
your copy of the project is in
the right shape to take on this task.
But for some helpful to-do comments,
you can run git reset hard to
remove any local changes you have.
Then git checkout task-page-skeleton
to get up to speed.
You only need to edit the service
worker to complete this task.
So head over to public/js/sw/index.js.
The root page is currently being cached
and served up in the fetch event.
Your job is to cache the page
skeleton instead and
serve that if the root
page is requested.
Once you've change the code,
refresh the page.
The browser will see the new service
worker and now we get this notification.
We can hit the Reload button to
update to the latest version.
You can confirm your changes
are working by checking view source on
the root page.
The source should be small like this.
To double check everything is working,
head to the settings page.
And type service skeleton into
the test field and press enter.