Okay, I'm going to answer these
questions before jumping into the XML.
First thing's first,
is selecting the views.
I'll draw boxes around
the ones that I see.
Okay, so there are five different views,
not including the view group,
which is technically considered a view.
But anyways, these five views
are two TextViews up here,
followed by three buttons.
And there are no ImageViews really here
anywhere, so I'd say no ImageViews.
Now you might be wondering why I decided
that these were two different TextViews,
well in the final product
the styling of team A and
the score look very different.
So I've decided to keep these
as two separate TextViews.
Moving on to step two,
which is positioning the views.
I'm going to select which
ViewGroup I want to use here.
And the two that are on my mind
are linear layouts and relative layouts.
Now this is a vertical column of views.
So it's pretty clear to me what I want,
and that is a linear layout.
Okay, finally I have step three
which is style the views.
And I'll tackle that one as
I'm working with the XML.
Okay, so let's jump over to the XML.
Okay, I want to be
looking at the Text tab.
Okay, so the first thing I'm
going to do here is just
delete some things that I don't need.
So I'm going to go ahead and
start by deleting this TextView.
And all of this paddingLeft,
paddingRight, paddingTop and
paddingBottom, I'm also going to delete.
Being very careful not to delete
anything I don't mean to.
Okay.
Now we had said that the ViewGroup we're
going to use is not a relative layout
but a linear layout, so
I'll go ahead and change that now.
And inside of this linear layout
I'm going to have two TextViews
followed by three buttons.
So I'm going to start making those.
Now I'm not going to be too specific
right now about what the width and
height of this TextView are going to be.
For now I'm going to just
leave it as wrap_content,
which will put the box of
the TextView right around the text.
I'll go ahead and set the text for
this TextView as well.
And this first TextView's
just going to say Team A.
Okay, lets see what this
looks like in the Preview.
Okay, I can see a little
TextView there that says Team A.
Now let's build out a couple more.
So the next one below that is the score,
and that's a TextView as well.
So we're going to start typing Text.
Okay, I see the word TextView,
so I press Enter.
And I am also going to
make this wrap_content.
And I'm going to add the text.
Well the score usually starts at zero,
so we'll have it start at zero.
Okay.
Now my Buttons.
So I'm going to start
typing the word Button.
Go ahead and wrap_content for
these as well.
Okay, now the first Button
is going to say +3 Points.
I'm going to go ahead and copy this and
paste it once,
paste it twice to get two more Buttons.
And we'll have a Button
that says +2 Points and
a Button that says Free Throw.
Okay, let's see what that
looks like in the Preview.
Well, I seem to have three Buttons.
I can see Team A and zero.
So I have all my views,
but this doesn't really look like what
the end goal is supposed to look like.
Remember, they're in a vertical column.
So I think I have to change
the orientation of my layout, so
I'm going to go ahead and do that.
So I'll start typing orientation and
I want it to be vertical.
Okay, that's looking
a little bit better.
Now these Buttons were actually expanded
to sort of fill the width of the window.
So I probably don't actually
want to do wrap_content for
the Buttons,
instead I'm going to do match_parent.
So, let me change that right now.
Okay, so the widths of all my
Buttons are now match_parent.
Let's go to Preview.
Okay, that's looking better,
they expanded out.
All right.
Well, my text is still kind
of squished into the corner,
and to fix that I'm going to
use something called gravity.
Okay, here I am with a Google Drawing,
now let's make a text
box in Google Drawing.
Okay, so
this is a lot like the bounds of a view.
I could type the word Team A,
and by default it'll be
in the upper left corner.
And this is the same with TextViews,
when you put text in a TextView,
by default it'll be in
the upper left corner.
Now, with Google Drawings, I could
select this text and use basically
the equivalent of an attribute,
called a line, to get it to be centered
horizontally inside the text box and
centered vertically inside the text box.
Pretty cool.
Taking the content of the view and
moving it around inside of the view
boundaries is exactly
what layout gravity does.
And if you're thinking this might be
similar to some of the alignment methods
that you can use with relative layouts,
it is, but you can use the gravity
attribute with linear layouts,
which is what makes this powerful.
We'll take a look at it in code.
So, I'm going to take my first TextView
and I'm going to start typing gravity.
Okay.
With gravity, I have two options,
layout gravity and gravity.
I just told you about
the gravity attributes.
So that's the one we're going to use.
Okay.
And then I have a bunch of options here,
and I think I want it to
be horizontally centered.
So, that's what I'm going to use.
And I'm going to go ahead and
see in the Preview what that did.
Doesn't look like it did much, but
actually there is a reason for this.
So if I click here, and let's zoom in
since it might be hard for you to see.
Okay, so
here we have Team A, and you can kind of
see the view boundary around it.
Well, if I were to tell you that this
was centered inside of the view,
you really couldn't argue with me.
It does seem to be centered inside of
the view, the view's just very small.
Going back to our Google Drawing,
it's kind of like if I decrease the size
to be just the size of the text.
It's centered, but
it doesn't really look very different
from if it were pushed to the left.
Okay, so
if I wanted to center within the phone,
I need to make the view stretch
the length of the phone.
Which is going to require
us to change the width.
Okay, so
back here I'm going to close my Preview.
And I'm going to go to the width here.
Instead of doing wrap_content,
I'm going to do match_parent.
Okay, let's look at our Preview again.
Zoom out.
Okay.
And that's looking a lot better.
It seems to be centered up.
So let's do the same thing
with the score here.
Okay, so I'm going to add
gravity to this as well, and
gravity in all the layout gravity.
center_horizontal and I'm going to
change the widths to match_parent.
Okay, let's check it out again.
Cool!
So, everything is centered up.
It's looking pretty good.
Except it's all really
kind of squished together,
there isn't a lot of breathing
room between these elements.
I'm going to give each of
the TextViews a padding of 4.
I'll start typing padding,
I'm going to do 4dp.
Remember the dp?
And I'm using just padding, not
padding bottom or anything like that.
And that'll provide 4dp
around the entire TextView.
Let's see what that looks
like in the Preview.
Okay.
That gives me a little bit more space.
I'm going to do the same
to the Score TextView.
Okay, now I'm going to try to
do the same to the Button.
Hmm, well that didn't
seem to do too much.
What if I make it a little bit bigger,
like 8?
20?
Hmm, interesting, so it seems to be
making the Button itself larger.
I don't want the Button
itself to be larger,
I want the space around
the Button to be larger.
And actually, that's a better job for
layout_margin.
Remember, padding is actually
adding padding inside of the view,
whereas margin puts
space around the view.
So we're changing this to layout_margin.
I'm going to do 8dp.
Well that looks better.
Now there's space around the view
in between these two views.
So let's go ahead and
do that with the other buttons.
Margin, not padding, layout_margin.
Okay, so that's looking pretty good.
Now if you chose different
attributes than I did,
like maybe you had the padding
five instead of four, that's okay.
Remember, at this point I'm just
trying to make things readable.
We'll worry about all the font sizing
and pretty colors at a later stage.
Okay.
And awesome work.
You are done with that step.