So the specific objectives of this lesson are for
you to learn how to compute edges from images.
We will look at how we can actually do derivatives using kernels and
neighborhood pixels, the concepts that we have learned again.
And with that, I'm going to introduce to you three different methods
of computing edges using kernels.
I will also showcase that as soon as image noise shows up into these images,
how it actually complicates the whole process of computing edges or
basically compromises the whole process of computing gradients,
which impacts how edges are computed.
And then I'll actually introduce a special type of an edge detector.