So we have these three
different situations.
For the first one find
the ten oldest gorillas.
Well, we're going to need, where,
in order to select out only gorillas.
We're going to need to find the oldest,
so
means we need to put them in
order by their birthdates.
And we want to find the top ten so
that's going to be a limit.
For the second one, list all the animals
in alphabetical order, ten per page.
We're listing all of the animals,
not some of them.
So we,
don't actually need where on this query.
We're listing them in alphabetical order
though, so we're going to need order by.
Since we want to get them ten per page,
we're going to need limit and
offset to put them into separate pages.
For the third situation, find out
which one species we have the most of.
First we're going to need group by,
to bin all the animals by species
using account aggregation.
Then we're going to need order by,
to sort by the result of that count,
and limit to get just the top one.
There's actually another way to do this
using a different SQL feature called
subselects, but with what you've seen so
far, this is how to do it.