First, let's look at the Pthread's thread abstraction and the thread creation
mechanism that corresponds to the mechanisms that were proposed by Birrell.
Birrell proposed the Thread abstraction and the Fork and
join mechanisms that work with that abstraction.
To represent threads, Pthread supports a pthread_t data type.
That's the thread data type.
Like Birrell thread data type,
variables of this type will uniquely be identified with an identifier and
will describe a thread, in this case a Pthreads thread.
They'll have an ID,
execution state, any other information that's relevant to the thread.
Most of this is not something that you will directly see as a developer.
Instead this is information that's used and maintained by the Pthread's library.
The equivalent to the Fork that Birrell proposes is a more
intuitive called pthread create.
It takes as arguments a start routine.
That's the equivalent to proc and
Fork, as well as arguments equivalent to the arguments in Fork.
It creates as a result and
returns a new data structure that's of the type pthread type.
And it's populated with all the relevant information so
that this thread can start executing.
It also takes as an input, a variable of type pthread attribute type.
And this is a data structure that you can use to specify certain things about
the thread that the pthreads library will need to
take into consideration when managing the thread.
We'll look at this in more detail shortly.
Pthread_create also returns status information that indicates whether
the creation was successful or a failure.
Last, the alternative to Join is pthread_join.
It takes two parameters, the thread structure,
that's the thread that need to be joined, as well as the status variable.
The status variable will capture all of the relevant return information,
as well as the results that are returned from the Thread.
The overall operation also returns a status that indicates whether the Join was
successful or it failed.
As you can see, these operations are fairly analogous to the operations that
were proposed by Birrell.
I would now like to talk, in a little more detail about Pthread Attributes.
As we previously saw,
there is a Pthread attribute-type argument to the pthread_create function.
This argument gives us flexibility to specify certain features of
the newly created thread.
For instance, we can specify the stack size, scheduling policy or
priority of the new thread.
We can set the scope of the new thread, whether it's system or
process, like what we explained in the previous lesson.
Whether the threads should inherit attributes from the calling thread,
whether it's joinable.
Pthread establishes some default values for all of these parameters.
And if you pass NULL as an argument to the the pthread_create function,
you will achieve that default behavior.
There's several calls that support operations on Pthread Attributes.
Pthread attribute init or destroy allow us to create and
initialize the attribute data structure.
Or to destroy it and free that data structure from memory.
Pthread set/get allows us to either set the value of an attribute field or
to read that value.
One of these attributes requires particular attention, and that's joinable.
To explain this, I will first need to explain some mechanisms that
are supported by Pthreads, but were not considered by Birrell.
The mechanism not considered by Birrell is detachable threads.
In Pthreads, the default behavior of thread creation is just like
what Birrell described.
The threads are joinable.
With joinable threads the parent thread creates children threads, and
can join them at a later time.
The parent thread should not terminate until the children threads have
completed their execution and have been joined via the explicit join operation.
If the parent thread exits early, the children threads can turn into zombies,
because they may have completed or
died, but not exited or have not been reaped properly.
In Pthreads there is a possibility for
the children threads to be detached from the parent.
Once detached, these threads cannot be joined.
If a parent exits, these children are free to continue their execution.
This really makes the parent and
the children equivalent to one another, with the exception that the parent
threads have some additional information on the children that they have created.
To detach threads, Pthread provides a pthread_detach operation.
That takes the thread data structure,
the thread that needs to be detached as an argument.
Threads also can be created as detached threads
using the attribute DETACHED state.
The value of this attribute first needs to be set to PTHREAD_CREATE_DETACHED,
because otherwise the default behavior for Pthreads is for
threads to be created as joinable threads.
So with DETACHED thread since the parent thread doesn't need to
stick around to wait for
the children threads to complete, it can simply exit using pthread_exit.
Here is an example of using pthread attributes.
First the pthread attribute data structure must be created and initialized.
This will allocate the data structure with sufficient memory, and
it will set its values to the default pthread parameters.
We can also adjust the values of the attributes using
calls like pthread_attr_setdetachstate or
setscope, or which ever other attributes we want to adjust.
For instance, here we are setting the detach state to be
PTHREAD_CREATE_DETACHED like what we described just a minute ago.
And we're setting the scope, the scheduling scope of the threading system,
to be the system scope.
This means that the newly created thread will share resources equally with
all other threads in the system.
Once the attributes have been initialized and set to the desired values,
the resulting data structure is passed to the call pthread_create