So, here's one possible answer.
Inside these parentheses,
is a select statement that
returns the average weight.
We call this table subQ,
because SQL makes us give it some name,
even though we don't use that name.
And then we're joining that
back to player's table, and
then doing a where restriction for
rows where the player's weight,
is less than the computed average.
Let's look at that in more detail.
First, start with the sub query.
It does an average aggregation.
Producing this little one
by one table called a subq.
Then, that gets joined
to the players table.
Making this one.
This then gets filtered, for entries
where weight is less than average.
Finally, we just take the name and
the weight columns.