[Male narrator] A* Search works by always expanding the path
that has a minimum value of the function f
which is defined as a sum of the g + h components.
Now, the function g of a path
is just the path cost,
and the function h of a path
is equal to the h value of the state,
which is the final state of the path,
which is equal to the estimated distance to the goal.
Here's an example of how A* works.
Suppose we found this path through the state's base to a state x
and we're trying to give a measure to the value of this path.
The measure f is a sum of g, the path cost so far,
and h, which is the estimated distance that the path will take
to complete its path to the goal.
Now, minimizing g helps us keep the path short
and minimizing h helps us keep focused on finding the goal
and the result is a search strategy that is the best possible
in the sense that it finds the shortest length path
while expanding the minimum number of paths possible.
It could be called "best estimated total path cost first,"
but the name A* is traditional.
Now let's go back to Romania and apply the A* algorithm
and we're going to use a heuristic, which is a straight line distance
between a state and the goal.
The goal, again, is Bucharest,
and so the distance from Bucharest to Bucharest is, of course, 0.
And for all the other states, I've written in red
the straight line distance.
For example, straight across like that.
Now, I should say that all the roads here I've drawn as straight lines,
but actually, roads are going to be curved to some degree,
so the actual distance along the roads is going to be longer
than the straight line distance.
Now, we start out as usual--we'll start in Arad as a start state--
and we'll expand out Arad and so we'll add 3 paths
and the evaluation function, f, will be the sum of the path length,
which is given in black, and the estimated distance,
which is given in red.
And so the path length from this path
will be 140+253 or 393;
for this path, 75+374, or 449;
and for this path, 118+329, or 447.
And now, the question is out of all the paths that are on the frontier,
which path would we expand next under the A* algorithm?