Okay, let's take a look at the solution.
I'm still over here at the MainActivity, and
I started off by defining two different arrays.
These arrays are related to one another, and
let's see a little bit more about that.
So this first array is a string array, and
it has the name of the columns that I want to bind.
What do I want to bind it to?
Well, they're the layout items in each of the ListView objects that I have.
Each ListView item that I have has two text views, and
they're identified by text view number 1 and text view number 2.
So the value of the WORD column is going to go to the text view number 1 space.
And the value of the FREQUENCY column is going to go into the text view number
2 space.
And this association is done purely by how I've ordered these arrays.
This is in position 0, this is in position 0, so they match up.
Okay, but I haven't actually done anything with these arrays, so
let's scroll down a little bit more and see where I actually do that.
Okay, so we're here the onCreate.
Notice how I'm grabbing a ListView instead of a text view.
These lines should look very familiar at this point.
And this right here is where I instantiate my SimpleCursorAdapter, and
it takes quite a few things.
Let's go through those.
Okay, so this first one is just the context.
The second line here is the XML for
the layout that I'm going to use for each of the items in the list view.
Cursor adapters are meant to be attached to list views, so
it's expecting this layout item.
Aha, and next over the cursor, which gives SimpleCursorAdapter its name, and
then I have those two arrays that I was talking about above.
And this last parameter is for
flags, and I'm not really passing any particular flags.
So I'm going to go ahead and scroll down a little bit more.
And just one more statement.
We're attaching the adaptor to the list view.
And if you did everything correctly,
it all comes together to look a bit like this.
Now, because it's a list view, there are some optimizations to get smooth
scrolling, and my list items look a little bit nicer than they did before.
Two more quick things that I want to point out.
If you're wondering what this is, it's a standard Android layout.
So, I didn't create this and neither should you.
But if you want to create your custom layout for the list view, go for it.
Also note, for compatibility's sake,
I'm using the Android support v4 version of the SimpleCursorAdapter.
Okay, so high five, [LAUGH] and congratulations on finishing the example app.