All right, let's do some more practice
exercises with Gaussian elimination.
Each of these systems could either have
a unique solution, no solution, or
infinitely many solutions.
The first system is x-2y+z=-1,
x-2z=2 and -x+4y-4z=0.
The second equation is y-z=2,
x-y+z=2, and 3x-4y+z=1.
The last system is x+2y+z=-1,
3x+6y+2z=1, and -x-2y-z=1.
For this quiz,
if there's a unique solution,
fill in the appropriate coordinates for
the answer boxes labeled x, y, and z.
If there's no solution,
check the box on the right.
If there are infinitely many solutions,
fill in these answer boxes
with the appropriate expressions
using the free variable or
variables as parameters.
So if x and z were the pivot variables,
then the expressions should only
contain numbers in the variable y.