So, let's now generalize k-means into expectation maximization.
Expectation maximization is an algorithm that uses actual probability distributions
to describe what we're doing, and it's in many ways more general,
and it's also nice in that it really has a probabilistic basis.
To get there, I have to take the discourse and tell you all about Gaussians,
or the normal distribution, and the reason is so far,
we've just encountered discrete distributions,
and Gaussians will be the first example of a continuous distribution.
Many of you know that a Gaussian is described by an identity that looks as follows,
where the mean is called mu, and the variance is called sigma or sigma squared.
And for any X along the horizontal access, the density is given by the following function:
1 over square root of 2 pi times sigma, and then an exponential function
of minus ½ of x - mu squared over sigma squared.
This function might look complex, but it's also very, very beautiful.
It peaks at X = mu where the value in the exponent becomes 0.
And towards plus or minus infinity, it goes to 0 quickly.
In fact, exponentially fast.
The argument inside is a quadratic function.
The exponential function makes it exponential.
And this over here is a normalizer to make sure that the area underneath
sums up to one, which is characteristic of any probability density function.
If you map this back to our discrete random variables,
for each possible X, we can now assign a density value,
which is the function of this, and that's effectively
the probability that this X might be drawn.
Now, the space itself is infinite, so any individual value will have a probability of 0,
but what you can do is you can make an interval, A and B,
and the area underneath this function is the total probability
that an experiment will come up between A and B.
Clearly, it's more likely to generate values around mu
then it is to generate values in the periphery summary over here.
And just for completeness, I'm going to give you the formula
for what's called the multi-variate Gaussian
where multi-variate means nothing else but we have more than one input variable.
You might have a Gaussian over a 2-dimensional space or a 3-dimensional space.
Often, these Gaussians are drawn by what's called level sets,
sets of equal probability.
Here's one in a 2-dimensional space, X1 and X2.
The Gaussian itself can be thought of as coming out of the paper towards me
where the most likely or highest point of probability is the center over here.
And these rings measure areas of equal probability.
The formula for a multi-variate Gaussian looks as follows:
N is the number of dimensions in the input space.
Sigma is a covariance matrix that generalizes the value over here.
And the inner product inside the exponential
is now done using linear algebra where this is the difference between
a probe point and the mean vector mu
transposed sigma to the minus 1 times X - mu.
You can find this formula in any textbook or web page
on Gaussians or multi-variate normal distributions.
It looks cryptic at first, but the key thing to remember is
it's just a generalization of the 1-dimensional case.
We have a quadratic area over here as manifested by the product
of this guy and this guy.
We have a normalization by a variance or covariance
as shown by this number over here or the inverse matrix over here.
And then this entire thing is an exponential form in both cases,
and the normalizer looks a little more different in the multi-variate case,
but all it does is make sure that the volume underneath adds up to 1
to make it a legitimate probability density function.
For most of this explanation, I will stick with 1-dimensional Gaussians,
so all you have to do is to worry about this formula over here,
but this is given just for completeness.