When we're clicking around in Xcode
setting break points and debugging code,
it's easy to forget the main tool behind
the scenes doing all the heavy lifting.
I'm talking about the LLDB debugger.
The LLDB Debugger, or the low level
debugger is what actually allows us to
set break points, step through code, and
see the state while the app is running.
Normally we interact with LLDB using
Xcode's graphical interface, but
LLDB also has a powerful
command-line interface too.
The LLDB command-line interface is
what you see here in the console of
the debug area.
It has many commands,
such as fr v, which is short for
the command frame, and
the sub command variable.
The command fr v shows
us all the arguments and
local variables that
are currently in scope.
So we can see that we have self,
we have bug, we have a shakeAnimation.
And if we look at the variables view,
this is the same information
that's available to use here
in a more graphical format as opposed to
this textual format here in the console.
And I'll type the same command,
this is just the shortened version,
the fr v, this is the full version and
we get the same results.
Now the entire LLDB command set is
rather large, so instead of showing you
each command, I'm just going to focus
on some of the most commonly used ones.
If you want to dive deeper into LLDB and
learn things like custom data
formatters or writing scripts for
LLDB then you can check out
the resources in the instructor notes.