As I was creating this course and
trying to demystify frameworks,
I kept realizing that frameworks,
they're just JavaScript.
There's no magic to them.
A framework is built up of
pieces of functionality.
For example, if we found a better
templating system than Underscore's,
we could swap it out and
give backbone a different one.
Well except that I learned Underscore's
template function is a real
powerhouse in converting
a template to rendered HTML.
We aren't ending here though, so
don't toss out your realizations.
In the following lessons we'll
be looking at larger frameworks.
The concepts that you've learned in
this lesson transfer over to those
frameworks too.