We obtained P of A0 given X0 through base rule, which should look very familiar at this point.
P of X0 given A0 is 0.1, multiplied by 0.5, and down here we get 0.1 times 0.5, plus the same probability for B0, which is 0.8,
times 0.5. As is easily seen, the 0.5 falls out, so we get 0.1 over 0.9 over a ninth, which is the answer for the first question.
In the second question we apply total probability. This is the formal definition of total probability,
which is the probability of A1, given previously in A0, times the probability of being A0.
And the same for B0 before, as you might easily recognize.
Now, turns out this hidden markov model is a funny one. Every single time step, it completely mixes.
The probability of transitioning is the same as staying in the same state, so you completely forget the history.
So therefore the answer to this question would be 0.5, or half.
But let me just derive it formally. The transition probability of going from A0 to A1 is 0.5, times our prior probability,
which is one-ninth, and we get the same 0.5 over here, times the prior probability of eight-ninth.
And if you work this out, you'll find that one-ninth plus eight-ninth is one, and therefore the 0.5 is the final result.
This is a really unusual markov model, where there's no memory retained from one step to the next.
This also means, if you now observe X again, and look at this probability over here, we can apply the exact same logic as before
because now our prior is still 0.5, and we get one-ninth again, with the exact same argument as before.
Before observing X0, we had a .5 chance of being an A, and it went down to one-ninth.
Here we still have a .5 chance of being an A. Therefore, the exact same math gets us down to one-ninth.