So here you can see
the onSignedOut function, and
it's pretty straightforward.
It just enables the sign in button,
and disables the sign out and
revoke buttons, and it just sets
a status text to be signed out.
That's it, you're done.
This app had many steps, but now you've
got something with a full sign in built.
Let's run it and see how it looks.
So here you can see
the application running.
I have my sign in button,
I have my sign out button and
I have my revoke access buttons,
the results are this little status text.
If I touch the sign in button,
what's going to happen first of all is
that the first error that came back,
came back because I hadn't
given the application consent.
So it's asking for my consent,
and then I'll say Ok.
Now you can see, it's signed in, and
it's signed in, and it actually got my
real name, my full name here, instead of
my email address, because all I provided
the application when I was
running it was my email address.
I now have my sign out and
my revoke access buttons enabled.
So if I touch Sign Out,
I'm actually signed out.
And if I touch Sign In,
I will sign in directly.
You might have seen a quick flash
as the intent was checking, but
now I'm signed in directly as myself.
If I revoke access now I've removed the
permission from the application to be
able to sign in.
So, the user has to
give permission again.
So, if I touch Sign In the intent will
come up, the arrow is triggered, and
it's saying, hey this wants
to look at my basic profile.
I'll say okay to that, and
then I'll continue, and get signed in.
So, now you have the full
sign in work flow going.
If you get stuck with any
of the code don't worry.
It's okay.
I've pasted
the entire code in the speaker notes.
You should be good to go.