Let's look at creating
an interstitial ad unit ID.
So we go down and
create another ad unit ID.
This time we select interstitial.
And first of all, for the ad type, you
can see that we also support video here.
That is because an interstitial
ad covers the entire screen.
The interstitial timeout defines
the maximum number of seconds that we
are willing to wait to
receive the interstitial ad.
If this time expires, then the
onAdFailToLoad method will be called.
And then we also give it
an ad unit name and save it.
So now we created an ad unit ID
also also for an interstitial ad.
Let's click Done now.
And here we can see the ad
units that we've created.
There are also lots more options
that you can set for ads.
For example, which categories
of ads you want to display.
You can do that by going here,
Allow & block ads.
And you can see lots of
different categories here, and
whether your app allows that
ad category to be displayed.
But let's go back to the main page.
And this is our dashboard.
You can now see the estimated
earnings for your app displaying ads.
That's it for
the basics of the AdMob interface.
There are lots more options.
For example, how you can promote your
app, or analyze the behaviors of ads and
users.
But those are more advanced topics.
But now, you know the basics of
earning money to show ads in your app.