When we talked about PThreads we said
that one of the attributes that's used
to specify the properties
of the mutex or
the condition variable when they're
created, is whether or not that
synchronization construct is private to
your process or shared among processes.
The keyword for
this is PTHREAD PROCESS SHARED.
So when synchronizing the shared memory
accesses of two pthreads multithreaded
processes, we can use mutexes and
condition variables that
have been correctly initialized
with pthread process shared styles.
One important thing, however,
is that the synchronization variables
themselves have to be also shared.
Remember, in multithreaded programs,
the mutex or
condition variables have to be
global and visible to all threads.
That's the only way they
can be shared among them.
So it's the same rationale here.
In order to achieve this, we have to
make sure that the data structures for
the synchronization
construct are allocated
from the shared memory region
that's visible to both processes.
For instance,
let's look at this code snippet.
Let's look here at how the shared
memory segment is created.
Here we are using the system VAPI.
In the gap operation, the segment id,
the shared memory identifier,
is uniquely created from
the token operation where we use
argument zero from the command line.
So the path name for
the program executable, and
then some integer parameter,
so in this case this is 120.
We're also requesting that we create
a segment size of 1 kilobyte, and
then we specify the areas
permissions for that segment.
Then using that segment identifier
that's returned from the get operation.
We are attaching this segment and
that will provide us with
a shared memory address.
So this is the virtual memory address
in this instance of the process.
In the execution of this particular
process in its address space.
That points to the physically
shared memory.
Now, we are casting that address
to point to something that's
of the following data type.
If we take a look at this data type,
this is the data structure
of the shared memory area
that's shared among processes.
It has two components.
One component is the actual byte
stream that corresponds to the data.
The other component is actually
the synchronization variable,
the mutex that will be used among
processes when they're accessing
the shared memory area, when they're
accessing the data that they care for.
So as to avoid concurrent writes,
race conditions, and similar issues.
So this is how we will interpret what
is laid out in the shared memory area.
Now, let's see how this mutex
here is created and initialized.
First of all, we said that before
creating a mutex, we must create its
attributes, and then initialize
the mutex with those attributes.
Now concerning the mutex attributes,
we see that we have here set the,
the pthread process shared attribute for
this particular
attribute data structure.
Then, we initialize the mutex with
that attribute data structure so
it will have that property.
Furthermore, notice that the location of
the mutex we pass to this initialization
call is not just some arbitrary
mutex in the process address piece.
It is this particular mutex element
that is part of the data
structure in shared memory.
This set of operations will
properly allocate, and
initialize a mutex that's
shared among processes.
And a similar set of operations
should be used, also, to allocate and
initialize any condition
variables that are intended for
shared use among processes.
Once you have properly created and
allocated these data structures,
then you can use them just
as regular mutexes and
condition variables in a multi
threaded PThreads process.
So there's no difference
in their actual usage,
given that they're
used across processes.
The key, again, let me reiterate,
is to make sure that
the synchronization variable is
allocated within the shared memory
region that's shared among processes.