Well, I'll tell you most of the time when I give a quiz, the answer is all of
the above or none of the above, but not really in this case.
The speed of the addition operation, you know, back in the Dark Ages,
you had to worry about the speed of addition, now addition is instantaneous.
Okay?
And by the way, last time I checked, 4 plus 2 equals 2 plus 4.
Addition is commutative, so
we don't have to worry about whether we add the noise to the image or
the image to the noise.
It's kind of weird to think if I start with some noise and
add an image to it, same value.
But what you do have to worry about, as I said before,
is the magnitude of the noise compared to the range in value of the image.