If we take a look at how I've
edited the buildApiClient function,
I've added a scope, new Scope("email"),
instead of the previous scope that we
had that was a profiles based scope.
Now, if you recall back
to the scopes slides,
the email scope is a much more limited
scope that just gives me access to a lot
less information than the profile scope.
And it makes your users feel more
secure if they only want to share their
email address.
Then you can put this scope, and
the consent screen will reflect that.
So now that I've changed it to this,
I just want to scroll down and
take a look at my connection code.
And if you recall earlier on, we had
this connection code that when we were
in onConnected, we then would retrieve
the currentUser from the PeopleApi.
By using
Plus.PeopleApi.getCurrentPerson, and
pass it the ApiClient.
We were then able to say
the person was signed in as
the currentUser's full name.
And you saw earlier when I was
demonstrating it, even though I just
gave my email address to sign in,
the UI of the screen updated.
And it said the person that
was signed in is my full name.
So I've set email Scope, and
I'm going to run this application.
What do you think will happen when I run
it with email Scope, but I'm trying to
access my full name, even though I'm
not given permission to do that?
Well, let's take a look and we'll see.
Note also that I've just put this
code within a try catch clause, and
you can guess why I've done that.
So I'm going to debug
the application now.
So here you can see I'm running
the application in the Android emulator.
And I have my new Sign In button,
and I'm presently signed out.
So if I click the Sign In button,
first of all you're going to
see the consent screen.
And the consent screen is
a much more limited one, and
it only wants to know
who I am on Google.
So now the sign in will begin,
and I hit my break point.
Now if you remember the code
was Person currentUser =
Plus.PeopleApi.getCurrentPerson and
pass it the client.
So I am going to step over
this line onto the next line.
Now take a close look here
down in the variables window,
we can see the currentUser is null.
The system did not allow
me to get this information.
So when I assigned it to
the response from this Person,
currentUser is actually null.
So when I try to set
the text on the label and
I set it to be currentUser.displayName,
of course currentUser is null.
So this will fail, and
it will cause an error in my code.
So if I step over this again,
we'll see the error, and
I fall in to the Exception handler.
And if I just go down here for a moment,
we can see the actual Exception.
It's a java.lang.NullPointerException.
And it's attempting to invoke this
interface method on a null object,
getDisplayName on a null
object reference.
So I'm actually erroring
out when I try to do that.
And the reason for that is I'm trying to
access information on a scope that isn't
actually available to me.
So how do we fix this?
How do we go about changing this?