I want to make the distinction between exploratory data analysis and
data visualization here.
Well, this addition to our graph,
coloring home games may seem exploratory in nature.
By this point in the pipe line,
we are already creating a polished visualization with D3.
And we've already discovered for
ourselves what interesting insights we want to communicate in our data.
Maybe we've performed our exploratory data analysis in a more flexible tool
like R or Python using ggplot2 or and matplotlib
While coloring the home games red and
making them slightly larger circles using the technique of double-encoding.
We're communicating something, but to a reader who doesn't know what's in
our data, or someone who may not actually look at the source of this, and
look at the D3 code to know that I'm coloring the circle based on whether or
not it's a home game, or not.
They have no idea what the red represents, or why it's important.
So, well, for us, the creator author of the plot,
we might have some sense of what's being communicated.
To the general audience, it's still very hard to interpret.