Welcome back to Computer Vision.
I hope it's welcome back because if you're jumping in now
you missed some really good jokes and some of the better lectures.
the, this one's okay, actually.
Anyway, today we're going to talk about extrinsic camera calibration.
We'll define what that means in a minute.
We took a little hiatus to talk about stereo so
you guys could get working on your stereo, and
stereo was our first look at multiview geometry, multiview cameras.
And we talked about how, in order to do real depth reconstruction,
we have to understand the geometry of what's gong on between the cameras, and
that's what we're going to start talking about today.
So, before the stereo thing, the stereo sections,
we introduced a projection, perspective projection.
And here is the model that we used.
In particular, we had a system where we went, where we had a center of
projection that was located at the origin of a three-dimensional camera system.
And then we derived from simu, similar triangles the location on
the image of the point projected down onto the image plane.
And then in order to figure out where the point was going to land on the image,
we just eliminated that last coordinate.
Now we said that this was a bit of an issue because this division by Z
was non-linear.
And because we had to pull out the particular Z,
it wasn't a constant Z, it was the particular Z.
So we introduced this notion of homogeneous coordinates.
And the homogeneous coordinates essentially added an,
another component to the vector.
And if it was 2D, it became a three long vector, 3D became four.
And the idea was, that we were going to be able to convert from
homogenous to non-homogenous when we needed it.
But before we did that,
all of our operations could be done through matrix multiplication.
Which, by the way made homogenous coordinates, the whole thing,
invariant under scale.
I could scale a coordinate, homogenous coordinate by anything and
when I did the, the normalization, divide by w here.
It would go away.
And, one of the reasons we did this is we said that perspective projection
could now be done as a matrix multiplication.
So, here I've written, one, one, and here, we've got 1 over f.
And by the way, just to make life easier, I'm using the absolute value of z, so
we don't have to worry about z being positive or negative.
So, when I do the multiplication, I get this homogeneous coordinate.
And when I want to normalize and
go to unhomogeneous, I get the u v by dividing it out.
But in all of this discussion about projection,
we have the notion of a camera's coordinate system.
By the way, I'm going to go like this.
And it's not some like, weird curse in Georgia.
It's, it's a coordinate system, one, two, three.
Okay, so we have an origin and a coordinate system.
And we said that we put the center of projection at the camera's
coordinate system.
And we have the z axis, the optic axis going down the z axis.
So to do geometric reasoning about the world, we need to know,
we need to be able to relate the coordinate system of the,
I guess I'm going to have to do this.
We have to relate the coordinate system of
the world to the coordinate system of the camera.
And, in fact, today, what we'll do is the coordinate system from the world to
the camera, and then next, I don't know,
today, I don't know when you're going to watch it, next month.
The next lesson will be the coordinate system from the camera 3D
coordinate system, to the image.