So now let's dive deeper and try to
understand what we can do with videos
and use them to generate a panorama.
Of course, this is the video,
you've seen it before.
And what we are interested in,
if you remember,
is when you talked about
video representation,
what really is happening is that
the local x y coordinates of each image
is stacked together in the time axis
to generate, of course, a video volume.
All right so this is what we
refer to as a video volume.
In this case I'm just showing you
a few frames of the sequence here and
stacked on top basically kind of saying
that in time, this is a stack of images,
this is my video volume.
But what we are interested in
really is kind of creating a global
representation of this.
So lets come out with a global
coordinate frame capital XY, and
rather than worry about time,
lets try to kind of start seeing
what we can do with these images.
So, of course that basically means
is if I can take these images and
move them around a little bit.
So you know, for example, this would
be an image that would be here,
other images from the back would be
realigned in different regions here.
Some of them might be the same images
because, as you notice sometimes,
the motion might be slow.
And of course, getting all of these
images together in this format and
then doing what we actually know how
to do, that is registering images.
Remember the stabilization
algorithm could also be used for
doing this kind of registration or even
the kind of simple methods that we've
looked at that is finding features and
doing ransack and
all of that kind of stuff to align those
features together to create, of course,
a wide field of view image like this.
Using this, we can of course generate
a panorama, which is shown here, but
more importantly what we also need to
do is identify regions that actually
are the ones that are dynamic.
That after I build this panorama,
those pixels are moving.
For example in this case the pixels will
be moving where all the water flow is.
In the case of this actual approach
by they actually suggested that you
can manually paint out the regions
where the dynamic motion was.
I leave it up to you to start thinking
about various methods we can come up
with to actually do this automatically,
and
in fact if you think about the kind of
stuff we did with video stabilization,
where we actually look for background
and foreground, some of those types of
approaches could also be used to
kind of generate this automatically.
That is finding which pixels are moving
after I will build the panorama, and
also asking questions about,
okay now I have a region
where just the motions are.
We would now actually use those to
generate, of course, moving parts.