So now that you've written the callback,
and you actually have a handle on a map
object, the next thing to do is to
write the code for the buttons.
To do this, you're going to
work in the onCreate function.
And for each of the buttons, you're
going to create an onClickListener.
Within the onClickListener,
a function that gets called, you're
then going to set the mapType property
of the GoogleMap to the relevant type of
map that you want, based on the button.
So, for example.
If you want a hybrid map, you would set
the mapType property of the GoogleMap,
to the constant that
defines a hybrid map.
These types and these constants can
actually be found on the GoogleMap
object itself.
Take a look at the documentation and
you'll find them.
When you're done creating all of this,
check this box.