Now, you may be wondering
why we are spending so
much time talking about cameras and
how that relates to VR.
Well, to answer that let me show you an
example of an image that gets rendered
on your smartphone screen.
See how there are two views of
the scene that look almost identical?
For VR, we need to generate
two slightly offset images.
One for each eye.
You can see that clearly if you look at
close objects like the 71 on the screen.
When viewed through an HMD, our brain is
then able to magically fuse these images
into a single perceived image
through a process called stereopsis.
This process allows us to infer
the depth of objects in the scene,
which is super cool.
Now to actually create an image like the
one shown, we need to use not only one
but two cameras in unity to
render the scene for each eye.
In order to correctly
fuse the images together,
we need to make sure we also set the
cameras in unity by the same distance as
the distance between the center
of the two lenses on our HMD.
This distance is called the lens
separation distance or LSD for short.
And no, not the acid.
The LSD is tied very closely to
the interpupilary distance or
IPD, which is the physical distance
between the centers of our eyes.
IPD generally range anywhere
from 52 to 78 millimeters, but
average around 63 millimeters.
If a headset doesn't include
an adjustment for the LSD,
it will most likely be
around the average IPD.
This is because for maximum comfort, you
want your IPD to be the same as the LSD,
which should be the same distance
between the virtual cameras.
So when playing with VR,
those values are pretty important.
So let's measure them.