In the next project, you'll be
extracting color and gradient features
from images and training
a classifier to identify vehicles.
In the very beginning of this lesson, we
mentioned that you could also approach
this problem with deep neural networks.
So Drew,
how does deep learning fit in here?
>> Well as it happens, the methods we
describe in this lesson were considered
state of the art up until
just a few years ago.
Since then, various groups have
made incredible progress using
deep neural networks for
the task of optic recognition in images.
>> So, if you were to compare the
process of using deep neural networks
for detecting images versus
traditional computer vision,
how would you say they're
fundamentally different?
>> Great question, in this lesson we
showed you how to extract color and
grading features by hand,
a process that's also known
as feature engineering.
After that, you trained a classifier and
ran a search for objects in an image.
With a deep neural network,
you're essentially performing
all these steps at once.
In training the network,
you derive the optimal set of features
to locate the object
you're searching for.
And you can even train
a network to locate objects,
wherever they are in the image.
>> Awesome, so, in this lesson,
we're sort of doing by hand what
a neural network can do automatically?
>> That's right, and while it might seem
like a lot of work to manually extract
features and search for objects and
images, neural nets can sometimes
seem like a black box, where it's hard
to visualize what's going on inside.
With the more traditional approach
we looked at in this lesson,
it's actually possible to conceptualize
what's going on inside a neural network.
>> Later in the program you'll get
a chance to try using deep neural
networks for image classification and
behavioral cloning.
But for right now, enjoy the project.
It's a great portfolio project and
I think you'll have a lot of fun.