So here we are at the course map and I want to take a minute
to talk about some big ideas that we will learn together. In this course, we
will start out with ideas that we
are somewhat familiar with. This includes functions, functions
like the simple print ("Hello World"). Soon
however, we will move onto learning new ideas.
[SOUND]
These ideas include classes and object oriented programming. Now, this
is a technique that's used by software engineers on a daily basis. And they
can use this technique to write and share code amongst each other. Now, while
we will start with functions in lesson one, we will spend most of our time
in the course right here, learning about
classes. Oh, but the way, all programs in
this course are written in the Python
programming language. So, let's begin by downloading Python.