So the first option here is
saying the VA needs to manage, or
the CIO who's explaining why
they got the poor grade.
It's talking about a huge
number of devices.
So this is how the complexity
gets you reason saying no
we have such a huge problem, okay?
And that's why we not
able to fully address it.
And actually this is one of
the explanations he gave.
The next option here says lack of sense
of urgency in fixing vulnerabilities.
And the CIO actually did not
say he did say that you know
they take vulnerabilities seriously,
so this wasn't that reason.
The last option here is choosing
to support key functions
even when this could
introduce vulnerabilities.
This is kind of interesting.
We say sometimes security
gets in the way.
These organizations have
to get certain things done.
And when it you have to choose between
you know not being able to do something
and having security of course you're
going to say no, this needs to get done.
And even if there's some vulnerability
that exists, I have to take the risk.
Because the risk of not being
able to do it is, is greater.
So the CIO actually did say that there
are situations where they run into
that they must support certain functions
knowing very well that support
those functions are critical.
They need to be supported, but
supporting them is going to
introduce certain vulnerabilities