So let's take a look at the code for
sending the purchase hits to Analytics.
In order_dinner.xml you add the code for
the purchase button.
And the onClick is purchaseCart.
And the initial visibility is invisible.
It's not visible when we
first go to this page.
So over in the orderDinnerActivity
class, we have the method purchaseCart,
which gets invoked when somebody
clicks the purchase button.
And again for now we're glossing
right over the actual implementation
of the purchase and
just popping up a toast, and
then we call a method to
send the hit to Analytics.
So for
learning purposes we're going to assume
that the currently selected
dinner is in the cart.
And we're going to buy
whatever's in the cart,
which means we're going to buy
the currently select dinner.
So we create the product as before,
set the variant to be
the currently selected dinner.
And of course in actual production
code you wouldn't do this,
what you would do is you'd iterate
over the items in the cart and
create a product object for each one.
Then we create a unique transaction ID.
And you need to have one transaction
ID for each purchase transaction or
each refund transaction.
So it really does need to be
unique to the actual transaction.
Recreate the product action.
We set the action to ACTION_PURCHASE and
then also we set the transaction ID.
And then we send the hit, remembering
to change the action to be Purchase.
We set product to product, and we set
the product action to productAction.
And then in the utility class,
I just added some code to create
a unique transaction based upon
the current time and the product id.
And if you came up with your own
different way of creating a unique
transaction, that's perfectly fine.