Before you can run any
sign in applications,
you need to get a key that gives access
to the Google sign in Android API.
This is pretty easy to do, but
it does involve taking a few steps
outside of Android Studio for
the time being.
First, you need to get the SHA1
fingerprint for your app.
Google uses this as a way to
identify your application.
So it can give your app a good service.
This fingerprint is a machine-readable
attribute of a certificate,
a way of determining that
the certificate is real.
And just like the real world,
a certificate is a sign of an authority,
where you can call upon a third party
to certify that you
are who you claim you are.
Now we're just going to use
a debug certificate for
this, as it's easier for
learning purposes.
A debug certificate is
issued by you to yourself.
And later, when you want to release
your app on the Play Store,
you'll need a publication certificate,
which is going to be verified by Google.
To do that,
you can follow the instructions on
the developer website linked below.
First, to get the debug certificate, you
have to locate your key store file for
debugging using your terminal.
It's called, imaginatively enough,
debug.keystore.
One a Mac or Linux,
it's that squiggle slash dot android.
So if I type cd ~/.android,
I know it's in this directory.
If you're using Windows,
it's at C:/users/yourusername/.android.
In both cases the .android
folder is hidden by default.
So you may need to set your
system up to show hidden files.
So now once I'm in this directory,
the next thing I'll do is to
get the SHA1 fingerprint.
And I do that with this command,
the keytool command.
Now with the keytool command, I tell it
that the keystore is at ~/.android and
in this directory is a debug.keystore.
I then just give my
-storepass android and
my -keypass android as dummy ones
to generate a debug certificate.
So if I press Enter on this line, we'll
now see that I have my alias, which is
androiddebugkey, and I have a number
of different things for my certificate,
including the fingerprints in MD5,
in SHA1, and in SHA256.
The SHA1 is the one that
you're going to be using.
So keep this window open, and make sure
you understand that this is the one that
you're going to use, and that you
can copy all of this out of here.
Next, you're going to go to
the Google developer's console, and
in the Google developer's console,
you'll be using this.