Okay let's look at the first statement.
The planes defined by the equations
have a common intersection.
This is definitely necessary for
the system to have a unique solution.
Having a common intersection point means
that there is a solution to the system.
However, it could be the case that
the planes have more than one common
intersection point.
So, having a common intersection point
isn't sufficient proof that the system
has a unique solution.
Second, there are no equations
of the form 0 = 0 or
0 = k found during Gaussian elimination.
It might be tempting to say that
this property is related to
having unique intersections.
But it turns out that this property
is neither necessary nor sufficient.
Why is this the case?
Let's consider the system x
+ y + z = 0 and y + z = 1.
If we solve the system, we never get
an equation of the form 0 equals 0.
In fact, the only operation we can
do is to subtract equation two
from equation one, giving us x = -1.
The solution set is a line that
can be parametrize as X, Y,
Z equals negative one one line is E and
Z.
In other words, we have an infinite
number of solutions, even though,
we never saw a Euro equal zero.
So never seeing zero equals zero,
is not sufficient to say we
definitely have a unique solution.
On the other hand, we can run into
instances of zero equals zero and
still have a unique solution.
Let's look at the system which
we saw in the previous quiz.
The fourth equation is equal
to the first equation.
Plus two times the second equation.
So during L.C. elimination,
it will be reduced to zero equals zero.
Nevertheless, the system has
a unique solution (0,1,-1).
Let's look at the third
statement in the list now.
There are exactly three
equations in the system.
Well, we actually just saw a system with
four equations but with unique solution.
So certainly, this property isn't
necessary, nor is it sufficient.
Since we've actually seen plenty of
systems with exactly three equations,
which have either infinitely many or
no solutions.
For example, in a previous exercise,
we saw a system of the form x
plus 27 plus z equals negative 1.
3x plus 6y plus 2z equals 1 and
negative x minus
2y minus z equals 1 and this system
had a line's worth of solutions.
However, there is a modification
of this third statement
that does have a relation to whether
a system has a unique solution.
If we change the word exactly
to the phrase at least.
There are at least three
equations in the system,
then the property does become necessary.
But not sufficient for
the system to have a unique solution.
We've already talked
about this geometrically
since we showed that two planes
cannot intersect in a single point.
But we'll see an algebraic reason,
which ends up being more generalizable
after we consider the last
statement of the quiz.
After reaching triangular
form each variable
is a lead variable in
an equation in the system.
This statement is both necessary and
sufficient for
a system to have a unique solution.
Under the assumption that we don't
run into any zero equals k equations.
Also, each variable
that is a lead variable
in an equation after
reaching triangular form.
Could be solved for any variables
left over cannot be solved for and
will end up being parameters for
an infinite family of solutions.
Thus, having all variables be
leading variables in triangular form
is equivalent to saying there
are no free parameters.
That is, each variable can be solved for
explicitly.
This last statement gives us
a useful computable criterion.
For determining whether a consistent
solution will have one or
infinitely many solutions.
We just run the Gaussian elimination
algorithm until the system is in
triangular form.
And then, check whether all
the variables appear as leading terms in
the resulting system.
This criterion also explains why
the statement "there are at least
three equations in
the system" is necessary.
For a system to have a unique solution,
because if there were fewer
than three equations.
Then there won't be enough equations for
all the variables to show
up as leading variables.
Meaning, there isn't a unique solution.