So the mediator, is essentially like watching over the, the height change of
the report and when that happens it will be reported to the mediator.
And the mediator will make note of it.
And then it will, I guess, request from the handle,
its new position and of proportion based on that resizing.
And then, it will then go to the file manager because this has changed and
request for the new lines to be passed on to the b port.
Mediator is, is a very object oriented solution.
That is, there's an object responsible for that invariant, okay?
And you could imagine at,
at run time introducing new invariants and turning them on and off, and so on.
Because essentially associated with, with an object.
Okay? In our case the text browser we had three invariants to maintain.
We would have three mediators.
Each one of them would express the knowledge or
implement the knowledge having to do with updating that particular invariant.