Well the answer here is clearly d, and the reason is, is that basically when I
move my camera, since essentially cap X, capital X,
capital Z don't change, all right?
Where the image, where the point of the moon lands on my,
on my image plane, it doesn't change either.
Now it'll change if I rotate, of course, but
we're just talking about translating.
Now, pretty soon I'll translate right out of the field of view and
Megan's going to get unhappy because I'm going to come back here.
But if you've ever been driving along and you see the moon and
it just sort of follows you, okay?
That's because the X and Z,
well the Z's not changing at all if I'm going this way.
And the X is changing maybe by miles, okay?
But the moon is, what is it?
It's like 200, I don't know.
It's really, really far away.
Somebody look up the, the, I think it's a quarter million miles,
something like that.
Anyway, a lot's, lot, a lot shorter than the distance between here and Roswell.
So, as I go all the way from here to Roswell, the X hardly changes,
the Z hardly changes, so where it appears on my image doesn't change.
And basically, this is why things that are very far away don't move as,
as I move.
The only thing that matters are the angles, so this is true for the sun or
the North Star or these kinds of things.
And that's, and, and it's because of this perspective projection.