Okay, so to change this logo
to the new one, the white one,
we'll need to select this element and
then change the source attribute.
We'll start with our D3
select statement, and
we'll use the header logo ID to
select the parent element A tag.
And then we'll pass on the image
to select the nested image below.
We want to change the attribute and
in particular,
the source attribute will change
it to assets/udacitywhite.png.
And sure enough, our logo changed.
Note there were slough of other answers
here, so if you did something else and
it worked, great work.
Just keep in mind how many
different selectors or
how complicated your
selection syntax is.
Usually the more simple you can make it,
then the easier will be for
others to understand
what you're trying to do.
A couple other solutions
are included here.
You might have used
the class of navbar-brand,
and then selected the image,
that would've worked.
Or you might have used
the class of logo, and
then selected the image,
that would work as well.
And as some additional information,
you're also able to include the HTML tag
name before the class or
the ID name in order to select it.
So we could've added a in
front of the logo class, and
selected our child image tag.
The same would've worked for
the class navbar-brand.