Apparently the app shows dummy data
that was hard coded into the XML file.
Let's make the actual
weather data appear on screen
using the forecast adapter.
For now we'll use the same layout for
all list items, but
we'll incorporate the today
XML layout in the next video.
Conceptually the forecast adapter
manages the logics so that for
each row of cursor we create
corresponding list item.
Think back on the explanation in
lesson one about the array adapter,
except instead of
the datasource being an array,
now the datasource is a cursor
from the database The layout for
the list item is defined in
the list item forecast XML file.
For one row of the cursor,
we're going to go through and
extract out the values.
We call it binding the data to
the views because we take the value in
each column and
we set it on to a different view.
For example,
the high temperature value would be set
on to the high temperature text view.
The low temperature value will be set
onto the low temperature text view.
For the next row,
we bind the data in the same way
until we create a list item for
each row in the cursor.
Currently, our code
defines forecast adapter
as extending from
the cursor adapter class.
If you look at the documentation for
cursor adapter, you'll notice
that it's an abstract class.
There are two abstract methods that we
need to override, bindView, and newView.
The newView method returns a new list
item layout, but has no data in it.
The bindView method takes
an existing list item layout and
updates it,
with the data from the cursor.
In the forecast adapter
class in the newView method
we inflate the list item
forecast XML layout.
Then in the bindView method,
we bind the data from the cursor
to the individual views.
For example, from the cursor we
read out the weather description.
Then we have to go through the view
hierarchy to find the TextView
that has the id
list_item_forecast_textview.
Once we find the TextView, then we can
update it with the right description.
We've provided a gist of code for
the bindView method,
to help you get started.
But we left some to-dos in there for
you to do.
In the gist, we also included some
helper methods and strings for
date formatting.
That's because,
in our current implementation, all
the dates are displayed in the same way.
In the wire frames, though,
we have a more friendly date format.
Such as today, tomorrow,
Wednesday, Thursday, etc.
Here's the logic for
what the helper method does to
get the friendly date string.
If it's this week, it says today or
tomorrow or the day of the week.
If it's more than a week out, then we
use the format Monday June 8 and so on.
After you compile and
run the app, the actual weather forecast
data should now be showing in the app.
And it's using a more
friendly date format.
Check these boxes when you're done.