Since the side bar will appear
on every page of the site,
a new entry in the router isn't needed.
A template absolutely needs to be made.
Remember that a template
is a bit of html.
The sidebar will need html, so
we should create a sidebar template.
We won't need a service since this
new feature won't be used anywhere
else on the site.
We will need a controller though.
Remember that a controller sets
the initial state for a view.
What will the deal of the day item be?
Will it have a description or a price?
All of that information will be
stored in the controller and
passed to the template to be displayed.
A module is a container for
all of these things.
Since we just need a sidebar feature,
we don't need a unique module.