There are four constraints involved.
The first one has to do with the deposit operation, and the precondition, as
was stated in the requirements, is that the amount being deposited is possible.
But the post condition is a little bit more subtle.
In particular, we decided to keep a record of the deposits and
withdrawals in terms of a sequence of integer values.
The order of the sequence corresponds to the order in which those deposits and
withdrawals are made.
So the post condition for the deposit operation is that whatever sequence you
had of transactions at the start of the operation, at the end will have one more
added to it, which has as its value the amount that was deposited in that step.
Similarly, for the withdrawal operation the precondition is the same,
however it had better be the case that, as the requirements stated,
that the amount being withdrawn if the account has enough money in
it that you can make that withdrawal.
The way that we express that part of it is that the sum of the transactions made
so far is greater than or equal to the amount being withdrawn.
Post condition is similar to the post condition for
the deposit except the amount being appended will
be the negative of the argument indicating that the amount has been withdrawn.
The third operation is the balance query.
This has no precondition, but the post condition is the results returned by
the operation are equal to the sum of all the transactions so far.
That is, we go through them and add and subtract as appropriate to get
to the current balance, and return that value as the results of this operation.
Finally, one other constraint to be aware of, and this is the case for
all such models that you produce, you have to set up the initial conditions.
OCL has the keyword in it to indicate that, and
in our case the initial condition is that the list of transactions or
sequence of transactions is empty to start with.