Given a Bitonic sequence,
a network like this will sort it.
But given an arbitrary input,
how do you generate a bitonic sequence?
Here's what I'd like you to do.
Create a comparator network that takes
an arbitrary sequence like this one and
produce a bitonic
sequence like this one.
Do that by inserting one or
more nonoverlapping
comparators in each column.
You can use either plus or
minus comparators.
Now to help you get started, let me
fill in the first and the last columns.
Here's another hint.
Here, I've traced the values
of the first comparator bank.
That should remind you of the difference
between a plus comparator and
a minus comparator in
case you've forgotten.
So insert your comparators
by typing pluses or
minuses into appropriate
subsets of these empty boxes.