One of the problems with
the constructs that we saw so
far is that they require developers
to pay attention to the use
of the peer-wise operations,
lock/unlock, wait signal and others.
And this, as you can imagine, is one
of the important causes of errors.
Monitors, on the other hand,
are a higher-level synchronization
construct that helps with this problem.
In an abstract way, the monitors will
explicitly specify what is the resource
that's being protected by
the synchronization construct.
What are all the possible entry
procedures to that resource, like, for
instance, if we have to differentiate
between readers and writers?
And also, it would explicitly
specify any condition variables that
could potentially be used to wake up
different types of waiting threads.
When performing certain types of access
on entry, all the necessary locking and
checking will take place when
the thread is entering the monitor.
Similarly, when the thread is
done with the shared resource and
it's exiting the monitor,
all of the necessary unlock operations,
checks, any of the signaling that's
necessary for the condition variables,
all of that will happen automatically,
will be hidden from the programmer.
Because of all of this,
monitors are referred to as
a high-level synchronization construct.
Historically, monitors were included
in the MESA language runtime
developed by Xerox PARC.
Today, Java supports monitors too.
Every single object in Java has
an internal lock, and methods that
are declared to be synchronized
are entry points into this monitor.
When complied,
the resulting code will include all of
the appropriate locking and checking.
The only thing is that notify
has to be done explicitly.
Monitors also refer to the programming
style that uses mutexes and condition
variables to describe the entry and
exit codes from the critical section.
And this is what we described in
the threads and concurrency lesson with
the enter critical section and
exit critical section section sub code.