Hello again, welcome to lesson three.
>> In this lesson, we're going to be
talking about two things that can really
improve your dev ops approach
to the systems that you work on.
>> First we'll talk about continuous
integration and delivery, or CI and CD.
These are systems for
managing your software life cycle,
taking your applications code
all the way from the repository
through testing and into production.
And trying to automate all
of the steps in between.
The CI tool we'll be showing
you is called Jenkins.
>> And then we'll talk about monitoring,
which is just about my favorite
subject in systems engineering.
We'll be showing you monitoring and
data visualization using
a tool called Graphite.
>> Okay.
Let's do it.