Here's another company with a problem.
Swanky Chat is a start up that
makes communication software for
awesome people, but sometimes
their awesome users start sending
weird new messages that cause
their servers to crash.
Swanky Chat operations team calls
these messages of oncoming doom,
or MOODS for short.
Ops tries to get the development
team to fix the mood bugs, but
the devs are usually busy
writing awesome new features.
So in order to keep the servers up, ops
puts an application level firewall in
place that filters the bad messages out.
That works just fine, but so
as a consequence, nobody worries
about the MOOD bug anymore.
But then the developers release
a new feature, Perky Soundtracks for
video chat, and it works great in
their development environment.
It's fast and it's awesome and
the QA testers even love it.
But when it launches in production,
it turns out that the firewall rule for
the MOOD messages also blocks
the traffic for the soundtracks, so
the new feature doesn't work at all and
the launch is a big flop.
Debugging it takes a long time, and
the next three feature
releases are all delayed.
So what do you think
are the causes of this problem?
Is it that the development and
production environments don't match?
The new releases aren't tested for
performance?
That a workaround relieved the pain and
hid the severity of a bug?
That firewalls are unreliable and
should never be used?
Or that the operation
staff should be fired and
replaced with more
developers to fix bugs?