All right, welcome back to Computer Vision.
This is going to be our last lecture or lesson or
whatever this is on frequency analysis.
And I bet you're happy about that because it's kind of off in the ozone of
mathematics and it's going to, hard to pull it back to
the work that we'll be doing in terms of manipulating the images.
But it's important and in fact today we'll finally get to the,
what is coup de grace, piece de resistance my, my french is terrible.
The fine, what I really wanted to get to is the notion of how
frequency explains the notion of aliasing.
So if you remember we've been talking about Fourier basis sets where we
decompose things in terms of sinusoidal basis.
And this is a picture that we've been using to represent that.
And then we talked about the relationship between convolution in
the spacial domain giving you multiplication in the frequency domain.
And we showed it with the math here.
We said that if g was the convolution of some functions f and h,
that we could derive that convolution in the spacial domain was
multiplication in the frequency domain.
And that was shown like this.
And, by the way, then this is really important for today that
multiplication in the spacial domain is convolution in the frequency domain.
And you might ask, when do we ever multiply functions together.
>> When do ever multiply functions together?
>> Today.
It'll be some very special functions, but we'll do that today.
We also showed some Fourier pairs.
We talked about how the Fourier of a Gaussian is a another Gaussian.
We talked about an impulse is straight.
We spoke about the box filter giving you this sink thing that
explained ringing in that like.