Let's learn about some non-binary
classification models.
We've spent some time
learning how to prepare data,
and we also solved binary problems.
Now it's time to get to the good stuff.
In this section, we're going to
discuss three types of models.
Decision Trees, Forest Models,
and Boosted Models.
Then we'll talk about
comparing the models, and
how you'll know which
one fits the data best.
Before we go any further, let's discuss
what our actual business problem is.
Our company's insurance policy has
a reward based benefits offer.
This benefit varies depending
on what mode of transportation
an employee takes to work.
So our company ran a survey to
understand the mode of transportation
of our employees, and
sadly, only 60% responded.
What our management
would like to do then,
is to predict the mode of transportation
of the other 40% of our employees.
This would help us better estimate
what benefits we can offer.