When specifying
synchronization requirements,
it is sometimes useful to distinguish
among the different types of accesses
that a resource can be accessed with.
For instance,
we commonly want to distinguish
those accesses that don't
modify a shared resource,
like reading, versus those accesses
that do modify a shared resource.
Like writing.
For the first type of accesses,
the resource can be shared concurrently.
For the second type of accesses,
we require exclusive access.
For this reason, operating systems and
language run times as well supports so
called Reader/Writer Locks.
You can define Reader/Writer Locks and
use them in a way that's
similar to a mutex.
How ever you always specify
the type of access,
read versus write that
you want to perform.
And then underneath the lock
behaves accordingly.