Here's Xcode and is currently open to
our PitchPerfect app. I'm going to go
over some of the basic parts of Xcode
and we'll be diving into the code in
just a moment. On the left side, you see
the navigator panels, starting with the
Project Navigator. In the middle is the
content area and it's currently showing
the settings for our PitchPerfect project.
On the right side you have the
utility area with the inspector panels.
The file inspector is what's currently open.
On the bottom, you can see the debug
and console windows.
Unlike other IDs and editors you may
have used in the past,
Xcode only requires a single click
- select a file or item. Starting with the
Navigator panel on the left, there are
many different ways to view the files
and other parts of your project.
There are even more ways to move through
these panels using just the keyboard.
As an example, you can use the command or
apple key + 0 to toggle the Navigators
panel on and off. And if you're like me,
I think you'll find this useful when you
need more screen space. On the right side
in the inspectors panel, the number of
available inspectors currently to
depends on the content or item you have selected.
In the case of the project settings,
we can see the file and quick
help inspectors. As you progress with
this app, you'll be using other
inspectors too. Just like the Navigator panel,
you can toggle the Inspector panel too.
You can use this button here in the
top right, or you can use this menu item
to show and hide the utilities also
called the inspectors. Or you can use the
hotkey alt+command+0. At Udacity, we have
a saying that content is king and with
Xcode that is also true.
Anytime code or user interface
Storyboards are selected, they're always
in the center view and in the prime spot.
Again at the very bottom of the screen,
you have the debug and console panels.
The console panel, the one on the right
is where you saw Hello World printed.
In Xcode, the center content editor is where
you're going to spend a lot of your
time as an iOS developer. It can help you
to edit any part of your project, from
project settings to code to user
interface elements. Knowing that it's
context-sensitive can help you a lot
when you're looking for how to change a
particular setting in Xcode. When we
select the PitchPerfect project which
is the little blue icon here in the top
of the project navigator, we see the
settings for the entire project. We can
see the version of iOS that this app is
targeting and the main interface file is
conveniently called Main, which stands
for Main.storyboard. That's the file
that we see over here. We can also use
the project settings to decide which
orientations to support and to launch in.
Here you can see that we're supporting
the Portrait orientation as well as
Landscape Left and Landscape Right. If we
select the AppDelegate.swift file,
we can see that the Xcode content editor
changes to let us modify the Swift
source code. Something you'll also notice
is that Xcode automatically highlights
specific syntax to make the code easier
to read.
So by default, certain things like types
are highlighted in purple and keywords
are highlighted in this pink magenta ish color.
Let's take another look at that
Main.storyboard file we were talking
about earlier. When you select it the
Xcode editor changes to show you the
interface for this application.
Within Storyboard, you can scroll around and
adjust the zoom to see and modify user
interfaces in your app. Right click to
adjust the zoom level.
This is where we'll set up UI elements
for the app. I know it seems like a lot,
but we're going to walk you through step
by step and touch every essential part
of Xcode by the time you've completed
this course.