In the ForecastAdaptor bindView method,
we have to traverse a view hierarchy to
find the views in order
to set data onto them.
If it's a recycled view,
meaning it's been used in the list
previously to display other data,
we still have to traverse the view
hierarchy to find all the views.
To remove unnecessary
find view by ID calls,
we can use the view holder pattern.
For a list item layout that
contains different views,
we can create a view holder object.
It contains member variables that
reference each view in the layout.
The view holder object is stored
in the tag field of the view.
The next time that the view
is recycled and used again,
we can just immediately set
the data onto these fields.
You don't have to go
find all the views again.
This is our ViewHolder class,
you can name it anything you want,
it's just a java class.
Given the list item layout,
we do all the fine view by ID calls.
That way, we can hold references
to all the child views.
In the newView method,
after we've inflated the view, we create
a new viewHolder object from that view.
Then we set the ViewHolder
as the tag of the view.
The tag can be used towards any object,
but don't abuse it,
because when you read it back, you
have to know what you stored in there.
Then in the adapter bindView call,
we read from the tag to get
back the viewHolder object.
Now we immediately have references to
all the individual views that we need to
update, such as the icon view,
date view, description view, and so on.