Using this projection from the rule point to that image plane,
we get projection equations.
And we can compute the intersection, that is where x prime y prime is
by looking at similar triangles, kind of just like we did for the thin lens.
So basically this triangle and the projection triangle here,
these are similar triangles.
And by the similar triangles, basically get that the x, y,
z location, the location of the point, is now mapped to this point here which,
by similar triangles, is minus dX over z, minus dY over z, and minus d.
And here you can see that negative d issue, alright.
So basically what it says is the x is divided by z and multiplied by d,
by whatever that, essentially, focal length scale factor's going to be.
So, using that similar triangle and
knowing what the location on that point on the image plane is,
well the question is, what is the location in the image of that point?
Well, to get the location of the image,
we just throw out the last coordinate and basically it says.
Not basically, exactly, it says that x prime, y prime, which is the x,
y location in the image, is just minus d, X over Z minus d, Y over Z.
Normally in class I'd say, so any questions, but Megan understands everything
totally, and you guys are all brilliant, so I'm not going to worry about it.
By the way, one of the obvious implications of this dividing by Z is what?
Well, it's that objects further away are smaller in the image which is
something we all know anyway, right?
Take an object, pull it further away, and its size and the image gets smaller.
And that's because you're doing perspective projection and
the points are mapped to the values that are proportional,
X over Z and Y over Z, as Z gets bigger, X and
Y get smaller with respect to 0, which we're putting at the center of the image.
Do you hear that?
0 is at the center of the image under this.
So not at the top left hand corner.
So you may have to worry about that later too.