Lets imagine that you've just finish
the friendlychat app and published it.
At first you see that your
user base is growing, but
then you look over the analytics and
you start to notice a drop on
active users and user engagement.
For instance, in the database you notice
that some of the users are sending very,
very long messages.
When users are chatting with friends,
there´s a good chance they don´t want to
read the dissertation, yeesh,
just look at these messages.
These users are trying to coordinate
plans to go to the movies.
But at this rate,
they'll never make it on time.
Currently in the main activity, you can
see that there is this variable default
message length and it's set to 1000.
I wonder if these long messages
might be reducing user engagement.
And this would be actually be a great
thing to consider doing an AB test for.
You could run one to try to help you
find the best message limit length.
But for simplicity sake,
in this example at least, we're going to
use remote config to change the friendly
chat message length for all users.
Okay, here I am in the console, and
I'm going to go head over here,
scroll down, and open up remote config.
The first thing that you need to do
when starting out with remote config
is to create a parameter
in the Firebase console.
I'm going to scroll down and
click add your first parameter here.
I'm going to make a nod
towards text messaging and
set my friendly message
length to be 140 characters.
That seems like a tried and
true amount of characters for
friends to use while chatting.
I'll then go ahead and click add
parameter, and publish my changes.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now this is actually everything you
need to set up in the Firebase console.
But I won't know it's happening for
sure until I check the analytics and
see if my user engagement has increased.
Anyways, we're done with the Firebase
console stuff for now, so
let's go ahead and
jump into the app code.