Welcome to the second of
many quizzes in this course.
If you've taken a Udacity
course in the past,
then you already know the drill by now.
If you haven't,
you're in for a real treat.
These quizzes are Udacity's secret
sauce, and they're totally different
from what you'd find in
a traditional classroom experience.
There, the point of a quiz is to
figure out if you're remembering what
the instructor is saying.
Here however,
the quizzes are an integral part
of the learning experience itself.
And we give the solution to every quiz,
either as a video where we explain
the answer, or as solution
code in the course repository.
Some of these quizzes are super easy,
some are very hard.
And you're not always expected to get
the answer right on the first try.
That means you shouldn't
feel bad at all,
if you need to go check out external
resources, watch the solution video or
look at the solution code.
So let's do an easy quiz,
just so you get the hang of it.
Why do you want to make games?
Is it because it's too much fun not to?
Is it to make a little income
as an indie developer?
Is it because you want to prepare for
a job in the gaming industry?
Is it to make the world a better
place through educational games?
Or do you just fight for the user?