Here's how I implemented
the Reward Method.
According to the RewardFunction
documentation, the method takes a state,
a grounded action, and another state,
representing the state before
the action, the action taken, and
the state entered after the action.
And the method need to return a double
In our state diagram, notice that
we only have one action leaving each
state, except for the initial state.
Also, each action is deterministic.
Each will lead to exactly
one possible state.
Finally, all the actions coming
out of the initial state
have the same reward, zero.
So the reward function
in this particular MDP
will only depend on the state
the agent is in before its action.
Therefore, it's fine to just perform
a check on the argument s and
to disregard the arguments a and sprime.
Here I use the static getNodeId
method of the GraphDefinedDomain
class to retrieve the ID of the state
the agent is in before acting,
then based on the state ID,
I return the appropriate reward.
In States 0 and 3, the reward is 0.
In State 1, the reward is p1.
In State 2, the reward is p2.
In State 4, the reward is p3,
and in State 5, the reward is p4.
Finally, I include a run time
exception after my check
in the case that a state ID outside
of the range zero to five occurs.
This isn't a requirement for
the method to work correctly, though it
can be useful for debugging purposes.