Once you have a good understanding of how Storm is driving the basic D3
visualization, you can find inspiration starting in
Michael Bostock's blocks page.
This page, and blocks.org is an awesome place to start if you're looking for
really cool visualizations.
I wanted a word cloud visualization for this course.
So I searched word cloud blocks.org and clicked on the top link
to find Eric Coopley's awesome implementation of D3 Word Cloud.
The main difference between most D3 implementations I found compared to
what we are trying to do in Storm, with real time visualizations,
is that most examples use a static load once data set.
Here we see the frequency list that actually extends quite a bit to the right.
Inspecting further shows that Eric Coopley's implementation uses the format text
and size.
Therefore, our general process is mapping our data to the D3 format first,
then updating this dynamically to visualize.
So let's navigate to cloud.html and, in addition now to D3,
we pull in the app-cloud.js file and
the d3.layout.cloud.js file, both located in the static directory.
Scrolling down to the body and script tags, we see that the original static
frequency list has simply been updated to take in our d3.entries and
our hash function which is our associate array.
We then define our own variable frequency list that takes in the d3.entries of
the variable hash which is in java script in associate array.
Again, similar to the basic implementation, we select the body and
append an svg.
But here we have a d3.layout.cloud function that
uses a function words to bind the data to the frequency list.
In our own modification,
we use the same words function, bound to the frequency list.
And finally map the font size from d.size to fontSize d.value.
Navigating to our new app-cloud.js file we see
the basic structure has not changed but now our updateViz function
updates the same frequency list to d3.entries of hash, and
calls the same d3.layout.cloud function with frequency_list and d.value.
We then navigate away from the basic path to the cloud path,
ending in only /, and we see that with a few modifications,
we can use the same structure, the same data engineering pipeline.
And use open source D3 visualizations for
dynamic real time visualizations of data.
During our Hack-a-thon, Team A, or
Team Awesome, used a similar approach to find an open source map,
link this starting from the basic D3 implementation I provided.
And used color defined by Sentiment to visualize top tweets per county.
You'll see a few of their team members discuss their approach later on in
this lesson, along with their actual code provided as part of lesson four.