Following the hint, one way to do it
is to combine scatter and all-gather.
So visually, that would look like this.
First, scatter the input,
then do an all-gather.
The key assumption is that
all-gather uses bucketing.
Now there are many possible
ways to write the pseudo code,
which our auto grader probably
doesn't even really fully check.
But hopefully you came up with
something that looks like this.
Remember that these reshapes
are not actually physical copies,
they're just different
perspectives on their inputs.
This code uses a temporary array to
hold the result of the scatter, and
then sends that temporary array.