Now we'll start building the app itself.
First, take some time to create
a single blank activity app.
There is a mapping template available
that you might want to make use of later
but, in order to learn the ins and
outs of mapping,
let's create one from first principles.
Next, you want to edit your build
up gradle in the usual way.
In your Android manifest there's a few
things that you'll need to set up.
First of all is the meta
data with the references for
Google services,
just like in Build.gradle.
Then there's the meta for the API key.
Now you created the API key in
the developer console earlier on,
and you need to put the API key as
a meta tag in your Android manifest.
To see where you do that, take a look
at the developer documentation,
or we'll show you the answer
in the next node.
You're also going to need permissions
for internet, network state, and
write external storage.
And then finally you're going to
need a mega tag for OpenGL, as well.
Now most of this should be review to
you, but we've linked some Documentation
in OpenGL and the API key metadata
tag in the instructor notes below.
When you've done all of this and you're
ready to go, you've added each piece to
your manifest, you've edited your
Build.gradle, check this box.