Here are the values we get after
surging to level two of our game tree.
We can see that the values
are significantly different from when we
surged to level three.
Previously, we would have chosen
one of these three nodes,
because they received the highest
value in our evaluation function.
But after only surging to level two, we
see that it's actually the other nodes
that get a higher value in
our evaluation function.
So in this case our computer player
would choose one of these two moves.
And if it takes the move on the left
first, it would choose this move, which
is a different choose than we would
have made after surging to level three.