Our tearout for
this lesson shows you visually how
items in our RecyclerView get recycled.
We set a different background shade of
green to each item as it's created,
along with saving an integer
ViewHolder instance so
you can see the order in
which each item was created.
We use one of the views to show
the index in the underlying data source.
Cool stuff.
You can see that recycling in
practice is more complicated
than our animation shows it to be, but
ultimately, it works in a similar way.
There are a bunch of steps to
get RecyclerView working at all.
Rather than having you do all these
steps all at once, we're going to give
you an almost working bit of
RecyclerView code each time, and
you'll fill out a single
section in each exercise.
This allows you to verify that each
change that you've made works correctly.
For these four steps,
the app should work exactly the same
at the end of each exercise.
We'll begin by creating the
RecyclerView, then we'll add the list
item layout and ViewHolder,
then we'll add the adapter and
finally we'll wire things
out with the layout manager.
We'll explain this as we go along.