The first logic we will consider is called propositional logic.
Let's jump right into an example, recasting the alarm problem in propositional logic.
We have propositional symbols B, E, A, M, and J
corresponding to the events of a burglary occurring, of\ the earthquake occurring,
of the alarm going off, of Mary calling, and of John calling.
And just as in the probabalistic models,
these can be either true or false,
but unlike improbability, our degree of belief in propositional logic
is not a number.
Rather, our belief is that each of these is either true or false or unknown.
Now, we can make logical sentences using these symbols
and also using the logical constants true and false
by combining them together using logical operators.
For example, we can say that the alarm is true
whenever the earthquake or burglary is true with this sentence.
(E V B) E or B implies A.
So that says whenever the earthquake or the burglary is true,
then the alarm will be true.
We use this V symbol to mean or
and a right arrow to mean implies.
We could also say that it would be true that both John and Mary call
when the alarm is true.
We write that as A implies (J ^ M)
and we use this symbol ^ to indicate an and,
so that this upward-facing wedge looks kind of like an A
with the crossbar missing, and so you can remember A is for "and"
where with this downward-facing V symbol is the opposite of and,
so that's the symbol for or.
Now, there's 2 more connectors we haven't seen yet.
There's a double arrow for equivalent, also known as a biconditional,
and a not sign for negation,
so we could say if we wanted to that John calls if and only if Mary calls.
We would write that as J  M.
John is equivalent to Mary--when one is true, the other is true;
when one is false, the other is false.
Or we could say that when John calls, Mary doesn't, and vice versa.
We could write that as John is equivalent J to not Mary,
and this is the not sign.
Now, how do we know what the sentences mean?
A propositional logic sentence is either true or false
with respect to a model of the world.
Now, a model is just a set of true/false values for all the propositional symbols,
so a model might be the set B is true, E is false, and so on.
We can define the truth of the sentence in terms of the truth of the symbols
with respect to the models using truth tables.