Let's use sum of square differences to find the best match.
Let's initialize a couple of variables we'll need, and
then let's run through the strip, placing the patch at every valid location.
We extract the second patch of the same size from the strip at each location.
And then compute the sum of square differences, and
keep track of the x coordinate that gave us the minimum difference.
And that's about it.
Let's see how it works.
Okay, so the best x coordinate found was 145.
The top patch is from the left image.
Here's the strip from the right image you saw earlier.
And the bottom patch has been extracted from the right image.
Notice that the appearance of the top of the house has changed a little bit, but
our algorithm is still able to find it correctly.
Now, instead of using sum of square differences,
you could have also used cross-correlation.
Feel free to try out alternate methods.