So a color image is also a function.
It's just that the value at each location is no
longer a single number that represents the light intensity.
Instead, it can be a vector.
A vector that holds three different intensities for three color components.
For instance, each location in an RGB has values for Red, Green, and Blue.
These values can be separated into three different channels or planes.
If you take all of the red intensity values in an image,
you have your red plane.
Similarly, if you take all the green intensity values, you get your green plane,
likewise, for blue.
Given this scheme where each location is associated with a tuple of three values
and assuming that each of these intensity values is a real number, and
so are the values for x and y.
How would you represent this image as a functional mapping?
Mark the expressions that correctly represent the desired functional mapping.