Here's the answer.
The lower bound analysis says you take
the bisection width of logical network
and divide it by the bisection
width of the physical network.
So for example,
let's take fully-connected to hypercube.
Fully-connected is o of p squared.
Hypercube is o of p, so the ratio of
fully-connected to hypercube is p.
So the lower bound suggests you
should expect some congestion.
What about complete binary tree to ring?
Complete binary tree has a bisection
of 1, and ring has a bisection of 2.
So the ratio,
one half is less than or equal to 1.
That tells us there might be a way
to do a congestion free mapping
from complete binary tree to ring.
So you can do the same
exercise on all the options.