The user defaults in the document
directory are valuable tools, but
they're not very inspiring.
A complex app has a lot of
state while it's running.
I live in San Fransisco and I use an app
to keep track of the bus schedule.
While it's running, it's full of objects
that represent bus lines, bus stops and
schedules.
It even keeps a list
of my favorite lines.
These model objects are allocated in the
device's RAM while the app is running,
but I expect it to keep track of them
when the app is turned off as well.
That wouldn't be very good if it
couldn't persist some of the state.
If you have a sense that NSUserDefault
isn't a sophisticated enough system for
adding persistence to these apps,
you're right.
The next two technologies we're going to
look at provide a more complete
sense of state.
In this lesson, we'll look at NSCoder,
and after that we'll be ready for
Core Data.
First, let's take a minute to consider
what state really looks like in
a running app.