Suppose I start here.
I look to the left, and it goes down.
I look to the right, and it's going up.
So I'll take a step in that direction.
>> And
what do you do when you reach the top?
>> Well, we will get stuck, just like
we did with the n-Queen's problem.
There's no immediate step that I can
do that has a positive gradient.
Everything is negative.
That's a bummer.
>> Is that a problem?
Didn't we want to get to a maximum?
>> We actually want to get
to the global maximum.
Looking at the graph we can see
that there's actually a taller
peak over here.
>> I see but
our computer agent doesn't know that.
It can only see what's one
step away from it, right?
So how are you going to get on stock?
>> Well, what if I just
start again somewhere else?