How about shape from a single image.
So given R(p,q), so that means that we
know where the light source direction is and we know the surface reflectance, so
we can eliminate that or assume it equals to one.
Can we determine p, q everywhere, the surface orientation, uniquely for
every image point.
So here we have, you know, some random point and maybe its intensity
compared to the brightest point is 0.7, so it's somewhere on that curve.
But it's somewhere on that curve.
I don't know exactly where it is on that, in that p, q space.
So no, I can't sort of just simply from this analysis be
able to determine the total shape or the orientation at every location.
So if I want to do this, if I want to compute shape from a single image.
How might we do that?
Well, basically this is a, this is an example of an ill-posed problem and
we need some additional constraints.
We need some additional information.
Like the lighting is known or
boundary condition, or maybe even other information.
And in fact there are sort of two standards moves to make.
Basically one that doesn't really work and what that does.
The one that doesn't really work which we'll talk about in
just a minute is the traditional shape from shading and
that is we're going to add some addition constraints.
And the one that does work is you actually take more images with different light
sources illuminated, and that's called photometric stereo.
That, that has some real applicability.
So let's first talk about traditional shape from shading,
where you add more constraints.
Remember here was our,
our question given a single image of known surface reflectance, so
we know the albedo with a known light source, can we recover its shape.
As we said, that means given that R(p,q) can we determine p,q everywhere.
And the answer is well, I have to cheat a little.
No not cheat, I have to make some assumptions.
Assumption number one, is that for
example, at this boundary, which is already drawn in red, I'll do it again.
We're going to assume the shape is known, and
in fact, what you can imagine is that everywhere at this boundary, because it's
falling off, I know that the surface normal is 90 degrees from the camera.
So I know something about the surface orientation.
Then the other thing that I'm going to assume is that the surface is integrable.
What that means is, remember I'm recovering orientation,
orientation you're going to give us the surface derivative.
Well, the whole thing has to integrate to a depth of value, okay?
And then finally, I'm going to assume some sort of smoothness, and
I'm going to put this whole thing in some form of an optimization method.
Back a 100 years ago, I did a paper Yvonne Leclaire called direct height from
shading, I think it was called.
Which attempted to not do it quite so much in a, orientation based way, but
directly in a height way and
take the derivatives, it was a, running out of connection machine.
But basically the idea was, to recover the full height from this image, under
these relatively restrictive assumptions that you know the albedo everywhere.
That you know a the, the, the, either the depth or
the orientation at some particular contour.
We actually use stereo at the contour to get that initialization,
then we did shape from shading in-between.