So this is great--we now learned a lot about cameras and images.
We learned the Law of Perspective Projection
and we also know when things are in focus.
Now the first law is really important.
and the second law doesn't really matter that much--
but I put it in so you understand what the implications of using a lens really is.
Let's talk of when we're in Computer Vision
and what type things we can do with images.
One of the primary purposes is to extract information from these images,
such as classify objects.
So here is one of my son's favorite objects.
And he might be interested in understanding that this is a car.
A second purpose is 3D reconstruction.
So you might care to take many images of this object, from different perspectives
or with multiple cameras, like a Stereo Camera Rig
and ask yourself what is the 3D model that we can reconstruct from these 2D projections.
Or you might care about motion analysis.
This is a common problem in Computer Vision
where things might move and are seen in the video of many images
and you might, for example, care how do things move, over time.