Remember the only way you can
really know which one is fastest is
by measuring.
So that's exactly what I'm going to do.
I've got the site open and
I will click the click me button.
And you can see the times pop up.
The first one is about 3.3
milliseconds the second is 1.4, and
the last is almost 400 milliseconds.
The middle selector is
the clear winner here.
However, things get a little
bit more interesting.
In fact, while we were filming this
course, we came to find out that
this last selector's awful
time is actually just a bug.
In fact, let me show you these same
numbers using web kits nightly build.
So this is the bleeding
edge version of web kit.
And I will click the same button.
Can you see those numbers?
Let me zoom in.
Holy cow!
These numbers speak for themselves.
The middle one is still the fastest, but
that 400 millisecond operation is
now only about 0.06 milliseconds.
This goes to show just how important
it is to measure your performance,
because, as times change,
so do the numbers.
So, this means that, for the moment,
the middle answer's the fastest.
But hey, that can change some day.
Make sure that you use the tools at
your disposal to keep measuring.