In the last lesson you
saw the ping command.
Here's something else that it does.
If you take the name of a host,
say a website like yahoo.com, and
ping it, you'll see an IP address
along with the ping results.
The ping command has to look up
the IP address of the host first
before it can actually
send it a ping message.
Now ping keeps running forever
until you stop it with Ctrl+C.
Alternately, as we saw before,
you can tell it how many
pings to do with a -c option.
For instance, -c 7 will have it
send just 7 pings and then exit.
So now for an experiment.
Run ping google.com to see how long
it takes to get to a well-known host
at Google.
Type CTRL+C to exit ping.
What IP address is your ping using for
Google?
And do you expect that everyone
who's doing this quiz is getting
the same answer?
Yes or no.