So this concludes the lesson on calibration.
In the homework, you're going to use the theory we developed for direct linear
calibration, and we'll give you those images that have the three-dimensional
locations of the points and the two, and you get the images.
And you have to solve for the calibration.
And it's, it's interesting that you
can actually recover that relatively precisely.
In the next lessons, what we're going to do is we're going to move away
from the notion of rigidly calibrating the camera to the world.
And instead, we're going to talk about the relationship between
multiple cameras, specifically starting with two cameras.
And that's going to eventually get to the point,
where we were talking about in stereo, that if you know the relationship between
cameras, that you can know where the epipolar lines are.
So basically, if I gave you some corresponding points,
you should be able to solve for the relationship between the cameras that will
allow you to find those epipolar lines.
And that's what we'll be doing over the next three or four lessons