Let's open GraphPad QuickCalcs. We want to calculate p from the chi square
distribution. Again, we'll push continue, and we'll go to the bottom where we
input the our chi squared value and the degrees of freedom. If we compute p, we
get that our p value is 0.0891. This is not significant at 0.01 or at 0.05.
Since our industry standard is an alpha level of 0.05 and this does not meet
that threshold, then we're going to guess that there is no reason hire Summit
Up over another guide company. While this would be significant at an alpha
level of 0.01 let's say, some might consider this marginally significant. But
this is a %9 chance of committing a type one error. Meaning that if we don't
conclude that Summit Up is better than average at getting climbers to the top,
there's about a 9% chance that we're wrong and that these differences are just
due to chance. We're just going to make our decision based on if we meet this
threshold of 0.05.