When adding IBOutlets and IBActions in Storyboard,
it's easy to make a mistake.
You might connect the wrong
element to the wrong Outlet or the wrong
element to the wrong action.
When this happens what do you do?
Let me show you. I’m going to go ahead
and make some mistakes on purpose and
show you what to expect.
I've removed connections for all the IBOutlets
for our playback and stop buttons.
And I'm going to link an incorrect
element to an IBOutlet. I'll control drag
from the Play Sounds View Controller
down to our EchoButton.
Instead of selecting the EchoButton, I’m going to
connect it to the SnailButton.
Once this is done,
there's a special place that I can look
in Storyboard to see all my existing
connections.
It's called the Connections Inspector.
With the Play Sounds View Controller
selected in the Document Outline,
go to the utilities panel and will select the
connections inspector. It's the one with
the icon that has an arrow pointing to the right.
Here I can see all the outlets
for this View Controller, including the one
I made by mistake. If I hover my mouse
over the connection we can see that the
Snail Button outlet is connected to the
Echo Button.
this isn't what we want. To remove the
connection, all I have to do is click the
X next to the button’s name.
Ok. So that was one common mistake, but
what about if I incorrectly connect an
IBAction? So let's go ahead and break
some things. I'm going to remove all the
existing connections to the IBActions.
And this time I’ll connect the Stop Button
to the IBAction for playSoundForButton.
Instead of making this connection
from the Document Outline, I can actually
make it from the Connections Inspector.
If I hover my mouse over the empty
circle, will see a plus icon appear.
Now I can click drag and then select the
element that I want to trigger this action.
So I’ll click and drag over to
the Stop Button, so that the Stop Button
calls the playSoundForButton action.
Then a pop-up will appear for
exactly which particular action we want
to trigger our playSoundForButton
function.
The default is Touch Up Inside.
So if you have a problem like this,
it's as simple as clicking the X to remove
the erroneous connection.
Alright, there's one more common mistake
that I want to show you. First we need to
set this up.
Let's connect the Stop Button outlet to
the Stop Button interface element.
You can also do this from the Connections Inspector.
Hover over the empty circle
for the stop Button and then click drag
to the stop Button interface element.
And let go. okay with this connection intact,
I want to actually remove the IBOutlet
from code. Go to the
PlaySoundsViewController.swift file, and let's
remove the IBOutlet for the stopButton.
oh oh, now what's going to happen to our
connection?
Well, it's definitely going to cause a problem.
Since I remove the outlet, we
have now what is known as a broken connection.
We go back to Storyboard and
we look in the connections inspector.
For the stopButton, we now see this ! over
the connection.
This means that the connection is broken.
If we try to run this code, we might even
get a crash. To fix this, I can remove the
connection by clicking the X.
Then I want to recreate the outlet
in Play Sounds View Controller. I can either
create the IBOutlet in code or I can set
the assistant editor and do the control
click dragging method that we saw
earlier in this course. I just set it
back up in code. And then in the
Storyboard, I’ll make the connection
again.
Perfect.
Awesome. So those are three common mistakes,
and a lot of them can be solved
easily by just looking in the
Connections Inspector
So if you find yourself running into
these types of problems, the Connection
Inspector can be a lot of help.