All right, so I downloaded the play
arrow icons from the material design
site, and included all the versions
in their respective drawable folders.
Now I need to change the layout
to include these play arrows.
And we need to make this change
in our list item layout.
So this is going to be kind
of a tricky layout change.
Because currently I have a horizontal
linear layout as the root element for
my list item layout.
So if I were to add the play icon
as a third child in this layout,
then I won't get the colored
background behind it.
In order to have the play arrow
overlap the color background,
I switch my layout to a relative layout.
Now figuring this out took me a couple
rounds of trial and error and
I didn't get all the attributes
correct at first.
Also there are multiple ways that you
could've implemented the same layout and
this is just how I decided to do it.
So in our case I made the image view
the first child in the relative layout.
And since the views get added to the top
left by default, I didn't need to add
any special attributes related
to positioning this view.
Then here we have two vertical linear
layouts that contain the two text views.
So they'll have the same
colored background according
to the theme of the category.
So these text views should be aligned to
the parent's top right and bottom edges.
We also must specify that it's
located to the right of the image.
Otherwise, they would end
up overlapping the image.
Next, we can place the player
on top of the LinearLayout.
And so we add this as an image
view where the source
is pointing to the image drawable
that we added to the app.
Now in terms of positioning,
we want the play icon to align to
the right edge of the relative layout.
We also want to center
it within the parent, so
we specify here center
vertical equal true.
Now according to the red
lines in the quiz,
we want 16 dips of space from
the right edge of the screen.
So to do that we added a right
margin of 16 dips on the ImageView.
So when you make those changes in
the code, this is what the XML for
those items should look like now.
So here we have a RelativeLayout as
the root view for the layout and
then we have our ImageView followed
by the vertical LinearLayout
with two TextViews inside of it.
So to the LinearLayout we just added,
we need to add some new
RelativeLayout parameters to it.
And what I mean by that is that I
fix the height of the list item
to be a list item height dimensions.
Otherwise the color background wasn't
stretching across the entire list item
though I wanted it to.
And I did that with the three
aligned parent attributes here.
So align parent bottom,
align parent right and
align parent top are all set to true.
And last but
not least our relative layout.
We have a new ImageView for
the play arrow.
So it has a height and
width of both 24 DPs.
It's also aligned to
the right of the parent.
It's vertically centered and
has a right margin of 16 DPs.
And when you're done making these code
changes, don't forget to reformat that
xml to make sure that the attributes
follow the Android code cell guidelines.
And so here's how you do that.
From the project view,
highlight the file that you want, head
up here to Code, and then Reformat Code.
And when this pop-up pops up asking, do
you want to reformat the selected files?
Go ahead and click OK.
All right, so now we want to
run the app on our device.
Let's tap into the Numbers activity and
see how that looks.
Whoa, it's looking a lot better now.
So now we have the player showing up for
all the items in the list.
Let's double check for
all the other categories as well.
All right,
play arrows are in the Family activity.
We have play arrows in
the Colors activity and same for
the Phrases activity.
So now let's go back through and
test the audio playback to make sure
that it still works in each list.
>> [FOREIGN]
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[FOREIGN]
>> All right, so it's all sounding good.
And lastly we want to test that
the layout looks fine when we rotate
the device and end up taking more
horizontal space on the screen.
So let's check that for
all our activities.
All right, fantastic.
So the audio playback feature
is now more easily discoverable,
leading to a better user experience.
So a new user can tell that
clicking on a list item
will play the pronunciation
of each word.
Great job.