If caches are write-updated, then all
of the processors will be able to see
when the lock is released immediately,
and they will issue
a test_and_set operation.
So, we'll have as many memory references
as there will be
test_and_set operations,
so the complexity of the contention
is going to be order of O of N.
If the caches are write-invalidated,
then all of the processor's
caches will be invalidated after
that initial lock release.
For some processors, by the time they
reread the lock value from memory in
order to execute this
part of the predicate,
the lock will already have been
set to busy by another processor.
So those processors will try to
spin on the newly read cached copy.
So back in this portion
of the while loop.
Other processors, however, when they
reread the value of lock from memory,
that will happen before any
test_and_set has executed.
So they will see the value
of lock is free.
As a result, they will try to
execute that test_and_set operation.
Now, only one of these test_and_set
operations will succeed.
However, every single one
of them will go ahead and
invalidate everybody's caches.
That means that that
will also invalidate
the caches on those processors that
did see that the lock was busy.
For this reason, the complexity of the,
the input that gets created,
of the contention that gets created
when the lock is freed using that
test _and_set spin
lock is O of N squared.