What did you write, David?
>> So, I wrote the sentence as
Bill propelled a bullet into Bob.
I looked up the verb shot and
decided what that really means is
pulling the trigger on a gun, which
results in a bullet being propelled at
high velocity out of the gun's barrel.
So, it's fair to say that shot
becomes propelled a bullet.
Given that,
I now have propel as my primitive.
I have the same rule that says
an animate agent that immediately
precedes the verb becomes
the agent in the frame.
So, Bill is now my agent.
I have my rule that says an inanimate
object that immediately follows the verb
becomes the object.
So, bullet is now my object.
Even though bullet wasn't
in the original sentence,
it's by rephrasing it that
I can pull that object out.
And I can use the constraints of into to
determine that the destination
of the bullet is inside Bob.
>> That's good, David.
But know this sentence could have
another interpretation also.
Imagine that Bill had a camera, and Bill
will soon be taking pictures of Bob.
>> That's true, Ashoke.
And I bet if we had used Bill takes
a picture of Bob as the meaning of shoot
earlier in this lesson, that's probably
what I would've thought of first.
If I wanted to then put Bill shot Bob
in terms of taking a picture into this
form, I'd first rewrite it as
Bill took a picture of Bob.
>> That's really interesting, David.
Because notice if you say
Bill took a picture of Bob,
it's not clear into what primitive
action will this took map into.
Perhaps we can discuss
this more on the forum.
There's one more thing to notice here.
Like David says, I can have multiple
interpretations of Bill shot Bob.
This sentence doesn't help me resolve
between those interpretations.
Perhaps it is something coming
before this sentence in the story or
something coming after that
that will help me disambiguate.
From the sentence itself we can
simply construct two particular
interpretations.