Throughout this course, we're going to
use Xcode's debugging tools to fix
problems in the So Many Bugs app.
That's what you see here.
When you launch the app you should
see this scene selection screen and
it contains buttons for
different buggy versions of the app.
I'll go ahead and run the final
version that contains no bugs.
At least, no bugs that I know about.
The app's pretty simple,
it starts with this main screen and
has this ominous spider
web in the background.
And if I tap the screen,
a spider should crawl on.
So there's our first spider, and I'll
go ahead and spawn a couple more, so
that you can see them all
animating at the same time.
And one more.
If I select the gear icon in
the upper right-hand corner,
then I can adjust the types of
the spiders that we're spawning.
So I'll pick this angry
red spider here and
go ahead an spawn an angry red spider.
And let's spawn some of
the other types as well.
So I'll spawn a blue one.
And spawn a green one.
There's our green one.
So as you can see,
the black spiders are basic.
The red spider here is pretty fast,
kind of angry looking.
The green spider's smooth,
calm, and collected.
And this blue spider is just
kind of dorky and slow.
If you want to know more about
how the animations are done,
then check out the link
in the instructor notes.