Here I just wanted to show that even very short sequences can be identified quite easily
with language ID models based on letter frequencies.
So for the 3-letter sequence T-H-E, I have trigram models for 3 different languages.
And you can see that in language A there's a 1.1% chance of representing T-H-E,
which is 4 times more than B and quite a bit more than C.
For the 3-letter sequence D-E-R, that's 10 times more likely to be language B
than to be language A and quite a bit more than language C.
For the letter sequence R-B-A, that's 50 times more likely to be C than it is to be B and even moreso than A.
What I want you to tell me is what are each of these languages?
Where did this column of numbers come from?
Is language A English, German or Azerbaijani, and the same for B and C?