Before we leave you, one more thing.
You now seen what you can
do with App Engine and
the Google Cloud platform today.
But what about five years from now?
Let's hear what Urs Hölzle,
Senior VP of infrastructure at
Google has to say about the future.
In this course,
we learned a lot about App Engine.
Urs, what can we expect from
Google Cloud platform and
App Engine in the future?
A lot of innovation because what I'm
really most excited about, is that
we're just at the beginning of something
that, I think, is going to be really,
you know, we're proud of what we have
today, but what we're really aiming for
is getting to something that five
years from now, is so much better.
I think the rate of innovation that
we're going to see in the cloud is
going to peak up and
we hope to be a big part of that.
But our goal really is to take
what we have and make it so
much easier to scale, and so
much easier to program, and so
much easier to be on mobile, so
much easy, easier to analyze data.
And then really get a,
get a, get a platform for
you that is everything that it is today,
but much, much better.
Really to the point where if you
remember, what you thought was
great today, and we really have a great
product, that, you know, five years from
now, you'll kind of remember and
say wow, you know, I'm, I'm kind of,
I was naive to think that this was great
because if I look at today's product.
It, you know,
was really just the beginning of it.
I, that's what I'm,
I'm most excited about.
>> Do you have any final words to
the students that have now learned a lot
about App Engine?
>> Now that you know App Engine,
you're actually in a great position to
try out other parts of our platform.
And one of the things that we're really
going to work on is make it very easy to
combine App Engine with VMs or with Big
Query or with Storage, so that you can
mix and match and implement your
application not just in pure App Engine.
But really combine it with any other
part that we have in our infrastructure.
And still, have it be very easy for
you to both write and run.
That's the path we're on.
And I hope you enjoyed App Engine and
you'll enjoy the other parts even more.
>> That's right.
This has been just the start of what you
can do with Google App Engine and
with the Google Cloud tools.
>> So
keep your coding fingers up to date.
And stay on the cutting edge of
what's possible with cloud computing
because every day the Google Cloud
platform becomes better and better.
>> So now you have all kinds of
tools to build great applications.
>> And scale them on the Google Cloud.
>> So go out there and
build something cool.
And we'll see you around.
>> Bye.