For a sequential
processor with a slow and
a fast memory, recall the basic concept
of the balance point of the machine.
In terms of our cartoon, it's R,
the peak rate of processing,
divided by peak memory bandwidth.
Let's also recall the historical
growth trends of R and beta.
The rate of improvement in
computation far outstrips
the rate of improvement
in communication.
This gap doubles about once
every five and a half years.
So, for your algorithms,
what does this mean?
It suggests that it might be beneficial
to trade off more computation for
less communication.
Let's be a little bit more
analytical about this claim.
Start with the DAG model of computation.
In it, you characterize
a computation by two components.
The first is the work or
the total number of operations,
which I'll denote by W or W(n).
The second is the span or
critical path length.
We call that D(n) or D for short.
Let's augment this representation
to reason about slow fast memory
communication.
In particular, remember that you can,
at least in principle, count the number
of slow fast memory transfers.
I'll denote these transfers by Q.
Q will in general be a function
of the problem size,
the size of fast memory and
the transaction size.
I'll also assume by convention
that W includes the count of Q.
So, for example, if Q is three and
W is ten, then that means there
are ten minus three or seven operations
that are non-memory transactions.
Let's also modify our machine
cartoon a little bit as well.
As before,
there will be a large slow memory,
as well as a small finite capacity
fast memory of size Z words.
When data moves between slow and
fast memory,
it does so in transactions
of size L consecutive words.
In addition, let's let the processor
have P processing cores.
Let's assume that each core can execute
some number of operations per unit time.
We'll call that rate R0.
Let's model the operation of memory
by analogy to the way the cores work.
Each transaction initiates
a data transfer across these
L wires in parallel.
The time it takes for
a word to go across a wire is beta 0.
In other words, beta 0 is the analog
of R0 in this cost model.
And remember, W, D, and
Q count the number of operations
ignoring these costs.
Put differently, we usually compute W,
D, and Q assuming unit cost operations.
But in a high performance setting,
let's try translating unit costs into
real costs to see what they
imply about the overall system.
Conceptually, you can account for
non-unit costs by
transforming a unit cost DAG.
For example,
consider some node in the unit cost DAG.
Suppose this node is one
of the compute operations.
Then executing it costs
1 over R0 time units.
So we could replace this single
unit cost vertex with a sequence
of 1/R0 unit cost vertices.
Now, what if a node in the DAG instead
represents a memory transaction?
Let me suggest that we model
transactions in the following way.
First, there's a latency cost which
is the same as the latency cost for
the compute operations.
In other words, the memory transaction
became 1/R0 unit cost nodes.
After all, a memory transaction
is just another instruction.
So, it should roughly share the same
instruction processing cost
as any other instruction.
Next, let's also say that the words of
the memory transaction can be in flight
concurrently with compute operations.
In terms of the DAG,
that's an additional set of L over
beta zero fully concurrent nodes.
Inserting them as concurrent nodes mean
they shouldn't increase the critical
path link.
However, by putting them in as explicit
nodes, we'll have to pay for their cost.
Most real memory systems
behave something like this.
That is, there's usually
a separate memory controller or
network processor onto which
you can offload communication.
So, what's the best case
execution time for this DAG?
To start, the usual work and
span laws apply,
just scaled by the processor speed.
There's just one extra
cost due to communication.
That is, for each transaction, we have
to pay for the cost of these nodes.
Now if you've done a good
job designing the algorithm,
the critical path is short.
In this case,
when is this right hand side minimized?
That's right.
It's basically when these
two arguments are equal.
Now remember the historical
growth rate trends?
Of course you do, because what better
way to beat insomnia than to always be
dreaming of exponential scaling trends.
From the trends, if you want to
benefit from transistor scaling,
then you need the compute time to
dominate the communication time.
I like to call this idea of
making compute time dominate
communication time,
the principle of balance.
That is, our collective goal
whether we design algorithms or
we design systems, is to make it as
easy as possible to achieve balance.
That's what gives us our best shot
at scaling into the distant future.
Now, let's start with this relation and
massage it a little bit more.
On the algorithm side,
your goal is to make the left hand
side as large as possible, knowing
that the right hand side is subject
to inevitable scaling trends
that cause it to grow over time.
What about the system side?
On the system side,
your goal is to try to keep this small
to help the algorithms people out.
Now would be a great time for some quick
exercises to see what this balance
principle, derived from
the modified DAG model, implies.