Hey, everybody.
I hope the course has been fun so far.
This lesson can be
particularly challenging, but
I want you to know that
I've been in your shoes.
So, to ease you into building
the My Favorite Movies app,
here are a couple things I
want to call to your attention.
First, some of the app's been
implemented ahead of time.
This is going to allow us to focus
on just the networking code.
Second, the AppDelegate's used like
a singleton to get the NSURL session.
If you've never heard
about singletons before,
check out the link in
the instructor notes.
And last, we've broken each HTTP
request into a seven-step process and
we'll cover that in just a moment.
For now, let's get started
with the movie database.