So the reason why the movie quote is still being played,
is inside PlaySoundsViewController.
Here, we have hard coded the audio player, to always play a movie_quote mp3.
Since I'm not playing this movie quote any more.
What I will do is, I will take these two lines and then I will bring those out,
outside of the if statement, like that.
And then I will just comment, my legacy code.
And I can use Cmd+/, to comment a whole bunch of lines together.
Okay. In here when I'm initializing the AVAudioPlayer,
I have to provide the NSURL to this parameter, contents of URL.
Now here, I can use the variable received audio, as this has received some data.
So I can say, received audio.
And this has a property called, file pad url.
All right.
Let's run this project and see if the code is working.
I'm going to hit the record button.
Swift is fast, but learning it can be slow.
And now let me play the sound.
Swift is fast but learning it can be slow.
All right, that worked for the first time.
Let's try the other button.
Swift is fast, but learning it can be slow.
Cool, so we have both of these buttons working with our recording now