Now we see how to modify
the tree search function and
make it be a graph search function
to avoid those repeated paths.
What we do is we start off and
initialize the set,
called the explored set,
of states that we've already explored.
Then, when we consider a new path,
we add the new state to the set
of already explored states.
And then,
when we're expanding the path and
adding in new states to the end of it,
we don't have that end,
if we've already seen that new state
in either the frontier or the explored.
Now back to Breadth-First Search, and
let's assume we're using
the graph search so
that we've eliminated the duplicate
path, Arad is crossed off the list.
The path that goes from Arad to
Sibiu back to Arad is removed, and
we're left with these one, two,
three, four, five possible paths.
Given these five paths, show me which
ones are candidates to be expanded next
by the Breadth-First Search algorithm.