An alternative to programmed IO
is to use DMA-supported devices.
DMA stands for direct memory access,
and it is a technique that
relies on special hardware support
in the form of a DMA controller.
For devices that have DMA support,
the way the CPU interacts with them is
that it would still write commands in
the command registers on the device,
however, the data movement will be
controlled by configuring the DMA
controller which data to be moved
from CPU memory into the device.
This requires interactions between
the CPU and the DMA controller, and,
in fact, the same method can be used
to move data in the opposite direction,
from the device to the CPU,
so the device would have
as DMA controller that it interacts
with to enable that interaction.
Let's look again at the network
interface card, the NIC example,
to illustrate how exactly DMA-based
CPU-device interactions are carried out.
Again, here, the data that needs to be
moved from the CPU to the device is
already formed as a network packet.
And the very first step requires
that the CPU write a command
into the device command register to
request the packet transmission.
This, however, needs to be accompanied
with an operation that configures
the DMA controller with the information
about the in-memory address and
size of the buffer that's holding
this packet that we want transmitted.
So that's basically the location
of the data we need to move,and
the total amount of data to be moved.
Once this is done, the device can
perform the desired operation.
From the CPU perspective, performing
this transmission requires that
we perform one store instruction in
order to write out the contents in
the command register and one operation
to configure the DMA controller.
All of this looks much better than
the alternative of performing 189
store operations that we
saw with programmed IO.
The second step, configuring the DMA
controller, is not a trivial operation,
and it takes many more
cycles then a memory store.
Therefore, for smaller transfers,
programmed IO will still be better than
DMA, because the DMA step
itself is more complex.
One important thing is that in order
to make DMA work is, we have to make
sure that the data buffer that we want
moved or where we want data to be
written must be present in physical
memory until the transfer completes.
It cannot be swapped out to disk, since
this DMA controller can only read and
write data to and from physical memory,
so the contents have to be there.
This means that the memory regions
involved in DMAs are pinned,
they're not swappable,
they have to remain in physical memory.