Now that we're getting more
comfortable stepping through code,
I want to take another look at stack
traces in the Debug Navigator.
First, let's start with
the BugFactory.swift file, and I want
you to set a break point at line 26 in
the beginning of the createBug method.
Then run the app and examine the stack
traces that are produced when this
specific breakpoint is hit.
By examining those stack traces,
you should be able to answer
the following question.
In the breakpoint debugging
scene of SoManyBugs,
how is the createBug
method being called?
Is the method being called
when we handle a tap,
when we handle a tap and when we animate
the bugs, when we handle a tap and
when the BreakpointBugViewController
initializes, or
only when the
BreakpointBugViewController initializes?
Mark the best answer
to complete the quiz.