Android categorizes the device
screens using two general properties,
size and pixel density.
And you'll have to take
both into consideration
when you design your app's layouts,
and include any image resources.
Density is the number of pixels in
the physical area of the screen, and
it's often measured in dots per inch,
or dpi.
There are five density ranges that you
should be familiar with for Android,
and I will refer to those
ranges as density buckets,
which most Android devices fall into.
There is m mdpi, hdpi,
xhdpi, xxhdpi and xxxhdpi.
This range from a medium density of
about 160 dots per inch to an extra,
extra, extra high density
of about 640 dots per inch.
Which has many more smaller tiny
pixels in the same screen size.
And a greater number of
smaller pixels allow for
a sharper and better image quality
on those high density displays.
The same physical area on one of those
high density devices will actually
take up more pixels than that same
area on a smaller density screen.
So how can we make sure that any
margins or images you include
would look the same across those
different device resolutions.
Well, you have to use
density-independent pixels, or dps for
short.
Density-independent pixels are the same
physical size on each device.
So 48 x 48 dp image on this high
density screen will appear the same
size as a 48 x 48 dp image on
the medium density screen.
But the image on the high density screen
will be actually made up by a lot
more pixels.
So in general, we want to use those
dps for spacing and images, so
that we can design for
size and not pixel by pixel.
And if you include images in your app,
you should provide multiple
image resources that
are appropriately scaled for
each of the generalized density buckets.
If you only provide one size of image
Android might have to scale that image
for each device.
This takes some processing power and
might distort the image.
So providing correctly sized images for
common density buckets helps you
achieve good graphical quality and
performance across different devices.
And you can actually see an example of
this in your project resources folder,
where it contains multiple Android
icons over different pixel dimensions.
But at the end they will all
appear the same physical sizes
across different devices.
Another type of alternative resource
we can provide are resources for
different layouts, based on the size and
orientation of our screen.
Let's take a look at that next.