We saw so far some rough indications how an operating system is laid out.
But let's now more explicitly look at different types of
operating system organizations, and
we will start with what we call a monolithic operating system.
Historically, the operating system had a monolithic design.
That's when every possible service that any one of
the applications can require or
that any type of hardware will demand is already part of the operating system.
For instance, such a monolithic operating system may include several possible
file systems, where one is specialized for, of sequential workloads where
the workload is sequentially accessing files when reading and writing them.
And then maybe other file system that's optimized for random I/O.
For instance, this is common with databases.
There isn't necessarily a sequential access there.
Rather, each database operation can randomly access any portion of
the backing file.
This would clearly make the operating system potentially really, really large.
The benefit of this approach is that everything is
included in the operating system.
The abstractions, all the services, and everything is packaged at the same time.
And because of that, there's some possibilities for
some compile-time optimizations.
The downside is that there is too much state,
too much code that's hard to maintain, debug, upgrade.
And then its large size also poses large memory requirements, and that
can always impact the performance that the applications are able to observe.