Okay, let's take a look at this sample.
When I change this,
the width of this green block and
then click this button,
all the paragraphs will change size.
You see, it took a really long time for
that to work out.
To understand why, we need to
look again at the pipeline and
specifically the order of
the tasks that it contains.
The order is pretty clear.
We do want JavaScript here.
Then we do our style calculations and
then we do any layout.
Maintaining this order is important.
And this is the code.
First we select all the paragraphs,
and then the green block.
And then we step through each
of the paragraphs in turn.
For each paragraph,
we request the green block's width, and
then we set the width of
each paragraph to match.
Now the problem is this, to answer the
question of the element's width, using
offsetWidth, the browser must first
calculate it, which requires layout.
But see what that does to the pipeline.
It moves the layout task into here, and
that puts the layout before
the style calculations.
Now this is not a problem unless
you now make a style change,
which we did when we set
the width of the paragraph.
Look again at the code.
We request the width,
and then we set a style.
We do layout and
then we do a style calculation.
Every time we change a style,
the layout pass that we just did is
invalidated because you changed things.
So now,
the browser has to do it all again, and
this can be an expensive
mistake to make.
If you trigger a forced
synchronous layout,
DevTools will denote this with
this little exclamation mark here.
In you're in flame chart view,
you'll see a little red triangle
in the corner of a layout record.
That's the same thing as the exclamation
mark from the waterfall view.
If you see this warning,
then you need to look at where it was
forced in your code and remove it.