Okay awesome, you've handled Load and
considered what you might do
during periods of idle time.
But what next?
Well, the user's going to
interact with the app, and
you need to be responsive to that.
This isn't responsive in the sense that
it responds to screens of different
sizes.
This is responsive in the sense that it
reacts to the user input without delay.
Well how responsive does
it need to be then?
Well, studies show that there
is a limit of 100 milliseconds.
So a tenth of a second after
someone presses something on screen
before they notice any lag.
So if you can respond to all user
input in that time, you're good to go.
That's great if the thing they did
was to say, toggle a check box or
tap a button.
And you show a single change,
like a selected state.
But there's another version of
this which is more challenging,
which is that the user does
something that requires animation.
The most challenging performance
issues always come out of the need
to hit 60 frames a second.
Which is either interactions that stick
to the user's finger or transitions and
animations.
For those we have a limit
of 16 milliseconds.
Which is one second or
a thousand milliseconds divided by 60.
In reality, we actually have
less than 16 milliseconds,
because the browser has overhead.
So really we get around
10 to 12 milliseconds.
That's not a lot of time.