Well, if you had actually highlighted it now, the answer really is that
both these images would require some sort of common set of coverage.
Basically, meaning is, this image in here have something similar.
Similarly, this board here is similar.
So, there have some matches between these two that are essential for us to use.
However, this one and this one are too far apart.
So, these were next to each other.
This was one side of the side.
The other one on the other side.
And yes while there is a green things of common.
If you really look at it there is no comparative matches that would happen here.
So these two things, if they were to actually match and
align they would be wrong.
These would be a better pair so, the answer would be of course, A.