I'm going to answer a pretty
common interview question,
what motivates you in the workplace?
Well there's a few different
things that motivate me.
One is just passion for what I do.
I'm pretty lucky that I really
do enjoy what I'm doing so
that's a great natural motivator.
Another thing I would have
to say is my distaste for
missing deadlines or
being pushed to the last minute.
So, I'm motivated to do things early.
That way I have
the opportunity to review and
iterate on something
before missing a deadline.
And then finally, probably the most
important thing for me is my desire for
I want to be a good colleague,
as a great motivator.
I know my previous company,
me completing what I'm doing and
doing that well allows my
colleagues to complete their job.
So if somebody's job is contingent
on me doing my job well and on time,
that's a really great motivator, because
you always want to be a good colleague.