Most mobile devices these
days have tons of hardware.
Touchscreens, cameras, GPS,
accelerometers, gyroscopes, you name it.
TVs, of course, don't.
So if you're developing an app that
will work on both TV and mobile,
then you have to handle hardware that's
not supported on one of the devices.
For example, let's say we have
a camera app for a mobile device.
Imagine it has two activities,
one to take pictures and
another to display a photo gallery.
If we're extending this app to also work
on TV, then we could disable the picture
taking activity and create a version of
the photo gallery for the big screen.
First, though, we'd have to update our
manifest to make sure we don't require
any hardware that's not
available on the TV.
Here's how we declare the uses camera
feature as optional in our manifest.
This will enable our app to be
installed on both mobile devices
as well as TVs in the same APK.
Before using the camera, we check to see
if our device has a camera and runtime,
and you can use the PackageManager
to do so, like this.
You can also check if your app is
running on a TV device at runtime
by using the uiModeManager like this.
Use this same strategy to handle other
hardware that's not supported on TVs.
First, mark the hardware as
not required in your manifest.
And second, check whether it's available
at runtime before trying to use it.
One gotcha to be aware
about is permissions.
Permissions can imply
hardware requirements.
This means that requesting some
permissions in your app manifest
can exclude your app from
being installed on TV devices.
So if you use the permission, be sure
to mark the hardware as not required.
Be sure your app can handle events from
dedicated media buttons found on remote
controls like play and pause.
Also, be sure your UI can handle
key events from buttons like A and
B on game controllers.
If you're using the Leanback Support
library fragments and
a MediaSession.Callback,
then all of this is handled for
you and this is the approach we take in
our sample apps later in this course.
If you're designing your
own UI from scratch though,
you can learn more about key events
in the game section of this class and
see the instructor notes for
more detail.
It's common for TV apps to use
location information, but of course,
most TVs don't have a GPS because,
obviously, they're stationary devices.
So here's a tip,
you can often get the static location
that was optionally configured
during the TV device setup.
If this fails, you can prompt
the user for their ZIP code.
Last tip, TV remote controls and
game controllers occasionally
go to sleep to save power.
Remember, they're powered by Bluetooth,
and the radio consumes battery.
When they go to sleep,
this triggers a disconnect event.
To prevent this event from
interrupting your app,
just add these lines to your manifest.
If you're building an Android TV app,
disconnects are not such a big deal but
if you're building a game,
see that section of the class for
much more detail.
Let's say you have
an existing mobile app, and
you'd like to extend it to
also run on an Android TV.
Your existing app has this
permission in its manifest.
Now remember, permissions can
imply hardware requirements.
So what two lines do you need to add
to your manifest to mark the implied
hardware as not required?
The instructor notes have a link to
developer training that you can look at
to answer this question.