You've done it.
Over the last couple of modules,
you've learned how to add Google
sign-in to your Android app.
You saw how to use the default
sign-in button for Google+, and
how to access the plus APIs using it.
You then saw how to modify that for
a more generic sign-in with
Google experience if you
don't want to use plus.
You also saw how different scopes give
you access to different information
With your users permission and
how to implement that.
To wrap things up,
you saw how this technology allows for
cross device logins.
Improving your users
experience with your apps.
That's it for signing in,
so I'm signing off.
Feel free to add some of
the functionality to your final app and
keep us informed of what you do.
Thank you.