[Narrator] And the answer is south.
The reason why it's south is if we attempt to go south,
an 80% probability we'll stay in the same cell.
In fact, a 90% probability because we can't
go south and we can't go east.
In a 10% probability, we find ourselves over here which is a relatively
safe state because we can actually go to the left side.
If we were to go just west which is the intuitive answer,
then there's a 10% chance we end up in the minus 100 absorbing state.
You can convince yourself if you go south,
find ourselves eventually in state C3, and then
go west, west, north, north, east, east, east.
You will never ever run risk of falling into the minus 100, and
that argument is tricky and to convince ourselves
let me ask the other hard question:
so what shall we do in state B3 that's the optimal action?