So way back in lesson one, I told
you about the idea of a primary key,
a column or
columns that uniquely identify
whatever it is the table is about.
Remember the bit about U.S. city and
state not being unique, because there
are five Springfield's in Wisconsin.
If we want a primary key for
places, we have to use something like a
postal code or coordinates or something.
In SQL, we need to tell the database
that something is a primary key if we
want to explicitly relate
other tables to it.
And here's how to do that.
If you have a single column primary key,
just put primary key after the column's
type when you create the table.
Whereas if you have a multi
column primary key,
you put it after all
the columns in the table.
For instance, postal codes don't
have to be unique around the world,
since two different countries could
use similar numbering systems.
The US, Germany, and Indonesia among
others all use five digit postal codes.
This means that if we wanted to
have a table of places that we
can mail packages to, we'd want
to have both the postal code and
the country as parts of the primary key.
Remember, primary keys are meant to
uniquely identify the thing that
a row is about.
What do you think your
SQL database will do,
if you try to insert a duplicate
value into a primary key column?
In fact, let's make that a quiz.
What should the database do,
when a user asks it to insert
a second student with an ID number
that is the same as another student's?
In other words, a duplicate primary key.
Should it insert the new row anyway?
Should it signal an error
like an exception in Python?
Should it silently drop the new row?
Or should it overwrite the old row?