And the answer is easily derived from the basic projection equation, here without the minus sign.
So if we move the object closer to the camera, which means Z decreases, then the size will increase.
If Z decreases, yes, the size will increase.
If you use a camera with a longer focal length, then the size of the projection will increase.
If you increase F, then yes, X will increase as well, in the same proportion.
If you double the distance to the object, which means Z is twice as large as before, the projected image will be half as large.
And yes, if we divide by something that's twice as big, then the result will be half as large.
And finally, the ratio of the focal length, F, over the distance of the object, Z,
is the same as the projected size of the object in the camera plane, x.
This specific statement, we really forgot about the object size, uppercase X, which plays a big role in this particular equation.
Therefore, this statement is false.