So when adding GeoFences
to LocationServices, so
they can monitor them for you,
there were a number of steps that
you had to follow, and
you've done all of these now.
Most notably,
you were calling the addGeoFences
method on the GeoFencingApi object.
You're passing it a GoogleApiClient,
a Geofencing Request and
a Geofencing Pending Intent.
Now, whenever you add one of
the Geofences to the services,
the service will callback onResult(),
and will pass you a status code.
You can then check this status
code to see if the GeoFence was
added successfully, or
if there was an error.
In the next step you're going to
implement this onResult(), and
check this box when you're
ready to go forward.