In this exercise,
you'll set up a cron job to periodically
update the announcement about
conferences that are almost sold out.
Since you've already written
the function to create the announcement,
pretty much all you're going to need
to do is to configure the cron job.
And you do that in a configuration
file called cron.yaml.
So you need to create a new file in your
project directory called cron.yaml, and
to find the cron job.
You need to provide the URL and
schedule, and option lay description.
The URL is the path to
the task to be run.
The description, which is optional,
describes the task so
you can figure out later what
your code was supposed to do.
And the schedule indicates
how often to run the task.
There are a variety of ways
to set the schedule, but
you must strictly follow the syntax or
the cron job won't run.
I recommend checking the format for
the schedule in the developer docks.
Note this says every 1 hours.
It would sound correct if you were
saying every 12 hours or every 2
hours but it turns out that even for 1,
you have to say every 1 hours, not hour.
You can see the defined cron jobs in the
cron job tab in the task queue section.
You can see the schedule, and
when it was last run, and
whether it was successful, and
you can also trigger to run it manually.
And now for your task in the exercise,
you should create the config file and
make it run, the /crons/set_announcement
URL every minute so
you can see it working.
But after you've tested your cron job,
you should set it to run much less
often, for example,
once every hour or two.
In general, you shouldn't run cron
jobs more often than necessary,
as they do consume resources and quota.
So after you complete each step here,
check it off.
Make sure, again, to change your
cron job from every minute to
every hour after you've seen it run.
And then, as a syntax check, how would
you schedule it to run every two hours?
Put that down here.