All right, so I'm going to take
a look at each of these options,
and we'll go ahead and
dive right in with Option Aim.
Now there are some very good
things about Option Aim.
Namely, I have this user
lists node right here.
When I want to display all of the lists
that Walter is involved with,
I could simply attach a listener
to this user list note here,and
this gives me all the lists that
he has anything to do with.
The issues that we're kind of
regressing to a worse data state.
The data here contains a pretty big
nesting issue that we've seen before.
Remember, you don't want to put
a shopping lists inside of users because
that means whenever you take a look
at Walter's user information,
you're also grabbing all of this
extra shopping list information.
So A probably is not the best option.
Okay, here we are with B and
we see we solved the problem
that I just mentioned.
We've denormalized and user lists
are no longer part of the user objects.
So we can see here we
have a list of users and
each user has a list of the shopping
lists that are associated with them.
We also have the sharedWith property
which is inside of the shoppingList.
And that's looking pretty good.
So let's keep B on the back burner as an
option that we might want to consider.
Okay, I'm going to load up option C.
Option C is actually
very similar to option B.
The only difference is that
we've taken the sharedWith node,
that used to be a property of a
userList, and we've de-normalized it and
moved it up out here.
So before where's this have
been part of the list K3MhMmVa,
now it's been scooted out over here.
So is this actually an improvement or
are we just de-normalizing for
de-normalization sake?
If you look at the shopping list
fragment screen, it actually doesn't
contain any information about which
shopping lists are shared with whom.
And if you even click on
one of the shopping lists,
this doesn't really contain any
sharing information either.
It's only when you start
getting into the sharing flow.
So the shared with information
actually doesn't have to be
deeply tied to the list itself,
and it's okay and
probably better to de-normalize
it by putting it up here.
So option C is actually looking even
a little bit better than option B.
All right, let's keep looking
at database options though.
D is an entirely different approach.
We continue to have a master
list called active lists
of all shopping lists of the database.
And then again embedded within
the user class, we have user lists.
But instead of having a huge amount of
extra data for each list, we just add
the push ID for the list, and
then true if the user has access to it.
So this is an interesting approach, but
let's look at the shopping
list fragment screen here.
So for each of these lists
that we can see here,
you're going to need an extra listener
that basically looks up this push ID
in the master list of active lists.
And that's not the end of the world but
it will create a lot of extra listeners.
It also continues to sort
of clog up the user class
with extra data that could be
de-normalized outside of it.
So I prefer C over D.
Now option E is kind of
combination of option C
with the duplications of lists and
user lists removed.
The thing is that is that
user list was useful.
It was a prime example of how we
were going to duplicate data and
save users time.
Even with the shared with lists,
it's hard to get a specific location
that you can attach a listener to.
Which will have all of the shopping
list data you need to display.
Again, you could use the information
in shared with to do searches
through the active lists.
It's kind of the opposite problem
of what you were doing before.
Instead of searching
through active lists,
you'd have to do these sort of
searches through the shared with node.
If I wanted to find all the lists that
I was associated with, I'd have to do
a search of all of shared with and look
for those lists that I was actually on.
Again, shared with could get very big.
So this search would again
require querying and filtering.
And would just generally be slower than
having a single location that you could
attach a listener to, that had all of
the lists that you have access to.
So at the end of the day option C is
looking the best out of all of these.
Well it would have been great
if we knew that beforehand.