Now the topic of data persistence,
or the need for
data to stick around,
is not a uniquely Android problem.
If you've ever used any desktop apps,
you're probably familiar
with the Save screen.
So, when I click on the Save button,
what exactly is it saving?
Well, it's essentially saying,
I want the computer to take
the state of my program as it is and
save it off into permanent
storage in something like a file.
The state of my program could mean
something like a document that I type up
in a text editor, or perhaps the
progress that I've made on a video game.
So, Android does provide a few
different data persistent options for
storing to local storage.
Now this is different from, if you've
heard the term, saving off to the cloud.
That method is more complicated, and
it requires Internet connection.
So, in this lesson,
we'll just be focusing on saving data
directly onto your Android device,
and that way,
you can access the data whether or
not you have Internet connection.
We'll be focusing on these
three Android options
that allow us to save data
directly onto our device.
So, first off are files, you're
probably pretty familiar with files and
you've likely used them in
apps that you use daily.
For example, in apps like Instagram,
where you're adding your favorite filter
onto your photo and
then saving that off into a file.
So, saving information to a file is
a great option if you need to, say,
save off a large media file, images,
books, songs, or video files.
For example,
the Camera app saves photos as files
that you can later
view in the Photos app.
Additionally, if you're using
Google Play Music and using it offline,
that music is saved off as files so
that it can be downloaded.
Our next option is SharedPreferences, so
SharedPreferences were built to store
user preferences within the app.
Now an example of this is,
say you have a Maps app that
would have a preference screen.
So, in this preference
screen amongst other things,
I'm allowed to set my distance units,
and my distance units can either be
Automatic, Kilometers, or Miles.
This preference will be remembered
even when I close off the Maps app.
This means I don't need
to keep going back and
saying, I want my distance
to be kilometers.
So, the developers of this map app
could have used SharedPreferences
to save all this data.
SharedPreferences store a small amount
of data using what's known as key
value pairs, so in this situation the
key will always be a unique string and
will be tied to a value.
That's what we're actually saving off,
so it's your preferences.
Our values can be primitive types,
which include ints,
booleans, couple of others, and strings.
Remember, you can use
a key to save the data
as well as to identify the value
that you want to open.
So, our next example, the key might
be something like distance units and
the value could be kilometers.
Now, if the user decides to select
a different type of distance units, so
they changed to miles.
Notice that the keys stays the same,
but the value updates here to miles.
So, if you like my examples of
how to use SharedPreferences,
I suggest checking out
the link in the notes below.
Now the final option for permanent
storage is the SQLite Database.
Now SQLite Databases are a type of
database, as the name implies, but
what exactly is a database?
A database Is an organized
collection of data.
With this information
properly organized,
we can extract out what we need and
analyze that information.
That was just talking about
databases broadly, but
like I mentioned, we want to focus
specifically on SQLite databases.
So, SQLite Databases are just
a specific example of databases, and
they can be made up of one table,
or even multiple tables.
However, I should note here that not all
databases organize data in the same way
as a spreadsheet does.
However, SQLite Databases do, so
for the purpose of this lesson,
you can picture the table of your
SQLite Database as a spreadsheet.
So, SQLite Databases
are divided into tables, and
these can have rows and columns.
A table will usually represent a list
of objects where each row of the table
represents a single object.
Let's see an example of that.
So in this situation, if we have
the database table that is keeping
track of coffee orders, each row
will contain a single coffee order.
So, in a single row, we see that
we have the name of the customer,
the type of milk they want in their
coffee, whether or not they want sugar,
and whether or
not they want decaf coffee.
Each of these columns represents
different attributes of the object, and
our object in this case
is our coffee order.
So, by organizing large amounts of
information, databases make it easy for
us to search and
sort through all this information,
much like how you would sort through
the column of a spreadsheet.
For example, because our coffee order
information is in a spreadsheet,
it's easy to see which
customer wanted soy milk.
Additionally, we could've seen which
customers wanted decaf coffees that day.
So, SQLite Databases,
SharedPreferences, and files
can all store the same type of data,
things such as strings and integers.
But we'll choose which one to use
depending on the situation we're in.
So, a key characteristic of our SQLite
Database is that it makes it easy to
share large amounts of related and
structured data, and
this information is commonly text data.
If you remember back to our coffee
table example, where each coffee order
had the same structure and
the rows were all related and
that they all represented coffee orders,
another key fact about SQLite databases
is that they store data
that's able to grow in size.
Over the course of using our coffee
ordering app, we will get more and
more coffee orders, so the information
will continue to grow, but
it will be easily searchable
in SQLite Database structure.
Now moving on to SharedPreferences,
these are better for single,
important pieces of information.
For example, in Settings we know
the fix keys ahead of time, so
this isn't really meant for
storing lots of user data.
That means, if you find that your
data that are easily thought of,
structured in rows and
columns like a spreadsheet, then SQLite
Database is probably your way to go.
So now we know about these three
different persistent data storage
options and how each one should
be used in a different situation.
You should note that using files and
databases are not specific to Android.
For example, all the large
media platforms that you use or
even antivirus programs, well,
these are just some of the products
that'll likely use SQLite to store
everything from user information To
even the data that we're inputting.
It's important to note that many Android
apps will use a combination of those
three approaches.
Take for example the camera app.
It could use files to
save pictures locally,
while also using an SQLite
database to save off meta data.
So meta data means information
about information.
So perhaps time, location, description
information about our picture.
To give you some practice determining
which data storage option
is best given the scenario, I'd like
you to go through this exercise.
So for each of these app situations,
decide whether it's best to use files,
share preferences or SQLite databases
to store off this information So
our first scenario of our Video
Everywhere App, this application lets
you film short video segments
when you're on vacation and
then it will automatically plot your
location and date of a film onto a map.
So which option should we use?
In the Baking Conversion App, this app
offers various conversions needed for
baking, such as cups to millimeters or
teaspoons to cups.
Which of these is the best way to
store off our users preference for
using the units?
In our third scenario of our Music Share
app, say this app lets you buy and
download a song that can be
used across any application,
which would be the best
way to store The song.
And lastly, say you have
an app that stores information
about pets coming into
an animal shelter.
What's the best way to structure
the information of all those pets?
All right, so give these scenarios a try
and I'll see you in the next video.