Here's the dolphin image we've seen before.
Let's say our interest point detector found this tip of the fin to
be a possible keypoint.
We zoom in on a five cross five neighborhood around the keypoint.
Now recall how you computed image gradients.
Say using a three cross, three filter.
When we place it over this pixel, what is the dominant orientation you see?
Right. It's along the diagonal going towards the top left.
Let's use this approach to mark image gradient directions for other pixels.
To avoid edge conditions,
we only consider locations where the filter fits inside the image patch.
Also, we approximate or
quantize to eight directions for it to go horizontal and diagonals.
Can you figure out the dominant orientation of this patch using the image
gradient directions?
Select the appropriate radio button.