Okay.
For displayName, well,
that's a String Property.
[INAUDIBLE] There, right?
Names are strings, and datastore
supports Unicode strings just fine.
MainEmail, well,
that's another String Property.
Later on, you might want to subclass
String Property to make sure that we're
only storing valid
email addresses there.
But for now, String Property is the
correct type for this, and teeShirtSize.
At this point,
this may not be any kind of surprise.
This will also be a String Property.
Even though this is an enum in the API,
to the datastore, it's just a string.
So, not too much variety here.
Everything ended up
being a String Property.
But we've made some progress defining
our app, and that's awesome.
The code for this is going to go
into the file called models.py.
The name indicates just where we're
going to put our data models.
You already saw this in
the previous lesson when I
introduced the profile class.
Now, back to Magnus for
some more about datastore keys.