First, let's start
with a visual metaphor.
Distributive file systems are like
distributed storage facilities,
specifically storage facilities
containing toy parts for a toy shop.
First, each is accessed via
some well-defined interface.
Also, both focus on
maintaining consistent state
as one of the major
functional requirements.
And finally, both of these support
different distribution models.
For the distributed storage facilities,
the toy shop manager needs to
be able to access, check, and
make decisions regarding the available
resources without having
to leave the toy shop and directly
visit some of the storage facilities.
This should be done via some
well-defined interfaces
that the storage facilities export.
Next, the distributed storage facilities
must constantly update their inventories
to represent consistent information
about the parts that they can deliver.
This helps managers and
other workers accurately determine
what are the inventories and
what are the times that these products
can be delivered, for instance.
Finally, these distributive facilities
can be configured in different ways.
Some of them can be for storage-only.
Some can provide both storage and
processing services.
Some can be specialized for
different types of toys or
different types of parts.
So there will be different
types of distribution models.
Now let's look at how distributed file
systems relate to these properties of
distributed storage facilities.
First, distributed file
systems are also accessed
via via some higher level
well-defined interfaces.
In particular,
this would be the virtual file system
interface that we already talked about.
This allows the operating system to take
advantage of multiple types of storage
devices or storage machines,
regardless of where they are.
Next, distributed file systems
need to maintain consistent state
of the files shared among clients.
If a file is updated by one client,
the distributed file system needs
to track information regarding
all of the file updates, some state
that's necessary, for instance, for
execution of cache coherence,
algorithms, and other information.
And also, the distributed file
systems can be implemented
via different distribution models.
They can be replicated or
the files can be partitioned across
the front machines in the file system.
Or all of the notes in the file system
can act more like peers amongst each
other when they're providing
the distributed file system service.