And the answer is 0.0333 or a 1/3 and now we're going to
apply the entire arsenal of inference we just learned about.
The joint probability of cancer and positive is 0.1 * 0.9. That's the joint that's not normalized.
So let's normalize it and we normalize it by the sum of the joint
for cancer and the joint for non-cancer.
Joint for cancer we just computed but the joint for non-cancer assumes the opposite prior 1-0.1
and it applies the positive result of a non-cancer case.
Now because the specificity first is negative, we have to do the
same trick as before and multiply it with 1-0.8.
When you worked this out, you find this to be 0 to 0.9 divided 0 to 0.9 + 0.9 * 0.2 that is 0.18
So if you put these all of this together, you get exactly a third.