The specific objectives of
this lesson are for you for
to learn about,
the Geometry of the scene.
Remember we talked about, that one of
the interesting things we want to do
with capturing images and photographs is
to capture the geometry of the scene,
that is the relative distance
of objects in the scene.
Here we're going to start getting into
that kind of geometry and look at depth.
That is how far away are pixels that
are visible in the image or photograph.
And also structure rela,
a lot of information of that scene.
Going to look at specifically
the concept of stereo.
That is how to do this from
two different viewpoints.
By introducing the concept of
the Parallax that could actually help us
look at the whole concept of how we're
going to extract depth from images.
And then, talk about specifically,
how can we compute depth
from a stereo image pair?
So let's get started.