The ticket really is a capability.
The possession of that ticket
allows Alice to go in the theater.
Be able to access
the movie in this case.
The reason it's a capability is,
it's not an Access Control Entry.
It's that, the person who's checking
the ticket doesn't even need to know who
Alice is actually.
The mere possession of the ticket.
Remember that sounds like what we
were saying about capabilities.
Mere possession of a capability
actually allows you
to gain access to the resource.
In this case,
the ticket really is a capability.
We don't even know the user ID of
Alice or the person who's doing
admission control doesn't even know
who Alice is so it's not an ACE.
Because an ACE remember requires the UID
and what kind of permissions they have.
So this quiz the ticket is a capability.