Paul just explained how he used Flip
to create a pretty snazzy animation.
He performed all the hard calculations
up front, so that he would touch
as little of the pipeline as possible
during the actual animation.
This is how he kept it going at
a silky smooth 60 frames per second.
When he applied opacity and transform
changes to reverse the animation,
what steps in the rendering
pipeline did Paul trigger?
Did the HTML need to get
converted to the DOM?
Did the CSS need to get
converted to the CSSOM?
Did the DOM and CSSOM need to be
combined into the Render Tree?
Did the browser have to run Layout
again, Composite again, or Paint again?
Check all that apply.