XDR provides the RPC runtime
with some helpful routines.
For instance,
after we compile a .h XDR file,
the compiler will generate a number of
routines that are used for marshalling
or unmarshalling, the various
data types in the RPC operations.
In the example that we talked about,
the square rpc example,
these will all be found
in the square_xdr.c file.
In addition, the compiler will generate
certain clean up operations like xdr
free, that are used to deallocate to
free up memory regions that are used for
the data structures,
the arguments in the RPC operations.
These routines will typically
be called within a procedure
that the name of the procedure
typically ends with _freeresult.
For instance, in our square program
it will be square_prog_1_freeresult.
And this is yet
another user defined procedure,
where the user can specify what are all
of the different data structures, or
pieces of state,
that need to be freed up.
And the allocated,
after the runtime is done servicing
RPC request and returning results.
So the RPC runtime will
automatically call this procedure
after it's done computing the result.