What did you come up with?
>> So I'll just go in order,
been or have not yet
been, get, put, a couple of is', take,
examine, consists, increment, throw,
throw away, split,
put them back and display.
>> Okay, first off, what happened
to keep, the very first word?
>> Oh, I missed it.
I guess I was assuming.
Most sentences start with nouns.
I probably just over looked it.
>> Okay, so keep is clearly a verb.
And then you had been, or has been.
But really that's just part of
the construction of has been counted.
It's counting that is the verb there.
You might want to add that to your list,
replace been with count.
So in the same sense that we dealt with
nouns by stemming, we might stem here as
well so the verb is count, and
counting is just one form of that.
And then you had get and put [COUGH].
Is, on the surface,
is a linking verb but
it was part of a phrase that
says is set and set is a verb.
And I don't see you
having set in your list.
>> Okay.
>> So
we want to add set in as a verb here.
And you've got take, you've got examine,
you've got consists.
Do you have increment?
Yes, okay, throw or throw away.
You've got split and you've got display.
Okay, you've got put twice and just like
before, we're going to combine those
together so that we only have
a single occurrence of that.
This is a list of candidate operations
and of course we're going to want to
associate them with the class
that they belong to.
And you have to use your knowledge
of the English language in order to
determine what that is.
But if you start with,
did you write down keep there?
>> I did not write down keep.
>> You might want to put that down.
>> Okay.