All right, back to computer vision,
some really cool stuff today.
We're going to be talking
about boosting and one of the,
applications of machine learning
classification to computer vision,
that really caused a bunch of us and the
rest of the computer vision community,
to say, oh, we really gotta
pay attention to how all this,
notion of integrating, discriminative
classifiers, the notion of detection,
and image features and representation
as a, as a holistic thing.
So last time we introduced
discriminative classification and
the basic outline was
there are two elements.
There's the train, and there's test.
For training,
you basically have to figure out what
representation am I going to build,
how do I construct a model or, or
a description of each instance?
So I describe these training instances,
and then I have to build a classifier,
train a classifier.
And we said once we've done
that when new things come in,
might take some work to figure out how
to generate candidates in the new image.
Or you might just slide windows
around to different sizes and
then you have to score them, all right.
We talked about a relatively
simple method last time called
nearest neighbor,
as it just very date intensive.
You pull up the nearest one, which was
implicitly representing the boundary
between every single point,
remember that Voronoi tessellation.
Today we're going to talk about
a different method called boosting and
in particular, we're going to
talk about it in the context
of a particular method that, that used
it that sort of shows you the power.