Whether you use raw colors directly or
build a histogram of those values,
you still haven't solved the problem of
representing objects of the same class
that can be of different colors.
That is, you still haven't
achieved color and variance.
Let's take this image, for example, and
look at how its color values
are distributed in the RGB color space.
That is, using red, green, and
blue intensities as three coordinates.
In this example, the red and
blue cars' pixels are clustered
into two separate groups.
Although we could come up with a scheme
to identify these groups using
RGB values,
it can get complicated very quickly as
we try to accommodate different colors.
So, are there different
properties that you
can derive from these color values
that might be common across cars but
that distinguish them from
the rest of the image?
In the lane finding lesson, you explored
other color spaces like HLS and
LUV to see where alternated
representations of color could make
the object you're looking for
stand out against the background.
To me, it looks like cars
are more saturated in color,
while the background is generally pale.
Perhaps you should look at saturation
values instead of the raw red,
green, blue values you
get from a camera.
Or maybe there is some other
color transformation like HSV or
LUV that is more useful?
I'm curious what the pixels
look like in HSV space.
Aha!
For this image,
the car pixels seem to cluster well
on this saturation value plane.
Which kind of make sense.
Regardless of the color or
hue of a car, it is likely to
have a more prominent appearance.
But this may not be true for
other images.
What you essentially want to do is
take a bunch of different images and
look at how their pixel values are
distributed in a different color space.
And then you want to check if car
pixels stand out from non-car pixels
in some dimensions of
this transformed space.
Try a few different color spaces and
see if you can find one that
gives you a useful feature.