So we'll definitely see an image
display next to each word for
three of our categories.
And remember the phrases
activity won't have any images.
So when we zoom in to
one category activity,
here are the changes
that we'll need to make.
So the list view would need to
show an image in each list item.
So we need to modify the layout.
Now remember that the phrases activity
won't show images in the list view.
So we'll leave that as an edge case and
discuss in more detail later.
So we'll also need to add images to the
app, so that they can be referenced by
the WordAdapter when need to
set up each list item view.
Next, we should also
change the type of data
that is stored in the list of Words.
So we need to modify each word
to be associated with an image.
And as a result,
we need to modify the instructions
in the WordAdapter on how
a list item is to be created.
So not only do we have to set the proper
English and Miwok words in the list item
text views, we also have to set
the correct image in the ImageView.
So all these changes in the list view
and adapter will make it possible for
the different activities to
show images for each word.
And as mentioned earlier, we'll worry
about how to make the phrases activity
not show images later on.