Congratulations on completing Stage1.
Now navigate to your Stage2 in Lesson1.
So, Stage2 > Source> jvm > udacity > storm and
open your reporter exclamation topology.
If we scroll down to the topology in the main section,
we see that we're using a spout called new TestWordSpout.
If we scroll up, we see that the TestWordSpout comes from
storm Core in backtype.storm.testing.TestWordSpout.
These were the four names that we saw up here.
Using TestWordSpout is a nice start, but
let's now add a RandomSentenceSpout to visualize sentences.
Your assignment is in four parts in the reading node.
You may need to do a Ctrl+C in order to stop your storm program, but once that's
done and you get back to your command line, you're at lesson1, stage1.
And navigate to lesson1, stage2 and do cd/vagrant/lesson1/stage2,
and LS should show your .pom files and source.
Notice if you're using Atom then you can see the file structure that I've
added in a new spout folder, then you can open and
we see the RandomSentenceSpout.java file.
In part three of the written instructions, you must modify the reporter
exclamation topology, to import the random sentence spout.
And please enter the import statement here in begin stage2 exercise part 1-of-2.
And don't forget the ending semicolon required in Java.
As a hint, you can look at the package structure of udacity.storm and
form your import statement.
Once your import statement is completed, you can go back to your command line.
Remember that you need to be in lesson1, stage1.
And write mvn package.
Once you have build success with your import statements,
in part four of the written instructions scroll down to your main method
where you see the TopologyBuilder builder with the spout word and
the bolt exclamation one and exclamation two.
In part 4a, I'd like you to ignore the TestWordSpout,
add in the random sentence spout with an id or
component id of rand hyphen sentence, using a parallelism of ten.
And finally, connect exclaim one to the RandomSentenceSpout with
a shuffle grouping.
And again as a hint, this idcomponent should match your RandomSentenceSpout.
Finally, package your program and submit.
Once your storm project is running you can check all your visualization.
And finally, once your Storm Topology is running, you should be
able to go to your visualization, and see now random sentences being visualized.
And once you see your visualization, you know you're done with stage2.
Congratulations.