Okay, so now we're going to
create a simple shader.
First, let's go to file, and new scene.
Just make sure you're
in a brand new scene.
And then, in the project pane, Select
your assets folder and then go to create
and then this time, go to shader and
then standard surface shader.
Okay, go ahead and name your new shader
My first surface shader, okay, great.
Now double-click on the shader
to open it in either
MonoDevelop or Visual Studio, depending
on how your computer is set up.
Okay, wow.
Look at all that code!
This shader is written in
a language called HLSL or
High Level Shader Language.
We're not going to cover HLSL right now,
but I wanted you to see what
shader code actually looks like.
It's similar to see and
it's actually a fairly simple language.
You know what,
let's make one simple change.
Just so you can get a taste
of shader programming.
Go ahead and scroll down to line 32.
You'll see it's the line that sais,
to own dot albedo is equal to C dot RGB.
Remember how the albedo basically
controls the main color of the material?
Well, this is where the shader
receives that Albedo color.
This line actually says,
set the shader's Albedo value to be red,
green, and
blue value of the main material's color.
So really,
you can change this to be any color and
it will change the material's color.
That's pretty cool, right?
So let's do that.
Let's say, O dot albedo is equal
to float3010 semi colon.
So what that actually is saying is,
set the color, the albedo,
to bright green,
because this is red,
this is green and this is blue.
So, let's see if that work, go ahead and
save this change and go back to Unity.
And let's go ahead create a new
material Called, "test material".
So, go to "create" and
then "material" and
then name your material "test material".
Awesome.
And then,
if it hasn't already been selected,
go over to the shader drop-down box.
Go to "custom" and
then select "my first surface shader".
And so now the shader for
this material is set to
the surface shader that you just wrote
and you'll see it's bright green.
Let's go ahead and
assign that to an object just to see it.
Go over to your hierarchy,
go to 3D object and then cube
and drag your test material onto
the cube and there it is bright green.
And no matter what color you
change your albeta to it's
always going to be bright green
because you coded it that way.
Pretty cool?
Let's take one step further.
Double click your shader
to open it back up and
now we're going to change
that color even more.
Let's change line 32 to say,
o dot albedo is equal to
float 3 and then the r value,
the red value is 0,
the green value is going to be
something a little bit more elaborate.
So let's say ABS and
that's short for absolute value.
And then let's say SIN,
and that's short for sine.
And inside of this, let's do
underscore Time with a capital T,
dot .Z, close paren, close paren.
And then the blue value will be zero.
So what does this mean?
Let's break it down.
Let's start from the inside out.
So _Time dot z,
that's a built-in unity shader variable.
But it all means is it's the number of
seconds elapse since you pressed play.
So you press play and
then it starts counting.
And then this is just the number
of seconds that it passed.
Sign is the regular math sign function,
it's just going to give us a number that
goes smoothly back and forth between
negative one and one, so as time passes
we're going to get a number that goes up
to one and then back down, negative one,
and then up to one, then back down
to negative one forever and ever.
And then the absolute value of
that makes it so that instead
of going from 1 to -1, it just goes
from 1 to 0, and then back to 1 again.
So this says as time passes, go from
one to zero to one to zero forever.
So we put that as our green value, which
means that our green is going to go
from one which is bright
green to zero which is black.
And back and forth and back and forth.
And as long as you type that correctly,
you can go back to Unity,
press Play, and there it goes.
You can watch your cube
pulse forever and ever.
Pretty neat?
And what's really cool is all of this
animation is running On your GPU.
So shader programing is the secret
to special effects like water,
elaborate particles,
believable shadows, and more.
So every virtual reality developer
should know a bit about them.
Great job.