So let's continue to build on the corner detection mathematics.
We looked at this M matrix.
Of course, we now put this M matrix in our E u,v term and
expand it out and we come up with this nice quadratic form here.
So, basically, the surface UV is a locally approximated by
a quadratic form here with a window here.
Let's look at this car, equation a little bit more carefully.
So as I said, this surface is locally approximated by a quadratic form, and
have just shown you, am showing you here, the surface.
Now, this quadratic here is basically a slice through this surface,
which is basically this equation.
And this equation is that of an ellipse.
And you can notice this ellipse is right here.
So this ellipse are these ellipses here, and
these are the slices to the surface.
Drawing them here, it's hard to see them because they get complicated.
But you'll notice each one of them, these slices, is an ellipse.
So basically now we can actually look at each one of
these slices as a single ellipse.
So again, this is my equation of the ellipse and in the surface and
these lines here on my ellipses.
Let's draw one ellipse out to just kind of see what we can measure out of this.
Remember where we were looking at, at any point the directions of changes at any
point and this direction and the magnitude of these change that will allow us
to kind of quantify at any point the strength of this feature that I
can actually use as a repeatable measure across two images.
Right? So, this is my center.
In this direction there is a change going on, from here to there.
It's a rather fast change.
I mean, the same magnitude is covered in over a short distance.
So in essence, we can start labeling this as maximum change.
So direction of fastest change is this direction in this ellipse.
And another one would be in this axis.
And we can refer to this as lambda min.
And this is direction of the slowest change.
Now, this is a very standard linear algebra trick.
Where basically when we have surfaces like this, and we have ellipses.
We can actually now compute the lambdas and also the orientation.
Notice again that while these are the values of lambdas,
this ellipse is rotated by certain angle from the original image at this point.
So, this is where we refer back to eigenvalue analysis where axis lengths,
the lambda values, are eigenvalues.
And the orientation is basically when you take these two vectors and
compare them to the normal axis or
frame of reference you know actually the angles of these two vectors.
So this allows us to now start quantifying the direction and
the quantity of change that goes on at any feature point in an image.
Help us simplify this,
now let's actually still continue to come up with newer ways.
Remember, we did come up with an M matrix here.
We can actually still go back and compute the M matrix this way.
This was the quadratic form we had looked at before.
And M here is a diagonal matrix which basically has nothing else but
R here and the two diagonals are the two eigenvalues, lambda1 and lambda2.
Let's talk about Rs in a bit because these are all methods we've come up
with to help us make an efficient set of calculations to
compute what we are interested in.