It sounds like being able to decide on a good topology involves being able
to analyze what the performance of one topology is.
So does Storm provide like real-time analytics.
>> Real-time analytics.
>> For when you want to run a topology.
>> Yeah, I mean we certainly have that.
>> Okay.
>> But not in using Storm, but we have this separate stack that allows you to
know how much resources each instance is taking.
>> I agree.
>> Memory as well as JVM, and how much CPU is being used, how many
tuples are emitted and consumed, how much time is spent on each one of them.
We have a whole can of metrics that you can look at it.
>> Okay.
>> So that if there are some problems, then it's an issue, yeah.
>> But then you're saying it's external to Storm itself.
>> That is external to Storm, yes.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
And that is a,
that is a good way to see barely work, especially we use for topology.
>> Right.
>> Because, I mean, a lot of teams like yours, when you write the topologies and
evaluated we have some issues here we don't know how to figure out.
Then we look at these huge humongous charts to figure out, okay, there it is.
This is the issue.
>> Yeah.
>> And one other problem that we face often is distributed debugging.
Especially with this case of running on so many nodes.
Then if one bolt is misbehaving how do you figure out which bolt is
misbehaving, right?
So that's very hard to do.
So, one of the things that we, and
Storm architecture also makes it more complex, because of
the fact that the Storm workers are running multiple tasks in a single worker.
So when I see the logs that you get, because each one can have a log,
a JVM based log, right.
All the logs are kind of an aggregation of
logs coming from these separate tasks.
So I don't know which one is spewing what logs, right.
So it's very hard to debug that.
>> Yeah.
>> So and, so because of that,
we have come up with an analytic system called log indexing, so that
all the logs that we produce about these topologies are indexed separately so
that I'm, each task is given a unique ID and the topology name is unique.
And you have [INAUDIBLE] topology name, this task, this task,
then to bring up the log that is pointing to that.
So at a one single place I can go and take a look at it.
Otherwise it becomes very hard to even debug anything.
And you can spend hours and even days to debug a particular issue.
And sometimes, you are not able to even figure that out.