As you might remember when we showed the
application earlier, geofence events,
such as entering or
leaving the geofence,
generated notifications on our device.
The next step that you'll need
to do to get these notifications
is to write a sendNotification
helper method.
This takes the string you
created in the last step and
creates a notification out of it.
If you aren't familiar
with notifications,
you should learn more about them
in the instructor notes below.
So your next task is to write
the sendNotification helper method,
put it in the
GeofenceTransitionsIntentService.java
file, and it should take a string and
generate a notification
containing that string.
Check this box when you're done.
If you're really stuck, don't worry,
I've included an implementation
in the code for this course.