So Leila's made us this
MT settings activity.
Why don't we make one of those fancy
preference fragments we've been talking
about and populate it with some
preferences we find in an XML file.
We'll be using the Version 7 support
library of the preference fragments for
backwards compatibility to API level 9.
Because of that,
in the Gradle file you'll need to
add the library dependency for
version 7 preferences support.
Okay, I've added it now and
I'm going to sync.
And once that's done, let's create a new
class and call it SettingsFragment.
This class will extend from
the preference fragment compact.
Make sure you are using compact, and
that it's from the Version 7 library.
Also notice the red error problem
because we've extended this class.
So to solve this, we can simply
implement all the methods in it,
which is just the one
onCreatePreferences.
Now that we have this fragment,
let's make an XML preference file,
which will define what
goes inside this fragment.
Start by creating a new folder under
the res directory and call it xml.
And this is where our
preferences XML file will live.
Once you've done that, you can
create a new XML resource file and
call it pref_visualizer.
Any preference XML's outer tag is
always a preference screen tag.
Within that tag you can nest other
preferences tags of different types.
You can even nest other preference
screen tags if you want.
This will create a nested
hierarchy of preferences.
What do I mean by a nested
hierarchy of preferences?
Well, here,
I'm in the found settings screen.
And if I click on the display,
it would actually show me
another settings screen.
But for our visualizer app,
we only have a handful of preferences.
So we will be using only this
one preference screen tag.
I'm going to start by adding
a preference tag for a checkbox.
This checkbox will ultimately determine
whether or not to show the bass circle.
Inside that checkbox preference tag,
I'll define five attributes,
the default value which is true, which
means show the bass circle by default.
The key, just called it show bass,
and then the title is Show Bass.
I'll also provide information
about the preference summary.
A preference summary simply tells
what the user should expect when
they check or uncheck an option.
So for that I've set the summary on to
say Shown and summary off to say Hidden.
Now that we have the XML, let's move
back to the settings fragment file.
In the onCreate method, you'll call
the addPreference from resource method,
passing in your XML file.
This will generate a preference
screen from that file.
Now that we've had all that sorted out,
let's add this preference
fragment to our activity.
To do that, I'm just going to go to
the activity settings layout and
replace this entire relative
layout tag with a fragment tag.
And then point that fragment tag to
the settings fragment we just created.
So we're almost done, just one
more quick change we need to do.
Because we're using a preference
fragments compact library,
we need to add a theme
to the styles at XML.
So browse to the values folder, and then
open up the styles.xml and add a theme.
If you don't add this preference theme,
and
you try to go to the Settings screen,
your app will crash.
And when you check your error log,
it will tell you you must
specify a preferenceTheme.
Okay, enough talk now.
Let's run this code and
see if it actually works.
Once you launch the app,
you can go to the Settings screen, and
we get to see our new
checkbox created here.
And you can tell that the summary
changes when you check or
uncheck it, sweet.