While weather prediction is a good tester performance.
The finer the grid on which the weather is computed, the higher the quality of
prediction made, and so having many, many computations on a fine grid, which
might stress the performance of a system is the best way to get good results.
As far as security is concerned, online banking.
Certainly, you don't want anybody interfering with your bank accounts.
And so, having a highly secured banking system is important.
As far as safety conce, is concerned,
I want the cruise control software on my card to be highly, highly safe.
Maintainability, I'm thinking here of the Twitter API.
That is we know that there are many, many applications that are based upon
the twitter API, and over time if we can maintain stability and
maintainability of that API, those applications won't be broken.
As far as reliability is concerned, I want my traffic light controllers.
So, at every intersection you come to where there's traffic lights
those traffic lights are controlled by some kind of control box, and we
want that control box to be, the software on it to be as reliable as possible.