In summary, then, we've learned how to do a lot with MDPs--
especially using reinforcement learning.
If we don't know what the MDP is,
we know how to estimate it and then solve it.
We can estimate the utility for some fixed policy, pi;
or we could estimate the Q values for the
optimal policy while executing an exploration policy.
And we saw something about how we can make the right trade-offs
between exploration and exploitation.
So reinforcement learning remains one of the most exciting areas of AI.
Some of the biggest surprises have come out of reinforcement learning--
things like Tesauro's backgammon player
or Andrew Ng's helicopter;
and we think that there's a lot more that we can learn.
It's an exciting field, and one where there's plenty of room for new innovation.