In practice, there are several
methods of message passing based IPC.
The first and
most simple form of message passing IPC
that's also part of the POSIX
standard is called pipes.
Pipes are characterized
by two end points, so
only two processes can communicate.
There's no notion of
a message per se with pipes.
Instead, there's just a stream of
bytes that pushed into the pipe from
one process and then received,
but into another.
And one popular use of pipes is to
connect the output from one process
to the input of another process.
So, the entire byte stream that's
produced by P1 would be delivered as
input to P2 instead of somebody
typing it in, for instance.
A more complex form of message
passing IPC is message queues.
As the name suggests,
message queues understand the notion
of messages that they transfer.
So a sending process must submit
a properly formatted message
to the channel, and
then the channel will deliver a properly
formatted message to
the receiving process.
The OS level functionality regarding
message queues also includes things like
understanding priorities of messages or
scheduling the way messages
are being delivered.
The use of message queues is
supported through different APIs.
In Unix-based systems, these include
the POSIX API and the System V API.
The message passing API that most of you
are familiar with is the socket API.
With the socket form of IPC,
the notion of ports that's required
in message passing IPC mechanisms,
that is the socket abstraction that's
supported by the operating system.
Which sockets processes send messages or
receive messages via an API that
looks like this, and then receive.
The socket API supports send and
receive operations that allow processes
to send messages buffers in and out of
the in kernel communication buffer.
The socket call itself creates
a kernel-level socket buffer.
In addition, it will associate any
necessary kernel-level processing
that needs to be performed along
with the message movement.
For instance, the socket may be a TCP/IP
socket, which will mean that the entire
TCP/IP protocol stack is associated
with the data movement in the kernel.
Sockets, as you probably know,
don't have to be used for
processes that are on a single machine.
If the two processes
are on different machines,
then this channel is essentially
between a process and
a network device that will
actually send the data.
In addition, the operating system is
sufficiently smart to figure out that
if two processes are on the same
machine, it doesn't really need
to execute the full protocol stack to
send the data out on the network, and
then just to receive it back and
push it into the process.
Instead, a lot of that will be bypassed.
This remains completely hidden from the
programmer, but you could likely detect
it if you perform certain
performance measurements.