Let's get started with FirebaseUI.
Right now, I'm looking at the GitHub
repository for FirebaseUI-IOS.
If you want the direct
link to the repository,
you can find it in the resources.
Scrolling down a bit,
there's a read me that gives us
general information about FirebaseUI.
There's a summary of all the ways
you can use FirebaseUI and
descriptions of which pods
to add to your pod file,
depending on the specific features
of FirebaseUI that you want to use.
Or, if you want to use all of
the features of FirebaseUI,
then there is a single pod
which includes them all.
This repository and
its documentation is incredibly useful.
And there's much to be learned by
just browsing its directories,
like this directory
called FirebaseAuthUI.
But for now,
let's jump back into our project, and
see how easy it is to add
authentication using FirebaseUI.