Now for the next question.
Which the following statements
are necessarily true about a system of
equations that has a unique solution and
which statements are sufficient to prove
that a system has a unique solution?
Again let's assume that we're only
talking about systems of equations in
three dimensions and also for
this quiz we'll assume that the letter
K refers to a non zero number.
The first statement is the planes
defined by the equations in the system
all have a common intersection point.
Second there are no equations
of the form 0 equals 0 or
0 equals K found during
Gaussian elimination.
Third there are exactly three
equations in the system and
four after reaching triangular form
each variable can be found as
the lead variable in an equation.
Let's also assume here for number four
that we don't run into any equations of
the form 0 = K if we do
Gaussian elimination,
since that would automatically
mean the system has no solution.
Check the appropriate boxes
next to each statement.