If you're up to the challenge,
go ahead and
add the code to your app to send another
event to analytics using TagManager.
In the ShowDinnerActivity, in
the removeMeal() method, change the code
that sends the event tracking data and
update it to use TagManager.
So here's the removeMeal method.
It sends an intent to start
the RemoveMealActivity, and
currently it sends a hit to
Analytics to report the event.
So, you're going to
comment all this out and
instead add the code to send
the data to TagManager.
Notice in this case the label
is not the food preference,
because we don't actually have
the food preference here.
Instead we're sending the selected
dinner, so you're going to need to
correct a variable in TagManager for
the selected dinner.
After you've updated the code
you'll need to go to TagManager and
do what you need to do to send
the data on to Analytics.
You may find you need to create a new
data layer variable, a new trigger, and
I'm pretty sure you're
going to need a new tag.
This time, you will need to
deploy your code to the app,
because you've made changes to the code.
Don't forget to publish in TagManager.
Start and stop your app.
And then look for the hits in
the TagManager real time dashboard.
Try out your app and look for
the results in the real time screen.