[SOUND] Oh, hey Colt,
what's up?
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> Yeah can I get a latte?
>> [INAUDIBLE]
>> Oh, you're right, yeah.
Dude, by the way, I have to say, Java's
manage memory is so cool, I saved so
much time not having to care about
when my objects are released.
>> [INAUDIBLE]
>> Yeah,
it's like the perfect setup for
a programmer.
Allocate objects,
this doesn't freeze them.
I can focus on doing cooler stuff.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> Yeah and the best part, it's for
free, the system just does it.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> No, seriously, the manage memory is
free, you don't have to pay a cent.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> Oh, dude, just embrace it,
I can write code however I want,
Garbage Collector does the rest.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> Oh.
>> Yeah.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> You're right.
>> Oh, I see, so you're saying there's
a tax for garbage collection events.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> Yeah when they happen
in a short period of time.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> Okay, yeah I'll be more
careful when I write my loops.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> Yeah, I totally hated to have
draining into my apps framerate.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> Oh so
how do I spot these problems then?
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> Run the tools, got it.
>> [INAUDIBLE]
>> Okay, sounds good, I'll see you.
Oh, hey wait, make it a double,
I'm going to need it.