Let's dive in with step one.
Adding the correct permissions
to use the Content Provider.
In your app go ahead and
open up the Android manifest,
right here add the following permission.
This format is very
similar to asking for
permission for using Internet access or
accessing the phone's camera.
I'm only asking for the read permission
from the content provider here,
since the quiz example app will
not be writing any information
to the droidtermsexample
Content Provider.
So why do you need to ask for
permissions via the Android
manifest in the first place?
It's a security feature of Content
Providers, that they're protected by
the same permissioning system
that will pop-up these dialogues,
which inform the user of
what the app actually does.
Since you must request permissions
to use Content Providers,
this means that an evil developer
can not just get access to
any data on the user's
phone that they want.
For example, they can't use
the context Content Provider to say,
steal all of the user's friends emails.
Or at least they wouldn't be able to
do it without a dialogue popping up
requiring the user's consent.
For a further discussion of permissions,
check out the information
below this video.