All right.
I hope you're all stretched out
because it's time to step
up to the perf plate again.
Let's take another look
at an overdraw situation,
this time involving custom views.
Now as a developer,
these are custom situations where you
want to create a unique experience or
behavior that isn't quite covered
by Android's built in views.
For example, in the following code,
some of the UI elements or
at least portions of them may be
invisible to the final scene, and
thus the app probably
doesn't need to draw them.
So, as Cole mentioned, these
are situations where you might want to
employ clipping to prevent
unnecessary use of GPU resources.
So, let's hop back to the render app and
take a look at Droid cards.
All right.
Now in the background here, I've
brought up some of the source files for
this activity.
Now as you can see in this
DroidCardsView Java file, the UI for
this activity is implemented
using a custom view
that displays a stack of
overlapping Droid playing cards.
Now, we don't have time
to cover it now but
if you'd like to review creating custom
views, feel free to check out some of
the useful resources in
the instructor notes.
All right, so let's gather some
information about our app.
Let's turn on GPU overdraw debug again
and see how this activity looks.
Whoa!
There's clearly lots of
overdraw happening here.
Particularly these red
areas right in the center.
Now, I have a question for you.
What could possibly be
causing this much overdraw?
Is it, we've inadvertently
declared extraneous backgrounds,
we're drawing cards to the screen in
a way in which they overlap leaving
some portions hidden, we shouldn't be
using a custom view in this scenario?
Or is it the frustration that builds
up from developers who chose not to
address rendering
problems like overdraw?