We've seen Karthik introduce the theory and motivation of the Storm data model.
Amazingly, his presentation is all that is given to real hackathons held at
Twitter, Stanford and Berkeley.
In this course, however, we will help you connect Storm concepts to
Storm code syntax in the remainder of lesson one and lessons two and three.
Finally, in lesson four, you will complete a simple final project to
complete the course with the option to hack away further on more
complex projects along with our hackathon participants.
Let's get started linking Storm concepts to Storm syntax.
The Storm Data Model contains two simple computational units, spouts and bolts.
In this course, we will identify spouts with a red triangle
to represent sources of data for the topology.
In other words, coming from Postgres SQL, MySQL, Kafka Spout, or
Kestrel Spout, or the Twitter Sample Stream.
Next, we will identify Bolts with a blue square to represent units of
computation on data.
In other words, filtering, aggregation, join or transformations.
I'm using a red triangle and a blue square,
simply because I can't really [LAUGH] draw the spout and bolt like Karthik.
The next concept of the Storm Data Model is that spouts emit tuples or
an immutable ordered list of elements.
Bolts receive a tuple, do internal calculation and emit a tuple.
Know that tuples are immutables.
So, a new tuple is emitted rather than a modified tuple.
Finally, spouts and bolts are linked together in a Storm topology to
create a directed acyclic graph, meaning simply that there are no cycles.
Although cycles are permitted, we do not typically use this feature.
Vertices are computational elements, either spouts or
bolts, and edges are streams of data.
Finally, edges are defined by four typical groupings.
There are more, but these are the typical and most often used.
Shuffle grouping randomly distributes tuples to the next stage of
bolt instances.
This shuffle grouping in Storm allows you to automatically rebalance tuples.
The fields grouping groups tuples by single column value or
multiple column values.
The all grouping replicates all tuples to the next stage of bolt instances.
This is a rare grouping because there typically is
fan out with all grouping, basically.
You need to be careful that all of your data is not going to
be replicated to such an extent that your topology fails.
We do use this in lesson three.
The final grouping is the global grouping which sends all tuples of
a single stage to a single bolt.
You will have the opportunity to work with all of these grouping types in
the remainder of the course.
Let's get started with code.
On a final note, linking Storm concepts to Storm syntax, navigate to
storm.apache.org at anytime throughout the course, and click on Documentation.
As an open source project, Storm has excellent documentation.
And as our hackathoners discovered, sometimes,
it was easier to simply look at the Java docs for any questions they had.
As of this recording, use the Javadocs on the left hand pane and
not the documentation Javadocs in the middle of the page.
Which again, as of this recording,
goes to Nathan Marz's old Javadoc's site as a version 0.8.1.
Navigating back to the updated Javadocs you see that
the Storm core documentation is at least up to 0.9.1.
Remember, our Storm version is 0.9.2 incubating.
For example, searching for tuple and clicking on tuple, we see in the method
summary the getString by position method along with getValue at position method.
Along with a number of different methods that may be useful for you.
As you can see by all packages and all classes, this course is
touching the surface of all of the different things that you can do with Storm.
So with that quick reminder, let's continue on with the course.