I walk through the solutions for
lesson 2, stage 3 implementing the SentenceWordCountTopology.
In part one, I asked you to navigate to stage 3, and duplicate
the SentenceCountTopology, and rename it the SentenceWordCountTopology.
Also in part one, I asked you to follow the Java convention and
make sure the class name matches the Java file name and the constructor.
You didn't need to do this, but I also think it's a good idea to build our
package as we develop so that we make sure we're not making any syntax errors.
We do that by mvn package remembering that
on your virtual machine you're in lesson 2, stage 3.
And we find we have a build success, which is great.
I'll do a mvn clean and clear the screen.
In part two you're implementing a new bolt, split sentence bolt, and I suggested
that you extend the base rich bolt by simply copying and pasting the count bolt.
Let's do that now.
I'll select and copy the count bolt.
I'll create a new area that says split.
For a split sentence bolt obviously the class name will need to change.
SplitSentenceBolt.
That extends the base rich bolt.
And now I'll just clear out the prepare, execute, and
declare output fields methods.
Here in prepare we no longer need our count map.
In our execute method all of this will change.
So we can delete that now.
And for our declare output fields we'll simply clear out some of these comments.
Remember that this split sentence bolt is going to be taking in a tuple of
a sentence.
And we'll need to split that sentence into individual words or tokens.
I gave you useful syntax hints with string delims and
string tokens, so I'll just copy that in now.
The first step in our execute method is going to need to,
again, take in a tuple and extract the sentence from position zero.
That's simply a string sentence,
sentence equals our tuple.getSTring at position 0.
Finally notice that our sentence.split method is returning tokens.
Let's just iterate through the tokens and emit each value.
Remember that the syntax here is collector.emit new Values.
Finally in our declareOutputFields we're emitting value token.
I'll call that a sentence word.
Therefore we tell the schema that we're emitting a tuple consisting of
one word sentence word.
And in our OutputFieldsDeclarer.declare method we have new fields and
not word but sentence-word.
Now that we've implemented our split sentence bolt,
let's make sure this compiles.
Mvn package.
Great, we have a build success.
Next in part three, I asked you to update the topology to make
a random sentence, split the sentence using your new split sentence bolt that we
just implemented, and send the output to the count bolt.
The implementation question I asked was, what stream method should you use to
connect a sentence to the split sentence bolt?
In other words, should we use a field grouping, a shuffle grouping,
a global grouping or an all grouping?
Do sentences really need to be sorted by field in order to be split?
Let's work on that now.
Scroll down to your topology building section.
And let's just look at the topology as it is now.
We have a sentence spout, a count bolt, and a report bolt.
These are connected by the fieldsGrouping and a globalGrouping.
Continuing on, notice I've labeled our sentence spout, count bolt, and
report bolt and removed the code for now so we can look at the topology.
In this exercise, we want to add in our split sentence bolt
between the sentence spout and count bolt.
In Storm this is very easy.
We first want to add in our new split sentence bolt,
connect out sentence spout to our sentence bolt.
In answer to the implementation question this should be a shuffle grouping.
And finally, we want to reconnect the split sentence bolt to the count
bolt using the fieldsGrouping.
Remember that the fieldsGrouping will hash or
bin on each word and send each word to the right count bolt.
Let's do this in code.
The first step is to copy and paste the syntax of a bolt.
Let's change the component id to split-sentence-bolt.
And that of course takes our new object, SplitSentenceBolt.
Let's leave the parallelism of 15.
And here the connection of the sentence-spout to the sentence-spout should be
a shuffleGrouping.
And lastly, remember that the shuffleGrouping does not need to hash on fields.
And therefore we can remove the fields grouping.
Graphically we can see that the sentence-spout is now connected to
our split-sentence-bolt by the shuffleGrouping.
Finally to connect the count bolt using the fieldsGrouping to
our split-sentence-bolt, remember that we have to change our fields component.
And it's no longer word and we actually named it sentence-word.
To see this we scroll up.
We scroll up to our declareOutputFields.
And remember that our field declaration sentence-word needs to
map in our topology.
Finally, we see that the sentence spout is connected to our
split-sentence-bolt using the shuffleGrouping.
The split-sentence-bolt is connected to
our count-bolt using a fieldsGrouping and fields sentence word.
And our CountBolt and our ReportBolt remains unchanged.
Let's compile this and run our package by submitting it in to storm.
The command here is mvn package.
Remember that you should be in lesson 2, stage 3.
Let's look at our hierarchy using tree.
We see that SentenceWordCountTopology has been created.
Let's scroll up a bit.
Our class SentenceWordCountTopology has been created.
Finally we see that our jar files, including dependencies, are there.
So submit our program using Storm space jar target/udacity.
Again hit using tab hyphen tab udacity.storm.SentenceWordCountTopology.
Once we've submitted our program, we can go back to our visualization.
We can see our program running in the background, and
here we see that seven is one of our largest words due to the count.
Here we have 14.
There we have 39.
As the program runs the random sentence spout is spitting out new sentences.
And our program is splitting the sentences and counting.
Seven is the largest word because we see four score and
seven years go and Snow White and the seven dwarfs.
Finally in part four I asked you to personalize your random sentences.
So you can go to the random sentence spout, change the sentences,
take a screenshot or screencast or video and upload it to the forum.
And how about commenting on two other posts?
Remember, that your sentence word count topology should now match Lesson 2,
Stage 4.
Great job.