Linux is really flexible
about file names.
There's no hard rule that
a particular kind of file has to
have a particular kind of name.
The file system doesn't require that
files have extensions on the end of
their names.
If you're coming from Windows,
that can be a big change.
You can see for instance,
a file called readme instead of
readme.txt, but it's still a text file.
But just as on other systems,
there are conventions.
If you don't know what a file is, you
can use your favorite search engine to
look up the extension on
the end of the file name.
Or, if there isn't one,
the whole file name and
maybe something about the context.
So, given what you already know,
and what you can find with some
quick searching, see if you can say what
each of these files is likely to be.
What type of things do you expect
to find in each of these files?
For Hello-Kitty.jpg is that
a photograph, a saved game, or
a Japanese textile?
License, is that a piece of copyrighted
software, piece of plain text,
or a crypto key?
Readme.md, is that a monitoring device,
a mark down document,
or a medical record?
Superuser.pem, is that a crypto key,
a printer config, or a recipe?
And install.sh, is that a shell script,
a data shard, or a shared file?
Again, if you don't already know, look
it up using your favorite search engine.