Now, the next question is where did these probabilities come from?
The honest answer for this simple example is I just made them up.
I just used my intuition to say that "the" and "a" are roughly equally probable,
and all the other probability judgments as well.
But in reality, numbers like this come from data.
So just as we've seen in the rest of the course, where we learn models by training on data,
we can do the same in natural language.
And the data that we have is naturally occurring text.
Now, when we dealt with word models, going from naturally occurring text to numbers that we can use in the model
was straight-forward because all we had to do was count, and then come up with some very simple smoothing techniques
in cases where our counts are zero or low.
In the case of dealing with parse trees, that's not the case, because we don't normally see a parse tree kind of out there in the wild.
People don't publish books full of parse trees. And so we have to go out and create our data.
And in the early 1990s that's what the field of natural language processing did.
They said, "We really need some more data having to do with parse trees, so let's go out and create it.
"Let's pay some people, let's train them to understand what parse trees we want, what they look like,
"And then we'll give them a lot of text and we'll have them mark it up. We'll have that resource that the whole field can use from then on."
And that's exactly what happened, and this is a sentence that's taken out of one of these resources.
It's called "the Penn tree bank." So "Penn" for the University of Pennsylvania, who put this all together.
And "tree bank", meaning it's a large bank consisting of parse trees.
And to do this, they had to decide on what the categories are, and we've seen some categories here that are different than what I showed.
These and Ns and so on are a little bit more complicated here.
So as a field, we had to agree on what the categories were, and agree on some techniques for deciding
what good parse trees are for a sentence, and then we have at it.
And now we can come up with those probabilities. So if we want to say, "What's the probability that a sentence
"is rewritten in a particular way?" we can look that up by counting.
So here we have a sentence, it is rewritten as a noun phrase followed by a verb phrase. This is a long verb phrase
that goes all the way down to here. Followed by a comma, followed by a sentence that's an adverbial phrase, and followed by a period.
And so that would count as one count for that particular rewrite of sentence, and then there'd be other trees
that counted for other rewrites. There might be others that were the same as this.
There'd probably be a lot where it's just a sentence consisting of a noun phrase followed by a verb phrase,
followed by a period. And we would go through and we'd have these counts, and that would be a resource
that people can draw on to create their probabilistic models.