Now we need to add the buttons for slow
and fast playback of the audio.
Before we get started, make sure you have added all
the images to PitchPerfect that we've
provided in the resources.
If you haven't done this already, you can still download
them from resources and you need to add
them to the asset catalog. I've included
a link where we did this earlier if you
need a refresher. Alright, assuming you
have the images, the first thing we're
going to do is add two UI buttons.
One for playing audio slow and one for
playing the audio fast. With the
Main.storyboard opened and the Play Sounds
View Controller selected, let's search
for button in the object library in the
bottom-right. Drag a UI button to the
Document Outline directly under the
Horizontal Stack View. With the button
selected in the Document Outline, look in
the attributes inspector, and remove the
word “button” for its title. And make sure
you press Enter for the changes to take effect.
In the image drop-down, find the
image named “Slow”.
In the Document Outline, we can rename
this button to Slow or Snail Button,
which ever you prefer. Just single click
on the word “Button” and then change its
name.
We now have our first button on the
playback screen. Now let's add the Rabbit
Button with the same steps.
Drag a UI button under the Horizontal Stack View
under our Slow/Snail button, then in the
attributes inspector, remove the “Button” title
and select the Fast image of our Rabbit.
Finally single click on the new
button in the Document Outline and
change its name to Fast Button Rabbit
Button or whatever you prefer.
Awesome, that's all it takes to add
buttons into a Stack View. Next we'll add
the buttons for playing the recorded
audio with high and low pitches in
another Horizontal Stack View.