I've created a new user class here like
so, similarly to the Restaurant and
menu items classes.
In both the Restaurant and MenuItem
classes there is now a user_id variable,
and the relationship declaration to
establish a ForeignKey relationship
between these items and
the user that created them.
I'll read in the database
output in the create_engine to
restaurantmenuwithusers.db.
So we don't override our
old database just yet.
You can go ahead and
run database_setup.py and
it will create a new database
complete with our user functionality.
There's a new lotsofmenus.py found
in the instruction notes that will
repopulate the database and set the user
ID for all the restaurants equal to one.
Go ahead and run this as well.
The sample code for this video is
available in the instructor notes.