Let's revisit the challenge question
from the beginning of this section.
We asked about which methods enable us
to find the maximum point in this graph.
We showed that we can have problems
getting stuck in local maxima, or
on plateaus, where there is not enough
local information to determine which way
to go to improve the answer, or to
determine if we've reached the maximum.
We used randomness and
three methods to get out of this trap.
They included random restart, where we
start many particles at random positions
on the graph, hill climb and
take the best results.
Another solution was simulated
annealing, where we make an analogy
to the process of gradually cooling
the temperature of our particle
to make it move in progressively less
random ways while hill climbing,
until we converge on the global maximum.
Finally, we said genetic
algorithms could help us.
This is where we select positions,
based on their fitness,
to breed children that mutate but
eventually converge on the solution.
We also talked about how random restart,
simulated annealing and
genetic algorithms are combined into
the idea of stochastic beam search,
where multiple particles
are released on the graph.
And their children,
generated progressively less randomly,
eventually converge
to the maximum value.
We'll see these ideas repeatedly in AI
in techniques like particle filters,
pattern recognition with hidden Markov
models and Monte Carlo Markov chains.
Keep these ideas in mind whenever
you're creating your own algorithms or
attacking new problems.
Sometimes letting go and embracing
randomness is the key to the solution.