The auth flow is complete and
we can continue implementing
the rest of the Movie Manager app.
Back in the code, I'm now working with
the more completed version of the app.
You can download this version of the app
with the link in the instructor notes.
This version has implemented some
more of the movie database client and
its methods, and
I'll run it to show you what's going on.
We can login using our new auth flow.
And here in the movie picker
view we can search for movies.
So I'll do a quick search and
I'll select a movie.
From here we can favorite and
unfavorite a movie, but
the watchlist functionality
is left incomplete.
If we go back you can see this
when we select the WatchList tab,
because no movies
are populating the table view.
But the Favorites tab
is working just fine.
Okay, so let's stop this and
go back to the code.
Here in the TMDBConvenience file,
we'll scroll down to getWatchListMovies.
This is one of two methods
that is not implemented yet,
and those will be the focus
of the next two exercises.
Now this method's what's used
to populate the WatchList tab
with movies from your watchlist and it's
going to be up to you to implement it.
To implement this method, I want you to
look at the already implemented methods
getMoviesForSearchString and
getFavoriteMovies.
Really study them and pay close
attention to the substitute key and
helper method that's used
in getFavoriteMovies.
When you've finished
implementing getWatchlistMovies,
you should see your watchlist
movies in the WatchList tab.
And when you're done with this exercise,
check this box.