your job is to teach the car how to
drive itself in order to do that you're
going to need to teach the car how to
perceive the world around it now when I
Drive I use my eyes to figure out how
fast to go and where the lane lines are
and where to turn a car doesn't have
eyes but in a self-driving car we can
use cameras and other sensors to achieve
a similar function that's right so let's
think about what those cameras are
seeing as we drive down the road you and
I can see where the lane lines are
automatically but we need to teach the
car how to do that so your goal in this
first module is to write code to
identify and track the position of the
lane lines in a series of images and
then the project at the end of this
first module you're going to use image
analysis techniques to do exactly that
so let's start really high-level here's
a picture of a stretch of wide open
highway what kind of features do you
think would be helpful to figure out
where the lane lines are in this image