A distributed firewall configuration
typically includes standalone
network firewalls, host based firewalls,
and personal firewalls.
That is,
the standalone network firewalls protect
the internal network from
attacks from the Internet.
In addition, host based firewalls
are placed at workstations and servers.
These host based firewalls protect
against internal attacks and
provide protection tailored to specific
machines and server applications.
For example, with host based firewalls
providing server specific protection,
we can have one public facing,
external web server and
an internal facing web server.
In addition, personal firewalls can be
used to protect personal computers,
regardless of where they
are in the network.
An important issue here is the need to
coordinate the multiple firewalls for
security monitoring.
This typically involves aggregating
the logs from multiple firewalls and
perform correlation analysis.
For example, if multiple host based
firewalls see the same attack,
this may suggest that there's a worm
spreading inside the internal network.