So think about, we're doing queries
where we're computing the average and
returning it and
we're doing that only for
students that come from a certain state.
So, what if there's only one
student from, say, a smaller state.
Wyoming for example.
So if there is only one
student from Wyoming,
this is kind of like the Junior
standing discussion we had.
There was only one student,
the Junior standing.
So there's only one student,
we ask the query,
saying give me the average of
students who are from Wyoming.
The average is going to be the same
exact score of that student,
one student, who comes from Wyoming.
So, depending on how many students,
if there are too few,
extreme case only one, then,
of course, the average is the score.
So, Yes is the answer.
It will not be possible if there
are lots students from each state.
But we didn't say that here so
I would pick the first answer.