Another very important part of your
nanodegree experience is that you're
part of a cohort.
This is basically a group of students
who are starting the program with you
and will stay with you
until the very end.
They'll be your community for
the whole time you're in the program,
and you'll be working on the same
timeline for your projects.
You'll interact with each other almost
every day throughout the program, so
we highly recommend getting to
know each other right away.
Your community will share a forum,
which is the first place you should go
whenever you need to get help,
or have questions.
It's important to get to know these
people because they'll be your support
network now, and the start of your
professional network in the future.
We'll help you stay in touch with each
other after you graduate, as well.
The cohort you're part of at
the beginning of the program
is based on the month
that you're starting.