(Sebastian) --to watch all the videos. (Peter) Right, so we'll try and do that better.
So let's see. Here's one you touched on a little bit.
"Many researchers believe we need a special, rather different kind of hardware to run human-like A.I.,
"and that von-Neumann architecture computers just won't cut it. So which advancement in hardware do you think will benefit A.I. the most?"
(Sebastian) That's a question out of New Delhi, India. That's a subject to a lot of ongoing debate,
and depending who you ask, you'll get very different answers. There's the diehards who believe the only way to get A.I.
is by emulating the human brain, or even more so, building a new computer structure that is analog
and has similar connectivity to the human brain. It turns out it's hard to build.
So building a device out of 10 to the 11 or so neurons and to the 14th interconnections is really difficult.
I personally believe the power will come from something else, but of course I don't know.
And future years of research will show us. I believe it will come from good and fast and interconnected processing
the way we have it today. And by using massive amounts of data.
People are able to sort through massive amounts of data. I have a small child, he's three years old;
For most of his life, I think he sorted through data in ways that are not understandable to me,
and if you have a child yourself, you know what I'm talking about.
I think that's the way to go: Use existing computers and be really smart how to process massive amounts of data.
That's my guess, and it's just a guess. (Peter) And I would agree with that. I think we've seen incredible progress
in what computer hardware can do. And the hardware is very different from the brain, but I think we should focus on
what the computers can do with us. We already know something about how brains work, and they can do their own thing.
So we should figure out how to make the hardware we have work as best as it can, and then how to put people and computers together
as a partnership. (Sebastian) Here's a question by Philip Scoco from Singapore:
"Thanks for the fun and interesting course. A question: Many great A.I. methods, such as SVM and SVD,
"are expensive and need a long time to train, especially in rich and large data sets.
In a real world setting, how do people handle these computational issues?
(Peter) That's a great question, and that's certainly true. First I want to say that a lot of these methods are not all that
computationally challenging, and that there are many very interesting things you can do in--
We mentioned image understanding and language understanding and so on.
You can do a lot running just on your laptop. So your laptop of today was the supercomputer of a decade ago,
and people got work done then, and they get work done now. So don't feel like you're locked out of the game
because you don't have a whole data center at your disposal.
So that's part of it, and the other question is--
(Sebastian) Said the man with a data center at his disposal.
(Peter) Right. If you do happen to have one, what can you do with it? And what types of approaches do you take
for dealing with huge amounts of data? I guess one thing that is increasingly important is taking these existing algorithms,
and most of the algorithms we've described in class for machine learning are batch algorithms,
where you have a fixed set of data, you do some processing on that, and then you're able to answer queries about it.
But you find with the online services today, you're much more likely to have to translate them into an online setting,
where the data is not fixed, where every day and every second there's new data coming in,
and that's updating what we know and updating the models, and then queries are intermixed with the new data,
and we have to make that all work out. So we change the models so that they're online, and then we aren't so worried
as much anymore about the complexity of the models.
So, many of the hardest problems we've talked about are, "What are N squared or N cubed?" or some of them are nP complete.
But that doesn't matter, because if you have to get to an online setting, it's got to be basically order one.
You've got to be able to respond immediately. And so you make whatever approximations you have to make
to get to that order one model, and then continue to update it as you go.
(Sebastian) And I want to add to this, this is one of my frustrations with our scientific field.
Our scientific field in the past has looked into lots of small data sets, and very few have looked at very large data sets.
And as a result, the algorithms are mathematically beautiful and they're really elegant, but they don't scale.
And sometimes you put mathematical beauty and rigor ahead of scaling,
and it's much easier to publish a paper that has beautiful math in it than one that just uses large amounts of data.
I think on the practical side, large data is becoming more and more important, and companies like Google live on large data,
and Amazon and many others. And we lack the tools, we lack the rigorous research that goes and builds
really fast and scalable methods that have good guarantees and good behavior.
I think there's a huge opportunity for anyone in machine learning to step in and take this seriously.
I can promise you, if you make a big impact and get something as good as, say, an SVM working in constant time
per data item, then you're going to have a really really big impact on the field.
(Peter) Okay. So speaking of impact, next question from Sydney, Australia, "What would you recommend as the next steps
"after the course finishes for those of us who would like to progress further?
"What steps should be taken to utilize this in the commercial domain?" It's from Greg.
(Sebastian) Well, the very thing I would do is, there'll be more classes that we hope to post here, so please stay tuned.
I think take any problem in your life right now, no matter how small, that annoys you, and fix it using A.I. technology,
is a great way going forward. There's certainly many in my life that annoy me.
And then if you really like what we're doing, Stanford is a great university. There's many fantastic universities.
Enroll. Come and learn with us, and learn more with us. It's a lot of fun. And you'll be much more powerful if you learn
all the skills that we're not even telling you today in this class.
(Peter) So I think there is a lot more to learn, and you can learn that by going to school, you can learn that by reading on your own.
And I think most important is by practice. So go out and find a problem and pitch in and do it.
So as Sebastian said, something that's bothering you or go out and find an open source project and volunteer and start working.
(Sebastian) Maybe the last question, Peter? (Peter) Okay. (Sebastian) Okay.
"Apart from trial and error, are there any ways to find out which technique fits a problem?
"For example, should we do dimensionality reduction or clustering or SVM?" This is by Vikovel from somewhere in this world.
(Peter) I guess maybe trial and error is the best way to describe it, or another way to describe it is experience.
Of saying, "What problems have I seen that are like this before?" And then experience comes in two forms:
One is personal experience. "What have I seen and worked for me?" Another is experience of the literature:
What have other people tried and what worked for them?
(Sebastian) Yeah. When I work with students on things, the number one rule I give them is, "Before you pick a method,
"look at the data. Just look at the data. Spend a week or so staring at the data, because you're going to discover things
"that are very insightful that you will not see if you just toss a random, say, machine learning method at it."
And that's really important. If you do this, you set yourself apart from I'd say 80% of the students I've worked with in my life.
Which tend to just say, "Oh, here's a method called SVM; I believe it's the right one," or boosting, or what have you.
"Let me just toss any data at it." Then as you do this, when you use a learning algorithm, I think it's really important
to reflect on it, and have your expectations and see if your expectations are met.
If they're met, that's great, and you're a really smart person, you understand what you're doing.
If they're not met, you have an opportunity to learn more, and maybe you'll find it back in the code,
or maybe there's some insight that you just missed so far.
I'm pretty much entirely self-taught. I never took a class in A.I. or in robotics of any meaning.
And most of what I've done is just look very carefully at data and methods and just learned from that process.
It's been very gratifying to me. (Peter) Okay, great. Seems like this is a good place to stop,
and let me thank everybody again for your hard work in the class and for your great and challenging questions.
(Sebastian) Do you think we can promise one of these office hours next week?
(Peter) Yea, we'll keep doing it. (Sebastian) Okay. We tried to do it online, and we had technical problems.
So this is, of course, a re-recorded session. But maybe next week we'll do the same thing again. (Peter) Yeah.
(Sebastian) It's a lot of fun. (Peter) We'll just do it this way--
(Sebastian) Let us know via Twitter whether you like it or not, or G+. Bye.