Let me now show you some examples of
where things don't work out as well.
For example, here I have one image that
actually you see a lot of different
black holes and stuff like that.
And if you were to compare
this to the ground truth,
which is basically again
what I've shown you before.
You notice that there are problems and
not a lot of things are happening.
Partly it is, because in an image like
this, sometimes even a good matching
algorithm may not find matches at
the patches that you're looking at.
There's a lot of research going
on there, stereo matching and
stereo reconstruction has become
really mature these days.
I encourage you to
look at various sites.
And the many algorithms exist
really do a much better job of
this type of disparity computation.
Another problem exists
is there are occlusions.
Therefore there are no matches.
So for example,
here you notice in this instance there
is a whole lot of black spots here.
Where partly because if you note this,
these two regions here don't
actually appear in this one.
And similarly there is, you know, lots
of information that's included because
as I moved the viewpoints,
different things are appearing.
So this region is missing because,
again, I just don't have
this information here, in this
viewpoint, so there are no matches.
Similarly, when you look at this,
this is caused by the fact that
while this region is appearing here,
it's not actually appearing
cleanly in both of them.