In addition to the knowledge and
skills you'll gain,
you're also going to practice
thinking like a programmer.
And we're going to to focus on five
ways of thinking that all programmers
must do.
And you already have
experience in all of them.
The first is procedural thinking, and
this involves taking a big problem and
breaking the solution into a set
of steps: one, two, three.
The next way of thinking is
called abstract thinking.
And if you couldn't do abstract
thinking, you may know that
if someone gave you one apple and
then another, you have two.
But if you someone asked you what
happened when they gave one orange and
then another orange,
you might have no idea.
But because you do have an understanding
of the abstract idea of numbers,
you know that you have two oranges.
But even more importantly, you know th
abstract idea, that one plus one is two.
The next programmatic way of thinking,
is a systematic way of solving problems,
or systematic debugging.
Because even the best programmers make
mistakes, and this is the skill where
they systematically identify problems,
or potential problems, and
then track down potential causes,
until they find the problem and fix it.
The fourth mental technique,
is called technological empathy, and
it involves understanding how
the computer sees things, and
you've already started developing this.
Now, when you see texts like this,
you can start to think about
it the way a computer would.
You may already be thinking
that the "is" should be bold.
The fifth technique that we're
going to keep coming back to,
is called "systems thinking".
This may sound a little intimidating,
but basically this involves taking one
big idea, like, what does it
mean to think like a programmer.
And break it down into
its component pieces.
Because we're going to keep coming
back to these five ways of thinking,
next you'll see a text
summary of all of them.
You can just skim it for now.
I'll link back to it as appropriate.