So I'm back looking at the RecordSoundsViewController
and the audioRecorderDidFinishRecording
function. If we were
to run this code right now, the Segue
would be triggered, we send the recorded
audio URL and the RecordSoundsViewController
would be displayed. And let's
just test that.
Now despite our best efforts here,
the RecordSoundsViewController still
doesn't have a clue about what to do
when the Segue being triggered and the
audio URL that we're sending it.
Lucky for us, when a Segue is called,
there's a function that's triggered on
the existing View Controller to help
prepare it for a Segue. It's called
prepareForSegue. Remember it's called
on the existing View Controller. So in
this case, it's the RecordSoundsViewController,
not the PlaySoundsViewController.
so it's going to be called on
this View Controller. So let's try to
implement this function. If we start
typing prepare, we see auto-completion
for the function that we want prepareForSegue.
Let's select it. In this function,
we only need a few lines of code.
First we check if this is the
Segue that we want, that it has the
stopRecording identifier that we set up in
storyboard. Then we grab the View
Segue that we want, that it has the
stopRecording identifier that we set up in
storyboard. Then we grab the View
Controller that were transitioning to,
the destination from this handy
destination property that's part of the Segue.
Because this property is of type
UIViewController, but we know it's a
PlaySoundsViewController, we can up
cast it to a PlaySoundsViewController
using a forced up cast.
And that's what's happening here.
Next we grab the sender, which is the
using a forced up cast.
And that's what's happening here.
Next we grab the sender, which is the
recorded audio URL.
This may seem a little strange, but if we
look back to where we're performing the Segue,
our sender is indeed the recorded
audio URL. And lastly we set the recorded
audio URL in the PlaySoundsViewController.
Now the PlaySoundsViewController
is receiving the recorded
audio URL and we're ready for playback.
Now the PlaySoundsViewController
is receiving the recorded
audio URL and we're ready for playback.