So if you're used to more flexible
query languages, like SQL,
these limitations may
come as a big surprise.
To understand them a bit more,
let's change up our query here
in the query playground method.
Let's say that instead of querying for
June, let's filter for big conferences.
Let's say conferences whose
maxAttendees is greater than 10.
And save this and
then try this one out on localhost,
just to prove that it's not
an index related problem.
Once this is up and running,
we'll go to the API's explorer.
Filter playground on local host,
execute, and we get an error.
Once again, the error message we
see here is not very informative.
But if you take a look at the logs,
you'll see something else.
Based on the logs,
what's the cause of this error?
Is it that a composite
index doesn't exist?
Is it that the sort order is named but
the inequality filter
is on maxAttendees?
Or is it too many inequality
filters in one query?