Okay, so to get started,
let's look at some alternatives you
have available to monetizing your app.
And when we go through
these alternatives,
let's look at how easy it is to start
making money using this alternative.
How it supports a good business model
where you can make long-term revenue,
and finally, what value this
monetization model provides to the user.
So, let's start with our first
alternative, paid downloads.
This is where the user needs
to pay in order to even
download the app to the phone.
So how about easy to launch for
paid downloads?
Well perhaps it's kind of obvious
that this is very difficult to do.
And you have to have an app where the
user really knows the value of your app
beforehand and is willing to pay for it.
Compared to overall number of apps,
there are very few that can do this.
So a paid downloads monetization model
is definitely not easy to launch.
What about long-term revenue?
Well, once the user
has paid up front for
the app,
they don't expect to be charged anymore.
So only using paid downloads will
limit your revenue to the number of
users downloading the app.
So paid downloads has a limitation
when it comes to sustaining long-term
revenue.
Then what about user value?
A paid download definitely
has a high use of value.
After all, the user is willing
to pay up front to get this app.
So they really want it.
All right, let's look at another
alternative, subscription.
This is where the user pays a certain
amount regularly, for example, monthly.
So is a subscription monetization
model easy to launch?
The answer is definitely not.
Again, you're asking the user
to pay up front, and even more,
you're asking them to pay,
for example, every month.
It is a huge decision for
the user to want to do this.
So what about long-term revenue?
Yes, spot on.
The user will continue to pay for
your app as long as it provides value.
So you will continue to get revenue
from all users of your app,
not only at the time
when they downloaded it.
And what about user value?
Same thing as for paid download.
You have a user that is willing to
make an up front financial commitment
to use your app.
So obviously, your app provides a very
specific and high value to the user.
And both these monetization models,
paid downloads and
subscription, can be configured in
the Play store when you deploy your app.
Okay, now let's look at
displaying ads in your app.
Is this monetization
model easy to launch?
Yes it is.
In particular, if there is no charge for
the app, users understand that you
have to make money from something.
What about long-term revenue?
The answer is yes to this one too.
As long as your app is used,
you will be paid for displaying ads, so
this supports a long
term business model.
What about user value?
As it turns out,
ads do provide great value to the user.
As we will see, AdMob, the platform
that we will look at in this course,
is very good at serving ads
which are relevant to the user.
And ads which are relevant
to you is a good thing.
And now for the last alternative we
will look at, in-app purchases enable
you as a developer to advertise and
sell digital goods right in your app.
For example, they can mean new levels or
items in a game.
So is this model easy to launch?
Yes, in-app purchases
are very easy to launch.
The user does not have to pay for
anything up front.
What about long-term revenue?
Well since you can offer and engage
the user with new digital goods all
the time, in-app purchases have
a great long-term revenue potential.
Then what about user value?
Well since the user is engaging with the
app, and you control what to advertise
and sell, it will be very relevant to
the user, so great user value as well.
All right, so those are some of
the monetization alternatives available.
And as you can see, ads and
in-app purchases provides a great
way to make money from your app.
They are easy to launch, they provide
great long-term revenues, and
they align well with the user values.
And in this lesson,
we will be specifically be
looking at displaying ads.