in 2014 two different groups nearly tied
in the internet competition with the
seven-percent classification error one
of those networks is called VG nett or
sometimes just DG and it came from the
visual geometry group at Oxford
University VG has a simple and elegant
architecture which makes it great for
transfer learning the VG architecture is
just a long sequence of three by three
convolutions broken up by two by two
pooling layers and finished by a trio of
fully connected layers at the end
lots of engineers use VG as a starting
point for working on other image
classification tasks and it works really
well the flexibility of VG is one of its
great strength