If you have not noticed yet,
performance considerations are really all about the metrics that we choose.
Ideally, metrics should be represented with values that we
can measure and quantify.
The definition of the term metrics, according to Webster, for
instance, is that it's a measurement standard.
In our analysis of systems, a metrics should be measurable.
It should allow us to quantify a property of a system, so that we
can evaluate the system's behavior or at least compare it to other systems.
For instance, let's say we are concerned with the execution time of the system.
That's a metric.
We can measure it.
We can quantify exactly what is the execution time of a system, so
it's a quantifiable property as well.
A metric is associated in some way with some system that we're interested in.
For instance, that can be the implementation of a particular problem,
the software implementation of a problem.
And that's what we want to measure the execution time of.
And a metric should tell us something about the behavior of
the system we're interested in.
For instance, it can tell us whether it's an improvement over
other implementations of the same problem.
For the later, in order to perform this kind of evaluation and
comparisons, we really should explore the values of
this metrics over some range of meaningful parameters.
By varying the workload that this implementation needs to handle, or
by varying the resources that are allocated to it, or other dimensions.