You have to remember something from your linear algebra.
And by the way, I have to look this up every time, so
if you don't remember, that's okay.
One is that the determinant of a matrix, remember the determinant of a matrix?
That's actually the product of the eigenvalues, okay?
So lambda one, lambda two,
multiply them together, that's the, that's the determinant.
With two zeroes in there, it's easy to see.
It's a little harder to see in the more general case.
The other thing is that the trace of the matrix, right?
The sum of the diagonals, is the sum of the Eigenvalues.
So the determinant of a two-by-two is trivial to compute, right?
This minus that, or however you like to determine some two-by-twos.
Trace is easy, sum them up.
And the Harris operator was just to compute some function R.
You take the M matrix.
You take its determinate, minus some constant of the square of the trace.
And I'll tell you that empirically, the constant was small number, 0.04, 0.06,
written here, exactly how things scale depends a little bit on your, the,
the way you do your gradient operators and pixels.
Okay?
So it's the determinant, which is a product.
Minus the alpha trace.
So the real equation of what you're looking at is right there.
Okay?
So taking a look at lambda one lambda two minus alpha one,
alpha times lambda one plus lambda two squared.
Let's think about this.
R depends on the Eigenvalues but we don't actually have to compute them.
And that's great, because even in 1980,
in the 80s you'd want to compute your eigenvalues, maybe, I don't know.
But the idea is that you compute a single number, all right, really fast.
All right.
So, we've already said that R is large for a corner.
And why is that?
Well, if they're large then both of the l one and l two are large.
Their product is even large and if you take the squares.
You know it's l one square plus l one l two plus l two squared.
Subtract it off.
Yeah but you're subtracting off alpha of it.
It's a small amount.
Okay? So it's still going to be large.
But if only one of the L's is large, then this term goes small,
whereas one of these terms is large so the R value is negative, okay.
So that you can measure the R value, it's negative along an edge, so
R is large for corner, it's negative, along an edge and if the magnitude
of R is small, basically that means that everything was small, right?
So L1 and L2 is, is small, everything there is small.
Well, that's the flat region we were talking about, right?
None of the gradients have any magnitude to speak of.