Now let's modify some of
the properties of the stack view.
Axis, it correctly changes
from horizontal to vertical.
And we can even do this at runtime and
have it animated.
Alignment also behaves as expected, and
we will leave it at fill so
it takes all the vertical space.
Now let's check out spacing.
First, we're going to make it negative.
And that will make the view overlap.
Now, let's increase it until we
reach 0 and increase it again.
So, what happens The stack view
just keeps growing wider and
wide to accommodate the necessary
space even when we reach the border
it will keep growing up.
This is happening because we
didn't set any constraints
to the size of the stack view.
Now let's take a look at distribution.
Distribution is the most
complex property, so
we will leave it at fill for
the time being.
In this simple example we made
the stack view's job ridiculously easy.
If the contents grows,
it just grows too.
This is not realistic,
and in the next examples,
we will limit the size of the stack view
and see how it rises to the challenge.
But before you do that,
why don't you pause the video and
then change the axis to vertical.
Try the following,
change the access o vertical,
add some spacing, and then try
the different options for alignment.