In this final question, I'd like you to learn the position parameters of Markov chains.
There's a Markov chain over here with two states.
There is an initial state distribution for the time step 0.
Then there is conditional state distribution from time T to time T + 1.
You might go from A and stay in A.
You might go from A to B.
You might go from B and stay in B and go from B to A.
What we observe is the sequence A, A, A, A, B.
This is our sample for the initial state and all these transitinos over here
are samples for the state transitions in this Markov chain.
I want you to compute all the parameters, which is the initial distribution,
and the transition distribution out of state A and out of state B.
However I'd like to do this with Laplacian smoothing with k=1.
It is not maximum likelihood.
It is Laplacian smoothing, which can be applied just exactly
the same way we saw it in class in various contexts.
I'd like you to learn these parameters of the Markov chain from the observed sequence.
Again, the only sample for the initial state is
the very first measurement observation in this sequence over here.