In order to see messages
in the Friendly Chat app
we need code that reads from
the real time database.
We'll do this in
the main activity class.
First you'll take your messages
database reference and
add an event listener that reacts to
the database changes in real time.
Then within that event listener you'll
the code that correctly handles
adding new messages to the apps UI.
Let's go back to Andrea in
the studio to see how it's done.
In MainActivity.java we already
have a Firebase database instance.
And we also have a database
reference which, if you scroll down,
you'll see that reference is
referencing the messages location.
And this is the exact reference
that we used a moment ago
when you worked on
writing to the database.
Now you want to read from the exact same
location so you could reuse this object.
To be able to read though,
you need to attach a child event
listener object to this reference.
This will allow you to listen and
have your code triggered whenever
changes occur on the messages mode.
Here let me show you.
We're going to start by making
a child event listener.
So I'm going to scroll up to the top and
right here I'm going to add
another instance variable.
The type will be ChildEventListener and
I'll just name it mChildEventListener.
Now I'm going to scroll all
the way down in onCreate and I'm
going to put this right under the click
solicitor for writing to the database.
I'm going to instantiate
a new ChildEventListener.
Okay, now when you do that
you automatically extend it
with an anonymous class which has all
these methods that you need to override.
I'm going to clean this up a little
bit so that we can look at it.
So now you can see these
five different methods.
Let's talk a little bit
about each of these.
The first is onChildAdded.
This is the method that gets called
whenever a new message is inserted into
the messages list.
Importantly it's also triggered for
every child message in the list when
the listener is first attached.
This means when you
attach your listener,
which you're going to do very shortly,
for every child message that
already exists on the list,
the code in this method will be called.
The next method is onChildChanged.
This gets called when the contents
of an existing message gets changed.
OnChildRemoved will get called when
an existing message is deleted.
Next is onChildMoved.
OnChildMoved would get called
if one of our messages changed
position in the list.
And finally we have onCancelled.
OnCancelled indicates that
some sort of error occurred
when you are trying to make changes.
Typically, if this is being called it
means that you don't have permission to
read the data.
Okay, now that I have
my listener created
I can add it to my database reference.
I'm scrolling below the instantiation
code, taking my database reference and
calling addCihldEventListener,
passing in the ChildEventListener
that I just created.
To summarize this code here,
the reference defines what
exactly I'm listening to.
And this listener object here defines
what exactly will happen to the data.
Now because I'm just listening to
the messages location, these events will
only trigger when one of the children
of the messages node changes.
If for example, some other data is added
which is outside of the message's data,
the listener would not be triggered.
Okay, now looking back at our code,
this listener's attached and
everything's great.
But we're not actually
triggering anything to happen.
All these methods are blank.
For this simple chat app, we're only
going to implement onChildAdded, and
this will be so that we can see the new
messages when we add them in the app.
In our chat app, you can't delete, move,
or modify messages after
they've been created.
And remember that
onChildAdded is called for
existing children, when the listener's
first attached, and then for
any future children added,
when the listener is still active.
Okay so
if we look at the onChildAdded method,
we see that we get this
DataSnapshot object passed in.
The DataSnapshot contains data
from the Firebase database
at a specific location at the exact
time the listener is triggered.
In this case,
the DataSnapshot will always contain
the message that has been added.
We could use the DataSnapshot's
get value method
to get the data of the new message.
The get value method can take
a parameter, which is a class.
By passing in this parameter,
the code will deserialize the message
from the database into our
played FriendlyMessage object.
This works because our play
FriendlyMessage object has the exact
fields that match the fields that are in
our messages object in the database.
We see here that we have a text
field and a name field and
over here our message has the exact
same named text field and name field.
Okay, so this will get deserialized
to a friendlyMessage object, so
we can save that object.
And then finally, we can add this new,
friendlyMessage object to our adapter.
And with that, we added
a listener to our messages list.
And when a new message is added,
it triggers onChildAdded, which in turn
takes the newly added message, converts
is into a friendly message object and
finally adds it to our adapter.
And this will display
it in our list view.
By the way, you could also check
out the official documentation
on retrieving Firebase data,
if you ever need a refresher.