We take in over 5,000 animals each year.
Each individual animal has their
own profile within our system, and
we utilize that information as far
as their behavior assessments or
their medical history to match
them up with a potential adopter.
Other ways that we utilize this
information would be tracking the amount
of animals that we have come into our
shelter as strays or owner surrenders.
There will be a ZIP Code associated
with the area that they came in from.
We've utilized the ZIP Codes to
create programs specifically based
in those ZIP Codes to
implement free spay and
neuter for animals within those areas
to help minimize the amount of animals
that are coming in through
those particular areas.