All right, you're done.
Let's take a look at my solution.
First, we add a function to utility to
reset the location status to unknown.
Note that we use the shared preferences
editor apply function rather than
commit, since this will be
called from the UI thread.
Next, we call that function to reset
the location status if the user
changes the location
within settings activity.
Next, we add the location
status invalid.
Remember, we have to add the constant
and then add it to the indef annotation.
Next, in get weather data from Json,
we add the message code Json definition.
Now let's check to see
if we have an error.
If the message code is 200,
which happens to be the same as HTTP_OK,
we can continue.
But if the message code
equals HTTP not found,
then we set the location
status to invalid.
If it is any other error, we assume
a server failure of some kind and
set the status to server down.
And then we add a string to display,
when this case happens.
Finally, we add this new
case to update empty view.
Done.
Let's test this.
All right, let's first of all
run this on our emulator.
All right,
let's put an invalid location.
London.
And then we get our new message.
No weather information available.
The location in settings is not
recognized by the weather server.
Awesome.