All right.
Here we are again with
another handy tool.
Now looking at a heap view of
your apps' memory allocations
is a great way to understand where
most of the data is going and
what type of data is being allocated.
This helps you find data that is
allocated and maybe shouldn't be.
But sadly, heap viewer doesn't
tell us exactly where in your code
that data is being allocated.
So for that, we need a tool
called Allocation Tracker.
As usual, go ahead and start
Android Studio, connect your device, and
load Sunshine into the foreground.
Okay.
So if we
want to get to the tool in Android
Studio, we can click on the Android tab,
which is at the bottom left of
a standard Android ID window.
This is going to open
the Android DDMS tab.
I'm going to go ahead and enlarge
this so we can see this a bit easier.
So, the DDMS tab shows the devices and
logs related to your device.
Now depending on what you've been
working on in Android studio,
this tab will show different views.
Make sure the Devices tab is
the one that you have selected.
And we'll go ahead and
select the Sunshine app.
Now next in the left margin go ahead and
click the bottom most icon.
This one right here.
The icon has a start
allocation tracking tool tip.
Okay.
So, the DDMS tab
shows the devices and log.
Depending on what you've been
working on in Android Studio,
this tab will show different views.
Make sure the Devices tab is
selected and select Sunshine.
Next, we're going to want to
go to this left margin and
click the bottom most icon.
This has a tool tip that says
start allocation tracking.
I'm going to go ahead and click it.
And see,
we're enabling allocation tracker here.
All right, so go ahead and
bring up your Sunshine application and
go ahead an interact with your app for
a little bit.
So let's go ahead and take a look at
what the weather is like in Cleveland.
Unfortunately looks like there's some
rain tomorrow, but a high of 74,
humidity is 93.
Ooh, sticky.
And we see rain Wednesday,
still pretty warm.
And then rain on Saturday,
but still pretty warm.
Fortunately, less humidity then.
Looks like you got warm and
rainy weather, Cleveland.
All right so go ahead and you can finish
interacting with your app a few times.
And when you're done,
click on the same button as before.
And the tool tip should say
Stop Allocation Tracking.
Now depending on how long
you've been doing stuff.
Processing the data might
take a little while.
And the button will stay depressed.
Don't click it multiple times.
Just be cool and hang out for a bit.
All right.
It looks like our's finished.
Now if you look closely up here,
a new tab was created in our IDE.
It's labeled something like
DDMS followed by a large number
that we have it right here.
Now, this view lists all the allocations
that occurred during that sampling
period when you were interacting
with your application.
And each row in this view
represents distinct allocation.
Now the order column
is going to tell you.
When the allocations happened.
The allocated class column is going to
show you what type of data was being
allocated, the size of it, and you'll
also have some information telling you
what thread made that
specific allocation.
Lastly, the allocation site column
tells you what function in your code
actually allocated that memory.
For example here, we select integer.
The value of method is what made
this allocation of this integer.
Now if you click on an allocation,
you can see its full call stack.
There's a lot of
information in this table.
If you don't see everything,
you may need to resize the panels.
Now, you can also move the columns
around to your fitting
to get the ones that you
care about within view.
Or you can sort columns by clicking
on the header of a column.
Now obviously this tool is super
handy for tracking down memory churn.
Let's go ahead and
take a look at this in practice.