The answer to this is that at some point
the manager will simply not be able to
control any more resources.
There is a limit to the attention
that a single person has, and
therefore one single manager will
not be able to continue controlling
all of the different types
of resources in the shop.
In addition,
another limit to the scale maybe that
there is a physical limit as
to how many different things,
how much staff, or how many workers, how
much staff can simply fit in the shop.
Outsourcing could sometimes be
an option, however if the manager only
trusts his own workers, then, he will
not be able to outsource those tasks,
and that's going to compose
some limits to the scale.
These kinds of limitations exist in the
context of internet services as well.
Given the size of the data center,
there may be a limit on the amount of
resources that can be placed there.
Given the complexity of the management
processes there will be limits as to how
many different things can be managed.
And if we want to run our own software
stacks, our own operating systems,
our own software services then we'll
clearly be limited by these factors.
In order to address these challenges,
cloud computing has emerged as
a solution that allows us to address
some of these limitations regarding
the scale that can be supported with
existing Internet service solutions.