Thanks for sharing your findings.
I can't wait to see what
discoveries you've made.
I wanted to improve the histograms
showing the number of days students
visit the classroom during
their first week, for
both passing and non-passing students.
So I started off with the same plotting
code that I had used previously.
Then I added the line,
import seaborn as sns.
To the top of the first cell, since
importing seaborn will automatically
make the plots look a little nicer.
You can see the difference here.
The colors are a little bit better and
there's a grid in the background.
Next, I wanted to use the bins argument
to specify that there should be exactly
eight bins for this histogram.
This will fix those blank
spots that we saw earlier.
There should be eight bins since there
are eight possibilities for the number
of days you visit the classroom in
the first week, 0 through 7 inclusive.
I also used plt.xlabel to specify that
the x access was measuring number
of days.
And I used plt.title to add a title
that would explain what the graph
was showing to someone
who didn't already know.
Re-running the cell, I can see that
the strange gaps have disappeared and
my axis label and title have been added.
Then I made very similar changes to
the second histogram adding an xlabel,
a title and
setting the number of bins to eight.
I didn't re-import Seaborn
since that's not necessary.
Seaborn will apply to all plots
that are made from now on.
And again I can see that all the weird
gaps are gone and my x label and
my title have been added.