Now that you've loaded
the student data into Python,
I want you to think about what questions
you could answer with this data.
For example, you could figure out how
long it usually takes students before
the submit their projects.
Or you could look at some different
characteristic of students and
try to find differences between
students who pass their projects and
students who don't.
This is a great time to let
your curiosity run wild.
There's a lot of really interesting
stuff you can figure out with this data
and you're about to do it.
So, start brain storming.
Take another look at what
data is available and
try to think of at least 5 questions
you could answer using it.
Share your thoughts with your
classmates on the forums.