So to help us understand this,
here's a simple quiz I want you to play around with.
I have two different smaller six by six sample images here, and
we want to blend them or merge them together.
And here my question to you is, where would we find the best seam?
So here is a simple example of two simple six by six images, and the question we
want to look at is, which are the best possible seams where would we cut
these two images, the left image and the right image, to generate a new image.
The output we want is basically an image that's blended like this.
Just mark out the pixel boundaries in this example where you
think these seams should be.