I think that the push ID
sounds like a good idea.
The end goal is that we're going to
make a value event listener.
And we need to have a Firebase
location to do this.
The shopping list name is not
part of the Firebase location.
I can actually show you that the list
name is not part of the list location
by going into the database,
clicking on one of these lists and
we can see our URL location up here.
It's the base URL, active lists,
and then the push ID.
There's no name in here.
So shopping list name
is not a good choice.
Now we could try to use a Firebase
reference object that's pointing
to the right location.
But putting anything in an intent,
other than a primitive value or
a string, requires serialization of one
form or another, which adds code bulk.
The push ID is the only changing part
of the location of a shopping list and
it's essentially just a fancy string.
So this is easy to pass
in an intent extra.
So push ID makes the most sense.