To summarize a common condition variable API, we'll look as follows.
First, we must be able to create these data structures that correspond to
the condition variable, so
there must be some type that corresponds to condition variables.
Then there is the wait construct that takes as arguments the mutex and
the condition variable.
Where a mutex is automatically released and
re-acquired if we have to wait for this condition to occur.
When a notification for a particular condition needs to be issued,
it would be useful to be able to wake up threads one at a time.
And for this, Birrell proposes a signal API.
Or it could also be useful to wake up all of the threads that are waiting on
a particular condition, and for this, Birrell proposes a broadcast API.
The condition variable as a data structure, it must have basically a list of
the waiting threads that should be notified in the event the condition is met.
It also must have a reference to the mutex that's associated with
the condition so that this wait operation can be implemented correctly so
that this mutex can be both released and re-acquired as necessary.
As a reference, the way the wait operation would be implemented in
a operation system or in a threading library that supports threads and
that support this condition variable.
It would mean that, in the implementation, the very first thing that happened is
that the mutex that's associated with the condition variable is released and
this thread is placed on this wait queue of waiting threads.
And then at some point when a notification is received,
what would have to happen is that the thread is removed from the queue and
this mutex is reacquired and then only then do we exit the wait,
so only then will a thread return from this wait operation.
One thing to note here is that, you know, when on a signal or
broadcast we remove a thread from the queue, and
then the first thing that this thread needs to do is to re-acquire the mutex.
So what that really also means is that on broadcast,
although we are able to wake up all the threads at the same time,
the mutex, it requires mutual exclusion.
So they will be able to acquire the mutex only one thread at a time.
So only one thread at a time will be re-acquiring the mutex and
exiting this wait operation.
So it's a little bit unclear,
that it's always useful to broadcast, if you're really not going to
be able to do much work once you wake up with more than one thread at a time.