We'll start with the image
of the envelope.
In the skit I place the request
inside of the envelope and
this is indicative of what
an NSURL request is doing.
The NSURLRequest encapsulates the URL
that the client is requesting.
The second image is of Jason and
the container that was
on my desk in the skit.
In the skit, Jason takes
the request from the container and
then he handles the rest of
the HTTP request on my behalf.
This is the same behavior as
the NSURL session for our apps.
It too handles the sending and
receiving of HTTP data.
Here on this third image we have
something that's a little bit
more abstract.
We have Jason and
we have pictures of arrows indicating
his path that are shown in color.
These serve as a representation of the
data tasks that's being accomplished by
Jason and therefore it's mashed
with the NSURL session data task.
The data task is specifically used for
retrieving data and then bringing
it back to the client or app.