And the answer is measurements are indeed ignored which has to do with the following:
We do weigh particles by the measurement probability but we normalize them to 1,
and if there's only 1 particle, it will always normalize itself back to 1,
so the measurement probability has no effect.
The results are generally poor.
That is, a single particle is just insufficient to anything interesting,
so that is absolutely the correct answer over here.
Clearly, a single particle cannot represent multi-modal distributions
because multi-modes look something like this over here
because it's just 1 particle, so this is actually correct.
The initial state, if known, is not necessarily ignored.
You might actually place the particle at the initial state
and it might consider it in the filtering result.
The state transitions are also not ignored because we will still propagate this particle
forward according to the state transistion, and because 3 of them are true,
the final one isn't.