Before we jump straight in to making
preferences for everything under
the sun, I wanted to a moment to talk
about something called choice paralysis.
In 2000, a team of researchers
conducted a famous study involving jam.
The researchers operated a booth at
a grocery store, offering jam samples.
Every few hours they alternated
between offering samples of either
six different types of jam or
a whopping 24 flavors of jam.
What the researchers were testing
was which method was actually more
successful at getting
customers to purchase the jam.
What do you think?
Now, you might be going, with more
options, the customers were more likely
to find their perfect, personalized
jam and happily purchase it.
But the findings of the study actually
found that shoppers who were presented
with fewer choices were more
likely to purchase some jam.
So what does this mean for settings?
Well, settings are kind of
like those jars of jam.
Giving the users a few key options is
good, but overwhelm them with screens,
upon screens, upon screens of settings,
and they don't buy any jam.
Or I mean, use your app.
If you and
your team can't decide on a feature,
resist the temptation just
to make it a setting.
That shifts the burden of deciding
the value of the setting onto the user.
Also remember,
it's always easier to add a setting
then it is to remove a setting.
When you remove a setting, you always
risk having that subset of users
angry about the feature
being taken away from them.
To help you with
the decision of whether or
not to make something a setting,
I've provided a handy flowchart below.
In addition, I've linked the material
design guidelines for settings.
In our case, I'm removing any choice
paralysis whatsoever on your part about
what to actually make a setting.
And I'm prescribing that we will be
making two settings for Sunshine.
The first is a unit setting for
Fahrenheit versus Celsius
to make Assar happy.
The second is a setting
where users can specify
what location they want
to get the weather for.
Let's get started