In this video we will apply what we
learned about updating a variable
within the context of the Just-Java app.
Once a variable is created we can update
its value using assignment operator,
that we learned earlier
when creating variables.
The format is to have a variable name on
the left, followed by the equal sign and
then the new value.
The statement also ends with
a semi-colon as always.
This line means that,
we're assigning the new value of 3
into the variable called quantity.
Going back to our box analogy,
int quantity equals 2 creates a new
variable called quantity,
and puts the value 2 inside.
When we say quantity equals 3, we set
a new value of 3 inside the variable.
We also take out the old value,
because the variable can only
hold one value at a time.
When we say quantity equals 4,
then we put in a new value
of 4 inside the variable.
We also remove what use to be in there,
which is the 3.
Then when we say quantity equals 5,
we assign the variable a new value.
Note that we only need to specify
the data type of the variable,
which is integer in this case, once.
On subsequent lines of code
where we refer to the variable,
we don't need to specify that data type.
If we did write int
again on that 2nd line,
then the computer would think we want
to create another quantity variable.
However, we're not allowed to create
two variables with the same name and
the same method,
that would give an error.
So when you declare a variable,
that's when you specify the data type.
When you update it,
you don't need to specify the data type.
Now I'm going to open up the main
activity Java file and modify
the increment method to take advantage
of the ability to update variables.
When the plus button is clicked
it will trigger this method, and
I'm going to initialize
the quantity variable to be 2.
Then I'm going to add a new line of code
that updates the quantity variable to 3.
Then we display the latest
quantity value to the screen.
When we run it on our device,
if I click on the + button,
then it updates to a quantity of 3.
This is because the latest value
in the quantity variable is 3 by
the time we try to
display it on the screen.
How do we know that the app didn't just
skip to setting the value to be 3?
Well, we can use the debugging
tool that we introduced earlier,
to check the value of the quantity
variable at each line.
Let's add a break point in the first
line of the increment method.
Then I can run the app in debug mode.
Okay, Android Studio says that
the debugger has been connected.
I can click on this Debug tab
to open the debug window.
Now when I click on the plus button,
it triggers the increment method and
the break point at line 25.
At this point the first
line has been executed, so
we've created a quantity
variable with a value of 2.
If we skip to the next line,
then quantity equals 3 would
have already been executed, and
then we do see that the quantity
variable has been updated to 3.
At this point it should
display on the screen, and
we can just hit Resume,
to resume the app.
And then you see that the screen
has updated to the value of 3.
I'd like to show you more examples
of updating the quantity variable.
Even though it doesn't make much sense
from a functionality point of view of
the app to have the plus button
increase the number of coffees
by more than one cup.
From a code perspective if you wanted
to, you could add additional lines of
code to update the variable
several more times.
Then run the app in debug mode again.
If I click on the + button,
then the break point will be triggered.
If I step to the next line then this
first line has finished executing,
and we've created a quantity
variable with an initial value 2.
We go to the next line then
quantity updates to a value of 3.
At the next step quantity variables
updated to a value of 4 and then 5.
If I hit resume execution, then
the screen will finally update to show
the latest quantity value, which is 5.
Now on your computer make these changes
to the increment method in the main
activity file.
Then use the debugger
to step through and
verify that the quantity variable
is being updated as expected.
Then repeat the above steps but
for the decrement method.
Within that method, initialize
the quantity variable to 2, and
then update it so
it goes down to one cup of coffee.
When you run it on your device,
the app should open and
start with a quantity of two.
If you hit the minus button,
then it changes down to a quantity of 1.
If you hit the plus button it
changes to a quantity of 3.
The quantity picker isn't working
exactly like we want yet, but
we're just learning
concepts one at a time and
slowly building up to
the right functionality.
For now you can leave whatever behavior
you currently have hooked up for
the order button,
because that will eventually change.
When you're done,
check this boxes to continue.