Once you finish each project,
you'll submit it to us, and
we'll send it back to you with feedback.
This feedback will come from
professional iOS developers.
You'll submit your entire Xcode project
directories and they'll review your
work, line by line, and help you
determine the project's strengths and
weaknesses and
find areas where you can improve.
>> Your evaluation will tell you either
that your project met our specifications
or that it hasn't yet.
However, you can submit each project
as many times as you need to for
it to meet our specifications.
We believe that projects are a super
important part of your learning process.
Because that process of getting feedback
and making changes in accordance with
it, is something that developers
do in the real world all the time.
>> No one, not even the most expert
engineer writes perfect code
the first time around.
So we want you to get in the mindset and
practice of iterating on your work now.