It's time to wire up the buttons.
This will allow us to start the audio
playback and change the state of the buttons.
Remember that when reaching from
code to an UI element, we use IBOutlets
and to go from an UI element and then
call our code, we use an IBAction.
So we'll start with the IBOutlets
Instead of doing the whole setup with the
assistant editor and then holding control
and click dragging from our interface to
our code, there's an easier way to set up IBOutlets.
what we can do is create
IBOutlets in code first and then
connect them via the interface builder.
So open the PlaySoundsViewController.swift file.
Here you can see our property
for the recorded audio URL.
Add the following lines above it.
These are the IBOutlets for the six
playback buttons and the Stop Button.
Now we just need to connect these IBOutlets
Open the Main.storyboard file
and select the Play Sounds View Controller Scene.
In the Document Outline,
expand each disclosure triangle, so that
you have all the buttons revealed, like I
do here. And I just noticed I didn't
rename my other buttons, so I'm gonna
take care of that really quickly.
There we go. With the control key held down,
drag from the Play Sounds View Controller
down to the Slow Button.
Then from the pop-up menu, let’s select the
outlet for the Slow Button or that will
also be the snailButton. Let's do the
same for the other buttons. For the Fast
Button will connect that to… that's the
same as the rabbitButton. For High Pitch
that's our chipmunkButton. Low Pitch is
the vaderButton. Echo echoButton and
Reverb is the reverbButton. And finally
for the Stop Button stopButton.
Awesome, now our view controller can reach
out to all of the UI buttons using the
IBOutlets that we created.
The next step is to connect the buttons to an IBAction.
So that when you press a button,
code inside of the Play Sounds View Controller runs.
From what we've learned so far,
you might be thinking we need to
create seven IBAction functions, one for
each button. But there's a better way
with less duplication of code.
I’m going to show you that now.
we're going to create just two IBAction functions.
One to handle all the six playback buttons,
and one to handle the stop button.
Open the PlaySoundsViewController.swift file.
Underneath the IBOutlets and our one property,
add these two functions.
There we go. We have an IBAction to play sound,
an IBAction to stop the sound.
Now we just need to connect the six playback
buttons to the PlaySoundForButton IBAction.
We also need to connect the
Stop Button to the StopButtonPressed IBAction.
Let's go back to the Main.storyboard file.
Select the Play Sounds View Controller
in the Document Outline
and make sure you have all the buttons revealed.
With the control key held down,
drag from the Slow Button up to the
Play Sounds View Controller.
Select the playSoundForButton function
from the pop-up. Let's do the
same for the remaining buttons.
And then for the Stop Button, will do the
stopButtonPressed function.
And then the last one is a Reverb Button.
And then for the Stop Button,
select stopButtonPressed. Let's run and see if
everything is wired up correctly.
Press the Run button to start PitchPerfect in
the iOS simulator. Let's quickly record
and stop, so we can transition to the
Play Sounds View Controller.
If we press on the Snail playback button, we can see
the playSoundForButton function is
getting called based on our print
statement in the console.
Let's try for the other five buttons.
That looks good.
Lastly let's check that the Stop Button
is wired up by pressing it as well.
That was a bit of work, but now we can reach
into all of our buttons
from the Play Sounds View Controller
using the IBOutlets and have the buttons color code
using the IBActions