Being a little more formal, we say
that if P is not equal to NP, then for
any constant alpha at least one,
there is no polynomial time factor
approximation for
the traveling salesman problem.
For the proof we reduce from Hamiltonian
Cycle, where we're given a graph,
not necessarily complete this time,
and we want to know if there's a cycle
that visits every vertex exactly once.
Here then is how we set up
the traveling salesman problem.
We assign a cost of one to every
edge in the original graph G.
And we assign a cost of
alpha times V + 1 for
every edge not in the original graph.
Clearly then, if G has a Hamiltonian
Xycle, then the optimum for
the traveling salesman
problem has a cost of V.
One unit of cost for
every edge that it follows.
Then a factor alpha approximation for
the traveling salesman problem,
will return a Hamiltonian Cycle H,
whose cost is at most alpha
times this number of vertices.
On the other hand, if the original
graph has no Hamiltonian Cycle,
then the cost of the Hamiltonian Cycle
returned by our traveling salesman
approximation has to be
greater than the optimum.
But that must include at least one of
these edges not in the original graph.
Note that this term comes from
following edges in the original graph.
This one from following edges
not in the original graph.
There has to be at least one of them.
Simplifying gives the lower
bound of 1 plus alpha times V.
Therefore, to decide
the Hamiltonian cycle problem,
we just run the alpha approximation
on the graph with these costs here.
Then we compare the resulting
cost to alpha times V.
If it's larger, then there can't be
a Hamiltonian Cycle on the graph.
Any Hamiltonian Cycle would have cost V,
and
our approximation algorithm couldn't
have returned such a large cost.
An the other hand,
if it's the same as alpha V or
smaller, then we can't have used one
of the edges not in the original, so
there must be a Hamiltonian Cycle.
Thus, if there were a polynomial time
constant factor approximation for
the general traveling salesman problem,
it would yield a polynomial algorithm
for the Hamiltonian Cycle,
which is NP complete.
Unless P is equal to NP, no such
approximation algorithm can exist.