Awareness of these ideas may not seem
like much, but it's actually a big deal.
Because with the awareness that you
have, you can now look at a substantial
code base like the code that
generates this page, and
get a feel for how it works.
You won't understand everything,
but a lot of it will look familiar.
So, let's go through the code that
generated this page and see what I mean.
I've already shown you the web page that
you'll be able to make when your done
with this nanodegree.
But now I want to show
you the code you'll write
that will generate a page like this.
So, if I find the folder in my
computer that has all this code,
it's this one intro programming nda,
I've called it.
And notice it's got a lot in it, this
is what happens when you write larger
programs, you can't fit all of
your code in a single file.
In fact, we have folders with different
sorts of files and more and more files,
and they're all of different types,
.py, .yaml, .css, .jpg, .html.
But as you can see, the majority
of the files are HTML files,
which is what you've
already started to learn.
For example,
this file is called adsubmission.html.
And it's responsible for
the page you'll see when you submit your
project at the end of this Nanodegree.
That's this page.
So notice that this page has
a nice heading at the top.
That heading has a description when
you complete the final project.
And then we have some
more things down here.
We have what looks like some sort of
form where we can add some input.
These forms seem to have some labels,
and
then way at the bottom we have this
button which will submit the project.
So let's see what the code looks like,
that generated this page.
so, to open this, I'm going to right
click > Open with > Sublime Text,
which is a program you're going to
be downloading shortly, and
this is what I see.
Now first, I want to point out there's
going to be a lot of code in here that
you don't understand yet.
That's to be expected,
you're just starting.
For example, this looks a little
weird and these class equals title,
class equals section, class equals
description, also look weird.
Though maybe you can begin to
guess what they may be doing.
Here we have an h1,
that's a header element and
it says degree student projects.
Here is that description we
were looking at and down here.
We have something called the form.
Hm, interesting.
Let me zoom out a bit, because if
the form begins here, I'm going to look
all the way down to see where it ends,
and it ends there, okay.
Let me see what's inside of that.
There appears to be a name to display,
a URL, a project description.
And notice that these are all in those
b tags that you're familiar with.
There's some other things that you
probably don't understand at this point,
but that's all right,
we're getting there.
And then at the end we have this end
block, and even if you don't know
what that means quite yet, it seems
to have something to do with this.
Now, this process I just went through
was me trying to demonstrate what I
actually do when I look at
code I don't understand.
And that happens all the time.
I try and anchor onto the things I
do understand and build from there.
Now, if I wanted to, I could look up
any of these things I don't know.
So for example, form, what is a form?
I'm going to go to Google and
I'm going to type html form.
And the first thing I get,
maybe it will help.
The form element, that looks familiar.
It says down here html forms
contain form elements.
Form elements are types of input
elements, check boxes, radio buttons.
Okay, this seems about right.
And I could keep reading,
I could learn more.
Right now, I'm not going to do that.
But Google is really a huge
friend in looking up and
researching what's going on
with code you don't understand.
I wanted to show you this process
of encountering new code and
looking into Google for what it does,
because it's a totally authentic
part of every programmer's workflow.
There's a lot to learn out there, and
you're never going to learn it all.
And so, looking up things as you need
them is a totally normal thing to do.
Anyways, just as a reminder, you're
about to take your boring black and
white page, and turn it into
something beautiful and colorful.
So good luck, and have fun.