Here we have a demonstration that the implementation of this algorithm into actual code
is not that much more complicated than the mathematical formulas I just described to you.
Here's the function segment, which takes a text, and it does what we just said.
So it splits the text up into all possible first and rest components,
and then the candidates will be the first word plus the best segmentation of the rest,
and then out of all those candidates we just take the maximum
according to the probability of the words
where the probability of the words is just the product of the probability of each individual word.
So that's the naive Bayes assumption coming into this definition,
and this is just the definition of how to split something up into a first and rest.
And you can follow the links in the note to see the source code for this
and play with it on your own if you like.