So arrays give us a better option for
storing information inside of
one neat data structure,
but what else can they do?
>> You can actually do
quite a bit with arrays.
You see,
arrays have a number of properties and
methods that make them
powerful data structures.
>> Man, properties, methods?
You're about to venture into some
really awesome programming territory.
>> Yeah, things are starting
to get really exciting.
You can think about properties as
special pieces of information about
a data structure.
For example, there's a special
property in an array called length.
>> Wait, haven't we used length before?
>> Yeah, actually we have.
Earlier in this course,
we used length with strings to get
the number of characters in a string.
However, we can also use length to get
the number of elements in an array.
This is useful when you want
to loop over an array, but
you're not sure how many elements
you're going to need to loop over.
>> That's right, so both strings and
arrays use the length property.
>> Yep, and
you've kind of seen methods before too.
You can think of methods like
special predefined functions
that a data structure can call.
Some common array methods you'll see
are reverse, which reverses the order
of the elements in an array, sort,
which sorts the elements in an array.
And push and pop, which are two
methods that allow us to add and
remove elements from an array.
>> But there are more than just
these methods you see here.
For a full listing of all
the available built-in array methods,
check out the link to
the MDN documentation below.
>> As you continue through this course,
you'll see the words property and
method thrown around a lot,
especially when we get to objects.
Spoiler alert,
arrays are a special kind of object.
But we'll get more into that later.
>> Julie Anne,
that was supposed to be a surprise.
>> Sorry.
Well, for now let's look at some
properties and methods of an array.