So let's work a simple example, all right, of finding the fundamental matrix.
And bunch of them out there, one that I'm going to show here is
one that's a little bit different, because it's not as sort of trivial.
Here's the one of the, the two side-by-side stereo views.
We'll do them a little different.
And remember, a fundamental matrix gives a corresponce between any two views.
It doesn't matter where the cameras are taken, okay?
So, for example, my images could look like this.
And you might say whoa.
Okay, you might not say whoa because that would be only if you
were born in the late 60s, or maybe early 60s.
But here I have a picture and the white lines drawn on it are meant to
be sort of nominal epipolar lines, I took a picture and
then the camera moves forward, and then I take another picture.
Can I do a fundamental matrix for that?
Of course I can.
In fact that's what this geometry is meaning to show here, it's a,
it's a little hard to see, all right.
What I have here is that I took one picture and my camera center was there.
And then I take another picture and my camera center is moved forward and
if you connect those and slice the image, those are the epipoles.
So all the epipolar lines,
have to go through the epipole and that's what this is showing you, right.
The epipole is right in the middle of my picture.
It's not exactly the middle, it's off to,
to the top, it's actually to the side a little bit, I'll show you in a minute.
But all the epipolar lines have to go through the epipole, and
that's another way of saying is.
You know, just think about that intuitively, if I move straight ahead and
I'm looking straight, the points move along that diagonal out from the center.
So that means that if you give me one point in, in the first image,
it's going to be somewhere along that line in the second image.
And how far it's along that line will be a function of its depth, okay?
Because remember, the amount that the points move, between one image and
the next, function of depth, going way back.
Remember disparity, the closer something is, the more it'll be disparate.
Something that's very far away like the moon doesn't change much at all.
Okay?
So they're going to move along the epipolar lines.
So we're going to use this as an example because it'll be very clear whether you
got the epi polar lines right or you got the epi polar lines wrong