Okay, let's look at what the data
would like in these different options.
Here's a diagram that I made of what our
data structure currently looks like.
We have activeLists,
shoppingListItems, and Users.
This is all the data for
one shopping list.
This is the data for
another shopping list.
Here we have the associated
items on the shopping lists, and
here's each item here.
And each of these little
clusters is a different user.
So three users and
we have two shopping lists, and
this first shopping
list here has one item.
The second shopping
list has three items.
Okay, so here's our current data.
So option A was a little crazy,
it basically was to take each of
these items and add a boolean.
And when the associated shopping
list is being shopped on
that boolean would be true.
For this list it would
look something like this.
You'd have an extra piece of data for
each item.
And if this list started being
shopped on the value for
each of these items would be true.
Now this isn't the best solution.
Because when somebody's shopping on a
shopping list it affects the whole list,
not just specific items.
I'm essentially copying
the data three times here.
Now option C is essentially
what option A was but
instead of having the Boolean
on the list items which
was a little bit strange,
we could put the Boolean on the list.
Basically we just have a Boolean here,
which says whether the list is
being shopped on or is not.
And this is pretty good, except it's
not storing any information about
who is actually doing the shopping.
So I could see that somebody was
shopping on a shopping list, but
I wouldn't be able to know,
in specific, that it was J.P.
So Option C is kind of
outta the running as well.
Now Option B, would be to similarly
add some data to the shopping list,
specifically a list of users
that are currently shopping
on that shopping list.
And B looks pretty good.
You know if a list is
being shopped on and
it's easy to see what users
are shopping on that list.
On the shopping list page,
they make it really easy to print
out who's shopping on the list.
Now D is a somewhat similar solution.
But instead of having a list of shopping
users in the shopping list data,
we can have a list of shopping
lists in the user data.
It makes it pretty easy to see
whether a user is shopping on a list.
The issue with this solution
is that when you want to know
who's shopping on a specific list,
it's inefficient.
In this scenario,
you'd have to iterate through all
of the users in your database.
And see which ones in this
list of shopping lists
had the list that you were
currently looking at.
When you get hundreds
of thousands of users,
that means you're doing a query
that's looking through hundreds and
thousands of user objects and
that's a pretty lengthy search.
So in this case,
option b is the superior option.
Attached to each list,
you'll add a list of users who
happen to be shopping on that list.
If this list of users empty and
doesn't exist than you know that
there's nobody shopping on the list.
Okay, so that clarifies what
you should be doing for
the data and
I'll send you the spec right now.