Let's take a look at the code for
making a listener at
the listening location, then
we'll see how to use the data that we
get from the listener to update the UI.
As you said, we're going to need
to listen to the node list name,
which is a child of your root URL.
Now these two lines of code
are basically equivalent.
You can either pass in a full URL string
specifying the exact node
that you're interested in, or
you can take a reference to any part
of the database, and then use the child
method to drill down to exactly
the node that you're looking for.
Again, these two are interchangeable,
so use whichever that you like.
Now that you have the exact location
that you want to listen to,
you attach a listener using
the addValueEventListener method.
This method takes a ValueEventListener
object as a parameter, and
just like with a click listener, you'll
usually make a new anonymous subclass.
ValueEventListeners have two
methods that you need to override,
onDataChange and onCancelled.
OnDataChange is the method
that's called whenever data
at this reference location changes.
I'll say it again, whenever it changes.
This means that as long as we've got
this listener attached, JP or myself or
Walter, or anyone else in the world,
could update a value here, and
onDataChange would get called for all
phones on which the app is installed.
onCancelled, we'll talk about
more later, but, basically,
it's triggered if you either can't
attach the listener to something, or
if the listener gets detached.
All right, so that's the general
structure, let's write some code.
What I want to do is update this view,
here.
This whole part of the app is controlled
by the shopping list fragment class, so
that's where we should
start looking at the code.
So here I am in the shopping
list fragment class, and
specifically I'm in
the onCreateView method.
Since your listeners update your UI,
generally you want to put them
in the onCreateView method, or
the onCreate method, so I'll start by
making my firebase reference object.
And then, I will create and
attach a listener to that reference.
Then, in the onDataChange, for now, I'm
just going to write a log statement, and
I'm just going to make an error
statement so that it's easy to see.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay, let's try running
this on my phone.
So I know it's super small here,
but I ran the app on my phone, and
it says the data changed.
Then, if I go to update the data,
it says the data changed again, and
whenever I do it,
it'll say the data changes.
You might be wondering why the listener
triggers when the app opens, after all,
nothing was getting updated.
The reason is that,
when you first attach the listener,
it automatically calls itself once.
This is so that you'll have
some initial data in the app,
even if nothing is actively
changing when you start the app.
All right, let's do more than
just call a log message.
If you look at the onDataChange method a
little bit more closely, you'll see that
you'll receive an object called a
dataSnapshot, so what's a dataSnapshot?
So you have your Firebase Database,
and you have a listener attached to,
let's say, this Node B, here.
When B or any of B's children nodes
change, a dataSnapshot is taken.
The dataSnapshot is a read-only
copy of the Firebase state
when the data gets changed.
Once you have a dataSnapshot,
just like a photographic snapshot,
it won't change, and this snapshot that
gets sent back includes the node that
you were listening to as
well as the children nodes.
So that's the object that
you have access to here.
Now, you can call a lot of different
methods on a DataSnapshot, and
here are some of them.
For example, you can call child method
on a DataSnapshot the same as you would
call a child method on
a Firebase reference object.
The DataSnapshot starts where
you were listening to, and
if I were to call child D,
it would move the child down here.
Then I could call something
like the getValue method,
and it would return the value at this
location, which in this case is 1.
I could also call it the getKey method,
which would return the key at
this location, in this case, D.
The snapshot includes everything of
the node that you were listening to and
all of its children, but it doesn't
include the parents of the node you
were listening to, so
you can't transverse the whole tree.
Okay, so I'm concealing some code that I
put here that got me the shopping list
name, and here I set the TextView
that I'm interested in
to the list name I just got here.
This mTextViewListName,
I'm going to scroll down, was
initialized here in initializeScreen.
Okay, but back to this code
that's hidden from you, so
I've got a DataSnapshot of the data.
Which method that we just talked about
do you think I need to call to be able
to get the name of the list?
Go ahead and change the code in your app
so that it displays the list name, and
then answer that question.
Is it getKey(), getValue(),
or child(), that you call?