If you choose to use MATLAB for
this course, you will need base MATLAB along with the image processing toolbox.
Head over to the MathWorks website and look for the latest release.
Click Buy Online to see pricing options.
We recommend getting a student edition.
You can either choose the MATLAB and Simulink Student Suite,
which includes the image processing toolbox, or, you can
choose the base MATLAB portion, and the image processing toolbox separately.
Know that you may need MATLAB or
specific toolboxes for other courses, so choose wisely.
Your institution may also have a volume licensing agreement with MathWorks.
So find that out before you download it for yourself.
Once you have MATLAB installed, try out a few simple commands.
The command window is connected to an interpreter.
This is where you will spend most of your time.
You can type in arithmetic expressions that are evaluated on the spot.
You can also create variables.
Note how it printed out the value of the variable here.
If you want to suppress that, use a semicolon at the end.
You can also create vectors and matrices and run operations on them.
You might have noticed this workspace being updated.
It lists all the variables currently in memory and the value assigned to them.
There is also a file browser that lists the files in the current folder.
MATLAB has built-in functionality to read images.
We will use the imread command.
Note that you can use tab completion to make your life easier.
Tab completion also works with file names in the current directory.
You can display an image using imshow.
The image processing toolbox contains several useful commands for
working with images.
One of these is rgb2gray.
It converts a red-green-blue colored image into a grayscale or monochrome image.
The MATLAB website provides great resources to help you get started, including
code examples, webinars, and extensive documentation.