I'll start at the top.
Change the title?
Mm, no, I wouldn't do that.
Right now the title is Create an Event,
and that seems pretty straightforward,
so I'll leave it alone.
Next up, consolidate inputs, definitely.
Look, right now you have to select
the time, the day, the month, and
the year separately.
And These are all really part
of the same question so,
I think it make sense that
they're the same input.
Seems like an improvement to me.
Now, what about better
validation messages, definitely.
Here, let me show you what happens when
you try to create an event without
valid inputs.
I will click this button,
then I have to scroll down.
And then I get a list of errors.
This could be a lot more helpful
in a lot of different ways so
that should definitely be improved.
And lastly,
what about adding more questions?
Well, you really want to minimize
the number of questions you
ask if you want to keep the form simple.
So no, I don't think that adding
more is going to improve this form.
Okay, not too bad.
In the next video you'll see
an interview with Luke Wroblewski
who is a product director at Google.
Luke is an expert on forms.
You're going to here him talk about
how he approaches forms as a whole.
Let's watch.