Now that you know about ordinal, interval, and ratio data lets take a quiz
where you decide which type of data these examples are. Lets put each of these
types of data into context. Lets say you're trying to create a dot plot showing
any trends in revolutions throughout history so you look up when revolutions
occurred. And you put dots there. Or let's say you want to figure out if
republicans and democrats are more likely to major in the sciences, humanities,
or business. Or maybe you want to find out if rats that have learned one maze
will learn a second maze more quickly than rats that never did a maze. In this
case you'd look at the time it takes for each type of rat to finish the maze.
For the final example, maybe you want to determine if your year in college
influences your reaction to stressful stimuli. So you take a sample of
freshman, sophmores, juniors and seniors And you look at each group's overall
reaction to stressful situations. One of more of these maybe not be either
ordinal, interval, or ratio. Keep that in mind when you do this quiz.