So let's recall what we've done.
We have two techniques
to reduce our Sudoku.
The first one is elimination,
which consists of
picking a box with a value and
removing this value from all its peers.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And the second one is
called only choice,
which consists of picking a unit, and
if there's only one value that is only
allowed in one of the boxes,
assigning that value to the box.
Now having these,
how do we solve the problem?
Well, one thing we can do is
to just apply them repeatedly.
We can start with our original grid,
pick some box, and apply eliminate.
This takes us to a more complete grid.
Then in this new grid, we can pick
any unit and apply only choice.
This will take us to
an even more complete grid.
Now, again, we can pick any box and
apply eliminate and then any unit and
apply only choice.
And then keep on going.
This may take us to a solution,
or maybe not.
Maybe we'll get stuck somewhere.
This technique is called
constrained propagation.
And we'll have the chance to learn it
more in detail later in the nanodegree.
So, let's find out how far
this gets us by coding it and
trying it on some examples.