These types of visualizations are a good
way to communicate the story behind
the clusters in a way that is more
understandable by management, and
the users of the segmentation solution.
Since most business users of your
solution will be more interested
in how the clusters effect their part
of the business, making it easy for
them the understand the differences
between the segments,
gets them to that point a lot quicker.
It can even be a good idea to start
out the report of the results
with some brief names of the clusters
that summarize the findings.
So, in our example exercise,
we could describe Cluster one as the
Grow Anything Anytime segment of stores,
or Cluster five could be the Lots
of Snow Half the Year segment.
A good example of this is how Experient
handles their consumer segmentation.
They divide up the United States
into 71 different segments, and
have given each a name
that provides the user
with a way to quickly understand
the basic makeup of the segment.
They have segment names like fast
track couples for newly marrieds,
and settled and sensible for
those maybe getting close to retirement.
Then if you need to understand
what is behind those designations,
you can dig more thoroughly
into the details.
You can download a PDF of their
segment names in the instructor notes.
Of course,
after the cluster solution has been
agreed upon by management, the real
validation of the solution is through
testing it out in the real world.
In the case of our exercise,
this would be done through
the allocation of product
using the created segments.
Depending on the business and
the use case, it may be appropriate
when starting with segmentation, to run
the tests on a limited number of the
objects first for further validation.
This mitigates the risk, for
some reason, of being totally
off with the segments, and
making the mistake of applying an
invalid solution to the entire business.
As mentioned in an earlier lesson,
you could use the method known as
AD Testing for this kind of process.
This provides the truest
form of external validation.
But even then, clustering should
remain an iterative process.
Whatever your use case for
segmentation and
clustering, remember that
whatever you are segmenting, and
whatever variables you are using to
cluster, these will continue to change.
Which means that a clustering solution
that is good today, may start
moving after a couple of years, and
should be re-evaluated as time goes by.