We'll start with one very simple
description that you've actually
already seen.
Right?
We talked about the Shi-Tomasi
feature tracker.
And basically it's this idea of only
compute motion where you should.
We talked about this when we talked
about the Harris corners and
we talked about how to analyze
that second moment matrix.
And we said well there are other ways
of analyzing that second moment matrix
including the the Eigenvectors and
Eigenvalues there.
And we said that there was
this Shi-Tomasi thing called
good features to track the thing
that OpenCV made use of.
And basically,
the idea was that just track points
that you can track reliably.
Their basic algorithm was the following.
Basically from frame to frame
you're going to do Lucas-Kanade,
pure little translational motion.
Right.
Remember the,
the idea was that we assumed
that within a given small patch
we're going to find some translation.
All right.
And what's nice about that
is that's pretty robust for
sort of a small neighborhoods, you know,
you can basically say that
they're all translating.
Then what you do, and we're not
going to go into this too much here is
we're going to take those
points that have moved, and
look for an affine consistency.
So the idea is for each of the, the
little points that you've tracked using
the, the translation,
is there an affine model that maps the,
the tracked points to
the original points?
And then you can compare
those back to the original.
And that's exhibited here.
So here's an initial image and you can
see this little sign in there it says 25
miles an hour, and here they're getting
closer and here you're zooming past.
So the, the, the frame,
the sign is both translating.
Right?
Its moving to the left in the image and
its also expanding.
All right.
And here you can see the frames
that had been recovered.
Or I should say you can see
the region that has been recovered
through the tracking.
And the idea is that all the points in
the sign, remember it's on a plane at
moderate distance, which means
it's a perfect affine transform.
All those points are moving in
a particular affine transform
as you move across the,
the image sequence.
And, like I said, that was this,
good features to track,
which later got incorporated into OpenCV
for, for doing, estimation of motion.