Authentication and authorization
are the two main principles
of web security we will
cover in this course.
So let's first talk
about authentication.
Authentication is the process
of verifying that you
are who you say you are.
If you've ever logged into a website or
service, you've used authentication.
Actually you've probably used
authentication outside of your
computer as well.
For example,
we can verify a person's identify
by comparing a trusted document,
such as a license or passport, with
the physical appearance of that person.
If the picture and information match
with the person standing in front of us,
we authenticate that they
are who they claim to be.
Of course, this isn't a foolproof
system, but for many use cases,
the human eye if sufficient at
recognizing if a picture and
a person do not match.
Even in the scientific world there are
also ways to ensure the authenticity of
artifacts.
For example,
you can use carbon dating to ensure that
a fossil is indeed 300,000 years old,
and not just the skeleton of some
goldfish that died two years ago.
An example of authentication on
the Internet can be seen when we visit
verified websites.
If I land on a page that has a secure
connection, such as PayPal.com,
this green icon appears on the page.
This indication is the browser letting
us know that the website has been
verified through a trusted
certificate authority.
This means that the browser
recognizes this web page and
can verify that it is indeed the real
PayPal.com, and not an impostor page.
But most relevant to this class is
a website user authentication system.
With a unique user name and secret
password, you are proving to a website
that you are indeed who you say you are,
granting you access to the website.
While the identity information in many
cases can be public, like your email
address or user name, the password is
something that only you should know.
And since only you should know
that it serves as proof to verify
you are who you claim to be,
the owner of that account, and
therefore authenticated and logged in.
It's also important to note that
whenever there is a process of proving
the truth of something, there are always
people trying to cheat the system.
This is why there are many security
concerns you have to be aware of when
using, and even more,
when implementing authentication.