Now that you have your VM up and
running, let's talk about how to use it.
In your vagrant folder,
there's a directory called rubynd.
This folder will be home to all
of your Ruby project files for
this nanodegree program.
Rubynd is a shared folder.
This will allow you to access the files
in it from both your Windows computer
and your Linux PM.
If you've ever used Dropbox or
Google Docs before, it's a similar idea.
You can upload files to
Google Docs on one computer but
access them from another computer,
just by logging in.
Take a look at what's inside the rubynd
shared folder using the file explorer.
You'll notice that there's
already a Ruby file in there.
We've included this file
as part of the VM setup.
Now take a look at the Linux shell.
Type cd rubynd to navigate to
the shared folder in the VM.
Now if you type the ls command, you'll
also see the same file in your VM.
Run the file by typing ruby hello.rb.
Open up hello.rb in your
favorite text editor.
I am going to use Atom, but
the default Windows text editor
Notepad will work fine for this demo.
Edit the message that
hello.rb will print.
Change Welcome to the Ruby Nanodegree
Program to a message of your choice.
And don't forget to save.
Now that your file is edited, you can
run the Ruby file again with ruby
hello.rb, and
it will show your new output.