All right, to create Pitch Perfect,
we first need to learn how to create a new
Xcode project. If you haven't seen this
before, start by opening Xcode. Then go to
File > New > Project.
This will open up a new project wizard.
Make sure that you have selected the iOS
section. And then select a Single View
Application and click Next. Then we need
to give our new iOS app a name.
PitchPerfect seems like a good choice.
Then for the Organization Name, you can
put whatever you'd like for now. I’ll put
Udacity. the same goes for the
identifiers, which we'll talk about more
later on.
Make sure the language is Swift. Devices
is set to Universal. And you can unmark
all the checkboxes at this point.
This looks good. So let's go ahead and
click Next. Select a location where you'd
like to put the project. For me I'll
choose my Desktop and I’ll click Create.
Xcode will now create a new iOS app
called PitchPerfect and automatically
generate some files and settings for you.
Here's the project Xcode automatically
created for me. Here in the top left,
it has an AppDelegate class that will
listen to system events, such as when
your app starts, when you get a memory
warning and when your app is sent into
the background. There's also this default
ViewController class. Will add more tips in.
For now we're going to add a single
line to the AppDelegate, to a function
that gets called when the app launches,
called didFinishLaunchingWithOptions.
This one line of code will print out
hello, world to the console. Here in the
didFinishLaunchingWithOptions
function and in green we see comments
Xcode has provided by default.
Let’s add our print statement right
after the comment. I’ll type
print(“hello, world”).
Ok, now let's test to see our code running.
To do this, we’ll want to click
the Run button here in the top left,
which will launch the iOS simulator and
kick off the execution of our app.
When the simulator launches, we see our
brand new app and just a simple white
background. In the console, you see the
words hello, world.
Awesome. In a few minutes, you've already
created an iOS app. It probably won't win
the Apple Design Awards, but it's a start.
we’ll work to build and improve it
throughout the course. But first, let's
take a closer look at Xcode