All right,
you ready to move on to the next one?
>> Sure.
Okay, so the next one,
we've got our expectation back.
That makes me happy.
>> Yeah.
>> So, we've got our expectation back,
but now what we're doing is we're going,
the next thing that'll
happen is rather than doing
the best action from that point on,
we will take sort of the average
over all possible next actions.
>> Mm-hm.
>> But give more weight
the better the action is,
if I remember what your
row of ord actually does.
>> That is a nice way to do it, but
this is not written to be that way.
It's just weighting by the ranking.
So it could be that we put higher
weight on higher rank things.
But it could be we put higher
weight on lower rank things too.
So this is a very general expression.
But you're right.
I mean, this would be useful in
the case where it's doing some kind of,
I don't know, maybe a generalization
of epsilon greedy exploration.
The idea that we're going to, with
highest probability choose the max, and
with lower probability choose
things that aren't the max.
So it generalizes that idea.
>> Right, and so actually that would
be nice because one of the things about
the way we go around learning MDP's and
do Q-learning and value iteration is
we kind of assume we're always
going to do the next best thing.
But since we still
have to do exploration
as well as exploitation that
isn't actually what we do.
So this would allow
us to do exploration.
>> Well, it's not that it's
allowing us to do exploration,
it's actually defining the values, so
they incorporate exploration into them.
>> Right.
>> So one way of thinking about what
this is,
is an exploration sensitive MDP.
>> Right,
that's exactly what I was going to say.
>> Oh, awesome!
Well, just to finish this thought.
The values that you define for
the states include in them
the probability that you might
take a non-maximum action.
That's the sense in which the values
are exploration sensitive.
We can explore in, say, Q-learning and
still use this first update rule
to try to figure out what
the value is for the best policy.
This is actually trying to
figure out what the value is for
the policy that is exploring.
>> Right and in particular the policy
we're going to follow as opposed to
the policy we could follow.
>> Yeah, that's a good point.
>> Right, I think that's important.
>> Yeah, so this is kind of neat
because unlike regular Q-learning
it's actually figuring out the value,
it's on policy, it's
actually figuring out the value of the
policy that we might really be taking.
Whereas if we were to literally always
take the max, we won't learn the right
value in the case of Q-learning because
we're going to get stuck not exploring.
>> Okay.
I like that.
I can't think of a better name.
Are there any other names for
this besides exploration sensitive?
>> Well as I said it generalizes max and
min.
[LAUGH] One of the things that I really
like but have absolutely no use for
is that you can imagine an update role
where you always are trying to choose
the median action.
kind of not too good,
not too bad, middle of the pack.
I guess it's kind of like
the decision process for
people who just want to be mediocre and
not stand out.
So I'll say mediocre.
>> [LAUGH]
>> Mediocrity-sensitive MDPs.
>> And there's another case
where I found use for this,
which I think is kind of interesting.
So imagine that we've
got a huge action space,
where actually computing this
max is going to be difficult.
>> Okay.
>> So instead of actually running
through all possible actions to compute
the max, we're going to take
some random sampling and
then just compute the max
of that random sample.
So does that make some
sense as an algorithm?
Like instead of taking
the max over everything,
we'll just take a max
over a handful of things.
>> Sure, that makes sense if you have,
for example,
an infinite number of actions.
>> Yeah, that's right, but even just
a very large number of actions though.
The first time I heard about this was in
the case of an MDP that was being used
to define scheduling actions for
the Space Shuttle, back when there was
a Space Shuttle, and there was just so
many of them that going
through them was intractable.
So this is Tom Dietrich's work.
He actually randomly sampled
some of the actions and
then chose the best among that sample.
So what that gives you actually is
there's some probability you will choose
the actual max.
But there's also some probability
that you miss the max and
instead get the second largest
out of all the actions.
And there's some other
probability that you get
the third largest of all the actions.
It's more likely that you get higher
ranked actions than lower ranked actions
because of the subset that you choose,
you're always taking the max of that.
But it's not going to be
with probability one,
so what you end up with is some kind
of distribution over the likelihood of
choosing the max and the second highest
and the third highest and so on.
And this equation generalizes that
idea and shows that if we use this as
our update rule for something like value
iteration, we get a well defined answer.
This will converge to something.
It's just a little bit hard to
say exactly what it converges to.
It's not the best possible policy.
It's more like the policy that we get
when we always choose the best
action from a random sample.
>> Right, but if they are a bunch
of pretty good actions then
you may not get the optimal policy but
you'll still get a pretty good one.
It's like be satisficing
as opposed to satisfying.
>> Ooh yeah.
I would accept satisficing
as an answer to this one.
That's cool.
>> Okay.