Next, let's discuss matching
stores based on continuous trends.
While we can use the average sales per
month, we might get a better match
if we could also measure trends
over time of some of our variables.
Two commonly used measures for
using trends are growth in store traffic
and seasonal patterns in sales volume.
In our problem,
we'll use the number of invoices per
week to indicate traffic in the stores.
And we'll use total sales per store
per week to help us measure and
compare sales trends.
Fortunately for us,
there's a tool in Alteryx that
will help us create measures of
trend and seasonal patterns.
One value per test unit,
such as a store or
customer, that we can use to
match treatment to control units.
When thinking of the duration
of your experiment,
you should take into account that the AB
Trends Tool in Alteryx needs an entire
year of data plus a minimum 6 periods
in addition to the year is required.
For example, if your experiment is
14 weeks long, you would need 6
weeks of historical data plus
52 weeks for calculating trends.
58 weeks of historical data
would be needed to analyze 14
weeks of experimental data.
Make sure you understand the
requirements of your analysis tool when
designing an experiment as you may want
more data for different size periods.
See the Alteryx help page for
more information on the AB Trend Tool.
Lastly, it's important to
consider the normal cycle for
what you're trying to test when
determining how long to run a test.
For instance, if a customer visits the
store weekly, the test should be run for
at least a week.
If they purchase a service on a monthly
basis, you'd want to run your test for
at least a month.