We've had our taskForPOSTMethod
in place for a while.
Now we're going to use it.
So let's go to the TMDBConvenience file
and find our last unimplemented method.
Here we go, postToWatchList.
This is the method
that you'll implement.
This method should closely mimic the
postToFavorites convenience method, and
when it's complete,
you'll be done with the movie manager.
Also, if this doesn't seem like enough
of a challenge, why not try adding
the ability to display a movie's
rating as a bonus feature?
With the movie database client in place,
it should be a short amount of work.
Now this isn't a requirement but
it is a cool bonus to really flex
your networking muscles, and
make sure you understand the benefit and
the power of our new client.