Okay, what'd you come up with.
>> So the context for this constraint is
the operation checkout which
belongs to the Patron class.
And we're specifying the precondition.
>> Well how about the arguments,
how about the signature?
>> Oh, sorry.
So checkout, and then it takes
a loanable item as an argument.
And then you have the implied
argument of the Patron itself.
>> Gotcha.
>> And the precondition for
this particular constraint is that if
the Patron's age is less than or
equal to 12, so they're a child,
then that means that they can
only checkout up to five books.
So, it's going to affect the operation
of this function based on that.
>> A couple of corrections.
>> Okay.
>> It's less
than five,
>> Less than five.
>> okay, and
it's not going to affect the operation,
it's going to prevent the operation.
>> Okay.
>> It's a precondition right, and
preconditions are essentially
preventative.
Okay, because I had some confusion in
terms of how to specify because your
less than or equal to twelve years old,
you age is less than or equal to 12,
then how's that effect this method in
terms of how you express it in OCL.
>> Okay so it prevents it.
>> It just prevents it, okay.
>> And ultimately the expression which
comes with the keyword pre is a boolean,
okay?
So booleans are true or false.
In actually coming up
with the expression,
there are several ways to manipulate the
logical connectives on it to get them.
The one that's here is that it's
in the form of an implication.
There's an implies keyword in OCL,
and we're saying that if the age and
this is the age attribute
of the particular Patron,
okay, is less than or equal to 12.
In this case the 12 is for
years not weeks, okay.
That then implies that
it must be the case that
the size of the collection
of items currently
checked out must be less than five.
So a couple of things to say about that.
There is an operation,
items currently checked out.
And remember that it returned
a set of loanable items.
>> Right.
>> Now the set is a collection,
and collections themselves,
collection class,
collections have operations.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And
one of the built in operations is size.
So this is cardinality.
Remember we had the in first year logic,
we had the vertical bars on things.
So this is saying that the size of
the items currently checked out is less
than five.
>> Two more questions
before we move forward.
Is the If-then syntax even supported in
OCL or if you're going to say something
that's got that If-then structure which
is like an implication statement,
you're just using was.
>> So,
we actually had an if-then a minute ago.
We had if the book was a best seller,
it was only two weeks, and
else it was three weeks.
>> Right.
>> Okay, so
yes you can have the if-then.
The difference is a technical
difference having to do with the order
in which you check things, okay?
So, if you have here a implies,
you're first checking the age is
less than or equal to 12, okay?
And then checking the other part
of it which was less than five.
>> Okay, and
then the second question is, or
it's not really a question I guess.
I understand it more now that you say
a precondition is almost like if this
does not hold,
then the method cannot execute.
So therefore, when I was looking at the
original requirements that children can
check out to five books,
less or equal to five was.
I guess that was me kind of falling
back and saying okay it's less than or
equal to five that's how
many books I can check out.
But prior to this method executing,
it can't have five books because then
they would go to six if it did execute.
>> [CROSSTALK] An interesting point.
If somehow magically, they had
checked out 50, and they came and
tried to check out the 51st,
this would prevent them from doing it.
>> Correct.
>> Now, you can then ask,
how could they have gotten 50?
Okay, and
you could then prove to yourself that
they couldn't have gotten to 49, to 48.
They couldn't have gotten past four,
right?
>> Correct.
>> So
this particular constraint is not saying
how many they have checked
out explicitly, but
you could use it to prove that they
could never have gotten above four.
>> Okay.
>> Okay, so I guess what we're talking
about here is the inner play between
an invariant statement that they never
have more than four checked out, and
the precondition on the operation of
which is preventing them from getting in
a state which violates that invariant.
>> So wait, the invariant though is
thick would never have more than five
checked out.
>> What's going on here is that
the precondition says that they
have to have less than five.
>> Right.
>> And then they can,
the checkout on the operation
would allow them to add one more,
and that would get them to five,
so you're right.
>> Okay, okay.