Let's suppose there's a rectangle here,
as A, B, C, D.
And you want to know the value
of the sum of the pixels in that
rectangle, okay?
So what you do is, and that you want to
know the value in the original image.
So what you do is you take
a look at that rectangle, and
you go over to your integral image,
all right?
And you realize the sum of that
rectangle compu, in the original image,
is computed by looking at just these
four locations in the interval image.
And it's written down that the sum is
equal this will go through that, right?
You start with A.
Well, what's A?
A is the sum of everything up
to here in the original image.
Okay, but I don't want everything there.
Right?
Like, I don't want this stuff, and
I don't want that stuff.
So you say, okay!
No problem!
I'll subtract off B!
B is just this stuff, right?
B, the value at the location B,
in the integral image is the sum of all
of these pixels in the original image.
So if I just take A minus B, it was
this whole thing, minus that part.
So it's just that region.
Okay well, I still have got
a section in there I don't want.
Namely I don't want this.
Well that's easy.
That's C.
Okay, so I subtract off C.
And I'm almost done.
The observant of you will notice that
I've now subtracted this region off
twice.
So what do I have to do?
I have to put it back in once.
Well, do I have some value that's
the sum of that little square?
Of course.
That's D.
And that's why adding D back
in gives me the sum of that,
of the pixels in that rectangle
in the original image.
So only three additions,
and/or subtractions, right?
I have to add, subtract C,
subtract B, and then add D to A.
So I access the image four times,
do three addition, subtractions,
and I get the sum of any size rectangle!
So once I compute the integral image,
and that's actually very quick to do,
because the integral image,
that means I'm going across the top row,
I just look at the current pixel, and
I know the sum of everything behind me
because I've already computed that,
just add that in.
So it's recursively very quick
to compute the integral image.
So I can compute any
size rectangle quickly.
What this does mean by the way is,
if I'm looking to, for big faces and
small faces, I don't want to change the
size of the image that I'm looking at,
instead just change the size of
the features that I'm looking at because
it's really easy to look at a small
rectangle or a big rectangle
once I've computed an integral image
over, for that original image.