We haven't shown you code for
responding with a cache entry, but
you've seen caches.match for
getting things out of the cache.
And you've seen event.respond with,
so time to put them together.
If you've completed the last task,
your project is in the correct state for
this task.
If not, you can go to the project
directory in your command line and
run git reset --hard to remove
any local changes you have,
then git checkout task-cache-response.
Once again, the work happens
in the service worker script
in public/js/sw/index.js.
First, you'll need to clear up any code
in the fetch handler you already have.
We don't need any of the special four of
four handling from the previous tasks.
Then, your task is to
respond to the request
with an entry from
the cache if there is one.
Otherwise, fetch it from the network,
here's a hint.
You need to call event.respond with,
synchronously.
You can't call it within a promise
handler, that's too late.
Once you've coded it up,
reload the page.
Remember to have DevTools open and
use force update on reload, so
you only need to refresh
once to see changes.
You'll know it's working
because you'll be able to put
the site into Offline mode and
still get a response.
Once you've got it working,
head over to the settings page and
type cache- served into
the test field and press Enter.
This will confirm it's all working.