Now in this scenario again, we'll need
to ultimately end up more workers,
more work benches, more parts so in a
heterogeneous architecture we would need
to add more processes,
more server note, more storage.
However, before we can do that,
we first need to profile what
kinds of toys are in the end.
What kinds of requests
are the external users requesting?
And then also profile what kinds
of resources is required for
those particular types of requests for
those toys.
Only after we perform these profiling
tasks will we be able to figure out
exactly what kinds of resources
need to be added in order to
continue maintaining some balance
in this heterogeneous design.
The bottom line is that the management
of these systems is much more
complex compared to what's required
in a homogeneous architecture.
A very popular reference that discusses
the design space of these large scale
Internet services is Eric Brewer's paper
Lessons from Giant Skill Services.
This paper also describes some of the
trade-offs associated with choices for
data replication versus
partitioning that we already
discussed in the previous two lessons.
I have linked the paper
in the instructor note.