The course itself is structured in these sort of ten overall units.
Don't worry, they're not all as equally long and pedantic as this introduction.
We'll start off early by doing some image processing because you have to
manipulate images to do a variety of types of interaction with them later.
And we actually have a problem set early on there that
goes from image processing to getting some basic structure.
Then we'll talk about the geometry of cameras and camera models, and what
happens when you have multiple views and how you can relate them to each other.
We'll get down to the image and talk about features, computing something about
one image and figuring out where in the other image those same points occur.
because once you can do that, there's a lot you can do in terms of
thinking about either transforming images or computing geometry between them.
We'll spend just a little bit of time talking about how images get formed in
the first place, what we call lightness and brightness.
How does light interact with material and
then come to your imaging sensor in order to make a picture?
We'll spend a bit of time talking about motion, remember we talked about not
just static images, but we can actually have sequences of images?
So the question of how things are moving can be looked at.
And these are sort of separated into motion in the image, and that,
that is sort of how the pixels change, and then tracking the object.
And we'll focus a bit on tracking as well.
Then we'll get to something which we're going to do just a little bit of,
of classification and recognition.
And some of you may be saying, aw that's disappointing.
No, no, no, it's not disappointing, okay?
A lot of classification recognition is deeply steeped in machine learning.
So what we'll do is, we'll do some of it here, sort of some basic pattern
recognition, and then computer vision applied to recognition.
And then if you want to do more in the recognition universe,
you'll have to learn some machine learning as well.
The course concludes with just some extra stuff that is just useful to know,
if you're actually going to do computer vision work.
And then finally, because I can't help myself and neither can Arpin,
because he has true inspiration from biological systems,
we'll talk a little bit about how the human vision system works.