The second primary method of clustering
is called the k-centroid method.
It is called this because,
as opposed to the hierarchical method,
with this method you need to specify
the number of clusters you want in
the solution,
which is the k in k-centroids.
The other difference is the methodology
is built around assigning an object
to the closest centroid, which is
essentially the center of the cluster.
This centroid is repositioned
after each change to the clusters.
This example is fairly basic with
just two variables, and dividing into
two clusters, but it will help visualize
what occurs during the process.
With the k-centroid process,
the initial positions of the centroids
is generally chosen at random.
The objects to be clustered are then
assigned to the closest centroid.
And then the centroid is
repositioned to become the new
center of the formed cluster.
With each step,
this reoccurs where the objects are
reassigned as needed to the centroid.
And the centroid is then moved again,
until the reassignment and
centroid shift becomes negligible.