So here's our addGeofencesButtonHandler.
It's pretty straightforward
what it does.
So first of all, we check if our
Google API client is connected.
And if it isn't we just throw an error
at the user and let them know.
If it is, then we go to our addGeofences
that we've been discussing.
We pass it the API client.
We pass it the result of
getGeofencing request,
which of course is
a Geofence request object.
And we pass it the result of
getGeofencePendingIntent which is our
pending intent.
And once we've passed it these we
then set the result callback to this.
And by doing so the results will be
called back into the onResult that we
created just a moment ago.
When doing this you gotta
put it in a try catch loop.
And we want to catch
a securityException.
And if we get one,
we're just going to log it.
And that's it.
That's everything we need to do
to have our Geofences configured
when we push the button
within this application.
And then the services will
monitor the Geofences for us.
And inform us when we enter or
exit a Geofence.