If an app updates in the background but
no one opens it to find out,
did it really happen?
Though notifications started
out as a convenient way
to notify users of background updates,
they've grown to become a powerful
standardized shortcut to interact
directly with apps in a lightweight way.
Starting in Jellybean,
rich notifications were
able to include actions.
Which let you define two or
three specific actions to perform on
the data included in the notification.
Lollipop added new template types for
notifications along with
heads-up notifications.
As a standardized UI designed for
specifically conveying timely
information in limited time space,
they're an obvious
mechanisms to use when Android expanded
into wearables with Android Wear.
Suddenly, the rich notifications
you designed for phone and
tablets make your app
wearable compatible for free.
Nougat changes the layout of
notifications to always show the app
posting them.
The new API allows for inline replies to
notifications, similar to Android Wear,
as well as specifying custom layouts for
heads-up and big notifications.
The best part is that the Android
support library wraps almost
all of these platform differences
with an easy to use API.
But don't overdo it with notifications,
there's a fine line between useful and
spammy.
And it's only a couple of clicks for
a user to disable your apps
notifications permanently.
So check out the link to
the design guide on notifications.