This is related to the general idea of what's called locality sensitive hashing.
All right?
So I'm going to assume that most of you, as computer science students, you know,
what hash tables are and what hash functions are.
And if you don't, you may not understand this.
Normally a hash function maps some data structure.
Into some nicely distributed space.
So you might have a function that maps, a structure to,
integers between one to a hundred, Okay?
And you can think of those integers as bins.
If you give me some new data structure, and I've already seen one of these
before, I map it through that function, and I go and I look at the bin, and
I only search through the ones that are in that bin, okay?
So, if it's distributed kind of evenly.
You're going to reduce your search work by a factor of 100,
all right, because you this function and, and you reduce it down.
But the problem with hash,
not problem, the design of hash functions is that they are very precise.
They're designed for precise data structures.
Locality-sensitive hashing works similarly, but it's a little bit
different because it takes the notion of distance into account.
And the basic idea is you're going to construct some hash function.
Here it's written as g.
Okay? And it's going to map onto some output U.
All right?
And the idea is, and there's some like Greek written here, et cetera.
But the basic idea is that if you have two points that are nearby
in the original space by some distance measure, then the probability that those
two points will land in the same bin should be pretty high.
Likewise, if I've got two other points that are far away in the original space,
the likelihood that they land in the same bin should be relatively low.
Okay? That's what locality-sensitive hashing is.
And when you do that, it means that I can compute this hash function.
Go to whatever bit it sends me.
And the idea is that.
Descriptors that were similar, not exactly the same, but
similar will be in the same bin.
There was some nice work done by, Kulis and Grauman.
The title is Kernelized by Locality Sensitive Hashing for Scalable Image Search.
There's a lot of work on kernel functions.
We'll talk about them them later.
This is not the kernel of a, filter.
Sorry, they use the same name.
But the kernel functions here are a way of mapping from some dimension,
some higher dimension.
And then operating on them.
And this is a approach of how to do.
Applying these kernels to sift features.
What.
What, what's important is it's the nicest discussion in there
about doing this locality sensitive hashing.