the name kenny refers to john f kennedy
who developed this edge detection
algorithm in 1986 with edge detection
the goal is to identify the boundaries
of an object in an image so to do that
first I'll convert to grayscale alright
and next I'll compute the gradient nice
ok so now you're looking at the gradient
of my world where the brightness of each
pixel corresponds to the strength of the
gradient at that point we're going to
find edges by tracing out the pixels
that follow the strongest gradients
alright but gradient world's a little
scary so let's go back to color by
identifying edges we can more easily
detect objects by their shape so what
exactly is an edge let's first get some
intuition by having a look at the
parameters for the opencv can function
you'll call it like this in this case
i'm applying the candy function to an
image called gray and the output will be
another image called edges low threshold
and high threshold determine how strong
the edges must be to be detected you can
think of the strength of an edge as
being defined by how different the
values are in adjacent pixels in the
image really just the strength of the
gradient next I'll show you how that
works so that you have a clear picture
what's going on under the hood when you
use the canny edge detection method in
opencv