Now that we've taken a look at
storage in the Firebase console,
let's shift our focus back to Friendly
Chat and configure it to send and
receive photo messages.
Here, the steps we'll take the send and
receive a single photo message.
First, we'll upload a photo
to Firebase Storage.
Then, we'll write a message
to the database containing
a reference to the photos
path in the Firebase Storage.
Finally, we'll handle
displaying the photo message
in FCViewControllers table view.
Before we can do this,
let's return to the pod file to insure
the 'Firebase/Storage' pod is listed so
that CocoaPods can pull in the storage
related classes and functions.
Remember, if we had just
added the storage pod
then we will need to run pod install
to download the correct dependencies.
But since this pod is already been
included, we are ready to go.