Time to bring our apartment
into virtual reality.
There are a lot of amazing
STKs that can make it really
easy to take a Unity Scene and
enable it for VR.
However, it's also interesting to see
how to build your own VR camera system
and you'll learn a lot in the process.
Let's start by opening
up our apartment scene.
Now, let's create two
new camera game objects.
Let's name one of them left eye and
the other right eye.
For the left eye,
let's set the viewport width to be 0.5.
For the right eye,
set its viewport x coordinate to
be 0.5 and leave the width as 1.
Now if we hop over to the game
view we'll see that the left eye
is now rendering the image on
the left side of the screen.
And the right eye is now
rendering to the right.
Let's now create
an empty game object and
group our camera eyes
together underneath it.
Remember the lens separation distance,
aka,
the LSD that you measured in the quiz?
Time to put that to use, the LSD
on my cardboard is 64 millimeters,
this might be different for you,
so you should use your own value.
Now, if we divide the LSD by two,
we get the distance between
our nose to our eye, which
is the value we want to use in unity
in order to separate out our cameras.
Let's shift the left eye
to left by 32 millimeters.
Which we can do by setting
the X coordinate to -0.32.
And now let's shift the right eye to the
right by 32 millimeters, which we can do
by setting the X coordinate to 0.32,
and with that we've correctly
implemented the rendering required to
view the image within our cardboard.
Next, let's implement our
own head rotations so
that we have more than just
a stereoscopic viewer.
We'll have our own VR app.