You're going to use a dynamic broadcast
receiver to change the UI depending on
whether the device is plugged in or not.
When the app is not plugged in,
as we can see here,
then this charger icon
down here should be gray.
But when it is plugged in,
as we can see up here, it is now,
this charger icon down here
should change to pink.
To do this, you're going to create
a method that changes the plug to either
a grey icon or a pink icon.
Make an intent filter for
the charging status.
Make a broadcast receiver that updates
the UI to pink if the broadcast receiver
is triggered because the phone
is charging, and gray otherwise.
Create and
register this broadcast receiver with
the intent filter that you just made.
And clean up the broadcast
receiver in onPause.
This exercise is going to take place on
the MainActivity so let's open that up.
The first thing I'm going to do is
create a new method called showCharging
which takes in a boolean.
What I'll do in this method, is check
that if the boolean passed in is true,
what showCharging will do is it'll
take the boolean that's passed in, and
use it to determine the source image
of the image view for the charger.
So if it's charging, we're going
to set the image view to pink.
Otherwise, it's not charging, and
we'll set the image view to grey.
All right, now that I'm done with this,
I'm going to create an intent filter.
And I'm not going to create it
in the manifest like you saw.
I'm going to make it dynamically.
Up top here, I'm going to make
a new variable for my IntentFilter.
And then down here in the onCreate I'm
going to actually exsanguinate it.
Up here, I'm going to create
a variable for my IntentFilter.
And then down here in OnCreate.
I'm going to actually instantiate it.
I'm going to take my intent filter and
I'm going to use the addAction method
to add the action powerConnected.
I will also add the action
powerDisconnected.
This intent filter is now set up
to catch when either the device is
connected to power or
disconnected for power.
Cool, but my intent filter is not super
useful without a broadcast receiver, so
let's make that next.
Now because I'm only going to be using
the broadcast receiver in this main
activity class I'm going to
make it an inner class.
So we're going to scroll
down to the bottom, and
I'm going to make a private class
called ChargingBroadcastReceiver, and
it's going to extend
BroadcastReceiver as you see here.
Now I'm going to implement
the onReceive method,
and inside of here I want to call my
ShowChargingMethod to update the UI.
And I am going to use my ShowCharging
method to update the UI.
Now inside onRecieve I want to be able
to use my ShowCharging method to update
the UI but how do I know whether
it's actually charging or not?
Well, because I plan on using this
broadcast filter with this intent
filter.
I know the intent that my
broadcaster receiver gets,
Will only be an intent that either has
the action ACTION_POWER_CONNECTED or
ACTION_POWER_DISCONNECTED.
That intent is passed down here.
So what I can do is I
can get a String_action,
and set it equal to the intent's action.
And then whether it's charging or
not will be equal to whether that action
is equivalent to
a POWER_CONNECTED action here.
And then finally I can take this
boolean that I just made, and
pass it on to showCharging.
So isCharging will only be true if
the broadcast receiver received a system
intent with
an ACTION_POWER_CONNECTED action.
Otherwise, it'll be false.
If showCharging receives true here, it's
going to update the plug to be pink,
otherwise, it should be gray.
Now that I have this broadcast receiver,
let's actually make
an instance of it in onCreate.
Here at the top, I'm going to
make a new instance variable for
my broadcast receiver and then down
here, I'm going to instantiate it.
I still need to actually register
the receiver to receive updates.
I'm going to register the receiver in
onResume, and unregister it in onPause.
This is because the receiver only
really needs to update the UI
when the activity is in the foreground.
So here, I'll call registerReceiver
with my broadcastReceiver and
my intent filter.
And here in the onPause I will call
unregisteredReceiver with my receiver.
And with that I'm almost done.
Let's run the code.
So I'm going to use some ADB
commands to simulate plugging and
unplugging the phone.
So right now the phone's unplugged.
And now I'm going to plug the phone in,
and woohoo,
it updated to pink, that's great.
Now we can see here it's plugged in.
And then if I unplug the phone it's
gray again which is also good.
But you might notice,
if you navigate away from the app, and
say plug in the phone,
like I just did here.
And then go back to the app.
You get in a kind of inconsistent state,
because the phone is plugged in, but
this is gray.
We're going to be fixing that bug next.
But for now, go ahead and
finish this exercise.
When you're done you should
be able to see that while
the app is in the foreground
this changes effectively.
I've also added some helpful commands
for simulating plugging in the phone and
unplugging the phone, in both
the emulator and the live device.
Okay, good luck.