An answer is that every one of these
is a potential problem for passive reinforcement learning.
So every problem won't show up in every possible domain.
It'll depend on what the environment looks like.
But it is a possibility that you could get bitten by any of these problems.
And they all stem from the same cause,
from the fact that passive learning
stubbornly sticks to the same policy throughout.
We have a policy, pi of S,
and we always execute that policy.
So if the policy here was to go up and then go right,
then we would always stick to that;
and the only time we would explore any other state is when those actions failed.
If we tried to go up from this state--
because that's what the policy said;
but, stochastically, we slipped over to this state--
then we wouldn't do something else, according to the policy
and so we'd get a little bit of exploration,
but we'd only vary from the chosen path
because of that variation
and we wouldn't intentionally explore enough of the space.