Vision is the main way humans
gain information about the world.
I see a cup of tea,
I pick up the cup of tea.
Ever since humans started imagining
machines moving around, and
interacting with the world,
we've given them eyes.
Look at HAL9000 from
2001 A Space Odyssey.
He's just one big eye.
Today, we want automated cars to be
able to distinguish between people, and
trees, and the road.
We're enabling our cars to do this
using Convolutional Networks.
Starting with the work of Yann LeCun in
the late 90s, Convolutional Networks,
typically shortened to cognets,
gained popularity for detecting and
recognizing hand written characters and
images.
In 2012, a huge data set called,
Imagenet was released.
With 1,000 labeled categories, and
over a million training images.
Alex Krizhevsky's AlexNet, used a deep
Convolutional Network trained on
GPU's to achieve a 15%
error rate on Imagenet.
And this easily beat the second
best attempt that had 26% errors.
In this project, you'll build
a Convolutional Network with TensorFlow,
and it'll recognize objects and images.
Here you'll be using
the CIFAR-10 Dataset,
which consists of 60,000 images
of ten different objects.
This data set is commonly used
in computer vision research, and
now it’s your turn to join the field.
Okay, enjoy.