So there's an entire region over here where there's no example anywhere near B.
This region is often called the margin. The margin of a linear separator is the distance of the separator to the closest training example.
The margin is a really important concept in machine learning.
There's an entire class of maximum margin linear rhythms, and the two most popular are support vector machines and boosting.
If you're familiar with machine learning, you've come across these terms.
These are very frequently used these days in actual discrimination learning tasks.
I will not go into any details because it would go way beyond the scope of this introduction to artificial intelligence class.
But I'd like to say a few abstract words specifically about support vector machines or SVMs.
As I said before, a support vector machine derives a linear separator, and it picks the one that actually maximizes the margin, as shown over here.
By doing so, it attains additional robustness over perceptron, which only picks a linear separator without consideration of the margin.
Now, the problem of finding the margin maximizing linear separator can be solved by a quadratic program,
which is an iterative method for finding the best linear separator that maximizes the margin.
One of the nice things that support vector machines do in practice is they use linear techniques to solve nonlinear separation problems.
And I'm just going to give you a glimpse of what's happening without going into any detail.
Suppose your data looks as follows: We have a positive class, which is near the origin of a coordinate system,
and a negative class that surrounds the positive class.
Clearly, these two classes are not linearly separable because there's no line I can draw that separates the negative examples from the positive examples.
An idea that underlies SVMs that will ultimately be known as the kernel trick is to augment the feature set by new features.
Suppose this is x1 and this is x2, and normally x1 and x2 would be (unintelligible) features.
In this example you might derive a third one. Let me pick a third one.
Suppose x3 equals the square root of x1 square plus x2 square.
In other words, x3 is the distance of any data point from the center of the coordinate system.
Then things do become linearly separable.
Plotted just along the third dimension, all the positive examples end up to be close to the origin.
And all the negative examples are further away. And the line is orthogonal to the third input feature, solves the separation problem.
Map back into the space over here, it's actually a circle, which is a set of all values of x3 that are equidistant to the center of the origin.
Now, this trick could be done in any linear learning algorithm, and it's really an amazing trick.
You can take any nonlinear problem, add features of this type or any other type, and use linear techniques and get better solutions.
This is a very deep machine learning insight that you can extend your feature space in this way.
And there's numerous papers written about this.
In SVMs, the extension of the feature space is mathematically done by what's called kernel.
I can't really tell you what it is in this class, but it makes it possible to derive very large new feature spaces,
including infinity dimensional new feature spaces. This is a very powerful, it turns out you never really compute all those features.
They're implicitly represented by so-called kernels, and if you care about this, I recommend you to dive deeper into the literature
of support vector machines. This is meant to just give you an overview of the essence of what support vector machines are all about.