so I've been working on neural network
since 2006 when I took my first day I
class in grad school but neural networks
actually have a much longer history they
go back all the way to the nineteen
fifties that's a great point one of the
fascinating things about neural networks
at least to me is how long they've taken
to become an overnight success as far
back as the late nineties there was a
network called the Lynette built by yon
lagoon that the post office and banks
used to read digital on mail and checks
and it was incredibly important but even
after one that not a lot of interest
picked up in neural networks deporting
is only really taken off in the last
five years
it's kind of a puzzle why it took so
long yeah that's a good question the
answer boils down to the increase
availability of labeled data along with
the greatly increased computational
throughput of modern processors for a
long time we didn't have the huge
labeled data sets that we needed to make
deep learning work those datasets only
became widely available with the rise of
the internet which made collecting and
labeling huge datasets feasible but even
when we had big data sets we often
didn't have enough computational power
to make use of them
it's only been in the last five years
that processors have gotten big enough
and fast enough to train large-scale
neural networks