So let's take a look at the new tag
that you created to send an event hit.
Click New to create the tag,
you know that by now.
I call mine
Send Daily Special EVENT Hit, so
I can tell it distinctly
from the Screen View Hit.
Configure the tag to get the Tracking ID
for the analytics account,
which is from the variable
we configured earlier.
Track type is event.
I called my category, Button clicks.
It doesn't matter what
you called your category.
I called my action, Show Daily Special.
You can call it what you like.
And then this one, the label, food pref,
notice how we use the variable.
Actually, the way you get the variable,
you just click the button, and
you go down to food prefs.
It's in here somewhere.
Go up to food pref and you insert it.
And because it's a data layer variable
it's available to us in that fashion.
No value.
If you do specify a value
make sure it's an int.
If you set the value and
it's not an int,
the hit will not show up in Analytics.
And then the firing,
it's actually going to fire the same
as the Screen View hit did.
I want it to fire when
the event equals openScreen and
when the screen name
equals Show Daily Special.
And save the tag.