So what's with these lenses anyway?
Well they serve a pretty
simple function actually.
Each lens makes it possible for
your eye to focus on a screen that
is extremely close to your face.
As an experiment,
try holding your phone screen
a couple centimeters from your eyes and
see if you can read anything.
Go ahead, I'll wait here.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Did you try it?
Well you probably noticed that you
can't read anything on the screen.
It's incredibly blurry.
All right.
Now take your cardboard device,
look through it and
hold your phone up against the lenses.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now if you did that you'll probably
notice that the image popped into nearly
perfect focus.
By using specialized lenses,
VR headsets focus the light from
a near eye display onto your retina.
You'll also notice that the lenses
greatly magnify the image shown on your
phone, just like this.
You might even be able to see
the individual pixels on the display.
The exact size, shape and
placement of these lenses can have
a huge impact on the final
quality of your VR experience.
Each headset manufacturer has to choose
a lens that makes the best trade off
between field of view,
focal length, comfort,
optical distortion, and finally cost.
All right, now let's dive
even deeper into the headset.
Let's look at VR display technology.