As before, we use normalized cross correlation.
Since the image is a two-dimensional matrix,
we need to be careful when finding the maximum.
Simply writing max of c would compute the column wise maximums.
Indexing c with a single colon flattens it.
Therefore, max of c colon would compute the image wide maximum.
We use a slightly different trick to find the location where this
maximum occurs.
The find function directly returns the row and
column, that is the y and x coordinate of the desired location.
Remember that these are raw indices into the matrix of correlation coefficients.
We need to account for the offset by subtracting the size of
the template along the appropriate dimension and adding one.
And that's it.
Let's see what y and x values we get back.
All right, 75, 150.
Isn't that where we cropped out the glyph from?
Indeed, those were the top and left coordinates.
We can do some additional plotting to make the result more intuitive.
Here we first show the original image, and
then we plot a red plus on top of it where the template was found.
Since this is not a fully interactive environment,
we have limited plotting capability.
In the local installation of MATLAB, or
Octave, you can a lot more, like draw a rectangle where the template is found.