Hi again, now that you've completed
some of your nanodegree projects,
it's time to work on communicating what
you've learned in a job application.
You may not be ready to apply to
jobs right now, and that's okay.
But you still need to work on your
career development in order to one day
be job ready.
I want to share a personal story of how
five minutes got me hired at Udacity.
[SOUND] I had just moved across
the country I was not applying to jobs,
because I wanted to wait another month,
to settle into my new home.
One day, I spoke with a friend
who worked at Udacity, and
she told me there was a job opening
that I would be a good fit for.
However, they were already interviewing
other people for the role.
So if I wanted to be considered,
I had to apply right then.
I applied five minutes later.
I was only able to do so
because I already had a resume and
cover letter updated with my
new contact information and
targeted to a role at
an education company.
My materials had already
been viewed by my peers,
gradually, last year and
I refined them multiple times.
So I was confident my
application would be good,
I just changed a few key words to
match the job description and applied.
If I had taken even just another
day to work on my resume and
cover letter, I would have missed
the window of opportunity and
I wouldn't be here with you today.
When your dream job comes
you want to be ready.
In this lesson,
we will go over how to effectively
conduct a targeted job search.
Let's get started.