Unit tests are designed
to verify that a small,
individual part of the code,
works as expected.
In this exercise, we've created some
unit tests for you so that you could run
them and verify that you've
implemented the contract correctly.
To run all units test, in the exercise
folder underneath the waitlist test
directory, right click on
the ContractClassUnitTest and
then select Run 'ContractClassUnitTest'.
You can see that once you've run it
before we've implemented the contract,
is that it tells you that
All 3 tests have failed.
And if you look down
underneath in the logs,
you can see what one the problems are is
that there should be 1 inner clause
inside the contract which
we haven't implemented yet.
Now once you have
implemented your contract,
you can rerun those tests
again the same way.
And then you'll notice that
the bar turns green and
it tells us that All
the 3 tests have passed.
However if one of them still failed, you
could take a look at the logs underneath
which might help you identify
what the problem is.