At this point, we should've covered
a lot about what lighting is, and how to
get the most out of it, to squeeze
the last bit of performance out of
our scene, we just need to adjust a few
more settings and some other windows.
Let's quickly go to Edit &gt;
Project Settings &gt; Quality.
By default, Unity will list a few
settings for a variety of platforms.
Since we're only interested in mobile,
lets go ahead and
delete every setting except fastest and
then re name fastest to mobile.
Now, we want to make sure that pixel
count is set to zero, texture quality is
set to full, anti-aliasing is set to 2x,
and shadows are disabled.
Going through those changes one by one,
let's start with pixel light count.
Pixel light count tells Unity how many
realtime lights it should consider for
a given pixel.
Since we don't have any
realtime lights in our scene,
we can set this value to 0 and be fine.
I should point out that everything in
this panel refers to realtime settings,
so disabling shadows here only
disables real time shadows and
not our baked shadows.
Next, we have tetra quality,
which we set to full.
And while yes, on mobile devices we
should be careful about our quality.
This setting is telling us whether
we want to lower the resolution of
our textures even further.
Since we've already optimized
the textures in our scene,
we can set them to full.
Last, we have anti aliasing.
Aliasing is a problem that results
because we want to display continuous
lines with discrete pixels,
this results in jagged lines.
Unity luckily provides some
efficient algorithms to combat this.
But nonetheless,
aliasing is a huge problem in VR
because we're effectively
using only half the resolution
AKA half the pixels of our display
since we need to render two images.
Thus while it's extra
computation to use aliasing
it results in a much better image
which is why we use anti-aliasing.
And that covers the tweaks we need
to do in our quality settings.
Now, time to put this in our phones.