Hi again. It's great to see you again.
We talked a lot about basic methods of AI,
and from today on we'd like to go into applications.
Specifically, today we'll talk about computer vision.
Computer vision is a very bright field
that concerns itself with making sense out of camera images or video.
Many devices today are equipped with cameras, such as cell phones or cars,
and making sense out of image data has become a really important subfield
of artificial intelligence.
Today I'll teach you some of the very basics.
It's not as deep as my graduate level class on computer vision,
and I hope you get a chance to take that in the future,
but I hope to enable you to apply some of the very basic methods
to, for example, use images and classify them using artificial intelligence technology
through feature extraction and other techniques
and also to start doing some of the more 3D-oriented tasks
such as 3D constructions.
So let's start with the very, very basics
and ask ourselves what is a camera.
Cameras come in all sizes and shapes.
This is my beautiful Nikon D3 camera [shutter clicks],
but I don't use it much because it's very heavy, even though it takes beautiful pictures.
This is the camera I use the most. It's a cell phone camera.
It's an 8 megapixel camera over here with a flash,
and I can start it, and you get to see whatever is underneath,
like this pen over here.
I can also activate the front camera, and you get to see the way I've been recording
all those wonderful online lectures over all those weeks
with this little camera over here.
In all of those cameras there is a lens and there's a chip,
and the light is captured from the environment and focused through the lens on the chip,
which raises the question, how does a lens and a chip really work?