So, finally to summarize, we introduced
the concept of video textures in this
lecture, talked about various methods
of how we can compute similarity.
We talked about how similar frames
can be used to find similar points.
And, and we can actually use that
to jump, arc back and forward and
that would allow us to kind of generate
a much more infinitely looping video.
We talked about how blending,
fading and cuts and
all that kind of stuff can
also be used in the domain or
video, then we talked about variety
of extensions of video textures.
Listing here a lotta
papers have come in,
including the three papers
from us that we worked on,
but there are additional papers that
you might actually find interesting.
Panoramic video textures
is another interesting one.
And actually these days of
course as we talked about it,
there's much more work going on
in trying to create cinemagraphs.
I'll show examples of that in
one of my future lectures too.
Again, look at my website and
of course as usual, search around,
you'll find lots of beautiful examples
of this kind of stuff on the web.