Hey there! My name is Cezanne Camacho. And I'm an instructor here at Udacity.
I've been working our self driving car course which focuses
on how a car sees a world through
cameras and sensors.
and then makes driving decisions
based on what it sees.
And deep learning is one of the most
exciting tools that self driving cars use
to navigate the world. Using deep learning
you can teach a car to drive
based on observations about the environment it's in
like whether the car is surrounded by people or other cars
Or if the car is moving quickly down the highway
The car should respond correctly in all kinds of situations
One problem that deep learning can help solve
is navigating efficiently through traffic
A problem that's near to my heart living in California.
People spend hours stuck in traffic every day.
So let's see how deep learning can help
To get you started, we'll be looking at a project developed by MIT
called Deep Traffic.
Deep traffic is a simulation of highway traffic
where the car in red is controlled by a neural network
that you can train.
And a neural network is just
a computer program that's loosely modeled
how our brain processes information
and learns from it. And these networks
acquaint themselves with the world like
humans do, learning by trial and error.
Let's see how this example works.
The car starts out not knowing much about its environment.
The only thing that's already programmed
is safety. This car won't ever crash into other ones.
The rest of its behavior is determined
by a neural network.
This neural network takes in input data
processes and learns from this input
from hidden, or unseen layers,
and outputs an action. The input
is data about the car's surroundings
like where it is in relation to other lanes
cars and empty space.
I'll call this data
the car's state.
And the action the car takes
will be to move left or right
or stay in the same place.
and to speed up or slow down.
New states and actions happen over
and over again as time progresses
and at each time step, the network
learns more about which states and actions
results in the fastest navigation
through trafffic. This is a type
of deep learning called
reinfocement learning. The car
starts out without any knowledge
but learns how to act by favoring or
rewarding actions and states
that result in faster navigation.
This reinforces the best behavior
So, given only well-defined input
and a goal,
to drive the fastest, the car can
learn for itself how to navigate traffic.
It'll be your job to tune the input to the neural network.
In code, this is controlled by the variable
"lanesSide," "patchesAhead," and "patchesBehind."
This whole simulation is laid out in a grid
defined by lanes and patches.
Each car is about
three or four patches in length
and you can see what the input grid looks like
by clicking Road Overlay and Learning Input.
Right now, the learning input is just one patch
which doesn't provide much information.
But if I change patchesAhead
to be 6, and lanesSide to be 1,
and I click "Apply Code,"
I can see
a larger learning input area.
I'll see 6 patches ahead of the red car
and one lane to the left and
and one lane to the right of it. This gives
a little more information, but you'll probably
want to expand this even more. This
area defines the input that the neural network will learn from.
Other variables you should change
include the number
of hidden layers. And the number
of neurons in the neural network.
Here, there's a single layer defined for you
in the starting code
with just one neuron.
I'd suggest increasing the number of neurons
and copy and pasting this code
to add more layers. This will
improve the network's ability to learn from the incoming data. You'll learn more about
these hidden layers and neurons later on.
For now, just know that one layer
can recognize a basic pattern in the data,
like all the places where an empty grid cell
is next to an occupied grid cell.
Then each successive layer
in the network looks for
a pattern in the previous layer.
Eventually these hidden layers produce
the outputs we're looking for that
determine the action that the car should take.
I know this all seems mysterious for now, but these
layers are just the way that neural networks
find patterns in data
and learn from those patterns.
This example is mainly meant
to give you some intuition for how
deep learning works and how quickly
a network can be changed
to solve a real-world problem like traffic navigation.
So, I urge you to play around
with the inputs to the neural network
then when you're done,
click Apply Code, then Run Training.
You should see the behavior of the car
change pretty quickly. Then,
to evaluate how well you're done,
click "Start Evaluation Run,"
or just take a look at how fast your
car is moving and how many cars
it passes. Try to get it to
go faster than 65mph. Good luck!