The friendly chat folder
contains a file called Podfile.
This special file is used
by a tool called CocoaPods.
CocoaPods is an iOS dependency
manager or in everyday speak,
a tool for incorporating code
already written by others so
that you don't have to write
everything from scratch.
Let's open the Podfile to get
a better picture what CocoaPods does.
We can see that the files comprise
the several pod statements.
Each of these pods tells CocoaPods to
download some code from a server and
incorporate it into our project.
For example, this statement pulls on a
code for a Firebase real-time database.
In the same way,
other Firebase features are bundled up,
it can be downloaded as separate parts.
When you want to add another Firebase
feature like including ads in your app,
you want to add the Firebase
ads pod to the pod file so
that the CocoaPods can do the leg
work of grabbing the code you need.
But how do you know what Firebase
pods you might need for your apps?
Here's a list of the current Firebase
pods and what services they provide.
You can also check out this list
in the link in the resources.
If you want to learn more about what
CocoaPods are and why we use them,
then check out the video we've
also listed in the resources.
Now, if you've never used Cocoapods
before then you'll need to install it
first by opening a terminal and
typing sudo gem install cocoapods.
If you get an error that looks like
this, don't panic, it's pretty common.
We've included a link for
how to fix it in the resources.
And you can always ask on the forums
if you have other problems.
But if it looks like nothing is
happening, then you're good to go.
This means CocoaPods is being installed.
Now this can take several minutes, so
it might be a good time to go grab one
of those hamburgers off the grill.
Okay, now we have the software we
need in order to use our pod file and
pull in the dependencies for Firebase.
It's worth noting again that Cocoapods
is extremely useful because it allows us
to use classes of methods that have
already been written by others.
As you develop more apps
you'll realize that it just
doesn't make sense to reinvent
the wheel every step of the way.
There may be third party
libraries in the form of pods that
have already done this work.
And you can use CocoaPods
to incorporate them.
Let's see how we incorporate
Firebase dependencies.