So let's start in a place very familiar
to all of us, slow function performance.
This is your basic computer science
101 concept of performance.
That is, you've written some code and
it executes more slowly
than you'd actually expect.
Now, this often happens
innocently enough.
I mean, you're focused on creating
some code change to solve a particular
problem in a particular way.
But soon you realize
that it's taking much,
much longer to execute
that code than you'd like.
Now the primary reason that
code can be taking too long
to execute has everything to
do with how the language and
of course the associated hardware is
handling the execution of your code.
For example on some older hardware
which we will not actually name
executing a branching statement on
a floating point comparison took almost
4x as long as doing the same
thing on integers or booleans.
The reason for
this was the chip architecture.
The part of the CPU dedicated to
floating point calculations occurred
after the Branching logic stages.
Meaning that any floating point
comparisons would have to
wait until the end of the cycle
pipeline, stalling the rest of
the operations until it could
finally execute its branching logic.
But, listen don't freak out here.
Modern hardware generally doesn't
have these type of nuanced
issues to deal with.
But it does illustrate a very,
very important point.
How you write you code
affects performance,
depending on how the language
executes on the hardware,
all the way down to how your silicon
chips are actually structured.
Let me be clear on this.
To optimize your code, you have to
understand the system that runs it.
Now, slow function performance
generally comes in two flavors.
Firstly, you have your
single slow function form.
Now, this is pretty straightforward.
You've got some function
that's taking like, 2x or
50x longer to execute than
you actually want it to.
This is actually pretty easy to fix.
I mean, you find the slow function,
take a look at its code,
figure out what the problem is, and
then try a few fancy ways to fix it.
Now much harder to figure
out is our second type.
Death of a thousand cuts effectively
this is when you have a hundred
functions, each taking one
millisecond longer than it should
resulting in a hundred millisecond extra
in your overall program execution.
This type of problem is
the hard one to track down and
even harder to fix because you
usually end up slogging through
every piece of your executed code
to find small wins that in the end,
can make the difference between
shipping and your company going under.
Now, fixing these tiny performance
problems is all about profiling.
That is, timing your code to figure out
what portions of it are running slower
or longer than the others and
then making some small tweaks and
then timing your code once again.
And, once you find one of the offending
functions, you'll then need to start
timing individual lines of
code in that function and
in all the functions that it
actually ends calling later.
Now this can get really gnarly unless
you're an expert in the field but
fear not.
The Android SDK has some excellent tools
to help you track down these problematic
portions of your code so
you can fix them up right.
Let's take a look.