So, now it's your turn to
explore the Analytics Dashboard.
Feel free to explore
the Admin Dashboard.
Look at the different options,
see what the things do.
You'll find that there's really a lot
of options here, Channel Settings for
example, e-commerce settings,
Adsense linking.
Things like this you may not be ready
to use, but don't worry about that.
There's a lot of resources for
learning how to use analytics.
And this course is going to focus on how
to add analytics to your mobile app.
Okay, so take a look around the Admin
Dashboard, switch to the reporting
dashboard, investigate some of
the options, go to the Home tab.
What do you see there?
Feel free to set your preferences,
uncheck everything, check them all,
as you like.
What about the Customization tab?
Again, I don't want you to necessarily
understand everything you're seeing.
I want you to learn how to navigate
through the different tabs.
And how to get back to
the Admin Dashboard.
When you've done some investigating,
take this quiz.
Which dashboard do you use to do what?