We need to add some code to the table
view, so that photo messages appear.
Here's what the FCViewController
cellForRowAt indexPath function looks
like right now.
Again, it only looks for name and
text, but not for our URL.
So let's remove some of our
existing code and start fresh.
Our first step is to add
code that handles messages
when they include an image URL key.
If the message snapshot
contains an image URL,
then we assign its value to
a variable called imageUrl.
With the URL we can use the Firebase
storage to create a reference to that
particular image.
And then with this
function call to data,
we can download the image
with its maximum size.
And by the way, I apologize if I've
been swapping between image and photo.
I'm just using them interchangeably.
Now this function takes a closure
with the data and error.
We'll go ahead and
get the error check out of the way and
then we're ready to display our image.
We can create an image from the data.
Then we can set the cell's imageView to
display the image that we've created.
Now if no image URL is found,
that's not a problem.
In that case we can safely assume
that it's a text message and
we can use an else block to configure
the cell like we've done before.
All right,
now I'm going to run the app and
see if the photo message
I sent earlier shows up.
And there's our photo.