It's worth pointing out that the Android
framework knows that overdraw is
a problem, and will go out of its
way to avoid drawing UI widgets that
may be invisible in the final image.
This type of optimization,
called clipping,
is highly important to UI performance.
If you can determine an object
will be fully obscured,
there's no reason to
go about drawing it.
In fact this is actually one of the most
important performance optimizations that
Android performs.
But sadly this technique doesn't
extend itself to complex custom views,
where you're overriding
the canvas dot on draw method.
In these cases, the underlying
system doesn't have insight into
how you're drawing your content,
which makes it really hard for
it to remove hidden views
from your rendering pipeline.
For example, in this stack of cards,only
the top card is fully visible and
the rest of the cards are mostly hidden,
which means that drawing all
of those overlapping pixels
is wasted processing time.
To address this problem,
the canvas class is equipped with
a few special methods that you can
use to tell the Android framework
what parts of the canvas are hidden and
don't need to be drawn.
The most useful method is canvas dot
clipRect, which allows you to define
the drawable boundaries for
a given view, meaning that if
any canvas drawing happens outside
these boundaries, it'll be ignored.
This could be really helpful when
you've got this type of staggered view,
like our cards for example.
If you know how much of your
custom view is visible, or
rather you know how much is obscured,
you can define the clipRect boundaries,
which will prevent any drawing from
happening in the obscured areas.
Now the clipRect API helps the system
know what to avoid drawing.
But it would also be helpful for your
custom view to do some of this work on
its own, ahead of time for example, it
would be really helpful if you knew what
you were going to draw if it's actually
outside of the clipping rectangle.
Fortunately, you don't have to figure
out all that intersection logic
yourself, the canvas.quickReject method
tests whether a given area is completely
outside the clipping rectangle, in which
case you can skip all that drawing work.
Now let's take a look at a common
situation where this happens and
take a swing at fixing it.