One issue with the delay based spinlocks
is how to pick a good delay value.
Two basic strategies make sense.
Static delay and a dynamic delay.
For static delay, we can use
some fixed information like for
instance the CPU ID,
where the process is running.
In order to determine
a delay that will be used for
any single process that ends up
running on that particular CPU.
The benefits of this is that it's
a simple approach, and under high loads,
likely this static delays will
sort of nicely spread out
all of the atomic references so
that there's no contention.
Clearly, the delay will have to be
a combination of something that
combines this fixed information and
the length of the critical section.
So that one process is delayed
one times the critical section,
another process is delayed twice
the critical section and so forth.
The problem is that this will create
unnecessary delay under low contention.
So what if we have two processes?
The first process is running
on CPU with an ID one.
The second process is running
on a CPU with an ID 32, and so
they're the only two that are contending
for the spin lock, and yet the second
process that's running on the CPU with
ID 32 will be delayed substantially,
regardless of the fact that there
is no contention for the lock.
So to avoid this issue, a more popular
approach is use dynamic delay and
that they named the delay such that
each process will pick a random delay
value based on the current perception
of the contention in the system.
The idea is that the system is
operating in a mode of low contention
then it will choose dynamic delay
value that's within a smaller range.
So it will back off just for
a little bit,
it will delay just for a little bit.
And if the system is opening
in a mode of large contention,
then this delay range
will be much larger.
So with the random selection, some
processes will back off a little bit.
They'll delay a little bit.
Whereas other processes will back off,
they will delay for quite a bit of time.
Theoretically both of these approaches
under high load will result into
the same kind of behaviors.
So dynamic will at high load will
tend to be equivalent to
the static delay based approach.
The key question is, however,
in this Dynamic Delay is
how do we know how much contention
is there in the system?
That's why we put here
the term perceived.
We don't know exactly what is
the contention in the system.
So each of the processes,
the implementation of the spinlock.
Somehow has to infer whether the system
is operating in low or high contention,
so that it can pick
an appropriate delay.
So a good metric to
estimate the contention,
is to track the number of
failed test and set operations.
If a test and set operation fails,
the more likely it is that there
is a higher degree of contention.
The problem with this, however, is if
we're delaying after every single log
reference, then our delay will
keep growing based on both
whether there is indeed contention in
the system, or if simply the owner
of the critical section is delayed or if
it's executing a long, critical section.
So then we may end up with
the same situation as before.
Just because somebody was executing
a long, critical section while holding
the spin log, that doesn't mean
that we need to bump up the delay.
So we need to be able to
guard against this case.