Lost card is hopefully is not as
big a problem because there's still
a PIN, isn't it.
So just because they have a card,
you lose it, the PIN still protects you.
Cloning of cards is hard because
of the chip that we have is in it.
And the way it works, obviously, in the
old days all you had to do, the credit
card number was encoded in a magnetic
strip that was very easy to clone.
But these chip-based cards, cloning
is harder, so that's not a weakness.
The third option is what this link, or
the story, or the paper I mentioned.
The protocol actually is
implemented had some problems.
Supposed to generate random numbers and
answers in each transaction.
Supposed to have random nonce but
the implementation had some flaws,
because of which, it didn't do that.
And those could be exploited.
So this is really
an Implementation issue,
in the protocol, that is based
on this chip and pin cards.
And that is the weakness that we
are exploring in this question.