Since we've been talking
about the animator recently,
why don't we take a look at how we can
actually use it in scripts we build.
To get started, we should take a look
at the animator Unity documentation.
There are a lot of methods here.
But the one's that I want to mention
are StopPlayback and StartPlayback.
With the Booleans we created last time,
these methods are perfect for
starting and stopping an animation,
like our sun rotating.
We've actually gone ahead and
created a simple animator that
you can use to rotate your sun.
Let's apply the animator to our sun and
then jump back into our script.
The first we want to do is
create a variable that we can
use to reference our animator.
Let's call it sunRotationAnimation.
Once we do that, all we need to
do is replace our Slerp code
with sunRotationAnimation.stopPlayback.
Then in start,
we actually need to call startPlayback.
And with that we're all set up.
Now before we leave this script,
I want to mention that.
Built in to MonoDevelop is an auto
completion feature that enables us to
not only complete our code.
But, also allows us to
find methods we might need
without searching the documentation.
Let's practice this really quickly.
In our animator we've added a Boolean
parameter that when set to true
will turn that directional light red.
Instead of going back
to the documentation,
let's see if we can find
a method to set a Boolean.
In activate rotation let's
type sunRotationAnimation.
This'll bring up
the auto-complete possibilities.
Since we're looking to set a bool,
let's start typing set.
This'll bring up all the options
that have set in the name.
And at the top we see
that we have set bool.
Once we click on it,
we auto complete that method name.
The parameters we need to provide are
the name of the boolean, which is called
changeColor and it's value that
we want to set, which is true.
Once we do that we can hop back into
the Unity editor, click on our sun and
apply the animator component and
then let's go ahead and hit Play.
Now if we simulate the trigger, we'll
see that our sun starts to rotate and
then our light also turns to a nice red.
And that was the simple magic trick
we did in the apartment scene to
activate our animations back then.
Cool, right?
[BLANK_AUDIO]