Next question is where do these trees come from?
And the answer is that trees come from grammars, and a grammar is a list of rules.
Rules have a left-hand side where we say a sentence, and a right-hand side, where we say a sentence can be written as
a noun phrase followed by a verb phrase. And so that's like making a small tree.
Saying the top of the tree is the S node, and the daughter nodes are the nP and the bP.
Then we can say that a noun phrase can be a noun all by itself, like raises,
or can be a new category that we haven't seen yet, called a determiner, like "the" or "a" followed by a noun,
like "the raises," and this vertical bar means "or." So this is saying we have two possibilities--a noun phrase can either be a noun
or a determiner followed by a noun. But there are other possibilities as well.
It might be a noun followed by a noun, like interest rates.
Or we can even have something like mortgage interest rates, which is a three-noun combination,
and there are many more, and we could have a internal structure here as well.
But I just wanted to give some of the ideas of some of the possibilities.
A verb phrase can be a verb followed by a noun phrase. So the verb "raises" and the noun phrase, the object,
"raises interest rates," or it could be a intransitive verb, the verb all by itself.
Or it could be a verb with a direct object and an indirect object. So, like, "Give me the money."
And that's all we're going to put in our grammar right now in terms of higher-level categories,
nodes that are up higher in the tree. And then we'll have the terminal categories or lexical categories,
categories that define classes of words. And we have three here: noun, verb and determiner.
And so the noun can be "interest" or "Fed" or "rates" or "raises." And a verb can be, again,
"interest" or "rates" or "raises." And the determiner can be "the" or "a." And so this is a tiny little grammar
that takes care of the sentence we showed, and maybe a few others.
Even with this grammar, some of the problems that show up in larger grammars is evident.
One of the problems is a problem of ambiguity. As we saw before, a single sentence but four words had at least two possible parses.
And what I want to ask you now is how many parses do each of these sentences have?
So, "The Fed raises interest rates." Tell me how many parses. If there are none, according to this grammar, put in a zero.
If there's one unique parse, put in one. And if it's ambiguous with two or more, put in that number.
"The Fed raises raises," or "raises raises interest raises."
Each of those tell me how many parses there are. Don't use your intuition or your knowledge of English,
but rather give me the answer according to exactly this grammar and nothing else.