That ends the lesson on stereo geometry.
The idea is that, if you have calibrated cameras,
if you know the match, then you could compute the depth.
So, this has been sort of general.
The only math that we did was the relationship between disparity and depth.
In the next lesson,
what we'll do is we'll focus on actually finding the disparity.
Figuring out which point in one image matches which point in the other image.
And that's what you're going to be doing in your problem set.
Then we're going to work on calibration which is determining the relative views.
And by the way, you're going to do that in a different problem set.
But, we're going to break these down one at a time.
That's it.