Let's move on to a different kind
of machine learning problem.
This time, I would like you to design
a plagiarism detection system.
So imagine students
are writing in essays and
submitting them as plain text files.
For a particular assignment,
you're job is to find pairs of
essays that look too similar.
By too similar I mean they've
used a lot of common words,
a lot of common language,
and try to flag them.
How would you approach this problem?
How would you process the data?
What machine learning
algorithm would you apply?
Can you describe that pipeline?
>> Sure thing.
So in order to detect plagiarism,
I want to analyze the similarity
between any two sets of documents.
So for me a technique that
I think would work is using
the cosine similarity
between the documents.
>> Okay.
>> In order to go about doing that,
I would use a tf-idf method
on all the documents in order
to basically vectorize
each one of my documents.
>> Okay.
>> Using that technique I could
find the cosine similarity
between all the documents.
And if I see a very high similarity
between any two documents I can flag
them and
maybe do some further analysis or.
>> Okay, so
let me understand the conversion from
document to vector part a little better.
So you said you're using
the tf-idf method.
I understand that
the input is a document or
a set of documents, what is the output?
What do the vectors look like?
>> Okay, so the tf-idf method
will basically just count
up the number of words and
generate a frequency for each word.
So documents that have the same
frequency of certain words
will have a higher cosine similarity.
>> Mm, okay, so
each element in the vector is
a frequency of a particular word?
>> Yes, that's correct.
>> Okay,
I'm concerned that in some cases,
two essays that have the same
counter frequencies of words but
had completely different language
could be judged as being too similar.
Is there anything you
can do to resolve that?
>> That's a good point
that I didn't think of.
So if I want to go a little deeper,
maybe I could look for
n-grams which are series of words
that appear multiple times.
So instead of doing the frequency
of each word, I would look for
the frequency of certain n-grams
to see if two essays used
the same string of words of a certain
length and if that popped up more often.
I think that would give me
a better representation
of the document similarity to see if the
same sentences are being used multiple
times across documents.
>> That's very interesting.
That's a very effective
approach I think.
It captures the context
in which words appear,
I think that'll be pretty effective.
Can you think of any other
methods to improve this further?
>> Maybe if I used,
implemented some sort of natural
language processing I
could dig even further and
find very similar sentence structure.
Maybe that might be able to even pull
out things where a student changed one
word in a sentence but
the structure of the rest of
the sentence looks identical.
And using natural language processing,
I might be able to pull out
different patterns that maybe with
a cosine similarity, or
an n-gram vector, might overlook.
>> Very, very interesting point,
yeah, that's a good approach.
I think it's a very good answer.
>> Thank you.