Can you compute these quantities for me?
>> Sure so
I gotta find the max a of f of a, so
I just have to find the maximum
value for f and that is 9.
Happens to be a2.
>> That's right happens to be a2.
>> And he maximum value for
g is 8 which is at about a3 and a5.
Good, all right so
then what goes in this box?
>> 9 minus 8 which is 1.
>> The absolute value of 9
minus 8 which is also 1.
>> Yes, that's amazing.
>> And the other box?
>> So that requires a little bit more,
I have to figure out what the maximum
absolute difference is for each a.
So I'm just going to do that.
I'm going to start at a1.
So 7 minus 5 is 2.
9 minus 3 is 6, 1 minus 8 is 7, for
the purposes of this discussion.
>> It's absolute value, it's fine.
>> It's absolute value.
>> 0 minus1 is 1, 6 minus 8 is 2,
3 minus 5 is 2, and -2 minus 5 is 7.
>> Good.
>> And
let's see the maximum value there is 7.
>> All right.
And just to make sure is 1 less than or
equal to 7?
>> Most days.
>> There we go.
All right so good, so we verified
that this theorem at least holds for
this one example that I
kind of made up at random.
>> Well and then we just simply use,
just simply say it's true for
one example.
It's true for two examples,
and then we're done, right?
>> This is, what, induction?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, I don't think we can do that.
I think we actually have
to do it by deduction.
>> Ugh, okay.