It turns out there's only one value that makes this equation true. And it's
positive 12. Great algebra skills for getting this one correct. Now if you
didn't get this solution, that's okay. Math can be pretty tough. So, let's
figure out how to do this together. First, we want to subtract 9 from both
sides, to isolate this radical. Next we'll square both sides to undo this
radical, or square root. So, I have x squared minus 18 x plus 81 on the left,
and x minus 3 on the right. We subtract x from both sides and add 3 to both
sides to get 0 on the right and this expression on the left. Now we want to
find factors of 84 that add to negative 19. This factor pair would be negative
12 and negative 7. It's pretty tough to find, so this might have been where you
got stuck. The easiest way to find the factor pairs of 84 is to start with 1
and 84. Then you can just go up to the next number to see if it divides in
evenly into 84. I know 84 is even so 2 does go into it. We can try each of the
numbers going up and then we can see that 7 and 12 would be the factor pair
that we need. They add to positive 19 so they must both be negative if they are
going to add to negative 19 and multiply to positive 84... This is how we know
this must be our factor pair. Next, we can set each factor equal to 0 and solve
for x. So, x could equal 12 or x could equal positive 7. Now, keep in mind that
we need to check these solutions. We took the square of both sides, so we
might've picked up a root that won't work in the original radical equation.
When we check x equals 12 we get 12 equal to 12 so yes, this answer does check.
But on the right side with x equals 7 we don't get an answer that checks. We'll
have 7 equal to 11 which we know isn't true. So, we remove 7 from our solution
set leaving us with just positive 12.