So by now,
you're probably starting to get
the hang of what the Uri matcher does.
Let me give you the formal
definition of what it is.
And it said the URI matcher matches
an URI with an integer code.
And this means it helps us ensure the
content provider doesn't have to handle
unexpected content URIs such
as this gibberish right here.
So there are two steps that we'll need
to implement to use the URI matcher
in a ContentProvider.
So first step is to setup the UriMatcher
with the URI patterns your
ContentProvider will accept and then
assign each pattern an integer code.
Secondly, we'll need to call
the UriMatcher.match method,
passing in a URI.
And this will return
the corresponding integer code.
That is if it matches a valid pattern.
And if not,
well it's going to tell us so.
So let's see an example of those two
subs implemented in our contacts
example.
So in the contacts provider,
this is what the code will look like.
So assume that the UriMatcher was
already declared as a global variable
which we've called here sUriMatcher.
Well on that we can call addURI and
the pass in the URI
which will be comprised of the
Contract.Authority and slash contacts
slash path and then the integer code
which is the constant contacts here.
So assume that these integer constants
where early declared as global
variables as well.
And then we'll repeat the same thing
down below here for the other pattern.
And here's step 2 of how we'll
call the UriMatcher.match method.
So then later in the query method for
example, we'll want to make use of
the UriMatcher by calling
UriMatcher.match such as we do here.
The return value of this method is
an integer that we store in a variable
called match.
So if the value of match is
equal to any of these constants
then we'll act accordingly.
For example,
If the value returned matches CONTACTS,
then we act on the contacts table.
If the value of match is equal
to the CONTACT_ID variable,
then we act on a single
contact in the table.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And the last case, is that, if it
doesn't match anything up above here,
we also check for that, and
handle it accordingly down here.
Now notice that we've used if and
else if statements to handle
these matching validations.
Well a more common way to do it,
is to express the syntax using
switch case statements instead.
So we learned about switch case
statements earlier in the networking
course when building out
the quick report app.
And basically, a switch case schema
is useful when we fork off into
different behaviors for different cases
based on the value of a single variable,
which in this case is
our match variable.
So if the value of
match equals CONTACTS,
then we'll fall into this case.
If the value of match matches
the CONTACTS_ID variable,
then we'll fall into this next case.
However if the match variable doesn't
equal any of these above cases,
we'll fall into this default case,
which we technically treat as
no match was found meaning
that the URI is not valid.
Now to see where we would add
those code snippets I just covered
in the context of
an existing provider class,
let's hop over into this
Android documentation site.
So here I'm in an article called
Creating a Content Provider.
And I want to head over to this
section called Designing Content URIs.
So down here we've actually covered
all of this information already.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And so let's take a look at
this example ContentProvider.
So here assume we have an example
ContentProvider with these URIs that
point to different tables.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And let's take a look at the code
snippet here of how how to add these URI
patterns to the UriMatcher.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now, in the example
provider class up here,
we extend from ContentProvider class.
Then we're going to define
the UriMatcher global
variable which we see
here called sUriMatcher.
So it starts with the lower
case letter s because it's
denoting that it's a static variable.
Then next in this static block here,
these two lines of code will be
executed to setup the global variable.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So we'll add these two URIs.
So the first line of code here
calls sUriMatcher.addURI and
passes in the content authority
which is com.example.app.provider.
In the path is table3.
And then we also give it
an integer code of 1.
So, the second line here,
calls sUriMatcher.addURI and
passes in the same content authority
we had up here, as well as the path.
In this case, we'll have table3/#,
meaning we're interested in
a specific row in this table.
And then we're going to give this
whole URI and integer code of 2.
So this first URI pattern represents
the whole table 3 table database.
So the second URI pattern here
focuses on just a single row
of the table 3 database table.
And we do that by adding
this /# at the end.
So with that example situation
I want you to go ahead and
set up the UriMatcher
in your PetProvider.
And here's some initial
code to get you started.
So within the PetProvider.java file,
we define the class and extend
ContentProvider, which you already have.
Then we're going to define constant
integer values by using the static
final modifiers and
we call them PETS and PET_ID cases, and
these will map to the integer
codes 100 and 101 respectively.
Next we are going to define
a UriMatcher as a global variable for
the PerProvider class.
And after which, we can actually
add URI patterns to this Matcher.
So this code snippet is provided as a
gist down below for you to build off of.
And what I want you to do is to
go ahead and fill in these blanks
to help build out the URI patterns
in order to add them to our Matcher.