Great job so far.
You now know how to extract
visual features from an image,
you've trained a classifier to identify
cars, you've used that classifier to
detect cars in different locations in
an image, and you've addressed several
issues along the way, including false
positives and multiple defections.
Now all that remains is to come up with
a way to track detected vehicles through
a video screen, this will allow you to
analyze the motion of the other cars and
avoid any potential collisions.
While you could treat each frame
of video as an independent image,
you can devise a much more efficient and
robust tracking pipeline
by utilizing what you know about one
frame when processing the next one.