So earlier, when I said
the CursorAdapter contains instructions
on how to make a list item view,
well, what exactly does that entail?
Well, let's dive in and
explore this area in more detail.
So let's assume that the list
view just requested for
the list item at position 0.
So now the CursorAdapter needs to
first create a blank list item.
And this involves inflating
one from the XML layout.
The layout that we want contains
a vertical linear layout
with two text views,
one that looks like this.
Then we'll need to populate
these two text views
with the correct data from the Cursor.
So, since we're interested
in the pet at position 0,
we'll move the Cursor to row 0.
And then we extract out the name column,
which turns out to be Tommy, and
set that to the first text view.
Afterwards, we'll extract
the breed column, and
get the breed to be Pomeranian, and
set that to our second text view.
Now on the list view request for
the list item at position 1, we'll also
need to create another blank list item.
Then we'll also move
the Cursor to position 1.
And then again bind the data
from this Cursor onto the views.
So, say we have a name of Garfield and
a breed of Tabby.
So, in code these two steps can
be separated into two methods.
First, the newView() method, and
then, the bindView() method.
So, the CursorAdapter class is actually
is actually an abstract class,
which means that not all
the methods are complete.
And that also means that we need
to create our own custom class.
So, for example,
we can call it PetCursorAdapter, and
extend that from
the CursorAdapter class.
Then we'll need to write code
that implements a logic for
the newView() and bindView() methods.
So sometimes, the newView()
method might not even be called.
And in those cases, the bindView()
method is called using an old view for
a previous pet.
For example, the user made have scrolled
the Tommy list item view off the screen,
and that means we can recycle that
list item view, and use it for
another pet in this list that is
about to be scrolled onto the screen.
So, we set different values
onto these text views, and
then, show this view on screen again.
And so, that's why it's useful
to have a newView() and
bindView() method be
two separate methods.
So, in our case,
we're going to be creating a class
called the PetCursorAdapter class,
which I kind of mentioned before, will
extend from the CursorAdapter class.
Notice that it contains a constructor,
which has caused the super class
constructor in order
to initialize itself.
Then, we as developers need to
fill in the NewView method,
which creates and
returns a blank new list item for
the current row being
pointed to by the Cursor.
And we also need to fill
in the bindView method,
in order to read data in
the current row in the Cursor, and
set it to the views within
this list item view.
So, the CursorAdapater class
handles some of the logic for
us, such as moving the Cursor
to the correct position.
So, we don't need to move
the Cursor to the correct position
within these two methods.
So, to show you an example of
a fully implemented CursorAdapter,
let's take a look at an online tutorial.
So, this tutorial is from CodePath and
explains how to populate
a ListView with a CursorAdapter.
So the goal of the example
that will be shown below
is to show a to-do list
in the Adapter view.
So, in this situation, the Adapter
view is a list view, and it's using
the Adapter to pull information from
a data source, which will be a cursor.
So let's assume that
the cursor looks like this.
So each to-do item has a body for
the task description,
as well as a numerical priority.
So start, we need to find
what a list item looks like.
So, we create a list item layout,
which here is referred to as a template,
in order to display a single to-do item.
We define the layout in a file
called item_todo.xml, and
this is defined within
the res/layout folder.
Now the convention has used the word
item in the file name itself
to indicate that it's a layout for
a single list item.
Now, in the XML file,
we can see that this list item layout
consists of a horizontal linear layout.
So, this outer view out here which
contains two text views, so one for
the body, and then one for the priority.
So, here's a screenshot of what
the app will eventually look like.
We see that each list item, so
each row here, shows the task body and
the priority.
Now, to make all this work,
we need to find a custom CursorAdapter,
which we're going to
call TodoCursorAdapter.
And this adapter will be responsible for
changing each todoCursor into a list
item view, using the item to do template
layout that we created in the file.
So now, let's take a look at the code
with a todoCursorAdapter class.
So, we'll scroll down here to
the Defining the Adapter section.
So, we notice that the TodoCursorAdapter
extends from the framework class
CursorAdapter.
And notice there are two important
methods that are required to be
implemented, the newView method and
the bindView method.
So, the newView method inflates,
which means that it creates a new list
item view object from our XML file.
So our item_todo XML file.
So the listView item it
creates is blank, and
it doesn't contain information
about the to-do item just yet.
Doing so
will be the job of the bindView method.
Instead the newView method returns
a blank list item as its return value.
And, with that, we're done
setting up the newView method.
So, the bindView method actually
takes the data from the cursor,
and then assigns it to the text
views within the list item view.
Now, notice that a cursor,
and a list set, and
view are passed into
the bindView method.
So, the view is the list set and
view, which is generated
from our newView method.
And the cursor is a cursor that's
pointing to a particular row you're
interested in making a view for.
So, for example, it might be
pointing at this row up here, so
the Get milk body with
a priority of two.
Now back down to the bindView method.
So the first thing you want to do in
this code is to find the two test views,
using the findViewByID method.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And into it we pass the view IDs.
>From there we have the references
to our two text view objects.
Next, we want to get the value
of the priority and the body for
the current row from the cursor,
so these two lines.
After that, we take the text
views that we got up here,
and then set their text to
the values of the priority and
body from the cursor, so
these two lines here.
So, after that, we have our
CursorAdapter, list item layout, and
listView all set up, and
now we need to hook them all together.
So, let's scroll down here
to the Attaching the Adapter
to a ListView section.
So, doing so
will be done in the activity class.
And usually, we set it up in the UI,
usually in the onCreate method.
So, attaching the adapter to
the ListView requires these three steps.
So first, we need to get
a reference of the ListView, and
you need to have a ListView as part
of the layout for your activity.
Next, we need to create a new adapter
by calling the TodoAdapter constructor,
and then passing in
the current activity context,
which we reference with this as well as
the cursor containing the to-do items.
And then finally,
we set the adapter on to the ListView so
they can begin populating it
with this line here, setAdapter.
Now it's your turn to do the same for
the Pets app.
So first thing we need to do
is to create a new layout file
called list_item.xml for
the list item layout.
And since you're already familiar with
creating layouts, I went ahead and
defined the item layout for
you in the code gist linked below.
And that means you can just copy and
paste from there.
Afterwards, you need to create a new
PetCursorAdapter class, so the provided
gist also includes some starter code for
you as well for this task.
And be sure to fill the logic for the
newView() and the bindView() methods.
So once you're done with that, I want
you to modify the CatalogActivity, so
that you can hook all
the pieces up together.
Start by modifying
the activity_catalog.xml file
to include the a ListView instead
of the existing TextView.
Then, in the displayDatabaseInfo()
method of the CatalogActivity, you need
to setup a PetCursorAdapter using
the Cursor returned from the provider.
Remember to set the adapter
onto the ListView.
And at this time, you can also remove
all code related to displaying any pet
information in the TextView.
Can you use some help?
Feel free to reference the tutorial,
which we've linked down below.