When a user logs in with email and
password, you make a user object.
Now, we also need to make those user
objects when they're logging in
with Google.
This might seem trivial, but it does
actually raise one good question about
how we deal with user creation flow.
Take my roommate Kagera.
She has a Gmail account, and
she also has a Google account.
When she creates an account with
this email it creates a new user.
So then what happens if she
logs in with her Google account
that's associated to
the same Gmail address?
Should it make a new user?
So I'm going to make a somewhat
executive call and say no.
In general I think it's safe to assume
that if they have an email with
the email password provider, and
they have the same email with the Google
provider that this in
fact the same user.
And because it's the same user they
probably don't want their data split up
into two different but
very similar accounts.
So, before I send over the spec,
quick question.
So what we want to do is be able to
associate a person's password email sign
in with a Google sign in,
if they're the same.
So given that, what should we use for
the key if we want to
associate these two accounts?
Here are some options,
what do you think?