The first step in implementing photo
messages is to handle uploading
photos to Firebase storage.
Just like we implemented the code for
sending and
receiving text messages, we'll start
by configuring the Firebase storage.
We'll do this by adding a call
to configure storage in
the SC view controller's signed
in status function, and we'll
want to add that call in the isSignedIn
block that we have highlighted here.
And here we've added the call.
The configure storage will look similar
to the configure database function.
We'll create a reference to
the location of our Firebase storage.
This line of code is surprisingly simple
because of the Google service info P
list file that we added to our project.
That P list contains all the information
necessary for this line of code to
determine the location of our storage
and create a reference to it.
And now that we have a reference
we can use it to add and
retrieve photos from storage.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The logical place for us to handle
adding photos to storage is when
an ImagePickerView has
finished selecting media.
If we scroll down in
the FCViewController Swift file you'll
find an extension to
the FCViewController that's focusing on
implementing the behavior after an image
picker has finished selecting media.
And here it is.
Assuming the image is selected,
we store the data about that image
in a constant called photoData.
And we use the UI JPEG
representation function to do this.
This function transforms the UI image
into JPEG data which is what we want for
storage.
Then, we call send photo message and
pass the photoData.
Finally, we dismiss
the image picker controller.
We also have this function for handling
if the user cancels out of the UI image
picker controller instead
of selecting a photo.
And here we also just
dismissed the view.
So once the image is chosen, we pass the
data to the sendPhotoMessage function.
Let's dive into that function..
Right now, it's empty, but
what we want to do is to
save our image to storage.
We'll start by building a path using
the folder name, chat_photos and
then the user's id and a timestamp.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Then, we can use Firebase Storage
metadata to set the content type for
the image to image/jpeg.
Finally, we create a child node
to hold the image path and
add the photo to storage using the
photoData and metadata as parameters.
This writes the photo
to Firebase Storage.
But if we want the photo message
to show up in the table view,
we also have to make sure to send
the image URL to the database.
Time to test our progress.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I'm going to tap on the camera,
and I'll select this photo.
But our photo doesn't
show up in the app.
Well, that's because we
haven't added that functionality
to the table view just yet.
It only knows how to
display messages with text.
But we can go back to Firebase console
to see if the photo message appeared in
storage.
Yep, here it is.
Right now it's sort of like
a message in a bottle.
We send it out but it's just floating,
waiting to be received.
We need to turn this photo into
a message that can be read in the app.
And if we look in the database we
can see that this image has been
added with the key image URL.
Now, we just need to figure
out a way to display it.
Let's tackle that next.