You should by now see that this
parallelization of a matrix spectrum
multiply has work that is O of n
squared, and is span that is O of n.
So the average available parallelism is
O of n, and that seems pretty good, but
I claim you can actually do better.
Essentially the trick is to
recognize that this innermost for
loop is nothing more than a reduction.
So here's some pseudo code
that embodies this idea.
Uses a temporary array of length n.
It uses the temporary array to
store the intermediate products,
which are all computed in one
shot using a parallel form.
And then finally,
we reduce the temporary array,
getting a single value which
we accumulated to y sub i.
Now, for this to work, you're going to
have to assume that this temporary array
is private to each iteration of i.
So that's a little bit of a problem,
because there could be a blow
up in intermediate storage.
But for
now lets just ignore that possibility.
Now my question to you is
which of the following options
best expresses the span
of this implementation?
Your options are logged in,
logged squared in, logged cubed in.