Okay. Well, here is a quiz for you to test your knowledge of these different
diagram types. In column one I have the names of the diagrams,
in column two I have some definitions, and I'd like you to match them together.
As a review that particular diagram types of the class diagram,
the composite structure, the component diagram, deployment diagram,
object diagram, package diagram, and profile diagram.
And then the definitions are in the right column. The static structure at
a particular time. The organization of physical software components.
Three is the logical groupings and dependencies. Four is the components and
structural properties. Five extensions to the UML metal model. Six internal
structure and possible interactions. And the seventh choice is the physical
system resources and how they map to the hardware. Try to match those together.