There is one last promise method
that you should learn to use,
and that is .all.
.All takes an array of promises,
it executes them, and
then it returns an array of values in
the same order as the original promises.
.All fails fast, in that it will
reject as soon as the first
promise rejects, without waiting for
the rest of the promises to settle.
This means that even if one
of the promises rejects,
the whole .all rejects.
But once ever promise has resolved,
then the next in the chain
gets the array of values.
For this quiz, I want you to refactor
this code from the previous quiz,
using .all.
When you do it correctly, of course you
should see the thumbnails show up and
you should also see
parallel network requests.
Check the instructor notes for
more information, and good luck.