So, the first question says,
does the use of stack canary prevent
return-to-libc buffer overflow attacks?
Remember return-to-libc
buffer overflow relies on
the ability to rewrite the return
address in the stack frame.
We rewrite it with the address
of a library function that we
returning to a library function.
But we have to write or
modify that return address.
And we said the use of a stack
canary is to detect if
the return address on
the stack has been modified.
Because when that gets modified,
the canary value is going to
be modified as well.
So the answer here should be the yes,
because a stack canary does
allow you to detect change or
modification to the return address,
so that's why the answer is yes.
Second question,
does ASLR protect against
read-only buffer overflow attacks?
Well, ASLR makes it hard to guess
where certain addresses of certain
variables are, so for example
a certain function in a library because
library starts at some random address.
When we talk about read-only
buffer overflow attacks,
we already have an address.
We start reading from that address and
then we keep going.
We overflow into whatever is after it.
So, we're not trying
to guess an address.
We have an address and reading starting
that and reading more than they should.
But there isn't a problem
that we have here of guessing
an address where we should start.
So because of that, ASLR does
not protect us against read-only
buffer overflows and
that's why the answer is no.
The last one is actually
read-only buffer overflow but
that's the open SSL
heartbleed vulnerability.
Can that be avoided with
a non-executable stack?
Non-executable stack remember, is
the code cannot be placed on the stack
because it can't be executed, it can't
fit instructions from the stack area.
The answer to this
particular question is no,
because the OpenSSL heartbleed
vulnerability read more data.
It didn't actually execute code.
The overflow was reading certain data
that was sensitive that it was not
suppose to the function was
not supposed to access it.
So, there's no execution.
We're not executing code to
get to the sensitive data, and
because of that it's had nothing
to do with non-executable stack.
So the vulnerability that overreads or
reads beyond the one that it's
supposed to, we can't prevent that or
make that go away just because
we have non-executable stack.
So here we talked about
a number of defenses and
where they work and
when they may not work.
And going back, write a secure code,
use a typeset language or
use a program in a language that
makes buffer overflows go away.
If you can do that,
you have to use a language where
that's a possibility then check input.
Use tools to look at potential places
where there may be a vulnerability.
And then hopefully, the system that
you're working on has defenses of
type such as ASLR for which you don't
need to do anything as a programmer.
Or things like stack protection where
you can't execute off the stack.