So we write that like this, all right?
So just as we said before,
we're going to maximize two divided by
the magnitude of W,
subject to the constraint,
we want to correctly classify
all the points, right?
So for
the positive X's where Y is plus one,
we want X dot W plus B to be
greater than or equal to one.
And if, XI is negative,
we want W dot, X dot W plus B
to be less than negative one.
All right?
So this is a standard, what's called
a quadratic optimization problem,
we want to sut, we want to minimize
this term that's over here, okay?
Because if you minimize the square of W,
then that's going to maximize
two over the norm of W.
Subject to a constraint, right?
Here's our constraints.
You'll notice that what we did
is by multiplying by the YI
we can say that this thing is always
greater than or equal to one, right?
because YI flips the sign, because YI is
positive when it's a positive example,
and YI is negative when it's a negative
example, so multiplying it through
keeps that constraint always
greater than or equal to one.
The solution to this, and I'm not
going to go through the solutions, but
it's sort of a standard
quadratic optimization and
some of the multipliers,
things like that, but what matters is,
is the form of the solution,
not how we got there.
It's just the linear sum for
W of some weights times,
and it's the YI times XI.
So, remember Yi sort of flips,
flips the sign.
All right?
And the XIs that you use
are the support vectors and
the alpha Is are these learned weights.
And another way of thinking
about it is that the weights,
you can think of that of alpha Is for
all of the XIs, but
they're only non-zero for
the support vectors.
Okay?
So when I, when I solve this,
I end up with a whole bunch of alpha Is,
most of which are zero.
But the alpha Is for
the support vectors are not zero.
Okay?
Well then I can just sort of substitute
in, we have this equation that for
any support vector W transpose X
plus B is equal to positive one or
negative one, depending upon the YI,
depending upon whether it's positive or
negative in this example.
So that can be written like this.
Remember the YIs are plus one or
minus one, depending upon the example.
So I can write,
just substitute in for W.
Okay, so I substitute in for
both B and for W.
Given this, we can now create
a classification function.
So remember, what we were doing
was we were drawing a line
W X plus B equals zero.
Everything on one side of the line we
were going to call positive everything
on the other side we were
going to call negative, right?
Our support vectors are out here
where that function equals one, but,
but if something's on the inside,
if it's greater than zero,
we'll call it positive, less than zero,
we'll call it negative.
So I'm going to build
a classification function,
which is right what it says here.
It says, okay, I'm just going to
take the sign of W dot X plus B.
Greater than zero,
I'll call it positive,
less than zero, I'll call it
negative I substitute in the, for
W this expression here, okay?
And take that sign, and if this
function, F of X is less than zero, I'll
call it negative, and if it's greater
than zero, I'll call it positive.
Okay?
So this all depends on you being
able to solve for those alphas, and
I'll tell you the support vector.
Machinery will do that.
And realize by solving for the alphas,
by finding some non zero alphas that's
selecting your support vectors.
Okay?
A critical, critical,
critical element of this equation
is that it only depends
on this dot product.
Okay?
It highlighted here in red,
I'll highlight it in red again.
The only thing I need to know is
the dot product between some new
point X and the support vectors XI, and
then I multiply it by the alpha,
sum them up, and build my classifier.
That dot product element, or
that dot product structure, is what
makes what we're about to do work.