Just behind a VR headset's lens,
you'll find one or
more high resolution OLED displays.
Sometimes those displays are embedded
inside the headset, like the Vive.
Other times,
you'll use your phone's display.
Like the Google Cardboard or
Samsung Gear VR.
First off, it’s very important for
these displays to have high resolution.
The magnifying properties of the lenses
make the display’s pixels much bigger
then when they’re viewed
with the naked eye.
According to Michael Abrash,
Oculus' chief scientist, we need around
16,000 by 16,000 pixels per eye
to have a completely sharp image.
For comparison, the Vive currently
has 1,080 by 1,200 pixels per eye.
And obviously, we have a long way to go
before VR displays are crisp
enough to look like photos.
For this reason, we want the highest
resolution possible for a VR display.
A second important component of
a modern VR display is something
called low persistence.
Low persistence means that instead of
showing you a full image, the display is
only showing you a portion of
the image in an moment in time.
It causes the display to
function like a rolling shutter.
Only showing your eye a moving
slice of the VR world.
Check out this video of
the Occulus DK2's low persistence mode,
filmed up close at 400
frames per second.
It almost looks like a strobe light,
doesn't it?
So why only show the slices of an image,
instead of the full frame?
Well, it's because low
persistence reduces and,
in many cases, eliminates motion blur.
This keeps the image clear
when you look around,
and it keeps it from smearing together.
The individual pixels in
a typical OLED display
don't change color fast enough
to eliminate motion blur.
Low persistence fixes that problem
by effectively hiding the pixels
while they change color.
This gives you sharp, consistent, and
a believable image when
you turn your head.
So behind almost every VR headsets
lenses, you'll find high resolution,
a led displays that
support low persistence.
Pretty cool, right?
So we've talked about lenses and
displays,
now let's look at tracking technology.