Okay, let's talk about
the options that we have here.
So it is true at the time this ad ran,
this is a few years ago, that vendor a,
its systems didn't have as many,
sort of, reported attacks as vendor b's.
Or maybe you can call this vendor a and
vendor m and
you can figure out who a is and
who m is.
So it's true that it didn't, but
both of the systems were running complex
rich operating systems that supported
similar kind of applications.
So both tried their best to meet
the requirements that we listed for
a trusted computing base.
So it's not quite true that one
vendor's operating system was
significantly more secure
than the other vendor.
Okay, let's look at the second one.
The second option says, the two
operating systems were similar as far as
security was concerned but
one was not as big a target.
So this is about threat modeling
that we're talking about.
Who is that coming off to you?
And it is too at that time vendor
a's systems were not as big a target
as vendor b's, because vendor b actually
had most of the market belonged to it.
So the attackers obviously were
going after these kind of systems,
and vendor b's system was a much
bigger target than vendor a's.
One reason was,
as we said, market shares.
So in this case, I'm going to say,
this is one of the reasons why the claim
that vendor a's systems didn't suffer
as much as vendor b's was true,
because vendor a's system was
not as big a target, okay?
So the last option says,
the more secure OS could be much
simpler than the other one, okay?
So this is our design principle for
secure systems.
So that's what I want
you to think about.
But I said both systems are actually
full faced operating systems.
They supported same kind
of applications and
neither one of them actually
we can say was much simpler.
By the way this used to
be an ad that Apple ran.
And the sickly system that suffered from
all the ailments was a Windows system.
So I gave it away