The answer for B is two again,
same as A.
Add three values, but one can be deducted
from the other two.
So it's three minus one equals two.
C is more difficult.
There's nine possible combinations for A and B.
And we multiply nine
by the possible outcomes of C,
but we observe that we only need two for the outcomes.
And not three by the same the logic,
that A and B had two.
So nine times two equals eighteen.
D is easier.
There's three different condition values for D.
And again for each of those we need two outcomes.
The third one can be deducted,
which makes it six.
E has three incoming arcs.
Three to the third is twenty-seven.
For E itself, for each of these cases,
we need two variables for the outcome.
Which makes fifty-four.
And finally, F is the same as D,
which is six.