Now let's talk about correspondence.
Again, similar idea to what we
talked about when we talked about
depth imaging.
Basically here I'm showing four
different images of the Trevi Fountain
taken completely under different
lighting conditions and
different scales.
If I run feature detection on it,
basically it would find
four features perhaps that are actually
on the head of the statue here.
Course what I'm interested in
making sure is that these features
are the same.
And of course, that basically is what
my correspondence is going to be.
After matching, within,
you know, thresholds and stuff,
it basically says this feature and
this feature are the same.
Similarly, it will do the same for
the next feature, and
of course, from there to the last one.
So in essence, now this says
is all features are the same.
And this will allow us to link
up pairwise matches to form
a connected graph of matches
across several images.
This image is connected to this.
And again, in the UI that was shown in
the video, you saw how that was used to
be able to kind of scale in and look at
different images at different locations.
I'll show you examples of that also.