Here we are back in our
ViewController.swift file
where we need to create two properties.
We'll declare the count and label
properties here at the class level,
setting count to 0 but
leaving the label undeclared for now.
Hm.
Looks like the compiler's complaining.
Let's see what it has to say.
Class ViewController
has no initializers.
So something's going on with the
initialization of these variables that
we just added.
Right now, this label property
has a non-optional type.
Let's see what happens when
we make it an optional.
Okay, that seems to please the compiler.
So what did I just do?
This exclamation point here indicates
an implicitly unwrapped optional.
We'll hear more about optionals and
conditionals in the upcoming
Swift session with Jason, but
the gist of it is that optional
properties can be nil and still compile.
In this case, our label
property is nil at compile time
because it hasn't been initialized yet.
You can see that the code also
compiles if we go ahead and
initialize the label
property when it's defined.
But we'll leave it as an optional for
now.
Okay.
We have our label property,
but we still need to set it.
With this line of code,
we're taking the object reference stored
in a local variable in ViewDidLoad and
giving that value a more
permanent home in our property.
It is this connection that will enable
our ViewController to set the label's
text when the button is clicked.
Now let's write the method that will
be called when the button is clicked.
Inside this method, we'll use
the two properties we just created
to increment the count and
then set the label's text.
Notice that we use this
self.label property
to reach out of the ViewController
object and modify the label.
It gives us an outlet to the label.
This is the reason properties
are called IBOutlets in storyboard.
Okay, now we're really close to
having a working click counter.
All that's left to do is get the button
to invoke this incrementCount method.