Jake, did you manage to get the HTML
working from a custom response?
>> I certainly did.
And here's how i did it.
Over in the service worker.
I'm going to add the a-winner-is-me
class to this bold element.
But the important bit is setting
the content type header.
To text HTML.
Now in the browser with force update
enabled I'll refresh the page and
it's being passed as HTML.
We can also see that
in the network panel.
It's important to note that at this
point we've created something that works
entirely offline first.
I'm going to disable
the force update settings so
we get the whole,
real user experience here.
Now if I bring the server down and
refresh the page, it still works.
Even if I switch to Lie-fi and
refresh the page.
It still works.
Instantly.
The network is completely untouched
when it comes to serving this content.
Of course, although it's offline
first it's a bit rubbish and useless.
Especially since we're responding
to every request in the same way.
In the next chapters we're going to
look at hijacking particular requests in
particular ways depending on information
in the request and the response.