Even the simplest of models can drastically improve the way we understand and
interact with systems.
Consider the following example, in the United States the EPA tries
to protect the American public by examining new compounds and
classifying them as toxic or nontoxic.
In the 1970s, a trained chemist would make the determination based on
chemical properties of the compound.
This process was slow and expensive.
So, the EPA started a project to see if you
could automate the classification of compounds with software instead.
The answer turned out to be a decisive yes.
A decision tree based model was able to algorithmically detect patterns in
the chemical properties that indicated toxicity.
Just like that.
A fast and inexpensive data driven model replaced an expensive and
difficult approach to solving the same problem.
You can find more information about this EPA project in the book linked in
the instructors notes.
>> Another interesting example is the field of advertising.
So originally, the advertising age was created by
Sigmund Freud's nephew Edward Bernays.
He used his uncle's theories of the mind to craft ways of
communicating with people.
In fact, in addition,
he was a pioneer of public relations as well as advertising.
See the instructor's notes to learn more about Bernays if you're curious.
Today, advertising looks like this.
Amazon sees what items you look at, collects the viewing and
buying history for you and other customers, and
recommends things that you are statistically likely to purchase.
Now this relies on models like collaborative filtering
to reveal patterns from data about buying habits among similar types of people.
Advertising using data-driven models is now one of
the primary sources of revenue for a lot of small and
large companies and is the focus of a lot of data scientists.