Great job on completing lesson two stage five.
In lesson two stage six, we've split the tweet topology from stage five into
individual files for spouts, bolts, and the tweet topology.
This structure is more typical of larger programs.
And this exercise is intended to give you practice searching for
required fields in your correct spout, bolt, and
topology class files to complete a real topology.
In part one, complete the tweet topology to attach the tweet spout
with the parallelism of one.
Attach the parse tweet bolt with a parallelism of 10 and the count bolt with
a parallelism of 15 and the report bolt with a parallelism of 1.
Remember to enter your Twitter OAuth credentials.
And finally, build and run your final topology.
Refer to your solution in lesson two stage five if necessary, but
try to solve the exercise without referring to your previous work.
Finally, refer to lesson three stage one if you need the solution.
Lastly, when you've completed your tweet topology and
it's running correctly why don't you post a screenshot or
video to the forum and comment or help out some of your fellow learners.
Good luck.