So let's expand the node at Pitesti,
we have to go down this direction,
up, then we reach a path we've seen
before then we go in this direction and
now we reach Bucharest which is
a goal and the H value is going to be
0 because we're at the goal and
the G value works out to 418.
Now again, we don't stop here just
because we put a path onto the frontier.
Rather we put it there,
we don't apply the goal test next.
Now we go back to the frontier and
it turns out that this 418 is
the lowest cost path on the frontier.
So now we pull it off, do the goal test,
and now we found our path
to the goal and it is in fact
the shortest possible path.
In this case A* was able to
find the lowest cost path.
Now the question,
which you'll have to think about because
we haven't explained it yet,
is whether A* will always do this.
Answer yes If you think A* will always
find the shortest cost path, or
answer no if you think it depends
on the particular problem given,
or answer no if you think it
depends on the particular
heuristic estimate function h.