So, we want to recreate a scale for
the x axis that maps values
from 250 to 100,000.
And keep in mind that we want to create
a log scale rather than a linear scale.
So, in order to do that, I'll bring
up my y axis scale code again, and
then make some changes.
So, first, I want to change my
y variable to the variable x.
I want to be careful that I don't
overwrite the scale that I just made.
And since the x scale
is a logarithmic scale,
we'll change the linear
function to a log function.
We have an input domain
of 250 to 100,000 and
that maps to a range
from 0 to 600 pixels.
Keep in mind that the range that we
want to map the data to corresponds to
the width of the entire svg element.
You need to switch the values here back
to their normal order because we want
the lowest input value to correspond
to the lowest output pixel value.
And similarly, we want the highest input
value to correspond to the highest
pixel output value.
Unlike the y axis,
the x axis starts at 0 at the origin and
then increases moving out to the right.
And finally,
I just want to check that my x axis
scale returns the correct values.
For an input of 250,
it should return 0 pixels.
And for an input of 100,000,
it should return 600 pixels.