The overarching theme in this module
is how to find what you're looking for
in images.
In previous lessons,
we've accomplished this task for
the most part using colors and
gradients.
Now that you're familiar with
some popular classifiers,
we're going to go deeper into
our exploration of colors and
gradients to see how you can locate and
classify objects in images.
>> Image classification is tricky.
And it becomes even trickier when you
don't know exactly where in an image
your objects of interest will appear or
what size they'll be or
even how many of them you might find.
Coming up, you'll focus on
the task of detecting vehicles and
images taken from a camera
mounted on the front of a car.
But the same principles apply to
pedestrian detection, or traffic sign
detection, or identifying any object
you might be looking for in an image.
>> In this lesson, you'll practice
searching for objects in images.
And you'll explore what features are the
most useful input for your classifier.
With those tools, you'll then work on
tracking vehicles in a video stream.