All right.
So that ends our conversation about
discriminative classification methods.
We've seen sort of the general
approach to finding a window and
somehow deciding that that window
is class A or class not A.
And we've talked about generative
methods which are not used nearly
as much for recognition,
and discriminative methods.
The ones we talked about
are boosting SVMs and
they have a deep history
in computer vision.
Recently other methods, and
we mentioned some of them have
become big computer vision.
But one that I think is really
being pushed on most these days
is what's called random forests.
And one of the reasons is they've become
they've been shown to be incredibly
effective for some problems that
people might not have thought.
Like labeling depth images as to
whether a point comes from an arm, or
a, a upper-arm or lower-arm.
A leg, a torso, etcetera.
And I'll tell you that's
actually how the Kinect
does its whole skeleton thing.
Maybe we'll talk about
that in a future lecture.
But random forces also, you actually
can write your own random forest code.
You might now want to because
the packages will work better.
But they're pretty easy to
understand what's going on.
So that's another method that has
become big in discrimination,
in discriminative learning.
I'll also end by saying, 15 years
ago when I was teaching computer
vision most of the students who took
computer vision had also taken graphics.
There was an interesting images and
things.
And so they were familiar with
things like Lambertian shading and
other sorts of models like that and
geometry.
Much less familiar with
things like feature vectors.
Now there's been a tremendous
shift because of the dominance
of machine learning in computer vision,
a lot of the students will take
a lot of machine learning along
with the computer vision.
That's one of the reasons why
I'm not going to go more into
things like how SVMs work boosting, etc.
Because if you really want to understand
that, there's such a wealth of stuff you
have to do that's actually
a whole other course.
In fact, machine learning
has grown that I think the,
the Udacity machine learning
course that I know about currently
is one flavor of machine learning,
and then there's others.
And in Computer Vision,
you're looking at the one's that
work on large feature vectors.
So, we're going to stop here with
recognition, and like I said,
if you want to do more,
you really want to do that in
the context of machine learning classes.