So, first step in trying to do any kind of panorama building is to
take pictures.
In the previous example I showed you,
that basically, the pictures were taken from left to right.
Of course, they could be right to left also.
So what it basically means,
is that I take these pictures by rotating the camera.
Of course, it's usually much better to actually rotate this
camera about the center axis.
This is just for demonstration purposes.
Let's look at it again.
One more time.
So basically an images are captured this way, and
of course want to be able to, do things like, identify the matches.
So if you noticed this image is offset quite a bit.
We want to align them all together.
All of the things here.
And then of course what we want to do is.
Merge and blend these images together.
We want to do of courses, align these images.
We noticed the structure here is offset.
Also these structures seem to have offsets.
You want to align these images together, and then blend and merge them.
Many different ways could be done.
This was of course me showcasing this by a handheld camera.
Which is how I actually took this image.
But these days you can use robotic cameras like this GigaPan camera,
which is on a robotic mount.
And it basically takes a picture, and moves in a controlled manner.
Takes a picture and moves in a controlled manner.
So this in essence shows how you can control the camera movement.
As part of the photography pipeline.
Or the computation photograph pipeline.