So here again, my input.
And that's my output.
Notice now that the eyes are merged, right?
And the hair is also kind of much more kind of a mixture here.
We still see a little bit of the Tigger ears.
But more of the hair of the Einstein image is now actually been put
on the Tigger head.
And you can see the frequency mixing is happening again much nicely.
This basically shows where some of the laplacian errors were.
I mean again, it accounted for
a lot of the high frequency information where the eyebrows are.
It did have a little bit of problems with the ears.
That's what showed up here.
And also near the edge of the mouth here which is showing up here.
But overall hopefully you'll see this is a much nicer blend than we
have actually see of these kinds of images so far.
And the secret was we actually counted for all of the frequency variations, and
put them again in the boat, the Laplacian, the Gaussian.
Up the scales, we were able to use this information.