Let;s talk briefly about
some of the pros and
cons of using third party
authentication and authorization.
If you use third party authentication,
authorization,
you don't have to think about how to
encrypt and store user passwords.
We can just let the OAuth
provider worry about that.
Another bonus is that,
users don't have to fill in another
form to create an account on your site.
Less friction for
signing up should hopefully lead to an
increased number of users on your site.
Also, it means that users don't have
to remember another password for
your site, and you don't have
to keep their password secure.
That means if your
site gets compromised,
you didn't just leak your users'
passwords to the attacker.
A neutral issue to point out is
that users need to have an account
on a third-party provider site
in order to log in to your site.
If they already have an account such as
Google or Facebook then that's great.
They can quickly be signed into
your app with just a few clicks.
But if they do not, then there's
an extra step of making an account
they may not be willing to go through
first before coming back to your site.
For this reason, you want to support
login via sites that are very popular
and already have a lot of users.
Having Google and
Facebook login is a good idea, and
can be beneficial to you and your users.
But it's important to make sure that
you're using all providers that
hopefully already cover a large
portion of your potential client base.
So there's a strong case for
using third-party
providers to store user credentials and
then use that for your own site.
But there are also some downsides
to this approach as well.
Maybe some of your users already
have a third-party account but
don't want to use that account on
your site for privacy concerns.
Most people don't like using apps
that could potentially post to their
social media networks on their behalf.
This is an important reason
to keep the OAuth scopes.
The resources you request
permission to access to a minimum.
And request access only to
things your app actually needs.
Just because you're authenticating with
Google doesn't mean that you have to
ask for permission to mess with all the
users Google resources and information.
And even though you can
authenticate with Facebook,
it would be a good practice
to let the user know you're
app does not have the authorization
to spam all of their friends.
If you're going to create a web app
that works completely offline, or
under intermittent internet connections,
a local authentication system
may be a better option.
The security for
most OAuth providers is pretty good, but
maybe it's not enough for
the application you're creating.
If you need the ability to
change the requirements for
password strength, or implement your
own form of two-factor authentication.
Then, third-party authentication
may not be the best option.
These are all cases where you might
consider creating your own OP system.
However, remember, that if you do decide
to do it yourself, you'll need to
address the many security challenges
to make sure that both your servers and
your user accounts
cannot be compromised.