[Thrun] This leads me to the general study of conditional independence in Bayes networks,
often called D-separation or reachability.
D-separation is best studied by so-called active triplets and inactive triplets
where active triplets render variables dependent
and inactive triplets render them independent.
Any chain of 3 variables like this makes the initial and final variable dependent
if all variables are unknown.
However, if the center variable is known--
that is, it's behind the conditioning bar--
then this variable and this variable become independent.
So if we have a structure like this and it's quote-unquote cut off
by a known variable in the middle, that separates or deseparates
the left variable from the right variable, and they become independent.
Similarly, any structure like this renders the left variable and the right variable dependent
unless the center variable is known,
in which case the left and right variable become independent.
Another active triplet now requires knowledge of a variable.
This is the explain away case.
If this variable is known for a Bayes network that converges into a single variable,
then this variable and this variable over here become dependent.
Contrast this with a case where all variables are unknown.
A situation like this means that this variable on the left or on the right are actually independent.
In a single final example, we also get dependence if we have the following situation:
a direct successor of a conversion variable is known.
So it is sufficient if a successor of this variable is known.
The variable itself does not have to be known,
and the reason is if you know this guy over here,
we get knowledge about this guy over here.
And by virtue of that, the case over here essentially applies.
If you look at those rules,
those rules allow you to determine for any Bayes network
whether variables are dependent or not dependent given the evidence you have.
If you color the nodes dark for which you do have evidence,
then you can use these rules to understand whether any 2 variables
are conditionally independent or not.
So let me ask you for this relatively complicated Bayes network the following questions.
Is F independent of A?
Is F independent of A given D?
Is F independent of A given G?
And is F independent of A given H?
Please mark your answers as you see fit.