Let me talk to you a little bit about
what's the underlying concept of
what makes video what it is.
And the whole concept comes through
some literature that actually comes from
psychology or understanding
of the human vision system.
Some of it is controversial and
not completely bought into.
But the idea really is what is
referred to as Persistence of Vision.
Our human vision system, when you
actually show it frames of something,
and if you could take those frames and,
basically, look through them very fast,
that is being able to change from one
frame to the other at certain frequency.
Our vision system
merges the information,
such that we actually
don't see any flicker.
And that's a large part of what
the whole concept of Persistence of
Vision is.
That our vision system, when shown
something at a certain refresh rate,
merges the information such that we
actually see motion that's flicker-free.
So, for example, here, this is very
classic example of a horse, and
this were bunch of pictures taken,
one by one, and
then basically put on top of each other
and that basically gives you the fact
that this horse is running
with the jockey on top.
Again these were individual images,
taken one at a time,
placed in front of the horse
as the horse was moving.
Again, they were lined up
at different locations.
And, now if you notice, by just aligning
them and being able to display them,
you basically see motion, and
a very continuous smooth motion.
Of course, in this case,
you might see a little bit of jerkiness.
So, in essence, the idea is, if you
give me a bunch of image frames, and
if they're captured in such that when we
can play them back at a rate somewhere
around 124th of a second, we will see
flicker-free appearance of motion.
And this is again a very
classic example from 1887,
by the way, of how this kind of
stuff was used to generate motion.
This another example of these birds
here is again showing motion of course.
They've been actually multi-exposed
into creating one frame
of all of that motion.
So this concept of Persistence
of Vision is, basically,
the foundational observation
of why we perceive video.
Again, video is a medium,
stacked frames of
continuous motion refreshed at
more that 124th of a second,
gives us an appearance of motion and
we don't see any flicker.
So this actually is also
the rationale behind building and
inventing video cameras.
We've talked a lot about cameras coming
up in the early 1800s, and some of
the earliest technologies of showcasing
frames of videos, including things like
zoetropes and stuff were in essence
about taking images and showing them to
you in a rate faster than our human
vision system can actually deal with.
And again that's one-24th of a second or
more, And when that happens,
we see complete flicker-free motion.
Again, examples of this are there.
And this is actually pretty much
the foundation of why people wanted to
invent cameras, video cameras,
that can capture these frames.
Some of the earliest work in this space
of pretty much building these ways of
kind of taking sequences, images and
then using that to understand motion,
and that's what he was interested in,
was done by Muybridge.
And in this case, in fact,
this video that you see of
the horse was done by him.
Basically, what he did was he used
stop-motion photographs to study
animal motion.
So, yes, this is,
in essence, stop-motion photographs,
photographs taken by a bunch of cameras
that basically fired as the horse
was moving in front of them.
And then, of course, using them to
generate this whole motion, and
a stabilized version of this.
Another person, who actually at the same
time frame as Muybridge, did work in
this, too, as well, is Marey, and he
developed a, basically a technique for
chronophotographie to capture motion,
and this example image is from him.
Both of them were pioneers and
actually had allot to do with the basic
concept of what video motion capture
that allowed us, in fact both of
them were interested in actually
understanding behaviors of animals and
people as they moved.
They started using cameras and
video cameras to support this.