All right.
Now, I'm going to make some simple
changes with a and b, right?
So, a is here and
a is just this quantity there and
b is here and
b is just this quantity there.
In which case, this whole expression,
I replace the a and b, keep going.
Again, a and b,
carry it forward here, here,
here what you'll notice
I've done is I took a here.
I added in the b there,
which ends up subtracting that there.
Keep going and
what you'll see is this expression
that says,
mu t plus our new belief after we've
taken our measurement
is just mu t minus.
What's mu t minus?
Mu t minus was the prediction and
then we have to change that prediction
a little bit and that prediction
is changed based upon two things.
The first thing is based
upon this difference here.
What's that difference?
That difference is the residual, right?
Y divided by m,
that's the measurement guess.
Right?
That's the measurement's guess of x.
Mu t minus was your prediction.
The difference between
them is the residual and
I multiply that by some factor k and
that k is called the Kalman Gain.
If my Kalman Gain was zero, then I
ignore my measurements all together and
I just go with my prediction.
Okay?
If my Kalman Gain was one,
let's see I put mu t minus t.
I ignore my predictions all together and
I just get my measurement.
And it's that Kalman Gain
that you're estimating
that goes between essentially zero
to one in the scaler case and
does something funkier in
the multidimensional case.
All right.
Let me show you that in a simple e,
example.
And this is going to be a constant
velocity model and what we mean by that
is we assume the velocity is constant,
except a little bit of noise.
So the state is two-dimensional,
it's the position and the velocity.
Right?
So, it's, I'm,
I'm moving in one dimension, but
my state is two-dimensional, because
it's the position and the velocity.
And now we're going to take
a look at this graph, all right?
So, in this graph, all right?
So we have time and position as
the things we're measuring and
the thing we're estimating.
The red line here is the state.
This, we happen to know was
the actual underlying state, okay?
How did we know this?
We booked a trip to Delphi, you know
where Delphi is, it's in Greece.
They have a thing there
called the oracle and
they also sell really good Baklava,
but that's beside the point and
you go to the oracle and
the oracle tells you the truth.
Okay?
It tells you if the Mets
will win the world series.
They always say no and they also tell
you the state, but the idea is that for,
for the points here,
I am just showing you the graph.
That is the actual state.
But
we also took some measurements, okay?
And the green dash lines, these
are the measurements we happen to get.
Now you'll notice,
pretty crummy measurements, right?
Life is the way life is.
This is the noise that we
actually happen to get.
The purple line here is
the corrected mean, okay?
And what you're seeing here is that
the mean is sort of being pulled,
the estimate, all right?
Is being pulled around by the
measurements, but you see that it tracks
the real state much better than
the measurements do, right?
because it's blending a prediction,
where it's estimating the velocity with
the ability to incorporate
the measurements.
If you want to take a look at the,
the error bars here a little bit,
one of the things that cool.
In fact, I'll look at just the last one.
Right?
This is the error bar of our prediction,
okay?
So remember, you see, it says, the
predicted mean, which is right there.
And after we did the common filtering
this was our new guess, all right?
And our error bars got smaller, okay?
So, again, this is what's happening
is we take a step, we get bigger.
We take a measurement,
we move and we get smaller.