Here's how I would have
answered the question.
I would have marked supply voltage,
clock frequency, and activity factor.
If you disagree,
let's duke it out in the forums.
Let's start with capacitance, C.
Why didn't I check it off?
Partly it's because I never really
understood what capacitance is.
Electricity and magnetism have always
been a bit of a weak point for me.
Curse you, Michael Faraday, with your
brilliant intellect, chiseled jaw,
haunting eyes and delicate,
albeit slightly sooty 19th
century industrial good looks.
Personally, I wouldn't pick capacitance
because it's a geometric and
electrical property of the materials
used to build the chip.
I don't normally think of controlling
that at the level of my algorithm
or software.
Though in the future, who knows.
Next, let's consider voltage and
frequency together since they're
supposed to vary together.
In fact, there's a feature of many
modern processors and memory systems for
changing these.
It's called Dynamic Voltage and
Frequency Scaling, or DVFS for short.
DVFS is typically controlled in
hardware, but there are some
processors and operating systems
that offer software level control.
In Linux, for instance,
there's something called cpufreq.
Speaking of freaks, look,
it's CPU Rick James!
She's CPU freaky.
[SOUND] Lastly,
there's the activity factor.
I've checked it off, but
it would be fair for
a hardware person to tell me I
have an overactive imagination.
Remember the activity factor is about
how frequently state transitions occur.
So if you know what at the algorithm or
software level that there are big chunks
of the processing system that you don't
need you might imagine
turning those chunks off.
For instance,
suppose you're doing a reduction.
Algorithmically, you know this
operation is mostly about
streaming the input data.
So, that implies there's
no reason to cash it.
Therefore, if the hardware gave
you a knob to turn the cash off,
you might do that.
Anyway, traditionally the topic
of the dynamic power equation is
one which mostly hardware and
low level software folks think about.
But, in the spirit of Danny Hillis's
question, I wanted to get you thinking
about whether there are interesting
algorithmic implications as well.