Okay, great.
So now you have Jenkins taking your
service all the way from your code base
to the borderlands of production.
But once you're there, how do you know
if your service is working right?
One of the principles of
DevOps is measurement.
That includes measuring how
effective our process is, but
it also includes measuring how
well our services are running.
What is it we want our service to do?
If it's a web server, well,
we want it to answer user queries,
we want it to be fast, we want it to
return actual results and not errors.
Measuring those things is what
service monitoring's for.
From an operations standpoint,
your service monitoring is a lot like
the instrumentation in
an airplane cockpit.
You know how an airplane
pilot can keep the plane on
course even when there's no visibility?
They need instruments even to tell
if the plane is in level flight or
if it's diving into a crash.
Or another way of thinking about
it is that service monitoring
is like a scientific instrument.
You can see things with a microscope or
a Geiger counter that you
can't see with your naked eye.
If there's dangerous bacteria in your
water supply, looking at a drop of water
with the microscope let's you know
what it is that's making people sick.
If you have dozens of servers and
you want to know whether they're
doing the right thing, or
if they're serving errors to maybe even
just 1% of users, you're not going to
find that out by just refreshing
the home page or something.
You need a monitoring
system to tell you.