Holy wow, that's a lot of fish.
Fortunately, we've got a lot
of animals that eat fish.
We talked about that
briefly in lesson one, but
now we can put together
an actual query to find them.
See if we can put it together
without looking back there.
Trouble is, the animals table tells
us nothing about what each individual
animal eats, and the diet table
doesn't list any individual animals.
It only lists their species.
Wait a minute though.
That species column is
in both of those tables.
That means it must be join time.
So, if we join animals against diet,
we should be to get the answer
that we're looking for.
Now, we saw one syntax for
joins in lesson one, but
it turns out there's also
a shortcut syntax we can use here.
The shortcut syntax won't actually use
the word join when it lists the joined
tables, but this form is actually
probably more common in real code.
If we want to join two tables to match
up rows where the column target in
table T equals the column match in
table S, we can do it like this.
So on the next page,
write a query to answer this problem.
You can use either kind of join,
but your query should only
return the name column,
not the species or the word fish itself.