You'll see that once we
know the properties and
relationships of the entities
we want to create,
the Model Editor is
extremely easy to use.
To open Story Board we
click on Story Board file.
To open the Model Editor
we click on the Model file.
Let's get some screen room and
we can see how it works.
You'll see that inside
the modelling tool we have our
entities here in the left column.
And then we have the area for editing
the entities over here in this center.
We want to learn how to use this tool so
let's just be bold here.
Let's completely recreate our entities.
To delete the entities, we just click
on the entities and press Delete.
It's kind of risky but
not anything to be too nervous about.
They're easy to re-create.
We'll create two entities and then
we'll give them their attributes and
relationships.
We add entities with this
Add Entity button down here.
It can be a little bit hard to find
because it's so low on the screen.
Let's click it twice
to add two entities.
Now we click the entities once,
wait, and then
click them again to change the name, and
we can do this for both of our entities.
Now that we have our entities, let's
click on Movie and add its attributes.
Let's add four attributes to the movie.
Let's set their names to ID,
poster path, release date, and title.
Then all we have to do is
select the right data types.
ID is an Int, and in general
we'll use Int 64 for Int values.
Poster path is a String.
Release date is a Date.
And title as a String.
It's really as straight forward as that.
Person is similar.
We click Person, and
then add three properties.
After we add them we have
to give their data types.
ID is Int 64.
Image path is a String.
And name Is a String.
Hopefully you're getting the impression
that you'll not need to spend a lot of
time inside this Model Editor tool.
Once you know what it is you want to
build, it's pretty easy to build them.
There's one last thing we need to do.
We still need to make our Relationships.
This is a topic we should
cover in more detail.
We'll visit this again
later in the lesson.
But, let's start by setting
them up here in the modeller.
Let's start with the movie entity.
In this app, each movie object
is tied to a single person.
To add a Relationship,
we click on this plus.
Movies have a property named
actor that point to a person.
That's the name of the Relationship.
The person class is the Destination.
We'll talk about these
Destinations more.
In the person entity,
we have a Relationship named Movies.
Again we add a Relationship and
we set it to Movies.
We'll set the Destination for
this Relationship to the Movie object.
Remember that we discussed that
Relationships have inverses.
If a movie is tied to a person,
then that person is tied to the movie.
We set these inverses
in the third column.
This is kind of cool.
Notice that once we
set the inverse actor,
the inverse is automatically set for
person's movies property.
We're almost done, but
there's one more step.
We said before that the Relationship
between a person and
movies is a too many relationship.
That means that one person
can have many movies.
We need to set that here
in the Model Editor.
To do that, we open up the left panel.
We click on the Relationship and we
come over here to the Entity Inspector.
Here we can set
the Relationship to Too Many.
But what is this?
That opens up some additional options.
What are the Arrangement and
Count Bounds?
What is this Delete Rule?
There are a lot of things we need
to learn about these Relationships.
Let's look into these in more detail