To implement the intent service,
there are a number of steps that
you're going to need to follow.
The first thing to do is to create
a GeoFenceTransitionsIntentService
class and have this extend
the IntentService base class.
You'll then need to add a constructor
and add an onCreate override to this.
Generally these will be empty, but
in the constructor you could call super
tag, and in the onCreate you could just
pass onCreate up to super as well.
Finally, you'll need to create
an override for onHandleIntent.
Now this takes an intent as
a parameter and returns void.
Once you've created all this stub code,
check this box when you're done.