How can we see some
evidence of stack behavior.
It'd be nice if we could see console
output every time one of our
view controllers was
popped off the stack.
Every time the OSD
allocates a swift class
including our view controller
it calls a deinitializer.
What if we put a print statement
into the deinitializer like this.
Think about what would appear
down here in the console
if a print statement was added to the
deinit method in the ViewController for
make your own adventure.
Or see for yourself by adding this
method to the ViewController class.
Then answer the quiz question.
ViewControllers are deinitialized.
When they are no longer on the screen,
they slide off the screen to the right,
or they're covered up by a new
Controller sliding in from the right.