Another useful operating system service,
that can benefit
from the hardware support from
memory management is checkpointing.
Checkpointing is a technique that's
used as part of the failure and recovery
management that operating systems or
systems software, in general, supports.
The idea behind checkpointing
is to periodically save
the entire process state.
The failure may be unavoidable
however with checkpointing,
the process doesn't have to be
restarted from the beginning.
It can be restarted from
the nearest checkpoint point.
And so the recovery will be much faster.
A simple approach to
checkpointing would be to pause
the execution of the process and
copy its entire state.
A better approach will take advantage
of the hardware support for
memory management and
will try to optimize the disruption
the checkpointing will cause on
the execution of the process.
Using the hardware support, we can write
protect the entire address space of
the process and
try to copy everything at once.
However, since the process will
continue executing, we won't pause it.
It will continue dirtying pages.
So, then we can track the dirtied pages,
again using the hardware MMU support,
and we will copy only the diffs, only
those pages that have been modified.
That will allow us to provide for
an incremental check point.
If we check point using these
partial diffs of just dirtied pages,
we will somewhat make the recovery
process more complex since we will have
to rebuild the image of the process
using multiple such diffs, potentially.
Or also, in the background,
these diffs can be aggregated to produce
more complete checkpoints
of the process.
The basic mechanisms used in
checkpointing can also be used in
other services.
For instance, debugging relies often
on a technique called Rewind-Replay.
Here rewind means that we will restart
the execution of the same process from
some earlier point.
So we will restart it from a checkpoint,
and then we will move forward and
see whether we can establish what is the
error, what is the bug in our program.
We can gradually go back to older and
older checkpoints until
we find the error.
Migration is another service that can
benefit from similar kinds of memory
management mechanisms that we described
are useful for checkpointing.
With migration, it's like we checkpoint
the process to another machine and
then we restart it on
that other machine.
It will continue its execution
on the other location.
This is useful in scenarios
such as disaster recoveries, so
as to continue the process on
another machine that will not crash.
Or, in consolidation that is
common in today's data centers,
when we try to migrate processes and
migrate load onto as few machines
as possible so that we can save on power
and energy or utilize resources better.
One way in which migration can be
implemented is as if we are performing
repeated checkpoints in a fast
loop until ultimately, there is so
few dirtied state from the process
that something like the pause and
copy approach becomes acceptable.
Or maybe at that point, simply we
really don't have another choice.
The process keeps dirtying enough pages
that we have to stop it in order to copy
the remaining contents.