For the rest of this practice set
you're going to gets build some apps.
You'll work with me through
a basketball scoring app, and
then we'll give you a few optional apps
that you could try if you want to hone
your skills a bit more.
Okay, the basketball scoring app.
This app is called court counter and
the purpose of this app is to keep track
of the score of a basketball game.
Now they end up is going to look like
this but will build it up in stages.
For the less athletically inclined,
and for our international audience,
I'll go ahead and explain how
scoring and basketball works.
The first way to score a point is
within the three point line which,
is a circle around the basket.
It's the most common way to score and
it's worth two points.
The second way to make a basket
is behind the three point line
which is this line right here.
It's quite a bit harder but
it earns you three points.
Finally the last way that a team
can score is something called
the free throw.
When a player is fouled such as kicked
in the shins, they get to try to make
one free basket behind the free throw
line Players will be lined up along
either side, but nobody will stop him or
her from trying to make that basket.
A free throw is worth one point.
With the court counter app, you can see
that you have a team A and a team B.
You also have the option to give
three two or one free throw point.
If you click on the buttons to
award team points as they score.
And if you want when the game's
over you can hit the reset button.
Okay, so to start off we're
going to make a new app.
You've done this a couple times before
so I'm just going to give you the major
checkpoints that you need to
hit to make your new app.
Make sure that you call your new
application court counter and
that you give it
the right company domain.
Set the minimum SDK to A.P.I. 15 and
choose the empty activity template.
You can go ahead and
accept any other defaults.
Then you should be done and
ready to get going with this app.