Up to this point,
all the apps that we've been building,
we've assumed there's a,
a perfect network connection.
And we know that we
can't always trust this,
in the real world or, networks are flaky
sometimes, sometimes non-existent.
So, I brought Jason in to talk about
what we can do in those situations.
>> Yeah.
Thanks Jared.
The problem with an app like
the Favorite Movies app,
is we have to fetch everything
every time we use it.
So you think the movie poster's coming
down, you fetch them all to populate
the table, but then as soon as
the cell scrolls off the bottom and
back up, we don't re-fetch that poster.
>> Mm.
>> Each time.
>> Right.
>> It'd be nice if we could
take that media and store it onto
the hard drive to make it persistent.
>> So, that's one type of data,
but what will we do with a more
structured data that we have,
the movie structs themselves,
that contain movie titles and
Other information about movies?
>> [CROSSTALK].
>> Yeah, that's no problem.
We, we pull down that JSON.
We punched it into an array of struts.
We can take that entire array and
persist it onto the hard drive in tact.
We can pull it out and
populate the table with it again.
>> Cool, so this is the type
of stuff we'd be learning in
the persistence course.
>> Yeah.
Keep in mind you don't need to use any
of this in the On the Map app, but
it's fun to fetch data
as much as you want.
But in the Persistence course
we'll learn these techniques.
>> Oh.