JavaScript profiling
takes some practice, but
now you know the tools
you need to succeed.
Hey, that rhymes, so it's clearly true.
>> It sure does.
So, have a look at your own projects and
see if you have some long-running
JavaScript or
some badly timed JavaScript.
See where you can reschedule it,
reduce its impact, or
just remove it all together.
>> Now, a lot of people
often think at this point,
they're done with their
performance work.
And, you know, and
if the JavaScript runs well,
well there's nothing else left to do.
But that's not at all true.
As you saw earlier, there's a whole
pipeline after the JavaScript runs, and
that also needs to fit into that
ten to 12-millisecond window.
As the developer,
you're in control of that pipeline.
You're the one who decides what
the browser does and when.
>> Yes.
So in next lesson, we'll be taking a
look at the different kinds of work that
JavaScript often triggers.
It could trigger style calculations,
layout, and paint.
Let's get started.