I used SW pre cache with gulp.
I installed a set of gulp plug ins
that I wanted to use and SW pre cache.
Then in my gulp file.js,
I added a generate SW task.
And added a few static file
globs including my index.html,
images and my styles.
I kept it pretty simple since
I don't have many files.
But for
bigger projects this'll be more complex.
And you'll probably want to have
a separate source and disk directory.
I told swPrecache to strip the dot
from the front of the static
files it included so
that everything is served from the root.
I also added runtime caching using
network first for the weather API.
I could run gulp generate-sw but
then I miss out on the automagical
service worker regeneration
whenever I change any files.
So instead,
I'll use gulp serv which uses browser
sync to serve the files locally.
Then anytime any of my files
are changed, not only does the service
worker get rebuilt but
the browser refreshes automatically.
If you want to see exactly what
I did the solution I built
is in the instructor notes.
It includes the gulp file.js and
a package.json.
So you can simply run MPN installed
to get everything you need.