I'm still a little fuzzy
on this likelihood thing.
Let's jump back to the moon.
Did I tell you about my star sensor?
I use it to navigate around.
There are hardly any other landmarks.
When I point it to a region in the sky,
it says, bright star.
That is, if there is a bright
star in that region.
If I told you that I was looking at
this particular region in the sky,
how likely is it that my star sensor
would go off and say bright star?
Choose the appropriate radio button
underneath on a three point scale.
From least to most likely.
Now do the same for
these other regions in the sky.
Remember that I'm asking you
to estimate the likelihood P
of bright star given the sky region.