So here's my method,
get GeoFence pending intent.
To this I create a new intent and
I pass it that this is the context.
And if you remember earlier we created
a GeoFence transitions intent service.
So we just specify the class of that.
So our new intent is going to
be a GeoFence transitions intent
service type.
And then we return pending intent or
get service.
This, zero, intent,
which is the intent we've just created.
And then this
PendingIntent.FLAG_UPDATE_CURRENT.
We use FLAG_UPDATE_CURRENT so
that we get the same PendingIntent
back when we call addGeofences.
We want to keep the PendingIntent
consistent across them all.