Let's go back to our polynomial
verification algorithm with repeated
trials and review its behavior.
If the two polynomials are equal,
then the probability that
the algorithm says so is 1.
On the other hand, if the polynomials
are different, there is a chance that
the algorithm will get the wrong answer,
but this only happens with probability
100 to the -k, where k is
the number of trials that we did.
We just need to extend
the argument we made before,
where k equals 2 to general k.
The fact that our algorithm might
sometimes return an incorrect answer
makes it what computer scientists
call a Monte Carlo Algorithm.
And because it makes mistakes
only when the polynomials differ,
it is called a one-sided
Monte Carlo Algorithm.
This idea can be extended
to arbitrary languages.
Here, strings in the language
represent equal polynomials.
This algorithm only makes mistakes
on strings not in the language.
Of course, it's possible for
the situation to be reversed, so
that the algorithm makes mistakes
on strings in the language.
This is another kind of
one-sided Monte Carlo Algorithm.
I should say that there also
two-sided Monte Carlo Algorithms
where both arrows are possible, but
regardless of which input is given
the answer is more likely
to be correct than not.
Suppose, however, that any
possibility of error is intolerable.
Can we still use randomization?
Well, yes we can.
Instead of picking a new point uniformly
at random, from the 100d possible
choices, we pick one from the choices
that we haven't picked before.
This is known as sampling
without replacement.
Since we don't place the sample we took
back in the pool before choosing again.
Since there are only d possible routes.
By the time we've picked the d+1 point,
we must have picked 1 of the non routes.
This algorithm uses randomization,
but nevertheless,
it always gives a correct answer.
If the polynomials are equal, the
probability that the algorithm says so
is 1.
If they're unequal,
the probability that it says so is 0.
The fact that this algorithm
never returns an incorrect answer
makes it a Las Vegas Algorithm.
The randomization can affect the running
time but not the correctness.
If the polynomials are equal
the algorithm definitely takes d+1
iterations, but when they're unequal,
it gets a little more complicated.
Let Ei be the event that A and
B are equal at the ith
element of the order array.
Then, we characterize the probability
that the algorithm takes at
least k steps as the intersection
of E0 through Ek- 1.
Note, however, that these events
are no longer independent.
If A and B are equal at the first
element of the order list,
then that's one fewer root that could
been have chosen to be the second.
So how do we go about
calculating this probability?
Returning to the Las Vegas version
of our polynomial identifier,
we can write the probability that
we don't detect a difference
in k iterations as this product here.
With a little more work,
we can get a tighter bound than this.
But for our purposes,
this simple bound works.
Note that even though
the probabilities here are the same,
the meanings are different.
In the Monte Carlo Algorithm,
the probability represents
the chances that the algorithm
will return an incorrect answer.
In the Las Vegas Algorithm, it says
something about the running time for
an algorithm that will always
produce the correct answer.