Alright we're ready to add the code to
play back the recorded audio using
various effects. To do this requires more
of the AVFoundation framework.
Specifically we need a class called
AVAudioEngine, which uses audio player
nodes to make changes to audio output.
That's what gives us the ability to
raise and lower the pitch of recorded audio,
increase or decrease the rate of
playback and effects like echo and reverb.
I've included links to the
documentation for AVAudioEngine and
audio notes if you'd like to take a peek.
In order to make the audio playback code
a little bit easier,
we've included the functions you need in
a class extension involved you can
import to your Pitch Perfect project.
This is a peek at what the extension
file looks like. Class extensions allow
us to add code to a class even though
the new code resides in a different file.
Our class extension for the
playSoundsViewController class provides some easy
to use functions for playing the audio
effects that we want. Back in our project
in the PlaySoundsViewController.swift file,
add the following code
after the recordedAudioURL property.
These are some properties in an
enumeration that will be used by our
class extension. Also we need to import
AVFoundation, otherwise the compiler
will complain that it doesn't know
anything about AVAudio file,
AVAudioEngine and AVAudioPlayerNode.
Now we're ready to bring in the class extension.
It's contained in the file
called PlaySoundsViewController+Audio.swift.
And you can find it in
the resources for this lesson. I already
have it in my Downloads folder and I’ll
drag it into Xcode. Make sure the Copy
items if needed is checked and that
PitchPerfect is the target and it's
also checked. And click Finish.
Ok now that the extension has been added,
the new functions it provides are
available to us from the
PlaySoundsViewController. As we start using the
functions from the extension, don't worry
if you don't know how each one is
implemented. I’m going to walk you
through them line-by-line in just a
moment.
For now, we can just concentrate on calling
functions and having the audio playback.
First you want to add a call to setupAudio
in the viewDidLoad, so the
AVAudioEngine is properly set up. This is
one of the functions that's included in
the extension that you just added.
So we'll make a call to setupAudio in
the viewDidLoad function. Next let's
configure the UI, so that the stop button
is disabled when the View first appears,
as the app won't be playing any sound
until the user presses one of the six
playback buttons. I’m looking at the
extension file and there's a convenience
function to reset the buttons to the
proper state when playing or not playing
music. It's called configureUI.
We need to configure the UI right before
the view first appears on the screen.
Now I wonder where we could call configureUI?
If you were thinking viewWillAppear,
then you're right. Back in
the PlaySoundsViewController, let's
add a call to configureUI in the
viewWillAppear function. First make
sure to add a call to the super classes
viewWillAppear function, and then we can
add our call to configureUI and we'll
pass it the notPlaying state. Also while
I'm here, I'm going to remove the rest of
this boilerplate code. Let's run this
real quick and see if the UI for the
PlaySoundsViewController appears as
we expect. This is a test.
Awesome our call to the configureUI is
correctly disabling the stop button when
the view appears.