Let's take a sneak peek
into the future and
see the final version of the app that
you'll be building with Firebase.
Meet the Friendly Chat app.
Friendly Chat, as the name implies,
is a chat app that lets
you chat with friends.
And you can do so in real time with
text messages and uploaded pictures.
When you first open the app,
you will see this screen,
which is a login screen.
And can login with both Google and
with your email.
I'm going to go ahead and
sign in with my email.
Once signed in, you can view all
the chat messages that have been sent,
even messages that were sent
when the app was closed.
You could even respond to a message.
And that response could be text
like this one, or a picture.
And one of the messages for
the app, my friend who is also using
the app gets the message in real time.
Cool right?