Now I'll be introducing you to
TFLearn; a Python network for
building neural networks.
It does a lot of the work for you,
such as initializing weights and
running back propagation.
As an introduction to TFLearn,
you'll be working through this notebook.
You can find the download link
at the bottom of the page.
By the end of the notebook,
you'll have built your own network for
predicting sentiment from the data
you saw in Andrew Trask's lesson, but
using TFLearn instead of NumPy.
And next I'll walk you through my
solutions so you can see how I did it.
First off, you'll import the data here.
I'm using pandas to read the data
because I find it makes working with
the data super easy.
Here you see the reviews and the labels.
Once the data is loaded, you'll need
to build the bag of words dictionary.
This is left out for you to do.
I've imported the counter class here for
you to use.
You can read the documentation for
counter by clicking this link.
Be sure to assign the variable
total counts to your bag of words.
If you did it right you should have
about 74,000 words in the bag of words.
As you might remember
from Andrew's notebooks,
most of the words show up very
few times in the reviews.
We can make our network train faster
by using a subset of the data without
losing accuracy.
So here I sorted the bag
of words by count and
kept the first 10,000
most frequent words.
Now that we have our vocabulary,
you'll need to make a dictionary
that maps the words to numbers.
This dictionary will be
called word to index.
This is left for you to do.
With the word to index dictionary,
now you can write a function that
converts text into a word vector.
The idea is that each element in
the vector corresponds to a word
in the vocabulary.
With a word to index dictionary,
now you can write a function that
converts text into a word vector.
The idea is that each element in
the vector corresponds to a word in
the vocabulary.
So the most frequent word is at index
zero, the second most index one, and so
on.
Then to build a vector you count up the
number of times a word exist in the text
and set the index for
that word to that count.
Here is the general method to do this.
This function is up to you to implement.
If you did it right, you should
get this vector for this text.
This cell uses your text to vector
function to run through the data set and
convert each review into word vectors.
Okay, now that we have
the input data ready,
it's time to create our training
validation and test data.
We use the training data
to train the network and
the validation data to find
the best hyper parameters.
We actually won't be creating
the validation data here.
TFLearn will do it for us later.
After you're satisfied that the network
has been trained well enough,
you use the test data to
measure the final performance.
It's really important that you only run
the network on this test data once.
Okay, now after all that data prep,
it's time to get into some TFLearn.
With TFLearn you build networks by
defining the layers you want to use.
For example, to create the input layer,
you use tflearn.inputdata.
Here you set the batch size and
the number of input units.
Remember that the input units should
match the size of your input data.
Set this variable net, and
that's your input layer.
To add in hidden layers you
use tflearn.fullyConnected.
FullyConnected here means
all the units in this layer
are connected to all the units
in the previously layer.
It's synonymous with the term hidden
layer that we've been using before.
Fully connected takes net as an input
automatically using the output of
the input layer as the input
to this hidden layer.
Here you set the number of units,
and here is the activation function.
So for example.
You can add more hidden units by calling
this fully connected function again and
chaining the layers together by passing
net from one layer to the next.
So then for the output layer, you just
add another fully connected layer.
Since we are trying to predict positive
versus negative sentiment here,
we have two classes, and so
we have two output units.
One for positive and one for negative.
We'll use the soft max function on
the output to get our prediction
probabilities.
And finally, to define how you'll train
the network you use Tf.regression.
You pass in net again and
set the optimizer.
So cast a gradient dissent here, and the
learning function and the loss function
which is cross entropy in the case
of using a softmax for activation.
With all that set you can create
the model with Tflearn.dnn.
I'll leave it up to you to
put all these pieces together
to build the network itself.
Write the code in this
build model function.
You'll initialize the model below and
then train it.
So this is how you train
the network with model.fit.
The fit method takes the training
inputs, trainX, and the labels, trainY.
You can set how much data to
reserve as a validation data.
You can also set the batch size and
the number of epochs to run.
After going through the epochs
you'll see the validation score.
Once you're happy with the performance
on the validation set,
run the model on the test set and
check out the final accuracy.
Try it out with your own text and
see how well it does predicting this.
All right, once you're done with this,
or if you're having problems
getting it to work, check out my
solution to see how I built the network.