So we talked about a number
of commercial policies.
For example, a Clark-Wilson and
Chinese Wall.
So here we have a scenario.
In this quiz, we have a scenario
where there's a law firm that has
two different client companies.
And the interesting thing about
these client companies is that they
compete with each other.
And lawyers work on cases
related to many companies.
So some of them work on company A,
others work on company B, or
whatever it is.
And they need to access the documents.
So to ensure proper access, in this
case, which policy should you be using?
That is the quiz question.
The two options are Clark-Wilson and
Chinese Wall.