Earlier, we talked about the diverse
uses for Firebase real-time database.
I mentioned that we wouldn't want
to store photos in the database
because it would prolong load time and
the database is meant to be fast.
Luckily, Firebase provides a place
to pop those larger items.
Its called Firebase storage.
Firebase storage is the perfect
place to store files.
Such as rich content documents,
images and video.
Firebase storage also provides
a robust connection for uploading and
downloading files.
This means that if you lose your network
connection in the middle of an upload or
download, then the transfer
can continue where it left off
once you've reconnected.
So regardless of a user's bandwidth,
uploads and
downloads are as efficient as possible.
Another benefit of Firebase storage
is that its storage space is
easily scaled to suit
the needs of your user base.
As your app grows,
your storage can grow with it.
Lastly, Firebase storage also has
security features, because we know
users and developers care a lot about
the security of their pictures, video,
and other rich content.
You can provide access controls that
dictate who can read data from, and
who can write data to your app storage.
You can also create folders in your
storage which provide a foundation that
makes it easy to designate which
users can work with groups of data.
We're going to examine how to set up
storage using the Firebase Console and
how to implement storage
within the Friendly Chat app.
And then, we'll see how to use
security rules to protect your data.