Google Sign-In is a technology
that allows you to get users
into your apps quickly and securely
with little development work required.
It allows you to create a seamless
experience across screens for
your users.
They sign in once and they're
authenticated on all of your devices.
It allows you to integrate Google's
services into your websites and
mobile apps, and also enables
over the air installation of
Android apps when users
sign into your websites.
In this lesson you'll learn how to add
Google Sign-In to your Android app and
how to manage the workflow of
your users signing into your app.
Are you ready to get started?
Let's go