So the first thing that I asked you,
is whether udacicolaVotes is a local
variable or a global variable.
And you should have determined
that it was a local variable.
Well, to figure this out, you go to
where the variable is declared, which is
here, and you know it's declared,
because the data type is right here.
And you see is it declared Inside of a
method, meaning between between the two
curly braces here, or
is it declared outside of the method?
Now, if it's declared
inside of a method,
that means that it's a local variable,
and
we can see very clearly that it is
in fact declared inside of a method.
So it's a local variable.
Well, what does that mean?
We should also be asking ourselves,
if I declared something as
a local variable, should I have?
Let's think about it in this case.
Here's our phone.
And we've been talking about udacicola,
so
let's only focus on when we
click the udacicola button.
When we click this button,
this method starts.
It sets udacicola votes to zero, and
then it adds one to udacicolaVotes,
which is zero.
So udacicolaVotes becomes one.
Now, because udacicolaVotes is a local
variable, at the end of this method,
it actually sort of dies,
or gets deleted.
The fact udacicolaVotes is trashed, or
gone, at the end of this method because
it's a local variable,
causes a couple problems.
So why is this a problem?
Well, you would think that if
three different people voted for
udacicola by clicking on the button,
that udacicolaVvotes should be three.
Well, what actually happens is the first
time you click on the button,udacicola
becomes zero.
It gets one added to it, becoming one.
And then it gets trashed.
It doesn't exist anymore.
The second time that somebody
clicks on udacicolaVotes,
well udacicolaVotes is
made all over again.
It's declared again.
Because remember, the first time
it had essentially gotten trashed.
So it needs to be remade.
And when it's remain, it's set to zero.
Now we add one again to it, but
remember the value is zero.
So udacicolaVotes is still one, even
though the button's been clicked twice.
And the same thing happens when
it's clicked the third time,
it still is one and it's actually
trashed again at the end of this method.
So that's the first problem.
It's not really saving the state
between button clicks.
About how many people have voted for
udacicola.
But another problem is down here, this
code's actually going to throw an error.
And the reasoning for that is because
remember I said that udacicolaVotes
sort of comes into existence or
its scope begins right here.
And then at the end of
this voteudacicola method.
It is trash, it's out of existence.
Which means when I come down here,
udacicolaVotes doesn't really exist.
More technically, we say that
this variable is out of scope.
Its scope was here It got declared here,
and it ended here.
But we're trying to use it down here.
And it can't be used.
Having udacicolaVotes be a local was
not a correct decision in this case.
And I can summarize why
with these two points.
It's not saving the vote about between
button click, and it's not in scope for
the show me votes method.
So this will actually cause errors.
So this will actually not compile.
Okay, so let's look at the other
variable in this program.