[Thrun] One of the most basic things we can do with computer vision
is to extract features.
For example, there is a very strong edge feature over here
and a strong corner feature right over here and right over here.
Let me tell you how to do this.
How can you find in an image like this whether there is an edge,
or in an image like this where there is an edge from a bright area on the left
to a dark region on the right?
Let us write a feature extractor that identifies transitions of this type,
and let's start with horizontal transitions.
The most obvious feature detector looks like this.
We run this little 2-value matrix across the entire image over here,
and we add whatever is on the left side and subtract whatever is on the right side.
So if both sides are approximately in balance, like these points over here,
adding an expression here is approximately 0.
But if the left side is significantly larger than the right side,
then adding and subtracting yields a very large value, like 212 - 7 over here.
So this specific mask gives us edges that run from bright to dark.
So here I'm taking the first value and subtract the second value from it.
255 - 212 gives me 43. That's applying this mask over here.
From 211 to 237 is -26 and so on.
212 - 7 is 205.
237 - 3 is 234 and so on.
7 - 1 is 6.
3 - 9 is -6 and so on.
If you look at this result of applying the mask over here,
you'll find that this column stands out.
It is much, much larger in value than any of the adjacent columns,
and that indicates that we have a high likelihood of a horizontal edge feature occurring
at the ridge between this column and this column over here.
So here we are applying that same trick to the original image, and this is the result.
You can see that areas where the original image has a strong transition
you get a strong response over here.
This is actually showing the absolute value of the difference
where we get rid of the minus sign, so you can see any transition from bright to dark
or dark to bright horizontally shows up.
Now, you can see these lines over here that are vertical show up very strongly.
The lines over here don't, and the reason is the way we defined our kernel,
it ran actually horizontal, so it finds horizontal edges and not vertical edges.
Vertical edges require a different kernel, so let me get to this in a second.