All right you're done.
Let me show you how I solve this one.
Alright, let's first take a look at
sw600dp dash port activity main.
In other words, this is the layout
our portrait tablet is going to use.
Now as I said we're going to
start with a relative layout.
Inside the relative layout
we begin with a toolbar.
Which is pinned to the parent top.
And is the width of the parent.
Also it is height action bar size.
Pretty reasonable.
Notice that we have an elevation
of appbar_elevation.
All of these in this draw
are going to have the same elevation,
so they don't cast
shadows on each other.
The next thing we do is
we have an image view.
The ImageView is below our toolbar and
it's a listPreferredItemHeight.
Pretty straight forward.
We center it, give it the elevation.
Finally we have just a View.
This View also has the same elevation
with the same background color, and
it's below the image view.
And its height is this
details_app_bar_overlap dimension
which we know is 24 dp.
so now if want our detail
container to overlap this view
all we have to do is say,
instead of it being below this view,
we say it is layout below
the image view, which is here.
That will cause it to overlap, and
we inset it exactly the way
we've inset everything else.
We use paddingLeft and
paddingRight in this case on inset
material which is of course 16dp.
Finally, we can put
our forecast fragment
just below that detail container.
Pretty straightforward.