Remember, Paul just taught you that
forced synchronous layout occurs when
you ask a browser to run layout first
inside the JavaScript section, and
then recalculate styles,
and then run layout again.
There are a few different properties
that when accessed will cause layout.
And you can find a list of
them in the instructor notes.
With that in mind I've got three
reasonable snippets of code for
you that I want you to analyze.
Each of these three includes
some kind of iteration
which I'm using forEach to do.
Now by the way you can't normally
use forEach with a collection of DOM
nodes which you get from using something
like Document.querySelectorAll.
But I really like using forEach because
of its pretty awesome call back syntax.
So what wind up doing is converting the
collection of DOM nodes, into an array
of DOM nodes which gives you the option
to use forEach and other array methods.
See the example in
the instructor notes to see how.
Anyways, two of these three will
cause a forced synchronous layout.
But which one cannot cause
a forced synchronous layout?
In the instructor notes below, you can
find a link to a sample site that uses
all three as well as
some other helpful hints.
So open the examples site, try out these
three and see if you can figure out
which one is not causing
the forced synchronous layout.