To deal with this great
device diversity,
devices are roughly grouped
in several categories.
This includes block devices like disks.
These are devices that operate at
granularity of entire blocks of
data that's delivered in and
out of the device and in and
out of the CPU complex in the other end.
A key property is that individual
blocks can be directly accessed.
For instance if you have ten
blocks of data on the disk,
you can request to directly
access the ninth one.
That's what makes it a block device.
Then there are character devices like
keyboards that work with a serial
sequence of characters and support
something like a get-a-character,
put-a-character type of interface.
And then there are network devices that
are somewhat of a special case somewhere
in-between.
Since they deliver more than
a character at a time, but
their granularity is not
necessarily a fixed block size.
It can be more flexible.
So this looks more like a stream of data
chunks of potentially different sizes.
In this manner the interfaces from
the operating system to the devices
are standardized based
on the type of device.
For instance for a block devices,
the driver should support
operations to read/write block of data,
for character devices, a driver should
support operations to put/get
a character from, into the device.
So, in that sense standard.
Internally, the operating system
maintains some representation for
each of the devices that
are available on the platform.
This is typically done by using a file
abstraction to represent
the different devices.
And in that way what really the
operating system achieves is that it can
use any of the other mechanisms that are
already part of the operating system to
otherwise manipulate files.
Too, now think mean to refer to
access different types of devices.
Given ultimately that these files
will correspond to devices and
not real files then things like read and
write operations or actual operations
that manipulate this file will be
handled in some device-specific manner.
On Unix-like systems all devices appear
as files underneath this /dev directory.
As special files, they're also
treated by a special file system.
They're not really stored
on the real file system.
In Linux versions,
these are tmpfs and devfs.