So how do we transform our
code to something that
actually allows us to load
different icon packs?
A lot less than you might think.
In fact, because all of our logic for
retrieving a URL from a weather
condition ID is in our utility method,
we actually don't need to touch any of
our fragments or notification code.
Kind of like we planned it that way, hm.
>> We will have to update our
setting screen, though, adding a new
list preference to allow users to
select which icon pack they want.
If you remember back to our
temperature units list,
preference is driven by two arrays.
One for the options the users sees,
and the other for the values,
what actually gets written in
to the shared preferences.
We'll use our URL templates for
the values.
Just need to replace our single
URL string with our options and
values string arrays,
wire up the list preference,
then do that last piece of magic.
Update our utility method to read the
URL template from shared preferences.
Sounds easy enough?