So here is an example of video
that actually has been tested for
these kinds of things.
I'm just showing example, so this is the
first at one of the earlier attempts at
trying to do rolling shutter removal,
so this was the original video they had.
This is known as the helicopter
data and, of course,
you notice lots of non-rigid warps.
So this is our original footage that we
want to actually start playing around
with, see a lot of non-rigid
deformations everywhere.
So when we applied the first system, the
one basically found a crop window, and
tried to do this as a global shutter
we also could not actually
stabilize it very well.
We see a lot of non-rigid
warping going on.
So what we basically have to do
is go back to drawing board and
start thinking about how
we can actually do this
knowing a little bit more about
how a rolling shutter works.
Not going to go into a lot
of detail right now.
I'm just going to kind of say is what
we basically did was we actually
took the whole image and
kind of dissected it into small regions.
Almost the scan rates that are coming
down as I move the camera, and
applied the same kinds of processing
of computing the homography and
all of that for different regions and
different slices itself and
used that to figure out, what is the
likelihood of this region moving here.
Use that as an estimate, and then,
of course, unwarp it, knowing more about
how each and every region would move.
So, the problem we had was we didn't
know exactly what the readout dor each
and every camera was.
We basically kind of said is, well,
let's look at multiple motion models.
So I basically had a different motion
model for each one of them and
then blend them back using
a mixture of Gaussians.
So, in essence, we took two of them
this way, another two and basically did
a blend between those and then I
did a blend between the other two.
Remember the kinds of blend concepts
we've looked at similar in this context
and what we did was basically use
a mixture of Gaussians to kind of take
all of the homography information for
each integral region and use that and
unblend it or unmerge or unwarp the
image to correct for all of the motion.
So here is the original video again.
Lot of non-rigid warping
going on in the middle.
This is basically the solution
using our newer approach now,
we actually look at
the rolling shutter also.
Now you may be noticing that
the input thing is moving around.
That's partly the artifact
of our cropping algorithm.