Let me show you what
this depth ambiguity
how it manifests itself in real images.
For example, here, you've seen
lots of these types of images.
Somebody basically being at a different
distance that is, in the scale,
which in this image means how far
that person is from an object, and
depending on where they are, you can
actually see them to be the same size.
Of course, you know that Leaning of
Tower of Pisa and this person are,
of course, not the same size.
You've seen other fun
images like this or
other images that basically show
how big your pumpkin could be and
this is actually what we also saw
when we talked about cameras, right?
Two different lenses actually basically
showed different depth information.
Here this person is looking bigger than
this one and again, they are exactly
the same distance here but they look
the same size, depending on where I am.
The scaling factor that
comes in from the lenses.
So this is the depth ambiguity that is
hard to decipher if somebody just gave
me a single image and that's the point
that we want to actually try to
take to the next level on asking
the question, how we can get depth?