Remember that the DOM is
a big tree as a result.
This means that elements will end up
inside one another, another way of saying
this is that elements end up
within the bounds of each other
because of this relationship.
The size of a child element can and
will be affected by its parent elements.
In many cases you will have
a large number of child elements
grouped inside one parent element.
These parent elements
are sometimes called containers.
And they can be pretty useful for
sizing boxes.
Take this example.
There is a child element
inside of a container.
Okay, cool.
And let's say that I change the width
of the container to be 400 pixels.
Now look at the width of the child.
It's 400 pixels.
In this case the constraint is
the width of the parent container.
The parent is four hundred pixels wide
and so the child stretches out to
400 pixels of course if the parent had
padding then the child would be smaller.
In other cases you might want
to child element to be sized
relative to a parent.
For instance you might
want this child to take up
half the width of the container.
For that you have percentages.
First let's change the width of
the child from 400 pixels to 100%.
Okay, nothing changed, that makes sense.
By default block elements are as wide as
possible but now let's change it to 50%.
Check it out,
now it's half the width of the parent.
You can see that it's 200 pixels wide.
Remember, percentages
are always calculated
in relationship to immediate parents.