A different way to assign work to threads in
a multithreaded system is using this pipeline approach.
In this pipeline approach, the overall task,
the processing of the toy shop, is divided into subtasks, and
each of the subtasks is performed by a separate thread.
So threads are assigned subtask in the system, and then the entire applications,
so the entire complex task is executed as a pipeline of threads.
In the context of our toy shop example, for
instance, what this would mean is that given that we have six steps in
the toy order processing, we can have six workers and
every single one of the workers will be assigned one steps to process.
At any given point of time we can have multiple tasks concurrently in
the system.
So, multiple toy shop orders being processed by different workers.
It just every single one of those orders,
every single one of those tasks, will be in a different stage in the pipeline.
So, one worker can be accepting one toy order, another worker can be
performing the parsing of the order for another toy, a third
worker can be cutting the wooden pieces for yet another toy and so forth.
The throughput of the system overall will clearly be
dependant on the weakest link, the longest stage in the pipeline.
Ideally, we would love it if every single stage of
the pipeline takes approximately the same amount of time, but
sometimes it just may not be possible.
So the way to deal with this is using the same thread pull technique that we
saw before.
If one of the pipeline stages for
instance, the wood cutting stage, takes more amount of time longer.
Then we can assign multiple threads to this particular stage.
Let's say it takes three times longer to perform this stage in
the pipeline compared to all the other stages in the pipeline.
If we assign three different threads, three different workers, to this stage,
then overall, every single stage in the pipeline will approximately be able to
process the same number of subtasks,
the same number of toy orders over a period of time.
So the system overall will still be balanced.
The best pay to pass work among these different pipeline stages
is using a shared-buffer based mechanism similar to
the producer consumer shared buffer that we saw in the previous pattern.
The alternative to that would be to require some explicit communication between
threads in the pipeline, and this will mean that a thread in an earlier stage
will potentially have to wait until a thread in the next stage is free.
The shared-buffer based approached, the queue based approach, helps correct for
any kind of small imbalances in the pipeline.
For instance, with direct communication in the context of our toy shop,
it would require workers directly to hand off the output of their processing,
so cut pieces etcetera to the next worker, to the next thread.
Where as in the shared buffer base communication you can think of a worker
leaves the output of its processing, so the piece is on the table and
the next worker picks them up whenever he or she's ready.
In summary, a pipeline is a sequence of stages where
a thread performs a stage in the pipeline and
that's equivalent to some subtask in the end-to-end processing.
To keep the pipeline balanced a stage can be executed by more than one thread.
And we can use the same thread pool management technique that we
described in the Boss-Workers model to determine what is the right number of
threads per stage.
Passing partial work products or results across the stages in
the pipeline should be done via a shared buffer based communication.
This provides for some elasticity in the implementation and
avoids stalls due to temporary pipeline imbalances.
A key benefit of the approach is the fact that it allows for
highly specialized threads and this leads to improved efficiency.
Like what we saw in the variant of the boss-worker model, when threads perform
a more specialized task, it's more likely that the state that they require for
their processing is present in the processor cache and
that kind of locality can ultimately lead to improve performance.
A negative of the approach is the fact that it is fairly complex to
maintain the pipeline balanced over time.
When the work load pattern changes, so we have more toys arriving or
when the resources of the pipeline change, so a worker slows down or
takes breaks, we'll have to rebalance the entire pipeline to
determine how many workers to assign to each stage.
In addition to that, there is more synchronisation, since there
are synchronisation points at multiple points in the end to end execution.