Let's just talk about a couple limit limitations on this,
which are going to get us to the Fourier series in just a minute, okay?
For this integral to exist,
this Fourier transform, we don't actually want infinites, right?
Because that's not so good when, when are, when we, when we try to like,
write down infinity, it just goes a really long time, all right.
One thing we'd say is that this whole thing is integrable,
okay, if the original function itself is integrable.
That is if I take the, the function, I actually have to take its absolute value.
If I sum it up from minus infinity to infinity, it, it can't explode.
It has to be limited to a value.
So you might ask, but wait a minute, I thought we had infinite repeating series.
>> I thought we had infinite repeating series.
We did when we were talking about Fourier series.
We're now talking about the Fourier transform,
where we're trying to keep things bounded.
So the idea is that these integrals have to exist.
It's base, it's based on the same principle, but it's, it's this idea.
So in Fourier series, we talked about repeating functions.
In Fourier transform we're talking about integral,
integrable functions, all right?
In a minute when we have a fixed length function, it'll be clear.
In fact, let's get to that right now.
You see it says, so obviously if there was a bound of width T.
Right, so if, if all my entire function fell within T, then obviously I could
just integrate from sort of, T, negative T over 2, to plus T over 2, right?
That would be the entire integral.
And that's going to lead us,
at least in my twisted mind, to this notion of the discrete Fourier transform.