Given the strict consistency is
next to impossible to achieve,
the next best option with reasonable
cost is sequential consistency.
If you look at the example from
the previous idiom, if x and
y are completely unrelated,.
And P2 computed the value of y
independently without any reference
to the memory location m1.
Then these two operations don't really
have to strictly appear in this
particular order.
For instance, it is possible for
P3 to observe,
just like what we did in the previous
case, that the value of m1 has become x.
And then to see that
the value of m2 has become y.
But it is also perfectly reasonable for
P3 at a particular point
in time to access the value of m1 and
to see that it's still zero.
So it doesn't know that this
right operation happened.
However, at a subsequent moment when it
tries to read the memory location m2,
it sees that it has
already been updated to y.
This is the equivalent of what would
happen in a regular shared memory system
if we have multiple threads.
And if we don't use any
additional controls and
your walking sequentializations and
anything like that.
When these two operations are issued,
they will be applied in
some way some order.
But we don't necessarily have control
which is the order that these operations
will be applied in.
So that's why we say that as long as the
ordering that's observed is equivalent
to some possible ordering
of these operations.
If they executed on a single
shared memory system,
then that would be considered
a legal operation.
According to this sequential
consistency model.
So, in summary, according to sequential
consistency, the memory updates from
different processors may
be arbitrarily interleaved.
However, if, we let one process
see one ordering of these updates.
We have to make sure that all other
processes see the exact same ordering of
those updates.
For instance, it is not okay
to let process P3 see that
the update to m1 with the value x.
Appear before the update
of m2 with the value y.
And instead,
at the same time to allow process 4 to
think that the value
of m1 was still zero.
When the value of m2 was
already updated to y.
In this case,
process P4 thinks that m2 has been
updated before the memory location m1.
It would be too hard to reason about
what exactly will happen in a program
execution.
If every processor can see completely
different ordering of some updates,.
And if we, the software or the
programmer doesn't have an understand
how and when are those updates reorder.
What this means is that
the sequential consistency,
every single process will see
the exact same interleaving.
This interleaving may not correspond
to the real way in which these
operations were ordered.
However, sequential consistency at least
guarantees that every single process in
the system.
Will see the exact same sequential
ordering of all of this.
And one constraint of the interleaving
is that the updates that are made by
the same process will not
be arbitrarily interleaved.
For instance, if P1 makes
another update in the future.
Then on any of the other processes,
it will not be possible to
first observe that the value z was
written to the memory location, m3.
And only then, find out that the value
x was written to memory location m1.
So for instance, what we see on P4.
This will be correct under
sequential consistency because
the updates to m1 and
m3 are observed here in the correct way.
When it sees that the value of m3 was z,
it already knew that
the value of m1 had become x.