All right, before we go into the code
of displaying an Interstitial Ad,
let's discuss this a little bit.
Because there are two important things
to think about with Interstitial Ads.
The first one, is about
the format of an Interstitial Ad.
As we know, the Interstitial Ad consumes
the entire screen of the device.
Therefore, it's important
not to interrupt the user
while they are engaging with your app.
So the first important things to think
about, is to display Interstitial Ads
with our natural breaks in your app,
for example, between levels in a game.
The second important thing with
Interstitial Ads is to prepare
the loading of the ad before showing it.
Why is this important?
Well, loading an Interstitial Ad
can take time, in particular,
if the network is slow.
When the time has come to display an
Interstitial Ad, you don't want the user
to sit there and wait for it to load,
you want it to be displayed immediately.
Therefore, we load it in advance.
We prepare the loading
before we're showing the ad.
So how do we do that.
Well, let's start by looking
at the class Interstitial Ad.
This is the class we use to load and
show an Interstitial Ad.
So it has a method called loadAd.
But this method is just requesting
the ad to be loaded and
to avoid blocking the UI thread,
it will return immediately
before the ad has been loaded.
So how do we know when
the ad has been loaded?
By setting an AdListener,
we can overload to onAdLoaded method.
So when the Interstitial Ad has finished
loading, this method will be called, and
we can then proceed to call
show on the Interstitial Ad.
So, this is the flow that we
will implement in our app.
You should also know that Interstitial
Ad has a method called isLoaded.
So if you're not interested in knowing
exactly when the ad has been loaded,
then you could simply call loadAd.
And when the time has come to show the
ad, you check if the ad has been loaded.
If it has been loaded,
then you call the show method.
Otherwise, you do not
show the ad at all.
Now let's check out the code
to implement this flow.
Let's open up
the InterstitialActivity Java file.
The first thing we've done here is to
add an InterstitialAd field called
mInterstital, there are no
changes to the onCreate method.
So let's go and
look at the loadInsterstitial method.
This code should already be there
because we set it in the previous
exercise.
So let's look at the other code.
First, we're creating an instance
of the InterstatialAd.
Then, we're setting the AdUnitId.
And we set it to this string that
will return test InterstitialAds.
And this string, we defined in our
resource string file, so we have to get
it using the getResources().getString
and then the resource ID.
And now comes the flow
that we talked about.
Here, you can see that we're setting
the listener for the InterstitialAd.
Let's talk about this in a little while.
But we're setting a listener here and
then the execution drops down here.
So now, you can see, we're creating
an AdRequest using the builder.
And then we're calling the loadAd
method on our InterstitialAd instance.
Providing the AdRequest as an argument,
and as we saw before,
this method will start
the ad loading process, but
it will return immediately
before the ad has been loaded.
That's where our listener comes
into play, and as you can see,
we're creating an anonymous class here
based on our ToastAdListener class.
And as you can see,
we're overloading the onAdLoaded method.
So since we're setting
the listener here,
this method will be called when
the ad has completed loading.
So we call our parent method that
will display the toast message,
since that is what we defined
in the ToastAdListener class.
And then we set the text of our
disable button to Show Interstitial.
And we also enabled that button.
That means that the user
can now press this button.
And when that happens,
the showInterstitial callback
method will be called.
So what are we doing
is showInterstitial.
Well, with simple check if
the Interstitial Ad has been loaded, and
this may seem like an unnecessary check,
since we know the ad has been
loaded since onAdLoaded was called.
But we're doing it any how.
And then the time has come to actually
show the Interstitial Ad, and
when this happens, the ad will actually
be displayed in full screen mode.
And for the button,
we go back to a previous state,
setting the text Interstitial Not Ready
and then disabling it.
And finally, going back to our listener.
If the ad could not be loaded, the
onAdFailedToLoad method will be called.
In that case, again,
we show the toast message and
then we set the ErrorReason
to the text of the button.
That's it, that's the code we have
to implement the Interstitial Ad.