And so here we have a sphere.
And the idea of a Gaussian sphere is it represents all possible surface normals.
So suppose I have a shape, and I'll just draw us some sort of shape like that.
It's kind of a potato looking thing.
Right, if I have some point here, it has a surface normal in some direction.
Well that surface normal is right here on the sphere.
And likewise, if I has a normal here,
that one would be right there on the sphere.
Okay? So there's a mapping, from all the surface normals to the Gaussian sphere.
And in particular if I have z as a function of x y and
I'm only worrying about things pointing up.
Then essentially, only the top half of that sphere do I have to worry about.
Right? So there's going to be a relationship between every normal, and
a point on the Guassian sphere.
So, the p q space that I was just talking about is actually a projection of
the Guassian sphere.
And the way it works is as follows.
Imagine, and I'll draw this in 3D in a minute.
A map by here in the 2D.
Imagine I have a, an origin at the center of the sphere and
I come out, at the location of that normal and
I hit a plane that's located at the top pole of this sphere.
So here I'm showing it in, in 2D.
It just makes it a little bit easier.
But actually to look at p q space, we have to look at this in 3D.
So here the idea is, here's my little normal who is there, and
it points up until it hits this plane.
And that location would be p0, q0.
All right.
For this particular normal.
And this z equals 1 plane up here,
that's sometimes called the gradient space or the p q plane projection.
And the idea is that every normal, has a p q value.
So I can represent normals just by their p q value.
And so now we're going to use that to define our reflectance map.
Got it, cool.