So our app contains five activities now,
but they're not all connected.
When we open our app,
we see the main activity, but
there's no way to open
the Numbers activity from there.
So, let's figure out the missing
pieces on how to open new activity,
when a category is clicked on.
So first, we need to know when
a user clicks on a certain category.
Then we need to learn how to send
an intent to open an activity
within our app.
So if you remember from the last course,
we learned about handling button clicks
on the Submit button
in the Just Java app.
So, we can apply what we learned there.
Now, let's start by making
the numbers category work.
So in the activity_main.xml file.
This is where the numbers category
is defined in our app an android and
a view and this is not just buttons.
Remembe,r that buttons
are subclass of view.
Any view can be configured to
respond to touch input and
I found it easier to define
these as text views.
And then, style the views to
look like the design marks.
Now, I can add on click attribute
on this text view X.M.L. element.
Just like we did on the Submit
button from the last course,
I can set the value to
be open numbers list.
Which tells Android to call
the function open numbers list,
when this text view is touched.
Note, that we haven't
implemented this function yet.
So, let's head over to the main
activity java file and do exactly that.
In the main activity file, I create
this new method called openNumbersList.
It needs to be a public method,
have a void return value.
Meaning that it returns nothing and
I have one input parameter,
which will be view.
If you're wondering how
I know what to write.
Check the documentation for
the injury on click attribute
in the instructor notes below.
All right, so
the open numbers list method
will get called when the numbers
Category view is clicked on or touched.
This means that all the lines of code
inside this method will get executed.
So, this covers step one
of handling the user click.
Now, I'm going to let you figure out
step two, which involves figuring out
the code that goes inside
the open numbers list method.
So you can set an intent to
open the numbers activity.
Don't worry about the other
categories for now.
All right, so when you're done,
you actually look like this.
Clicking on the numbers category takes
you to the numbers activity, and
it's expected that the other
categories don't work yet.
That will come in later coding steps.
If you need a hint on
how to accomplish this,
check out the notes
below the image quiz.