Okay, here's the answer.
You need to shop that op is associative.
You don't need all this other stuff.
In particular,
associativity means that op of a, b,
then op with c has to be the same as a,
op with b and c.
Basically you put
the parenthesis where you want.
So let me just quickly run through
some of the other options.
So the constraint of constant time only
affects the work in the span of a scan,
not its correctness, so
this is not relevant.
What about being in place?
Well, our algorithm
uses op as a function,
so being in place doesn't matter.
Now the fourth option
commutativity is interesting.
Like a sociativity,
it's kind of rearrangement property.
But actually, it's a stronger
property than what we need.
In fact, you should go back and
look at the parallel scan, and
you will observe that it always
only combines consecutive values.
So that means,
we really only need a sociativity,
It's not too hard to show that our
definition of op is in fact associative.
But it's mostly messy algebra.
I'm super lazy so
I'll leave that as an exercise to you.
As an aside there's a really neat and
very general framework for
many other kinds of recurrences.
These include things like segmented
scan, which you just looked at.
For moe information,
please see the instructor's notes.