The answer, is that the threads will eventually agree on
who's better. Before, each method had its own copy of
the variable in its stack. Now, the threads share the
variable via the global memory. In fact, this is a common
way for threads to communicate. Because who's better is a
shared variable, it must have the same value in all the
threads. Looking back at the code, we see that this
sets off a race condition, only in this case, the winner
is the second thread to reach the assignment statement. Suppose
that thread one reaches the assignment first. Then he sets
who's better to one, and it's possible that he gets
to print out that he's better a few times. But eventually
thread two will seize control, change the value of who's
better to two, and then from then on, they will
both agree. That thread two is better. Now I've treated
this as all fun, and games, but in reality this situation
where we have two threads trying to write to the same memory can create
some very serious [INAUDIBLE]. And it's particularly
bad when the order in which rights happen
is indeterminate as it depends on the choices of the schedulers, and the library
library, and the OS make, and maybe let that affect the output of our program