Inside the login.HTML I
will first add the code to
load the Facebook JavaScript SDK,
as shown here.
Be sure to substitute the value
here with the code for your APP ID.
This next function calls
the SDK asynchronously, so
that the rest of the page
can load without it.
The code here uses the Facebook SDK
in order to create a Facebook
log in button.
I can write whatever I want
inside the Facebook button here.
This button also specifies the scope of
authorization my app wants to request.
When my button is clicked I'm also
going to invoke this send token to
server method.
So now we'll create a send Token To
Server method here inside of one of
my script texts.
This function here retrieves
my short-lived accessToken.
Here, I'm just showing how I can use
the Facbook SDK to also make API calls.
Now I sent the access token
to the server via Ajax,
along with the state value.
I will name the route fbconnect, which I
will now implement on the client side.