In the last chapter we learned about
the service worker life cycle.
Thankfully you don't have to keep
all of that state in your head,
there are dev tools for that.
At the time of recording this, some of
our dev tools are still in development,
but I recommend giving them a go.
I'm using Chrome Canary which is
google's almost nightly build of chrome
with all the experimental stuff.
As a developer, I recommend installing
it so you get all the new features and
tools before everyone else.
It runs completely independently
of regular chrome, so
installing this won't mess
with your other settings.
Check out the instructor's notes for
links to download Chrome Canary and
once you've launched Canary
open the WITTR up again.
Once you've got Canary all set up,
check the check box and
we'll have a play with
the latest dev tools.