Today I'm talking with Graham Grieve
the project leader of the global
HL-7 Fire Standardization Effort.
He's here all the way from Melbourne,
Australia for
an HL-7 meeting this week in Atlanta.
Graham thank you very much for
taking the time to be with me.
I know this is a busy week for you.
Perhaps we could begin by you
discussing your background.
>> So I qualify as a biochemist,
worked in a clinical lab,
did a bit of research.
And then I ended up as a lab
systems vendor, tech lead and
got more involved in
interoperability and HL-7 and
eventually created my own consulting
compan to do HL-7 consulting.
>> So beginning in 2011,
you invented the whole idea of fire
can you tell us how that happened?
>> We were getting to a point
where the HL-7 was a crossroads.
We had a lot of existing standards
that no longer reflected what people
wanted to do, and it was a lot of
unhappiness in the user community.
And we said well,
what if we did something like this?
And it grew into Fire and
it was a bit of a surprise to me as much
as everyone else that it was so popular.
But it's been certainly
keeping me busy ever since.
>> By all accounts the growth of Fire
adoption is nothing short of phenomenal.
Could you give us an idea of how it's
being adopted not just here in the US
but around the world?
>> Well, we expected that initially
while it's still a trial,
beta standard which it still is, that
we would have a little bit of adoption
particularly in companies doing health
data exchange in the social web area.
But it's just been crazy.
We have government programs,
large government programs and
other insane programs, other national
governments around the world.
They have big vendors creating
consortiums like Argonaut and HSPC.
Lots of little companies and
institutions creating
solutions based on Fire.
We have thousands of
happening at the moment.
>> So I believe the ballot on Fire as
a second version of a draft standard for
trial use was just conducted,
or is being conducted.
Where are we in the whole evolution
of Fire to a full HL-7 standard.
>> So
we have balanced it to standard in May.
And then we just published last
week in September, the second,
formal second version.
It's an ongoing process but
we started with a very initial draft.
And then this is I think of this is
the first fully usable version and
we're calling it a trial version.
So we can still introduce new content
and refine the core standard but
increasingly, we're going to treat
the core as a normative standard.
And I think the next version will
represent a stable version for
implementors to base the core
of clinical stuff on.
But it's an ongoing process and we'll be
very driven by the feedback we get from
the community about that, which is why
we're not saying right now how it will
unfold, we don't want to
dictate to the community.
>> Well, I've heard numbers in terms of
the ultimate number of Fire resources,
anywhere from 100 to 200, I suppose
nobody actually knows at this point.
>> Well,
we have been a success off today.
And we sort of said 200
was a nice the number.
We didn't want to have thousands or
hundreds of thousands,
which were possible choices.
We haven't got a fixed number
that we're going to get to.
>> So
that leads directly to a topic you and
I have discussed when we
were together in the past.
To me obviously the use
of Web services and
JSON objects these technologies
that are so common in other domains
is very interesting I think very
important to the success of Fire.
But perhaps even more interesting is
your mission of not allowing Fire
to become an overly complex
standard like many of
the predecessor standards in HL-7.
How is that going?
That must be a very tough thing to do.
>> It's an interesting thing to try and
do.
We have constant pressures to try and
simplify it and constant pressures
to try and complicate it.
And we've got to strike
a balance between
handling the things people need
to do and not letting it get so
complicated no one can
do what they need to do.
Most of the success in that area
comes from the processes that we
laid down at the start
around solid engagement with
the implementation community and
and being responsive to them.
And we grade the successive parts of
the standard not by publication but
by adoption and that's a very
important metric that drives a wider
consideration of the perspective than
just how do we produce a standard?
>> So the people who only
have to use this standard and
implement it have a big voice in
what the standard looks like and
it isn't just designed by I'll
use the term standards geeks.
I hope that isn't a pejorative term.
>> It's a very common term.
That's exactly what we're
trying to achieve so
that you can define on
the standard as a committee.
But until it's been adopted and
proven in practice,
it's always going to be draft.
>> So as you look out toward
the future after the final version of
Fire is published, how do you
see it continuing to evolve and
adapt to an ever changing world?
>> Any community goes through a phases
of storming, norming, conforming.
And clearly the core of
the specification is moving into
the norming phase and
will become more and more stable and
growth will happen at the margins.
And then some point where you'll
say to the standard has now
got as big as it can be.
It's no longer sufficient to keep
growing and to keep pushing it along and
it's time to start
considering a new choice.
I kind of thought just looking at
the past record of standards that
a development lifespan might be 15 years
or so and we're sort of 5 of 15 now.
And then at that point,
you start to say maybe it's no
longer worth keeping going.
That's ten years out.
We'll see how we go.
But at some point, you go it's
just not worth keeping going.
>> So one final question.
So what would you say to the students
taking this cours about Fire and
about how they might both think
about it, use it, and look for
opportunities that Fire creates?
>> Fire's really different to all the
other approaches we've had because it
allows you to modularize
your solutions and
to create capabilities that can be
used in all sorts of different ways.
And so in the long term,
it's going to represent decomposing
large systems into more
interoperable small systems.
And there's going to be
a lot of opportunity for
changing the health care system,
not IT but in healthcare itself driven
by the capabilities of the decomposition
and the flexibility that it offers.
We didn't write Fire because we
wanted to have a nice standard.
We wrote Fire because we wanted the
implementations to drive a better health
care system.
And that's going to be our main
focus going forwards is we'll round
out the standard and
finalize the standard.
But our main focus is going to be how
do we drive that to get a health care
system that's more nimble, more patient
focused, more responsive to change,
because the existing system's
pretty pretty rigid.
>> Well, I not only want to thank you.
I want to tell you how much I
admire you and what you're doing.
I'm a lot older than you are.
I'm not even sure you were born
when I got involved in health IT.
And I never thought I'd actually
live to see what we're seeing,
which I agree with you completely is
an absolutely workable implementable
deployable solution to and
to actually making health data
a tool for improving health care.
So congratulations, thank you so much.
>> Thanks.