[Narrator] Now why do we have to interleave
planning and execution?
Mostly because of properties of the
environment that make it difficult to deal with.
The most important one is
if the environment is
stochastic.
That is if we don't know for sure what
an action is going to do.
If we know what everything is going to do,
we can plan it our right from the start, but if we don't, we have to
be able to deal with contingencies of
say I tried to move forward,
and the wheels slipped, and I went someplace else,
or the brakes might skid, or
if we're walking our feet don't go 100% straight,
or consider the problem of traffic lights.
If the traffic light is red,
then the result of the action of go
forward through the intersection
is bound to be different than if the traffic light is green.
Another difficulty we have to deal with
is multi-agent environments.
If there are other cars and people that can get in our way,
we have to plan about what they're going to do,
and we have to react when they do something unexpected,
and we can only know that
at execution time, not at planning time.
The other big problem is with
partial observability.
Suppose we've come up with a plan
to go from A to S to F to B.
That plan looks like it will work,
but we know that at S,
the road to F is sometimes closed,
and there will be a sign there
telling us whether it's closed or not,
but when we start off, we can't read that sign.
So that's partial observability.
Another way to look at it is when we start off
we don't know what state we're in.
We know we're in A, but we don't know
if we're in A in the state where
the road is closed or if we're in A
in the state where the road is open,
and it's not until we get to S
that we discover what state we're actually in,
and then we know if we can continue along
that route or if we have to take a detour south.
Now in addition to these properties of
the environment, we can also have
difficulty because of
lack of knowledge on our own part.
So if some model of the world is unknown,
that is, for example,
we have map or GPS software
that's inaccurate or incomplete,
then we won't be able to
executive a straight-line plan,
and, similarly, often we want to deal with
a case where the plans have to be
hierarchical.
And, certainly, a plan like this
is at a very high level.
We can't really execute the action
of going from A to S
when we're in a car.
All the actions that we can actually execute
are things like turn the steering wheel a little bit
to the right, press on the pedal a little bit more.
So those are the low-level steps of the plan,
but those aren't sketched out in detail when we start,
when we only have the high-level parts of the plan,
and then it's during execution that we schedule
the rest of the low-level parts of the plan.
Now most of these difficulties can be
addressed by changing our point of view.
Instead of planning in the space of world states,
we plan in the space of belief states.
To understand that let's look at a state.