We've created a script to
change our scene to the island.
However, right now, since we have to
manually type 00-FallingCoconut into
our script,
it will also go to the island scene.
But, if we make the scene name
a variable, we can give our method
the name of any scene and
it will load that scene for us.
So let's do that now.
So go back to MonoDevelop and
instead of it saying 00-FallingCoconut,
let's change this to sceneName.
But where does scene name come from?
Well, what we can do is actually put it
as a parameter to this method,
right here.
And what this means is,
whenever we call GoToScene,
we also have to specify
some name to go to.
And then whatever name that we
specify will be the scene that we load
down here.
So this is another way
of using variables.
And you can put a variable
right here beside a method.
And any time that you use that method
you just have to specify the variable.
So let's do that now.
So let's go back to Unity,
go to our vacation box, and scroll down.
And you'll see that it can't find any
method called go to scene anymore,
because we changed it.
We have a different method now,
that expects a scene name.
So let's go scroll down and
find that method.
So ChangeScene &gt; GoToScene and you'll
see in parenthesis it says string.
So it's detected that we
will need to supply a string
which will be the name of our scene.
So, let's click on that, and
now we have a textbox and
this is where we type the name
of the scene that we want to visit
when we click on this vacation box.
Just like last time, let's go ahead and
copy and paste the name of the scene,
which is 00-FallingCoconut.
I'm going to go back
to the vacation box,
scroll down,
find that text box in the event trigger,
and paste the name of the scene
that we want to visit.
I'm going to press Ctrl+s and save,
and then try it one more time.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And there we go, it works.
Same as before.
So the reason why we did
this is that it's much,
much easier and more configurable for
us to reuse this script across
different objects in our VR world.
So now,
instead of just being able to visit the
island scene, you can visit any scene.
Now, load this build on to your phone
and try it out in a cardboard viewer.
You'll notice that it works
just as it did in Unity.
With the only difference being that,
now when you depress the trigger,
it counts as a click.
Give it a try.