Here is the answer.
That is the plateau occurs at y0 = w*/w.
It's the maximum possible value
this expression could take.
Just take i and
let it go to infinity and
you should be able to convince
yourself that that's true.
Now what this ratio also tells you
is that if you design an algorithm
that is not work optimal with respect
to w*, then you will pay a penalty.
That penalty will be reduced
maximum performance.
So what about the critical point,
x zero.
Again, according to this formula,
you reach the critical point
as soon as I is equal to B.
Overall, this says that when
you design an algorithm,
a good target is to try to get
an intensity that is B or greater.
By the way this is a good point
to introduce some terminology,
if your algorithm is to the right of
x zero we say it's compute bound,
if on the other hand it's to
the left we say it's memory bound.