Now that our project is imported,
let's get it fired up.
We'll do most of our prototyping
using the desktop back end
since it launches the fastest and
doesn't require an external device.
So, what we need to do is tell Gradle
that we want to run the desktop version
and we can do that with this
console command right here.
If we run ./gradlew desktop:run,
and wait for
Gradle to do its thing, there we go.
Beautiful Udacity orange.
And if we click and drag around, whoa!
Super sweet particle effects!
All right, so
it's not really a game yet.
We'll get there.
While you certainly can run all your
games from the command line like this,
it's really convenient to be able
to hit the green Run button and
have your project run.
You can also use the Ctrl+R keyboard
shortcut, however, to do that,
we need to set up a run configuration.
Don't worry, it's not too complicated.
We simply click on this drop down and
select Edit Configurations.
Then we can hit the plus button.
Since we want to run a Gradle task,
we'll click Gradle.
We'll give it the name Desktop, and
then the task we want to run is
in the desktop project and
the task is called run.
If we click OK,
now we see that the current selected
run configuration is Desktop.
And if we hit the green arrow,
there we go.
Our game runs just as before.
So now it's direction
to run the desktop app.
To set up the run configuration,
you can go to Run > Edit Configurations,
click +, select Gradle,
name your new run configuration Desktop,
give it the task, desktop:run, click OK.
Then you can hit the green arrow in
the toolbar and poke at your screen for
a while,
which I guess will make you profit.