Now, the next choice we have in agent design
revolves around how adventurous he wants to be.
One possibility is what's called the passive reinforcement learning agent--
and that can be any of these agent designs,
but what passive means is that the agent
has a fixed policy and executes that policy.
But it learns about the reward function, R,
and maybe the transition function, P,
if it didn't already know that.
It learns that while executing the fixed policy.
So let me give you an example.
Imagine that you're on a ship in uncharted waters
and the captain has a policy for piloting the ship.
You can't change the captain's policy.
He or she is going to execute that, no matter what.
But it's your job to learn all you can about the uncharted waters.
In other words, learn the reward function,
given the actions and the state transitions
that the ship is going through.
You learn, and remember what you've learned,
but that doesn't change the captain's policy--
and that's passive learning.
Now, the alternative is called
active reinforcement learning--
and that's where we change the policy as we go.
So let's say, eventually, you've done such a great job
of learning about the uncharted water
that the captain says to you,
"Okay--I'm going to hand over control
and as you learn, I'm going to allow you
to change the policy for this ship.
You can make decisions of where we're going to go next."
And that's good, because you can start to
cash in early on your learning
and it's also good because it gives you
a possibility to explore.
Rather than just say: What's the best action I can do right now?--
you can say: What's the action that might allow me to learn something--
to allow me to do better in the future?