The calling mask property tells
the camera which layers of the scene
it should render in the image.
A layer is simply a group that we
can place any game object into.
To explore this,
let's create a simple cube.
Go to GameObject &gt; 3D &gt; Cube.
Now take a look at
the top of the inspector.
See the Layer drop-down?
By default, any game object we create
will be placed in the default layer.
Let's go ahead and
open up the drop-down.
As you can see, Unity gives us five
different layers to play around with.
In generic cases,
we can use these layer names.
But, we can also create our own
layers by clicking add layer.
That will open up the tags and
layers panel.
Unity reserves the first eight
layers for it's own names and
potential future names.
Let's go ahead and create a new
layer for our cube called NinjaCube.
Once you've typed the name of the layer,
find the cube in the hierarchy, and
navigate to the layer drop-down.
Select Ninja Cube.
Let's bring up the camera and
the inspector again.
Now that we know what a layer is we
can better understand what the calling
mask does.
As mentioned before the calling
mask lets us choose which
lairs surrender in our image.
By default a camera will
lender every layer.
if we click the drop down we
can see all layers listed and
can check which ones we
want the camera to lender.
Let's unselect NinjaCube.
You can see that our cube is still
in the seen view but if we go
over to the game view, you'll realize
that it's going to just like a ninja.
We can of course bring it back
by enabling the NinjaCube layer.
And boom, it's back.
The calling mask is one way to
efficiently render parts of our scene
and hide others until the time is right.