Now, one of the advantages for
setting up provider and all this
infrastructure is so that we can take
advantage of various family
classes such as the cursor loader.
And I showed this diagram
earlier lesson three and
briefly describe that cursor loaders
were able to query the provider for
pet data and then help us
automatically refresh the list of pets
in the UI when any
underlying data changes.
So for example, if a new pet gets added
to the database, or perhaps a pet gets
updated there, then this list will get
refreshed to show the latest changes.
So before we start, let's first figure
out what the heck a cursor loader is.
So a cursor loader is a loader
that queries the ContentResolver
with a specific URI and
returns to us a cursor.
So in other words,
the loader loads data from a certain
URI and returns back a cursor.
Now, we first learned about loaders
back in the networking course, for
building out the quake report app.
So there, we had a download information
from the Internet into our app.
And more specifically,
we're trying to fetch earthquake data
from the USGS server on a background
thread using an AsyncTaskLoader.
So since there could be a body or
potentially a slow internet connection
on the device, this network request
could potentially take a long time.
And therefore, it should not be
happening on the main thread.
Remember that the main
thread is responsible for
handling all user input and
any drawing operations.
So things such as this click button
events but performing this time
intensive works on the main thread,
the app could potentially freeze up and
maybe not even respond to
other user input events and
nobody wants an unresponsive app.
So remember don't perform any long
running operations on the main thread.
Now, as a result we move the HTTP
request to a background thread using
an AsyncTaskLoader and we created
a custom loader called EarthquakeLoader.
Now, within the EarthquakeLoader
class we had to over ride
the load in background method.
So inside this method we perform
the HTTP network request.
So they could be performed
on a background thread.
And once that was set up
in the earthquake class
we implemented the loader
callbacks to create the loader and
then handled the result that
came back in onload finish.
Finally, we initialized the loader in
the oncreate method of the activity.
And the Earthquake data was
magically loaded into the app and
then we all lived happily ever after.
So after the recap, we should
probably get back to the pets app.
And where exactly are we?
Yeah.
So we were talking about loaders and
how we can use it to fetch
pet data from the database.
So specifically we want our
cursor loader because our data
is in the form of a cursor.
So just like network operations that
are expensive and time consuming so
are database operations.
Things like reading and
writing to a pets table.
So currently we're performing
the ContentResolver query method
on the main thread in the call activity.
But we don't want to
bluff the UI thread.
So a loader allows us to do
the operation on a background thread.
Now, as we mentioned earlier, the loader
is tied to a URI as its source for data.
And coincidentally,
we've already set up URI's for
all our data within Pet Provider,
such good foresight.
And furthermore, when the underlying
data in the database changes,
the loader will automatically
recreate the data at the same URI.
Now, this is awesome because the list
of pets in our UI won't be out of date.
And we also won't have to keep manually
recreating the database over and
over again,
wondering is new data getting added?
So this behavior here requires a couple
of tweaks to our provider, but
we'll be walking you through how to do
that exactly a little bit later on.
So as you can tell there are multiple
benefits to using the cursor loader, so
let's dive right in and
see how to implement this.