During the last lecture, we talked about processes and process management.
We said that a process is represented with its address space and
its execution context.
And this has registers and stack and stack pointer.
This type of process, the process that's represented in this way,
can only execute at one CPU at a given point of time.
If we want a process to be able to execute on multiple CPUs,
to take advantage of multi-CPU systems, of multi-core systems today,
that process has to have multiple execution contexts.
We call such execution context within a single process, threads.
In this lecture, we will explain what threads are, and
how they differ from processes.
We will talk about some of the basic data structures and mechanisms that
are needed to implement threads, and to manage and coordinate their execution.
We will use Birrell's paper,
An Introduction to Programming with Threads, to explain some of these concepts.
And this is an excellent paper that describes fundamentals of multithreading,
synchronization, and concurrency.
In a later lesson,
we will talk about a concrete multithreading system called Pthreads.