All right, so now that we have
a mental model of the app in our head,
let's talk about how we're going to
modify the app in lesson one.
In this lesson we'll learn how
to create new activities and
navigate to them using Intents.
That'll allow us to have
multiple screens in our app.
This will involve revisiting
many concepts, like Intents,
that we learned in the Android for
beginners course.
Then we'll move into demystifying
how the click is actually handled in
Android.
From there, we'll learn more
about event listeners and
a new concept called interfaces.
These key steps will set
up a good foundation for
our app as well as a good foundation for
the object-oriented programming
concepts to enter in lesson two.
First we're going to dive deeper
into the MainActivity.java file.
This class should look pretty familiar
to you based on your experience from
the Just Java app in the last course.
Read through the file as best you can.
It's expected that you won't
understand all the syntax.
And there's no need to memorize
every line of code in this file.
We just want you have a basic
understanding of the important parts
of this file.
Then if you need to change anything
later, you'll know which part to go to.
After you've read the file, complete
the following matching exercise.
For each block of code on the right,
figure out what text description
accurately describes it.
Put the letter A through
E in the blanks here.
And we know that you haven't seen some
of these vocabulary words before.
So you may have to do some research or
educated guessing.
And if you do need help, search online
in the Android documentation using
the text descriptions here on the left.