Over this weekend, you will learn
about a variety of Firebase tools and
you will use them to create
a chat app called Friendly Chat.
The Friendly Chat app gives us a chance
to implement many of the features of
Firebase.
So that at the end of the course, you
have enough foundation to be comfortable
with diving deeper into
the features on your own.
You should be comfortable already with
making a simple mobile application
using a basic command line.
You should definitely have experience
calling a web or cloud API.
Using Friendly Chat, your users can sent
and receive text and photo messages.
Five basis of platform
with the tools and
infrastructure you need to build
better apps for your business.
Why would you use Firebase at all?
Traditionally, may apps need to
access data over the network, but
this isn't always
a straightforward process.
Let's say that we're designing
a chat app like Friendly Chat, but
then we're without using Firebase.
We need to decide where we
are going to store the messages, so
we need to choose a database.
And then in order to access that
database, we also need to choose and
setup the server that's perfectly
accessible on the internet.
We then need to decide where we will
store larger items like photos,
because database storage and file
storage are often two separate services.
So to glue all of these services
together, we'll need an app server.
And on this app server,
we then take the request from our app.
We route in to the different services.
So, we need to write code to communicate
via the server with a database and
file storage.
Then we also need to pick a platform for
handling authentication, so
that we can monitor and control who
uses the app's features and we need to
implement whatever app code is necessary
to use this authentication service.
There are also separate options for
other features that we may want to
include in the app like analyzing user
engagements, showing advertisements and
maybe doing push notifications, but we
have to do the hard work in connecting
all of these surfaces together and
that's a lot of work.
Most of that work has nothing to do
with what makes our app unique and
fun to use.
All of it is plumbing,
front work and infrastructure.
There's so much involved with setting up
what should really a simple chat app.
I'm tired just thinking about it.
There's no way we could make an app
like that in just a weekend.
But if we use the tools and
the infrastructure provided by Firebase,
we could really make
Friendly Chat in just a weekend.
Because Firebase handles authentication,
authorization and data storage and
much more, so that you don't have to.
Firebase provides easy ways
to enable many features.
We will include the following
features in our Friendly Chat app.
We use the Firebase Realtime Database
to store data in the cloud and
to keep it in sync between users.
Firebase storage gives you a place
to store user uploaded content,
such as photos, audio and video.
Authentication is easier than
it's ever been in the Firebase.
Firebase handles all for requests
to verify the user's identity, so
that you don't have to write that code
to your app and analytics are included
to contract of how your app is being
used, then Firebase notifications
enables you to reengaged parts of your
audience from easy to use web interface.
You can send notifications to all your
users, to just a specific group of users
or even to a single user, so you can
target messages to different audiences.
With Firebase Remote Config,
you can test changes to your app and
see how they impact users.
This allows you to change the feature in
your app without rolling out an update.
You could even target groups
of users since you can
compare the success of
different configurations.
I know this sounds like a lot of work,
but believe it or not, you apply
all of these features to create a
Friendly Chat app in just this weekend.
Let's get started.