Now that you have a SettingsActivity,
you can make a PreferenceFragment.
Do the following steps.
First thing is to add a support
preference library to the gradle file.
You can copy it from
the instructor notes below.
And then create an xml folder
under the res directory and
create a preference xml
file in that folder.
Inside, create both an EditTextPeference
and an ListPreference.
The EditTextPreference would be used for
the location, and the list for
the units.
And don't forget to use
the resource files.
Then create a class called
SettingsFragment and
have it extend
the PreferenceFragmentCompat.
After that, replace the layout for the
settings activity with a fragment tag.
Make sure to add the correct theme,
so that it actually runs.
And finally,
implement the updates to the preference
summaries when the values are changed.