All right, so 1,
keep track of the MDP we have so far.
We're saying that any unknown state
action pair is an arm act self loop.
We can get the maximum amount of reward
and we can get back to that state and
get it again and again.
So clearly,
there's no policy that's going to be
better than that from that state.
>> Right.
>> So then we're going to solve the MDP,
again,
with the assumption that
anything we don't know is Rmax.
>> So solve the MDP assuming 1 and 2.
>> And then we go back to 1,
essentially, right?
>> Well,
you just execute the optimal policy.
>> Like that.
Yeah, and
then as we take those action we
may discover that some of the 8
action pairs were wrong, but
we'll just fix that by doing 1.
And we'll just solve the new MDP.
>> Good, all right, so
there's a couple of things we need
to convince ourselves about this.
One is that we get
Epsilon optimal reward.
>> Yeah.
>> Another one is that the number of
mistakes that it makes is going to be
relatively small.
>> I think the second one's
probably pretty easy, right?
>> Well, let's go through it.