First I'll look at what happens if I
add two series with the same index.
So here are both series 1 and
series 2 have the index a, b, c, d.
When I add these series together,
the results aren't surprising.
The first element from each
series is added together,
the second element from each series
is added together and so on.
Now we'll take a look at a case where
the two series have the same indexes,
but the values are in a different order.
So series 1 still has the index a,
b, c, d, but
series 2 now has the index b, d, a, c.
Now when I add these
two series together,
I can see that the matching up has been
done by index rather than by position.
Instead of adding the first two
values together, both values for
index a have been added together,
both values for
index b have been added together,
and so on.
Now we'll take a look at two series
where the indexes don't have exactly
the same values.
Here, both series 1 and series 2 have c
and d, but only series 1 has a and b,
and only series 2 has e and f.
When I add these two series,
I see that c and d,
the index values in common,
have been matched up.
For index values that were only
present in one series, a, b, e and
f, NaN is the result,
which stands for not a number.
Given that, I have a hypothesis for
what will happen when I add series with
indexes that don't overlap at all.
But I'll still try it and see.
So in this case,
series 1 has index values a, b, c and d.
And series 2 has index e, f, g, and h.
Sure enough, when I add them together,
I get all the index values from both
series and value in each case is NaN.
By the way, other vectorized operations
with series work the same way.
Values are matched up based
on index not position.
And if an index value is
present in one series but
not another, the resulting value
will be NaN, for not a number.