You've made a good point.
Hm.
So
Firebase is not storing all of the data
that you need to represent a user
in the AuthData object.
Don't get me wrong,
when you log in, Firebase does provide
a bit of information about the user, and
it passes along most of that
information in the AuthData object.
But the pivotal thing is that you can't
control the properties that are stored
in the AuthData object.
If you need to associate data with
a user beyond whats in the AuthData
object, you need to explicitly store
it in your own Firebase database.
And because Firebase doesn't store a lot
of app-specific data about the user.
This is a fairly common
practice among devs.
Many developers will have user objects
that hold app-specific user information
that not available in
the AuthData object.
So, as we have done other times in
the app when we need to create new data,
we are going to make a POJO.
>> Yehey!
>> Your POJO should include a Name,
an Email for
convenience although it is technically
part of the AuthData object.
And a Timestamp for
when the user joined.
Now, what I want to know is
where in the code should you add
your new users to Firebase?
Well, there are two ways
that a user can log in.
With Google and
then with email and password.
And the code watch would be
a bit different for each.
So I'm going to start with a spec for
implementing the email and
password functionality.
Okay, so in what class do you
think you should create and
write your users to
the Firebase database?
Specifically for
the email password provider.
You can put your answer here.