So did you try out all
those different queries?
If you did, you've seen several
modifiers that you can put on
select statements,
these are called select clauses.
Where is one of them too.
Limit offset is what you'd use if you
wanted to make several pages of results,
it takes two numbers.
The limit number tells how many
results go on one page, and
the offset,
tells how far into the results to start.
So if you wanted ten rows from your
table starting with the 151st row,
you'd use limit 10 offset 150.
Another clause is order by,
order by lets you say how you'd
like your results to be sorted.
That'll usually be by one or
more columns.
If you want them sorted from
the largest to the smallest, that is,
in descending order, then you add
desc to the end, for descending.
So if you wanted to do a query
against the animals table sorted first
by species.
And then within each species by name,
you'd say, order by species, name.
A clause that works a little
bit differently is group by.
You'll only ever use it with
aggregations like count, or sum.
What group by does is to say instead
of aggregating over all the rows,
just aggregate the ones that
share some column value.
LIke if you wanted to find out how
common different names are in the zoo,
you might do this.
Here we use as,
to give the count column a name.
Here the name is num.
So here's a quiz.
Here are three different situations.
Find the ten oldest gorillas.
List all the animals,
in alphabetical order, ten per page.
And find out which one species
we have the most animals of.
For each of these situations, which ones
of these select clauses would you use?
Where, limit, offset,
order by, or group by.
Check all of the boxes that fit.