Here we talked about
the nature of the data, okay?
It's sensitive data who
gets paid how much.
Company obviously doesn't want to
disclose that to people for
whatever reasons,
even within the company or outside.
So the user who is creating this file
is obviously should not be able to
share it with whoever he or
she feels like.
Even if they try to be cautious and
careful, remember, they can make
a mistake or they may not be.
We talk about going back to threat
models, talk about insider threat.
Someone can be unhappy and do
something that could harm the company.
So it shouldn't be at the discretion
of this user who is creating a file.
This kind of data really needs to, the
company needs to, not just mandate but
control how it can be shared.
So, really, this is an example
of where a mandatory access
control model would be the right one for
controlling access to
the data that is in this file
that has people's salaries.
DAC and MAC,
these are two different models.
And this is a scenario where DAC is
not going to be able to address or
meet the needs that we have for
how this data should be accessed.