So let's really think about what we're doing when we're executing
the active TD learning algorithm.
First, we're keeping track of the optimal policy we've found so far;
and that gets updated as we go,
and replaced with new policies.
Secondly, we're keeping track of the utilities of states--
and those, too, get updated as we go along.
And third, we're keeping track of the number
of times that we visited each state.
And that gets incremented on each trial.
Now, what could happen? What could go wrong?
There are really 2 reasons
why our utility estimates could be off.
First, we haven't sampled enough.
The end values are too low for that state
and the utilities that we got were just some
random fluctuations and weren't
a very good, true estimate.
And secondly, we could get a bad utility
because our policy was off.
The policy was telling us to do something that wasn't really the best thing,
and so the utility wasn't as high as it could be.
So let's do a little quiz.
I want you to tell me, for the 2 sources of possible error--
too little sampling and wrong policy--
I want you to tell me, is it True or False--each of these statements:
One: Could the error--either the sampling error or the policy error--
could that make the utility estimates too low?
And secondly, could it make utility too high?
And third, could it be improved with higher N values--that is, more trials?