Once you've stored data in an array,
you then want to be able to access and
manipulate each element in the array
without having to operate on
each element one at a time.
For instance, if this was our
original donuts array and
we decided to make all of
the same donut types but
sell them as donut holes instead,
we could write the following code.
This code seems simple enough but
it's actually pretty horrible.
It's repetitive and not scalable for
large number of donuts.
But the good news is,
you don't have to do this.
You have a better tool that
you've seen before, loops.
Here's a for loop that we can use
to loop over the array of donuts.
To loop over the array,
you can use a variable to
represent the index in the array.
And then loop over that index to
perform whatever manipulations
your heart desires.
in this example,
the variable i is being used to
represent the index of the array.
The loop keeps going until just
before donuts.Length is reached and
then donuts i is used to
change the names in the array.
So, this is pretty cool but
since we're working with an array,
we have something even
better that we could use.
Arrays actually have a set of methods
like can be used when looping over them.
Here's an example of
a method called forEach.
forEach can be used to loop over
the elements and the array.
myAwesomeFunction is just
the function that you defined and
that will be used to perform some
operation on each element in the array.
Note that myAwesomeFunction has three
parameters, element, which refers
to the actual value of the element
in the array, not the array index.
For the array index, we have
a different parameter called index,
which refers to the elements index.
And finally array, which is just
the array that you started with.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Here's an example of for
each with the donuts array from before.
See how the printDonuts function is
passed into the for each method?
The for each method will execute that
function for each element in the array.
You can also see that the printDonuts
function has only one parameter,
donut, which corresponds to each
donut element in the array.
There's no need for
index variables here or
the array parameter so,
we're going to leave those out.
This code is looking
pretty good right now but
there's one more thing we can do.
Since we know that this printDonuts
function is never really going to be use
anywhere else in our code,
we could define it as an inline
function expression like this.
See, much cleaner.