We did it, physics and
audio in one lesson.
&gt;&gt; Right, and although it was a lot
of stuff to cover all at once,
as usual, to have this first exposure
is really what you need to get started.
And from here, you know which
directions you can take it.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so now's a great opportunity to
practice and play with the scripting in
all of these components we've
already played around with.
&gt;&gt; Right, and don't worry,
you're not going to have to do
this exploration all on your own.
We have some really great examples that
we prepared, and we'll be going through
those with you so that you can be
accelerated into your exploration.
&gt;&gt; So
let's dive in to the Udacity scripts.