Here I am in the iOS simulator.
Prepackaged with the simulator
are several different apps,
including Apple Maps.
To get Maps to actually focus in
on a location, we need to go to
the debug settings, and set our location
to one of the predefined locations.
Or you could even put in
your own custom location.
I'll just select Apple for now.
Then if you click the arrow in
the bottom left-hand corner,
it'll ask us whether we want to allow
Maps to use our location or not.
We'll click Allow.
And now we're focused in
on the location of Apple.
I'm going to start dragging
around on the map.
I want you to pay attention to
what's happening as I approach
into new areas that
haven't been loaded yet.
As we expect the map just continues to
load in these new grid squares, for
new locations on the map.
Now here's the fun part.
I'm going to use a networking tool,
which I'll introduce in just a moment,
to change our packet loss to 100%.
Essentially we have no
network connection.
My question to you is, what will happen
when I start dragging this map around,
when we have 100% packet loss?
Will Maps crash?
Will Maps display an error message that
we've lost the network connection?
Will Maps even allow us to drag at all?
Or will Maps load empty grid squares?
Put a check next to your answer.