Okay, it's time to start another
coding exercise, finally.
Open t2.4-Exercise-ConnectToTheInternet.
After all that Internet lecture and
quiz stuff,
you might guess that we'll start by
adding that INTERNET permission.
We go to android manifest.xml and
add the internet permission now.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Then we just have to change
the makeGitHubSearchQuery method to call
network utils that get response from URL
rather than simply displaying the URL.
Store the response in a string
called GitHubSearchResults.
Watch out though, because you're also
have to cache that io exception.
Since we want to see the result
we'll call set text on our search
results text view.
So, now it's your turn!
Follow the to-dos.
Add the Internet permission
to the Android manifest.
Call getResponseFromUrl in your
makeGithibSearchQuery method.
Set the results in the search results
text view and watch things crash.
So, look in the Android monitor logcat,
what error do you see from your
application when it tries
to connect to the internet?