Back when we used Gamespace UI we used
the Unity event system to color code
whenever those events fired.
&gt;&gt; Right and using the Gamespace UI
is great because it would
automatically handle layer you interact
with, whatever you were looking at.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, but suppose now we actually
want to color code regardless of what
we're looking at.
&gt;&gt; Right,
if you want to create a custom events.
So like say something
happens after ten seconds or
when you reach a certain point.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, and for
that we need to use C-Sharp events.
&gt;&gt; The event system.
So the event system can be your friend,
but it's a little complicated.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I mean to be honest,
the first time I looked at it,
it was kind of a little scary and
overwhelming.
&gt;&gt; But don't worry.
It's really important and we're going to
go very carefully so you can master it.
Once you master it, you have so much
more flexibility in what you can do.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so let's just go ahead and
get started with it.