This notation is very succinct.
And so we can actually rewrite some
things that we've talked about already
in this very nice operator based form.
And it makes it look smaller, and
neater, and easier to work with.
So just to try to prove that to you,
the equation Q star, that's a value
function, equals B applied to Q star
is another way of writing something that
we've talked about a bunch of times.
So I was hoping you'd be
able to fill that in here.
And also, the notion that if we
define some value function Qt to be,
like a whole sequence of value
functions, where each value function
Qt is defined as the Bellman
operator applied to Q(t-1).
These both are things that we’ve
talked about and have names,
and I just want to try to get you
to connect those to each other.
>> Okay, I will do my best.