In the olden days of Android,
there wasn't an easy way to schedule
a periodic job with complex run rules,
like, run within 15 minutes, but
only while on WiFi, charging, and
if the job fails, keep re-trying, but
wait more time between re-trying
the job to not overwhelm the network.
And that's a lot of
constraints to keep straight.
Well first,
you'd need to set up a mechanism to
trigger the job after 15 minutes.
Then, when the job was triggered,
you'd need to check all the WiFi and
charging constraints manually.
If the user wasn't on WiFi or
charging, you'd need to manually
calculate when to re-schedule the task.
Your app also would have to
be instantiated all the time
just to check to see if
it has to run your job.
Needless to say,
things were complicated.
Thankfully, there is an easier and
more battery-friendly way.
In Android L,
JobScheduler was introduced.
JobScheduler allows you to simply
grab a reference to a job schedule or
object from the context, create a new
job with all the constraints you wanted,
and then schedule the job whenever
you want by calling js.schedule.
In this course, we'll be using
a class called FirebaseJobDispatcher,
which is a more compatible
version of JobScheduler.
Since JobScheduler was introduced
in Android L, it only provides
compatibility back to API level 21,
whereas FirebaseJobDispatcher provides
compatibility back to
API level 9 Gingerbread.
Here's what using
FirebaseJobDispatcher looks like.
First, you make a GooglePlayDriver, and
use that to create a new
FirebaseJobDispatcher object.
Then you build the job,
specifying all the constraints.
In this case,
the job triggers the MyJobService class.
It has a unique identifier called a tag,
which is set to complex-job.
The job doesn't recur, and it doesn't
persist if the device is rebooted.
It starts between zero and
15 minutes, and
will replace a current job with
the same tag if one exists.
It uses an exponential backoff
strategy as a failure strategy.
Jobs, especially network jobs,
might fail if a server is down.
An exponential backoff strategy
will keep re-trying the job, but
will wait longer and
longer between successive attempts.
Finally, this job will only run on
an unmetered network like WiFi, and
while charging.
Taking a closer look at the timing,
we see that we can set when the job
executes by using the setTrigger method
and passing it an executionWindow.
The times applied here are in seconds.
The first time is how long from when
the job is scheduled at minimum before
the job service executes, and
the second time is the maximum
time before it executes.
The second time must be
greater than the first.
And this all assumes that all of
the other constraints are met.
Other constraints could be things like,
the device is currently plugged in.
So if you put 60 and 120 as these
parameters, the job service would
execute somewhere between 60 seconds and
120 seconds after it's scheduled.
Why the window?
Battery life is saved if the phone
can do a bunch of processing,
especially network calls,
all in a batch.
This allows the phone to stay more
continuously in a low-power state if
the user is not actively using the
phone, which means more battery life for
your user.
Supplying a window lets the system
pick the best time to schedule
your job in that window.
I've provided the sample code below.
Now that you know a little bit
more about FirebaseJobDispatcher,
it's time to make your first job.