To begin, you want to get your
project up-to-date for this task.
To do that, on the command line
in the wittr project directory
run git reset hard to get rid
of any local changes you have.
And git checkout log request
gets the project into the state
where it's registering a service
worker and logging requests.
Over in the service worker script file,
public/js/sw/index.js.
It's just logging requests.
I want you to alter the service
worker so it responds with some HTML.
It can be whatever HTML you want as
long as it includes the class name
a-winner-is-me.
So a strong tag with
the class a-winner-is-me
would be a valid response for this task.
Once you've written the code,
test it's working in the browser.
Like we saw Jake do in the previous
chapter, in the sources tab,
check Force update on page load so
you can see your changes straight away.
You'll know what's working
when you refresh the page and
you get something like this.
To confirm everything's working,
head over to the settings page and
type HTML response into
the test field and press enter.
This will double-check if
everything is working.