In this app,
you can see a map of New York City.
And I have control
over this map by touch.
I can pan around the map and as you can
see, I can pinch to zoom in and out.
When I press the buttons at the top
of the map, map, satellite, and
hybrid, I can change the map type.
So if I touch satellite,
I now can see details of the buildings
taken from satellite pictures.
Here you can see Madison Square Garden.
And even when I zoom in I can begin
to see some of the seating plans in
Madison Square Garden.
And of course,
hybrid gives me a hybrid of the two.
I can see satellite but
I can also see data such as landmarks
like the Empire State Building and
street names such as 5th Avenue,
as you can see here.
I've done all of this using a Google
map object in my Java code.
This is slightly different from the
fragment that you used in the earlier
sample.
We're going to dive in to take
a look at how to do this next.