Okay, so, it seems very much.
This is going to be
broken up into pieces.
So, our first distributed
responsibility here is that
the height is now changed, and
it gets reported to the viewport.
>> Okay.
>> The viewport will look at its
current height and make a determination
of whether it's grown, shrank.
Essentially, then having to
distribute to the scroll bar,
the handle that needs to move, and
also if its proportion needs to change.
>> Okay.
>> That in turn,
will be distributed down
to the file manager from the scroll bar.
It could be that the first distributor
responsibility goes to the scroll bar,
waits on something to come back.
So, actually I think that's the case.
>> Okay, so Jared has raised
an interesting point here.
We know we're eventually going to
have to go to the file manager
to get some more lines.
Is it the scroll bar that
informs the file manager?
Is it the viewport that
informs the file manage?
Because both of them are dependent,
right?
>> Right.
I think it's the viewport.
Because our last example kind
of did a similar thing when
we just moved the handle.
It eventually came back to the viewport.
The viewport reported down to the file
manager, I need these new lines.
It seems like it's going to.
Let's recap here.
We're going to resize the window.
The height is going to
come to the viewport.
It going to then report, or
send a message to the handle about where
it needs to be and its proportion.
That will come back to the viewport, and
the viewport will request from the file
manager any nuance that it needs.
>> Okay, and one of the takeaways from
this is that distributed is just that.
There's different choices
as to who's going to tell
whom else about what's going on, okay?
So although each particular event is,
each particular segment of
code is probably fairly small,
consisting of some method calls,
that are distributed all over the place,
which might make them
hard to understand.