When we talk about image distortion,
we're talking about what happens when
a camera looks at 3D objects
in the real world and
transforms them into a 2D image.
This transformation isn't perfect.
For example, here's an image of a road
and some images taken through different
camera lenses that
are slightly distorted.
In these distorted images, you can see
that the edges of the lanes are bent and
sort of rounded or stretched outward.
And distortion is actually
changing what the shape and
size of these objects appears to be.
This is a problem,
because we're trying to accurately place
the self-driving car in this world.
Eventually, we'll want to look
at the curve of a lane and
steer the correct direction.
But if the lane is distorted,
we'll get the wrong measurement for
curvature in the first place and
our steering angle will be wrong.
So, the frist step in analyzing camera
images is to undo this distortion so
that we can get correct and
useful information out of them.