Here is a short excerpt from
the National Institute of Standards &
Technology's document that
defines cloud computing.
This is a document that was read or
published, rather, on October 25, 2011.
Cloud computing is a model for
enabling ubiquitous, convenient,
on-demand network access to a shared
pool of configurable computing
resources, including network servers,
services.
It can be rapidly provisioned and
released with minimal management effort
or service provider interactions.
I want you to place
the following underline phrases,
which there are five of them,
into these text boxes,
where each text box corresponds to
one cloud computing requirement.
If you need to list multiple
phrases in a single text box,
please comma separate them, and if you
need to leave a text box empty, or
blank rather,
then don't write anything in it.