Now the two indices that Alteryx
produces, the Adjusted Rand Index and
the C-H Index are calculated for
each of those solutions and
then combined to form its own dataset.
The means, medians,
minimums and maximums and
interquartile ranges are all calculated,
so that we can get a sense for
how good the cluster solution is for
each number of clusters that is tested.
Alteryx then provides
a visualization of this data
that is typically a good way
to evaluate the results.
To see the visualizations in Alteryx,
you just need to add a browse tool
to the cluster diagnostics tool and
click run.
Keep in mind that depending on
which clustering method you choose,
the time it takes to go through
this process, because there are so
many iterations, can vary considerably.
On these charts, along the y-axis
is the value of the index.
And the x-axis is
the number of the clusters.
For each cluster number, it displays a
box and whisker plot of the index value.
With the black line
representing the median, and
the blue area representing the area
between the first and third quartile.
The whiskers show how far
out some of the values are.
For the AR Index, the higher the index,
the better the stability of the cluster.
For the C-H Index, the higher the index,
the better the distinctness and
compactness of the clusters.
So what we are looking for is where
the median of the index is high and
the spread of the various
iterations is minimized.
In other words the minimum and maximum
and interquartile range is compact.
In this instance, using the K-Means
method, the Adjusted Rand Index
might indicate that clusters
number 6 and 7 could be good.
With 7 having a little higher median but
with a bit more spread of
the interquartile range.
The C-H Index indicates clusters
number 9 through 12 might work,
with probably 10 being
the best solution,
with that having the highest median and
a fairly compact spread.
These results aren't
all that conclusive.
So the next step would be
to run the same diagnostics
using the two other methods available.
The K-Median and Neural Gas methods and
compare those results to see if
there's a standout kind of solution.
Keep in mind that when
comparing methods,
you need to pay attention to
the scale of the index results.
In this case, the C-H Index
ranges from about 4,000 to 5,700.
When comparing,
the boxplots might look the same but
could be relatively higher or
lower than another method.
Also, this could be where
you begin to reconsider
the variables that you are using
in your clustering process.
With our example, it pretty much
revolves around the actual climate
metrics, so we won't worry about that.
But with other business cases,
such as segmenting a population
of customers, you begin to have
much more flexibility around what you
want to use to determine your clusters.
Again, as a reminder, the type of data
that you use will be dependent on
the objective of your segmentation.
Regardless of
the clustering methodology,
building a clustering model should
be considered an iterative process
where you need to determine how many and
which variables provide the best model,
as well as how many clusters
provide the best model as well.
So a typical process is to run some
initial cluster models, attempt to
validate the results with what is known
both with internal validation methods,
using indices, as well as with external
validation, which we will cover later.
And then we run the modelling process
with differing variables to see
if improvements can be made.
Also as I mentioned,
each software package will
use their own set of indices.
The key here is to make
sure that you understand
what the specific index is measuring and
the appropriate way to evaluate it.