Now, we get to the ugly stuff.
Homogeneous coordinates.
It's not ugly, it's beautiful, for some twisted notion of aesthetic.
So, that operation where we take x over z and y over z.
Is that a linear transformation?
Well, the answer is no.
Now, before we said that well, division's a linear operation.
Sure. Division by some constant by a,
1 over a, multiplying 1 over a, that's a linear operation.
But, here and I take x, y, and z, okay?
I actually have to pull out that z and divide the x and the y by it.
And so, if I've got another point with x1, y1, z1, I divide by that z.
So, it's not a linear operation.
I have to essentially change what's going on.
So what we're going to do is we're going to do a trick.
And the trick is, we're going to add one more coordinate, all right?
And we can do this in either two dimensions or three dimensions.
In two dimensions x,y becomes xy1.
X,y,z becomes xyz1.
And this bottom coordinate, which right now here is written as a 1,
later we're going to, they'll, it'll take other values,
that's the homogeneous edition, the homogeneous coordinate.
Sometimes it's called the scale factor but I, but I think that's inappropriate,
it should just be viewed as the homogeneous coordinate.
Or the homos, homogeneous component of the vector.
So, converting from regular coordinates to homogenous and
back again is pretty easy, right?
If I have the homogeneous coordinate x,y,w I
get the nonhomogeneous by just dividing by w.
So 2dx over w and 3d x, y, and z, each over w.
So now you see why converting xy1 to nonhomogeneous I still get back the x and
y as I had before.
But if that last homogenous coordinate is not 1,
then I'll get a different value.
By the way, this makes homogeneous coordinates invariant under scale.
If I were to multiply the entire homogeneous coordinate by some constant, say a.
So, I have ax, ay, aw.
When I do the conversion back again doing the division, the a just cancels out.