The other app is, of course,
the favorite actor's app.
It's up and running now, and
in truth, it's pretty nice.
I don't think we'd be wrong to
congratulate ourselves, but if we think
about the relationship between our
view controllers and our Core Data,
I think you'll see that there is room
for us to do something even cooler.
Think for a second about
the ActorPickerViewController.
That's the view controller where we type
actors' names into the search bar and
then it continuously pings
the movie database API to get
the corresponding actors.
Then it places those actors into
a scratch Core Data context.
Let's go through that interaction
again one step at a time.
First the view controller initiates
a task, contact in the movie database.
And the result come back
to the view controller.
The result is some actor objects.
Then the view controller inserts the
movies into the scratch database, and
also holds on to them.
That's perfectly fine
as far as things go.
It works like a charm in fact.
So, what's the problem?
The problem is that our view controller
is a little bit over burdened.
One way to think about this is to
consider what it would be like if there
were other entities changing
the Core Data state.
Notice that the way things stand now,
there's no way for
our view controller to know about it.
Another way to think about it is think
of this view controller as a window
into the data.
It's job is to reflect
the state of the data.
It would be really cool
if we could set it up so
that it would always be able to change
its table anytime the data changed.
That would simplify its role.
In that case, the view controller could
begin the task with the movie database
to download the data.
But it could ask the task to
communicate directly with Core Data.
Then it could just sit back and be
content to show the data in Core Data.
Whatever that happens to be.
As the state changes, it would like to
be notified with method and location, so
that it could respond by adding and
removing and updating table rows.
Well, Apple likes this idea a lot,
and if you take the time to
get comfortable with it, we think that
you'll learn to like it a lot too.
What would be better than being
automatically notified of a data change?
To pull this off,
we need an assistant object, an object
that's part of the Core Data library.
An object that's closely
tied to the context, so
they can know when it changes.
An object that's willing to share that
information with our view controller.
That object is not just a fantasy.
It's real.
It's the NSFetchResultsController.
Read on to learn its secrets.