Let's first go through the process of
running and testing a project locally,
then deploying to App Engine.
The app's very simple, and
it runs out of the box.
Let's first run it and
see what it does, and
then take a look at the code
that makes it happen.
First, open up App Engine Launcher.
Add a new project and point to the
directory for the hello endpoints app.
As you can see it gets added and
it will set a port for
the web interface and
different one for the admin interface.
The default port for
app engine is 80/80.
If you add several projects
to the launcher, the port for
the next app you add to
the launcher will be different.
So when testing locally,
pay attention to that port number.
Click the green Run button.
Then click on the Logs button to
see the deployment process, and
if there are any problems.
Look at the logs.
Once the app is deployed,
you'll see several lines.
One will tell you the URL and the port
that the app can be accessed at.
When you go to the URL for
that starting module default,
you should see this page.
Hm, it looks really basic.
Since this course is about
the back end part of the app,
we haven't put any CSS or
any other front end work into it.
So click on the buttons and
see what happens.
You know, my name's not actually Zebra,
so I'm going to change that.
That's much better.
Okay, great.
The local server works.
But if you want other people
to be able to access your app,
you have to deploy it onto App Engine.
Let's do that.
It's actually almost as easy.
You just press the deploy button and
it'll want your Google login.
The password is swordfish, by the way.
Let's take a look in the logs and
see how the deployment process goes.
Hm, appcfg.py has finished
with exit code one.
Exit code one is usually
not a good deal.
Let's see up here.
Begin server output.
This application does not exist.
App ID equals you, your project ID.
Oh, it's complaining that
it can't deploy to that.
That's right.
You have to actually enter your own
app ID into the configuration first.
So remember when you
created an App Engine app,
get that project ID from
the developer's console.
Don't use the one that you see in
this video, it won't work for you.
Get your own.
Then, in the code,
open up app.yaml, and replace your
project ID in the application line
with the one you got from the console.
And save that.
And when you go back to Google App
Engine Launcher you'll see that the name
has already changed.
Now you can deploy the app and
watch in the logs as it gets sent to
app engine compiled and deployed.
Eventually, you'll see,
completed updated of app, and
the URL for your app will
be your app id.appspot.com.
If you go to your app id.appspot.com,
you should see the very same thing.
So you now have the app running
both locally and on App Engine.
So now it's time to
explore how it works.
Let's take a look back at the code.
Let's take a look at helloworldapi.py,
and here we go, endpoints.api,
that sounds familiar.
Look at this, endpoints.method.
Hm, one of these things,
endpoints.api and
endpoints.method, oh this
uses Python decorators.
Maybe we should talk about those first.