Now, when it comes to running
tasks that have the same priority,
we have other options in addition
to the first-come first-serve or
shortest job first that we discussed so
far.
A popular option is so-called
a round robin scheduling.
So let's say we have
the following scenario.
We have three tasks,
they all show up at the same time, and
they're all in the queue.
With round robin scheduling, we'll pick
up the first task from the queue just
like with the first-come,
first-serve scheduling.
Now, let's say we pick up T1,
that's the first in the queue, so
T1 starts executing.
Now, if they're executing for
one time unit,
the task stopped because it now
needs to wait on an I/O operation.
So it will yield the CPU and
be blocked on that I/O operation.
This is unlike what we saw
in first-come first-serve,
where we were assuming that each of
the tasks executes until it completes.
If that's the case, we'll schedule T2.
T3 will move to the front of the queue.
Now, potentially,
T1 will complete its I/O operation and
will be placed at the end
of the queue behind T3.
Then when T2 completes,
we will schedule T3.
The execution time here we
assume is only two time units.
And then when that one completes, we'll
finally pick up T1 from the queue and
complete T1.
If T1 had not been waiting on I/O,
then the execution based on T1,
T2, T3, the order in which
they were placed in the queue,
would've looked something like this.
So each of their tasks executes one
by one in a round robin manner, and
the queue is traversed in
a round robin manner one by one.
We can further generalize round
robin to include priorities as well.
Let's assume that the tasks don't
arrive at the same time, T2, and
T3 arrive a little later, and
that their priorities are as follows,
T1's priority is the lowest and
T3's is the highest.
So in that case, what happens is that
when a higher priority task arrives,
the lower priority
task will be preempted.
If T2 and T3, however,
have the same priorities,
then the scheduler will just go round
robin between them until they complete.
So basically,
in order to incorporate priorities,
we have to include preemption, but
otherwise the tasks will be scheduled
from the queue like in
first-come first-serve.
So, the first task from the queue.
However, we will release the requirement
that they have to control the CPU,
that they have to execute on
the CPU until they complete.
Instead, they may explicitly yield.
And we will just round robin
among the tasks on the queue.
A further modification that makes sense
for round robin is not to wait for
the tasks to yield explicitly,
but instead to interrupt them so
as to mix in all of the tasks that
are in the system at the same time.
We call such mechanism time slicing.
So let's say we can give each of
the tasks a time slice of one time unit.
And then, after a time unit, we will
interrupt them, we will preempt them,
and we will schedule the next task in
the queue in a round robin manner.
So we will cycle through them,
T1, T2, T3, and then again.
We will focus our discussion next
on timeslicing to better explain
this mechanism.