So the way this is done,
is in what's called the dynamic programming formulation.
And it's a little complicated but bear with me.
So what we have here is, I'm going to pretend that I've got the left
scan line signal down here and each of these is supposed to be the pixels.
Although, I noticed there are more dots than pixels.
So, assume that there's as many squares as there are dots in this grid.
And same thing over here.
And let's assume for
a moment that we know that the leftmost pixel here corresponds to this one.
And the rightmost pixel there corresponds to that one, all right?
Well then, a solution to the mapping of the left to the right
is just a path from that top left-hand corner to the right, bottom right corner.
So, there's a particular path, okay?
And the goal is to find the best possible path.
And best possible path meaning the least cost.
Now, when you're located somewhere in this grid,
there's only three different ways that this path can go.
The simplest way is when you go on the diagonal.
Now, when you go on the diagonal, what it means is,
if this pixel was mapping to this one, then this one is mapping to the next one.
That is, they're staying at the same disparity.
So if, if I have to go plus three to match this pixel,
then this one's also plus three.
And I just keep going along.
But, suppose I have some pixels that are visible in one image and
not visible in the next.
So, here I have an, an area that I'm saying is left occlusion.
What I mean by that is visible to the left eye and
is not visible to the right eye.
So, what that means is that all of these pixels,
this range here, are all being mapped to this one location.
So you can think of it as that this pixel was mapped to this pixel, but
all of these were not seen.
So that's a left occlusion.
Correspondingly, you can have right occlusions, all right?
And the goal is to find the least cost through.
Now, when you're going diagonally, you're cost is just the match between two
pixels and that can be a match much like we did before.
[INAUDIBLE] normalized correlations or sum of square differences,
depending upon whether you're doing similarity or dissimilarity.
But when you're not going the one-to-one, but
you're actually doing the occlusion, you're,
what you need to do is pay a price for occlusion pixels.
And a variety of methods have been designed that
tell you that say how to try to assign that cost.
Some of them are Bayesian, some are other ways.
Now, for those of you that know about shortest path or
Dijkstra algorithms or other forms of solving this.
This can be formulated as a dynamic programming problem.
And dynamic programming approaches are nice because they're
computationally efficient.
You don't actually compute all possible paths.
And yet you can still compute the best possible path.
And the only thing required is that you basically have to be
able to evaluate the costs of going horizontal, vertical or diagonal.
And here, I've listed some references,
including one by [UNKOWN] Bobick, that showed about how to do that.
We introduced this thing call ground control points which was a cool way of not
being very sensitive to the occlusion cost value that you use.
Which was part of the problem of,
of earlier methods, but this is in the way backs