In, digital images in computer vision, we typically operate on discrete images,
right, and that means we have to do two types of discretizations.
First of all, we have to sample, the 2D space on a regular grid, that is we have
discrete pixels at locations, you know what pixels stand for, picture elements,
okay, in the old television world that was called pells also for picture
elements, but for computers we have to be special so we call them pixels.
So we have to pick them at specific locations, the other thing is we have to
quantize, each value, we don't get to have a continuous real value,
we have some finite number of bits to represent that, so like we said,
maybe have 8 bits, so it will go from zero to 255.
These days, you tend to have 16-bit images, or 12-bit, or
depending upon the device, but the idea is that it's quantized, to some level.
Even though, it's quantized, later we're going to tend to think of
these things as floating point, and I'll tell you now,
that if you compute with integer images like unsigned integer 8,
8 bits your code will just break, so, use floating point images.
So in general, especially in MATLAB, which we'll be doing a lot of,
images are represented as a matrix of values, typically integer values to
start with [INAUDIBLE] so here's Phyllis, looking as delightful as ever, and,
we index our matrices by, again, i and j, row and column,
sometimes, x going over this way and y going that way,
if I say some pixel i j it means row i column j, if I say some pixel at x y,
all right, x y, x is horizontal so I have to go get the column that, so
you'll have to swap them, and part of the problem is our math is always
determined by x and y, and our computing is always determined by i and
j, row and column, and, and that's a, a tension that we'll have.
Sometimes we use 1D signals, 1D signals will just be an array of,
of numbers as well.
All right.