All right, my next question
is a classification task.
So your job is to categorize
fish as salmon, trout or
cod and the input features that you have
include the fish length, body length.
Its weight, and
say the type of scales that it has.
Like round scales, long scales,
or the scales are absent.
How would you take this input data and
prepare it to feed it into
a machine learning algorithm and
go forward and actually categorize it?
Can you walk me through that process?
>> Sure thing, all right so
let me just write down all of
the information you gave me.
First thing that I remember is
the labels, the different types of fish.
And so I heard salmon, trout.
>> Trout and cod, but you could
pick another a fish if you want.
>> Okay, we can even add tuna.
[LAUGH]
>> [LAUGH]
>> Why not?
Okay so this is the labels
I want all of my data to
fall into one of these categories.
And the information that I have
on these fish is their weight.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>> The length of the fish.
>> Mm-hm.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And the type of scales it has.
>> And the type of scales.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>> So the weight, you could
consider it's measured in pounds.
>> Okay.
>> Most of these fish weigh
around five to ten pounds.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The length is measured in inches.
>> Okay.
>> And again, the range is roughly,
say, 50 to 100 inches.
>> Okay.
>> Not strictly within those bounds but
most of the fish fall in that range.
And the type of scales I mentioned were
they could be round, long, or absent.
>> Okay.
Round, long,
absent, okay.
So provided this data, I need to make
some transforms to the data such
that I can easily fit it, feed it
into a machine learning algorithm and
predict some of these labels.
So looking at the data I have,
weight is a numeric value,
length is a numeric value, but
type of scales is a categorical value.
So what I'm going to do is transform
these into dummy variables.
>> Okay.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And what would your transformed
feature vector look like?
>> Okay,
I think it would look something like
this where I have the weight,
the length.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then, I can say,
are the scales round?
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Are the scales long?
And since I have just three
different options for the scales,
I only need two dummy variables.
So if the scales are round,
I can put a one here and a zero here.
If they're long,
I can put a zero here and a one here.
And if there's no scales at all,
I can put a zero here and a zero here.
>> That's a good observation.
All right.
I think that this looks like
a step in the right direction.
Is there anything else you might need to
do to the data to make it suitable for
a machine learning algorithm to consume?
>> One thing I want to be concerned
about is to make sure that
the dimensions of my data,
are sort of in the same range.
because if we get into a situation
where maybe something like length which
are much higher numbers than weight,
I might be leading my machine learning
algorithm to think that this is a much
heavier contributor than the weight.
So, some sort of regularization
of these variables or
standardization needs to happen.
>> Okay.
>> For this situation, I see that
weight sort of ranges between 5 and
10, and length between 50 and 100.
So a simple solution that
might work just fine,
is instead of defining length in inches,
is defining length in inches times 10.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then these two should
be of about the same value.
>> Okay,
that's a reasonable transformation.
But this is based on sort of prior
knowledge that these values are within
these ranges.
Sometimes on a real world data set,
it's hard to know beforehand
what those ranges might be.
So how would you deal
with that situation?
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>> Hm, so assuming that I
didn't know what the length and
weight ranged in,
I could figure out another new
way of normalizing these variables.
By sort of defining a scale and
dividing that by the standard
deviation such that each
of these has a range but
it's also based on
the standard deviation
of the data that we've already seen.
>> That's a good point.
So, usually for a normalization step,
what are some of the other statistics
you might need to compute?
You mentioned standard deviation.
Is there anything else that
you might need to look at?
>> The variance also might
be very useful in this case.
So, either one of those might work.
I might try with both of them and
see which one gives me the predictions
that I expect after I feed it into
my machine learning algorithm.
>> Okay, cool.
I think this is an effective
way to transform the data and
make it available for
a machine learning algorithm.
My follow-up question would be what is
a possible machine learning algorithm or
model that you might
use to model this data?
>> Okay, So
since this is a classification problem,
my default go to would
be a random forest.
That's sort of a personal preference,
but I usually like to start by just
feeding everything into a random
forest and checking the accuracy using
cross validation to see how
my model is actually working.
And then after that going back and
seeing if I should try and
tune my machine learning algorithm,
or maybe go back and
try a different
classification algorithm.
>> Okay, that makes perfect sense to me.
Thank you.
>> Thank you.