So NS arrays and NS dictionaries can be
persisted using an NS keyed archiver.
But what about custom structs and
classes?
Let's say we have an array filled
with three person structs.
Can we still persist it
with a keyed archiver?
Turns out we can, but not for free.
If we want a custom structs to work in
the system, we'll need to add a little
bit of machinery to each one of them,
two methods to be exact.
We need them to conform to
the protocol that will let them work
with the keyed archiver.
To see why the person structs
need these two methods,
let's think through the mechanism
from the beginning.
In this orange color,
let's follow an invocation of
encode root object to file.
That's the invocation on the keyed
archiver that asks it to save this
array as data.
And this keyed archiver begins its
recording at the start of this array.
As it does its work,
it's recording the data into the array.
Let's represent the data
with some lines over here.
This will represent the data that'll
eventually be written to the hard drive.
When the invocation is
done with the array,
it comes down into the person object.
When the invocation flows
into the person object,
the person object needs to be able to
give its data to the keyed archiver.
That data will be added to
the accumulating data over here.
The invocation will return to the array,
so
we'll add some more data for the array.
After that,
the persistence will continue.
The keyed archiver will go into
the second person object and return.
And so the keyed archiver
will accumulate data for
the second person object.
Finally, the invocation will flow into
the last person object, and the red and
black lines over here will represent
the last person object, and
the end of the array.
The question for us is, what method is
being invoked on this person object?
How is receiving the keyed
archiver in this invocation?
The person object needs to implement
the encodeWithCoder method.
This NSCoder property is in fact,
the keyed archiver.
When the keyed archiver gets passed in,
it's received by the person with this
method, will write the method and
inside, will encode our person object.
You'll see more during the lesson.
The parameter type might be confusing.
NSCoder is a protocol that the NS
keyed archiver implements.
We've seen now how the contents of
the data file get put together.
This data will be persisted
on the hard drive.
Let's imagine that
the app is turned off, so
all the objects in the app's
active memory go away.
The data is still persistent
on the hard drive.
The app may stay off for days, who
knows, but someday the app will start
back up and we'll want to
extract our array of actors.
When that day comes we'll be up and
running again so
we can create objects in memory.
We'll start out with
the Keyed Unarchiver,
it's the companion to
the Keyed Archiver.
The Keyed Archiver made the data.
Now, the keyed unarchiver is going to
turn the data back into the objects.
You might be able to imagine
how this is going to work.
It'll start with the data in the file.
It will consume the beginning of the
array and create the array in memory.
Then it will consume the first person
object and reconstruct it in memory.
As it works through
the rest of the data,
it will recreate
the other person objects.
Finally, it'll consume
the last bit of the array and
the array objects will be complete.
This is our persistent object graph.
To participate in this
decoding project a persons
structs need to implement
a special init method.
Which receives the NS Unarchiver
as an argument.
Again, this is a protocol name.
The Keyed Unarchiver implements
the NSDecoder protocol.
The interesting thing about this is
that we don't need to control the whole
process.
That's the Archiver and
the Unarchiver's job, and
they've already been written for us.
We just need to take
care of our custom types.
The key is to have our person and
movie classes implement the two
methods in the NS coding protocol.
Read on for the details.