Let's check out Udacity's
website on a Mac.
See how the site dynamically changes
based on the size of the browser window.
Now let's try it on an iPhone.
Does the homepage look exactly the same?
No.
It does certainly display
the same information but
it adapts to the size of the screen.
This is done by our
front-end developers And
in web developer jargon it's
called responsive design.
If you've never heard this expression,
pause the video and Google for it.
Web developers have had
this problem since day one
as you can freely change
the size of a browser window.
On the other hand,
the Android unbelievers have had to deal
with this almost since the beginning
because of the huge number of
different Android devices out there.
In the meantime, iOS developers
were happily programming in their
ivory tower,
blissfully ignorant of the mess outside.
Why?
Because until recently, there were
no other devices but iPhone and
iPads and they all had the same size.
In the worst case scenario,
it would create a UI for iPhone and
another one for the iPad.
The good old times are gone and now we
have to deal with different sizes of
iPhones, iPads,
plus Apple TV and Apple Watch.
The craft of creating adaptive
UIs is a necessary skill for
any iOS developer and Auto Layout is
the most powerful tool in our belt.