Hi, welcome to Udacity's machine
learning nano degree program.
My name is Luis Serrano and
I'm a Course Developer here at Udacity.
But before I worked here I was working
on machine learning at Google for
a few years.
I was using machine learning algorithms
to generate video recommendations at
YouTube.
Machine learning is widely used for
many cool things.
Such as image and
voice recognition, spam detection,
fraud detection, stock market, teaching
a computer how to play chess, and,
of course, self-driving cars.
So it may sound like something so
useful must be pretty complicated.
But I'm here to show you that machine
learning is actually pretty easy.
And most importantly a lot of fun.
So first off, what is machine learning?
Well, we have the world and in the world
we have humans and we have computers.
And one of the main
differences between humans and
computers is that humans
learn from past experiences.
Whereas computers need to be told what
to do, they need to be programmed.
And now the question is, can we get
computers to learn from experience too?
And the answer is yes, we can.
And that is precisely
what machine learning is.
Teaching computers to learn to
perform tasks from past experiences.
Of course, for computers past
experiences are just recorded as data.
So together, we're going to look at
a few examples in which we can teach
the computer to learn
from previous data.
And most importantly, I'm going to show
you that machine learning is actually
pretty easy, and nothing to fear.
[MUSIC]