While we talk about the pervasiveness of cameras,
we also have to discuss the availability of these cameras in all contexts.
Camera phones would most probably be the widest selling
electronic platform out there.
Initially it used to be things like television and, you know, VCRs and
stuff like that, but camera and camera phones have basically taken over.
Primarily because they're not just cameras, but they're phones and
communication devices at the same time.
Basically newer platforms like, you know,
YouTube, Flickr, all that kind of stuff is now becoming available.
That makes the distribution of content that's not just textual, much,
much easier.
People share images and videos a lot, but then at the same time, and
this is very, extremely important is our ability to analyze images, video,
has been enhanced because we can actually do analysis of text, speech, and
other types of things.
So multi-model analysis has of course grown considerably with the growth of
the internet and computational technologies which impacts our ability to
deal with photographs and images a lot, too.
And of course, not to forget, it's an important element in art, and science,
and research.
And more important these days, it's becoming an amazingly important tool for
social computing.
Instagram and other types of technologies are really basically made photography
as a first class medium and even things like Facebook, Google Plus, you name it.
Any social media platform supports and
leverages images and pictures extensively.
To help us understand this,
now let's look at some interesting ways of seeing how the trends have changed.