Okay let's look at the two options,
so the first one says professional
code of ethics requires you.
So if you read the IEEE or
ACM code of conduct that I was
talking about, actually does ask you.
And personally that may
be something If I don't
want others to violate my privacy I
have to give the same to others and
not do things that
violate their privacy.
So my ethical standards or
professional code of conduct
says even though the file has come to
your computer, the information it has
is none of your business,
you shouldn't be looking at it.
So, that's what I would
pick in this case.
You shouldn't be liable under CFA
because you didn't break into that
computer, okay?
You didn't use unauthorized
access to pull this data out,
so because of that I will
not pick the second option.