Now, let's do a quiz on RSA and
Diffie-Hellman.
Check the statements that are true.
First statement.
RSA is a block cipher in
which the plaintext and
ciphertext are integers between zero and
n-1 for some n.
Second.
If someone invents a very efficient
method to factor large integers,
then RSA becomes insecure.
Third, the Diffie-Hellman
algorithm depends,
for its effectiveness, on the difficulty
of computing discrete logarithms.
Fourth, the Diffie-Hellman key
exchange protocol is vulnerable to
a man-in-the-middle attack, because it
does not authenticate the participants.
Fifth.
RSA and Diffie-Hellman are the only
public-key algorithms.