Let's use this new knowledge to add mutual exclusion
to our digitizer, tracker program. Hopefully now we won't
have the same problem but before, were we could
end up reading from a frame that was only
half filled with the data we wanted, because bufavail got out of sync. So we'll
create a new mutex lock variable. And we will set
this lock Before we do our manipulation and unset it afterwards.
We'll do that both in the digitizer part and then also in the tracker part.
What's wrong with this program? Does it not have any concurrency? Will we end
up with deadlock, where there's no thread to run? Is it that two threads cannot
use the same lock? Or is it that two procedures cannot use the same lock?