So which algorithm are we going
to show first to solve constraint
satisfaction problems?
>> Well the stupid one first of course.
>> I had to ask.
>> Then we'll add
intelligence as we need it.
>> Okay, we'll use simple search.
States are defined by
the values assigned so far.
>> The initial state is
the empty assignment.
First we'll check to see if
the current assignment is the goal.
>> Then we will assign a value to
an unassigned variable that does not
conflict with the current assignment.
>> We call it a dead end if
there are no legal assignments.
In that case, we will back up
to the previous state, and
try another assignment.
>> And we recurse until we
either find the answer or
try all the possible assignments and
report failure.
>> Let's make the algorithm
complete by doing an example.
>> Okay.
Here's our map of Australia.
>> We will work with
western Australia first.
>> We could have one of three colors,
orange, green or blue.
>> I'll choose orange.
>> Okay.
What section do you want
us to look at next?
>> How about the northern territory.
>> Great.
Since we chose orange for western
Australia, for northern territory,
can have two colors, green or blue.
>> Let's choose green.
>> Okay, now let's work with Queensland
next, it can be orange or blue.
>> Let's choose blue.
>> But now we are in trouble, there
are no colors left for South Australia.
>> Okay, well that's a dead end,
let's back up and try the other branch,
where we only used orange and
green up to this point.
>> And eventually we'll find
the answer this way, but
we can improve the efficiency
of the algorithm significantly.