All right, welcome back to Computer Vision.
Today, we're going to sort of finish up our edge detection unit.
Which will then be used for things that you're going to be doing later.
Our last lesson we talked about the notion of edges and
how they related to magnitudes of gradients and derivatives of functions.
And we remembered what a gradient was in case that part of
your brain had fallen off.
And we talked about developing some operators that you could apply to
the image that would be computing these gradients.
We showed how they were sensitive to noise, and
we had to do worry about filtering in order to smooth these things out.
And we talked, we could sort of first filter the image.
And then apply the operator.
Or we could filter the operate.
We could, sorry, smooth the operator and apply that to the image.
And here is a,
a picture just reminding that by doing this, saved us that one operation.
So here is our function, f.
Here is the smoothing filter.
We take the derivative of that.
And from then on in,
we could just use that operator to find these peaks and edges.