The more categories we have, the more degrees of freedom we have. And the
larger our chi-squared statistic will be. We don't want to reject the null, in
other words decide that the observed values are significantly different than
what we would have expected. Simply because there are a lot of categories.
Therefore, the more categories we have, we need a higher critical value in
order to reject the null hypothesis. For this distribution, the critical value
for 5% in the tail is further to the right. So this distribution has more
categories and therefore more degrees of freedom. All chi-squared distributions
are positively skewed, with the skewness decreasing as the number of categories
and therefore degrees of freedom increases. So you see that this red one, it
has nine degrees of freedom and the skewness is a lot less than for the
chi-squared distribution with one degree of freedom, this yellow one. As the
degrees of freedom increase, the chi-squared distribution better approximates
normal distributions but they never become perfectly normal.