you might think of GPUs as devices built
for rendering graphically intensive
video games and that's true but gpus
have also become extraordinarily
important for deep learning GPUs are
optimized for high-throughput
computation whereas CPUs are mostly
optimized for latency running a single
threat of instructions as quickly as
possible
GPUs are optimized for throughput
running as many simultaneous
computations as possible throughput
computing is important for computer
graphics because we want to update lots
of pixels on the screen at the same time
and it turns out that throughput
computing is also important for deep
learning because the computations
fundamental to deep learning have a lot
of parallelism what level of
acceleration do you typically see when
you move from training a network on a
cpu to a GPU it depends on a lot of
factors including how the software
running has been designed and the
precise cpu and GPU are comparing for
example the low-power processor in your
laptop is going to be much slower than a
big server processor but a rule of thumb
would be that Network strain about five
times faster on a GPU that on a cpu
that's similar to what I've seen and I
know from my own experience that it's
just so much faster and easier to make
progress when my network is training 5
or 10 times faster and I have all that
extra time to experiment with new
approaches and get fast feedback on how
they work
another good approach for getting fast
feedback is to use transfer learning to
take advantage of networks that have
already been trained instead of just
starting from scratch every time