Like a good performance-aware developer,
I am starting in the timeline panel
with the Paint Profiler checked.
I will hit record and
then scroll down and up the page a bit.
Now, that I've got my timeline,
I will click on one of the frames
to get some more information.
Aha!
This little picture here is pretty
telling about what's going on.
Notice that I've got
this Paints checked,
which means I'm seeing what
is being painted on the page.
Here at this random frame in
the middle of the scroll,
the background is being painted.
And it looks like it's the only
thing that's being painted.
It looks like all the blobs that I saw
before are not, in fact, being painted.
The blobs are clearly
on their own layers,
because they're not being painted on
this page, only the background is.
I've gone back to the Elements pane to
see if I can find it, and lo and behold,
the style has WebKit
transform translate.
Now, this is a 2D
translate which doesn't
automatically create a new layer.
So, I've added will change transform
to the element of ID background.
Now, let me see what this looks like.
Now, back on the page, you can see that
the only thing lighting up in green
when you scroll is the scroll bar.
And there's really nothing
you can do about that.
The rest of the page though,
however, looks awesome.
The performance is better and
there's definitely not
paint happening everywhere.
So, this means the correct answer is
the element with the ID of background.