The situations with signals differs because signals are not generated by
an external entity.
For instance, if this thread is trying to access a memory location that hasn't
been allocated to it, so it's basically performing an illegal memory access.
That will result in the signal being generated, that's called SIGSEGV.
So once the OS generates this fault,
then the rest of the processing is similar to what was happening in interrupts.
The OS maintains a signal handler for every process in the system.
For each signal in the system,
this table will specify the starting address of a handling routine.
So the signal would discuss SIGSEGV.
That's number 11 in Linux, the access illegal memory.
And for that signal, there will be a handling routine whose
starting address will be specified in this table.
And as a reminder, again, the signals that can occur on a particular
platform are really defined by the operating system that executes there.
And how they're handled can be specified by the process.
A little more on signals now.
The reason we said that a process may specify how a signal should be handled.
Is because the operating system actually specifies some default actions for
handling signals.
For instance, a default action for
a signal could be that when that signal occurs a process should be terminated.
Or maybe that the signal should simply be ignored.
An example of what could happen when the SIGSEGV signal occurs is
to terminate at and core dump.
So that one can inspect the core dump and determine the reason for
the crash of the process.
Other common default actions in UNIX like systems include to stop a process or
to continue a stopped process.
For most signals however,
a process is also allowed to install its own custom handling routine.
And there are system calls or library calls that allow a process to do this.
There are certain signals which are exception to this.
These refer to them as signals that cannot be caught.
For instance, that would always kill the process.
Here are a few examples of synchronous signals.
For instance as a result of an attempt at
access to illegal memory location to protect that memory location.
This signal SIGSEGV would occur.
Or that we have a signal that occurs synchronously as the result of
an attempt to divide by 0.
An example of a synchronous signal is also the one that can be
directed from one process to another.
So there is an API how to send a directed signal to a specific thread.
And this is really asynchronous event.
There are also asynchronous signals.
For instance, this same command kill that's here used to
send a directed signal can also be used to cause a process to terminate.
And from the process perspective, this is generated asynchronously.
Similarly, a timeout that's generated as a result of a time expiring,
is another example of an asynchronous signal.