So here's our Sudoku puzzle.
After running constraint propagation by
iterating the functions eliminate and
only choice, we get to this point,
where in each box we're recorded
the values that are allowed in that box.
And let's pick one at random,
say this one with values eight and nine.
Since we don't know what
value will go here yet,
we'll just consider both possibilities.
We'll try to solve the Sudoku obtained
if this value is an eight and
also the Sudoku contained
if this value is a nine.
Thus, we start to create
a tree of possibilities.
Obviously we could have
picked any other box and
split it to it's available values, but
the reason we picked the box with only
two values is because
this will be less work.
So let's recap.
Here we have our original Sudoku and
the two possibilities for
this box, eight and nine.
For each of the two possibilities,
we again run constraint propagation.
Let's say we run one on the left.
After running constraint propagation,
we see that we're still not done.
We look at one of the boxes with
the fewest number of possibilities,
and let's say this box here, with three
possibilities, one, five, and nine.
Well now we branch out
our tree again and
try to solve the three
Sudoku's obtained this way.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Let's say we try to solve
the one on the left and
that ones doesn't give us a solution.
No problem, we'll try the next one.
Let's say this one splits
into two Sudoku's.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And again, let's say the one on
the left doesn't reach a solution but
the one on the right does.
Hooray, we've reached a solution.
This will be the general procedure.
If we don't solve the Sudoku and
we get a few possibilities for
some boxes, we'll branch out and try to
solve the Sudoku's obtained this way.
If we reach a Sudoku
that can't be solved,
then we move to the next one, and
we do this until we reach a solution.
This procedure is called
depth first search.
The depth first search
algorithm works as follows.
We start by the root and traverse the
tree, always in the left most fashion.
When we reach an end, we go to the next
branch to the right and keep going.
We'll have the chance to learn this
more detailed later in the 90 degree.