Now I'll be walk you through how
I built out this decision tree.
The first thing we should do is go grab
our data set with an input data tool.
I'm going to grab
the Employees_TransportationData.yxdb.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
After bringing in this data set, the
first thing that I want to do is bring
in a field summary tool to
check the health of our data.
What I want to see is first, are there
any null records within our data set?
And, from looking at the green ticker
bars below each of the different fields
within this interactive browser,
the field summary tool, it looks that
100% of each of the fields are valid,
meaning that there are no null
values within our data set.
The other thing that I notice is that
all of our fields seem evenly
distributed, and there's no skewed data.
So for example, there seems to be a
normal distribution of the age category,
the drive distances miles is
pretty normal, besides for
only a few number of records of people
driving between 10 and 12 miles to work.
And as well, our categorical
variables has only two or
three different categories within them.
And this all seems very logical and
our data seems pretty healthy.
So, I'm happy with the field
summary tools results.
So what I'm going to do is I'm
going to deselect this tool and what
I'm going to do is I'm going to create
different samples of our data set,
70% in the estimation sample, and
the 30% in the validation sample.
As we can see, we have about 70% of
raw data in estimation sample with
almost 2700 number of
records over there.
With only 1100 in the validation sample
and nothing in the hold out sample.
So now what I am going to do is I am
going to go straight to our decision
tree tool.
First thing I'm going to do is
I'm going to name the model.
So Dt for decision tree underscore and
I'm going to say transportation since
that's what we're trying to predict.
Then our target variable is going to
be that mode of transportation.
And then my different predictor
variables is I'm going to choose
the gender, age, marital status and
drive distance in miles.
Since we can't choose the mode since
that's what we're trying to predict.
In the first field,
the employee ID is simply an ID field.
I'm now going to bring in a browse
tool after interactive result and
run this model.
What I'm able to see first of all is
that the drive distance in mile and
the age are the only two variables
that are actually important at
all in this model.
Therefore, the other
variables that we put
into the model were not used at
all to build this decision tree.
The next thing I see is that we
have many different splits within
this data set to go to our three
different possible terminal nodes,
public transportation, bike and car.
But instead of going to interpret these
results what I'm going to do is go over
to our confusion matrix and
view that 96% of our different
variables were classified correctly.
This is very strong but again this
is the estimation sample against
the data that was used
to build that model.
So we need to definitely go and validate
or model verses and independent data set
but I'm able to see that bikes where
predicted correctly 100% of the time.
Cars where as well but public
transportation was quiet lower at 86%.
So overall this looks very promising so
far but as we know
decision trees have a high likelihood
to possibly over fit a data set.
So what we should do is we should really
test this model out against a validation
data set, to determine how
strong this model actually is.