All right, so
I've got a long list of these metrics.
I'm not sure how many you would actually
think of, but let me list some and
then maybe you can riff with me.
>> Okay.
>> So
one metric that we could use is,
if we have an algorithm,
does that algorithm identify
the optimal arm in the limit?
If you ran this infinitely long,
would at the end of infinity, you know
which arm has the highest payoff.
>> Okay.
>> So that's good.
>> Yes.
>> because it's good to know
what the highest arm is, right?
But it's kind of bad because this is,
this metric is actually achieved
quite well by an algorithm that just
round robin chooses all the arms.
Pull the first one, pull the second,
pull the third one.
So in the limit, we'll all the data that
we need to estimate them as accurately
as we want, but we'll actually not
have taken advantage of it ever.
>> Right.
And so
I think it's important to say then that
this is like the normal reinforcement
learning setting, so
while you're learning and
doing whatever you're doing,
you're still accumulating reward.
>> Yes.
>> Or not.
>> Right,
so it would be nice to have a metric
that actually paid attention to not just
how much we're learning, but how much
reward we're getting in the process.
So we could just make that the goal.
>> Sure, but
is that the original problem?
I mean, how do you do that?
>> No, no, no.
I mean we were phrasing the original
problem as figuring out which arm has
the highest payoff.
>> Okay.
>> So this
is kind of different than that, right?
This is maximizing
the discounted expected reward,
which is going to do that well.
You should do some amount
of exploration, but
also some amount of exploitation.
You're getting reward, but
you also need opportunities to get high
reward by identifying high scoring arms.
>> Yeah.
Sure.
That makes sense.
>> Okay.
So this is totally doable,
except it's not so doable in that it
ends up being the computation for
this ends up being somewhat intractable.
>> Oh, of course.
>> We could talk about how you
can actually do this in practice.
There's some special cases that
actually work out beautifully.
There's a thing called a Gittms index.
So Gittms index is a way of saying, all
right, here's an arm, and I've pulled it
some number of times, in the
denominator, and I've gotten some number
of successes, these two numbers can be
mapped to a value called the index.
Such that, if you do that for
all their arms,
compute all their indices, and
always take the maximum one,
you actually maximize
discounted expected reward.
So it's this really clever mapping
from the number of successes and
the number of pulls, to a number,
such that always greedily choosing with
respect to that number is optimal.