[Narrator] Now let's define a function for solving problems.
It's called Tree Search because it superimposes
a search tree over the state space.
Here's how it works: It starts off by
initializing the frontier to be the path
consisting of only the initial states,
and then it goes into a loop
in which it first checks to see
do we still have anything left in the frontier?
If not we fail, there can be no solution.
If we do have something, then we make a choice.
Tree Search is really a family of functions
not a single algorithm which
depends on how we make that choice,
and we'll see some of the options later.
If we go ahead and make a choice of one of
the paths on the frontier and remove that
path from the frontier, we find the state
which is at the end of the path, and if that
state's a go then we're done.
We found a path to the goal; otherwise,
we do what's called expanding that path.
We look at all the actions from that state,
and we add to the path the actions
and the result of that state; so we get
a new path that has the old path, the action
and the result of that action, and we
stick all of those paths back onto the frontier.
Now Tree Search represents a whole family
of algorithms, and where you get the family
resemblance is that they're all looking
at the frontier, copying items off and
and looking to see if their goal tests,
but where you get the difference is right here,
in the choice of how you're going to expand
the next item on the frontier, which
path do we look at first, and we'll go through
different sets of algorithms that make
different choices for which path to look at first.
The first algorithm I want to consider
is called Breadth-First Search.
Now it could be called shortest-first search
because what it does is always choose
of the frontier one of the paths that hadn't been
considered yet that's the shortest possible.
So how does it work?
Well we start off with the path of
length 0, starting in the start state, and
that's the only path in the frontier so
it's the shortest one so we pick it,
and then we expand it, and we add in
all the paths that result from
applying all the possible actions.
So now we've removed
this path from the frontier,
but we've added in 3 new paths.
This one,
this one, and this one.
Now we're in a position where
we have 3 paths on the frontier, and
we have to pick the shortest one.
Now in this case all 3 paths
have the same length, length 1, so we
break the tie at random or using some
other technique, and let's suppose that
in this case we choose this path
from Arad to Sibiu.
Now the question I want you to answer
is once we remove that from the frontier,
what paths are we going to add next?
So show me by checking off the cities
that ends the paths, which paths
are going to be added to the frontier?