Now I want to give you an idea of how well the segmentation program performs.
Here I've trained it on a corpus of 4 billion words--
not just the Shakespeare corpus but a larger corpus,
and then I give it some test cases to try to find the best segmentation.
So I gave it the test case here. The program came up with "base rate sought to,"
but the correct answer was "base rates ought to."
In this case, it just seems somewhat like bad luck that that was the right answer,
but both segmentations seem like good segmentations.
Next was this trial.
My program came up with "small and in significant,"
but the correct answer was "small and insignificant."
Here it seems like it really has erred that "small and insignificant"
seems like a much better segmentation than the one my program came up with.
What I want you to tell me is what do you think could help us do a better job of getting the right answer.
Would it be helpful to gather more data?
Check that box if you think that would be helpful.
Would it be helpful to make a Markov assumption rather than the naive Bayes assumption?
Check here.
Or would it be helpful to do a better job with our smoothing algorithm? Check here.
And you can check more than one.