Now the first problem that I notice is
probably the first problem that you
notice and that's that
the spiders are being created,
however they're not
crawling on the screen.
So I've spawned a couple
spiders here and no luck.
They are not crawling onto the screen.
So let's add a break point for this.
I'll do it again in
the bug to view method.
And we'll trigger it again.
There we go.
And now let's bring up
the debug view hierarchy and
select one of the UI image views for
one of our bugs.
Here's something I noticed off the bat.
All the bugs appear to
be in the same position.
Every single one of them.
They're all here in the top left hand
corner slightly out of our view.
And something else is strange and
that's the visible content doesn't
really look like what we saw earlier.
Last time I didn't even see bugs here.
This time I see some of the red bugs,
some of the blue bug,
there are some black bugs.
I'm not seeing them at all.
If I go to the inspector,
I'm not really getting a lot of
information about what's going on.
This is a little confusing and
what I'd like to see is a little bit of
information that describes where
the visual content the actual spider is.
Let's try running again.
Create another bug, see what happens.
Actually the debug view hierarchy.
This is another oddity here.
Now we see some of a blue bug.
What happened to our red bug?
Let's try it one more time.
See if anything changes.
Yeah.
Each time so now we can see almost all
the blue bug and some of the red bug.
So my hunch is that the content for
the spider image is being randomly
placed somewhere within this frame
instead of the position of the frame
being randomly placed
somewhere within the view.
So seems like we're randomly
placing the wrong thing.
Instead of randomly placing
this thing's position,
we're randomly placing
the visual content.
So let's use the command line
interface to test this assumption.
So I've selected one of
the UI image views here so
that I have an address I can work with
and in the console let's use the unsafe
bit cast to cast this address into a UI
image view object that we can use.
So we'll type the expression
spider equals unsafe bit cast and
we'll pass the raw address for
this image view and
then the UIImageView.self since we're
casting into a UI image view object.
Lets go ahead and
print out this spider object.
There we go.
And the first part of the images frame
shows a negative 100, negative 100,
which are the x and y position.
But this is a little weird.
The spiders bounds show
the CA basic animation thing.
So this kind of plays on the same hunch
that maybe we're doing something with
the visual content or
the bounds instead of the frame.
So let's set a new break point when
the animation shouldn't be occurring.
Like maybe if there is an animation
it's played through and
that could tell us something.
So, there shouldn't be any animation
of position, which we're on this hunch
that maybe we're updating the bounds
instead of the position of the frame.
There shouldn't be any animation
of that going on when we pop
back to the master view.
So let's go to the visual
debug controller.
Let me hide these things away.
And here in the pop to master view
controller I'll set a break point.
Let's see if we can trigger
this break point and
see if we can get any new information.
So I'll re run the app and
then I'll tap the back arrow.
That should trigger our new break point.
And now let's print out the spider
object again and see what's happened.
Okay,now our bounds.
I don't see anything there for bounds.
The animation, maybe that's gone.
I think this is enough evidence to
work on this idea to prove that
maybe the issue is happening
when we animate the bugs or
maybe we're animating the wrong thing.
We're not moving the frame.
We're moving the bounds.
Let's stop the app and
go to the move bugs animation method.
Because this is the method where
that movement is supposed to happen.
And I think we see the problem now.
Instead of updating the frame,
we're updating the bounds.
So let's change bounds to frame and
then rebuild our application.
[SOUND] And
lets disable this.
There we go.
So now our bugs are appearing just fine.