Okay, so actually I haven't told you, so
far, we're going to talk about it,
what a system call is.
But let's sort of think about
what would be a system call.
We said the operating system controls
access to protected resources.
So if the operating system is going to
control access to protected resources,
and if you are one of those
applications that needs this resource,
you have to ask the operating system.
When you ask the operating
system the way you do that is
by making a call to the operating
system, and that's called a system call.
As I said we haven't discussed this, but
I want you to sort of think about
this question here that says system
calls allow application code to
gain access to operating system,
and particular resources that
are controlled by the operating system.
A system call is different
than a regular call.
When you run code, you make function and
procedure calls all the time
to do control transfer,
to go from one part of the program
to another part of the program.
Here we are going from the user part
of the program to the operating system,
and when you make a call
like that it is special and
it is called a protected procedure call.
So a protected procedure
call is different.
And the question that you should
think about at this point is
how different is it?
One way to sort of characterize
the difference is the cost of a call.
So I want you to think about
the cost differences between
these two kinds of calls.
When the system call is how a user or
application code actually goes into
the operating system to gain access
to some resource it needs, and
things like that.