We'll be experimenting with D3.js
on a webpage for this class.
So that way,
you can get familiar with methods and
syntax that comes along with D3.
Because D3 JS is a client-side
JavaScript library,
it means that you can load
it on any webpage and
start selecting different elements
on the page and manipulating them.
First, you'll want to
open up a web browser.
I'll be using Google's Chrome
browser throughout this course.
But any modern web browser will
have all the same functionality of
a JavaScript console and
in HTML inspector so
that way you can see the different
elements that are on the page.
Once you have your browser opened, you
can open up the JavaScript console by
hitting Cmd+Opt+J, that's for Mac users.
If you're a Windows or a Linux users,
you'll want to hit Ctrl+Shift+J.
Now, if you are using a different web
browser, keep in mind that some of these
commands might be slightly different for
your browser.
This is the JavaScript console, and
if I click on the elements tab up here,
I can go and see the HTML inspector.
The HTML inspector allows
me to see the different
HTML DOM nodes that are on the page.
Another way of bringing up
this JavaScript console
is by going up to the menu in Chrome.
You can click on view and then you
can scroll down to developer and
then click on JavaScript console.
So now let's see how we could start
using D3 in our JavaScript console.
Let's start by loading
it on to the page.