So we learned quite a bit.
We learned about Naive Bayes
as our first supervised learning methods.
The setup was that we had
features of documents or trading examples and labels.
In this case, SPAM or not SPAM.
And from those pieces,
we made a generative model for the SPAM class
and the non-SPAM class
that described the condition of probability
of each individual feature.
We then used first maximum likelihood
and then a Laplacian smoother
to fit those primers over here.
And then using Bayes rule,
we could take any training examples over here
and figure out what the class probability was over here.
This is called a generative model
in that the condition of probabilities all aim to maximize
the probability of individual features as if those
describe the physical world.
We also used what is called a bag of words model,
in which our representation of each email
was such that we just counted the occurrences of words,
irrespective of their order.
Now this is a very powerful method for fighting SPAM.
Unfortunately, it is not powerful enough.
It turns out spammers know about Naive Bayes,
and they've long learned to come up with messages
that are fooling your SPAM filter if it uses Naive Bayes.
So companies like Google and others
have become much more involved
in methods for SPAM filtering.
Now I can give you some more examples how to filter SPAM,
but all of those quite easily fit with the same Naive Bayes model.