I'd expect all three of
these conditions to be true.
Unfortunately, one of them is not
with our current implementation.
This third option 0.1
plus 0.2 equals 0.3
would actually equal 0.300 more zeros,
4.
The reason behind this weird math isn't
that important to this discussion, but
it relates to how computers
perform floating point math.
If you'd like to understand
this problem a bit more,
check out the link in
the instructor notes.
What is important is that
we've defined test and
we've noticed one of these
tests isn't currently failing.
Something as easy as adding
two numbers together.
And we've already encountered an error.
That's the value of testing.
We now have definitive proof our
function is not working correctly,
and we can start fixing that error.