You ready to fill some of these in?
You might not know all of
them right off the bat, but
I think we can piece them together.
>> Okay,
well if we're going to work together,
I think we can do
a pretty good job here.
Well can I ask you a question first?
>> Sure.
>> Do you know the answers?
>> No, [LAUGH] but
I'm confident they exist.
>> Okay, good, so let's work this out.
So I do think I know one of them and
it's really easy.
So the one that I'm going to do that's
really easy, is writing V in terms of Q.
>> Excellent choice, sir.
>> Right, so if you think about the
equation, which we have conveniently not
written on the screen, the value
is immediately a max over actions.
So I think, it's just the max
of over actions of Q(S,a).
>> Yeah, exactly so, very good.
>> So one way of saying that is that
the true value of a state is just,
you're going to take the best action.
>> Yeah, and so that also gives a nice
interpretation of what Q values are.
Right, it's the value of each of
the actions you could take in the state,
the best of which is the one
we're actually going to take.
>> Right, exactly, exactly.
So I think there's a similar
argument to make for C.
So I guess, I don't know where
you want to put the max, but
I guess what I'm thinking of is, you
had a state followed by an action, and
that gives you Q.
But in C, you have sort of the state
followed by an action, and a reward.
So C is happening after the reward,
right.
So it should be the reward
that you get plus C.
Right, so is that right?
That makes sense, right?
>> Yeah, that feels right to me.
So one of the things that's interesting,
already, is that means if we have C and
we want V, we still need to
know the reward function.
But if we want V and we know Q,
we don't need any other special
knowledge about the way the model works.
The Q values kind of encapsulate
all that we need in terms of,
at least for computing V.
>> Okay, but that's because,
let me just see I understand that.
I think you're right,
that's a cool insight,
but basically, we need to know what
the reward was after we did the state.
So we yeah okay that makes sense,
we have to kind of keep that with us.
All right I'll buy that.
>> Okay, so let's see what happens
in some of the other boxes.
>> Right, so this is harder for me,
because I think doing V in terms of Q
and C is easier because it's the future.
V is the like the first thing
before the future comes along.
And Q and C captures the next
set of things in the sequence.
But here, I guess I want to
know how that's going to work.
>> Well, I like the way that you started
when you thought about this box here.
You said that the V
equation starts with max A.
Well what does the Q
equation start with?
Good.
>> [LAUGH] Right.
And then after that, oh,
well once you have the rewards,
it's just, discounted value where
you're going to end up next.
>> So what's the end of this thing?
>> V of S prime.
>> Yes.
>> Right, so the trick there,
is to realize that you don't
have to go backwards in time.
You just have to unroll
the infinite sequence,
until you get to the point where you
can now express it in terms of V.
>> Exactly, and
that's the trick to all these, in fact.
>> Right, so, in fact, I don't know how
you're going to fit this, but I could
just substitute what I learned about
how V can be expressed in terms of C,
by just substituting that bit,
for the V that you did in Q.
Express in terms of V.
>> So it's as if we fill in the same
answer that we did, and then we say,
okay, well what's V?
We know V in terms of C looks like this,
and we just can keep,
[LAUGH] I guess we need
to keep doing that.
That can't be right.
>> Why not?
I mean,
I don't think you have to do that.
>> No, because in fact.
This is already C.
>> Exactly.
>> So that's not so bad actually.
But again, to getting Q from
C requires us to know R.
Getting V from C, requires us to know R.
Getting Q from Q, doesn't require
us to know anything other than Q.
And same from V from Q,
Q from V, we need both R and T.
>> Great.
>> All right, so let's do this last row.
>> Wait, I have a question.
>> Sure.
>> Do I need a gamma in front of
C for Q?
>> I'm going to say no, because
the equation for gamma starts, sorry,
the equation for C starts with gamma.
>> Oh, you're right.
Okay, yeah, yeah that's right.
Okay, cool.
All right, so how do we do this one?
We'll start the same way.
We'll start off, just writing
the definition of C as it is.
Which is usually then what?
Plus?
>> The next reward I'm
going to get followed by C.
No, I'm missing something.
Wait what am I missing?
This is where me not having
written down the equations,
now comes back to bite me.
There's a max of A in there somewhere.
I ended up in S prime, so
now I need to take an action.
So it's max over A prime, then I'll
get the reward, and then I get C.
>> Yeah, so we could do [LAUGH],
we could write C in terms of C, but
that's not what we're trying to do.
We were trying to write C in terms of V.
The thing with the max
in front of it is V.
Boom.
>> Right.
Because it already contains
everything we need to know.
>> Right, yeah.
So in particular, the continuation for
being in some state taking some action
is the discounted next state value,
which we already have in this case,
we have V.
>> Yeah, that's exactly right.
>> All right, last box!
>> All right, so
there's a similar argument there.
I think you just write the same thing,
and then just replace V with,
max A prime over Q(s,a).
There you go.
>> Yeah, that seems plausible.
>> So is everything that you said before
still true about how I don't need to
know R?
I guess so.
>> Read down the columns.
If we have the C function,
we can get the V and
the Q from it if we just have R.
If we have the V function,
then we can get the Q and the C, but
we actually need the T, the transition
function in the case of getting C, and
we need the reward function and
the transition function to get Q.
And if we have the Q function already,
then we don't need anything special,
except for if we want the continuation,
we need the transition function but
not the reward function.
So this is why that the C function
turns out to be a really useful form,
if the reward function
is hard to represent.
We're going to be able to
kind of work around it.
And Q function is actually really
powerful, because it gives us answers to
lots of other questions without
having the know the model.
>> That makes a lot of sense to me.
Okay, that's good.
That's really cool.
>> So, what we should do next I think,
is talk through how we can
actually make a reinforcement
learning algorithm out of this idea.
>> I like that.