Now let's discuss firewall
deployment strategy.
That is, where in the network
do we put a firewall?
Typically, we put an application
level gateway, such as a web proxy,
to a dedicated machine and we call
these machines the bastion hosts.
These machines are made
to be very secure.
Here are some measures that we can take
to make this bastion host very secure.
First, these machines execute a secure
version of the operating system.
In addition, only the services
that the admin consider
essential are installed on the host.
For example, a bastion host may
only allow DNS and web traffic.
A bastion host can also require that,
even for traffic coming from an internal
host, the user must authenticate
himself to the bastion host.
Each proxy running on
the bastion host is configured
to allow access only to specific host
systems in the internal network.
This is important because we
don't want compromised proxy
lead to attacks to
the entire internal network.
Each proxy module is a very
small software package,
designed with security in mind.
That is,
we want each proxy to be as small and
simple program as possible so
that we can check for security.
For example, a typical Unix
email application may contain
over a couple hundred
thousand lines of code,
while an email proxy may contain fewer
than one thousand lines of code.
A proxy typically performs
no disk access other than
reading its initial configuration file.
This makes it difficult for
an attacker to install a Trojan horse on
the bastion host and affect the proxy.
Proxies are typically non-privileged and
they're isolated from each other.
The security benefit is that if
a proxy is compromised by an attack,
it cannot easily compromise the entire
bastion host or affect other proxies.