Problem six is the first really foray
into trying to do machine learning on
the problem. If you're going to embark
into solving a problem using machine
learning,
it's really good idea to start simple
and actually convince yourself that
machine learning can solve your problem
and that the data is actually fit
for being treated as a machine learning
problem that you haven't messed up or
that you don't have, you know, one feature
in your data that is going to allow you
to solve the problem in a trivial way
and that will you will get one hundred
percent accuracy but that feature
actually is something that you might not
be able to have a test time. So let's try
a very simple model and one, for example,
that you can consider is the logistic
regression that's in sklearn.
Sklearn is a package that's very popular,
that's that has a lot of already pre-
implemented machine learning approaches
you can call the function fits and it
will fit a model to its input-output
pairs and that's basically training.
you can also call score and that's just
saying give it a test data and test, test
labels and it will return the accuracy
of your model on the data. So it's very
simple. Four line of code, five lines of
code and you can basically run a small
classifier on your data and convince
yourself that there is actually
something to learn here. Next assignment
will be to actually start using this
data and implementing your own logistic
regression and subsequently deep learning
models.