So how do we find the correct values
of theta to minimize our cost function
J of big theta?
We'll use a search algorithm that
takes some initial guess for theta and
iteratively changes theta, so
that J of theta keeps on getting smaller
until it converges on
some minimum value.
The algorithm we're going to
discuss is called gradient descent.
Here's a one dimensional depiction of
what gradient descent might look like.
We have some starting point
where J of theta is large, and
we continue to try new values of theta.
And J of theta keeps on
getting smaller and smaller,
until we arrive here, the final value.
This theta value gives us our
smallest value of J(theta).
And so
we know that we've minimized J(theta).
This is what gradient descent
might look like in one dimension.
Let's see what it looks
like in two dimensions.
Here again we see that we start
at some high value of J(theta).
And we continue to iteratively
update theta 1 and
theta 2 until we arrive here,
the global minimum of J(big theta)