One way of getting at these relationships is to determine which components have
responsibilities for handling the two user actions.
The use cases and
corresponding operations can provide answers to these questions.
However, each of these events is just the first step in the text
browser's response.
For each of these two actions,
determine what subsequent events you would expect to see.
So if, so for example, if the user is resizing the window, or
moving the scroll bar, not only do we expect the window size to be different, or
the scoll bar position to vary, but
we want this, the rest of the application to respond somehow.
So, can you lay out what other things you would expect to happen?