Testing asynchronous functions is a bit
different, because we need some way
to inform the testing framework that our
asynchronous function has completed.
Let's imagine our application needs
to make an API call to a server
to retrieve a list of initial contacts
to put back into our application.
Let's write a new test suite to work
on our new asynchronous functionality.
We're just going to fake our
asynchronous functionality.
So, in this case, we'll have to
write our implementation first.
Normally, you'd be given an asynchronous
method from an API provider,
like this push method from Firebase.
We'll write a getInitialContacts
function, and to make it asynchronous,
we'll just use setTimeout.
You can ignore most of this.
A lot of it's just boilerplate to
make this function act as if it's
asynchronous.
The important part is
the self.intialComplete=true
within the callback.
This is what our fake API call will
do when the asynchronous function
is complete.
You can also see I set an initial
value of false within the constructor.