All right, so
let's talk about memory leaks.
Memory leaks are sneaky.
They can be slow and insidious,
sometimes taking days or
weeks before you even
realize that you have one.
In fact, you might only realize
memory's an issue when your users start
complaining about mysterious slowdowns
that happen after using your app.
Don't let this happen to you.
Fortunately, with some patience,
a perf mindset, and the right tools,
you'll have the opportunity to abolish
these leaks from your app, period.
We'll use Memory Monitor to watch
the behavior of a leak in action, and
then in the next video, we'll use Heat
Viewer to gain initial confirmation.
Now let's look at a micro example
of what a leak can look like, and
see how the SDK tools can
help us identify such a leak.
In this example, we're going to go
ahead and rotate the device for
a few minutes and
profile it with Memory Monitor.
This is by design to showcase a common
leak situation that can arise during
the creation and
destruction of an activity.
We can intentionally trigger this cycle
by changing the device's orientation.
And yes, I know, it may seem that
this is a totally weird thing to do,
but we're going to do this to
demonstrate how a leak may happen and
to show how they can be slow and
insidious.
Now, in the first pass, the leak slowly
consumes the free memory available to
your app, until eventually it causes
a garbage collection or GC event.
More important, the key thing to
notice is, the garbage collector
isn't able to reclaim that much
energy due to the leak in the app.
And then, eventually,
a second GC event occurs much sooner,
about 30 seconds later.
Now, notice when the leak
consumes all of the free memory,
Android actually adjusts and
grants the app a higher memory ceiling.
While this is a nice adjustment by
the system, if the leak isn't fixed,
it will keep consuming memory until the
system can no longer allocate any more.
This will slow the performance
of the device and
eventually lead to your app crashing.
You can wait a little bit longer,
and the third GC will occur.
And then a fourth somewhat
similar to the first two.
Now, as you can see,
the pattern continues, and
more memory is allocated by the system.
You can also similar
behavior using Heat Viewer.