The good news is that NDB
manages caches for you.
There are two caching levels,
an in-context cache and memcache.
Both caches are enabled by default for
all entity types but
can be configured to
suit advanced needs.
For most applications, you can just
allow NDB to manage the caches and
leave the default settings on.
When you've deployed
your app to appspot,
you can see what entries are in Memcache
by going to the Memcache viewer.
If you used the application recently,
there may already be some
entries in the cache.
If you don't see anything, or if you see
items in cache zero, open the web front
end, make sure you have some
conferences created, and browse around.
For instance,
look at conference details.
Then refresh the Memcache viewer and
you should see that there
are some entries there.
After you've explored
the Memcashe viewer,
can you check which of the following
information you can see there?