The tightest lower bound is 4, and
the tightest upper bound is 7.
For the upper bound, we first use the so
called inclusion exclusion principal.
To write the probability like so.
Note that in the sum of
the first two terms,
we've counted
the probability of 2 twice.
So the third term subtracts it out.
Now all probabilities are non-negative.
So we can obtain an upper bound by
just taking the first two terms and
dropping the third.
This is called the union bound.
The probability of
the union of any two sets
is at most the probability
of the sum of the two sets.
We might be counting something twice but
we don't miss anything.
This then gives the upper bound of 7/10.
And this is as good as it gets.
The probability of 2 might be 0,while
the probability of 1 is exactly 3/10.
And the probability of 3 is 4/10.
For the lower bound,
we break the probability up in two ways.
The quality holds here because
these sets are disjointed.
And again these probabilities
are non-negative.
So we obtain two lower bounds,
4/10ths being the tighter of the two