So now I'm talking with
Charles Hewitt who's the Director of
HIE Program Management here at
Rhode Island Quality Institute and
Current Care.
Thank you very much for
taking time to be with us today.
>> You're welcome.
I'm glad to be here.
>> We're mostly going to
talk about direct and
the direct services you provide, but
before we do that, as the student's
are going to learn in the next lesson,
patient privacy is always a concern
when health data is being utilized.
>> Absolutely.
>> And can you briefly tell us what
patient privacy model you use?
Students are going to learn about
the various models later on.
>> Sure.
In Rhode Island, is a so
called opt-in state.
In our case, the opt-in is very strict.
As an HIE, we cannot even see your
data until you have given consent for
us to see it, to collect it.
When you do give your consent,
in the Rhode Island model,
you give consent for all of your data,
including sensitive data like substance
abuse treatment, for example.
You know also when you give consent,
you're consenting to
who can see your data.
And you basically have three choices.
The first choice is anyone that's
treating me, providing treatment or
coordination of care.
The second choice is
only in an emergency,
only in an emergency will I
allow anybody to see my data.
And the third choice is just for
these providers.
And you actually list them on the form.
>> Well that's interesting.
Do you know off the top of your head
what percentage of patients fall
into each bucket?
>> Absolutely.
About a little over 95%,
96%, that range,
select the first option,
all of my providers.
About 2% to 3% select emergencies only,
and
about half of 1% select the third
option, just these providers.
>> Just skipping ahead for a second,
what's being avoided here, which we'll
discuss a lot in a lesson later on in
the course, is the issue of allowing
patients to select which data they want
to share, which is very hard to do.
>> Absolutely, and
in fact it's a very challenging topic,
this so-called segmentation.
In Rhode Island,
the law is all of your data.
And that was basically the result of
a compromise between the consumer
advocates that wanted to be
able to hold certain data back.
And physicians that said, I need it all
in order to provide effective treatment.
>> Well, data segmentation will be a
topic we look at in some detail, later.
The second thing, and really,
the primary focus, I hope, is for
you to give us more detail.
Laura and
I talked briefly about direct, and
the idea that it's used as a service.
But can you give us more
detail about the sorts of
things you're doing with Direct.
>> Sure,
we're doing two things with Direct.
One is on the inbound side,
where we are collecting data
from data-sharing partners.
We use Direct to get feeds of
continuity care documents, CCDs.
>> Students know what those are.
>> From the instance of the EHR
that they happen to be using.
So if they're using, for example,
Allscripts, we worked with Allscripts so
that Allscripts would
generate a proper CCD,
attach it to a direct message, and send
it to the current care gateway where,
it is checked to see whether that
patient has consented or not, and
if the patient is consented,
it flows on into current care.
Otherwise, it's blocked at the gateway.
>> And I understood from
chatting with Laura that that
process is fairly automated.
The provider doesn't have
to do that every time.
>> Very much so.
In fact, it's automatic.
Once it's set up, when the provider
takes a certain action like lockup
their record after an encounter.
The system automatically does all
this process of creating a CCD and
sending it off to CurrentCare.
It's all completely
invisible to the practice.
>> I also know from talking to Laura
that you have a fairly large number of
EHR systems implemented
here in Rhode Island.
Were the vendors pretty
amenable to doing this?
>> I would say some were, some weren't.
>> [LAUGH]
>> Part of the problem is that
the vendors have a lot of priorities
especially meaningful use.
And so implementing this feed for
the Rhode Island HIE, in many cases,
has been way down the list.
And we have to basically
encourage the practices
that want to send us data to go back
to their EHR vendor and tell them.
I need you to do this for me.
>> So what about some of the services,
go the other way.
You've got the data now.
>> I've got the data now.
Now on the outbound side,
the major service we provide
using Direct are alerts.
There are three kinds of alerts.
One is a so called hospital alert.
In that case, we receive ADT
transaction from a hospital.
You've been admitted say, to the ER.
And in that transaction
has been entered the identification
of your primary care physician.
We look up that primary care physician,
and if they're subscribing to alerts,
then we create
a notification message and
it's a very simple email type message.
Very little information
in the message itself.
And send that off to the practice.
Typically, that message is received
in an inbox that's being monitored
by a nurse case manager, and that person
will decide what to do with the message.
There's a link in the message
to the CurrentCare viewer.
So if they want, they can go in and
review what the ADT was in detail,
along with all the other
information that's in CurrentCare.
>> What is the adoption of these alerts?
>> Right now we have, here in
Rhode Island and we're a small state.
>> Yes.
>> But we have 150 practices
that have subscribed and
they represent about 400 to 500
subscriber providers, individual people.
And we generate about between 5 and
6,000 alerts per month to that group.
>> Well, this has been fascinating.
Thank you very much for
taking the time to do this.
>> You're welcome, Mark.
Nice to speak with you.