I'm going to show you how to fix one
example of a four synchronous layout
in this page.
But believe it or not, and you probably
can believe it, there are other examples
of four synchronous layouts that
you can fix if you want to.
So first off, I'm going to turn on
Causes and the Javascript Profiler.
So I can get some more
information when the slider runs.
I will go ahead and
hit record and then change it.
Now, I want a little bit more space, so
let me pop this into another window.
You can see that when the slider changes
a few different functions get called.
Let me zoom in a little bit closer.
When the change event happens,
resizePizzas gets called, then
resizePizzas calls changePizzaSizes.
And here's where I think
the problem might be coming in.
It looks like some function called
determineDx is running over and over and
over and over.
I think this is a good point
to take a look at the code.
So here's the resizePizzas function,
which gets called when
the slider gets activated.
It looks like a few things
are happening inside resizePizzas.
First off I'm using the User Timing API
to collect some metrics.
And then I change
the label on the slider.
This seems pretty straightforward I
can't imagine this would be causing
a Forced synchronize layout so
I'm going to keep drilling down.
Here's that change PizzaSizes function.
Now this piece of code may
look okay on the surface, but
it is absolutely insane.
And it's not insane in some kind of
beautiful way in that it's doing
a lot of very elegant things
in a very compact manner.
Now this is insane in that it is
doing way way way too much and
there's really no reason for
any of this to exist.
First off there's the very obvious
problem that this function doesn't pass
the do not repeat yourself test.
Look document and
.queryselctorall random pizza container.
Document.queryselectorall random
pizza container.
pizza container
like why is this in here three times.
So first things first save this
collection of downloads to
the variable random pizza's.
Now I can use random pizza's in my for
loop without querying
the dom every time.
Now take a.
At this for loop.
It access is a geometric property of
the elements in this case offset width.
And then changes their styles.
So this is clearly the source
of the four synchronous layout.
So then there's this function,
determine DX.
Suffice it to say without
going into any detail,
this function is remarkably useless.
It's complicated,
it creates a lot of work, and
it has no business being inside this for
loop.
I'll leave it as an exercise to you,
to figure out what's going on here.
In the end I just use
this pixel value creation
as a ruse to do a lot
of unnecessary work.
There's no reason to deal with
anything other than 8% with so
let me simplify this.
In this version all change into pizza
sizes does is simply figure out which
with that wants And then sets the width
for every element to that percentage.
There is no more query selecting
inside the for loop and
there's no more conversion back and
forth between pixels and percentages.
This is a lot simpler but the ultimate
test for this code is whether or
not it produces for synchronous layouts.
Let me take a look.
Here's the new and improved version and
first off let me just see if
it's giving me better numbers.
And look at that time to resize
pizzas in under one millisecond.
This is clearly much more performant.
Or in this case two orders of
magnitude more performant.
But i want to see what this
looks like in the timeline.
I will hit record and i will change
the pizza sizes and then stop recording.
I'll pop this into a new window for
some more space.
So here's the slide event.
Here's the resize pizza's event.
And here's the resulting lay up.
And look at that.
No more ugly red triangle saying that
there is a four synchronous layout.
This timeline is much cleaner.
By the way, so I made this website.
Yeah.
I'm proud of it, believe it or not.
Because creating a website with all
of these four synchronous layouts
is a lot harder than it looks.
You basically have to issue
all the best practices you've
ever learned in order to
create something like it.
It's kind of a weird brain challenge
where instead of forcing yourself to do
everything as well as possible you try
to do everything as poorly as possible.
And so I think it's actually a bit of
a feat that I made this website run
well under 60 frames per
second when it's so simple.
Anyways there might be a few
more problems in here so
see if you can find and fix them.
That is if your eyes haven't
already burned out if your skulls.