So we mentioned earlier that you can
store pretty much any data in an array.
You can even store arrays
inside of an array.
An array of arrays can be represented
as a grid like structure,
where each element of the array
corresponds to a row of cells.
Iterating over a two dimensional
array can be tricky.
So it's helpful to think about
the whole thing as a grid,
where each row of the grid is an array,
and
each of those arrays is
an element of the larger array.
You can use a single loop to access each
row of the grid, as you can see here.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And you can use nested loops,
or a loop inside of a loop,
to loop over each elements
of each of those rows.
The outer loop will cycle though each
row and then in the row that's currently
being iterated over, the inner
loop will iterate over each cell.
It can help to use easy to recognize,
distinct variable names for
your outer and inner loops.
I usually like to use variable
names like row or column, or
in this case I used r and c, since this
will help you visualize the rows and
columns of the grid that
your code represents.