By this point in your web dev education,
you already know aboutt HTTP
verbs like get and post.
And sending requests to web servers.
If not, check out the link
in the instructor notes.
Likely you've done that
from your own code and
you've run web services that accept and
handle these requests.
And you also know about port numbers
which let servers on the internet
distinguish one service like HTTP and
port 80.
From another one like SSH and port 22.
So what happens if on your Linux
machine you run this command,
printf HEAD / HTTP/1.1\r\n Host:
en.wikipedia.org \r\n\r\n.
Pipe to nc en.wikipedia.org port 80.
Describe the output of this
command in your own words.
What do you think is happening?
By the way, don't retype this,
copy it from the instructor notes.