Remember how I said loops could
be used to count to a million?
Well, we're not going to do that.
We're going to count to 10,000 instead,
starting with x equals 1.
Hey look, we're already done,
1 mississippi!
We're on our way to 10,000 already.
Just so you know,
counting to 10,000 is a tough task, and
like many tough tasks,
it's good to work on them incrementally.
Let's increase the value of x by 1.
This is awesome.
See, we're making progress.
In no time,
we'll be all the way to 10,000.
Yay, look how far you've gotten.
Okay, let's keep going.
Hey, wait a minute!
This is all the same code.
So repeating the same code over and
over and
over again is definitely not going
to be the best option for us,
if we want to print out all
the numbers between 1 and 10,000.
There has to be a better way.
And you know what?
There is a better way, loops.
Using a loop will let you
iterate over values and
repeatedly run a block of code.
In this case,
the block of code you want to repeat, is
incrementing the value of x and using
console.log to print out the message.
The only piece you really need to
start your loop is right here but
we'll need to tweak it a bit.
Now, this code shows x
starting at the value of 1,
and then it prints out the value of
x and finally, x is incremented.
And because we want to do these two
steps all the way until we reach 10,000,
we'll wrap that code in a loop.
This particular type of loop
is called a while loop.
As long as this condition is true,
the loop will print out the number and
increment the value of x by 1.
And then it will restart if
the condition at the top of the loop is
still true.
So congratulations, in just five lines
of code you can count to 10,000 and
pretty much any number
you'd like to count to.