The answer is that the starting blocks are
the busy blocks that don't have any other
blocks pointing to them. Right away then, we
can eliminate the blocks that aren't busy. And then
I'll just read these next pointers, and eliminate those blocks as well. So this
eliminates 6. This is an ending block, so he's not eliminated. This
eliminates 1. And this eliminates 2. So,
we are left with 3, 5 and 1 as starting blocks. Just for
good measure, let's go ahead and build the chains as well. We'll start with 3
and he then would seem to point to 1 who then points to 6,
when he then is done. 5 just sits there all by himself, and 7,
would seem to point to 2, who
then is the last one. So there are the 3 files captured by this fact.