The concept of Feature Detection that
we'd looked at, in case of images,
still applies here.
Here I'm showing a video, and
you can see all of the green dots.
And these are features
that are being tracked.
And, of course,
there is a red box in the middle that
actually is trying to remain stable.
We'll cover this a little bit more in
detail when we actually talk about video
stabilization.
But you can notice that,
in essence, feature detection
is going on here as it was for images,
except that we're doing this over time.
So, the whole concept remains
the same apply to images.
But we're interest in here
is in leveraging the fact
that features found in one frame
may also be visible in the next.
So as long as there's
not a drastic change,
that is each and every pixel has not
changed from one picture to the other,
If there is some sort of commonality
in frames between one to the other,
we can use that fact to
help us track features and
observe similar types of things
from one frame to the other.
So I could learn for example that in
this frame there was a building here
with these types of colors.
As it moves around there might be
a bunch of pixels coming up in the next
few frames that may have the same
kind of color and appearance.