Other than being linear time, the nice
thing about bucket sort is that it's
easy to distribute,
at least in principle.
Just assign each bucket
to a compute node,
assuming you have say k = p of them.
Now let's assume that the n
input elements are also
equally distributed among these nodes.
Then you'd expect there to be
about n over p elements per node.
Lastly, let's also assume that all
the nodes know all of the bucket ranges.
Here's my question.
What is the running time of
a distributed bucket sort in a big O
sense?
By our usual conventions, let tau
be the time to do a comparison or
some other local work, and
let alpha and beta be the latency and
per word messaging costs.
I want you to put your answer here.
And I'm looking for something of
the form tau times something + alpha
times something + beta times something.
Now since I haven't given
you a specific algorithm,
you might feel the need to explain
the answer you come up with.
So for that purpose,
here's an extra little box.
Use that box to explain your reasoning.
Or if you're stuck and you just don't
feel like explaining your reasoning,
you can also use this box to vent
about your boss or your frenemies.