In this first exercise, we will handle
incrementing the number of glasses of
water that the user has consumed
when they click on this cup icon.
You have already seen this
PreferenceUtils clause that
handles incrementing the shared
preferences count values.
Now, even though updating a single
integer value in short preference is
pretty fast,
we have decided to use intentServices
to manage this increment
process in the background, why?
Well, imagine if this increment action
was to update the counter in some remote
database that keeps track of
all your health activities and
synchronizes all your devices together.
This could be a time consuming
process that we'd want to perform on
a background thread.
Also, when we get to sunshine,
we will need to update the weather data
in the background separately from
the activities life cycle because server
requests could be time consuming and
might outlast the activities lifetime.
So learning how to use
IntenseServices here
will help us update sunshine later on.
So to help keep our code organized and
modular, we will create a helper
class called ReminderTask.
This class defines all the tasks that
will run in the background for this app.
We'll start with creating a task
to increment the water count.
This means the activity will
start the IntentService,
which will then execute the increment
order count task in the ReminderTask.
And then this task will
use the PreferenceUtils to
increment the counter in
the SharedPreferences.
Okay, so to implement all of that,
you'll need to create a class
that extends from IntentService.
Inside, you'll execute
the tasks in onHandelIntent.
And then finally, in main activity,
you'll start this IntentService
using startService.
Okay, let's start coding.