To download Xcode, click on the link in the instructor notes.
This software will help us make our app.
Xcode comes prepackaged with the programming language Swift.
So this is the only thing you need to install.
Depending on your Internet speed, however, this download can take a while.
So while you're downloading Xcode I want to present you with a puzzle.
I will show you some Swift code in a second.
This code is going to look new.
And it's okay if you do not understand it fully.
I just want you to read through the code and
make a prediction around what you think this code does.
So here's the code.
Now as you're reading through this I want you to find as many clues as you can.
But, I'm going to start you off with one of own.
This code runs on a really popular app on your phone.
You should think about the following questions.
Which app on your phone uses this code?
What even triggers this code?
And also things about the code that you do not understand just yet.
So here's the question one last time.
What do you think this code does?