I'm going to get you started with
implementing FirebaseRemoteConfig in
friendly chat.
Here's an overview of what
you'll be implementing.
First, you'll set up a list of default
parameters for FirebaseRemoteConfig.
These are the locally-defined
fallback values that the app will use
if the parameters aren't defined
in the Firebase console.
You'll set up a FirebaseRemoteConfig
instance with these values.
Then you'll fetch the values
of the fire-based console for
any remote config values
that have changed.
After that fetch,
your object will be updated with
the latest remote config values.
Simple enough?
Let's go to the code.
The first step like always is to
include the correct gradle dependency.
We're doing remote config so
I'm going to copy that.
And then over here,
in my apps Gradle file, I'll add it.
And I'll sync to include
the new library.
As with the other services
that you've implemented,
you're going to need to make
an object for this one as well.
So I'm going to scroll down here.
And in my instance variables I will
add a FirebaseRemoteConfig object.
And you'll also initialize
it in the on create method.
Okay and now I'm going to start setting
things up at the bottom of the on create
method.
I'll start by using a handy trick
provided by the FirebaseRemoteConfig
object.
Enabling Developer Mode.
You'll do this using a
FirebaseRemoteConfigSettings object and
then you'll build it with
Developer Mode enabled, like that.
Then you can take your RemoteConfig
object and set the config settings
to the FirebaseRemoteConfigSettings
that you just made.
Note that this BuildConfig.DEBUG is
a boolean created at build time.
And it's true when you're using debug
builds and false for release builds.
That allows you to keep this
configuration code around for
both debug and release builds.
Okay, now that's done you're going to
define the parameter values for
remote config.
You'll do that using a map object,
and in the map object
you'll add the values to the parameters
you're going to be using.
Now in friendlychat you only
really have one parameter,
which is the message length.
So in our hash map we're going to add a
key value pair for that message length.
The key will be a constant called
FRIENDLY_MSG_LENGTH_KEY and
the default value for
that will be the DEFAULT_MSG_LENGTH.
Okay, let's go ahead and
define this key.
I'm going to scroll up to the top
of the class and add it right here.
Okay, good.
Okay, so
now my defaultConfigMap is setup.
And I'm going to take my RemoteConfig
object and I'm going to call
the setDefaults method and
pass in that map.
And that sets up FirebaseRemoteConfig.
Next.
You actually need to try to
fetch values through the server
to see if any of the config values
changed in your Firebase project.
I'm going to separate this out in
a new method called fetchConfig()
which I'm going to call here.
Okay, now let me define this
method at the bottom of the class.
The first thing you want to do is
specify the cache expiration time.
I'm going to set it to an hour for
production builds.
And I'll set it for zero for
builds where developer mode is enabled.
This is where our config
setting comes in.
This allows us when we're bugging it to
get the latest values from firebase if
there are any changes immediately.
Next, we'll take our
remote config object and
call it fetch to fetch the values.
And we will also pass in
the cacheExpiration time.
But you're not finished yet.
Because you actually need to do
something with those return values.
So what I'm going to do now is add
two listeners, a success listener and
a failure listener.
Now when the fetch is successful,
you can take your FirebaseRemoteConfig
object and
call this method activateFetched.
And this will do something called
activating your parameters.
And I'm going to make another helper
method called applyRetrievedLengthLimit,
which I will define down here.
Okay, so
point of the applied retrieve leg limit
is to appropriately update
the edit text length.
And to do that, I'm going to take my
firebased remote config object and
call this get long method,
passing in the friendly message key.
Now if the fetch was successful,
friendly message legs will now
contain what I got from the server.
Which then allows me to
take my edit text and
apply a filter which updates
the edit text length.
And this is similar to what I do above.
Here in on create when I
first setting up the app.
Okay, well let's go back down.
And finally here I'll just go ahead and
add a log statement that prints out
whatever our friendly message like this.
Okay, so that's everything I need for
the success case.
For the failure case, I'm going to
go ahead and write a log message.
And then I will also call
apply retrieve length limit.
Now this failure case will
happen if you're off line.
In which case down here,
what I call mFirebaseRemoteConfig and
getlong, it's going to give
me values for the cache.
The cache may be different from
your default parameter mapping, so
it still makes sense to update
the edit text length here.