Let's take a moment to make
something insanely clear.
As far as battery is concerned,
networking is the biggest, baddest,
dirtiest offender that there is.
Remember that inside of your phone
is a small piece of hardware that's
effectively a HAM radio,
its whole purpose it to communicate with
local cell phone towers and
transmit data to them at high volumes.
But the trick is that this chip,
isn't always active, you see,
once you send a packet of data the radio
chip will stay on for a certain amount
of time, just in case there's a response
from the server that it's expecting.
But if there's no activity, the hardware
will shut down to save battery life.
And as we've seen before, there's a
large battery spike when this chip first
turns on, and as long as it's
keeping itself awake to wait for
responses, it's going to keep on
draining the battery at the same time.
Now it's worth pointing out that there's
two primary ways in which most apps
interact with the radio.
Firstly, there are events
that need to occur right now.
These events are the result
of some user action, or
they arise from the immediate need
to update the UI of your app.
For example, imagine when the user
asks to load a new batch of tweets for
a trending hashtag,
since this is a user initiated action,
your app should respond ASAP.
On the other side of this coin are all
the networking jobs that don't need
to happen in a time critical manner for
example, uploading user data,
synchronizing background statistics, or
re-sizing all of your social photos.
So while the first set of tasks happen,
has to happen immediately,
in order to provide feedback to the
user, the second set of tasks can easily
be put off until later, when they can be
performed in a battery efficient manner.
And there's a high probability,
that the majority of your
network requests in your application
fall into this second category.
[LAUGH] Converting networking jobs
over to being more efficient is
a two step process.
Firstly, take a hard look at the mobile
radio row in your battery historian
tool for your application.
Each of those red bars that you see
here represent an active mobile radio,
any gaps between those bars
represent when the radio is asleep.
If you see lots of narrow bars and
gaps in your graph, this can point to
your performance problems, since it
means that you're churning through
lots of wake up and sleep cycles.
What you want instead, is to see large
gaps next to large blocks of activity.
This way you've reduced overhead by
minimizing the number of network
requests, and even better,
don't use the radio at all.
I mean you can wait until
the phone is connected to WiFi and
then let the WiFi hardware do all this
work with much less battery train.
Now, the problem is that writing
the code to batch, cache,
and defer all these networking requests
is really difficult to get right,
which is why we've done the work for
you.
The JobScheduler API that rolled out
with the L release of Android provides
a full suite of API's that do all of
this network request management work and
more, on your behalf.
But rather than telling you
about this wonderful API,
why don't you take a swing
at it in practice?