The proportion of students who said they saw broken glass is 29 out of 150,
which is about 19%. There was 50 students in the hit group so we would expect
that this proportion of 50 would say yes within that group. This comes out to
9.67 even though it's a decimal and we wouldn't expect 2 3rds of the students
to say yes, this is still our expected frequency. We do the same thing here. If
we expect 29 out of 150 to say yes, then we would expect how many out of just
50? This is just another way to look at the same thing we did here in the hit
group. This is the same as 29 divided by 150 times 50 which is the same thing.
9.67. This will also be 9.67. Note that we could have put different numbers of
students in each of these groups. We didn't have to divide them evenly. In the
problem set you'll get more practice with unequal groups. Now for no, we expect
121 out of 150 to say no. And so out of a group of 50, we would expect 121
divided by 150 times 50 to say no. This is 40.33 and this will be the same in
all of them since each group has 50 students. To simplify things, we can
calculate the expected values by simply doing the column total times the row
total divided by the grand total where the grand total is the total number of
people involved in this study. However its really important that you understand
intuitively how to calculate the expected frequencies. Don't just use a formula
because I give it to you. Its better to understand it than to plug and chug. By
plug and chug, I mean you plug values into the formula and you get something
out, but without really understanding what you're doing. Hopefully I explained
it enough to where you understand it intuitively. But if not, feel free to
write in the forums. You can also email me because I email you every week. So
you should have my email address.