To address the free
space fragmentation and
aggregation issues we mentioned
in the previous morsel,
the Linux kernel relies on two
basic allocation mechanisms.
The first one is called
the buddy allocator and
the second one is called
the slab allocator.
The buddy allocator starts with some
consecutive memory region that's free
that's of a size that's a power of two.
Whenever a request comes in, the
allocator will subdivide this large area
into smaller chunks such that every
one of them is also a power of two.
And it will continue subdividing until
it finds the smallest chunk that's of
a size that's a power of two
that can satisfy the request.
For instance, in this figure, when the
first request of eight pages came in,
the buddy allocator subdivided
the region that was 64,
the original area,
first into two chunks of 32 pages.
Then it subdivided one
of these 32 page chunks
into chunks that were 16 pages in each.
Then it subdivided this 16 page chunk
into chunks that were eight pages each.
And it turned out that this eight page
chunk satisfied the request that was for
eight pages.
So that was great.
Subsequently, another request for
eight pages came in,
and then a request for
four pages came in, and for that reason,
this chunk of eight pages was
subdivided into two chunks of four.
Now when this eight
page region is freed,
there will be some fragmentation here.
However, when the next eight page region
is freed, the algorithm will quickly be
able to combine these two to
produce a 16 page free space.
So fragmentation still exists
in the buddy allocator, but
its benefits are that
when a request is freed,
it has a way to quickly find
out how to aggregate data.
When this allocation of eight pages
was freed, with the buddy allocator,
it was very easy to figure out what is
the start of the adjacent allocation.
Where does the buddy of this
eight page region start?
If we didn't have this information, if
we didn't know that the adjacent region
is also an eight page region, we would
have had to potentially scan all of
these pages to determine which
one is free and which one isn't.
So as to figure out whether we can
increase this free space to nine, ten,
11, 12, or some other number of pages.
So the benefit of the buddy algorithm
is that the aggregation of the free
areas can be performed really well and
really fast.
The checking of what are the free areas
in the system can further be propagated
up the tree to check the buddies
of this 16 page free area,
and then the buddy of the 32
page free area, and so forth.
The reason why these areas
are the power of two is so
that the addresses of each of
the buddies differ only by 1 bit.
This makes it easier to perform
the necessary checks when combining or
splitting chunks.
Define that allocations using
the buddy algorithm have to be made
in a granularity of a power of two,
means that there will be some internal
fragmentation using the buddy allocator.
This is particularly a problem because
there are a lot of data structures that
are common in the Linux kernel that
are not of a size that's close to
a power of two.
For instance, the task data structure,
task_struct, is 1.7k.
To fix this issue, Linux also uses
the slab allocator in the kernel.
The allocator builds custom
object caches on top of slabs.
The slabs themselves represent
contiguously allocated physical memory.
When the kernel starts,
it will pre-create caches for
the different object types.
For instance, it will have a cache for
a task_struct or for
the directory entry objects.
Therein, when an allocation comes from
a particular object type, then it will
go straight to the cache and it will
use one of the elements in this cache.
If none of the entries is available,
then the kernel will create another slab
and it will preallocate an additional
portion of contiguous physical memory
to be managed by this slab allocator.
The benefit of this slab allocator is
that it avoids internal fragmentation.
These entities that
are allocated in the slab,
they're of the exact same size
as the common kernel objects.
Also, external fragmentation
is not really an issue.
Even if we free objects in this
object cache, future requests will
be of a matching size and then they
can be made to fit in these gaps.
So the combination of the slab allocator
and the buddy allocator that are used in
the Linux kernel, these are really
effective methods to deal with both
the fragmentation and also the free
memory management challenges that
are present regarding memory
management in operating systems.