Unit testing is something we're going to spend a lot of time
in this course looking at, and unit testing means
looking at some small software module at a time
and testing it in an isolated fashion, and so this is what we were doing
with the bounded buffer example from the last unit
and with the square root function that we were talking about earlier in this unit.
The main thing that distinguishes unit testing from other kinds of testing
is that we're testing a smaller amount of software.
Often the person performing the unit testing
is the same person who implemented the module,
and in that case we may well be doing white box testing.
But unit testing can also be black box testing.
The goal of unit testing is to find defects in the internal logic
of the software under test as early as possible
in order to create more robust software modules
that we can compose later with other modules
and end up with a system that actually works.
Besides the size of the software under test the other thing that
distinguishes unit testing from other kinds of testing is that
generally at this level we have no hypothesis
about the patterns of usage of the software under test.
In other words, we're going to try to test the unit with inputs
from all different parts of its domain.
Remember, the domain is the set of possible inputs for this piece of software.
Unit testing is also a kind of testing
that enjoys a great deal of good tool support,
and so Python, in fact, has a number of frameworks for unit testing.
It also has a number of frameworks for what are called mock objects,
and what mock objects are are fake objects
that we can bolt under the software under test that mock up the behavior
of the larger software system in which this unit lives.
And what we'll do is we'll include links to some of these tools
in the supplemental material for this course.