All right.
Hopefully this wasn't too tricky.
This is actually a very similar
situation to the udacicolaVotes.
pepcityVotes was also
made a local variable.
And similarly, its scope is limited
to just the votePepcity method,
meaning that it gets created here,
and then,
in this next line, after adding
1 to its value, it gets trashed.
That's something you might have
noticed is how pepcityVotes
doesn't have the initialization
to 0 that udacicolaVotes does.
This is actually a pretty big error, and
will cause your code to not be able to
compile, meaning it won't be
able to run on the phone.
Local variables must be initialized,
meaning that they must be given some
sort of initial value like we're
doing here with the udacicolaVotes.
Then we have the same problems
that we had Udacicola.
Between button clicks it's not actually
really counting up how many votes that
Pepcity has, and when we do the
showMeVotes method, because the scope
ends here you actually won't be able
to use the variable value down here.
So if you said that this has the same
problems as the udacicolaVotes does
you'd be correct.
Okay, let's look at another problem.