The answer is it depends.
There's a deliberate ambiguity here.
For example, suppose node zero
sends to node eight via this path.
If the second message takes this route,
then the two paths intersect
going in the same direction and
there will be congestion at this link.
If instead the second message takes
this route, then there's no contention.
So, in fact, if these are the only
two pending messages,
you can overlap them by
choosing good routes.
In genera,l for some analysis, you're
going to need to reason about whether or
not congestion or
contention are occurring.
We'll discuss some techniques to do so
in a different lesson.
Now the question asks for the minimum
time, so if you assume optimistically
the non-colliding paths, then you
would get just a plus b times n.