The correct answer is all of the above.
The more frequently you checkpoint,
the faster you will be able
to recover from a fault.
This is true because, with a frequent
checkpoint you will have a recent
checkpoint compared to the point of
execution when the fault occurred.
So you will have to replay or
re-execute a less amount of time
of the execution of the process.
Clearly the more
frequently you checkpoint,
the higher the overheads
of that will be.
And furthermore, with frequent
checkpoint, it's more likely that you
will end up catching every single
write to your particular page.
If you spread out the checkpoints,
it's possible that a single page will be
written multiple times, so
dirtied multiple times.
And also,
the more frequently you checkpoint,
you will end up transmitting more state,
checkpointing more state.
And the reason for
this is that with a frequent checkpoint,
it's more likely that you will end
up catching every single one of
the references of the write
updates to a particular page.
If you spread out the checkpoints over
time, it's possible that there will be
repeated writes to a particular page
that you will observe as a single dirty
page and so you will amortize the
checkpoint costs over multiple writes.
With a frequent checkpoint,
both the amount of the state
that will be checkpoint, and
in general the overheads of
the process will be higher than if
you do the checkpoint less recently.
So this is just one of those tradeoffs
where you end up gaining something,
but that's going to cost
you something else.