Well, clearly this is an admissible heuristic, because the distance to the goal
is strictly underestimated. From here, it would take one step, from here, it
will take one, two steps. So the answer is yes. Now,
to understand A star, let me also draw the g
function for development part of this table. Clearly g is 0
over here. To understand which node to expand, this one or this one, let's
project the g function, which is 1. And we'll see that 3
plus 1 is smaller than 4 plus 1. Therefore, this is the second
node to expand, which is b1. Now let me, for the next step,
expand the g function from this guy here, 2 and 2. So
3 plus 2 plus 2 is 4. Whereas this
3 plus 2 is 5. To expand this node next,
which is c1. And finally, the g function
from here would go 3 and 3. 3 plus 1
is better than 3 plus 2, so we will expand d1 next.
And notice how in the sum of g and h, this node over here, which has a total
of 4, is better than any other node that is unexpanded.
So in particular, 4 plus 1 is 5, and 3 plus 2 is 5 as well, and 2 plus 3
is 5 as well, so this the next one to expand.