Let's start off with the basics.
The pinhole camera.
Recall again, a pinhole camera
basically had a opening,
a small opening in a scene and
of course,
an image was formed upside down at
the focal length at the image plane.
An upside down image is formed there.
In essence, we also kind of
discussed this, that this point here
basically captured all of the light
in the scene at this point and
of course, that's what was
then projected at the back.
Now, of course, you can imagine,
that any point on this surface here,
the gray patch which is basically
where I have the pinhole, any point
in the surface is also actually
kind of capturing all the light.
Of course, since it's no longer a
pinhole, they're not actually coming in.
So, in essence, I could close this hole
and put another hole anywhere else
on this screen, and
that will actually act like a pinhole.
So you could actually put a number of
points, pinholes, in this surface.
And each one of them will basically
then, for this point here, become
the sensor, the light source, that will
actually create an image like this,
of course from a different viewpoint.
So you can imagine now anywhere on this
one surface here, a two-dimensional
patch, I can put a pinhole and it will
generate a different image, right?
So in essence that proposes to us
that any point in this whole region
has the same capability, not just
on this two-dimensional surface.
So, a point here in space is also
getting what we refer to again when we
looked at earlier stuff as a bundle of
rays of light converging to this point.
And that bundle of rays of light here,
basically, is captured here.
And of course,
if I was to put a pinhole camera I
would actually capture an image here.
So this is a pencil or
bundle of rays of light at this point.
Of course,
we need not actually just be stuck
to all of the monolith's rays of
light coming from just one direction.
Any point anywhere in
the world basically gets
all of the light converged at this
point from all directions, right?
So any point in this scene is basically
capturing a whole lot of rays of
light converging to one point.
And it could be any point here, any,
you know, any point in this scene
could actually be doing this.
So just to kind of reiterate that point,
a 3D scene, many points exist in
that 3D scene and I'm just pointing out,
you know, a few of them.
So any 3D scene there are lots of these
points around it, each one of them
a bundle of rays of light are actually
being collected at it in the 3D scene.
Again this is just pictorially showing
it, look around it at any point in
the scene, for example, here, all
rays of light are hitting this point.
Another point here, all rays of
light are collecting on this point.
I could actually create a camera,
pinhole camera, that would capture all
the light and similarly, I could capture
a ray of points of light here to
capture all of the light that
is hitting this point too.
Now, just to simplify this, we can
actually say is that each point here
can be represented as a sphere,
all right?
All of the rays of light are converging
onto this sphere from the world.
So all rays of light
are coming in to each and
every one of these spheres from
all three directions, right?
So we can basically say that in essence
this world is full of these types of,
you know, specific spheres, and
the point of that center is where
all the light is accumulating.
So in essence, any scene is
full of these types of points.
So in essence, again, that basically
says any point in the whole 3D
world is actually capturing pinhole
types of camera information,
except that we are not
just capturing it.
That point is already
capturing that information.
We just haven't put a sensor
there to capture it.