To understand the result we are seeing,
let's take a closer look at the computation that is happening behind the scenes.
Here are the two images.
The first image is the result of dividing each image by 2 and then adding them.
And the second is the result of adding the two images first and
then dividing by 2.
The first image has better detail and
is also slightly brighter than the second one.
Now, we know that these images are just collections of intensity values.
And values at each corresponding location are being added together.
Let's take two sample values, say, 183 from one image and 152 from the other.
Now, in the first case, we divide these numbers by 2 and then add the results.
In the second case, we add the two numbers first.
What do you think is the result in these two cases?