Hopefully you're able to complete lesson two, stage two.
I'll walk through my solution.
First after creating the sentence count topology, scrolling down to part one of
two, I asked you to import the random sentence spout,
which is located in the Spout folder of Storm Udacity.
Therefore, it's simply import udacity.storm.spout.RandomSentenceSpout.
Once this is imported, I ask you to make sure that your class name and
your constructor matches your file name, SentenceCountTopology.
Therefore public class SentenceCountTopology and
private SentenceCountTopology constructor.
Scrolling down to the main method and
your topology builder, I asked you to remove the word spout.
I simply commented it out.
But here's our word spout.
And attached the new sentence spout to the topology.
Simply that's .setSpout, sentence spout, and our anonymous declaration
instance of a new RandomSentenceSpout with a parallelism of one.
Next I asked you to attach the count bolt to
the sentence spout using a field grouping.
A field grouping was the third question.
Remember that a field grouping creates a hash or
a subset of all of the spout or connection into the bolt.
What this means is that each individual sentence, each unique sentence,
is going to be sent to the same bolt and therefore we increment the count.
I'll just scroll a bit to the right so we can see the rest of the syntax.
Notice that the fieldsGrouping connects the sentence-spout using the new
field, sentence.
This may have been a bit tricky but
I asked you to look at the declaration in random sentence style.
And scrolling down,
we see that the declare output field names the new field sentence.
Therefore, to connect the count-bolt to the RandomSentenceSpout,
we need to connect on the field sentence.
One final point is that the count-bolt is already connected to the report-bolt.
Using our color scheme once again we see that here is our RandomSentenceSpout.
Here is our count-bolt, and finally our report-bolt.
We're making the connection here using a fieldsGrouping.
And we're making this connection using the globalGrouping.
So hopefully that's clear on how our syntax translates to our visualization.
Finally, to run and build our topology, we go to our command line.
Submit our topology.
Storm space jar target tab udacity tab hyphen tab.
Again, with dependencies udacity.storm.
And this is our SentenceCountTopology.
Navigate to your visualization, and as you see Storm running with no errors.
We see the words from the random word spout growing with count.
You can also hover over one of the sentences to see the current count.
There we see 32.
And if we let it run a bit further, we see we have 49.
Finally, I asked you to go to the RandomSentenceSpout and change the random
sentences to your own personalized version of the RandomSentenceSpout.
Hopefully you were able to do that,
create your visualization, take a screenshot and post it to the forum.
And hopefully comment on two others.
Remember, that at the end of stage two, your code will match stage three.
Great job.