Jay show us how you did this one.
>> Sure thing,
it went a little like this.
So first I'm going to open the cache for
our images.
Once I've got the cache,
I'll look for a match for storageUrl.
If there is one I'll return it, done.
Otherwise, I'm going to fetch the image
from the network using the fetch API.
Once I get the response, I'll add it
to the cache using the storageUrl and
a clone at the response.
Then I'll return the original
response to the browser.
Remember, you can only read
a response's body once.
This is why we have one
copy going to the cache and
the original going to the browser.
Now I'm going to use Force update and
reload the page.
If we check in the Resources
panel in dev tools, yep,
we can see the new cache and
it has images in it.
If I resize this panel so
we can see the whole URL,
you can see the URL ends before
the bit with the pixel width,
confirming the cache URLs
aren't site specific.
Let's test the serving.
We'll bring the server down,
go offline, and reload the page.
And the images are still loading but
here's the ultimate test.
If I change the width of the browser and
reload, yep, the images still load.
This means the service worker is
returning the image we have cached
no matter which width of
image the browser requests.