In the same thread, let's look at some recent stuff that people from
thousandmemories.com put up there on their site.
This is the number of photographs taken each year and
as you notice the claim is that about 2011, 380 billion photographs were taken.
And, of course, initially, the analog number of pictures was pretty strong too,
but that's fading away.
But digital photographs are still continuing.
So in about the 200 years of photography, the claim is that
more than three five, 3.5 trillion pictures have been taken overall,
just 4 billion of them in the last year or so.
So in essence that would suggest that 10% of all photographs that exist
in the world right now, just 10%, were taken just in the last year or
so, and that's the kind of the growth curve of number of photographs out there.