Welcome to the iOS nanodegree program.
Hi, My name's Jason, and
I'm Udacity's iOS curriculum manager.
>> And, I'm Miriam.
Your nanodegree community manager.
We want to take a few minutes
to talk about this program,
and help you think through the nature
of the effort you'll be undertaking.
>> We're really excited
about this program.
iOS is the original
smartphone environment, and
the App Store is the most lucrative
of the mobile app markets.
It's a lot of fun to be able
to join in and create apps.
>> Our goal is to help you develop the
skills you'll need to make those apps
and to prepare you for
a job as an iOS developer.
>> We think that you'll find that it's
also a profound learning experience to
learn the iOS libraries.
Taking the time to wrestle with
the architectures that Apple has written
is a valuable way to expand
your programming experience.
Our next code,
the development environment,
is an exceptional tool as well.
>> The core of this nanodegree program
is a portfolio of apps
you'll be writing.
Each of these apps will help
you learn key iOS skills and
will give you great technical
talking points in future interviews.
You'll make progress by
completing these apps, and
submitting them to be reviewed
by professional iOS developers.
In addition to helping you build
the technical skills you need,
we offer career involvement activities
to make sure you know how to market
yourself as an iOS developer.
>> To make sure that you're
prepared to build these apps,
we've created courses to
help you get started.
If you have a lot of
experience writing for
iOS, you might want to jump right
into the projects, but in general,
we think most people want to
go through the courses.