Mm-hm. >> I know Lab Door Architecture is getting pretty popular as a buzz
word nowadays.
>> Mm-hm.
>> But sort of looking beyond that into having exactly one system where you can
potentially re-process from your, your message buffer, whatever else.
Do you guys have any plans to extend Storm Architecture to do that?
>> I mean [INAUDIBLE] exactly from this point of view I see advantage, for
doing exactly once because it can deduce the constraint on the backside plane.
>> Yeah.
>> Because any going.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And that in turn if you make that exactly ones without having too
much resources added into the existing pipeline.
Then you can save a lot of cost on the batch pipeline because easily can go to
the point where you cannot once a day or.
>> Mm-hm. >> Probably can only on demand if the real biplane is steady enough.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> Now we've given,
having said that now the batch, I'll do good if you're doing exactly once.
So now, that might be hard because the reason why it is especially when you're
doing real-time pipeline, there are some failures that's possible.
Even though you might be exactly want, there could be failures,
not on the arctic pipeline, but on more of the data capture pipeline.
>> Right. >> Right, for
example, operationally as it could be mission going down but the data in
that might not have been collected until the mission was brought back up, right?
>> True. >> But as on the batch pipeline the data can lazily get there,
eventually the batch will pick up, right?
As long as there's enough time to transferring the two on
the real time pipeline there is a bunch right?
>> Mm-hm. >> So which means so you can not live with exactly one semantics,
i'm not saying that, no I don't want any batch anymore, right?
>> Right.