Last time, we saw how each
type of light is different.
But because they all use
the light component,
they share a lot of
the same common properties.
To really see them, let's first
switch back to a point light.
So underneath range is the first
common property, color.
If we click it that opens up a color
picker which we can use to color light.
Picking a color adds
a tint to our light,
just kind of like what
we see at a concert.
Let's experiment with this by
making our point light red.
See how the walls have
a red tint to them now?
Now let's experiment with the intensity.
As you've probably guessed,
this property allows us to control
how bright Intense our light is.
We can bring it down to zero for
no effect, or
max it out to eight,
completely saturate our scene with red.
As you can see, we have a lot of
control over our light's brightness.
But for now,
let's tone it down to a one.
Next, let's talk about shadows
which has the real selling
point about using lights within unity.
Done properly, you can get some
really nice effects like this.
However, on mobile, we need to be really
careful about real time shadows as they
are fairly computationally expensive for
shadow type we have three options.
The first being no shadows,
the second option is hard shadows
which are shadows with sharp edges.
In the real world these shadows don't
exist but they are a lot more performant
than their counterpart soft shadows,
which is the third option.
Soft shadows tend to look more
like shadows in the real world but
at run time,
they are very impactful on performance.
On mobile, we highly recommend
not using real-time shadows, so
we're just going to turn it off.
Later, we'll show you how you could
get some nice shadows by using baking,
like we discussed briefly,
with area lights.
The last two properties I want to touch
on are render mode, and calling mask.
Render mode is a property
that tells you unity
how important this light is for
the scene.
By default, it set to auto but, we could
change it to important or not important.
Let's leave it as auto, with auto,
unity automatically determines if
the light is important to our scene,
if the light is not important and
unity realize the app is
not maintaining frame rate.
It can turn it off and
thus save on performance.
Although not ideal,
it's better to have a high FPS than
an experience that makes people sick.
And last we have the culling mask.
If you remember from the cameras lesson
the culling mask let's us
choose which layers to render.
In a similar fashion,
the calling mask lets us choose which
layers this light should affect.
If we set it to nothing,
our light basically doesn't even exist.
Just like with the camera,
we can create our own layers and
define what objects can and
cannot interact with the light.
Let's allow our light to
interact with everything for now.
There are a few more properties
that are generic to most lights but
they're not used as often compared
to the other ones I just mentioned.
So I'll leave them for
optional reading if you're interested.
At this point you now know enough to
start and come around with lights and
making each one unique in your scene.