In this question, we're saying in
the following script is used to generate
the query, so the query is going to be,
we want to select account information
from a table called users, and
we want to do it for those users for
whom we going to have the login,
a password, and PIN.
These three values going to be red,
all these arguments going to
be red from a form.
And once we read them,
we going to generate this query that is,
this SQL query that is going to
get submitted to the database,
what input is necessary for
it to generate the correct query.
So there are three options here.
Mark whichever ones you
think are applicable.
So it's really understanding this
little script code that we have
here that is used to generate
the query that we going to submit.