So here I am in the command
prompt inside sqlite3 program,
looking at the shelter database.
So using our .schema command,
I can see that this is the CREATE TABLE
segment used to create the pets table.
Well as it stands this CREATE TABLE
segment is a little bit problematic, and
I'll explain why.
So first,
let's actually look at the information
that's in our pets table right now.
So to make it easier to read I'm
going to turn on the header, and
then change the mode to column, and
then select all the information
from the pets table to print out.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So you'll notice right now we
have two pets with IDs 1 and 2.
Well let's say a cat named Binks,
perhaps a breed of Bombay,
was just dropped off at the shelter.
And the attendant enters this
information into the database.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Did you notice that something is off?
Let's take a look at using the select
statement to see in more detail
what exactly went wrong.
So looking at the output here we
notice that our supposedly unique IDs
are no longer unique.
Notice that both Tommy and
Binx both have the ID 1.
Alternatively, what if
this scenario happened?
Say an attendant forgot to enter
the name of a cat completely.
So for example,
a cat enters the shelter,
the attendant enters this information.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So notice that the attendant completely
forget to enter the name of the cat.
And so here we just see a blank
space for this fourth object here.
SQL has solved these easy keywords that
we can add to the columns to help us
avoid this.
And note that these are just a small
subset of all the attributes
available to you.
But these are going to be the important
ones for us in this table.
So the ones I've listed here
are the primary key, auto increment,
not null and default.
So let's take a look at these at work.
Let's see how they would effect our
headphones example from before.
Now their headphones, remember there
were five attributes we want to store.
So it's the name, the price, whether or
not it's in stock, the description,
and the style.
So I've taken those five attributes and
put them as the columns in this table.
As well as included the ID column.
Now to create our headphones table,
we would need to use this statement.
So CREATE TABLE,
with a table named headphones.
And here would be the columns,
ID which is an INTEGER,
name which is TEXT, price which is
an INTEGER, style which is an INTEGER.
And stock, that would be INTEGER,
and lastly description,
which will store as a TEXT.
Now, let's see how we can use those key
words from before to help make our table
more robust.
So first off is the primary key.
So this key word marks the column
used As a uniquely identified row.
And like I said,
this ensures uniqueness.
Meaning there can only be
one primary key per table.
So the PRIMARY KEY attribute
is often used in conjunction
with the AUTO INCREMENT keyword.
And this keyword is used to make
an ID column that is both unique and
automatically picks up a new
unique ID when you make that row.
So this is how it would look
in our headphone table.
So I've added the keywords right after
I declare the data type for ID, so
after integer here.
So I've added PRIMARY KEY,
and AUTOINCREMENT.
So note that I could've added one or
the other just by itself, but
in this case, I decided I wanted
to add both of the keywords.
So having added those keywords, this
means if I add three new headphones,
inserting three rows, even if I
don't add the ID, the table would
automatically increment the ID without
me specifying what the number would be.
So for example,
this one might get the ID 1.
This headphone might get the ID 2, and
this one might get the headphone ID 3.
Now, say I've added those three
rows into the table using
the autogenerate IDs, 1, 2 and 3.
What if I try to enter a new row
with an ID that's already used?
So in the example here,
I'm inserting a headphone into the ID 1.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Well, I would get this error.
And this error tells me that I can't
enter the ID that's already being used
because it's not unique.
So this here is an added
layer of protection.
So next up is the not null keyword.
So this keyword allows us to say when
a value's inserted into the table,
it must have a value associated with it.
So if, for example, we didn't want to
allow a missing name from the table,
we can change our creation
statement to be this.
So adding NOT NULL after
the data type TEXT
indicates that the name value must
have something associated with it.
It can't be just null.
So let's head over to the terminal and
try out what this command
looks like there.
So let's use our .open store.db command
and move over to our store database.
So inside this database I'm
going to create a table.
Where the ID is the primary key, and
I want that ID to auto-increment.
And I also want the name
value not to be null.
So let's enter those specifications.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now if I enter a headphone that doesn't
have a name, I should get an error.
So let's try that out.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And as expected,
I'm getting this error that says,
NOT NULL constraint failed:
headphones.name, and
that's because I had specified up here,
that I want the name not to be NULL.
But when I inserted a headphone into
it I didn't have a name specified.
And so the database is telling me,
nope, you can't do that.
Remember, you have to have the name.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So finally we have here our DEFAULT
keyword which adds a default value of no
other values given.
As it says here, when inserting
a new row, if no value is defined,
the default value given can be used.
So say for example if no value for
in_stock is given,
I want it to be set
automatically to zero.
Meaning that there's no stock.
Also if I want in_stock to never be
NULL, I'd add the NOT NULL keyword here.
So this is what the entire
create scene will look like.
Notice that I don't add any commas
between the keywords, just spaces.
All right, so here we are back
in the command prompt, and
lets see that DEFAULT
keyword in action here.
So before I do that, I'm going to
drop the table we just created in
the previous example so we start fresh.
So DROP TABLE headphones,
and just want to make sure.
So no more tables inside this database.
So from here I want to
create a new headphones tool
that involves our keyword DEFAULT.
So CREATE TABLE headphones.
So for our in_stock com here I
want to specify that it's an INTEGER,
I don't want it to be NULL.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And I want to give it
a default value of 0.
Now given these constraints,
if I insert a new headphone again but
I don't specify it whether or
not it's in stock.
The tables automatically set
the headphone to default as 0
which corresponds with not in_stock.
So let's try that.
So when insert a new headphone in,
leaving off the in_stock column.
All right, so that command should've
inserted a new headphone into our table.
And we can see that by using
our SELECT FROM command.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So here's what the headphone looks
like as a row inside our table.
Notice there's a little bit of
a wrap around for the description,
but that's okay.
So first of we have the ID that we
enter, actually we didn't enter.
Remember we automatically
incremented it here.
And then we have the name
of the headset, the price,
the style that we specified,
and then in-stock.
So look, it automatically
used our default 0 here, and
then our description,
Standard inner headphone, color black.
Now to make our create
table even more robust,
I'm going to drop this existing
table and they create a new one.
Where I add NOT NULL to the price,
as well as having nothing for the style.
So here's what that would look like.
So like I mentioned before,
style won't have any constraints on it.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
But in_stock will have
a couple of constraints on it.
And the description will just be TEXT.
And there we have it.
So this is the newly created headphones
table with all this new constraints
added to it.