Let's go over an example
of packet filtering.
This is a simplified example of
a rule set for SMTP traffic.
The goal is to allow inbound and
outbound e-mail traffic, but
to block all other traffic.
The rules apply top to bottom for
each packet.
That is, for each packet,
the firewall is screened up high,
each rule, one by one, from top to
bottom, until there is a match.
So let's explain
the intent of each rule.
As we can see, each rule here has a rule
number, has a direction of the traffic,
has a source, and a destination
IP addresses of the packet.
The protocol,
the destination port, and the decision,
whether it's permit or deny.
The first rule is to allow inbound
email traffic from an external host,
therefore it says the direction is in,
meaning inbound.
The source IP address is
an external IP address,
because we are talking
about inbound traffic.
The destination IP address
is an internal IP address.
The protocol is TCP, the destination
port is 25, which is for SMTP.
Again, this permits inbound email
traffic from an external source.
Second rule, it's intended to allow a
response to an inbound SMTP connection.
Because here, in the first rule,
we allow inbound email traffic, so
we should allow outbound
response to the email traffic.
The third rule allows outbound
email to an external source.
That is, we allow outbound
traffic to external email server,
SMTP server, port 25 on an external
destination IP address.
And since we allowed outbound
email to an external email server,
rule number four allows
the inbound response.
That is rule number four is intended
to allow an inbound email response.
Rule number five,
this is an explicit statement of
the default policy, which is denied.
This means that if a packet does not
match any of the previous rules,
then the packet will be discarded.