Welcome back to computer vision.
Today we're going to talk about, stereo correspondence.
Up until now we've defined the epipolar geometry that talks about how
the two views relate, and how if you have a point in the left image,
then if you know the camera's relation, it's a one dimensional search.
And in general, the epipolar lines can be,
well, arbitrary, not arbitrary, but skewed in a variety of ways and located.
But today, in order to make life easier, we're going to assume a bunch of,
simplifying assumptions.
For example, we're going to assume, basically the geometry that we
drew out last time, of parallel, or coplanar actually, image planes.
We're going to assume the same focal lengths of the two cameras.
We're going to assume that they're,
the cameras are horizontally aligned at the same height.
So we're, and that the images are pulled out such that the epipolar lines,
are horizontal, and, that they are, in fact lined up, so a xy location
in one image is at a different x but the same y location in the other image.
So look, that's a lot of assuming, and for real stereo, you wouldn't be
able to do that, you'd have to do a rectification of the image first.
We'll talk about that, couple lectures from now.
But for now, we'll make the assumptions which will allow us to
attack the correspondence problem more easily, and in fact,
it's the way you're going to be doing correspondence on the problems sets.