So now I'm going to
show you a variety of
conditions where actually would allow us
to both increase the envelope and figure
out the best possible smooth paths to
the original red path here of a camera.
So, for example,
we can define various ways of defining
how big we want the envelope to be.
And, of course, in that condition's
based on different types of constraints
we can add, we can actually look
at different types of paths.
We can actually have constant length
paths, linear paths, that actually now,
if you notice, there's linear
connections on the blue line itself.
Parabolic ones, which start giving
it more curves, much more smoother.
And if you notice, these basically
are now allowing us to control
how we can actually figure
out both the envelope.
And this envel,
envelope defines, of course,
how big my crop window is going to
be and how smooth the path would be.
We actually did a lot of analysis in
this work to figure out some best paths,
and that's what we refer
to as the YouTube paths.
That's the one that's been widely
used in the system right now.