So finally, we can talk about full camera parameters or
camera and calibration matrix.
The camera and its matrix M, and sometimes it's called pi, and
that's what I've written here, as we know, is described by several parameters.
It's got a translation T of the optical center from the origin of the world.
We've got a rotation R of the coordinate system.
We've got a focal length and aspect, f and a.
Pixels or, or pixel size, sx sy.
A principle point, that's the offset x, xc, yc or cx cy.
And skew.
And in this slide, the blue parameters are called the extrinsics and
the red are the intrinsics.
And we can put the whole thing together,
we want to find this as a sort of a single matrix.
M is going to be built up of all of the effects of our parameters,
and so that looks like this.
Okay?
What is says is that M is a combination of translate,
this is extrinsic, and rotate.
So now we have the point in the 3D camera coordinate system.
Project, this is just the extraction of the xyz, and
then you pump that through the intrinsics.
And how many degrees of freedom are there here?
Well, there are 11.
Five for the intrinsics, three for the rotation, three for the translation.
I'll get rid of all that scribble.
That equation there, that M, that is the full camera calibration matrix.