The next step is to add the client
side functionality to login.html.
Facebook has two options for
doing OAuth login.
Import the Facebook JavaScript SDK,
and use the Facebook functions.
Or construct your own Auth manually.
Since our web application only uses
JavaScript from the client side.
I will create an implementation that
uses the SDK to create a log in button
and retrieve the short
lived access token.
Similarly to the Google Plus function,
I will create an Ajax call to
send this token to my server.
On the server side I will
manually trade this token for
a long lived token with Python.
So, let's dive into the code.