While you will not be required to use
the Network Link Conditioner tool for
on the map, you should at least
install it for future work.
To install the tool,
you need to follow these steps.
First in Xcode, go to the Xcode
menu item here at the top, go to
Open Developer Tool, and then click
on this More Developer Tools option.
From here, you'll be directed
to Apple's website and
it'll ask you to log in if you
haven't already using your Apple ID.
Then on this Download for
Apple Developers page, search for
the network link conditioner tool.
Once you've searched for it,
you should see one of these
Hardware IO Tools for Xcode downloads.
You'll want to download the version of
the hardware tools that's compatible
with your version of Xcode.
To complete this exercise,
you'll need to download and
install the Network Link Conditioner.
If you get stuck at any point,
you can check out the article I've
linked to in the instructor notes.
Check this box when you're done.