One major use of diagrams is that you can use them to convey information to
others in the group.
The others might be your teammates, but they also might be
people on other parts of the project which you don't normally communicate with.
They might even be persons down the line time-wise.
That is, the maintainers who are going to deal with the system
five years from now.
Communication is the first answer.
Second, we're talking about, in the case of UML object-oriented development, and
object oriented development has a particular process often used in
association with it.
That is, the diagramming technique can support a process that you're using.
For example, your process is likely to have some kind of
validation step associated with it, maybe a design review, and
using a particular design diagram can help you structure that review.
Also, by using a particular kind of diagram, there,
you may be able to find some tool support for that diagram.
The tool support might inform the user when a violation of
the visual syntax occurs, or inform the user that a piece is missing.
As far as the disadvantages are concerned, just like source code, any time that
you build a diagram, you have to worry about it getting it out of date, that is,
keeping it up to date with respect to changes in the rest of the system.