Right.
I've checked out the app.
Now, I'm ready to run it.
Once again,
all of the commands I use here will be
detailed in the presenters as notes.
First step CD into the project
folder and run npn install.
This fetches all the third
party code the app needs, and
it'll probably take some time,
so be patient.
Also npn does like to scare us
by showing errors and warnings,
but these are optional dependencies and
different operating systems will show
different warning, so
that's something to enjoy.
I love it when text flies by on the
command line like this it makes me feel
really smart like I'm hacking
the metrics or something.
Right.
That's the install done.
You shouldn't need to run that again.
To run a project the command
is npm run serve.
When you run that the build script
executes, building all the JavaScript,
CSS, etc, and finally it tells
us we have two servers running.
If you ever want to shut these
down it's control and c.
You can also modify the port
numbers of the servers if you want.
Those details are also in
the instructor's notes, but
now we can open a browser and
point at localhost port 8888.
And there we go.
The app is running.
Excellent.
Now it's your turn.
Once you have everything set up,
check the boxes to confirm, and
we'll explore the app in more detail.