In this new notation, instead of writing
plans as a linear sequence of, say,
succ, move right, and succ, I'm going
to write them as a tree structure.
So we start off in this belief state
here, which we'll diagram like this.
And then we do a succ action.
And we end up in a new state.
And then we do a right action.
And now we have to observe the world.
And if we observe that
we're still in state A,
we loop back to this part of the plan.
And if we observe that we're in B, we
go on and then execute the succ action.
And now we're at the end of the plan.
So we see that there's a choice point
here, which we indicate with this
sort of tie to say we're following
a straight line, but now we can branch.
There's a conditional, and we can
either loop or we can continue on.
So we see that this finite
representation represents an infinite
sequence of plans.
And we could write it in a more
sort of linear notation as S,
while we observe A do R, and then do S.
Now, what can we say about this plan?
Does this plan achieve the goal?
Well, what we can say is that if
the stochasticity is independent,
that is, if sometimes it works and
sometimes it doesn't,
then with probability 1 in the limit,
this plan will in fact achieve the goal.
But we can't state any
bounded number of steps
under which it's guaranteed
to achieve the goal.
We can only say it's
guaranteed at infinity.