All right, we probably already gave it
away based on the earlier videos, but
we need to create a string array to
store the list of English words for
the numbers one through ten.
An array is ideal for this situation,
because there are related groups of
words that we need to keep together.
We also want to maintain
the order of the words.
So we ensure that the order goes 1,
2, 3 and so on.
And it would be weird if the words
were displayed out of order.
Since there are ten words, we initialize
the array to be of size ten, so
we have ten slots.
We also give the array variable a name,
words.
As for the data type of this variable,
you need to be an array of strings.
Because we want to store text
at each element of the array.
And if each word were one character
long, we could just gone and
use char and created a char array.
Then remember char is another
primitive data type, but
these words are much longer,
so we use a string array.
Let's add code in the numbers
activity to create a new words array.
To create the array variable we'll start
with a capital letter S for string.
And remember this is because
string is an object data type and
not a primitive data type.
Following that,
we'll need to add brackets to
indicate that it's a string array.
We'll give the variable a name called
words, and then I'll write in the equal
sign followed by new space String
with a value 10 within the brackets.
So 10 here indicates
the size of the array.
And remember that we always end our
statements with the semi-colon.
So once we've created an empty string
array we can start assigning values into
each position by specifying
the value at each index.
So, for example, at the 0th index,
assigning the value one,
and remember that this value
here is a text string.
So I'm going to do that for each index
and until we reach the text string 10.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So here's how the full
solution will look once we've
added all ten words into our app and
store them into a string array.
I know this might look a little bit
strange, because we had the value one
stored at the 0th index and our ending
value ten stored at the 9th index.
But this is correct, and
you'll get used to arrays starting at
the 0th next as you use them more.
So great work, now we have
an array of words in our app.