The final topic in object design, that I want to mention,
has to do with how you're going to deal with abstraction.
During the process of development,
you may wish to increase, maintainability by enforcing abstract interfaces.
And there are various mechanisms in object oriented languages, available for
you to do this.
For example, there are abstract methods.
An abstract method is essentially a method signature,
in a parent class that says the types of the arguments and
the type of the return value possibly also any exceptions that might arise.
Child classes then, have to provide the implementation of the abstract class,
obeying that particular signature.
Any class, with an abstract method becomes an abstract class.
And abstract classes can have no direct instances.
It's only the child classes,
that have implemented the particular method that can have instances.
Essentially then, abstract class is providing a kind of contract.
That all subclasses must obey.
Java provides, goes one step further and provides the concept of interfaces, and
interface is an abstract class in which all the methods are abstract.
For example, the serializable class is an abs, is an interface.
I should say that serializable interface is an interface.
In addition there are no non-final attributes in interfaces.