Before we write any code,
I'm going to take just a moment
to return to the pod file.
And remind you that this is when you'd
want to add the pod to your pod file for
Firebase UI.
Now, you could add the pod for just
the Firebase UI Authentication Features.
But in our case, we've added the pod for
all the Firebase UIs, so
we'll get everything.
Back in our Xcode project,
we're going to be making some
changes to the FCViewController, so
that Firebase auth UI presents
its authentication view for us.
First, we'll implement email
password authentication.
And then once we see
fire-based auth UI in action,
we'll add Google authentication too.
First, let's make sure we
import the module necessary for
Google auth UI's authentication.
And now, let's review the properties
of this view controller
which pertains specifically
to authentication.
We have the auth handle,
which is an instance of this
FIRAuthStateDidChangeListenerHandle,
that's a mouthful.
We have the user, which is an FIRUser,
which represents the currently
authenticated user.
And of course, the displayName.
A string that's used for
the name when a user sends a message.
Lets talk more about the auth handle.
This handle gives us the ability
to specify what we want to happen
when authorization state changes.
And as a user navigates
the authorization flow,
the state will certainly change.
The callback that we specify for
this listener will be invoked when
the app registers itself as a listener.
When the current user changes, and when
the current user's access token changes.
That may sound confusing now,
but let's see a concrete example.
We want to create our listener handle
the moment the view controller loads, so
we could do this in viewDidLoad.
But we've already stubbed
out a separate function for
configuring our authentication
called configureAuth.
Let's remove the call to isSignedIn
because we no longer want users to be
automatically signed in as Anonymous and
then call configureAuth.
Great, now, let's go to that function
and create our listener there.
The code to create
the listener looks like this.
Let's go over it line by line.
First, we set the auth handle by using
the default instance of the FIRAuth and
adding a state change listener.
This function takes a closure
which is where we can specify
what we want to happen when
the authorization state changes.
The closure takes two parameters,
FIRAuth and FIRUser.
First, we refresh the table data so
it doesn't contain any previously loaded
messages, because this could be out
of data or from another user's login.
Then we check to see if
there is a current user.
And we make sure that the current user,
according to Firebase, is the same as
the user who is currently using the app.
If an authenticated user is found,
we set the SignedIn status to true.
And set the displayName to the portion
of their email before the at sign.
If there's no current user,
we set the SignedIn status to false.
And then we call loginSession.
Cmd-click, or scroll down to
the log-in session function.
You will see that this function
instantiates a view controller called
authViewController using
Firebase auth UI.
This view controller is simply
the default view controller provided by
the FIRAuthUI.
We present this view controller
whenever a user needs to log-in.
Now, that's almost all we need but
there's still a few small
items left to address.
Like the other listeners
we've seen in this project,
when it's no longer needed,
we should remove it.
Let's go back to the deinitializer.
And using the auth handle,
we can unregister the listener so
the app stops listening for
authorization changes.
And that's all we need to enable
email password authentication
using Firebase auth UI.
What was that, five, six lines of code?
Let's go ahead and build and
run the app to see it in action.
Now, when the app opens, it presents
this authView Controller because there's
no currently authorized user.
If you press cancel,
the authViewController is dismissed, but
the FCViewController is blank.
Because it is signed in as false and
there's still no authenticated user.
So let's press sign in and
bring the log in screen back up, and
we'll sign in with email.
Now, when you put in an email for the
first time, Firebase UI recognizes this.
And segues to a view that enables
you to create an account.
If I was an existing user,
then I would have been segued to a view
where I just put in my password.
We can't see it now, but there's
also a trouble signing in button,
when users can reset their passwords
using a request that's sent by an email.
Let me go ahead and finish filling
this out, and we'll click Save.
Wow, how easy was that?
That was all taken care of
you by Firebase auth UI.
Now, that we can see
the existing messages,
let's try sending a new message
as an authenticated user.
Now, when we send a message,
it shows the first part of
your email as the username.
We were able to handle authentication
with multiple views with only
a few lines of code.
It's easy to see why Firebase UI Auth
is useful for handling authentication.
Next, let's see how easy it is to
add another authentication provider,
Google, to friendly chat.