Now, we talked about using language for learning,
and this slide is demonstrating the power of language,
how it has such a powerful connection to the real world that allows us to learning things
just by observing language use.
What I've done here is I've gone to Google trends and types in two search terms--
"full moon" and "ice cream" and gotten back a graph of how popular those queries are over time.
We also have a graph of the news volume for those terms over time,
but that's not so interesting here.
What's interesting this side is the regularity in these patterns.
This pattern allows me just by observing language to do amateur astronomy.
What do I mean by that?
Well, look at the curve for ice cream.
Popular in the summer. Not so popular in the winter.
What that means is if I wanted to figure out what the rotational period is of the earth around the sun,
all I have to do is measure these peaks, and it would come out to 365 days--
a very regular performance of language speakers using the term "ice cream" in the summer
repeatedly year after year.
Now, there's a little bit of a blip here.
What happened in this case?
Well, it turns out that a manufacturer of cell phone operating systems
decided to call the latest update to their operating system "Ice Cream Sandwich,"
and so there was a lot of searching for that when it came out.
But that just lasted a few days, and then things went back to normal.
Similarly for the query "full moon" in blue, we see this period here,
and we can measure that period to be 28 days,
we we can do amateur astronomy and figure out how the moon works as well,
just by observing how people in the real world use language.