[Thrun] The last example I want to talk about in this lecture
is related to general purpose path planning
where we don't have a road network.
Here is an example of where this occurs.
This is an example of where a blockage occurs.
None of the preplanned paths are drivable by our robot,
so it has to, after a certain time out here--20 seconds--
find itself a path anywhere in the environment.
In fact, our Urban Challenge car did just this.
We don't do this today in traffic. It's a little bit dangerous.
But for the Urban Challenge it was perfectly doable, and it was safe.
So this car found a route that was outside any pre-given corridor.
Here is an even more challenging example
where our robot Junior approaches a complete road blockage,
but its target location is behind the road blockage.
You can see that none of the paths can possibly make it there
and the only correct action is to turn around and pick a different road
to finally approach the goal location from the opposite side.
You can see an attempted lane shift to the opposite lane doesn't function either,
and there is time models supposed to be with all of those.
Eventually, using a general purpose planner
of the type that Peter talked about in his class
to find what ends up to be a really complicated multi-turn turnaround
where the car backs into a driveway a little bit, as you can see over here,
and it is all planned completely dynamically without any preconception
how such a multi-point U-turn would look like.
Then it goes forward, then it goes backward, and does so multiple times
until it finally has turned around.
It's not particularly efficient or elegant, but it's very, very safe.
This vehicle will eventually be able to drive in a different direction
and reach the goal point behind the blockage.
That was one of the tasks DARPA gave us.
So you can see it do its job until it finally breaks free
and is able to navigate around this blockage onto a different street, as shown over here.