The final step is when we now
want to run something referred to
a structure from motion.
Some of you have taken a computer
vision class are going to
learn more about this.
I'm going to just brush over it and,
if needed, can provide more details
to anybody who is interested.
Let's start off by basically
saying here's an image.
I'm using a simple box here,
but actually let's think about
this image here as the image
that we're trying to match.
Of course, we have one camera.
In this case, we're going to
talk about more than one camera.
Remember, in stereo, we talked about
two cameras, but let's talk about
three in this instance, basically
shown by these three simple cones.
Again, in this larger image,
this is the one image that we're
actually trying to pay attention to.
Of course, there might be more images,
because this is a real scene, right?
This is a real scene
with lots of 3D points.
One image is captured.
We want to figure out where this image
is in all of these three different
cameras.
Pretty much like what we did for
panoramas.
Again, when we looked at
a bundle of rays, and
basically asked the question if
the bundle of rays could be used.
We can now actually
synthesize a new image.
In this case, we're not trying
to synthesize a new image.
We're trying to use the fact, that can
we figure out the registration and
alignment of this one image in all
these three different viewpoints?
Of course, there are lots of
caudal points visible to each and
every one of the cameras
which relate back to
all of the points that
are basically in the scene itself.
Just take point p1 here and
we're going to project this into all
three of the different view points.
Again, each and every one camera
has a transformation matrix.
For simplicity's sake, I am basically
referring them to having a rotation,
because that's what's actually
true here, and a translation.
So, for camera one R1,t1,
camera two R2,t2, and camera 3 R3,t3.
So using this, of course,
these are the transformations
we need to optimize over.
Each camera is rotated differently and,
of course, translated.
So, of course, this will allow
us to hopefully figure out what
the transformation matrix for each and
every one of the cameras are.
But basically, it's coming as each point
is, of course, being seen in each and
every one of the three different
cameras, as shown by this ray of light.
So again, like what we've done before
when we talked about panoramas,
here we basically want to be
able to take this function and
minimize it to basically have,
and again,
this could be done with a variety
of different points that we have.
To compute a minimum function
which actually optimizes our
rotation transformation for
each and every point.
Recall again how we did this when we
talked about the whole concept of
panoramas.