Now that's a contract.
At this point, we define
the names of the columns we want,
but we still don't have a database.
To actually make a database, we're gong
to extend Android's SQLiteOpenHelper.
SQLiteOpenHelper contains cool
stuff to create the database and
help us handle database versioning.
As we make changes to our
database in the future,
tt will help us modify our tables.
For many apps,
being able to upgrade to a new
version without data loss is critical.
For Sunshine, we just want to make
sure that upgrades in that involve
schema changes happen smoothly.
Let's take a look at SQLiteOpenHelper
more closely in action.
We're going to be working in the
WeatherDBHelper class that you've been
given which extends SQLiteOpenHelper.
It contains code to create and
initialize the weather database.
Let's examine it.
At the beginning of the DbHelper, you
can see that we've defined constants for
DATABASE_VERSION and DATABASE_NAME.
The DATABASE_VERSION typically starts
at version 1 and must be manually
incremented each time we release an
updated APK with a new database schema.
The DATABASE_NAME is the name of the
actual database file in the file system,
which will be weather.db in our case.
Note that we're using version 2 since
this revision of the course uses
an updated database version.
These values get passed
into the constructor
to initialize the database helper.
Next we have the onCreate method.
This is where the SQL we've
been talking about and
our new contract class
are used together.
The first time the database is used,
SQLiteOpenHelper's onCreate
will be called.
We need to write the correct
SQL statement string so
that we can create
the table sunshine needs.
We then have the system execute
this SQL by calling db dot execSQL.
Note how we're using all of the weather
entry constants to write our
sequel statements.
Also note that we use lots of not
null constraints on this table.
These constraints help prevent us from
inserting records without columns being
filled out into the database,
and that helps to prevent bugs.
Here is the implementation of the
FOREIGN KEY constraint from the not yet
created location entry table.
This means that we cannot insert
a weather entry into the database until
a location entry for
the weather location has been inserted.
And we cannot delete locations
while there exist weather
entries that point to them.
That being said,
it's going to be a while before we
have UI that can demonstrate that
our database code is working.
Fortunately, there's a way we can
have Android run any code we want,
even if there's no UI yet ready.
Android has a built in testing framework
that allows us to create a test APK that
executes a JUnit test that call
into classes in our main APK.
If you aren't already
familiar with JUnit,
it is a testing framework that allows
you to write automated test suites.
You can run your automated tests easily.
You can find your tests in this
section of the Android Studio project.
Just right-click on the test package and
select Run.
Once the test pass or
fail, you'll see the output down
here at the bottom of the screen.
I'm not going to display the emulator
on our screen because it won't actually
show that we're doing anything.
The tests we're running don't
have any user interface.
But you can see here in the test runner,
we're instantiating tests.
An empty window and
a green result means the test succeeded.
Let's look at the TestPractice class.
You can see it sits in the data
package of our test project and
extends AndroidTestCase.
When you extend AndroidTestaCase,
you can implement the setUp method
which will be run before each test.
You can also implement tearDown
which we run after each test.
Similar to JUnit test, you simply add
new methods in the class with the prefix
test such as
testThatDemonstratesAssertions.
And those will automatically
be run by the test processor.
Some other things to note.
The FullTestSuite class contains
code to include all of the Java
test classes in its package into
a suite of tests the JUnit will run.
This allows us to easily
add additional tests,
by just adding additional Java
class files to our test directory.
You'll likely have a class like
this in each test project you make.
They aren't typically project specific.
So you can literally
just copy this file.
Each test should have at least
one check which uses an assert
to see if the program
applies the correct output.
An assert is just that,
it's a declaration that
the outcome after part of a test
is run matches our expectations.
If the assert does not match,
the test will fail.
Let's look at our
testThatDemonstratesAssertions in
TestPractice.java.
AssertEquals asserts that the expected
value equals the actual value.
If they are not equal than
an assertion failed error is
thrown with the given string message.
Other useful methods
include assertEquals,
assertFalse, assertNull, or
we can just call fail if a certain code
path should never have been reached.
Feel free to write your own test
cases to play with assertions.
Let's see what happens
when we make a test fail.
As you can see our results are now red,
and
we can see exactly where in
the test are application failed.
Let's uncomment out the testCreateDb
function inside of the TestDb class.
You might have to import a few
classes to get this to compile.
Let's also uncomment out
the createNorthPoleLocationValues and
the insertNorthPoleLocationValues
functions from within TestUtilities.
This is the last chance to fix
up your location contract if
things don't compile.
So let's run our new
test with our TestDb.
As you can see, we get a pretty good
error message back, that our database
was created without both the location
entry and weather entry tables.
Don't worry.
We can fix it.