So now let's look at
another simple lens system.
Here I'm going to actually just
complicate things a little bit, and
add an eccentric aperture.
What that basically means is,
I'm going to cover a part of the lens,
so no light is going through,
so only part of the lens
is open, and it's eccentric,
it's no longer symmetric.
I'm going to cover just the,
this part of it, so this lens is open.
What happens to rays of
light in this instance?
So this light source,
of course, will go through, and
create a point where we expect it to,
right?
So amount of light is reduced, but
we will still get something
at the point we want.
So of course, that basically means an in
focus object still forms a point image
where we expect it to.
When we move the object closer,
what happens this time?
Remember, again, from what we looked
at in the last instance, in this case,
forms near object is blurred, but
it's only appearing to the right
of the optical center, right here.
Right?
In the old case, of course,
when we didn't have an eccentric,
we had,
of course, a blurred region everywhere.
But in this, by,
by covering this part of it,
we're only getting it on this side,
and it's blurred.
No rocket science needed.
If I move the object far away,
same experiment, and this time around,
the object is still blurred, but is
blurred to the left of the center line.
So just by creating a simple,
eccentric thing, we're now actually
capturing a lot more information.
Yes, we're losing in
the quantity of light, but we're
capturing more information, even about
the distance of the object itself, too.
Again, something we looked at when
we looked at things like depth, and
all that kind of stuff, earlier.