Remember earlier, we implemented
a DetectedActivitiesIntentService, and
we saw that we sent the array
list of detected activities
back to our main class using
the local broadcast manager.
Well you can receive this in a class
that extends BroadcastReceiver.
And to make life even easier,
this class can be embedded in
the main activity as a nested class.
If you're not familiar with nested
classes, you can learn more about them
in the link that I've put underneath,
in the speaker notes.
So next,
you should create a nested class, and
you should call it
ActivityDetectionBroadcastReciever.
And this should extend
BroadcastReceiver, as we've said, and
it should override a method called
onReceive which takes a Context and
an Intent.
When you've done this, check this box.