Previously you seen that viewDidLoad
gets called when the ViewController class
is loaded into memory.
This diagram illustrates the View and View Controller lifecycle.
When the view and
is loaded into memory.
This diagram illustrates the View and View Controller lifecycle.
When the view and
View Controller are changing states,
these functions if you've implemented them
will get called. In iOS, the will
functions always get called before the
did functions. For example viewWillAppear
gets called before viewDidAppear.
viewWillAppear gets called before
did functions. For example viewWillAppear
gets called before viewDidAppear.
viewWillAppear gets called before
the View Controller and its viewer on-screen.
viewDidAppear gets called right after the
view and View Controller on screen.
This is really useful if you want something
to happen right before or right after a
View Controller appears. If you override
these functions in your View Controller,
they will get called, otherwise their
default and empty implementations in the
UIViewController class will get called instead.
If you haven't seen before,
let's add the function called viewWillAppear.
Notice I've mistyped the
If you haven't seen before,
let's add the function called viewWillAppear.
Notice I've mistyped the
function name,
there's an extra p. Even though I
mistyped its name, this function is still
valid code and Xcode would compile this
without error. To the compiler, this is
just any other function.
But unfortunately for us, this function
doesn't actually refer to the viewWillAppear
function that belongs to the
UIViewController. So it's not going to
behave like we might expect.
That's okay though.
UIViewController. So it's not going to
behave like we might expect.
That's okay though.
Let's remove this and let Xcode help us
avoid this problem.
The viewWillAppear function belongs to
the UIViewController class. So for our
ViewController which subclasses
UIViewController will want to override it.
As we begin typing override func and
then viewWill we can see that Xcode
shows us a suggestion of the function it
As we begin typing override func and
then viewWill we can see that Xcode
shows us a suggestion of the function it
thinks we're trying to complete.
As we begin typing override func and then
viewWill Xcode shows us suggestions of what
it thinks we're trying to type.
viewWillAppear is what we want, so I’ll
hit Enter and let Xcode do the rest of
the work for us. And this is really handy.
Now the first thing that we want to do
is to call the super class’s
the work for us. And this is really handy.
Now the first thing that we want to do
is to call the super class’s
implementation of viewWillAppear
before we do any of our own custom stuff with viewWillAppear.
So we'll go ahead and do
that now.
before we do any of our own custom stuff with viewWillAppear.
So we'll go ahead and do
that now.