The most ambitious and most recent type of Middleware is sometimes called
Object, or Component, Middleware. This is an extension of remote procedure calls
to deal with objects. Thinking instead of making a function call, you're sending
a message to an object which might happen to be on a remote machine.
Some issues arise when we do this. One is what's called object identity.
If you're on a single machine, the identity of an object is really its memory
address. If you've got multiple machines, those memory addresses you can no
longer guarantee to be unique. So you need some kind of a global mechanism for
numbering or naming the various objects so that you can send message to
the appropriate object. And then inheritance. Could it be that a child
instance is on one machine and a parent instance is on another machine and
there’s delegation of message passing from child to parent. Features that
object and, and component middleware might provide include both synchronous and
asynchronous message passing. Marshaling of data. Exception handling across
machines. Some of the the product approaches for dealing with this include
CORBA which was a mainframe approach developed in the 1990s. COM from Microsoft.
And then SUN, SUN's now Oracle's Java remote messaging invocation RMI