All right, welcome back to Computer Vision.
Last time we talked about images as functions.
An image could be thought of as a function of
two dimensional position like i of xy.
Or a two dimensional array we'd say f of ij row column.
And sometimes I'll try to distinguish between whether I've got rows and
columns and x and y.
And we talked about how x and y are not the same as rows and columns.
In fact, a row is typically going down so if we go row, column, that's y, x.
The other thing is, and we're going to talk about this in a little bit,
there's going to be this question about whether y gets bigger as you go up
in an image, which is like what you learned in grade school, right?
Y positive goes up.
Or maybe a lot of you think of rows going down, and so
we'll, we'll have to wrestle with that.
And, we also talked about that, even though indexing in a computer world should
start at 0, in MATLAB, indexing of arrays starts at 1, and you're sure to screw
that up somewhere in your code, but eventually, you'll learn to figure it out.