So let's look at these
developer tools in more detail.
We've already seen the console and
any code that you run here,
will run against the documents.
But it's obvious what
lives outside documents.
So if I log self.registration which
only exists in a service worker,
we get undefined back.
However, I can change the context of
the console using this drop down here.
I can select different frames,
workers, including the service worker.
Now if I log self.registration,
it works.
If you're familiar with
JavaScript debugging,
you'll be happy to know that this
works with service workers, too.
You can go to the sources panel,
open the service worker, and
debug it like any other
bit of JavaScript.
Here I'm going to set a break
point in our Fetch event.
Now if I refresh the page,
our script gets paused.
I can inspect the state of
objects just as you'd expect.
If you're new to dev tools,
check out the instructor's notes for
links to guides and tips.
But away from standard
JavaScript F tools,
service worker has its own
panel in the resources tab.
This bin icon lets us
unregister the service worker,
which is useful if you want to refetch
the service worker from scratch.
And these tabs give us insight into
the service worker life cycle.
We can see here there's
an active service worker, but
there isn't a new version waiting.
We can tell that because its
waiting tab is grayed out.
It seems like we have an incoming
communication from Mike Wales.
>> Hey, I can't help noticing you've
been talking for quite a while now.
We should probably let the student
become familiar with all this new stuff.
>> That is a very good point.
I have been going on a bit.
Take it away, Mike.
>> So Jake's been demonstrating
the service worker lifecycle and
developer tools to observe it.
What I want you to do is make
a change to the service worker.
Get it into a waiting state, then allow
that service worker to become active.
If you've been following
the course in order,
the demo app is in
the correct state already.
If not, you can run this,
git reset hard,
git reset hard gets rid of
any local changes you have.
And git check out log requests gets
the project into the state worth
registering a service worker and
logging requests.
Now for the challenge.
Make a change to
the service worker script.
It can be anything.
A new console log,
even just a JavaScript comment.
Then refresh the page to pick
up the new service worker.
In the resources tab, you should
see the new service worker waiting.
This is what it should look like, an
active service worker and a waiting one.
Once you've done that,
head over to the settings page and
type sw-waiting into the test field and
press enter.
This will let you know
if everything is working