Now back in the Chrome browser we
have this full featured JavaScript
interpreter.
We can execute any arbitrary JavaScript
code like 5 + 7, which returns 12.
We can also even create functions.
Here's the Start of a function that has
no parameters and is called, say_hello.
I start by defining the function
with the keyword function,
I give it a name and
then any parameters, I'd like.
I'll hit Shift+Enter at the end of this
line to go down into the console and
then I'll hit Shift+Enter again
to close off my function.
For the body of the function, I'll
simply return the string Hello, World!
Great, notice that when I hit Return,
I get undefined returned
to me in the console.
Now, that doesn't mean my
function is undefined,
because if I start typing in the name of
the function even the first two letters,
I see that the JavaScript console
recognizes the function and
tries to auto complete it for me,
I can hit Tab to auto complete.
Now, if I leave the parenthesis
off of this function,
the console will simply return the
function definition that I just defined.
See, there's the same function.
Now, this is small but
very important point.
The definition of a function or
what code you get executed when calling
the function is separate from
actually running the function.
If instead I add the parenthesis
at the end of the function and
run it, then I see I get
the string returned Hello, World!.
Now if your console starts to get
cluttered with a lot of output or
statements, you can type
clear into the console
followed by two parens
to clear the console.
And finally, if you hit up or
down on the arrow keys,
you can get a list of all the commands
that you've run through on the console.
So this is a quick way to
jump back to other commands
that you've already entered.