Here's a game tree for a stochastic 2-player game.
There are max nodes, min nodes, and chance nodes.
What I want you to do is back up all the values, so fill in a value for the value of
each of these nodes, and then check off all the nodes that could be pruned away
by a procedure that's similar to alpha beta, but updated to handle chance nodes.
So what I mean by that is, a node can be pruned away if evaluating the nodes
is not necessary to figure out what the best moves are for max and min.
For the chance nodes, all the possibilities are equally probably.
So here, there's a 1/3 chance of each of these.
Here there's a 1/2 chance of each of these.
And in this game, the result of every game is either +1, -1, or 0,
and all the players know that those are the only possible outcomes for the game.
Therefore, the players can take that into account when trying to figure out
which nodes to prune away.