Let's keep our image
cache under control.
We're going to do this from
a index controller in public JS
mainIndexControl.js.
I'm going to start by creating a new
method called cleanImageCache.
When the page loads it
starts the controller so
in there I'm going to call a new
cleanImageCache method but that means
the cache can still go out of control If
the user keeps the page open for ages.
So will also call it every five minutes.
Now we need to do is implement
this new clean image cache method.
Implementing clean image cache is
going to bring together index TB and
the cache API.
A combination of things we've
learned in this course.
And we've got a Mike on the line.
So Mike it looks like this is
the end of course boss fight.
>> Yeah.
This is a toughy but
I bet they can do it.
>> To start you want to catch up
with the code Jake just wrote.
Do this by running git reset --hard
to remove any local changes you have.
Then, git checkout task-clean-photos
to get the stubbed methods.
Now head over to
public/js/main/indexcontroller.js,
the main page script.
Your task is to implement
_cleanImageCache.
It involves getting all
the messages from the database,
looking at what photos they need,
then going through the images cache and
getting rid of ones you
don't need any more.
Remember that the photo's property may
not exactly match the URL in the cache.
Once you've written the code,
head over to the browser and
refresh the page using the force
update on reload option.
So you only need to refresh
once to see changes.
Looking at dev tools,
you should see the cache only
contains images that are on the page.
An easy way to test is to open a new
tab and navigate to the URL here.
We can see in the cache that
this image has been stored.
Now when I reload witter
the cleanup code kicks in and
the image is gone from the cache.
To double check everything is working,
head to the Settings page and
type cache-clean into the test field and
press Enter.
You now have eight seconds to
trigger your cleanup code.
The best way to do this is
to just refresh the app.