Images of course have been an important part of our society, and
they play a role in a variety of things that happen around us.
I always like to show examples that, you know, image,
availability of images like this, from Kennedy Assassination, the Zapruder film,
was, you know, an important part of the history of America,
where people were able to see what happened.
This was an interesting thing because Zapruder was by just chance available at
that moment with his own camera to take this.
And that's one of the reasons we got a lot of pixels of this sad event.
But you know similarly if you think about it Rodney King's beatings in L.A.
again resulted in a lot of imagery that was seen by people, and again,
in this instance, there was a film crew at the other side of
the street where something was happening, and when these,
events started unfolding, they just came over their camera and started shooting.
But now, of course, when you start thinking about 9/11, 7/7 London bombings and
Virginia Tech, a lot more images of those events were possible.
These were people just there by chance.
But now, more and more, people have access to cameras and
they can share pictures.
In an example here is Michael Richards, where he bent and
started saying foolish things on telev, on, in a, a comedy stage.
Of course, people use their cell phones and
put his video up on YouTube, I believe.
And that resulted in a lot of uproar about what his statements were.
But more importantly,
this is the kind of stuff that we're seeing more and more of now.
In Russian, there was a meteor shower in Russia.
And all of a sudden, we've got amazing pictures of this meteor
shower not because photographers were waiting to take pictures of it but
people had cameras on their cars for variety of security purposes.
And all of a sudden when they were driving they started seeing these
meteors come down.
And all of a sudden the Web was full of images of people
sharing these images on the Internet.
And again, they were not just sitting there taking pictures.
This was just by chance.
And even more in the Boston bombings at the Marathon,
at the Boston Marathon bombings, there were lots of photographs taken.
And these photographs collectively were used to actually even to
figure out how the scene unfolded and find the people responsible.
So again if you notice just by chance these cameras were there.
And the number of images from these things increases.
So what I claim now is, with the growth of these cameras,
we really are creating a beast with a billion eyes.
There is not a point on Earth where we cannot get images from any more, and
that's actually pretty much evident as we grow from
just taking a few pictures to billions and billions of pictures.