Copying that over.
Well, this is just matrix multiplication.
I hope you all know that a b bracket transpose is just b transpose a transpose.
If not, trust me, all right?
So I can regroup using the associative property here.
Such that here I have the transpose and
that's where this comes from, from, from that.
Okay.
And then what I can do is I can combine this whole thing,
the K inverse intrinsics from the right transpose times
Z times K inverse of the intrinsics on the left.
Remember I don't know what they are but I just know that they exist.
And I'm going to call that whole thing F.
And when I do that I end up with this beautiful, beautiful, beautiful equation.
It just says that p transpose of the image point on the right,
'kay, so this is from the image now, times F
times p in the image on the left equals zero.
Okay?
And this is a relationship between image points, which I can just write
this way a p transpose F p prime equals zero.
P being in one frame, p prime being in the other frame.
That is the fundamental matrix constraint.
That's what's going to allow us to solve for the relationship
between one view and another given enough points that correspond.
Enough p and p primes that correspond, we're going to be able to solve for F.
And once we do that we know what relates the two images, or
this can just be written as p transpose F p prime equals 0.
P in one frame,
p prime in the other frame it's the relationship between the points.
Now, with this equation, I'm going to be able to do a lot of things.
In a minute, I'm going to show you how we can solve for F.
That is, if you give me enough points p and
p prime that correspond, I'll be able to solve for F.
But the other thing is F is actually very powerful in terms of
describing how the epipolar geometry works.