Imagine Jarred here.
He represents the client, and
he wants to make a request for
the Udacity homepage.
But to do so,
he has to make an http request.
The request itself can
get pretty complex.
But all Jarred really needs to know is
the uniform resource locator or URL.
For Jarred, he writes the URL for
Udacity homepage.
Once he's written that request,
he places it on his desk to be handled.
This request gets picked up by Jason,
who then travels
over the network to Jessica because
she has the Udacity homepage.
Jessica represents the server.
Jessica analyzes the request to
make sure that it's valid, and
then she looks for the Udacity homepage.
If she can't find it, she'll send
an error code back to Jarred.
But as we can see,
Jessica's found the resource, and
she prepares it to be
sent back to Jarred.
She gives the response to Jason,
who then carries it back to Jarred.
Finally, once Jason's
brought the response back,
the http request is finished.
This specific example
is an http get request.
And we'll learn about the other types
of requests later, also called methods.
Of course, there are many complexities
that I'm not mentioning right now.
But all you really need to
remember is to send and
receive data via http,
a client makes a request to a server.
If you'd like to take
a deeper look into http,
check out our awesome video on
http in the instructor notes.