So great,
you've now created your application.
So the next thing to do
is to edit your layout.
To do this, you're going to use
a StreetViewPanoramaFragment.
You can add a StreetViewPanoramaFragment
to your layout.xml simply like this.
You create a new fragment,
and you give it this name,
com.google.android.gms.maps.StreetViewP-
anoramaFragment.
Now over time this name may change
because of refactoring of the code, so
if this doesn't work for you,
just check the latest documentation for,
StreetViewPanoramaFragment, to
see the package that it's in.
Once you've done that,
in the standard way, you give it a name.
I've just called it streetViewPanorama.
And you give it a width and a height.
And for this application,
I just matched the parent to them.
So go ahead and edit your layout.xml
now to add this fragment to it.