hi Brian hey David so you've got a
pretty impressive title vice president
of applied deep learning research what
does a vice-president do all that
that's a great question actually right
now I'm looking for people with deep
learning experience to come join my team
but most of my career I've spent
building deep neural networks and
infrastructure for deep learning and i
still spend a lot of my time on that
alright so impressed me what's the most
amazing thing you've ever done with deep
neural networks
well one of the things I'm most proud of
is that i wrote a library that became
cool D&N which has become really
important for using gpus to accelerate
deep neural network training all right
I'm impressed
Brian's being a little modest kudiye has
become so important in fact that it's
effectively a requirement for
successfully training deep neural
networks
well I certainly think so soku zan is
great i would be happy if I built one
project is successful coup D and then in
my life but beyond kudiye and what's the
most exciting deep neural network you've
been working on recently
well the last big project I did was at
baidu and I was part of the deep speech
team where we built a new kind of
end-to-end deep neural network for
speech recognition in English and
Mandarin Chinese that is amazing