So now let me tell you a little bit about the overview of this class and
how we have structured it for you.
We're going to have these video lectures where I'm going to introduce to
you variety of technical concepts associated with the field of
computational photography.
Within these lectures there'll be once in a while a few quizzes, and
each one of them is aimed to get you more engaged with the material, and learn
more about different aspects of this specific discipline we're talking about.
In addition to the lectures, we've also created a variety of assignments.
There will be one assignment due almost every week throughout the whole term,
and in these assignments we're going to play,
have you interact with material in different ways.
Sometimes we'll actually have you do coding to be able to
generate computational photography artifacts.
But also how we produce artifacts that can engage with each other,
in a peer feedback, peer review manner.
There will be an exam, somewhat near the end of the term, which will cover and
review the concepts throughout the whole term of what we've looked in in
computational photography.
Then, we will actually allow you to do a final project in an area of your
own choosing.
I will provide you with variety of different ideas on what you can do, but
again this is something in my many years of experience in
computational photography and teaching these concepts is the students enjoy
finding something free form that they can do on their own.
We have a great team of people working with me on supporting this class.
There will be head TA who will be interacting with you,
as will I, on the different types of fora made available to this class.
And we look forward to interacting with you throughout the whole term,
engaging with you in different variety of ways.
I'm excited about this class, I'm excited bringing this whole concept to you.
I hope you're excited in learning about it,
and hopefully you'll engage with me throughout the term.
The tagline I always tell everybody about computational photography,
have fun computing with photographs.