Let's see what the correct answers are.
So which of the following are not a responsibility of the scheduler?
First, the scheduler has no control over when I/O operations occur.
So clearly the first choice should be marked.
One exception are the timer interrupts.
Depending on the scheduling algorithm, the scheduler chooses when a process
will be interrupted, so when it will context switch, so clearly it has
some influence over when events based on the timer interrupt will be generated.
This also answers the third question.
It is the scheduler, based on the scheduling algorithm,
that decides when a process should be context switched, so
this clearly is responsibility of the scheduler.
Similarly, it is the scheduler that's in charge of maintaining the ready queue.
It is the one that decides which one of the processes in the ready queue will be
scheduled to execute next.
And finally, the scheduler really has no control over when external events can
be generated, other than the timer interrupt as we discussed.
So it has no control over events that a process may be waiting on.
So this choice should be marked as well.