So using this diagram, here's some quiz questions that ask you to
figure out what's really going on there. And for this quiz, you should be
aware that the events labeled A, B, C, and D correspond to the four buttons on
your stopwatch. First question is how many outermost states does the watch have?
Second, what button must be pressed to turn on the alarm clock feature?
It's the alarm clock, not the stopwatch. Third,
in the ALIVE state, how many concurrent machines are running? Fourth, when the C
button is pressed to set the time, which part of the time, that is the day,
date, hour, minute, or second, is the first one the user can change?
And fifth, if you are changing the time on your watch and you press the B
button to indicate you are done, what unexpected side effect occurs?