In the previous lesson, we were given a
function, the sum function, and we later
added our tests, identified some bugs
and started refactoring our code.
This approach works, but
the real power behind testing shows
itself when you write your test first.
This is called the red,
green refactor cycle.
It's called this because you
write your test first and
they all fail since there's
no code to make them pass.
You then write the code required
to make your test pass.
Once that's complete you can safely
refactor your code as continue to add
new features.
Let's put the red, green refactor cycle
into practice by writing our very own
address book application.