So, welcome to
the Android Basics Data Storage course.
Right now, we're at a pet shelter, and
we'll get to exactly why
we're here in a moment.
>> The most important thing is
that this is the last course of
the Android Basics Nanodegree,
so you're almost done.
>> And so far you've built a lot
of different apps along the way.
You have your birthday card app,
one for ordering coffee, another for
learning languages, and even one for
fetching data from the internet,
such as earthquake information.
>> Yeah, and you're probably anxious now
to go off and build your own app, but
some of you might not
have a specific idea.
A really good way to practice would
be to ask a local small business or
a non-profit if they need any help
with building an Android app.
>> So, a lot of small businesses in the
neighbourhood have information they need
to provide to customers.
For example, restaurants have menus and
dry cleaners and
tailors have a list of
services that they offer.
>> And even more likely will need
to store all this data somewhere,
like in an app, so that way we can
access it at any time from our pocket.
This app could be used by
customers like you and
me, or it could be used
internally within the business to
manage like the day to day operations,
or you can track inventory.
>> Exactly, and one example that we're
going to explore is the idea of using
a mobile app for the staff to keep track
of all the different pets in this local
shelter, and
that leads us to exactly why we're here.
>> Besides the fact that Jessica and
I also wanted to pet furry animals.
[LAUGH] We're at the Humane Society
Silicon Valley in Milpitas, California,
so we can chat with a staff member about
what the day-to-day operations are like.
>> So, let's go ahead and meet with
Jessica, the Supervisor of Adoptions
here, to learn more about the data they
collect and how they keep track of it.