So, as I said before,
in this class we will specifically
look at displaying ads.
So how can you display ads in an app?
And perhaps the first question of all,
where do ads come from?
Well, ads normally come from companies
out there that want to advertise.
We call them the advertisers.
And in addition to the classic ways to
advertise like TV, commercial signs,
or when you browse the Internet,
the advertisers want to reach
all the mobile users out there.
Now how can they do that?
While mobile users use apps and
you as a developer creates
these apps that the users use.
So we have a great story here, we have
the advertisers that wants to display
ads, then we have you the developer
that wants users to use your apps.
But as we saw before, users are
typically not willing to pay a lot of
money for your apps.But what if we could
connect the advertisers with your users,
and the advertisers could pay
you to show adds to the users?
That would solve everything, but how can
you get in touch with these advertisers?
That's exactly what this
lesson is all about, and
the platform that enables this,
is called AdMob.
AdMob can retrieve ads from
a huge number of advertisers.
So when your app requests
to display an ad,
AdMob will select from all of these
advertisers to get an ad to display.
And this is a very complex flow, for
example it needs to consider ad bidding,
how much did advertisers pay to display
the ad compared to other advertisers.
Ad displaying how many
times has an ad been shown.
And spending caps,
how much is an advertiser willing to
spend on displaying ads this month.
But fortunately, you don't need
to think about any those thing
as an app developer, because AdMob is
hiding all this complexity for you.
AdMob will select the ad that
should be displayed in your app.
You only need to use a simple API
that we 're going to look at, and
then it will do all the magic to
retrieve an ad from the advertisers
that makes sense in your app.