In order to get continuous updates,
the first thing you need to do
is ensure that your activity
is a LocationListener.
So you'll have to
implement this interface.
You can find it in
com.google.android.gms.location.Locatio-
nListener.
If you don't want all of this
in your class declaration,
of course you can just
import the name space and
then extend LocationListener,
and that should work well.
You'll also need a module level
variable for the location request.
So be sure to add it at the top of
your code along with all the others.
It should look something like this,
protected LocationRequest and
you give it a variable name.
In my case,
I've called mLocationRequest.
Once you have that in your on connected,
instead of just getting the last
location, you would setup a location
request class with an interval for
polling the location services.
You'd then request location updates,
calling back to this activity.