To help us understand kind of how to
do this analysis of camera motion,
let's look at some of the motion models.
Now this will remind you
of the stuff that we looked
at in one of the previous lectures about
image transformations where we were
trying to model how an image would be
transformed from one to the other.
Now, all of a sudden, this should start
making sense in the context of how we
can do this with video.
So here, for example is a video
that we are interested in.
What we are interested
now in is finding,
in this image by these point
moving around like this.
What's the best possible camera
motion in terms of a variety
of degrees of freedom.
And of course,
we want to be able to model the least
number of these degrees of freedom.
Remember, the degrees of freedom when
we talked about image transformation?
Well, the image transformation
is here is from one frame
to the other in the video volume and
we're now interested in finding out
what those degrees of freedom are.
Let's start off with of course,
the simplest one, translation.
So here, of course, we basically
are looking for a translation where
the frame is just moving from one
print to the other in x and y.
If we just did this,
this is a two degree of freedom.
And here, you basically see the example
that I've just modeled the two degree
of freedom.
And if I was to show you the result of
how the stabilized crop window would
look like,
that would be on the top here.
And you see it,
it has a little bit of wobble still.
Which suggests that just by doing
a two degree of freedom transformation
between frames here is not going to
result in a very stable video.
You can see the jerkiness in
the middle of the video here, right?
Of course, we have learned that when
we can't actually model it with just
the translation x and y, we can also
start thinking of adding rotation and
perhaps scale into the equation.
So let's do that.
Of course,
we can look at translation in x and y.
But also let's add uniform scale,
scale in both x and y and rotation.
Of course, we know very well that, that
is basically a four degree of freedom,
where now we have a theta x and
y and the scale.
It's a uniform scale, so
it's the same in both.
That basically suggest that now my crop
window can rotate a little bit, but
also can get bigger and
smaller a little bit too.
And that actually results
in this solution here.
Good.
It's not very shaky, but
still has a lot of little, you know,
wobble in the middle of the image.
You can see this part shaking around.
Of course, let's move to homography.
We did all of this kind of stuff
when we talked about image
transformations again.
In this case, we want to be able
to translate the image from one
frame to the other in an x and
y rotating scale, but
let's now add perspective and
skew to the whole thing.
That basically now means is now we
have an eight degree of freedom model.
We remember that from
our early lectures.
And now, I basically have a crop
window that can also have a shear and
perspective whole thing going on,
in addition to the translation and
rotation and this is the output.
So, if you notice this
looks much stable.
In essence, we're basically what we
have done is now gone through the steps
of identifying the camera path by
looking at these degrees of freedom for
this rectangular region,
the crop window.
And if I can figure out those,
those degrees of freedom are,
I can actually start
generating a new video.
Just showing you the small region here,
which is basically moving around
in the larger viewpoint here.
And remember, we are cropping the image,
but of course, in this case,
we're getting something
nice in the output there.