Wow, this page looks oddly similar
to a certain website's catalog.
I wonder, anyway, here's what I picked.
For the top most element,
you could have chose header,
but I think the most
appropriate answer is nav.
If this entire area was selected
with the navigation links and
the company name,
then header might have made more sense.
Headers have navigation elements and
heading elements, but
because Company Name wasn't
part of the selected area and
these elements are navigation links,
the is the best answer.
For the next one, I chose artical.
Now you could have used section here,
but section seems a little too generic
when you consider MDN's definition for
an article.
An article is self-contained and
intended to be independently
distributable.
It also says that an article
should be identified, typically,
by including a heading,
which leads me to my third answer.
I chose an h3 tag, but really,
you could have used any heading here.
One thing to keep in mind is that your
headings should go from biggest to
smallest.
So, your h1 is the biggest,
then h2, and so on.
For me, I would have used an h1 on
the text logo and maybe an h2 for
the profile name in the sidebar,
so h3 sseemed like a good option.
Next, at the bottom of the page,
I chose a footer.
Again, you could have used section here,
but would be more appropriate
because this area signifies
the end of the page and
contains copyright information.
So, footer it is.
To the left of the page, the aside
element makes the most sense, and
is often represented
by sidebar or insert.
This side bar, which looks to
contain a profile picture and
some additional information,
definitely fits the bill.
Last, I used the img tag for
the lessons image.
This one was sort of given
away by the thumbnail icon,
but you could of inserted another type
of multimedia like video or picture.
We haven't really touched
much on these yet, but
as you start looking at more advanced
topics, they will pop up more.