But before we get stuck into the code,
we're going to be in pixels
across the Atlantic to Mike.
Mike, I hear you've got a bit of
an interactive task up your sleeve.
>> Hey, yeah, I do.
We want to make sure the project
is working correctly.
And you're able to
alter the connectivity.
We've already seen both servers running,
one is the app itself and
one has these configuration options
including this little test form.
When one of these challenges
requires you to change the project,
either by changing settings or
writing code, you get it all working.
Then, type the test name into this box,
and press Enter.
The system will run a little test,
and decide if everything's
working as it should.
If you want to stop the animations for
some reason, although I don't know
why you would, who doesn't like cats?
Just clear the text field.
So on to the first challenge.
Use the connection controls to get
the app server into offline mode.
Once you've done that,
refresh the app to see what happens.
Type offline into the test field and
press Enter.