Now, our Cat function isn't very smart.
It makes the same cat every single time.
I'm going to refactor it a bit so
we can make all kinds of cats.
Now, right now, when you call to make a
new cat, it just runs this function and
does all of this stuff.
But we're not passing anything into it.
Let's pass an object literal into
our Cat constructor function.
I'm going to call it data.
Now, if someone gave us, say, an array
of cat data, we could easily make
those different cats by saying new
Cat and passing an object literal.
See?
Thinking ahead is good.
Now let's go through
the steps to make this work.
Now, before we tackle this part here,
let's tackle what gets passed in.
Down here when I say new Cat, I'm
going to pass in that object literal.
Later on, we'll actually have multiple
cats, so we'll be doing this again and
again and again for each Cat object.
Now here are the various properties for
the same cat that our Cat function up
above was making over and over again.
Now we're passing them into
the Cat constructor function.
Now up at the top, instead of actually
setting these values like this,
we're going to actually set them based
on the data that gets passed in.
So, this.clickCount will actually
be equal to data.clickCount.
From the object literal that we
passed down below into here,
we'll set the clickCount of
that to the cat we're creating.
We'll do the same thing for
all the rest of them.
Now, this.title stays exactly the same
because for every cat, if the clicks
are less than ten, the title will be
Newborn, less than 50 is Infant, etc.
That's hard coded into the cat.
And now, rather than having our
data actually explicitly set here,
we're setting the data down here
where we create these cats.
Now we're ready for more cats.
Let's add them in the next video.