Welcome to the fourth Office Hours.
We are doing this episode a little different
than we have done them in the past
because a lot of people hang out with a bunch of
students and Peter is doing too.
Alright. I hope the technology is going to work and
it’s good to see you all there.
I see a bunch of smiling faces. Let’s get started.
So I think the first question, who is it from?
Let’s let Amy asked the first question.
Okay.
I am just curious if you are going to have a
programming contest or final project like
you did in CS 101?
Yeah, I think that’s a great idea.
So we will do something and I think it will be
open ended like in 101so the contest will be
impress us with something cool.
So we will go ahead and get that going for you.
Next, Deep, why don’t you ask your question?
So in what instances are – is functional programming
a better solution than imperative programming?
That’s a great question.
If you want to start some long battles,
you can bring that up,
and people will take their sides.
I see – I am not dogmatic about any one approach.
I think there is – you could use all the tools
you have.. So why would you want to use
functional programming?
I think one of the best arguments for it is that
it’s easier to test in that functional programming is a
it inputs to the program, test if I’ve got the
right outputs, that’s all I need to know.
The imperative programming is not just one
of the inputs and outputs but is
what happened to me recently.
I need a whole history of statements and
what the current state is and then I can tell you
the stuff that I need to do but that's a little bit
harder to come and set up the test.
Then – so then the question is why would somebody
want to do imperative programming and
I think the answer is – there is two,
one is an efficiency issue that sometimes
it’s easier to modify an existing structure than
create a new one. So for example in functional
programming, if you have a database
especially the million elements amongst you want to add
one but use it in the functional way you have to create
a new database that has a million and one elements.
Sometimes it’s a little hard to do that.
And other, besides efficiency, there’s also sort of a
naturalness idea; that some problems are easily
expressed as a mathematical function
and other problems are expressed as a
set of actions, a recipe,
first you do this, then you do this,
then you do the next thing.
And you want it to be as natural and you want to
have a close as a match as you can
between problem and solution
so that’s I think the main way to fix them.
I guess another issue that’s starting to come up more
and more is how to deal with parallel program.
And that’s one reason why I think you see functional
programming making a come back that had been
mostly kind of an academic thing throughout
like the ‘70s and ‘80s, now it’s seen as more practical
because people have access to parallel machines
and it’s harder to deal with states in imperative
programming when you have to say, well,
now one processor is operating on my data to
make sure it doesn’t step on the other processor.
But functional is easier to deal with in that way
because you just compute one function on one
machine, another function on another machine and
if you are passing in the right data, then there is
no way that they can interfere with them.
So those are some of the issues involved and then
I think beyond those issues, a lot of it is
just experience, whether you are used it.
Alright, great, thanks. Neal, what about you?
You had some questions that you sent me.
I think I might have accidentally muted you.
This isn’t what I wanted.
Well, I turn myself on, can you hear me now?
Okay.
Yeah.
Alright, here it is. I will see if the Internet connection
holds up. In the answer to Unit 4.8, Peter, says
everything is in flux.
The solution that he was going through,
it was a little messy by his standards. I guess it
wasn’t on one line and it has more than seven
characters. So he – the implication was that as
you code, you find out whether your representation
is any good. And then if you don’t like how the code
is working out, you go back and change the
representation. And the overwhelming thing for me
experienced the program is to solving a problem is
the feeling that everything is in flux.
You don’t know where to start, you don’t know
what to decide you are going to sit,
while you vary other things around it.
So it’s a general question. But is there
any guidelines for you, how you get started
on a workable representation if that’s the first
thing that you are going to pin down?
Yeah.
And you talked about listing concepts, but that’s
hard to decide what a concept is?
That’s right. And I think –
so this is another question of style, which is maybe
even more important than the imperative versus
functional and this is kind of the exploratory versus
the waterfall model. Obviously the waterfall model
is you finish one stage and then water starts
flowing over the dam on to the next stage.
So the first stage would be you specify the problem
and you do that completely and then when it
specifies, then you start to design your classes
and functions and then when you have the design,
then you start to do the coding, then when you have
the coding, then you start to do the testing and so on.
One step at a time. And in the past
that was a recommended approach.
These days I think it’s more common to use
an exploratory approach where you say, well,
if I do that, I may spend a lot of time at one level
and then three levels later find out that
everything is wrong and I have to go back.
And so the more exploratory approach says let’s use
all our tools at once. Why spend all this time
writing a paper document that describes what I am
going to do when I have a computer at my fingertips.
We are fine with it. And try something out,
see if it was like it’s working, computer will help tell me
if it’s a good design or not.
And yes, I can do some of that design in my head
and try to imagine it sort of good but sometimes
doing it with a computer really helps because
you start out and you find out that it’s too efficient
or the code – the detail code you have to write is
messier than you thought and if you thought the
overall high level design was good, but then the
details of how you manipulate it not so good.
And then – so it’s look like it’s not going in a
good direction, why not back up now.
Don’t live with your bad mistake.
Go back and fix your mistake.
Alright, Next Jeff, looks like you have a question.
I think I have him muted again, I am sorry about that.
I am trying, yeah.
No, I think you muted him.
My question for Andy is, are we going to
have any new glossary sections or
Andy’s corner videos coming up soon?
Yes, I have one in the mix on scoping and specifically
there was a lot of questions in the forms about
decorate or decorator. And I think it’s a
- a part of it - it’s actually not that complex,
it’s going on there but it’s in dealing with all the code
that I think it’s worth explaining.
Yeah, it looks really cool,
and I am looking forward to seeing that video.
Next Alan had a question and Alan I am not sure if
your audio is working right now, so maybe I will
raise it for you but…
Go ahead and try.
You are not coming through for some reason.
So Andy why don’t you read it for him?
Yeah, sure. Okay Alan’s question is – no, actually
Jeff’s lowest cost search function, and he eliminated
the add frontier function by adding next day one as
an explorer continue. And so for certain methods,
Peter you mentioned in the forum I think that this
method may not be ideal and so can you explain why?
I guess, I remember that something was in the forum
but without the code in front of me right now
I am in a little trouble figuring it if –
Jeff maybe you could explain it a little bit more, I don’t have
Yeah, what we did is we took out the
sorting function and use the heap instead.
Oh yeah.
And I didn’t do any filtering before
I approve things on the heap,
I just threw items on the heap one after another
and then relied on the order in the heap to ensure
that I got the lowest item first.
Okay.
And I put a little filter on, yeah,
but it’s not great for all cases is what you got at.
Right. So, a couple of points there.
The one point is the heap absolutely is a right data
script. I wanted to keep the thing simple, you
already knew about sort, so I said that was just
sorted and then we will sort it as often as possible
just to make sure it doesn’t get messed up.
In fact we are sorting it more often than necessary.
But you are right instead of – in a
real implementation a heap or sort of a more abstract
form as we call it a priority queue and then a heap is
a way of implementing a priority queue.
The priority queue is something that –
where you can pull off the best element and
add elements in and you can pull off the best one,
one at a time. But, you don’t have to keep it completely
sorted. So, it’s a little bit more efficient.
So that was a great choice on your part.
So that was one thing.
That was one clear improvement.
Now, the other part is not a clear
improvement but it really depends on the particular
problem where you were saying, if you had two paths
through the same location,
should we do the work of trying to see if there’s
duplicates and if there is, patching it up to make sure
we get the best one through that path or could we
just throw them all on there and say, yeah,
there’s going to be some duplicates but let’s not
worry about it because the sorting function or the
heap will make sure that we get the best one first.
And, the choice between those two really depends on
the problem that if there are lots and lots of
duplicates then probably you want to eliminate.
If there’s only a few duplicates,
then why bother complicating the code.
So, it’s – we like to have one solution
that’s perfectly general and solves every problem.
But, really, different problems have different trade-offs
in terms of the topology of the search space and you want to
choose the implementation that’s right for that
topology, at least when you have a big problem.
If you have a small problem, then it doesn’t matter.
Any algorithm will solve it fast and get it done.
– Alright, looks like Neil has another question. Neil, go ahead.
Yeah, I was going to raise the specter of grading
because people are asking about it and it is,
obviously, one of those things that’s in flux.
But, the overhaul to grading I thought was great.
I thought it was a big improvement to,
you know, to show people that they are right
when they are right and to give them a chance to try again.
But, people like to compare themselves to other people
and when you let everybody get everything 100% right,
then there’s no way that they can
line themselves up against other people.
So, they go to the forums and they wave
their algorithms at each other.
But, how are they – can people find some way of
comparing themselves to each other using the
grading system that’s not being used?
And, has the grading settled down enough so
you can make some definitive ruling about what’s
going on and let everybody know?
And, finally, with the official certification,
is there any progress since -
just anything to be said about whether
there will be at some stage official certification?
– Andy, maybe you know more about this stuff than I do.
– I’ve been and actually programmed the case, so…
Okay. So, there are a lot of questions in there.
So, about the – I’ll go backwards.
I remember that I did expect that, okay.
So, certifications, I think the certifications –
right now if you took 2 – 101 or a 273,
you complete the class you have of PDF I think
it is that says you completed the class with ecstas.
We’re going to do the same thing for this class and
probably go to the next one but don’t hold me to that.
And, eventually we’re going to move to a
testing center sort of module where, if you want,
you can go and get an official certification there and
then we’ll have a little more weight to it –
I know people are worried about the credibility of
these certificates but there’s nothing you can achieve in
at least that would give a little more weight to those certificates.
For now, though, we’re going to do the same thing we did in
101 and 373 and I think at these levels of distinctions and
we haven’t set those specials yet.
We’ll do that and message it to you as soon as we
figure out what we want to do but it will be
based basically on the final because, like you said,
there is no reason someone who wants to get 100
on their homework to not get 100.
Remind me what your question two and
one were or one of them at least.
Now, you’re making me go backwards.
– Yeah.
Now you’re making me go backwards. What did I say?
The – has the grading – the model settled down now
so people will know what it is?
People were saying do I get graded on the homework,
do I get graded on the exam at the end,
how do I tell what my grade is, how do I
tell how I’m doing.
– Right, yeah. The short answer is no.
We’re grading using the re-sit exam.
– We’re still working on it.
– Yes. As people have noticed, coding is a hard thing to
do algorithmically and so what we want is –
I think for this round of classes you can count on the final exam….
Alright.
– …which I think is a great exam.
– And, I think as we get experience we’ll get better at the exams.
I also think that you should think of what you come
away with these classes, not just a grade,
but also portfolio of things; here are some things
I’ve done and when it comes to showing off to
somebody else, yes, it’s nice to say I’ve got a
certificate that says high distinction on it.
But, ultimately, the point where you’ve got this
portfolio – or notebook,
here’s all the stuff I’ve done and you can
show that to somebody else and
that may be more convincing than just having a grade.
Right. Thank you.
– Next one, we’ll take – Prajit,
looks like you have another question.
Hi. So, I was thinking – so, obviously,
you can’t look through your whole code just to find one bug.
So, how would you narrow down your search space to
look for a bug?
Is there some sort of, like, process?
Or, is it just, like, intuition?
– The first place to start is to write lots of tests.
I’ve been trying to emphasize that.
I’ve been going a little bit quick in class so I haven’t
done as many as I probably should.
But, as you write each function, an important part is
writing tests for that function.
And, then if the tests are all passing, then you know
that you have at least some constraints on where
the bug could be and then you’ve asked, well,
does some function have a bug.
Yes, let’s concentrate there.
No functions have a bug but I’m still not getting the
right answer, then either one of my functions
I haven’t tested well enough or it could be something
wrong or an input that I haven’t looked at.
One of my tests is just wrong; I tested does
two plus two equal five and my program said yes,
so I’m happy; then yes, fix the test.
Or, maybe it’s some interaction between something
that you didn’t quite understand and then you –
I think the first place to look is start having other
tests that say go about the individual functions,
how they work together.
So that’s one way of looking forward in
terms of debugging.
But, also backwards that you run something and
either you get an error message and then you can
look and say where am I,
what was the error message, usually it’s
something like some function or some line of code
where it’s passed a value that I didn’t expect, and
then you can start saying where did that come from
and you can either add more tests and break it down
and test each part of the program to see if it’s
generating the right thing.
You can put in some print statements into your functions that’s
saying okay, I have an error here.
What was happening there?
And, you have a choice of either –
there are debuggers that you can run that
can calculate loss in an app and show where you are
right now or you can rerun the program after putting
in print statements and examine the output.
So, I think those are the main strategies.
– Alright. Amy, you have a question. You can go ahead.
I was confessing earlier that on the bridge problem
my test was completely wrong and so I
came up with the wrong answer for the best solution.
How do you go about validating your tests if you
don’t have a domain expert available or if you
don’t really know it well enough yourself?
Yeah, That’s a great question because I did the same thing.
I cheated too, right?
I didn’t know what the right test was – or
I had – I put in a couple of little tests, right?
I know what the right answer is when it’s one
step away but, when it’s eight steps away,
I didn’t know what the right answer was.
So, I just ran my function and said, okay, that’s my test.
And, this is a good way to indicate that
there are two types of tests, right?
thing and then there are regression tests that ask
has something changed.
And, the regression tests, you are trying to prove
that I got the right answer but you’re just saying,
anytime I make a change to my program,
run these things over again and see if the results
I get are different than they were before
so there’s an indication that you broke something.
– Does that make sense?
– If you don’t know what the right answer is,
you can at least have this regression path.
But, you really want to know what the right answer is.
And, you can break – you can search
and break it down into pieces.
So, one thing that I probably should have showed but I didn’t
is I should have had a function that says is this a
valid solution to say given a problem and a solution,
does this path that is the solution,
is that valid and are all the actions legal and
does it reach the goal at stake.
And if you have that, then you can say –
the first assertion you can make is valid solution
of search from start-to-go is true.
And, if that’s true, then at least you know that the
thing that you’re returning didn’t make any mistakes.
Now, you don’t know that the thing you’re returning is
the shortest test or the best test but at least you’ve
gotten partway there by saying at least it’s not wrong.
And I think that’s another way to kind of approach it.
Then I guess another approach would be exhaustive of –
you can take a small problem and say, now,
I got to write another function which generates all
possible paths between A and B and checks to see if
they are valid and reduce the cost and figure out
which is the best one and then you can say
okay, that should be my answer when I applied a search.
So you can write a separate program that’s going to
compute the answer for you that’s solely for the
purpose of testing and I think this is like building scaffolding.
When you’re constructing a multistory building with a lot
of scaffolding that gets built on the outside just so
that the construction workers can step around
and not falloff,
but then when you done you take all the scaffolding down.
So testing is a lot like that, you may end up
writing functions that are only good for testing,
they don’t end up as part of your final program,
but of course you don’t have to take them down,
you can still leave them in your program,
because you may want to test again later.
Cool. Thank you.
Jeff, you had another question?
A lot of questions, I have to go back and
try to remember which one it is.
I think this one is, after this class is over,
there is a lot of different things we could do on,
so follow up on it, we could learn a new language,
we could learn more data structures, more algorithms and
I was wondering what you would recommend that
we do and also what is you’d ask they going to offer
on ERM versus the tape. Thanks.
I can talk about what you’d ask he’s going to offer?
Yeah, go ahead.
So, as far as computer science is concerned,
we have algorithms and data structure class,
software design and the
software testing class coming up.
We’re also doing a little bit of branching:
we’re going to go into stats and because, of course,
which actually I will be teaching and discrete
math course, so once we actually get
some more interns and stuff.
Yeah, I think you should be driven by your own
interest and I guess from my point of view,
if you want to learn programming,
the best thing to do is program and so find a project
that you are interesting in that you want to do
and start doing it and then figure out what if
it is that we don’t know and find a class or
book or a website or a friend that
together you can learn what’s missing.
Alright. So next, it looks like Neil you have another question?
My microphone is on now. Okay. Can you hear me?
Yeah.
Yeah, this was in unit 4,
just about brute-force versus analysis because we
had these two problems, there was the glass pouring
and there was the bridge, but the bridge there is a
simple insight you can have as a –
you can realize the slowest people have to go across
together and that’s something that a brute-force
simple search doesn’t realize,
it just tries everything and finds us the best result.
But a little bit more analysis might have given you a
clue to go somewhere else with the solution
you looked for.
And the same with the glass pouring because you
can think about it and ST Powchar found simple
mathematical solution to it and I looked at it and
found a loop in – a loop of states that lets you cut
by half the number of places you have to explore and
really you only go in one or two directions, so.
Right.
So the question is, how do you figure out whether –
you can throw these general tools at something,
like a brute-force search or you can analyze further,
think more about the individual problem,
so what do you do?
I guess in the sense of what
we’re trying to do to some extent,
and it depends on the problem.
So for all the things we did,
you can apply brute-force search and you get an answer
within a second, so if you get an answer in a second
why bother spending hours working on it.
Now, that’s not completely clear cut because yes we
can get an answer quickly, go ahead and do it,
but if you spend time thinking about it,
then you’d be more prepared to solve bigger problems,
bigger problems with the same kind,
or problems of the different kind,
if you have that kind of analysis for you.
So I think you need to decide where do you –
when you’re stuck,
when the tools you have aren’t working,
aren’t scaling up the larger problems
then you have to think harder.
Now, there are ways of having a combination of
sort of this novel mathematical analysis and the fully
automated analysis that I showed where you can give
your algorithms hints rather than give them complete
solutions and we didn’t show any of that. Right?
So we showed sort of – we’re about halfway there
and we said we have an algorithm
that’s smart enough to
only consider the shortest task first.
But if you think about it,
you want to get from start state to a goal and
where’s shortest path first, so we’re starting at
the start and we’re like going out in concentric circles
and that’s good so we aren’t going a really long
ways and not getting anywhere but we’re going in concentric
circles in all directions,
so we’re really like to go in
concentric circles more in this direction,
towards the goal and not in
concentric goals in the other directions.
And there are algorithms that do that,
that allow you to specify a function which is an
estimate of how far away the goal is,
if you knew exactly how far away the goal is,
the problem would be easy because you just follow
that path, but if you have an estimate then
you can make the search be more of it.
And so there is all sorts of techniques that saying,
well, what types of estimates do I have and
if I have that, what types of search
algorithms can I apply given that?
Now – but all these sort of techniques apply given a
representation of the state space and
I think part of what you are talking about is
you come up with a novel understanding of the problem
of the state space then you can bypass
a lot of these searches and maybe come up with
a state space in which there is far less branching:
it’s only one or two branches big point.
So I think it’s a mix of intuition and
brute-force and kind of guidance
that makes the brute-force more intelligent.
Thanks.
And if you’re interested in learning
a little bit more about sir,
CS 373 I think it’s unit 4 is all about search so A*
and programming that first.
Alright, so maybe we should do one more question.
looks like you have one?
So you always talk about how we had to tackle on
projects to like expand your skill.
So how do you find such open source projects,
would you go to like GitHub or something like that
and just look around or what we’re going to do?
Well, I think GitHub is a good place to look.
You can also start a project on your own if
there is something you want to do,
join somebody else because you learn from other
programmers if you work with somebody to see what
they are doing and get new ideas and just nice to be social
and have somebody else to get partner with.
I know Google does this Summer of Code thing where
we actually pay interns to work on open source projects.
And so that’s a good place to look at it if
you are looking for an internship job, but it is also
a good place to work just because it’s a collection of
open source projects that had been deemed worthy of some funds.
So you can search through there and find a big lesson.
Alright. Seems like Jamie has a question? Jamie?
Hi. I wanted to know if there are thoughts of offering
again the introduction to artificial intelligence schools.
Yeah. So that’s definitely I’d like to do it.
We’re all learning a lot here.
I am learning a lot from doing these classes and
one of the things I’d like to learn is,
is it actually easier the second time around? It’s not.
Boy, it’s going to be bad.
So we want to find out how much and so
I do want to do it at some point.
Sebastian also wants to do it.
It’s just a question of when.
We both have day jobs.
When we did in it in the past,
we did it in conjunction with Stanford,
we don’t know yet Stanford’s schedule,
whether they are going to invite us to teach again or
whether it’s some other professors turn to teach that class.
So we will wait and see what happens there.
And then whether or not we teach at Stanford,
we will at some point definitely do it through udacity
but our schedules aren’t set yet.
Yeah, understood.
So…
Thanks. I am waiting for it.
You could go and you know the material is archived
there so you could look through it, but…
No, I did it the first time.
So you won’t do it again, okay.
We’ll have to make it better than second time then
to make it work really well.
Okay.
Well, thank you.
Will be nice to see it.
Thanks to all of you for joining us and to everyone.
We current have 10 viewers but I suspect
that will go up once this gets posted.
Thanks for watching.
Okay, great. And I also wanted to say, thank you to everybody
here for your participation in the forum.
The forum is really an important part of the class.
In any class you want to have that interaction,
you can come up to me at the end of the lecture
and talk so the forums are the next best thing and
all of have made great contributions,
both in terms of the technical content,
you’re jumping in there and you’re answering questions
and you’re helping people out and also all of you
and the others have really set the tone to
have a very welcoming and supportive forum.
There is nobody complaining or jumping
on other people or being mean and abusive,
I am really impressed with how helpful
and supportive you all have been. So thank you all for that.
Alright, see you in class. Thanks and good luck.
Great. See you. Bye.