In designing your code,
it's important to understand
the problem that you're solving.
So, let's think a bit about
the math of tournaments.
If you'd like to skip straight
ahead to the code, feel free, but
working through this may be helpful.
In an elimination style tournament,
each round eliminates half of
the players from contention.
That means if you start
out with n players,
it takes log to the base 2 n
rounds to find a champion.
And the total number of
matches played is n minus 1.
Like in this tournament here, there are
eight entrants, A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H.
And finding a champion
takes three rounds.
And sure enough,
the binary log of 8 is 3.
There are four matches in the first
round, two in the second, and
only one match in the third for
a total of seven matches.
But how about in
the non-elimination Swiss system?
For a given number of entrants,
how many rounds does it
take to find a champion and
how many total matches are played?
Let's take a specific example for
a quiz.
Suppose there are 16 players.
How many rounds and
how many matches will have to be played?