Jake did you get this working?
>> Yeah.
It's one of the ones that takes a little
bit more thinking than actual typing.
First I'm going to bring the server
online, then refresh the page.
This is our current 404 page that
we want to display a gif instead.
Over in the code, now if you
return a promise within a promise,
it passes the eventual
value to the outer promise.
Now I know that sounds kind of like
a proverb Mr Miyagi would say but
here's what I mean.
Rather than return a response
I'm going to return a fetch for
the gif''s URL and that's it.
Over in the browser if I refresh
the 404 page I get the gif.
But if I load a non-404 page,
everything works fine.
Okay, it's been fun
playing with the stuff.
But it's time to start putting it into
practice and do something useful.
In the next chapter,
we'll start doing the real work
to make Wittr offline first.