So fundamental to our notion of imaging is our projection operation.
And today we're going to talk about modelling projection.
So first we're going to talk a little bit about the coordinate system.
What we'll see here is the coordinate system we're using for
our pinhole a, approximation.
The first thing is that we're going to put the optical center of projection at
the origin.
So here's our little COP, center of projection.
And that's also going to be the origin of our camera coordinate system.
Also with our center of projection at the origin, we're going to
use a standard x y coordinate system for the stuff we're going to show here.
So now we're back in the land of mathematics.
So x and y are like regular xyz, so x will go to the right and
y is going to go up.
Later when you convert this to images you're going to have to
worry about making that flip.
Now, here's something a little strange.
We're going to, as we were talking about before in cameras,
normally a light comes in,
goes through the focal point of the lens and then hits the image plane.
But in our mathematics here, what we're going to do is we're going to put
the image plane here, in front of the coordinate system.
As if the light sort of magically knows how to pass through the image and
hit the coordinate system in just the right place.
So why do we do this?
Well, because it's mathematically convenient,
because this way our images don't get inverted, y stays up, all right?
Before we had to worry about things being switched left and right and
up and down.
Well now, x stays to the right, y stays up.
And we don't really build a camera with the image plane in the front.
We put the cam, the image plane behind, and
then we have to rotate things back to get y up and x to the right.
So for the math here, we're going to put the image plane on the right.
Now, one of the implications of this x y coordinate system, in order for
this to remain a right-handed coordinate system, so
you remember x, y, that this way is z.
What it means is that z is now pointing in from the camera,
not out to the world.
So, here, here's z pointing this way, all right?
Sometimes this matters, sometimes this doesn't.
You see here we wrote down that the world's position of some point was x,
y, and z.
And we didn't say negative z.
Well that's because it's a z value, which could be negative 20.
And we can go back and forth on this.
But basically, in order to keep a right-handed coordinate system and everything
sort of not have to worry too much about how we do the matrix multiplication and
stuff like that.
We have that z goes negative the further away that you get.
So what's going on here?
So what we have here, we have our world point here.
All right, so here's our point in the world, and
the ray projects down, to the center of projection.
Normally our image plane would be back here, but we're going to say.
So, the idea is that, that ray intersects the image plane at this point,
which we're going to call x prime, y prime.
And it's written as minus d because the idea is that the distance,
like the focal length distance,
the distance d from the origin to the image plane, that's a positive distance.
So what that means is that the location of this point is going to be x prime,
y prime, minus d.