The world around us is complex.
We're constantly being bombarded with
visual information, pictures, words,
symbols, and more.
When it comes to quickly
processing that information,
we make sense of the chaos
around us by using a few tricks.
We recognize patterns,
compare and contrast things, and
refer to our past experiences all in
an instant without even realizing it.
We can make sense of
how our brains do this
by looking in the field
of cognitive psychology.
More specifically, a set of principles
called the Gestalt Laws of Grouping.
Let's take a quiz to get started.
Here's a UI from which we
removed all the images and text.
What do you think this app does?
There may be more than
one correct answers,
so don't think about it too hard.