Now, we obviously don't want to play
the fluty sound for all our list items.
So it's time to update our onClick
listener code to play the correct files.
As a heads up, there's going to be some
pretty big code changes coming up.
So I'm going to ask you a multiple
choice question to guide you along.
So in the first quiz of lesson four,
we decided that we needed to
modify the Word class to store
the corresponding audio resource ID.
So for example, R.rawnumber_one,
and remember this is similar
to how we modify the word class to hold
an image resource ID in the last lesson.
So assuming that we make
this battle model change.
I like you to think about which one of
these four inputs to the on click method
would be useful to determine
which audio file to play.
So in the documentation
provided below the quiz,
we will point you to this
interface the adapter of you.
And I don't click listener and here you
can learn more about the parameters that
you're responsible for
in the on item click method.
Now make your selection and continue.