So what the union bound gives us,
then, is this idea that if each of
the arms individually has a certainty
of one minus delta over k,
then all k of them together have
a certainty of at least one minus delta.
So that was what we wanted.
And now the last thing that we want
is to know that the arm that we pick
is within epsilon of optimal.
So what gives us that?
Well, I mean, the idea is that whatever
true the optimal is in this case,
it might be at the bottom of
a bar's range, for example.
>> Whatever's optimal cannot be
at the bottom of a bar's range.
>> Yes good point.
But it could be at
the top of the wrong bar.
>> Right.
>> Not the bar
that we think is the highest.
So here we think that this bar here,
this third bar, is the highest, but
its true value might actually be
all the way down at its bottom.
Whereas, some other bar that looks lower
than it's true value might be, actually,
much closer to the top.
So the worst case is what happens is
we have one bar that is infinitesimally
above another bar, we just pick it.
Because it's slightly better.
But in fact,
its actual value is down at the bottom.
Whereas we failed to pick this other
arm that has the optimal in it, and
that optimal's at the top of its range.
So the most we can be off,
you know we picked this arm,
the most that that arm can be off is the
height of the bar, which is is epsilon.
>> Right.
So that makes sense,
although I don't think it has
to be infinitesimally lower.
>> You're saying if it's just a dead
tie and we picked arbitrarily.
>> because you gotta pick one of them.
>> That's true, and
we could pick the wrong one.
>> Right, and the wrong one could have
been as far off as possible, and the one
that we didn't pick could've been as far
off as possible in the right direction.
>> Cool. Okay. >> And then still,
you'd be epsilon away,
as opposed to epsilon minus epsilon.
>> Epsilon minus epsilon,
which I feel like is small.
Okay.
All right, excellent.
So that gives us both pieces here.
That means that if we can just figure
out how many times to sample an arm, so
that the guarantee that we
have is that the value that we
predict is within epsilon over two,
with confidence one minus delta over k.
Then putting all those estimates
together is going to get
us an arm that is epsilon optimal,
with probability one minus delta.
>> That's perfect.
And we know how many to sample.
>> We do.
We're just going to do
a little bit of algebra and we're there.
>> Okay, cool.