If any user can decide
what files to be accessed,
then of course,
there's no mandatory aspect to it.
They should be able to decide
about their files, not any file,
but that doesn't make
it mandatory access.
The fact that only the company can
dictate, somebody on behalf of
the company, for example, sysadmin,
what programs can access what files.
That's what makes it mandatory, okay.
So somebody, other than the user
who creates a resource,
is required to specify
how it can be used.
That's what makes it mandatory.
And here, the company or
company's representative,
someone in the security organization,
is deciding it which makes it mandatory.