If you take a class in probability theory you will likely hear the story of the
Chevalier de Mere. He played two dice games. In game one, he would throw a die
four time and bet on at least one six. In game two, he would throw two dice, 24
times and bet on at least one pair of sixes. He thought that the odds of
winning both games were 2 3rds. But from experience, he knew or at least his
wallet knew that he was wrong. Pascal would later come along to figure out the
actual odds and invent probability theory. But we don't care about that right
now. We just want to help the poor Chevalier with the drudgery of throwing two
dice 24 times. Let's complete this program that simulates game one and game
two. These methods should return true if the Chevalier would win. Now there's
one subtlety to this problem. In this case, the moment you see a six, you
already know that he's won, but our generator is hooked up and doing a
particular sequence. So that we can help you check your answer. Make sure to
simulate rolling the die four times, even if you already know that he won.