So tell me about what got you
interested in web development.
What got you sitting here
interviewing for this position?
>> Ever since I've grown up, I've
always grown up with the Internet and
one of my first experiences with
the Internet was log onto AOL.
And it was something magical about just
seeing all these moving pictures and
parts about the browser in a while.
It just made me realize
wow this is the future.
>> Okay.
>> This is the internet and
like this is a really cool or
this is a really great way for me to
I think made an impact on the world,
it's just the will to build cool stuff.
And i figure out like you know,
ever since i was a child, yeah.
Ever since I was like
working on like my Angelfire.
[LAUGH] And all those sites,
were like yeah like here's a little
walk-through through, you know.
This awesome game that I've made of and
I just made my little website.
And it was just fun.
And figure out you know it's a great
way for me to build something.
And you know make
the impact on the world and
future of for future kids.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.