This conversation reminds me of a game
show that has a very interesting and
non intuitive problem
associated with it.
>> Are you thinking
the Monty Hall problem?
>> Yes, I am.
You're shown three doors,
behind one of them is a shiny new car,
while the other two have a goat.
These are randomly assigned so
you don't know which is which.
You're asked to pick one door,
then the host, Monty Hall,
opens one of the other two
doors to reveal a goat.
Note that Monty never opens
the door with the car behind it.
Now, you can choose to either stay or
switch to the other closed door.
Monty then reveals what is behind
the door you decided to go with.
If you stayed with your original door
and the car is behind it, then you win.
Similarly, if you switch
to the other door and
the car is behind that one, you win.
Ending up with a goat
is considered a loss.
>> Now the question is, which is better
overall strategy, stay or switch?
Or is it the case that
neither is clearly better?