So, for this code checkpoint,
since we allowed all the pet values in
the database, we're going to be using
the CONTENT_URI in the PetEntry class.
And remember, this URI is equivalent to
content://com.example.android.pets/pets/
for the entire pets table.
So, here's what that change
looks like in the code.
Back in the catalog activity in
the display database info method,
I've updated the query method to contact
the content resolver instead, and
here I've added a little
comment to clarify that.
Here's a line that I ask you to
fill in with the CONTENT_URI, so
if you want to double check where
this is set up, let's Right-Click,
head to Go To, and
then go to Declaration.
Here it jumps us into the pet contract
into the pet entry innerclass, and
we see this is the URI
that we're referring to.