In lesson two we talked a bit about
developer and production environments.
But it's more complicated than that.
Between the developer's workstation and
production, there are lots of nooks and
crannies that our application
code has to land.
There are no hard and fast rules on how
many environments you need to maintain,
and will most likely be
driven by use cases.
In most cases you'll have
at least six environments.
The starting place for
all code is the local environment, which
is just the developers work station.
Secondly you'll have
the development environment.
An example of this can be a server where
the developer can deploy their own
branch of the code and play around
without messing up someone else.
It's often referred to as the sandbox.
After the development environment
an integration environment is needed.
It can be a CI build target or for
developers to test side effects.
This is where the app gets built and
tested and
changes are merged back into
the main working branch.
It is possible to have a separate test,
QA environment for
functional, performance testing, quality
assurance and user acceptance testing.
Or, if the team is small,
it can be just one environment that gets
deployed right after the CI process.
Up next is moving your code
into the staging area.
The staging area is a mirror production.
It includes databases that usually have
a fairly recent copy of live data.
By now a lot of problems or
issues should have been caught
before moving code into production.
Production serves the end users and
clients and hence can have scale and
size that you might not be able to
test within your other environments.
It's also possible to have production
canaries, a subset of production servers
where the new version gets deployed,
the ability to test performance with
real workload but limiting the impact of
any negative things that might come up.
As the code gets written on
a local developer work station,
how does it transition into production
and how are the environments different?
Clearly there must be some difference
between a development server and
a production server.
For example, databases may have
old versus current data, and
software patches may be out of sync.