In lesson one, I implemented the entire exclamation topology for you.
In lesson two, we will explore more of the code and
syntax to implement spouts, bolts, and connections in topologies.
Let's walk through the basic Storm components, along with the terminology and
syntax link.
Throughout the course, I'll try to use a red triangle to represent Spouts.
Here in code,
we see the class WordSpout here in our topology as new WordSpout().
We don't give it a name and
pass it as an anonymous instance into our builder.setSpout function.
We see that the component id, word-spout, is the first argument here.
And we also have a parallelism of five.
Our next component is the CountBolt.
We see that the CountBolt is also passed into our builder,
through the setBolt method.
It again is anonymous with a parallelism of 15.
We see the component id, count-bolt is the first argument count-bolt.
And here we come to the connection of the Bolt and the Spout.
We see that the Spout does not know that the Bolt is connecting to it.
The Spout simple emits tuples.
The CountBolt subscribes to the Spout tuple stream by this
method, fieldsGrouping.
We see that the connection is made by identifying the connection
word-spout through the component id.
And again, an anonymous object is instantiated with new fields word.
Word is defined in the declare output field in the definition of
the class WordSpout.
Therefore the connection fieldGrouping connects the WordSpout to
the CountBolt with the fieldsGrouping connection.
Now let's get started with a quiz.
In lesson two, stage one, you'll implement the CountBolt and
connect this in your topology to a ReportBolt.
I've implemented the connection to readus in the visualization for
you in the Report Bolt.
You job now is to decide what connection to use between the ReportBolt and
the CountBolt.
What is the best connection between the CountBolt and the ReportBolt.
Choose the best answer based on our use case to send all CountBolt streams to
one ReportBolt.
Is it the shuffle grouping, a fields grouping or a global grouping?
Please check the answer that you feel is the best in
our use case to send a all CountBolt streams to one ReportBolt.