Let's start with our first equation over here. If log based 10 of 100 all taken
to the third power, equals 3 times log base 10 of 100. So let's see what each
side is equal to. Well first you need to figure out what log base 10 of 100 is.
And it's two, since 100 is 10 squared. That means on the left-hand side, we
have 2 cubed, or 8. And on the right-hand side, we have 3 times 2, or 6. 8 is
definitely not equal to 8, so this equation is not true. Let's move on to our
second equation. Log base 10 of 100 cubed is equal to 3 times log base 10 of
100. On the left hand side we can rewrite 100 as 10 squared and that means we
have log based 10 of 10 squared taken to the 3rd power. We know from our rules
of exponents that this is just log bas 10 of 10 to the 6th. We need to multiply
the 2 and the 3, and that just simplifies to 6. Awesome. What about the
right-hand side? Well once again we make use of the fact that log base 10 of
100 is just 2, 3 times 2 is just 6. So this equation is true. Awesome. And now
for this last one over here. Log base 10 of 100 cubed, equals 3 times log base
10 of 100. The only difference between this equation and this one is the use of
parentheses here around the 100 cubed. However in this case the parentheses
don't actually change the way we're evaluating the expression. The first thing
we did over here was find what 100 cubed was equal to and that was 10 to the
6th. So that means that this is going to be equal to what we got here, just 6.
Once again the right-hand side is the same as it's been the other 2 times and
we know that we got 6 before. So look at that, this time we have 2 true
equations. Wonderful. Both of these show proper uses of the product rule. And
in both cases the exponent is only applying to the input of the log expression.
It doesn't go around the entire log expression, which is why this first one was
not correct.