Firewalls also provide
additional features.
Firewalls can lock all
traffic that passes through.
And the law can be analyzed
later to learn about the traffic
such as the traffic volume to
a specific part of the network.
Firewall can also provide
network address translation.
This is useful when multiple machines in
the internal network has to share an IP
address to the external
networks on the Internet.
The firewall translates the source
IP address of an internal host
through this shared IPv4 address for
outbound traffic.
And for inbound traffic, the firewall
translates the destination IP address
to the IP address of an internal host.
It can also provide encryption services.
For example,
when traffic goes out from one internal
trusted network to another trusted
network across the Internet,
the firewall can automatically encrypt
the traffic so that the untrusted
networks on the Internet cannot
learn the contents of such traffic.