Hey, welcome back, so previously,
I talked to you about the concepts
behind RNNs and LSTMs.
But now I'm actually going to walk
through an implementation of these
things in TensorFlow.
So here I'm building
a character-wise RNN.
So what that means is that it looks
at the characters in text and
it can generate new characters.
So it generates new texts
character by character.
And I'm going to train
this on Anna Karenina,
which is one of my favorite books
of all time, it's super good.
So then the idea is that
train it on Anna Karenina,
and then it can generate
new text from the book.
And it's going to learn names in
the structure and all these cool things.
So this network is based off
a blog post by Andrej Karpathy.
You should check out this link here.
I'll share this notebook with you so
you can work through it and
also check out these links.
So this was a really
good blog post of his,
he has an implementation that
was in Torch and it's on GitHub.
When I was building this,
I also checked out some other code,
which you can find at this link,
r2rt, and this dude's GitHub repo.
He made a character-wise RNN also.
So below here is a diagram that
was made by Andrej Karpathy.
And it basically shows the general
architecture of what I built here.
So the idea is to encode each of your
characters with one-hot encoding.
So this is your input layer, so you just
have your one-hot encoded characters.
This goes to the hidden layer
which is then passed to the next
character in the sequence, right.
The output of this hidden layer also
goes to the output layer where you have
your logits.
And you use these logits with Softmax to
predict what the next character will be.
And then your target characters are just
the next character in the sequence,
right.
So this is the general
architecture of this network,
and you'll see how I implement
this in TensorFlow later.
Great, so
here I'm going to import modules.
This is where I'm loading the text.
So Anna Karenina is in
the public domain, so
you just find the text online.
Here I'm making the vocab, so this is
basically a set of all the characters.
And I take those characters and
make a dictionary where I can
convert the characters to integers.
And I have a dictionary that goes
backwards from integers to characters.
And this is just a giant array of
all the characters that we have.
So here I'm doing vocab_to_int.
So I am making this character array,
so all the characters
are converted to integers.
So this is the first
100 characters you see.
This is the first line of the book.
And this is what it looks like when
it's converted to integers, cool.
So now that we have our
data in a form we can use,
we need to form batches, right, that
we're going to pass into our network.
We also wannna split it
into a training set and
validation set and also into the input
features and the targets that we want.
Basically I wrote this
function to do just that.
So it takes this character vector,
this array that I have here, in
the batch size and the number of steps.
So the number of steps is the sequence
length of characters that we're
going to pass into our network.
And so the longer the sequence is,
then the further
back it can look for
correlations between characters.
So it's just kind of
the more steps you have,
the better performance
your network will have.
But it also makes it longer to train,
of course.
Okay, so the cool thing about
this is that our target's y.
It's exactly the same as the input
characters, just shifted one over,
right.
So like in hello, our first character
is f and the first target is e.
So you can just have your x as
just grab a bunch characters and
y is just everything
just shifted over by 1.
Here what I'm doing is dropping the last
few characters to make sure that
when I'm going through and I'm making my
batches, that all the batches are full.
So I'm just kind of leaving off
the tail of this character array.
Great, so now that I have my x and my y,
I need to split these into batches.
So what I'm going to do is I
take split(x, batch_size).
What this does is it makes a number of
different arrays equal to batch size.
And then when I stack them,
what this does is it makes rows,
it stacks them vertically.
And so
you have rows equal to batch size, and
then columns equal to all
the rest of the data.
So basically what we can do now with
this is that we can put a little window
on top of this.
And the height of this window is
going to be the batch size and
then the width of the window is going to
be the number of steps in the sequence.
So you can just move this window
along this big 2D array and
just kind of slide it over and
get your batches.
So here's just splitting out
the training and validation sets.
So pretty standard, you look at this.
If we do a batch size of 10 and our step
size are 200, then we see the train x,
the shape is 10, so it's 10 rows for
the batches, pretty normal.
And we can look at all the batches for
the first 10 steps,
so this would be
a window into your data.
So if your sequence steps
was doing 10 steps,
right, so this would be the first batch.
And for the second batch,
you would just shift it over 10 and
you get the next batch.
And this is basically
what that get_batch is,
exactly what I just described.
Where you are just sliding this window
along your data that you see here.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So now this is where I
actually build the network.
So this is all done in TensorFlow,
now I'm going to go through it now.
So here just kind of typical,
your placeholders for the inputs and
the targets.
And this keep probability is a
placeholder that I'll use for drop out.
So this is how
many of the different connections I'll
be keeping in the drop out layers.
In this network,
I am passing in characters, so
actually integers, because I converted
them to integers in inputs and targets.
And then here,
I'm encoding them to one_hot vectors.
And this is the RNN layer, it is
actually pretty simple to do this part.
So you just say I'm going to
make a BasicLSTMCell, and
the (lstm_size) is the number
of hidden units in these cells.
And then you just wrap it in Dropout, so
it just does Dropout for you, basically.
And then it's super
easy to stack these up.
You can do MultiRNNCells.
So this automatically
routes the output from
one layer of an LCM to
the next layer of the LCMs.
So you can just stack however many tall,
how many deep LCM cells you want.
So drop is from the DropoutWrapper and
then you just multiply it by the number
of layers, and so you get that.
Then here we are setting the cell state,
so that we're just setting it to zero,
so it's the initial state.
So it just starts all zeros and
this is what we're going to
be training as we go through.
All right, now this part runs
the data through the RNN.
So what we're doing here
is we're splitting.
So first we're splitting tf.split, our
x, our input data into number of steps.
So what this is doing, it's making
just a column of sequences, right?
So it's t = 1, i = 1, so
this is your first time step.
You just get a vector,
just a column vector that is
the length of your batches.
So you're just kind of the stepping
through one time point at a time, and
you're making this list.
And so every element of this list
is one step in your sequence.
And then you're passing each of this
steps in the sequence through your
recurrent neural networks,
which you have defined here.
And all that squeeze does is
it just removes any dimensions
that are only of size 1.
So basically, what we have here
is just a list of column vectors,
and the length of this column
is the size of the batch.
So in this line is actually where
we run through our network.
So we're passing the inputs
into our network,
I'm just taking cell, and
setting the initial state.
And what this does automatically for
us is that it passes the state from
each sequence step to the next one.
So just does all that for
us, it's really convenient.
And at the end, we get out the final
state and we get out the final outputs.
And the outputs are the outputs
of the hidden layer for
each step in the sequence,
and this is just a big list.
So here, we'll keep the final state for
later, okay.
So like I was saying,
the outputs is a big list of the output
of each hidden layer at each step.
So to make this easier,
we're just going to concatenate it into
one big list, just get all these outputs
and mash them together into one array.
Then what I do here is I reshape it so
that each row is one output,
so lstm_size, so this the size of the
number of hidden layers in our cells.
So I can reshape it into
the size of the lstms,
and each row is a different output,
so every step has an output.
And the number of columns,
the width of this
output array is the number of
hidden units in the lstm cells.
So now that I have all that done, I can
send all of the hidden outputs through
some weights and biases and
do softmax, basically.
So here I'm just calculating my logits.
So you just do your matrix
multiplication of the output and
the softmax weights and
add the softmax biases.
And it pass through softmax
to the predictions.
So here I'm calculating the loss now.
So, again,
I look to reshaping my targets so
that they match the same
kind of form as our logits.
because remember logits, each row of
this array is one output for one step.
So we're going to compare each output
of a step to the target at that step.
And that's exactly
what we're doing here.
So we're doing
softmax_cross_entropy_with_logits.
So our logits and
our labels here calculate the cost.
So we just reduce the means,
so just calculate the mean for
the losses for
each of the steps in the sequence.
So here you might remember
me talking about how
gradients can explode in
a recurrent neural network.
The easiest way to fix this is
that you just clip the gradients.
So if the gradient is above 5,
you just set it to 5,
and that's kind of what
this block of code does.
It's a pretty simple thing to do,
that's nice.
And here I'm just exporting the nodes
that I want, because the whole thing is
just a function right, so
I just run the function.
Then I export the nodes that I want, so
that I can use them
later during training.
Right, and here
are the hyperparameters I'm setting.
So batch_size and number of steps in
the sequence that I'm looking at,
the lstm_size.
So this is the number of hidden
units in each lstm layer, and
this is the numbers of layers I'm using.
So then the more data you have,
the more parameters you need.
And so you cam up your parameters
by including more layers and
by increasing the size
of your hidden layers.
Okay, and now we're training.
So the idea here is that we
have all of our epochs, so
I'm just going to use 20,
and this is just for saving.
Don't worry about it too much.
So here this is pretty typical,
we just get our batches of data,
create your feed dictionary.
So here, my inputs are x,
my targets are y.
And for
training the dropout keep probability,
I'm going to keep it at 0.5.
new_state is being initialized, so
I'm taking the initial_state and
I'm passing it as the initial_state for
the rnn.
So what's going to happen is that for
every batch, I'm going to get the state
after a batch, and I'm just going to
route it back into the next batch.
So in this way, you can keep your state
going through each batch as you're
going through the training.
Session run, so getting the cost,
getting the final_state, which is I'm
going to use the new_state for
the initial_state for the next batch.
And then the optimizer, and so this is
what is actually reducing the loss for
the network and changing the parameters.
And then down here is just
the validation part, pretty simple.
So again, I'm going to provide this
notebook for you so you can look through
it and see how it all works, and
just kind of work it out for yourself.
So this is some of the output for
how it trains.
And I'm running this on a NVIDIA 1070,
and
I get 0.13 seconds per
batch at these settings.
Okay, so I trained it and
now we can actually see what the results
are, and they're pretty cool.
So first off, I wrote this
function here, so it's pick_top_n.
So basically we have something
like 65 different characters.
And so every time we try to predict
what the next character's going to be,
it's going to be one of these 65.
So to make it more reliable,
what I did is I said, okay,
well let's just look at the 5
most likely, or you can set this.
Just look at the most likely characters
and then pick from those, right?
So I'm saying, basically, for 5,
what are the 5 most likely characters to
come next, and then choose from those.
So with sampling, the whole idea
is that you pass in a character,
and then your network will predict for
you what the next character will be.
And then you take that character, pass
it back in, and you get the next one.
And you take that, you pass it back in,
and you get the next one.
And so
you can just build up text this way.
You're just continuously getting new
characters, passing it back into your
network and then it all just works
out and just makes a cool thing.
In here I'm also priming it,
so when I'm doing this,
I'm passing in characters,
so in this case, Far.
And it actually starts
generating the state for you, so
that the rest of the characters
have something to be based on.
You're starting to sequence
going through your network.
So again, read up on this,
go through this notebook, and
see how all of this all works.
And this is what we get out of it.
So this is after 3,560 iterations,
so not epochs but iterations, so
going through all the batches and
the epochs.
This network learned English and
learned sentence structure and question
marks and to put quotes around stuff.
And put commas before a quote and
a space, and it's really impressive.
I just went from nothing and
then it learned English, really cool.
However, mostly it doesn't
really make a lot of sense.
It can get sentence structure and
you can figure out words, but
actually making sense as a sentence,
it doesn't do that very well.
He could not trouble to his wife, and
there was anything in them of the side
of his weaky in the creature
at his forteren to him.
I mean,
most of the words make sense, but
as you're going through it, the whole
sentence doesn't really cohere.
So it's pretty cool that it can learn
English words and sentence structure and
spaces and stuff.
There's apostrophes s,
like it knows this stuff, but
it's not really understanding
sentences and meaning.
So now I'm showing you this is
after the 200th iteration, showing
you what the network knows as it's
training, which is pretty interesting.
So after 200 iterations, it actually
knows where to put spaces, right?
So it's, okay, I got a little word,
space, little word, space, word, space.
Yeah and it's pretty impressive,
this is not all that much training and
it's understanding that kind of stuff.
It doesn't really know any words yet.
It knows a few short words,
and, out, as, the, etc.
Then at 600 iterations,
it's looking a little better.
We're getting paragraph structure,
it's learning longer words, or
it's kind of making up longer words.
And it knows more short words, so we've
got some here, it's looking pretty good.
So finally at 1,000 iterations,
we see that it has learned how
to use quotation marks, right?
So quotation, so it's somebody speaking
in the book or the dialogue and
then a comma and another quotation.
I'm going to provide this notebook for
you, and this is not the final form.
This is still just
kind of me working on it.
I'm going to keep it on our
GitHub Repo and make updates to it and
make it nice and easy to use.
And feel free to take it and
build off of it and
make your own recurrent neural network