Now that we're signed up
with the movie database,
let's take a quick glance at
the starter code project.
I'll run the app.
And right now we have this login
screen with the username and
a password text field.
We also have some space below where
we can put debugging information.
If we try to log in with
the username and password,
the UI becomes disabled and
it's waiting for a login to occur.
Let's go ahead and stop this and
take a look at the classes
involved in this project.
Starting with the app delegate.swift,
this file's a lot more involved than
it's been in previous applications.
It has properties for
the shared NS URL session
that we can get access to from
any other class in the project.
And it also has properties for a request
token, a session ID, and a user ID.
These are all things that we'll
need when authenticating and
using the movie database.
There's also this config property,
and we've taken care of this for you.
You don't really need to worry about it.
It's just another black box,
treat it like the GCD black box.
And then the last thing I want to
show you is here at the bottom,
it's this method called
tmdbURLFromParameters.
This method, like the ones that
we saw before in Flick Finder,
is a method that returns a properly
escaped and ASCII safe URL.
But instead of for Flickr,
it's for the movie database.
It also has this additional
parameter called withPathExtension.
And this adds a path to
the URL that's constructed.
This is because for the movie database,
the different methods of the API
are specified as part of the URL path.
This is different from Flickr where
the method was specified as part of
the URL's query.
So take a second and let that soak in.
Okay, let's go back to the code.
Next we have the movie.swift file
that contains the movie struct,
which is the main model for this app.
I'm not going to go over
this struct in detail,
so we can just focus on
the networking part.
But I encourage you to look over it,
it's relatively simple.
Next we have the Constants.swift file.
This file contains constants for
the movie database that you can use
in your implementation for the app.
And of course, we still have
the GCDBlackbox.swift file.
Under this, the next folder we have
is this Provided Classes folder.
In this folder, there's a swift file for
the movie database configuration and
then a border button class,
which is used for that login UI.
We'll skip these two and move on to
the folder that contains the files where
you'll be making all of your
changes in the view controllers.
For this exercise,
you will be making changes to
the LoginViewController.swift file.
Here at the top, you'll notice we have
this property for the app delegate.
Then in the viewDidLoad method,
we're getting the shared
applications delegate.
This is what gives us access to the
properties that we just saw on the app
delegate.swift file.
Now scroll down to the log
in pressed action.
Here we go.
Assuming we've provided a user name and
a password, we disable the UI,
setUIEnabled to false.
And then we call
the getRequestToken method.
This is going to begin
our authorization flow.
And this aligns with the steps
we saw in Ian's flow chart.
The first thing we need to do is get
a request token, so let's follow this.
Oops, we use a command click.
There we go.
In the requestToken method,
we've commented the seven steps.
We have one, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, that need to be
taken to get the request token.
Now, we've already implemented some
of these steps to get you started.
Let's go over them.
First, we define the methodParameters.
For this method, the only parameter
that's needed is the API key.
Then, we build our URL using
the appDelegates tmdbURLFromParameters.
This method takes the methodParameters
as an argument, and
then we specify the PathExtension for
this particular method,
which is /authentication/token/ new.
And you would see this if you look
at it in the documentation for
the movie database.
This particular method will
get us a new request token.
From here, the code is like
what you've seen before.
We create a network task, and
then we need to start it.
It's going to be up to you to handle the
response and finish steps five and six.
To get started, I recommend that you
go through the documentation for
the authentication/token/new method and
look at the example response.
I posted a link in the instructor notes.
The basic idea is this,
deserialize the JSON data and
then parse out the request token.
Once you have the request token,
you can just print it out for now.
Also feel free to use
the login view controllers
debugTextLabel as a nice way to display
errors to the user in case something
goes wrong when making your request.
When you're done with the exercise and
you've printed a request token,
check this box.