Okay, you're doing a great job.
And, the functionality for
the app is almost finished.
We've got one more thing to
add before styling the app,
and that's adding the Reset Button.
The functionality of
the Reset Button is this.
So, I can start making a score.
Let's say that the teams
have some points.
When the game ends,
you could hit the Reset button, and
both of the scores will go back to 0.
You can then add more points,
and they'll add from 0.
Before you start coding,
I want you to plan out what
you're going to do in PseudoCode.
Here's a space for you to do that.
To make this a little more
challenging and true to real life,
I'm actually not going to tell you the
PseudoCode that I would use after this.
Instead, you'll jump right in
to transforming your PseudoCode
into your actual Java code.
Okay, so write your thoughts here.