The answer is no, we're not done yet.
We have reached the goal state.
We put a path onto the frontier that
reaches the goal Bucharest, but
we haven't popped that
path off the frontier.
And uniform cost search continues to
search until we pop it off the frontier.
We can continue looking to see if
there's a better path that also reaches
the goal.
So, let's see.
I forgot to say Fagaras is explored,
so let's continue.
Let's take the cheapest path on
the frontier and expand that.
The cheapest path is this 146,
we'll expand that.
Get another path into Sibiu, that's
the worse path that we had before.
So we'll drop it then
let's see what's next.
Looking on the frontier, the cheapest
now is here at 299, we'll expand that.
We get a path of cost 374,
put that on the frontier.
Now let's go again.
Now the cheapest path
is over here at 317.
We'll mark that as explored and
add two more paths.
One here.
That's a worse path, so it gets dropped.
And one path that also reaches the goal.
And that has a total cost of 418.
So that just shows it's
a good thing we waited,
a good thing we didn't stop when we
found the first path to the goal.
Because now this second path found
is actually cheaper than
the first path found.
But we're not going to stop here,
because we still haven't popped
off a path that reaches the goal.
So we'll continue.
What's next?
Now the cheapest path on
the frontier is here at 366.
We expand that and
we get paths that are worse paths to
points we've already seen before.
So nothing new goes on the frontier.
Next, the cheapest path on
the frontier is at 374.
Again, expanding that
leaves nothing useful,
only worse paths than we've seen before.
And now finally, the cheapest
path on the frontier is this 418,
paths to Bucharest so we pop that off.
And now we reach the goal and
now we stop.
So even though we found the 460
path first, we don't stop there
because there might be another path that
also reaches the goal that's cheaper.
We keep on going until we pop a path off
of the frontier that reaches the goal.
And that's why uniform
cost search is guaranteed
to find the cheapest path to the goal.