To solve this problem,
I decided to first create a set of all
students who pass the subway
project at some point.
First I looped over each submission
in the paid_submissions table, which
contains all the project submissions
from students that we're analyzing.
Next I pull out the project
key into the rating.
Next I wanted to check if this
project was the subway_project, and
I could have done that by separately
comparing is this project
the first project in the list, or
is it the second project in the list?
This would work, but there's actually an
easier way to do this if you're familiar
with Python's in keyword.
So instead I checked if this project's
in the list subway_project_lesson_keys.
Next I wanted to check if
the student passed the project, so
I added a condition that
rating is equal to pass.
However, this isn't actually
the only way to pass the project.
In the table description, it mentions
that past means meets specifications,
but distinction means
exceeds specifications.
So I also wanted to consider a rating of
distinction to be passing the project.
Finally, when using multiple ands and
ors in the same check,
it's always important to add
parentheses appropriately.
In this case I wanted to check that
the project was the subway project and
that the student had passed the project.
If so,
then I added this student's account
key to the past subway project set.
Finally, I wanted to check how many
unique students had passed the subway
project, and that turned out
to be 647 in this data set.
Next, I was ready to split the data
in the passing_engagement and
non_passing_engagement and
I started each office the empty list.
I looped over each engagement record
in the paid engagement_in _first_week
table, and I check if the account
key for that engagement record
was one of the account keys that
had passed the subway project.
If so, I appended this engagement
record to the passing_engagement table.
Otherwise, I appended it to
the non_passing_engagement table.
Then I printed out the number
of entries in both tables.
There are about 4,500 entries in
the passing_engagement table and
about 2,300 in the non_passing table