The tricky part is how to compute the best possible alignment.
It's usually done by dynamic programming.
The recognition here is that in principle there are
exponentially many ways to align pixels in the left and right image,
but in practice you can get away with an n-squared algorithm
where n is the number of pixels in the scan line.
Let's write this as n-squared. It's a much, much faster algorithm.
Here's the idea. Let's write down both scan lines as shown over here.
And let's write down a matrix of size and square.
The neat thing here is that any path from the top left to the bottom right
is a specific correspondence of pixels over here on the left scan line
to pixels over here on the right scan line.
For example, if I take the path that's diagonal, that line pixels by each other.
But the best possible path would assume that the first two pixels correspond,
and there's a left occlusion afterwards.
Then all the red guys correspond.
So this red guy over here corresponds to this red guy over here.
There's an occlusion over here.
Then we go diagonal again.
So any path that picks actions that go diagonal, down, or right
so that the top left is connected to the bottom right
becomes a valid correspondence of the left scan line to the right scan line.
How do we find the best one?
Well, just like in MVPs we use the same methodology as an MVP.
We define the value of any of these points in the grid to be the best,
taking the value of getting there.
The value of a point ij in the grid is the maximum of the match value
if we chose diagonal, which is expressed over here to be the match of ij
given that we chose the diagonal, which means add the value of i minus 1 and j minus 1,
over the occlusion penalty plus any way we could have occluded for the left or the right.
If we look at these three different things we maximize over here,
then each value over here becomes the maximum of assuming we have no occlusion
plus the corresponding match penalty or assuming we did have an occlusion,
either from the top or the bottom, and then we just pay the occlusion penalty,
and we assume the value over there.
Now, that's not trivial. You have to think about this.
Why does this give us the optimal path?
But if you think about it and look at the optimal path,
we pay no penalty over here because the match is perfect.
We pay no penalty over here because the match is perfect again.
So, again, the first clause in this formula.
Over here we do pay a penalty.
We pay a penalty of 10, which is the occlusion penalty,
because we assume that between the blue pixel over here and the right scan image
there's just no appropriate match. We're going to pay a penalty of 10 over here.
Over here we pay no penalty, because the right corresponds perfectly to the red,
and we assume it is a perfect match.
The same over here and the same over here.
Down here we pay a penalty of 10, because we assume an occlusion,
and down here we just assume no penalty at all.
Now with dynamic programming, it computes for every possible location.
For example, this guy over here would have a best optimal path,
which might assume we had a perfect match over here and two occlusions over there,
but now the penalty is already 20 whereas the penalty over here is 10.
So likely this point won't survive.
By working out the value function in this really interesting grid over here,
we find the value of the final point, which is 20,
and we also find the best possible path
by tracing the way in which the value propagated through this grid.
This becomes the best possible correspondence of the left and the right image
by aligning the entire left scan line and the entire right scan line
simultaneously using dynamic programming.
This is the state of the art in stereo computer vision.