Okay, take a look at this image as an example.
See how the appearance of this wall,
which we can assume to have constant color, varies gradually due to lighting.
But look at the features in this image,
these are created due to reflectance of color variations.
So we can expect reflectance to change more frequently with respect to
the location compared with irradiant light.
There are of course other elements to consider.
For instance, object boundaries and shadows.
Sharp edges can also affect observed lightness.
These factors definitely complicate things, but realizing that they change
more or less frequently or in different ways, forms the basis of identifying and
ultimately separating these factors while observing an image.