I created the storefront template and
added it to the index file.
Then I added the ng controller
directive to add the Lego store
controller to this template.
First, I display the basic
information of the store's name, and
the number of bricks it offers
with a couple of expressions.
Then I used ng-repeat to loop
through each of the colors.
Then I used another nested ng-repeat
to display each color's item size.
So this is what we currently have.
Now I need to add the classes and
the more coming soon message.
I used ng-class to test
the item stock levels.
If they are less than 10 then
I add the low stock class.
Then I used ng-if to display this
message if the quantity is less than 5.
Now to hook up these buttons so
that they actually work.
When this button is clicked,
I need to tell the store which color and
size were bought.
The same information needs to be passed
when the return button is also clicked.
In the controller, I created these
functions to change the bricks quantity.
And that's it.
We used a number of different
directives in this quiz.
But I hope you see the power
that directives give us.
I mean look at how small this template
is and yet we have an app that displays
dynamic information and
lets customers interact with the data.
I'll say it again,
directives are awesome.