When we looked at
Firebase notifications,
we talked about how well
they work with analytics.
One of the benefits of analytics is
that you can see how users respond
to changes in your app.
In most cases, large changes to apps
are published as part of an app update.
But this means that only users who
download the update will see that
change.
And if the update is
offered to all users,
you can't try multiple
configurations with the app at once.
And what if the change doesn't
increase user engagement?
You have to present another update
to try another configuration.
But don't worry, there's a better way,
Firebase Remote Config.
With Firebase remote config,
you can change parameters of
your app from the Firebase console
without pushing all new updates.
Maybe you want to find the optimal
text size for your app.
Would be helpful to try multiple
configurations of the app
with different text sizes.
And then compare with what text size
users spend the most time using your
app.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The point is, there are plenty of
cases where you might want to try out
small changes to improve your app, and
see if they change user engagements.
For these cases, use Remote Config.