Step one is about picking
the views that you want to use.
First I should explain what
exactly a view an Android is.
Simply put, a view is a rectangle on
the screen that shows some content.
It can be an image,
a piece of text or a button or
anything else that the app can display.
Now these individual views make up
what we call the layout of the screen.
Everything about what you see and
interact with in your app is called
the user interface, or UI for short.
There are different types of
views with different names.
A view that shows some
text is called a TextView.
Here are some examples.
A view that shows an image is called an
ImageView, and these are some examples.
A view that shows a button is called,
well, a Button.
These are some examples.
Now, there are many other types of views
in Android which are really helpful to
use, but we're going to
focus on these three first.
Earlier I mentioned that every
view is a rectangle on the screen,
but where are all the rectangles?
Well, technically they're invisible,
but I will draw them for you so
you can see where the bounds
of each rectangle is.
As you can see,
every app can be broken down into
the individual view that make it up.
In other words, a view is the basic
building block that you use
to build up the layout for your app.
To help you understand the idea of
views being rectangles on a screen,
here's a situation you may
be more familiar with.
If you ever use an application
like paint or Google drawings
then you may have added a text box to
the canvas, then you type in your text.
If you click outside of it though,
you don't see the bounds of
the rectangle but they are there.
And bounds actually do start
to matter when you start to
do things like adding
a background color or
adding a border around it then it
does matter how big the rectangle is.
I also want to point out that the format
of these view names is in camel case.
Camel case means that there are no
spaces in-between words, and
the beginning of each
word is capitalized.
The reason why it's called
camel case is because
the outline of the word goes up and
down like the humps of a camel's back.
You're going to be seeing camel
case more throughout this course.
Okay, let's practice what you learned.
This is a screen shot of the new
email app from Google, called Inbox.
Can you identify the different
types of views here?
To help you,
I've highlighted the individual views.
For example for A,
can you tell me if it's a TextView,
an ImageView, or a Button.
Do the same for B,
as well as the rest of the views.