So we've made it to the table
where the messages will appear.
Not bad, but we still got a bit of work
to do before we're actually sending and
receiving messages.
So let's dive into the starter code and
see what needs to be done.
In the top level folder for the project,
you'll see three different Swift files.
The AppDelegate,
FCViewController, and Constants.
The AppDelegate doesn't
have much going on.
However, it does have a comment here
in the didFinishLaunchingWithOptions
function telling us that we need to
configure our Firebase application.
It also has a functional stub for
opening a URL.
There's already some code written here
that will handle Google Sign in for
us, but there will more on that later.
Moving on, the next swift file
is the FC view controller.
This is where most of our work
this weekend will be focused.
Some of the View Controller is already
implemented but much of the file is
littered with to dos to help guide
us towards finishing the app.
You can quickly see the to
dos by clicking here in
the navigation bar at the top.
Or you can just browse through
them as we scroll down the file.
Here we can see to dos for handling what
the user sees, when the view loads or
configuring fire based
authentication amongst others.
There are also some to dos for
sending messages, both text and photo,
and here they are in code.
If we scroll down far enough we'll
find some to dos for the table view.
Here we go.
And if we go a little bit further
we can see some to dos for
selecting images with an image picker
and uploading them for photo messages.
The remaining code all the way at
the bottom that I have highlighted here
is already implemented and used for
adjusting the view when
a keyboard is shown on screen.
All right that's it for
the FCViewController.
The final file is called constants.
In constants, we have a struct of
static values that are used in our app.
Now that we've had a brief
look at the starter code,
we're going to shift gears
to talk about databases.
We'll look at what makes fire-based
database so powerful, and
explore some ideas of how
to organize our data,
depending on the type of app
that you're trying to build.