So we're done with making our GitHub
query application life cycle aware.
Or are we?
We've left out an important edge case.
What happens if the device is rotated
while the network transaction is going
on?
When we destroy and recreate an activity
the application continues to run.
That means that all of the threads that
were running continue to merrily process
away.
In the case of our GitHub query app it
delivers the result of the query to
a zombie activity that has gone away and
the activity is left empty.
But it's even worse in
the current version of Sunshine.
In Sunshine, we create our AsyncTask
in the onCreate method of our activity.
It starts a thread which
begins a background task.
If we rotate the device or
do something else which causes
the activity to be restarted, the new
activity will create another async
task to do the background operation.
There will be extra network usage
as both threads run in parallel and
it will take a longer time for
the user to see the result of the load.
Even worse because those background
threads ultimately deliver
their result to a callback
that's part of the activity,
those async tasks actually keep all of
those old zombie activities around as
long as the threads are running
causing extra memory pressure.
Enter loaders to solve this problem.
They've been a part of Android since
Honeycomb and were added to the support
library so they are available
on any useful Android release.
Loaders provide a framework to
perform asynchronous loading of data.
They're registered by ID,
with a component called the
LoaderManager, which allows them to live
beyond the life cycle of the activity
they are associated with,
preventing duplicate loads
from happening in parallel.
If we want to load data
on a background thread,
we can use an implementation of a loader
pattern called AsyncTaskLoader.
The AsyncTaskLoader implements the same
functionality as AsyncTask, but
because it's a loader,
its lifecycle is different.
With an AsyncTaskLoader, once we rotate
the device, the loader manager will make
sure that the running loader is
connected to the AsyncTaskLoader
equivalent of onPostExecute,
the onLoadFinished function.
The loader thread keeps running in
the loading background function.
And once it finishes, the activity
gets notified through onLoadFinished.
Life cycle problem solved.