We've been considering sensorless
planning in a deterministic world.
Now, I want to turn our attention to
partially observable planning, but
still in a deterministic world.
Suppose we have what's
called local sensing.
That is our vacuum can see
what location it is in, and
it can see what's going on
in the current location,
that is whether there's dirt in
the current location or not.
But it can't anything about whether
there's dirt in any other location.
So here's a partial diagram of the part
of the belief state from that world,
and I wanted to show how the belief
state unfolds as two things happen.
First, as we take action.
So we start in this state, and
we take the action of going right.
And in this case,
we still go from two world states in
our belief state to two new ones.
But then, after we do an action,
we do an observation.
We have the act-percept cycle, and
now once we get the observation,
we can split that world.
We can split our belief state to say if
we observe that we're in location B and
it's dirty, then we know we're
in this belief state here,
which happens to have exactly
one world state in it.
And if we observe that we're clean then
we know whether we're in this state,
which also has exactly one in it.
Now, what is the act-observe cycle do
to the sizes of the belief states?
Well, in a deterministic world, each
of the individual world states within
a belief state maps into
exactly one other one.
That's what we mean by deterministic.
And so that means the size of the belief
state will either stay the same, or
it might decrease if two
of the actions sort of
accidentally end up bringing
you to the same place.
On the other hand the observation
works in kind of the opposite way.
When we observe the world, what we're
doing is we're taking the current
belief state and
partitioning it up into pieces.
Observations alone can't introduce a new
world state into the belief state.
All that can do is say some of them
go here and some of them go here.
Now, maybe, that for some observation,
all the belief states go into one bin.
And so we make an observation and
we don't learn anything new.
But at least the observation can't make
us more confused than we were before
the observation.
[BLANK_AUDIO]