To explain the file sharing semantics
in a distributed file system,
let's see what these look like first
in a single node environment and
then compare how they differ from
the distributed multi-node environment.
On the single node in
a Unix environment,
we have the following semantics.
Whenever a file is modified by any
process, in this case process A write c,
that change will immediately be visible
by any other process on that machine.
So Process B will immediately
see that c when it performs a read
on this file, will get abc.
This will be the case, even if
the change isn't actually pushed out to
disk, because both of these processes
have access to the same buffer cache.
In distributed file systems,
that's not the case.
Even if the fact that Process A
performed an update, wrote c to this
file, gets pushed to the file
server immediately, that message,
it may take some time before that
message actually arrives here.
So it is possible for Process B to
not be able to see that message for
a while, and whenever it performs
a read operation on that file,
even in that period after
this file was written to,
it will continue seeing that the file
consists of only the elements a and b.
Given that message latencies may vary,
we have no way of determining how much
should we delay every possible read
operation in order to make sure that any
write that may have happened anywhere in
the system arrives to the file server,
so that we can guarantee
that this Process B
does read the most recent
version of the file.
So in order to maintain
acceptable performance,
distributed systems would typically
sacrifice some of the consistency,
and they will accept some more
relaxed file sharing semantics.
Let's see what are some possible,
meaningful file sharing semantics for
distributed file systems.
As a baseline we will contrast this to
the case when your file system is on
the single machine where every
write is immediately visible, and
this is what's referred
to as UNIX semantics.
Something that makes sense to do is to
enforce what we call session semantics.
Whenever a file is closed,
the client writes back to the server
all of the changes that it has
applied to that file in its cache.
Whenever a client needs to open a file,
it doesn't use the cache contents,
instead, goes and
checks with the file server whether or
not there is a more recent
version of that file.
We call the session semantics with
the period between the file open and
the file close being
referred to as one session.
With session semantics
it is very possible for
one client to be reading a stale version
of a file while another client is either
updating that file or even reading
a more recent version of the file.
But at least by knowing that when we
open or when we close the file, we will
be consistent with the rest of the file
system at that particular moment.
We can reason something about
what kind of sharing guarantees
do we have when we run in this
type of distributed file system?
Although session semantics are intuitive
to reason about, they're really not good
for situations when clients want to
concurrently share a file, write to it
and see each other's updates, then have
to open it and close it repeatedly.
And also when files stay open or are
being updated for long periods of time,
these can result in long periods of
inconsistency in the file system.
For that reason,
it makes sense to introduce some time
intervals when these updates happen.
With introducing time intervals,
the client updates,
writes, will be propagated
to the server periodically.
One way to think about this is that
the client has some sort of lease on
how long they can use the cached data.
However in this case know that we don't
really mean that it's an exclusive
lease, like locking.
This is a completely separate issue.
In the same way,
the server notifications,
the invalidations, are also
periodically sent out to the clients.
This can establish some sort
of time bounds during which
the system can potentially
be inconsistent.
So at least if there are any conflicts,
it will be easier to correct for them.
There will be likely fewer of
them that have accumulated
during the period of these updates.
Since the client doesn't really have
any idea about what are the start and
the end times of these
synchronization periods,
the file system can also provide some
explicit operations to let the client
flush its updates to the remote server.
Just like what we do with flushing the
updates to disk when it comes to local
storage, and also to explicitly sync its
state with that of the remote server.
Again these types of operations are not
necessarily distributed file system
specific, they're used in regular,
local file systems as well.
Other file sharing policies also exist
and make sense for certain situations.
For instance, files may be simply
immutable, you never really modify
a file, you simply delete it, or
you create a new file with a new name.
When you're sharing photos
via Instagram or Facebook,
you don't really upload a photo and then
go and edit it, if you need to change
the photo you change the photo and
you upload the modified photo.
These types of distributed storage have
these kind of semantics immutable files.
Another useful file sharing
semantics would be for
the file system to provide
transactional guarantees.
What this would mean is that
the file system will need to
export some interfaces, some API so
that the clients can specify what is the
collection of files or the collection
of operations that need to be treated
like a certain single transaction?
And then, the file system can make
some guarantees that all those changes
are atomically committed, atomically
made visible into the file system.
As we work through
the rest of the lesson,
we will look at what are some of
the file sharing semantics that
are supported in some distributed
file systems, and also what
are the mechanisms that are required
to achieve these types of semantics.