Congratulations on completing Stage six.
What we're going to do now is actually use some of the existing code
in the official Apache Storm, Storm Starter to implement a RollingCountBolt.
This exercise builds on your completed Stage six code, so we'll start here.
Again, if you did not complete Stage six.
You can always copy the Tweet Topology file from lesson
three stage one to begin.
Remember as well, to enter you Twitter OAuth credentials.
In this new exercise, we're going to use an existing rolling count
bolt from the storm-starter code to visualize rolling tweet counts.
In step one, find and
review the rolling count bolt from the standard storm-starter code.
From the link provided.
And simply copy and pasting the address or searching for
Apache.storm storm-starter, we'll be able to find the RollingCountBolt.
This is an exercise of using.
Bolts that we didn't create.
But we can use their functionality.
So in step two,
copy the RollingCountBolt.java, so you can simply copy and paste this.
Add a file, Roling CountBolt.java, and there we go.
Next in your text editor, add a new folder under the Storm folder, and
label this Tools.
So we now have the structure udacity storm tools.
Next following along in the written instructions.
In Step 4 determine which files from the Storm Starter code is
required to run the RollingCountBolt.
Copy these dependencies into our tools folder.
Where are these files located?
Hint. Take a look at the import statements.
In step five.
Add the import statement to your copy of the RollingCountBolt And in step six.
Without connecting the RollingCountBolt.
Run maven package to check your import process.
Next in step seven.
Update your topology to ignore the CountBolt and
use instead the RollingCountBolt.
Connect this to your report bolt.
Finally, in step eight of the written instructions, build and run your topology.
And finally, when you run your topology you'll see a rolling count
of real tweets.
And once you see your visualization running you'll see that your topology is
taking in an outside bolt, can a useful part of your development process.
Good luck.