Here i'm basically showing you, the, sale of, camera units,
for simple film like this kind of stuff since, since mid 1950s.
If you noticed there's a growth around in the mid 1990s, and
then of course there's a fade away coming in in recent times.
Of course, this could easily be explained,
with what happens when you replace film with digital cameras.
So, digital cameras started coming into the market in you know,
late 1990s early 2000, and that has been a, rapid growth.
Again, these, plots are not entirely to scale, but
this shows this is continuously growing as we hit further years down here.
This is just showing 2006, and we have reached, really a huge magnitude.
So of course when we grow this to 2016,
we notice there is a dip, but at the same time there is an up but
there's a really strong dip coming down at about 2012.
Well this could be explained if you think about it,
because this where basically.
Cameras like this were getting replaced by, smart phone cameras.
So again, just by projecting this further, we can see that basically you know,
less and less of these cameras wouldl probably be sold.
Only people who are serious about photography would consider cameras like this.
Here you notice the big trend that's coming in.
The smart phone cameras are coming into the market.
And this is what I was making, basically suggesting, that as
camera phones are becoming the most widely used electronic device out there.
Because of the dual purpose nature, communication device and
capture content device, they're becoming really pervasive.
And, you know,
there are quite a few of these in several billions of these devices out there.