Jake, did you figure this one out?
>> I absolutely did.
Here goes.
We can see the problem here.
I've had Wizard running for
a while now, and
I've got almost four hundred
messages in the database.
The code for dealing with this
is a little bit tricky so,
well done if you did it.
Over in on socket message, after adding
that into the database, I'm going to
continue using the same transaction and
the same object store from above.
I'm going to get the by-date index,
because I want to remove the oldest
posts, and I'm going to open a cursor,
but pass a null and prev, so
the cursor goes backwards for the index.
Starting with the newest post.
I don't care about the first 30 posts,
those are the newest ones,
they can stay.
I'm going to advance past them.
With the posts after that, well if
the cursor is undefined, we're done.
Overwise I'm going to delete the entry,
then continue the cursor
Calling the same function again to
loop through the remaining entries.
This keeps the news 30 post,
but deletes the rest.
Now i can reload the page
using force reload.
And in the resources panel, I've got
the latest 30 posts, but no more.
This is something we want to ship, so
I bump the static cache
of the service worker,
disable force update, refresh the page,
and there's our update.
Things are looking great.
We've absolutely covered continual
update of pages and this is huge.
Once again,
this is something we could launch.
Here's what we've achieved.
Things haven't changed much when
the connections perfect, but yeah,
perfect doesn't really exist.
On a slow connection we get to
render content, much quicker,
way quicker in fact.
Life our users get content rather
than an infinite white screen.
Even offline users get content.
Although, as I'm sure you've noticed,
things are still a little slow, or
broken when it comes to images.
That's all we've got left to fix,
then we're done.
You're on the home straight now,
just those images, and
we have a full offline first experience.