Now it's worth noting by
using the JobScheduler API,
you're being a good Android citizen.
And the more good Android
citizens there are,
the greater the collective impact
you'll have on battery life.
Now what we've shown you is just a small
sample of what job scheduler supports.
There are way more options and
configurations that you an tailor for
your own jobs.
Now for
more details on how to use this API,
see the Android documentation
in the instructor notes.
Also be sure to check out the Google dev
bite on how to use the job scheduler.
You'll find the link in
the instruction notes as well.
All right, now it's time for
a little quiz.
What jobinfo.builder method
would you append to your job
to make sure it runs when
the device is plugged in?
Go ahead and
enter your answer right here.