So far you've seen several examples of
closure expressions being passed as
arguments to functions.
Just like any other variable that's
passed as an argument to a function,
a closure expression has a type.
This closure expression we pass to
the sort function had this type.
You can see it takes in two Ints and
returns a Bool.
This other closure expression we pass
to the sort function had this type.
You can see it takes in two doubles and
also returns a bool.
Here's another example.
Here, we have an array of soup names,
and
we want to put them in
alphabetical order.
The code to do that looks like this.
What is the type of the closure
expression being passed
into the sorted function?
Indicate your choice in the text box.