So, far you've been manipulating and
transforming color values.
But they only capture one aspect
of an object's appearance.
When you have a class of objects that
can vary in color, structural ques
like gradients or edges might give
you a more robust presentation.
In fact, the presence of gradients in
specific directions around the center
may actually capture
some notion of shape.
Let's take a look at some simple
shapes to better understand this idea.
Here's a triangle, and
its corresponding gradient image.
If you chop up the gradients
into different grid cells, and
treat the cells as a flat, one d array.
You obtain a signature for the triangle.
Similarly, if you have a circle,
you obtain a different signature.
Ideally, the signature for
a shape should have enough flexibility
to accommodate small variations
in orientation, size, etc.
But it should also be distinct, so
that you can use it to
distinguish between shapes.
One problem with using
gradient values directly,
is that it makes
the signature too sensitive.
Can you think of a way to allow for
some variability?