So here we are back in models.py
in our applications source code.
So far, you've created the profile
entity class in your application, but
you haven't actually used if for
saving data in the datastore.
The next step is to add
code to do just that.
So you've already worked with
the getProfileFromUser function in
conference.py.
So far, it creates and
returns a profile object,
but it doesn't actually save
the profile in datastore.
Let's add the code to do that.
Before you can save the profile entity,
you need a unique key
to identify the user.
There are a bunch of choices
we could use for this.
For now, we've provided a function in
the utils module, utils.getUserId,
which takes a logged in user record and
returns a unique ID.
Utils is provided in
the additions folder,
since it's a new addition
to the code base.
And then once you have the user ID,
you can use nbd.Key to make a key.
The first argument is the kind of key
you want to make, in this case, profile,
and the second is the string
you want to make the key from.
And then you'll be able to
save the profile entity.
Doing that is actually super easy
since you've all ready created it.
You just have to use the put method
on the entity you want to save.
So in this case, it will be profile.put
and that's TODO 2 for this exercise.
I've shown you these two, but there are
some other steps you have to do around
them which are described
in the TODO steps.
Once we deploy and use the save
profile method in the API Explorer,
the profile will actually be saved.
One thing you'll have to do in
the API Explorer is to turn on OAuth for
this method.
This will authorize this
method to access your account.
Once you've executed this method,
you should be able to see the results in
the datastore,
under Storage > Cloud Datastore > Query.
And there I am.
So now mark these steps as you complete
them doing the TODOs including
the several steps of TODO 1 and
number 2.
Testing on localhost and
finding the profile in the datastore,
which properties do you see in
the admin tool for your profile entity?
User_id, mainEmail,
displayName or teeShirtSize.