So our starter code presents the user
with an option to be able to enter data
into these edit text fields
of the editor activity.
Now for this part of the lesson,
we'll focus on how to be able to save
off the data that the user's
entered here into our database.
So first, let me start by showing you
what the app will be able to do by
the end of the following quiz.
Let's start by going back
to the catalogue activity.
So here, note that there are currently
zero rows in the database.
So let me we click the floating
action button to the editor activity,
where I can enter some pet information.
So let's enter a pet name Toto,
let's make him a terrier.
And give him a gender of,
let's say, male, and
he will weigh 4 kg, so little tiny guy.
So after I've entered this information,
I'm going to click the Save button, and
once I do that,
a toast appears at the bottom
showing me the ID of the pet
that I've just saved off.
Also notice here that the number
of rows in the pet database has
increased to one.
Now to double check that this is
correct, I can download my database and
then check that Toto was
saved to our shelter.db file.
So to review again how to do that, first
off, remember that this can only be done
with a rooted physical device or
on an emulator, like I'm doing here.
Next open up your
Android Device Monitor,
then select the device that you want,
so I want the emulator.
Open up the Data folder,
down again to the second data folder and
then down to the package.
And then down into databases,
and then we see here,
we have the shelter.db file.
So I'm going to save that off, and
let's save it onto our desktop.
So once it's saved off,
we can open it up in the terminal.
And we can find that directly
here in Android Studio,
it's the command prompt in Windows,
if you are using a Windows device.
So now let's head into the desktop.
So let's CD out of this folder.
All right, and then now let's
open up the sqlite3 program and
directly open up our shelter.db file.
So now, in the sqlite3 program,
remember the command to select
all the information from
a certain table is SELECT *.
Selects all rows and
columns from our pets table and
then end with a semicolon.
And if I hit Enter,
I see here that the information for
the first row of my table is what I
entered into the editor activity.
So with that demonstration in mind,
let's take a look at how we can
execute that in the code now.
So to start adding that
functionality we just saw,
we first need to figure
out when to save a pet.
So when we press the Save button,
that means you're done editing and
that's when the pet should be saved.
So after that happens, we'll need to
grab the data from the edit text fields
and then put them into
a content values object.
And after we've created
this content values object,
we'll use the insert method to
store it off into our database.
So as an overview, here are the four
steps that we'll need to complete.
First we'll need to trigger when
the Save button is pressed.
Second we need to get all the data
from the EditText fields.
Next we'll save that information into
a ContentValues object, and then lastly,
we'll need to insert the ContentValues
object into the pets table.
So, you should be familiar with
how to do steps 2, 3, and 4.
And step 1,
I know is a new step for you.
So, we'll go over how to do that.
In addition, I'll also review
how to cover steps 2, 3, and 4.
So, first let's recap how we get
a value from the EditText field.
If you remember, we actually did
this back in the Just-Java app,
which I have open here.
So first,
let's navigate to the MainActivity.
Remember that you can easily
do this by hitting T, and
this pulls up a search through
all the files in the project.
And then I'm going to search for
MainActivity.
Now, down in the submit order method,
when you press the Submit button
in order to send an email, we needed to
grab the name from the EditText field.
And the id of this EditText
is R.id.name_field.
So first,
we used the find view by id method
in order to get the EditText
with the correct ID.
And then we used getText and
toString in order to get
the string from that EditText.
So let's apply similar
principles to our pets app.
So here I am back in our pets
app inside the editor activity.
And right above our onCreate options
menu, I've added this insertPet method.
So as it says here,
it gets user input from the editor, and
then saves a new pet into the database.
So this method will be called when
the user clicks that Save button
in order to save their inputted
data into the database.
Notice that I've set it to private,
and right now,
it doesn't have any return variable.
So the focus now will be
setting up this method, and
we'll figure out how to call it from
the Save button trigger later on.
So to get the data from the EditText
field, if you remember back to the Java
example, we first need to
reference the EditText.
So in this case,
let's just focus on the pet's name.
So I could use find view by ID,
which we did in the Java example,
in order to get the name EditText.
So since I've already done this
up here in the onCreate method,
we can go ahead and use this variable.
So I can call getText on
this EditText object,
and then in order to make a string,
let's call toString on it.
So doing so returns whatever
was typed here as a string.
So one more method I
wanted to add is .trim.
And doing so eliminates any leading or
trailing white space from
the string that we got.
So for example, if the user had typed in
extra spaces after they entered the name
Toto, this will just trim it off, so
that we only have the string T-O-T-O.
Now, to create a variable so that we can
use the string, let's create a string,
just name it nameString, and
set that information to that value.
All right, so now, if I want to
make a new content values object,
I can use the key value pair,
where the key is the name column, and
the value is the name
from the EditText field.
So I'll leave setting up
the remaining fields up to you.
So that leaves the breed,
the gender, and the weight.
And those will look similar
to the setup we did here.
However, there are two key
things that I want you to note.
First, in order to convert a string into
an integer, what you'll might need to do
for some of those values,
you can use the integer.parseInt method.
So this method will take whatever
stream was passed in here and
convert it into integer form.
So we'll take this
string version of 1 and
then change it to
an integer variable of 1.
My second hint to you is if you're
wondering how to get the value for
gender, remember that we stored
it in the variable M gender.
All right, so now you should know how
to get started on steps 2, 3, and 4.
And that leaves the question of when do
we know when the user has pressed that
Save button, meaning we can
trigger that insertPet method.
All right, so to answer that question,
let's take a look back in our
Editor Activity in our
onOptionsItemsSelectedMenu.
So this is where we can set up what
happens when a user clicks on different
options in the app bar overflow menu.
So currently, we have a case already for
our Save button, so
this action save here.
But right now,
it's not set up to do anything.
So if we want it to trigger the
insertPet method when the user clicks on
that Save button,
let's just do that now.
So instead of doing nothing, let's
change it to save pet to the database,
and that means we'll call
our insertPet method.
So after the pet insertion's done here,
we actually want to exit that editor.
And in order to do that,
we'll call our finished method,
which closes up the editor activity.
And then that returns us automatically
back to the catalog activity where we
originally came from.
So let's add that in.
All right, so to summarize,
what we're doing here is setting up,
so that when the user clicks
on the Save button, so
in this case,
these two actions happened.
First, the insertPet method is called,
and then afterwards,
we exit the activity and
jump back to our catalog activity.
So combining all of
the information I just covered,
I'd like you to finish
the code to successfully save
a new pet into the database from
the editor activity screen.
Also as I showed in the demo,
I'd like you to make a toast message
that shows the id of the pet
displayed in the catalogue activity when
the user has clicked the Save button.
So, one more thing before you head off,
in the catalogue activity,
I'd like you to add this block of code.
So here,
I'm overriding the onStart method, and
that means when
the activity starts again.
So this means after it comes back after
the user has clicked Save in the editor
activity that the list will refresh
with the new pet in the database.
So this will allow the row count
on the screen to increase.
And you'll be able to find this snippet
of code down in the quiz below.
So I know there's a lot
that I just covered, and
here's a summary of what I'd
like you to do in this exercise.
So I'd like you to modify
the editor activity, so
that when the user clicks
the Save button in the app bar,
it first inserts a pet into
the database and shows a toast message.
I want the toast message to say the pet
saved with ID and the number of the ID.
If the insertion wasn't successful,
if it was not,
then show this host message instead.
There was an error with saving the pet.
Also remember to add
the snippet of code, so
that the catalogue activity restarts.
And the row count updates, and that
snippet of code is down below this quiz.
So I know there's quite a few steps
you need to complete this exercise.
So as a suggestion, go back to
the four steps I listed earlier, and
think of the connection
points between each of them.
And that will help you figure out
where you need to execute different
parts of the code.