Couple of other things to think about when you compare, yeah, film,
digital cameras and the concept of photography.
So in essence, if you really look at these two cameras,
this is a traditional film camera and this is a digital SLR.
Basically, they have the same functionalities, right?
They have the same set of features.
You can zoom and focus, you can control the aperture and
exposure shutter release and advance a kind of built-in into motors.
And but again mostly, what you can take is one picture but clicking ones and
that's what you get.
So in essence if you were to kind of compare the growth of
digital photography from film photography not much is different.
You still get the same kinds of images, and
some may argue that film was giving you better resolution and better detail.
But, what does computational photography do to it?
Film or digital photography, we can use the devices, but
in computational photography we can changes some of these functionalities, live.
So for example, as we've discussed, we can control and
change the optics, illumination, sensor, and movement of the camera.
This could be for example how we build panoramas or
how we controlled the lighting illumination, and of course how the optics is
controlled or the sensor was controlled for dual photography.
We can also actually exploit more characteristics of the wavelength,
the speed of the scene, depth, and polarization and all additional information
that might be available to our camera live, based on what we want to do.
Again, there has been a whole long history of using depth.
For doing focusing in traditional cameras we can actually use
this much more in a live manner with computational photography cameras.
Further, you know,
in the old days of photography it took a probe to measure the light.
We could take a picture with that,
but now a probes could also be much more dynamic changing things as we use them.
We can apply actuators, and we played around with this a little bit when moving
the cameras, but also moving the optics and the apertures and stuff like that.
We can also start using information by a network of cameras that
has put a bunch of different cameras in the environment to all be connected, and
now of course we would get a multi-view synchronized images.