To start off I'm calling gulp serve, and
I'm letting that run in the background.
So here's my promise wrapper inside get.
Notice that I'm returning the promise,
and
I'm resolving when
the request status is 200.
I'm passing the response to resolve so
that then gets the response as well.
I'm rejecting on any error whether
that's not a status of 200 or
something else, and
the rest of it looks good.
I didn't have to change anything else.
Down here in the web
components ready listener,
I am actually doing
something to the page.
Once I get the data, I add the search
header, and if something goes wrong,
I add a search header of unknown and
then console that log error.
Okay, let's see what happens.
So it looks like this query works
because you can see earth-like
planets on the page.
But let me see what happens
when I mess up that URL.
I'll go ahead and
just delete a character.
Let's see what happens.
Okay, that looks good.
I see unknown as the query and
I see an error here in the console.
I can open it up and see that
something went wrong with the XHR.
Cool, I want to show you
one more thing though.
Inside the addSearchHeader there is
this call to JSON.parse of the response.
If you think about it, parsing a JSON
really has nothing to do with adding
a search header, so in the next quiz
you'll be removing this all together and
putting it inside a different
method where it does belong.