Now that we have the project one
files opened up inside of Unity,
why don't we have a little fun and
customize it up a bit?
We'll go over everything we're doing in
a lot more detail in future courses, but
we thought it would be cool to
show you how to customize and
build your own app so that you
can show it off to your friends.
To get started,
navigate to the Projects window and
click on Udosity VR &gt; Scenes
&gt; Modified Google Demo Scene.
As you can probably guess from the name,
we've modified the Google demo scene
that comes with Google VR so
that it's a bit easier to customize.
For starters, let's center the scene
view around the Hello World text.
Just as a reminder,
hold down the right mouse button and
use the WASD keys to move around.
Pause the video here until you're ready.
Next, let's click on
the Hello World text.
In the Inspector window,
we should now see a bunch of options for
styling our text as well as
the text we want to display.
Let's go ahead and
change the text to include our name.
Awesome, now if we rotate
down in the scene view
we should see a menu
that has five buttons.
The Reset and Recenter buttons
were provided by Google.
The first button resets the scene
to its original state and
the second will re-center
where you're looking.
In Cardboard,
those are both valuable options to have.
So let's leave them there.
The bottom three buttons
should all say Switch Shape.
If we run the app using the play
button at the top here,
we will then switch into the game view.
With Google VR's SDK if we press Alt and
then move our mouse,
we'll be able to rotate where
we're looking in the scene.
Use it to rotate and look at one
of the Switch Shape buttons and
click anywhere on the screen.
Now, if we look up we'll see that
our cube has switched into a sphere.
If we go ahead and
click that button again,
we'll notice that it switches back.
For this project we've written
a script called Udacity Fun Effects,
which contains five different
effects that we can have happen.
To use it,
we'll need to stop playing our scene and
then click on one of these
Switch Shape buttons.
Now if we look at the Inspector,
we'll see a section called on click.
Here we can see that the button has
already been assigned to toggle shape.
But we can easily change
that using the drop down.
For some fun, let's change it to
spawn some random cubes by going to
Udacity Fun Effects &gt;
Spawn Random Cubes.
For clarity, we should also
change the text of the button.
In the hierarchy,
you'll notice a triangle next to the
Switch Shape button we have selected.
If we click it, it will reveal
a text component that we can
use to change the text of our button.
Let's change it to
Drop Cubes From the Sky.
Now if we hit Play and
rotate down to click the button,
we'll see that we have ten cubes
falling at us from the sky.
In addition to having
cubes fall from the sky,
we can also play around with
changing the particle colors,
toggling the flashlight, or
toggling a day night cycle.
For your first project, your task is
to play around with these different
effects in Unity, and get it onto your
phone, which is what we'll do next.
But most importantly, just have some fun
playing around with the Unity editor.