Let's learn about the chi-square test with an example. This is Mount Shasta,
and this photo was taken by Professor Rogers. Mount Shasta is the solitary
giant of Northern California. And it rises 14,179 feet or 4322 meters. It's the
fifth highest peak in California. Doctor Rogers would like to successfully
climb Mount Shasta this summer, but he needs statistic to help make some
choices. According to summitpost.org, only about 33% of the 15,000 summit
attempts each year are successful. Being an amateur mountaineer, Doctor Rogers
plans to make his summit attempt with the aid of a professional guide company.
He's considering a guide company called Summit Up. I made that up, but let's go
with it. And they state that of the 100 trips they had last year, 41
successfully reached the summit. Does this represent a significantly better
success rate than would be expected by chance? In other words, should he hire
this company? What do you notice about these data compared to the types of data
sets we've used before? Select all that apply.