Hi, my name is Jimmy,
I'm a data analyst at Udacity.
>> Hi, my name's Charlie.
And I'm a course manager on
the Data Analyst Nanodegree Udacity.
>> So today I'm going to be interviewing
Charlie just going through general
questions that are generally asked in
data science or data analyst interviews.
And, yeah, here we go.
So Charlie, would you tell me about
the project that you are particularly
proud of that you've
worked on in the past?
>> Sure.
One of my favorite
projects was the project
that I did as part of the Data Analyst
Nanodegree about the New York Subway.
So we had some New York Subway
data from the MTA in New York,
and we had some weather data
collected relating to those places.
And I was looking at
the effect of weather and
other factors on the number of
riders on the New York Subway.
It was great to get my hands
on some real world data.
>> So what were some of
the cool things that you found?
>> I found, I guess it wasn't
surprising in the end, but
I enjoyed investigating that one of the
most important factors was the station.
So you might not think of it at first,
you think, maybe the weather makes
the biggest difference, but really it's
whether you're in Central Station or
somewhere else that makes
a really big difference.
I found also that some confusing
effects of the weather.
So, you might,
depending on how you did your analysis,
if you did like just a statistical
test on rainy days on not rainy days.
I found that in that case it
looked as though rain was
causing a change or
related to a change in the ridership.
But when it came down to it, and
I used regression to predict ridership,
I found that that really
wasn't a big factor.
And I thought that was good because I
realized that I was controlling for so
much more when I was
doing the regression,
regression felt like
the right tool to use.
>> What type of regression did you use?
>> It was just a linear regression but
I did some transformations
on some of the variables,
I encoded all the stations and
some other stuff as dummy variables.
>> Of course, of course.
I say, how many variables do you have?
>> There's-
>> Approximately.
>> Yeah, there's a few hundred.
>> A few hundred?
>> Because of all the units, so-
>> Okay.
>> With all the stations.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Like there's a few hundred,
300 or so stations.
>> I see.
>> So, but apart from that if
you take things as groups they're
only a handful of things I was using.
>> I see, so how do you do with
all the large number of variables?
>> I guess it wasn't too bad with that,
it wasn't too big.
>> Okay.
>> On my case like they were dummy
variables, I had a few hundred
thousand records, not millions.
So everything was kind of manageable.
>> But do you have any
problems with overfitting?
>> I think I did when I did certain
things, so I kind of corrected that.
One of the things I tried was
to fit things with the station,
and the day of the week,
and the time of day.
And if you do all of those and
if you were to kind of create,
I've forgotten the word.
Where you, [SOUND] sorry.
>> It's okay.
>> Like features where that includes
all of them at the same time,
I've forgotten the technical word.
And then, that would be really
overfitting because really
you're fitting to
a very few data points.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> But yeah, if you kind of consider
them separately, then it's okay.
And I actually ended up not using
just the day of the week to check,
but whether it was a weekday, or not.
>> I see, so yeah, so
you took the subset of the features that
you thought were the most important.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, that's excellent.