So if a pet were entered
by mistake into the list,
they can remove from the list
simply by clicking the X button.
Now in the final version of the app,
we'll store all this data.
But to start out, we'll make an MVP.
And that stands for
minimum viable product.
So this will store the most important
attributes as identified by the shelter.
So first we'll have Name,
Breed, Gender and the Weight.
Now as we saw in the quiz,
using the SQLiteDatabase seems to
make the most sense for our pets app.
But how will we store all the
information about these different types
of animals into our database?
So let's say we're given
information about these three pets.
But the information came
to us all unorganized.
Now, given the three methods that we
know about data storage, let's look at
how we can structure this data into
a way that we can effectively use it.
These were the features
of the SQLiteDatabase.
SQLiteDatabases look
a lot like spreadsheets.
Now, just as a single spreadsheet
can contain multiple sheets,
a single database can
contain multiple tables.
So in this case, we're only interested
in our one table, our table about pets.
So if the SQLite tables are like
the pages of a spreadsheet, let's make
a single page in a spreadsheet represent
the pets that come into the shelter.
So how would you organize
the information about those three pets
that we saw earlier,
into this spreadsheet format?
We'll here's your
chance to try that out.
So for this exercise,
given these three example pets,
I'd like to either sketch or use Google
sheets to organize information of
these three pets into a table.
And if you need help with Google sheets,
take a look in
the instructors notes below.
I've linked it out where you can learn
about it as well as download it.
And then afterwards,
answer these questions.
Excluding a row where you might
have to put column headers,
how many rows does the spreadsheet have?
Thirdly, how many columns
does your spreadsheet have?
And then lastly, which one of these
attributes could be a column header?
Pets, weight, the name Toto or male.
So give this a try and
I'll see you in the next video.