So if you hit an unexpected paint like
you just saw, you've got another tool at
your disposal, and
it is called the Paint Profiler.
You can find it in the Timeline tab.
The Paint Profiler makes
it really easy to identify
what areas of the page are being
painted and when they're being painted.
For this quiz, go back to the scene you
were on and turn on the Paint Profiler.
Hit the record button,
and scroll up and down.
You should see a bunch of
long-running paint records.
Click on one of the paints, and then
check out what you find in the paint
profiler tab down here by the details.
Scroll through what you find
in the paint profiler and
then tell me what is the first
paint command that is listed there.
Type it in here.