You've completed these three steps for
your preferences, so
what about step four?
And also what exactly is
a preference summary?
There's one annoying thing that
you might have noticed about our
new shaped color preference.
When you change the color
in the settings,
it's a little hard here to see
what the current color is.
Now for the check box setting, here,
when we change the check box says we
can actually see what that means.
For example, it's checked on so
it's shown, checked off so it's hidden.
This smaller gray text here is
known as the preference summary.
And it's meant to contain more info
about what the preference is for or
its current value.
You can set the preference summary to
some static text, but what I want to do
is have the preference summary
show us what our current color is.
To do that,
I'll need to have the settings fragment
update the summary programmatically.
This is done in a way that's
very similar to how we load
the preferences in visualizer activity.
I'm going to head over
the settings fragment now.
I'll start by getting
a reference to sharedPreferences
in the onCreatePreferences function.
Here's my reference to sharedPreferences
and notice that I'm using
the PreferenceScreen to get my
reference to sharedPreferences.
I also get a reference to
the PreferenceScreen so
that I can get a count of
the total number of preferences.
Next, I'm going to iterate through
all of my SharedPreferences.
And I do that by calling getPreference
on the Preference screen and
passing in an index.
I'm going to create a helper method
now called setPreferenceSummary.
And this method is going to take in
a Preference and a String value.
The purpose of this method is to
set the correct preference summary.
Setting the correct summary for a list
preference is a little bit tricky.
We can't just use the key or
the value string.
Remember, these words right here
are the list preference labels and
they're what's shown in the UI.
The value and the key are both behind
the scenes and the values are associated
with these labels while the key is
associated with the entire preference.
In the summary,
we want to display the current label.
Because if we make a localized
version of the app,
the label will be translated but
the value will not.
So the first thing I want to do in my
set perfect summary of that it is check
if the preference is
an instance of ListPreference.
If it is, I'm going to cast it,
then I'm going to find the index of the
current preference which was selected.
And I'm doing that here using
the findIndexOfValue, and
then passing in the value.
I'll then check if the index is valid,
and
if it is, I'm going to use this
setSummary method for my listPreference.
And what I'll pass in is,
I'm taking the listPreference here,
I'm getting all of the labels, and
I'm indexing into that array using the
listPreference index that I got up here.
So this is getting the label that
is associated with this value.
Okay, now going back up here to my for
loop which again,
is in the onCreatePreferences menu.
I'm going to take this preference, and
check if it's a CheckBoxPreference.
And if it's not a CheckBoxPreference,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to get
the value by taking my sharedPreferences
object and using getString with the key.
And I'm going to pass that value and
those sharedPreferences to my
setPreferenceSummary method.
Note that I am intentionally excluding
the CheckBoxPreference here,
because I changed the CheckBoxSummary
by using the on summary and
off summary XML attribute.
Also, this called a getString would
cause a runtime error, because for
CheckBoxPreferences, the value
type is a Boolean.
Okay, so I'm programmatically
setting my preferences on load, so
let's go ahead and run the app.
And I can see here that
it has a summary now.
But if I change this preference,
it's not updating the summary.
For that, I'm going to need to use
a OnSharedPreferenceChangeListener.
And this is just like in
my visualizer activity.
So going to the top of
my settings fragment,
I'm going to implement
OnSharedPreferenceChangeListener.
And it is of course unhappy because
I haven't implemented the associated
method which is
OnSharedPreferenceChange, so
let's do that.
So here's the OnSharedPreferenceChange
method, so
essentially what I'm doing here is I'm
finding the preference by its key, and
if that preference isn't null and it's
not an instanceof CheckBoxPreference,
then I'm getting the value and
I'm calling setPreferenceSummary.
Again, that is almost identical
to what I'm doing here.
Now that my
OnSharedPreferenceChangeListener is
set up, I need to actually register and
unregister it.
And I'll do that in the appropriate
place which is onCreate and onDestroy.
So I'm going to scroll
down to the bottom, and
I'm going to override onCreate.
And in onCreate,
I'm going to get my PreferenceScreen,
getSharedPreferences and
register the PreferenceChangeListener,
which again is this.
Because this up here is the class that
has the onSharedPreferenceChangeListener
implemented.
And I'm going to unregister
it by overriding onDestroy.
And here I'm just unregistering
the listener as well.
Okay, let's run the code to see if
the summaries are being updated.
Now I'm going to try updating
the summary to blue, and
I see that the summary is updated.
Yes.