I was just at Yosemite, and now I've
decided to create a soon to be world
famous website that aggregates important
information if you want to go hiking.
But I can't seem to get
the routing figured out.
Going to the site's home page
should activate the home function.
I also want to let people
look up specific mountains.
So when the route is mountain/ some ID,
I need the mountain function called.
And then people should be
able to download brochures.
This right here should be
able to be anything, and
then download/whatever should
load the download function.
I need to turn these URLs into
routes that Backbone can understand.
Can you help me finish the mountain
router by adding in the correct routes?
What is the route to
call the home function?
What about the route to handle
the mountain and its ID?
Enter the route here that will
call the download function.
For help with figuring out the ID and
the brochure,
it might be helpful to review Backbone's
documentation on route parameters,
specifically params and splats.