Let's fix the issue of determining when
we should transition to the second View Controller.
We can do this by changing
the Segue to only be called from code
and not directly from Storyboard
when we press the Stop Recording button.
We know that we are recording our voice in the
Record Sounds View Controller.
And once our recording is finished, we need to
send that file over to the second scene.
But how do we change the current Segue
to be called just by code and not from
the UI button. If you look in the
Main.storyboard file, we can see that the
two scenes are connected via the Segue.
In particular it's the Segue that's
wired up from the stop recording button.
Every time this button is pressed,
Storyboard performs the Segue for us.
What we want to be able to do is call
the Segue programmatically once we know
the AV Audio Recorder has finished
writing out the file. This is easy to do.
Let me walk you through it now.
Let's start by deleting the current Segue.
Make sure you have the Segue selected and
then press the Delete key. Once you
delete the Segue Xcode is going to
complain that the second scene is no
longer reachable since we have no way to
segue into it from anywhere else on the Storyboard.
We can see that warning mentioned here.
To fix the warning and
set up a Segue that we can call
programmatically, we need to rewire a Segue.
But instead of going from the stop
button to the second View Controller,
We just need to go straight from the first
View Controller to the second View Controller.
The easiest way to do this is
from the Document Outline. So make sure
you have the first View Controller
selected the record sound View Controller.
Hold down the control key and
then click drag to the second View Controller.
And make sure we select Show
is the type of Segue. Now that these two
scenes are connected via Segue, we can
have the Storyboard performed the Segue
for us by calling a special function
named performSegue. will set up the call shortly.
But in order to distinguish this
Segue from any other, we need to give it
a unique name. So make sure you have the
Segue selected and then in the Attributes
Inspector, we want to give it a unique
identifier
I'll use “stopRecording”. These names are
case sensitive by the way, so make sure
you spell it correctly.
Next we need to know that the AV Audio
Recorder has finished writing out the
recorded voice Wav file. And to do that,
we're going to use a concept called
delegation.