Hey Travis.
We're about to try our hand at
building a more complex app that uses
the movie database.
But before we do, we were wondering,
what kind of apps would you like to see?
What makes a great app that
uses the movie database?
>> You know, honestly anything and
everything around movies, TV shows and,
and actors and actresses.
We have apps that let you, you know,
keep track of personal watch lists,
let you search your favorite movies,
and find out who is in
that movie with so and so.
You know, my favorite apps are the ones
that, you know, combine a nice, sleek,
well thought out interface and
tie in all those account features
that we make available via sessions.
It's really, really awesome when
you see your hard work be taken
by another developer and designer and,
you know, lay it out on an iPhone.
And you just see how that
API powers the experience.
You know, behind the scenes,
and it's so seamless.
And, you know,
it's my job to make sure that that is,
is as seamless as possible,
and just works.
And, you know, the more we
get to see of that, you know,
those, the pretty mobile apps,
websites the better.
>> Awesome.
Thanks Travis.
So, what to make of this?
The big take away from Travis's answer
is that his favorite apps are ones
that are sleek and just work.
I'd imagine that most people would agree
with this statement because at the end
of the day,
users don't care about the code,
they just care about the end product.
But there's a catch.
To make sure the end product
is as seamless as possible,
we have to have well-designed code.
So let's take a look at our end
product now, the Movie Manager.