So, here we are in the text
editor working on forum.py.
We've got some HTML down here, and we've
got some web server code down here,
and back up at the top it looks like
there's actually another module,
forumdb, for the database code.
So if we look over at forumDB.py,
we'll actually see rather
a lack of database code.
It looks like we're currently using
just a Python list to store the posts.
No wonder they went away when
we restarted the server.
So this AddPost function,
inserts a topple into our database list.
And the GetAllPosts function, transforms
the list into a list of dictionaries.
Where the content key
points to the post content.
And the time key points to
the time it was posted.
Over in forum.py,
if we look in the view function,
we'll see where
forumdb.GetAllPosts is called.
And then down in the post function,
we'll see where AddPost is called.
We don't need to edit any
of the forum.py code,
because everything that talks about
the database is over in forum.db.
So what we need to do is change
this database code up here,
to actually use a real database.
So on the next page,
you're going to do exactly that.