Now let's see if this works.
Instead of building a server I've
created a simple web page we can
use to send the post request.
You'll just need two things
I mentioned along the way.
Your server API key which you
generated in the API console,
this is your authorization key and
it is how Google servers know that
you are who you claim to be, and that it
is okay to send a message to your app.
And to the registration ID or
token that you logged in
registration intend service.
Now, copy both of these values into the
web page linked below, click Send, and
see the magic.
If you followed all instructions
correctly you should receive a weather
alert on your device at this point.
Copy that alert message here to
let us know you've succeeded.