In the previous lesson,
you saw how you can control the flow of
the program with conditional statements.
Basically, if a certain condition is
true, execute this block of code.
Otherwise, execute this
other block of code.
>> But there are often times when
you want to execute a block of code,
not once, but
maybe a hundred times, or more.
Maybe you're a teacher who needs
to calculate the grades for
all of your students.
You might have 170 of them, or
maybe you have 300 Facebook friends,
and you want to calculate the number
of mutual friends for each friend.
Or maybe you just want to
count to a million because who
wouldn't want to count to a million?
>> Writing code to do these kinds
of tasks could result in hundreds,
thousands or millions of lines of code,
all doing pretty much the same thing.
In this lesson, you will learn how to
use JavaScript loops to repeatedly
execute a block of code.