Hey, welcome to our first quiz.
You'll have to excuse my handwriting.
A big part of this course will be
quizzes and programming exercises.
This approach to teaching is
called formative assessment,
that means we're not asking you
questions to give you a grade, but
to challenge you and
keep you interested.
Don't worry if you need to
submit a quiz multiple times or
even skip ahead to the answer video.
The questions are here to help you,
not to examine you.
With that in mind,
let's do our first quiz.
Which of the following are advantages
of using a build tool, portability,
automation, deliciousness,
repeatability, or delectability?