Looks like we're getting
a call from Mike.
I was wondering when he'd appear next.
Mike, what can I do you for sir?
>> Well, you've explain the cache and
the install event.
Sounds like something for
the student to put together.
>> Couldn't agree more.
Take it away.
>> To begin,
you'll probably want to get your copy of
Witter into the same state as Jake's.
To do that, open a command
prompt to the project folder and
run git reset --hard to remove
any local changes you have.
Then git checkout task-install.
Let's take a look at the code.
In public/js/sw/index.js there's
an array of URLs to cache there.
Your task is to cache those URLs
in a cache named wittr-static-v1.
Remember to have dev tools open and
use force update on reload, so
you only need to refresh
once to see changes.
You can also verify the state
of the cache in dev tools.
Click on the resources
panel then cache storage.
Hopefully you'll see
your cache in there.
Once you've got it working,
head over to the settings page and
type install cached into
the test field and press enter.
This will confirm its all working.