So in TCSEC we know that
D was the basic one.
Really had to do nothing.
For C you had to implement some security
functions, including discretionary
access control, but you didn't have
to do mandatory access control.
For mandatory access control,
if you did, you could go to B.
If you don't implement mandatory access
control, you can't be higher than C.
The best you can do is C.
So if you don't support MAC, you cannot
be in a TCSEC division higher than C.
This is the answer.
Automatically also means you can't
be higher than D, so this is
somewhat poorly formulated question, but
you could be higher than D actually.
You could be in C, even if you don't
implement MAC, which is higher than D.
So the only option that you should
be checking here is the second one,
which is C.