So let's first dive into Novel Illumination.
What I'm going to do is, I'm going to introduce this concept very simply first.
and then we're going to look at that example in much more detail and, and
those examples some of these details will be repeated again.
So we just have a 3D scene.
What I can do is, I can put a photo cell,
to be able to capture all the rays of light that are going into this photocell.
And of course that is going to generate an image.
Of course what I could do to illuminate this scene,
now of course it's already naturally illuminated.
But I could actually do something different.
That is I can put a projector, and
what this projector is doing is, basically illuminating the scene, and
what we can do is of course this can be considered a controllable light source,
but what we can also do in front of it, is create some sort of a modulator.
Which is in essence a controllable aperture.
Which basically would mean is, it would open different regions of this
modulated region, depending on what kind of computer code we will send it.
So, in essence what I can do is, I can basically illuminate just this part and
close all of it, and therefore the light would come from here, and
through here and hit the scene, just that ray of light, as shown here.
So, only this ray of light from this projector is illuminating the scene.
Of course I can computer control and move this light source within this region.
This is in essence what it means by an aperture, is I'm basically opening only
the regions and I know exactly which region I'm opening.
And I can of course move this in a predefined manner depending on
what I want to do.
We'll see this again in a bit, but I just want to setup the situation.
So this is what novel illumination means.