The irradiance, sometimes called energy E,
that's the energy actually arriving at the surface.
Okay, so now we're going to talk about the energy at the surface.
Okay, so now I've gone back to and
I'm going to leave both this perpendicular part.
And this little, this is the area on my surface, okay.
Now, it's because I'm actually looking at my surface I'm just going to measure
that as the power per unit area so that's just watts per meters squared, okay.
So clearly, there's this relationship between the amount of energy hitting that
perpendicular part, and then this skewed, the, the, the area on the surface.
And, the, the easiest way to think about that is to think about this
as a foreshortening effect, all right.
So, here we have a, a light source, and the idea is that this is the direction
of light, and this area, this card here is meant to be perpendicular, right.
So there'll be a certain amount of light falling on that, on that card, right.
But if the card was not perpendicular right, if the card was tilted away,
then the same amount of light now gets spread over a larger area.
And so it's foreshortened.
So in other words, we get less light per little unit
area from that light source.
And we can write that down in the following way.
Sort of for the surface receiving some radiance and
from some direction, coming from this we'll say, fixed little patch,
the omega, the corresponding irradiance, the light landing on the surface,
is just the radiance modulated by this angle.
Right? So is that angle gets closer and closer and closer to, to power of 290
degrees, the amount of ra, irradiance goes down to zero, which is right because
you're essentially spreading the same amount of light over a much bigger area.