The single biggest contributor to
student success to the Nanodegree
is time commitment.
The first graduate of any
Nanodegree at Udacity
didn't have any prior experience.
He simply worked hard, and
put in time consistently
making his Nanodegree part of
his daily and weekly schedule.
Now, as I mentioned before,
the timeline you're operating on
assumes that you'll work on your
Nanodegree for ten hours a week.
Since many students have a lot of
other things going on in their lives,
like jobs, families, or other big
commitments, it's really important to
block out time on your calendar
every week for your Nanodegree.
While binge learning works well for
some people, the most successful Udacity
students work on their courses and
projects multiple times a week,
not just in one big chunk.
And really,
a ten hour chunk would be exhausting.
This helps the learning you're doing
stick better since you're thinking
it more frequently.
On top of that, having a regular
weekly routine that you stick to
is really helpful for
keeping up your dedication.
Working at about the same time slots
each week can be really helpful.
After you do it for a few weeks,
it'll just feel like second nature.
So go into your calendar right now and
mark out which times you'll work on
the Nanodegree this week and next week.