So if your website has users log in
that's one way to tell the traffic apart
from each other even if your site has
some users who are logged in and some
users who aren't logged in as in the
case of sites like Wikipedia or Google.
You can still get a pretty
good estimate this way.
Now you can't tell much from the speed
of the users network connection.
And multiple users coming in from
the same net are probably going to have
the same speed anyway.
Apps can assign the session cookie
to a particular browser instance
even if there's no logged
in users identity.
So that can work to distinguish
different users that are behind
the same net.
Now a remote user's ethernet MAC address
is not something that a web server can
see so that won't work.
And geolocation involves looking up
the user's IP address in a table or
service to find out where
on the planet they are.
But that relies on
the public IP address,
it's going to return the same answer
from multiple users behind the knot.
And because these two will work,
it's not the case that
none of these will work.
There are ways you can find out
how many users your site has,
even if some of those users are behind
the same public IP address.