The expression I used is 5 by 698
times 6 by 699 times 7 by 700.
In the first iteration we might
choose any one of the 7 groups among
the 700 possibilities.
Given that we chose a root in
the first iteration, however,
that leaves only 6 roots left to choose
from in the second iteration, and
there are only 699 numbers to
choose from in S, as well.
Remember that we are sampling
without replacement.
We don't put back the sample we
chose in the first iteration, so
that we might choose it again.
And the logic for
the last term is the same.
We've used up two numbers already,
both of which are roots.
In terms of the probability
theory that we've established,
we can formalize this
argument as follows.
Let Ei be the event that the ith
element chosen from S is a root.
The probability that all three samples
are roots is the probability of E1 and
E2 and E3.
Which we break up into this
product using the definition
of conditional probability.
We play the same trick with the second
term here to get this expression,
replacing it with the probability of E2
given E1 times the probability of E1.
Now, we have the probability of each
event conditioned on the previous ones.
Given that 2 routes have
been chosen already,
the probability of picking
another is is 7-2, by 700-2,
and we end up with the same argument,
and the same expression as before.