Let's do a web search on
how to define behavior for
when a list view item gets clicked on.
So I'm just going to search up
handle list view item click Android.
Search that.
Now this first result
here looks good and
notice that it's also
a stack overflow post,
so that means it's probably a common
question amongst other developers too.
So let's click into that.
So the phrasing of the question,
how to handle the click event
in list view in Android sounds
exactly like what we need.
Now I won't bore you with the details
of reading through the question here.
So you can take some time
to read that on your own.
But jumping down to the answer here,
it looks like it's very promising.
So we have the green checkmark,
as well as quite a number of up votes.
Now in this answer code sample,
it says here.
L.V., which stands for the variable name
list view, .set on item click listener.
And then it passes in an on
item click listener object.
And then following that, it says that
when an item in the list view is clicked
on, a new intent is created and
then we started a new activity.
So that method sounds
like it could work.
But to double check that it's
the recommended way to define click
behavior, let's double check in
the official documentation for ListView.
So here I am in the Android developer
documentation in the Develop and
Reference section, looking at
the information about ListViews.
So from here I want to search up
explicitly the set on item click
listener method.
So this is the first one here.
So the description for this method
says that it registers a callback
to be invoked when an item in this
adopter view has been clicked.
That sounds correct.
So when an item is clicked on,
the listener, what's in here,
contains a callback method that will
be called by the Android system.
Now let's click on this
OnItemClickListener
to learn more about it.
So similar to
the OnClickListener interface,
this OnItemClickListener
is also an interface.
Recall that in lesson one we learn
that an interface contains one or
more abstract methods that we can
use to interact with an object, but
we'll need to define and
implement those methods ourselves.
So in this case, we see down here that
the onItemClick listener interface has
one abstract method and
that method is called onItemClick.
So we need to define what
code goes inside this method.
Then the system will then call us back
and execute these instructions that
we've put in when a specific item
in our list view has been touched.
Let's go back to our
stack overflow example.
So here you can see that an on item
click listener object is created when
the developer provided their own logic
within the on item click method.
So the answer to the first question
is that we call the ListView
setOnItemClickListener method.
In that method, we'll take in one input,
which is a listener with the data
type OnItemClickListener.
Now here's some extra information, but
in the documentation you may have
noticed references to an AdapterView.
So why does it keep mentioning
AdapterView when we're clearly looking
at ListView logic?
Remember in lesson two we
learned that a list view
is just one type of adapter view.
Other types of adaptor we've looked
at are GridView and spinners.