Let's check that you understand how
a sequential BFS works by having you
simulate its execution.
Start by recalling
the sequential BFS algorithm.
Let's say you run it on
the following input graph.
The vertices are labeled a through f,
except for one vertex which
is the source labeled s.
For this quiz,
assume that the graph is directed.
Thus, when you hit array over
the edges of a particular vertex v,
you'll look at the outgoing edges.
Let's take an example.
The vertex F has one
outgoing edge from f to s.
So if v were equal to f in this example,
then the loop would only
visit the edge f goes to s.
Here's my question.
Let's call this particular
line of code L1.
That is the line L1 tests if F
is not empty before deciding
whether to continue or
to break out of the loop.
So on the third execution of L1,
meaning the third time you evaluate this
condition, F not equal to the empty set,
what does F contain?
Your answer will be a list of
vertices that you type into this box.
You can just list the vertices by
their labels separated by spaces.
So for example suppose you thought
the answer was the vertices a, b, and c.
Then you type in the box a,
b, and c separated by spaces.
Now one more bit of clarification, there
can be more than one correct solution
because there's an inherent
ambiguity in the algorithm.
In this quiz,
I want to force you to think about that.