Now let me introduce to you
an additional concept on how we can
actually do this warping that
actually tries to avoid some of
these granularity and aliasing and
minification, magnification problems.
And that is using a mesh on an image and
deforming that mesh to
generate the warps.
To demonstrate this let
me use these two images.
We will refer to this as a source and
this as a target.
Some of you may recognize this person,
actually these are images from my
PhD thesis from many many years ago.
And the big difference between these
two images is one neutral expression,
the other one is a smile expression.
Now we are interested in basically
computing the warp between these.
Now, one way to compute a warp would be
basically finding out a corresponding
set of points that are common
in between these two.
To achieve this, many different methods
could be used, I'll talk about one in
a second, and basically, once we find
these corresponding set of points,
we can interpolate between them
using a displacement field.
So first, we want to do is take this
image and basically this or actually
represent this as a mesh, which each
element is basically a set of triangles.
So here I'm basically showing that
I can actually now take this,
put it on top of this.
And this would be rectangles but
what we're interested in is triangles,
each of every one of these squares
would actually be two triangles.
And you, you basically see what I mean
by this, and now basically, I have
regional pixel the values intensities,
and stuff like that, of an image.
Put on each every one
of these triangles.
But we can then do is
basically use an affine model
to transform each triangle
from one to the other.
Of course, we will also want to
generate a similar triangle mesh with
the deformations that
kind of show all of this.
This is my displacement field here,
if you notice that there is
a little bit of, asymmetry.
The eyes get a little smaller, and, this
basically showing most of the motion
is here, and most of the motion is here,
you see a lot of deformation.
Again, deformation is 3D, but
in 2D you can start noticing
this is where the changes are.
So using this now, actually we can
come up with a model of how we would
transform our region points from
here to here to get to this.
And of course, to achieve this, one will
be able you affine model for each and
every one of the triangles then
we'll basically use inverse mapping.
To be able to go from there to here, and
being able to then
generate a warp field.
So now you notice basically
the interpolation resulted in going
from a neutral expression,
to a small expression.
And basically what we did, was we
created a warp from one to the other,
and in this case of course I showed you
all of the in between frames to kind of
make it look like a person
went from neutral to a smile.
Again remember,
we did not have any of those frames,
they were generated
because of the warp field.
Let's look at it one more time