In the paper on caching in the sprite
system, the authors performed a study
of how are files accessed in the file
system used at their department.
That was a production system used for
all types of tasks.
This is what they found.
33% of all of the file
accesses are writes.
What this means is that caching
can be an important mechanism
to improve performance.
Two-thirds of all of the operations
can be improved, but
what about updating this remaining
one third of the accesses?
If we choose a policy
that's write-through where
every single write goes
back to the server,
that means that these one-third
of the file accesses will not be
able to use the fact that there is
a local cache on the client side.
What this means is that caching is okay,
it's a useful policy to use in sprite.
However, using write-through
is not going to be sufficient.
They need to figure out
what else they can do.
So one thing they considered was
how about session semantics.
We don't have to write-through
whenever the file is updated, but
when it's closed.
However, then they looked at these
two numbers and it turns out that
75% of the files are opened for
only half a second, just very briefly.
And that if you look at what is the
number of files that's opened less than
ten seconds,
we go up to 90% of all of the files.
This means that with session semantics,
they will need to perform updates
to the remote server within less than
half a second for many of the files and
then within less than ten seconds for
really most of the files.
So for that reason,
session semantics is really not
going to solve their problems.
They're still going to have too
many interactions with the remote
file server and
this is what they're trying to avoid.
Now next observe something interesting.
They realized that a lot of the data
is deleted within a relatively
short time after it is created.
20 to 30% of the new data is deleted
within 30 seconds in their trace.
And then for 50% of the new data,
they observed that it was deleted
within five minutes of being created.
And they also observed that file
sharing in their system was rare.
That the situations in which multiple
clients are at the same time working on
a file, that really doesn't occur very,
very often.
So because of these observations,
they made first the following decision.
A write back on close, which is
what appears in session semantics.
Well, that's really not necessary.
We don't really have two
sharing situations and
most of the data will
get deleted anyways.
So forcing the data to be written back
to the server when the file is closed,
doesn't seem like it will be useful.
If the file is deleted, who cares.
Now, all of these things are not very
friendly to situations where a file
needs to be accessed concurrently
by multiple clients.
However, the fact that they observe
that file sharing is very rare,
that meant that, that's okay.
There's no need to optimize for this
kind of situation of concurrent access.
However, they did observe
some file sharing.
It's not like their statement is that
there is no file sharing in the system.
So because of that,
they have to make sure that this
distributed file system is useful for
the situation when the files are truly
shared and it somehow must be supported.