So what we're going to to talk about today,
is essentially the surface appearance of objects.
And, what we mean by that is, you know the question is,
if I've got some surface element, and
it's being illuminated by a source, what is it the sensor's going to see.
And the idea is that the image intensity is going to be a function of
a couple of things, one is the local shape, and
we can think of the shape as just being the surface normal of a little patch.
Then there is the, surface reflectance, that is,
what, what are the properties of the surface that affect the light.
And then there is the illumination, that is both the direction and
the type of light that's coming in,
sort of its intensity, maybe its wavelengths, and those kinds of things.
And, the amount of reflection that'll be observed is a function of both,
sort of the incoming direction, and the outgoing direction and
its relationship to the surface, and
we're going to make that a little bit more formal going forward.
So now we're going to do just a tiny bit of, nomenclature with respect to
the physics, it's a little bit confusing and later we'll drop some of it, but
it's, but it's important to get just a little bit of a basis.