Speaking about saving time
through deep searching.
Another powerful trick is to look
at the structure of the problem.
And see if we can decompose it,
to several independent problems.
>> For example, Tasmania is independent
of the rest of the Australia problem.
We can solve it separately.
>> Which takes a level
off our search tree.
In general, suppose we have
a problem with 80 binary variables.
We can divide it into four
problems of 20 variables.
We go from a search space of two to
the 80th to four times two to the 20th.
>> Even better, if we have
a CSP where there are no loops.
We can solve the problem in OND squared
time, instead of O, D to the N.
>> How?
>> We pick any variable to
be the root of the tree, and
choose an ordering of the variables.
Such that, each variable appears
after it's parent in the tree.
We then start at the end and
make each parent arc consistent.
Going up the tree,
until we get to the top.
>> What if that is not possible?
>> Then we report
failure of the problem.
>> Okay, what's next?
>> It's simple,
we start at the top of the tree and
pick any assignment available.
Going back down the tree,
until we get to the end.
Since the trees are consistent,
any of the variable assignments
will solve the problem.
>> How fast is this process?
O of ND squared, where N is
the number of variables again,
and D is the size of the domain.
>> So this trick really helps out
with the speed of finding a solution.
But what if the constraint
graph really isn't a tree?
>> Well, sometimes you can condition
a problem by assigning values to
some variables.
And change the constraint
graph into a tree.
>> Like with our Australia
coloring example.
If we assign a value to
South Australia first, and
remove that value from
the possibilities of its neighbors.
Then the problem becomes a tree,
and we can use our fast
method to solve the problem.
>> Precisely.