So, how do we compute disparity?
Let's take the simple example here and
we know disparity is, in essence,
the difference of Xr and Xl.
We need correspondence.
It, basically means is,
in both those images, I need to
know exactly the locations Xr and
it's the same point that should
be visible in the other image.
In essence,
what we need is each pixel, or
any pixel, has to be corresponding to
the other pixel in the left image.
So, any point that's in the right one
should also be appearing in the left
one.
Now of course,
we have learned how to do feature
matching at stuff like that already.
Of course, you can imagine that any
point I find in the right image,
I can search for it and
match for it in the left image.
And, many different
methods we have looked at,
including even just simple correlation
methods, and normalized corel,
cross-correlation methods that we've
looked at, could be used to find
a feature in one image and find that
same feature by doing again as I said,
you know,
cross-correlation does is basically,
a inner product or dot product, and
it will find the most similar pixels.
Computationally, you can imagine
this gets to be pretty complicated.
Similarly, the other method we can
actually do is sum of squared difference
measure errors take any pixel region and
neighborhoods.
Remember, the kinds of stuff we've
looked at already when we've talked
about just neighborhoods, and pixels and
how to do kinds of filtering and
comparisons.
Well, that all could be applied here.
But, you can imagine, this is going to
get pretty complicated if I have to do
pixel by pixel region by region matching
and also perhaps a different scales.
To help us,
we can actually rely on something
called the epipolar constraint.
Basically, that says is, you don't
need to search the whole 2D image.
When I actually found something, I want
to match to from the left to the right.
Basically, what it does,
is it reduces the search space
to one dimensional line.
Let me show you what that means, but
the idea really remains is in this case,
there is no change in the y-axis.
So, why should I search for
everything that is in this
point across the whole image?
I should search for
it just across that line.
Remember the interesting things
about stereo imaging, right?
Both eyes are on the same y-axis,
most of the time we want to use that
constraint for two cameras on,
basically being at the same axis.