Now it's your turn to set up a goal for
your app.
You do that in the admin dashboard.
Go to Goals and
then you create a new goal.
Make sure your app is sending
the hits Analytics needs.
To figure out if the goal is being met.
And use it in a way that you know that
the goal is going to be satisfied.
And you shouldn't need to re-deploy
the app after you set up the goal.
So I found in the real time
screen of Analytics Dashboard,
I did not see the goals being converted.
So you're just going to have to be
patient, and check back in your
Analytics Dashboard after some amount of
time, to see that the goals were met.
And what kind of goal did you create?
Did you create a destination goal?
Duration goal?
A screens per session goal?
For an event goal.
So, I want you to carry on going
on through this course, and
checking back periodically
in your dashboard
to see your goal conversion
data when it comes in.
I recommend that you don't wait for it.