Awesome.
Your work here is done.
Feel free to close your text editor, and
in your VM type exit to leave the shell.
And vagrant halt to shut down the VM.
It's important to remember that exit
leaves the VM but doesn't shut it down.
Having a VM is like running two
computers on the same machine.
It's hard work and can be tough on
your computer's battery and speed, so
it's a good idea to shut it
down every once in a while.
You don't have to shut it down
every time you leave your computer.
But try to remember to run bigger and
halt, when you're done working for
the day.
You've now seen how to use
the shared folder in your Linux VM.
It's all right if you're not feeling
super confident in all the commands
you've seen in this lesson.
You will learn more about how to
navigate the Unix command line
in the next lesson.