So here's the basic idea, all right?
Two slightly different images.
These are two stereo animations taken from this website listed here
where we just alternate showing you the left image and the right image.
Already, if you just take a look at the fence post here,
you can see that these pictures were lined up in such a way
that the fence post was sort of right at the same point in the two pictures.
And you can see that the stuff that's in front seems to be going that way,
stuff in the back goes that way and then back again.
All right.
Or you can switch them, but the idea is that stuff in front of
what you're verged at moves in one direction and the stuff behind it goes back.
We'll actually see that when we talk about the ordering constraint two
lessons from now.
Here's a cool one that was done of somebody diving into a pool.
And you can see he adjusted the images, so
that at the depth of where the swimmer is the two images are exactly lined up.
So the bubbles, the splash moves in one direction and
I love that the shadows on the bottom of the pool move in the other direction.
So the basic idea is that from two different views from how they move,
you get a sense of what their depth is.