Now to ask these questions, I want to introduce you to someone.
This is Oliver.
He's the Director of Mobile here at Udacity.
Oliver has an illustrious background.
He built an app, that was number one in the App Store in 2009.
Here, we've caught him in the middle of an interview with a job candidate.
Let's see what he asks.
>> I'd love to hear about any apps you've built using Swift.
If you got any demos or examples of any apps, or
if you've even got any code to show me, that would be fantastic.
>> So at this point, you probably haven't built a complete app using Swift.
That's okay, because that's what we are here to learn.
By the end of this course, however.
You will have a really impressive first app,
that will be great to showcase in an interview.
We will hear from Oliver several times during this course.
For now, let's start making our app by downloading Xcode.