Just like we did in the example, we're
going to start by rearranging the order of
the terms in this expression, so the terms
with the same variable are next to one
another. Great, now, we have 7x-10x+5y+3y.
The next step is to add together the
coefficients of the like terms. Great, so
now we have -3x, since 7-10 is negative
three and the variable there was x, plus
8y, since 5+3 is eight. If we wanted to
make this a little bit prettier, since we
have a negative sign at the front, we
could because of the commutative property,
rearrange the order of the terms one more
time. So, I personally prefer to write it
this way, 8y-3x. So this is our new
version of the expression on the left.
It's almost hard to tell from looking at
these two expressions that they're
actually equal to each other, but that
just shows you how powerful combining like
terms is. We end up with an expression
that's much nicer to look at and much
easier to use.