As you probably realized
a few videos ago,
or maybe even longer,
XHRs are really annoying.
Even the simplest use case
is fairly verbose, and
it only gets worse as you address edge
cases and browser compatibility issues.
Fetching resources really
just shouldn't be this hard.
Luckily there's a new API that
simplifies XHRs, the fetch API.
Currently it's natively
supported by Chrome, Firefox,
Opera and Android browsers.
Its support is growing, and
it's incredibly useful,
also it's built on native promises.
This is going to be a two step quiz.
On the first part you're going to
re-factor GET with the Fetch API and
in the second part, you're going to be
creating a new wrapper called getJSON.
getJSON should return a Promise and
it should return a promise,
that's two steps.
The first part should be getting the URL
and use the get method for that.
And the second part should be
parsing the JSON response.
I want you test getJSON by
adding a search header in
counsole.longing the parse of JSON.
When you do so, you should see an object
with search data appear on the console.
If there is an error, catch it.
Pass unknown as the search header and
then counsel.log the error.
As always see the instructor notes for
more information and good luck.