This flight picker app was annoying.
I was tapping way too much
to pick flight dates.
This site is obviously using
the wrong kinds of inputs.
There's gotta be a better way.
So for this quiz,
I want you to think about the types of
inputs you're inflicting
upon your users.
So you don't make the same mistakes
that I did when I built this.
Here are two HTML inputs.
The first input is for date and
the second one is for time.
What types of inputs make the most
sense for these two inputs?
Check out the link in the instructor
notes to a list of inputs
on the Mozilla Developer Network.
Do some research, and when you're done,
type your answers into these boxes.