As you might expect, Android stores
your persistent data in the file system.
These files can be stored in internal
storage that is private to your app.
They can also be stored and
shared or external storage.
On older Android devices,
this shared storage was actually
on an external memory card.
Today most Android devices only emulate
this card, so that there is the shared
external storage apps need
available on the device.
Some Android devices have
emulated shared storage and
secondary external storage.
Android 4.4 KitKat added an API to
allow developers to access this
secondary external storage.
We're going to focus on
internal storage in this class.
Check the instructor notes to learn
more about Android storage locations.
As I mentioned before, Android
persists data into the file system.
It does provide two
functional layers on top of
the file system in the form of
SharedPreferences and SQLite.
The SharedPreferences class provide
the general framework that allows you to
save and retrieve persistent key
value pairs of primitive data types,
such as booleans, floats,
ints, longs and strings.
SharedPreferences is used by the Android
preference activity to store our
settings data such as the location.
>> An SQLI database or
any relational database stores and
organizes all its data in tables.
Each table is made up of rows and
columns.
Each row being the data record or entry,
and the columns represent the data
fields that make up those records.
When you decide to use a database,
you should think of how many tables
you need to represent your data.
And what each table will
contain in terms of columns.
Once you have a design for
your database,
you can then create those tables.
And upon those tables you can create,
remove, update, or delete data.
These four operations are usually
referred to as CRUD, and
any database system
should support all four.
Any operation in an SQL database
is executed using SQL queries.
Retrieving data operations
are done using a select query.
For example, this query would select
all the orders that were made by
any person with the last name Wales.
Almost every popular Android
app uses an SQLite database.
And to perform any database
operations from our Android code,
you'll have to generate
the appropriate SQL queries.
So if you're unfamiliar with relational
databases or how to create SQL queries,
check out the links in the instructor
notes below, before you proceed.