The first part of the process
is continuous integration,
an automated process of getting changes
into existing codebases and building and
running tests.
The goal's not to create
a backlog when you go to deploy.
A boring deployment would
be deemed a success.
No surprises is a good thing.
When embarking on changing and
updating code, a developer takes a copy
of the current code base to work from.
As other developers make changes
to the source code repository,
the local copy gradually ceases
to reflect the repository code.
Not only can existing codebase change,
but
new code can be added as
well as new libraries and
other resources that create
dependencies and potential conflicts.
So, what's the best practices
to prevent this from happening?
You want to maintain a code repository.
Automate the build.
Test the build.
Commit your changes often.
Build each commit.
If it breaks, fix it right away,
while it's fresh in everyone's mind.
And when possible, test from a clone
of the production environment.
While most of these practices
are automatable by tools,
committing code is
still a manual process.
Developers have to adopt this
approach for it to work.
If someone will commit their
changes only once a month,
it's going to create problems,
a human problem.