All right, you're done.
Let's take a look at my solution.
First, we add the permission for
ACCESS_NETWORK_STATE to the manifest.
Then we add a no_network string
to the strings .xml file.
As I suggested, in the utility class
we add an isNetworkAvailable function.
That uses that connectivity service to
return the active network information.
Then, I added a function to
handle updating the empty view,
which we'll call from on load finish.
Finally, we call this function
from on load finished.
Let's test it.
Remember how we do this.
We go to our emulator.
We uninstall the app.
Then we set the emulator
into airplane mode.
At this point,
let's launch and run the app.
And now we get a far better message.
No weather information available,
the network is not available
to fetch weather data.
Once again, if we switch off of airplane
mode, it'll automatically go and
run our sync adapter.