A, a simple example is shown here.
Here is a sphere, you could sort of tell that it's a sphere, right?
It falls of down here so we're looking straight down.
With five different illuminations.
When we do photometric stereo on that, remember we can recover both surface
normal and the albedo, and that's what this looks like here, right?
So the albedo, you can see that it recovered,
the fact that it's got these four quadrants.
So even though this thing falls off slowly,
it knows that it's all the same albedo.
And then this is the estimated of the surface normals.
And so this is what's sometimes called the needle diagram, where you're
looking at where the needles are pointing, that's the surface normal.
Now you can actually do this somewhat for real.
So, here's an example where there are four input images, so
the lighting is coming from different directions, right?
You can see here, you get different kind of shading, right?
And it recovers both the albedo, which is sort of the paint, the color.
And you can see that it actually knows that there are these stripes on
there along with the surface normals.
So it recovered the shape.
In fact, there's a really cool app you can download from this
company called trimensional.com, and this is not a commercial endorsement.
It's just a Georgia Tech endorsement.
This was an app put together by Grant Schindler where you basically,
I don't know if he's got it on Androids now as well but
certainly at the time it was on iPhones.
And you take pictures from different locations and
it uses the light to illuminate it.
And it does a surface reconstruction.
All right?
And it works pretty cool and download it and I think it's it might be free.
I know it might be a dollar, maybe it's four.
Whatever it is, if you, if you buy it, grant, send me