Here's a website that you'll be
improving at the end of this lesson.
And like before, there's a slight
chance that what you'll see
may look slightly different than this,
and
that's only because we might tweak it
between now and when you take the class.
Anyway, you can find a link to a live
version of this in the instructor notes.
What I really want you to do
though is play around with it.
Start clicking through,
start giving it a shot, and
start thinking about what you
would want to do to improve it.
This is another quiz where
you'll just be brainstorming.
I want you to think about what areas for
improvement that you
can find in this form.
How would you make it faster?
How would you make it simpler?
And once you've thought about it,
check this box to continue.