For the, for the collector, when you admit, so you admit object, but then when
you get them you have to cast them to the appropriate objects that you want.
[CROSSTALK] If you use, if you use-
>> Yes, that's right. >> Use the value method.
>> Mm-hm, mm-hm. >> So then, and so-
>> And I think like.
>> Does that method actually just returns a based Java object?
And what's the-
>> There is some method, there are some methods that for
example if you know it is a that some is something >> Yeah sure.
>> Those things are there, but you, you are doing your own objects then you
should know what you should cast it out as.
>> But if you just use get value it just like.
>> Mm-hm. Then you would just cast it.
>> Okay.
>> Because and that could be anything.
>> Makes it more than a life form so he can pass any objects.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So if anybody do that.