Let's practice. Open the Google spreadsheet that's linked in instructor
notes. I like to snowboard, [NOISE] and I want to know
how much it snowed over the last three seasons in
Tahoe so that I can get a feel for how much
it'll snow this season. Every time it snowed, I listed
the inches of snowfall and the date. So when you
open the spreadsheet you should see three columns of data.
One for each season. We want to know the total amount
of snowfall that occurred each season. When we're doing
any type of calculation in a spreadsheet, we start with
an equal sign. In this case, we want to sum
up all the numbers in each column. So I'll write
equals sum, and then the name of the start
cell, colon, and then the name of the end cell.
This colon means that we sum all the numbers in
between the start cell and the end cell. And remember,
you've already learned how we denote the names of each cell. So, if we want
to know how much it snowed in season one, what should we put here, and here?