Awesome.
We've identified three places,
where app design could use
a high fidelity code prototype.
You may have found one,
many, or none of these.
First, as James said,
our apps new event functionality
could be usefully prototyped.
This part of the app uses user input,
and could behave in a couple of ways.
When a user presses the FAB to create
an event, some animation happens,
which we could ask a designer about.
And then again,
once the event is filled out and
saved, something happens to transition
the user back to the main screen.
We need to define these animations,
as well as how the event goes
into the list of events.
Does it always go in at the top?
Does it slide in
somewhere along the way?
Does that addition to the list
get animated in any way?
These are important questions to answer.
Secondly, our overview page
could use a code prototype.
Right now, we have sort of a placeholder
graphic that shows completed tasks
versus created tasks
versus snooze tasks.
But this graphic would presumably
change when a user actually makes, and
modifies, and completes tasks.
What would that look like?
We'll need to find that out over time.
Finally, many calendar and to do
list apps rely on notifications for
communicating with users, when the app
is not the active app on their device.
What will these notifications look like,
and when will they be triggered?
Code prototypes could help us answer
that question using user research.
The second and third options are
defiantly things that we would want to
work on, after building a minimal
viable product for our app.
The new event however,
is central functionality and
should be built out immediately.