So we talked about removing noise using a filter,
let's see how well that really works.
Let us load a perfectly good image.
Spoil it by adding some noise.
I should really name this sigma to avoid confusion later.
Finally, we know how to create a Gaussian filter.
We define a size and a sigma.
And then we can use the fspecial function from the image package.
So load up the package first.
And then create the filter.
Now, we can apply this filter to remove noise.
Note the order of parameters in imfilter.
First is the image and second is the filter.
Notice how the filter has smoothed, or rather, blurred the image.
The fine particle like appearance of the noise is now smudged.
But the filter has also affected the original image a great deal.
So, noise removal is no magic.
You don't get back exactly what you started with.
Visually, it might not seem very impressive, but
image processing routines further down the road
behave quite differently given a noisy image versus a smooth image.
Go ahead and run this code yourself.
Try out different parameters for noise generation and smoothing.