Okay, let's take a look at the code.
It's all in main activity.
Here the imports that we need for
the DataLayer, the TagManager, and
here's the updated version of
the showDailySpecial method.
We get the pop-up menu, we use the
food_prefs_menu, that's already defined,
to Show the menu of food preferences.
We set the on click action for
the pop up menu
to call the new method that puts
the food preference in the data layer,
and then it calls a method to start
the ShowDailySpecial activity.
And then we show the pop up menu.
And then here's the method to
get the food preference and
save it in the data layer.
We'll get the Tag Manager instance,
we get the data layer, and
then, depending on which
menu item was selected,
we push the appropriate value into
the data layer, keyed by food_pref.
There's vegan, vegetarian,
fish, and so on.
And then here's a method that simply
starts the ShowDailySpecial activity.
Notice that we don't pass
the food preference here,
because the activity's actually
going to get it out of the data layer.