You may have noticed that the URIs
you defined to access data
all look pretty similar, with the same
starting scheme and authority.
And it's good practice to store any
URI components that you commonly use
as constants in the contract class.
Remember, the contract is designed to
keep track of constants that will help
you access data in a given database.
So we'll add to it by including
the most commonly used URIs and paths.
As we've seen, to access data
from the task content provider
you needed to define the following URIs.
One for the task directory,
and one for a single task.
And they're comprised of a few parts.
After the scheme,
there's the content authority which is
a unique reference to the provider.
And all of the URIs that
our provider recognizes
start with these two pieces as a base.
So in the task contract well want to
define the combination as one constant
called the base content URI which is
the scheme and the authority together.
After that, is a path, and
paths point to a specific table or file.
And finally, inside your task entry
class, you'll want to have a constant
for the most specific content URI
that combines all of these elements.
So let's add these to the contract.
So let's open our task contract and
add our constants.
Let's start with the content authority,
which is a string.
This is the same authority that
you defined in your Android
manifest file earlier.
So it's actually a good idea to copy and
paste it from there.
Next we create the base content URI and
import URI.
This is an unchanging URI
that will be the start
of all the URIs we'll be
using to access our provider.
It's the content scheme plus
the authority we just defined.
Then, let's include a string for
accessing our tasks table specifically.
This is a path constant named path tasks
that will be appended to
the base content URI.
If our provider kept track
of multiple tables of data,
we would include multiple
corresponding path constants here.
Finally, inside this task entry class
in the contract, which keeps track of
the data that a task entry contains,
you should create a complete URI for
these entries as a constant
called Content URI.
The buildUpon and
appendPath methods append our tasks
path to the end of the base content URI.
So this final content URI will
include the scheme, the authority, and
our tasks path.
And now it will be simple to
refer to these URIs again and
again to access data.