So, next part is, warping.
If you noticed again, in the earlier example I had shown you, not only are these
images aligned, they need to be warped a little bit to register them on top of
each other, so then actually when certain regions are the same,
the images will also be kind of, appear to have similar, detail.
So, here basically kind of shows is that images are warped, so these were,
of course, rectangular images, before aligning them to various types of things,
I need to warp this image, this image, this image, and
this image, so then they'll register on top of each other.
So, let's look at this warping example, I am showing one frame.
In the next one, if I was to put them top of each other, while some parts may
align, if you notice there's still lot of blurriness going on,
none of the crowd is visible, so, to achieve this, I would have to take one of
the images and kind of put a warp on it to register to the first image.
So in this case, basically I need to find, what is the between points here
to there, so, if you notice this person's head is here on the other example, so
I need to figure out how to warp it, similarly, this person here,
this person here, and again, you can see the same thing for this building here.
They're all kind of misaligned here, and
I need to find these warp fields, this corner here with the same,
this corner here, this building is also in between two images.
So I need to kind, a, and complete warp field between these two and use that to
align the two images together, and here I basically show you how we did this.
After I do the alignment, if you notice there's no more ghosting,
that's what we want to do.
Let me show them to you again.
This is before warp.
Post warp.
And that's the final result after we've done all the warping between the two
images, everything is registered.