>> This time, I'm going to be talking
with our startups about design sprints.
I'm back here again with Pete and Pete,
could you tell me a little bit
about design sprints at Optimizely?
And so first, I guess does
Optimizely use design sprints?
>> So we're an agile shop, which means
we use sprints for not only design, but
also product and engineering as well and
that means that we all get
together every two weeks.
And we talk about what we
did in the past two weeks.
We plan what we're going to do
the following two weeks and
do a bit of a retrospective and
that goes for our design teams,
we have sort of two big
parts of our design team.
We have our product design team and
they focus on our user experience.
They actually design the products we
build and we have our communication
design team and they design our sales
collateral, our marketing collateral and
sort of all of the branding and imagery
that we use to convey Optimizely brand.
They both use agile, as well.
>> Great.
How does Optimizely actually
do user testing for its users?
>> Good question.
So as you might expect, we do run
a lot of AB tests on our own website.
We use our product to use that,
of course.
>> [LAUGH]
>> But that's not the whole picture,
it never is the whole picture.
It's one aspect of understanding your
customers, but it's not the end all be
all and so we try to spend a lot
of time with our customers.
We have a program we call OPS,
Optimizely Promoter System.
Where we try to measure how likely
our customers are to recommend our
product to their colleagues and then
we allow them to give us a bit of text
feedback on why they would or
why they wouldn't and we then
follow up with the detractors and
try to understand what's going on there.
That's another venue for
customer feedback.
We also have a great user research
team who will bring in customers, so
we can watch them use our products.
Ask them questions,
put prototypes in front of them.
So I'm really proud of the way we've
tried to integrate the customer into our
development process and I think it
comes from our early days when we were,
Dan and I were the engineers.
We were the designers,
we were the sales people and
we were sort of doing all of that.
And that's really hard to do, but
the beauty of it is that your customer
engineer feedback cycle is zero.
>> Yeah.
>> And that's I think,
a really powerful thing about
an engineering founder of a company.
>> You can be so close to the source and
iterate so quickly.
>> That's right,
you can iterate instantaneously.
>> Yeah, sounds good.