Much of the background that you'll need to
know, is covered in this introductory lesson and
the review lessons taught by Charlie Brubaker. However,
to get the full benefit of this course, you
should have a strong undergraduate background in computer
systems and networks. With that in mind, let's
get started with our review and load some
of the operating systems basics into our collective memories.
I've intentionally structured this lesson to be quiz-heavy, since most
of the background material should be already familiar to you. And
hopefully that format that I'm going to use, we'll find this
to be a more fun way to jog our collective memories.