Let's construct the route for
our new menu item.
Now when i visit slash restaurant and
pass in an integer and then slash new.
This integer will get passed in as
the restaurant ID for the new menu item
function and successfully return
that task one is complete.
The edit menu item takes
in two parameters, so
we need to make sure that our
route also has two parameters.
The restaurant ID and the menu ID.
And then slash at it.
Now we'll see that this page also works.
Similarly to the edit route the delete
route looks just about the same.
Except that it has slash delete.
Now our final route is also working.
The solutions for this challenge
are available in the instructor notes.