As we discussed earlier,
a string is a sequence of characters.
By now, you seen a few strings and
other parts of this curriculum.
You seen them passes arguments
to print statements and
you seen them to find as variables and
also constants.
Now, we're going to dive deeper into
how strings are implemented and
how they're used.
Let's start with initialization.
Click Next to continue forward.
We often initialize strings
using string literals,
which are a series of characters
between double quotation marks.
Here we've defined a string
constant by using the word let,
and then the consonants name, which is
theTruth followed by a string literal.
Now technically, a string doesn't
have to have any characters.
You can also initialize
an empty string like this.
Or you could use string followed
by an empty set of parenthesis and
it'll also create an empty string.
Are you following along
in the playground?
It's time to click Next and move on.
[BLANK_AUDIO]