In both formats,
the page offset is six bits.
That means that each of the pages
is 2 to the 6, that's 64 bytes.
In the first address format in the case
of the single-level page table,
six bits are used for
the virtual page number.
That means that there will
be a total of 2 to the 6, so
64 different virtual pages and
in a single-level page table design,
we have to have an entry for
every single virtual page number, so
there will be a total of 64 elements.
In the second address format,
the first two bits are used as an index
into the outer page table, so
the page table directory, and
the inner four bits are used as
an index into the inner page tables.
But, take a look at this address format,
these two bits, so
the outer page table entries,
will address 2 to the 10,
4 plus 6 virtual addresses from
the virtual address space.
That means that every single element
of the outer page table can be used
to hold the translations for
one kilobyte of the virtual addresses.
Given that the process is such
that only the first two and
the last one kilobyte of the virtual
address space are allocated.
That means that one of the entries
in the outer page table
will not really need to be populated
with a corresponding inner page table.
So, we can save the memory that's
required for that inner page table.
Now, the inner page table is
the reuse of four bit index to
index into the inner page table, that
means that, that will have 16 entries,
every single one of the inner
page tables will hold 16 entries.
So therefore, the total number
of entries that are needed
across the remaining inner
page tables will be 48.
So, we reduce the page
table size by 25% by
choosing this multi-level page table
format in this particular example