So I see that one layer is sort of computing the the individual.
>> Tweet.
>> Tweet value on a, on a particular dimension.
>> Mm-hm. >> Panic dimension or misinformation dimension.
>> I mean they, they may not be compared this way.
>> Yeah. >> I mean, I inc,
this kind of gives me a model design, that's all it is.
[LAUGH] Yeah. >> In, in this, in this sample topology, and
then the second one sort of aggregates them for each tweet.
>> Mm-hm. >> And then the third one computes some statistic.
>> Oral statistics, globally.
>> Is this a, a reasonable way to approach topography design or-
>> Yeah, yeah this is a way to reasonable to,
I mean this is a reasonable way to approach topography.
I mean typically people, the way you do is like, you kind of split the work.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And do some local, what do you call simple first stage filtering,
like more local joining or whatever it is.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Then finally, you can find like so
that is typically, this is the final application, right?
Like, that is, typically all the [INAUDIBLE] tend to do.
Mostly like sometimes, like, [INAUDIBLE] happens at this stage, then followed by
some kind of counting happens, partially counts happen this stage,
then the global aggregations, analytics, happen at third stage, right?
>> Right. >> So, yeah, so that is a typical, design of a [INAUDIBLE]