So now let me show you a simple example
of combining two images that have
a different perspective, that is,
they're actually taken at two different
viewpoints, but with some overlap.
And how we can use those two images and
go through the whole pipeline of finding
the right features and matching them and
using that to align and create a simple
panorama, just from two images.
Of course, we start off by first loading
in numpy and copy, I'll open CV.
I'm going to load two images.
I'm going to load the Einstein image and
then I'm going to load the da Vinci
image I'm going to print some
information about these two images.
And of course,
also show the original images.
So to help the computation,
I'm going to convert these images,
which are in color into grey scale.
That of course,
helps with your computation time.
And of course, I should be able to
now find the features in a much more
efficient manner here.
So we are going to do that.
We applied this to both the first
image and the second image.
So here is this line of
code here is initializing
the ability to find features in images.
Here we're actually going to use the ORB
function to be able to find images
features and images.
There is another method available
in a different version for OpenCV,
which actually uses SIFT, the algorithm
that we have discussed in detail.
That's available in
a different version of OpenCV,
that's not available in this
version that I'm using.
Both of them actually give you feature
matching that actually can be used for
this application that
we're interested in.
So, after we've initialized an dete,
feature detector,
let's start using that approach or
this method to identify and
locate keypoints and
then use those to match them.
So here in these two lines basically,
using orb.
We have detected and computed
features for image one and image two,
we put them in these two
different data structures.
Here, I can actually also go ahead and
print them out to see what these things
look like in terms of what
feature points are extracted.
These two lines of code are used to
actually now draw circles around those
keypoints.
This is a good debugging tool, it'll
tell us more about how we can actually
visualize where those keypoints are.
And of course,
then we think to display them.
So by using a BFMatcher function,
I'm going to now start get ready to do
some simple matching of these features.
We're going to create two sequences
of corresponding match points and
then look through the whole process and
find matching feature points that
we've identified using
the orb feature detector.
Here basically,
now those are accumulated into
the two different points arrays.
And then using that,
we will compute the homography for
both points two and point t.
And of course, here,
we're using the RANSAC algorithm,
which I've also talked
about in this lecture.
After this we get the homography matrix,
we'll print that out to
see what it looks like.
Finally, in this piece of code,
we are going to create a panorama.
We are going to take
the homography matrix and
actually use that to generate
a shape of the panorama
which is where we can actually
project all of the small images into.
And using that, warp the images apply
the transformations that we have
actually now computed.
Remember, the homography matrix is here,
which can be applied to
the whole size of the image.
And using that, we will actually
now generate a new image and
copy information into that image that
actually has all the panoramic pixels.
And of course, showcase this result.
Let's look at the solutions.
Couple of things to just
help us debug things.
We have two images,
both of them are the same size.
We actually used the orb detector
to find 500 keypoints each in one
of the images.
Then we basically went ahead and
found matches,
305 matches were found of the 500
keypoints in both of them.
Using those matches we actually
computed The homography of
the transformation matrix.
This is now just displaying the images,
so this was the first image.
The second image.
The circles here show where
the keypoints were found using the orb
detector in the first image.
And the circles here, showcase
all of the interesting points or
keypoints found in the second image.
Notice again, this is the overlapping
part and this is the final panorama,
which is actually now, if you notice
combining these two images here.
In this image or in this code,
we haven't done anything about accurate
blending of this kinds of stuff.
So, if you pay attention and look hard,
you might be able to find a seam.
And of course, it's the one seam here.
Again, remember all the stuff we've
talked about with blending and
cuts that could be used
to make this better.