Not just to, actually, for those of you
looking at other ways of doing things,
let me actually show you something well,
relatively fun and interesting.
Here's a video of a person who
actually then figured out that if you,
if you look at a chicken, chickens have
an ability to keep their head stable.
Here, if you notice,
he's moving the chicken around, but
the head is as stable as possible.
Right?
This is not made up video,
this is original,
if you have access to chickens,
you can try to do this yourselves.
But you'll notice the chickens have
an ability to keep their heads
really stable.
Of course this whole idea was made into
a little bit more craziness by this
person here, who basically then kind
of claims to have made this mount for
a chicken and used that to generate
a stable camera or steadicam.
Ok well, to be honest, this is
a fake ad for a new LG camera, but
it's kind of interesting to note
that this, chickens do have a way of
keeping their necks stable and in fact,
more and more fun things have been done.
This, I'm just showing ti to you,
just to be funny.