Now that you've gotten overdraw under
control, it's time to bubble up a bit
and start looking at the CPU
portion of the rendering pipeline.
In order to draw something on
the screen, Android generally needs to
convert that high-level XML into
something that the GPU can accept and
use to render to the screen.
This is done with the help of a internal
Android object called a display list.
A display list basically holds all
the information needed to render a view
on the GPU.
It contains a list of any GPU
resident assets that might be needed,
as well as a list of commands to execute
with OpenGL in order to render it.
The first time a view
needs to be rendered,
a display list will be created for it.
And when we need to render that view to
the screen, we execute that display list
by submitting its drawing
commands to the GPU.
If we want to render that view in
the future again, like if its position
changed on screen, we simply need
to execute that display list again.
However, in the future, if some
visual part of this view changes,
the previous display list
may no longer be valid.
As such, we'll need to
recreate the display list and
then re-execute them
to update the screen.
Now, remember this.
Anytime the drawing content of your
view changes, it will repeat the process
of recreating the display list and then
re-executing it to get it to the screen.
The performance of these
operations varies,
depending on how complex
your view actually is.
And depending on the type
of visual change,
there's other impacts on
the rendering pipeline as well.
For example, let's say that a text
box suddenly doubles in size,
causing the parent container to
reposition other sibling views
before updating its own size.
In this case, we've updated one view and
it cascaded to other work
that needed to be done.
These types of visual changes require
additional stages of the rendering
pipeline to occur.
See, when the sizing
of your view changes,
the measure phase will be kicked off.
And it will walk through
your view hierarchy,
asking each view what its new sizes are.
Basically, this happens anytime you
change the size of a view, for example,
padding, drawable size, set text's
scale, width, height, et cetera.
And if you change the position of
things or call request layout, or
a view group repositions its children,
then the layout phase will kick off,
traversing the hierarchy and determining
where all the new locations of
the objects should
actually be on the screen.
Now, the Android runner
system is really,
really efficient at handling the record
and execute phases of the pipeline.
And unless you're doing something
crazy with custom views, or
suddenly a ton of views
are getting drawn at once,
these shouldn't account for
much of your frame time.
Measure and layout phases are also
pretty performant, but are more prone to
run into performance problems when
your view hierarchy gets out of hand.
See, the time taken to execute these
functions is proportional to the amount
of nodes in your view hierarchy that
have to be processed as a result.
The more views that this system has
to touch, the longer it takes, and
some views may have worse
overhead than others.
And the number one overhead for this
operation is having a lot of redundant
unneeded views lying around
in your view hierarchy.
See, these views don't visually
contribute to the final scene, and
generally end up just eating up
your performance when a measure or
layout phase actually kicks off.
Thankfully, there's a great tool
available to help you find and
fix these rogue views
called Hierarchy Viewer.
Let's take a look.