Before we talk about the correctness
of the mutual exclusion,
let's take a look at
the efficiency factor.
So this goto spin statement, as long as
the lock is not free, this means that
this cycle will repeatedly be executed
and this will waste CPU resources.
Therefore, from efficiency standpoint,
this is not an efficient implementation.
It's inefficient.
But efficiency aside,
this solution is also incorrect.
In an environment where we have multiple
threads that execute concurrently, or
multiple processes,
it is possible that more than one thread
will see at the same
time that lock is free.
And they will move on to
perform this lock equal busy
operation at the same time.
Only one thread will actually set
the lock value to busy correctly.
The other one will simply override
it and will then proceed.
It will think that it has
correctly acquired the lock.
So as a result, both processes or
both threads can end up in the critical
section and that clearly is incorrect.