The answer is one-third.
Let's first consider the probability
that a fixed cycle say,
this one illustrated here
is in the permutation.
The probability that this first
edge here is made is one-hundredth.
Some edge has to come out of 55 and
all 100 destinations are equally likely.
Next, we consider the probability that
this next edge in the cycle is made.
57 already has an edge going
in from the first edge, so
we can't have a self loop here.
That leaves only 99 destinations to
choose from, all equally likely.
So there's a 1 in 99 chance that
we pick 58 and we applied the same
logic to this last edge here to give
us another factor of one over 98.
Overall then, this gives the probability
that any fixed recycle will
exist in a random permutation.
We can also think of this as
a random variable that is one,
if the cycle is in the permutation and
zero, otherwise.
Therefore, this is
the expected number of times
that this particular 3-cycle
will occur in a permutation.
Well, to calculate the expected
number of 3-cycles overall,
we just need to sum up this quantity for
all possible 3-cycles.
All of their expectations
will be the same, so
it becomes just a matter
of counting them.
Counting 3-cycles is the same as
counting permutations of length three,
except that this overcounts
by a factor of three,
because the starting point is arbitrary.
There are 100 ways to choose the first
element, 99 the second, 98 the third.
But in counting this way,
we counted every 3-cycles three times.
Once for each possible starting point.
Of course, in this calculation,
everything cancels out, except for
the 3 and we get one-third for
the answer.
This argument is actually much
more general than the question.
Note that the fact that we were using
100 vertices didn't show up anywhere in
the answer.
And in fact, we can replace
the 100 with some arbitrary n and
we get the exact same answer.
The cancellation happens
in exactly the same way.
And in fact,
we can also replace the 3 with k.
The exact same cancellation
will occur and
we get an expected number of
1 over k cycles of length k.