So what is a video texture?
Let's look at a few instances to
convince us of what the concept of video
texture and videos itself provide.
So, if we look at static
images like this.
Here you can basically
see that there are static
images of four relatively dynamic scene.
A flag here, most probably is fluttering
and this is just one snapshot of it.
Right?
Now you can see the flag, I mean,
you can pretty much perceive that it
must be moving and here is a candle.
Of course,
we know candles are always flickering.
So this is a static version of this.
Looking at these two children on
a swing set, you pretty much again know
that this must be a dynamic scene,
where the children are swinging and we
basically have captured them on snapshot
and another example of these balloons.
And of course, if you,
you don't have to imagine much, but
you know that when it might be
fluttering these types of things.
Each and everyone of them,
there is some sort of motion going on.
And still pictures,
of course are capturing it, but
that's the extent of what they do.
That is they just capture
one moment of it.
Again, photographic value
was they're valuable, but
they don't actually show
the dynamics of the scene.
Video on the other hand can
actually show the dynamics, right?
Now, I can see everything in terms of
what the flickering is going on for
the flame the flame for the flag,
the balloons and the children's swings.
But of course, we notice one thing.
It has a very well defined beginning and
end.
As soon as the motion has ended,
the video came to a stop.
I want to be able to
kind of see more of it.
Well, and I want to be able
to film more time to it.
So here is what basically we can do it
by basically creating a video loop.
So looping video basically
takes this video,
which ends after a certain time here and
loops it again.
So basically, what it does,
is it actually stops at that time and
goes to the beginning and
starts another video.
Now, of course, there's a lot of
luck involved here, because what
may happen is you see a sudden jump when
the looping begins from begin to end.
So for example here, boom,
everything shifted by a lot,
because it went back to the beginning.
So, of course, that basically
means we can actually loop it, but
it does kind of have
an artifact of a sudden jump.
Video textures avoid all of this.
See here,
all of these videos continuously play.
And in fact,
they can go on infinitely long.
There is no sudden jump,
there is no end to this video.
Basically what we've done is
created an infinite loop of videos
that continue to play forever and ever.
And that's what video
textures is all about.