All right, so
let's start off by taking a look
at the Gist I've provided for you.
So here we see it contains an XML for
the list item layout.
So inside it, there's a vertical in
your layout with two texts used.
So one for the pet name and
then one for the pet summary.
So in our case right now, the pet
summary will just include the pet breed.
But in the future,
you could always modify the summary
to include other pet attributes.
Now down below,
I also included some starter code for
the pet cursor adapter class.
So this class extends from the cursor
adapter class, and inside it,
contains a constructor.
And I also left some to do's for
the new view and bind view methods.
So let's start off by copying
over the list item xml layout.
So here in Android Studio, in my
RES folder inside my layout folder,
I'm going to create a new RES file.
I'm going to call it list_item.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So in this new file, I'm going to paste
over the code that I just copied.
So there we go.
Our list item layout is all set up.
And next, let's copy over the code for
our pet cursor adaptor.
So from the Gist, copy over this code.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now back in our project.
Inside my Java folder,
inside my .Android.pets folder,
I'm going to create a new Java
file called PetCursor adapter.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then inside that,
I will paste the code I just copied.
Now inside the cursor adapter class,
I'll need to finish implementing
the new view and bind view methods.
So within new view, all I need to do
here is inflate the list item layout.
But normally I don't usually
remember the syntax for doing so
right off the top of my head.
So in any case I'll just copy over the
code from the tutorial that we looked at
earlier, so
let's go back to that tutorial.
So here in the tutorial in
the defining the adapter section,
I want the syntax for inflating
a layout, and that happens right here.
So let's copy this line, head back to
Android studio and paste it in here.
Now all we need to do
is modify the code, so
the reference is our list item
layout instead of this item to do.
Let's delete this.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Also if you get an error from Android
Studio about this layoutinflater class,
it's because it hasn't
been imported yet.
So the shortcut to do it on the Mac
is Alt+Enter, and that's shown here.
So whatever it is on the device
you're working on, go ahead and
use that shortcut.
Now the next to do left in
here is the bindView method.
So bindView is a little
bit more complicated but
it's using all the same methods that
I used to populate the text view.
So let me go ahead and
write out this text first and
then I'll walk you through
the code needed for bindView.
So bindView requires these four steps.
First, I'll get the two
textViews using their IDs.
And the IDs are the ones I got from
the list item view that I passed in.
Next, I need the pet data from
the current row in the cursor.
And I want to make sure that I
have the correct column index, so
I get the column index for the name
column and then for the breed column.
After that, I can read out the values
at those specific column indices.
And lastly using the text
views setText method.
I can update the text for
the pet name and the pet breed.
So with those todo's complete,
the pet cursor adapter is complete.
Now we need to move on to the catalog
activity to hook everything up.
But first let me start out
by replacing the text view
in our catalog activity layout.
So this one here.
With a list view instead of a text view.
So this list view will take up the full
width and height of the screen.
So here in the catalog activity,
I removed the text view and replaced
it with this list view here that has
the layout width of match parent and
a layout height of match parent.
So it fills up the whole screen.
Next we need to make some modifications
to the CatalogActivity class.
So in this class, I want to modify
the display database info method,
this method here, to use list view in
pet cursor adapter we just created.
So, that means I can delete anything
that references the text view or
anything related to formatting
the result from the cursor
into the text view.
But remember, we want to leave
the code that fetches the cursor
from the provider because
we'll need that cursor still.
So this information here.
So let me go ahead and set that up.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
All right so there we go,
I stopped all the code from using
a text view to using a list view.
In order to set up the list view,
I needed to get a reference to the list
view using the ID that I've defined
in the CatalogActivity.xml file.
So, this id here refers to this list.
And then, I created a new
PetCursorAdaptor instance as adaptor
here, passing in the context this and
the cursor of the pet data.
And then finally I
associate the list view and
the cursor adapter using
the set adapter method.
So that completes all the changes for
this quiz.