So for my final example,
let me now showcase the perspective or
projective transformation of an image.
Again, the usual things.
Here just to be different we're going to
play around with a different image,
the Berlin Wall image.
We can actually compute the,
the height and width, and
all of that kind of stuff
here from the image itself.
And again it should be no surprise to
you so far that now we need four points.
So, for example, so in the first image
I'm going to find four different points,
so I've basically given them
those coordinates here.
And for the second image I've found
four other points, and we need those for
perspective transformation using these
two points, points one and point two.
In this code I'm going to compute
the matrix, transformation matrix that
actually uses these four points to
compute the perspective transformation.
We're going to print it out and
then of course, as we have done before,
we're going to just apply
this transformation here.
Let me just run this code.
Here you see the perspective transform.
Again, this should be no surprise.
This value is still 1.
But of course we have other
values in the rest of the matrix.
So this is the original Berlin Wall
image, and you'll see why actually this
image was chosen to showcase
this effect of perspective warp.
This is the perspectively corrected
image, now just being able to apply
the perspective warp, and
again the points were correctly chosen.
You notice now all of a sudden you
get a warp of actually seeing this
image right in front as opposed to,
in the previous case,
where you saw an effect
of foreshortening.
Again, notice here straight lines remain
straight, which is what we talked about
as one of the values of these
types of transformations.