All right, so we've said before, so
far our main ideas are, we're going to
use those rectangles as features.
And it's really easy to compute them
because or the integral image, and
then we're going to use that
discriminative ones as the weak learner,
the weak classifiers.
All right, well we're using this with
a within a boosted framework so not
surprise you that we're going to combine
them to make our final classifier,
that's what boosting does.
But the other idea they had,
was to form this thing called
a cascade of classifiers.
And it's such an important idea that
I made it in italics, yellow, and
red, okay?
We're going to form a cascade
of these classifiers, and
we're going to reject
clear negatives quickly.
What's this all about, all right?
So the second big idea of this paper,
besides the integral image one,
was the cascade.
And here's the issue.
Even if our filters are really
fast to compute, so
even if we can get these you know,
compute these rectangles on a new thing
very quickly there's an awful
lot of places to go search.
How can we make the detection
more efficient?
And this was the insight.
Almost everywhere in
a picture is not a face.
I don't care what the picture is.
You know, unless you happen to
be looking at the, you know,
the 1972 New York Yankees like this,
you know, we got, you know, 75 faces.
But even then,
most of the locations are not a face,
there's only 75 locations that
are a face, and all the other locations,
remember Kristen's little,
those are not faces.
So, what you'd like to be able to do,
is quickly know that
something is not a face.
Right?
So you can move on.
And, if I say that
something's not a face,
I want to be sure that it's not a face,
so I can move on.
So what they built was
a cascaded set of filters.
Okay, so at each level, there's
going to be a boosted filter, but
here's what they did, all right?
So, you have a whole bunch of,
of images, windows, scales,
et cetera, whatever.
You train a classifier,
it's called stage 1.
All right?
And Whatever it says is not a face,
you're sure that it's not a face.
So when you adjust your classifier,
you adjust it so
that it has no, what are called,
false negatives.
Everything it says is not
a face is really not a face.
Everything that you say is a face,
you're going to put into
another classifier.
So you're going to train
a second stage classifier, and
what it's going to do is,
remember this is on training data so
it's labelled, you're going to give
it a whole bunch of positive faces.
But what negatives
are you going to give it?
The negatives you're going
to give it are the false
positives from the last stage.
So stage 1, remember, we set it so that
everything it says is not a face isn't,
but it says a whole bunch
of things are a face.
Some of those are wrong.
Those are false positives.
So use those negatives, plus real
positives, to train the next classifier.
And we do that again, and
what that gives you is a cascaded set of
filters where when you apply this in
testing data, you have to make it
through all the filters, all the stages,
in order to be labeled as a face.
But to be rejected,
you can be rejected quickly.
Its just like dating in college, right?
You can get rejected quickly, but it
takes you a long time to get accepted.
All right.
Just as a quick summary, we have a whole
bunch of images, faces and non-faces,
we're going to train
a cascade of classifiers,
they used AdaBoost, all right, which
is a particular boosting algorithm.
And we're going to select out features
and thresholds and weights, which is do,
you have to do in AdaBoost.
And then, what you're going to do,
is for some image,
you're going to apply it to the window.
That's where the face really is.
We clicked the window,
we slide it around, and there it is.
And it finds the right face.