Suppose you're given this
complete binary search tree.
Here's what the conventional in-order
ordering of the nodes would look like.
The numbering serves as offsets for
laying out the nodes linearly in memory.
And, by the way, if this is an actual
tree data structure with left and
right pointers,
let's assume that those pointers
are stored along with the node values.
But, what about a different ordering?
For this quiz,
I want you to generate the sequence that
would result from a Van Emde Boas
ordering instead.
Enter the node values and the linearized
array that appears below the tree.
So, you'd type a, b, c, d, e, f,
g, or whatever in these boxes.