Now that we've finished defining the MDP
in burlap, we can use a planning or
reinforcement algorithm,
provided by burlap, to solve this MDP.
For this tutorial,
we'll use a value iteration to find
the values of states S1, S2, and S3.
Whichever of these states
has the highest value,
will tell us which action, a, b, or c,
we most prefer for our initial action.
Value iteration is
a class in burlap which
implements the value iteration
algorithm from lecture.
It does all the work of iterative
bellman equation updates for us.
To instantiate it, we need to pass
the domain reward function and
terminal function we previously defined.
We also need to pass
a few more parameters.
A double gamma, which is
the discount factor between zero and
one, a state hash factory object,
which I'll talk about in a moment,
a double maxDelta and
an int maxIterations.
Which are two stopping conditions for
the value iteration procedure.
The procedure will stop if no state's
value changes by more than maxDelta
in a single iteration.
And the procedure will also stop
after running max iterations times.
The state hash factory is an interface
providing the method hash state,
which takes a state object and
produces a state hash tuple.
This allows for
fast retrieval of state objects
during the value iteration procedure.
Since our MDP consists of a finite
number of discrete states,
we will pass a DiscreteStateHashFactory
to the value iteration constructor.
Let's go ahead and
add a DiscreteStateHashFactory
to our first MDP class.
And later we'll pass this object to
the value iteration constructor.
Note that we'll need to add
these import statements to
use the discrete hash factory and
the value iteration objects.
The packages you need to import can be
found by browsing the documentation.
Or if you are using an IDE,
the appropriate import statements can
likely be added automatically as needed.
Next, lets add the member field
hashfactory, and then in the first MDB
constructor, initialize hashFactory to
a new DiscreteStateHashFactory object.
Now that we've created our hashFactory,
we're in the position to
perform value iteration.
Let's write a private method,
computeValue that will be used to return
a ValueIteration object,
available internally to the class.
Let's make the method dependent on
just the single parameter gamma.
For our purposes,
we'll just set the maxDelta and
maxIterations parameters
by hand to 0.0001 and 1000.
Then we'll pass all the required
parameters to a new
ValueIteration object.
Now I'd like you to fill in this blank
in the code to perform the value
iteration procedure on our MDP
before returning the object vi.
Feel free to refer to the value
iteration documentation as needed.