We have here in core raw asset sprites
all of the assets we've created for
gigagal.
Now we don't want to have to
individually load each one of these
files into our completed game.
What we really want to do is pack all of
these images into a big texture atlas.
Then we can load that whole
atlas all at once, and
we don't have to load
a bunch of different files.
To do this we have to delve into the
mystery that is the build.gradle file.
The to do's in the course code will
show you exactly how to do this.
But first of all,
we need to add a dependency on the GDX
tools package in the build script block.
That means that this code itself
is dependant on GDX tools.
Then we need to import texture packer.
Then down in the block of the build
script that applies to the core project,
we're adding a new task
called packTextures.
That first of all,
deletes the previous atlas, and
then processes our
core/rawAssets/sprites directory.
Finally we ensure that every time
the compileJava task is run,
the packTextures task is run first.
I am sure all of this Gradle stuff
is still a gigantic mystery.
Don't worry about it.
Check out the To Dos in the course code,
and
it'll explain it all in
excruciating detail.
The upshot is that if we open
up our project pane again and
we go into Android > Assets > Images,
we find a big PNG with all of our
assets packed together in one image.
So how do we actually use the textures
that we've packed into our atlas?
Well, the answer is kind of complicated.
First we have to create
an asset manager and
have the asset manager
go load up our atlas.
Then, we can use findRegion
on our atlas to grab
particular regions of the atlas that
contain the texture we're interested in.
So down here in the render callback.
We've got our standingRight texture
region, we'll just get the texture and
we'll draw it using a spread batch.
Let's see what happens.
Whoops, okay, we just wanted the the
standingRight texture right here, but
instead we got the entire atlas.
To get a texture region to
draw correctly, we have to
use one of the more complicated versions
of the draw method on the sprite batch.
That takes into account what portion
of the incoming texture we actually
want to draw.
Again, the annotations in the course
code will do a better job of explaining
this than I will here.
All right, time for you to go
through the entire texture workflow.
From packing all of your
textures into an atlas.
To loading textures back out of
that atlas that you want to draw.
And then drawing them correctly.