What a week.
I mean, I just, I've been working on
this database the entire week and
it's just so hard to figure it out.
I'm doing primary keys, I'm doing
foreign keys, I'm doing inner joins,
I'm doing outer joins,
just thank goodness it's Friday.
>> Yeah, I can imagine.
It was a long week indeed, right?
So, you have any plans for the weekend?
>> I think I'm going to work on a few
burgers, I'm going to work on my tan.
And of course, all the database stuff is
just going to be going around the back
of my head so that when I hit
the desk again on Monday or
probably Sunday night, at least I'll
have something to start working on.
How about you?
What are you going to do this weekend?
>> Yeah, I'm not sure yet actually.
I think I might be building
an app this weekend.
>> You're building an app this weekend?
>> Do you know how long I've
been working on that app?
I've been working on it for weeks and
I've barely written any code yet.
I'm still designing data.
It's just, how are you going to
do an app in a weekend?
>> Yeah, I'm not sure yet.
But I think I'm going to
be using Firebase for it.
>> Firebase, I kind of heard about
that as a middleware type thing.
Is that going to help with the date?
Tell you what, I'll look after the
burgers, and you tell me about Firebase.
>> Okay, well with Firebase,
like normally when you build an app,
you spend a lot of time on
the backend and on the middleware.
With Firebase,
you can ignore all that and
actually focus on what your
app needs to be special.
So what makes your app your app.
And I think with that, you could
be building an app in a weekend.
>> I could build it in a weekend?
>> I think so.
>> Really?
>> Yup.
>> Wow.
Hey Lila.
>> Yeah?
What's up?
>> We're going to build
an app this weekend.
>> Cool.
I'm in.
>> What kind of app are we going to do?
>> So how about we build a chat app this
weekend, but then let's actually set
the bar a bit higher
>> Alright.
>> Let's build a chat app not just for
one platform, but
we're going to build it for
iOS and for Android.
>> Okay.
>> How do we feel about that?
>> Well I could build an Android
app with my eyes closed, but
iOS, hey, Jared's calling.
Hey Jared, what's up.
>> Hey,
are you having a party without me?
>> Perfect timing,
want to build an iOS chat app?
>> Sure let's do it.
>> That's great, that settles it then.
So we're going to be building a chat app
for iOS and Android in the weekends.
How do we feel about that?
Are we ready to build an app guys?
>> Yeah okay.
>> Yeah, let's go.
>> Let's do this.
>> Bring it on.