So getting started in part 1,
install the beautiful soup in ubuntu by using the apt-get command, and
again you can do this by copying and pasting in the lesson 3, stage 2.
In part 2 modify your TweetSpout to emit only the first
URL contained in a Tweet.
We do that in lesson 2, stage 2, navigate to the TweetSpout.
We see that in the TweetSpout, the current logic states that
the status.get text is how we're getting our Tweet messages.
First comment out the queue.offer and
using the syntax hint we create a string URL,
we check that the status.getURLEntities.length is not equal to 0.
If length does not equal zero, we assign the URL using the getURL function in
the hint, and finally using the same syntax, we add the URL in the queue.
Scrolling down in the TweetSpout we see the next tuple method.
We'll pull from the queue, check that the queue is not null, and
if not it admits the string using the collector.emit function.
Finally the declare output fields method, you can leave the field as tweet.
Next it's time to create your python file in part 3, create a new python file in
the resources folder urltext.py to an adamant ad file urltext.py.
And again, remember that it's a python file that goes in
the resources directory.
In part 4, we define the main functionality to use urllib2 and
BeautifulSoup from bs4, to define a new class URLBolt to open and receive URL's
parse intimate text, I use the splitsentence.pi example from stage one.
Using SplitSentenceBolt as an example, we create the URLBolt class.
First we get the url coming from the tupBolt.values at zero.
Next in the URL lib2 library we get
the HTML file using urllib2.urlopen(url).read.
Finally from the syntax hints using beautiful soup making the soup.
We have soup equals beautiful soup that takes in the html we defined.
Next, using the syntax hints again,
we use the soup.findAll method that searches for title and paragraph tags.
And finally, we check if the urlText is not null.
In Python this falsies.
So if urlText is link 0 this will be false.
But if it's true, we form a list comprehension, this is why I
kept the storm.emit word syntax here but we'll, we can now get rid of this.
And using the storm.emit syntax we emit t dot string for t in url text.
Finally again in the hints, we want to wrap this in a tri except past statement,
because any 404 error will crash Storm,
once we wrapped the try except pass, we update our URLBolt class.
And now we have our URLBolt class .run statement.
And, finally, we include our import statements,
urllib2, and from bs4 import BeautifulSoup.
Finally in part 5, create java bolt URLBolt.java and
remember this is located in the storm folder and not the resources folder.
Once created, again, keeping the import statements the same,
we can copy the splitsentence.java file into our URLBolt.java file.
Next, we update the class to URLBolt, update the constructor from
SplitSentence to URLBolt, update splitsentence.py to
urltext.py and finally, I declared my new field text instead of word.
Note again that the Python bold URL text.pie does not declare an output field,
and this must be declared in the URL bolt.java.
The URL bolt will be connected to our Python parse bolt
using a shuffle grouping.
Therefore, the field we choose will not be using a.
Field grouping, but we will call this text.
Finally, in part six, we update the topology by navigating to
the Tweet topology, we add the URL bolt with a component ID python-URL-bolt.
And here we have a shuffleGrouping connecting the tweet-spout.
And finally, to complete the topology, we see that the tweet-spout connection to
the python-split-sentence bolt needs to be updated to the python-URL-bolt.
And one final check on our topology, we have the tweet spout,
the python-URL-bolt.
The python-split-sentence bolt, the count-bolt and the report-bolt.
This is connected with a shuffleGrouping of the URL to the Tweet spout.
Another shuffle grouping of the Python URL bolt to the split sentence bolt,
the split sentence bolt to the count bolt and
finally the count bolt to the report bolt.
Just labeling our components a little nicer, we have the tweet spout,
the Python URL bolt, the Python split sentence, the count-bolt,
and finally the report-bolt that connects to Redis and our live visualization.
We see that the python-URL-bolt actually calls the urltext.py file,
and finally the python-split-sentence bolt is calling the splitsentence.py file.
So notice that if you don't follow the hint in the split-sentence-bolt to
check for empty values,
you'll get a runtime error of NoneType object has no attribute split.
What's happening is, the URL being passed is going to be empty but
our split sentence bolt is trying to parse it and so
we get a runtime failure here, and to fix that we'll simply go and add a check.
For empty values.
And so here following the hint, we simply check for empty values.
Remember that Python is so if tuple.values at zero is empty,
this will evaluate to false.
If it exists, that is true.
We set our words, and
if words, again checking to make sure that that's not empty.
We simply go through and use storm.emit for that word.
Finally, in part six,
update your topology to visualize url words parsed using a python bolt.
Again running maven package and submit as usuall.
And finally we see our word cloud updating.
So great job on Lesson 3, Stage 2.
Remember that your code will now match Lesson 3, Stage 3,
if you ran into any issues.
Great job.