Okay, so for the first one, learn
to fly.com, it can be a bit tricky.
We need to think about
our overall traffic, but
we also want to look at
overall conversions.
Now if we increase
the amount of traffic,
by people who are serious about taking
flying lessons and who actually can.
We're going to see a greater number of
people of actually buying those lessons
than if it was just random traffic.
So we're going to look
at C Conversions and
A traffic, but
the most important here is Conversions.
And for the second one, movie man.com,
we're going to want to look at retention
rate for
the first month after people sign up.
If your retention rate increases,
you know that you've achieved your goal.