Now, we've seen how to assign a probability to a tree, but how do we come up with the trees to begin with?
In other words, how do we parse a sentence like this into a tree structure?
Well, we can do that as a process of search, and we can use any of the search algorithms that we saw earlier in the class.
And in particular, we can go in either direction--either from the goal of having a sentence,
or from the raw words themselves, and because we usually draw trees with the derivation of the sentence at the top,
we speak of that as being top-down, so top-down search would say that a sentence can be broken up into a noun phrase
or a verb phrase, or a bottom-up search. And a bottom-up search would say that "Fed" can be a noun,
"raises" can be a noun, but could also be a verb,
and same with these other words in the sentence.
And then the search is a process of trying to connect these up so that we get a tree that spans all the words in the sentence,
and comes up as an S node at the top.
Most of the search techniques break it down by a process of saying, "If a sentence consists of a noun phrase and a verb phrase,
"and that has to span the entire set of words, then we can break that up at either point."
So we can say, "Maybe the first word is a noun phrase and the other three are the verb phrase.
"Maybe the first two words are the noun phrase, and the remaining other verb phrase," and so on.
And we would just enumerate those possibilities. And so here, in fact, it is very simple to say that
the first word can be a noun phrase, and then the second one, we can break verb phrase up into several possibilities.
Verb plus noun phrase, or verb plus noun phrase plus noun phrase, and let's choose one of them.
And the idea is that this is a search. If this works out, fine. If it doesn't work out, we would backtrack and try one of the other possibilities.
But in fact, this one hooks up quite easily by rewriting a noun phrase as noun plus noun.
So there we have one parse. But we could continue backtracking and come up with other parses.
So for example, still staying with the choice of having the first word be the initial noun phrase,
we could break up this verb phrase into a different constituent.
Instead of a verb plus noun phrase, we could have it be a verb plus two noun phrases.
And then we'd continue to search. And in fact, we'd find that there's an alternative parse there.
And we would continue going through for each category, all its possibilities, and try to match them up.
And we can enumerate all the possible parses.
Now, in terms of attaching probabilities, that could be done in the same way.
We just, for each rule, put in the appropriate probability.
And one of the nice things about this type of approach of using context free grammars is that,
when we make a choice in one part of the tree, it doesn't affect the choices in the other part of the tree.
So if we break it up into a noun phrase plus verb phrase, and if the noun phrase is some large constituent with many words in it,
and the verb phrase is as well, there's no interaction between the two pieces.
We just know any noun phrase can combine with any verb phrase.
And when we're going for a probabilistic parse, it means we can take the highest probability
of the product of the noun phrase and the verb phrase, so we get one best parse, even though there may be
dozens or hundreds of possible parses for each of the constituent.
That's the advantage of being context-free.