Now in the last lecture, we have started
talking about image warping already.
So now let's actually try to
make it much more foundational.
Again, let's take this
simple image here.
And what we want to do is basically
we want to distort this image.
And one of the ways we can do this is
distort it by simulating some sort of
an optical change in
aberration of some sort.
A typical one of that type would be
basically something like a fish eye lens
here, right?
If you notice,
if you had a fish eye lens in a camera,
everything in the front would pop out.
And of course, if you notice,
farther things are going back here.
And in this case, there's a bulging
in the middle here, right?
And this bulging is showcased by E is
much bigger here than it was there and
of course, there's all kinds
of curvature information.
Another operation could be,
we can project this onto a curved or
a mirrored surface.
So in this case, I basically
projected this image onto an arch.
So if you notice, it's curved and
of course, it now has a shape.
In essence, this almost could be looked
at as taking this image and warping it,
and putting it on some sort of an arch
so now it actually looks like, curved.
This could also be referred to as
texture mapping where I basically made
this image be a texture on a surface.
And in this case, it could be
a curved surface like this one.
It could be a cylinder or a sphere also.
Another method is,
we can basically take polygons and
basically kind of discretize this
into small regions of polygons.
And basically,
each polygon would be distorted.
So for example,
this is my original image.
This is my output image.
Let me show you some polygons on top.
So here I've basically,
in the original image,
basically shown a small quadrilateral.
What I want to do in this one is
of course I'm going to take this
quadrilateral, and
it will be warped in this one.
And any information that's
in this quadrilateral,
rectangle in this instance,
would now be transformed in this one.
Basically, you see that warping here,
right?
The T is there,
you notice the T is still there.
But the E is curved.
And of course,
there are other polygons next to it too,
I'm just showing you this.
For example,
you can see the other polygons.
This shape here, and
another one is also down here.
And there is another one here.
And these are again polygons.
In this case, I'm basically showing
the polygons not to just be linear
quadrilaterals but
to be various types of deformations.
In essence, what's happened
in this instance has been,
this has been converted
into a warped polygon here.
And of course, there's another whole
concept of distorting using morphing,
and we'll talk more about that too.