All right, so let's take a look at
how we would change the setup in
the NumbersActivity to use a for
loop instead of a while loop to
move through the words list.
So currently in the while loop we
have the setup of the index position,
the condition, and
update variable all outside.
But remember for the for loop,
we can have that all in one line.
So now I'm going to go ahead and
remove those three parts.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So what we've done here is start off
with the for keyword, then condense
the three parts of the while loop, the
initial condition, the test condition,
and the updating of the counter,
all into this one line here.
So the task we want to complete in
each iteration remains the same, so
we won't alter the body of the loop.
So now this is what the final version
of the NumbersActivity using a for
loop looks like.