Now let me just show you
a simple demonstration.
And I'll actually be
sharing the code for
this demonstration that you can
actually use for a variety of things.
And again, you'll have an opportunity
to play around with this on your own.
Here I want to basically demonstrate
how we can morph between the two
different types of jaguars, the jaguar
the car, and the real jaguar here.
Now recall,
to accomplish any kind of morphing,
we need to find feature
points to create a mesh.
In this case, I've actually created
a mesh that covers the whole image, but
I've found specific feature points
that I want to be able to identify
in this image here.
And this is, of course,
now the same mesh with different feature
points applied to the real jaguar.
So, basically again,
you should see that this feature
point here is matching this one.
This feature point is matching this one.
So once I have these two meshes and I'll
basically now figure out how to do this
alignment of these types of
meshes across the two images,
I can use that to generate
a morph sequence between the two.
So here you see the animation sequence
that basically is morphing from this
jaguar to this jaguar, and you basically
notice all the key points deforming, and
these mesh triangles deforming with
the right kinds of pixels, and
warping them appropriately
to generate a new sequence.
Let's look at this again
without the triangles.
So there you see the original
image sequence now without any of
the triangles and see the morphing.
We will share this code with the slides
for you to play around with this
on your own with your open cv package
that you've been playing around with.