Now that you have Vagrant and Virtual Blocks set up on your local machine,
either Windows, Mac OS X, or Ubuntu, or another version or distro of Linux,
we now are going to clone the gate hub repository for the course.
So in step one on your local machine at the command prompt,
navigate to the directory you want to create the course.
I've created a directory called Real-Time$.
Next type in the command git clone with
address https://github.com/Udacity/ud381.
You can also simply copy and paste.
So I'll copy this, go back to my directory, type this in and hit Enter.
Once you see your repository cloned, you can do an ls which stands for list.
You see ud381.
Do cd into ud381 and now we do an ls again and
we see that we are in the ud381 directory.
Going back to the directions in Step 2, I'll scroll down a bit.
Depending your download speed,
the following command will take about 20 to 30 minutes.
You can continue on with the course once you hit Enter and
the process can take place in the background.
So, go back, make sure you're in ud381, and type the command vagrant up.
So type in, make sure you're ud381, vagrant up.
So that's two words, vagrant up, hit Enter.
Just wait a few seconds and make sure you see the download process begin.
It shows that the box can't be found and what's happening is your computer is
connecting to the Vagrant cloud to download the box udacity/ud381.
So notice the progress here may take 20 or 30 minutes.
And we can just continue on with the course.
Great. And hit Next to continue.