[Thrun] This finishes my unit on clustering,
at least so far.
I just want to briefly summarize what we've learned.
We talked about K-means, and we talked about expectation maximization.
K-means is a very simple almost binary algorithm
that allows you to find cluster centers.
EM is a probabilistic generalization that also allows you to find clusters
but also modifies the shapes of the clusters by modifying the covariance matrix.
EM is probabilistically sound, and you can prove convergence
in a log likelihood space. K-means also converges.
Both are prone to local minima.
In both cases you need to know the number of cluster centers, K.
I showed you a brief trick how to estimate the K as you go,
which also overcomes local minima to some extent.