Now let's see how mutexes and condition variables can be combined for
use in a scenario that's common in multithreading systems,
multithreading applications, as well as at the operating system level.
And this is a scenario where there're multiple threads.
But of two different kinds.
Some subset of threads that want to perform read operation to
access the shared state for reading.
And other set of threads that want to perform write operations or
that want to access that same shared variable, shared state, and modify it.
We call these types of problems the readers/writer problem.
The readers/writer problem is such that at any given point of time, zero or
more of the reader's threads can access this resource, but only zero or
one writer threads can access the resource concurrently at the same time.
And clearly we cannot have a situation in which a reader and
a writer thread are accessing the shared resource at the same time.
One naive approach to solving this problem would be
to simply protect the entire resource, let's say this is a file, with a mutex.
And put a lock and unlock operations around it.
So whenever anyone of these types of threads is accessing the resource,
they will lock the mutex, perform their respective access, and
then release the mutex.
This is, however, too restrictive for the readers/writer problem.
Mutexes allow only one thread at a time to access the critical section.
So they have a binary state, either zero and the resource is free and
accessible, or one and the resource is locked and you have to wait.
This is perfectly fine for
the writers, since that's exactly the kind of semantic that we want to achieve.
But for readers, with mutexes, we cannot express that multiple readers
can be performing access to the shared resource at the same time.
So how can we solve this problem?
Well, we can start by trying to come up with the situations in which it
is okay versus it is not okay to perform certain type of access to the resource.
So we'll start enumerating these things and we'll try to express this based
on the number of readers and writers that are also performing an operation.
In the simple case when there are no readers and no writers accessing this
resource, both a read operation can be granted, so an upcoming read operation,
as well as a upcoming or pending write operation can be granted.
As we describe the problem, if the read counter is greater than zero, so
if there are more readers already accessing this file,
it's perfectly fine to allow another reader to access the file concurrently.
Since readers are not modifying it, so
it's perfectly okay to grant that request.
And then finally, if there is a writer that's performing an access to
the resource, then we cannot allow neither the reads nor the writes.
So, given these statements, we can express the state in which the shared file or
the shared resource is as follows.
If the resource is free, then some resource_counter variable,
we can say well that will be zero in that case.
If the resource is accessed for
reading, then this resource_counter variable will be greater than zero.
And so it will be actually equal to the number of readers that
are currently reading this file.
And let's say we can encode the fact that currently there is a writer,
somebody's writing to this resource, by choosing that, in that case,
the resource_counter variable should take the value negative 1.
And of course, this will indicate that there is exactly one writer currently
accessing the resource.
So there is a saying in computer science that,
all problems can be solved with one level of indirection.
And here, basically,
we produce a proxy resource, a helper variable or a helper expression.
In this case, it is this resource_counter variable.
This resource_counter variable reflects the state in
which the current resource already is.
But what we will do, as opposed to controlling the updates to the file,
so controlling, with a mutex, who gets to access the file,
we will control who gets to update this proxy variable, this proxy expression.
So as long as any access to the file is first reflected via an update to this
proxy expression, we can use a mutex to control how this counter is accessed.
And in that way, basically monitor, control and coordinate among
the different accesses that we want to allow to the actual shared file.