In 2D of course, it's not just a derivative but
we have to talk about the direction of the derivative.
In gradients, we have derivatives in the x direction and
derivatives in the y direction.
So when you do this same trick of taking the derivative of our filter,
we have to say, in what direction are we taking that derivative?
So let's write this like this.
So what we want to do is,
let's suppose we want to take the derivative in the x direction.
And what this little h of x is meant to imply is that
that's a little filter that just takes our derivative in the x direction.
Maybe it's a Sobel operator, maybe it's one of the others.
But it's a small filter taking a derivative.
And g, here, is going to be our Gaussian.
And you know, as we said before, because of the associative property,
besides smoothing and then taking the derivative,
we can apply an operator that is the Gaussian with its derivative.
So that's what's shown here.
Okay? And the minus 1 1, that's a trivial one,
it could be minus 1 0 1, it's my generic derivative operator.
And the g, this is my Gaussian, my nice smooth, and
I just pulled out a chunk of the matrix that's, that's kind of like that.
And what does that give us?
Well that gives us this function like that, okay?
And so that is, it's first derivative of the Gaussian, which when I apply to
an image gives me the derivative of the Gaussian smooth image for
that associative property from before.
So the question is, is it preferable to do this, right, to apply this.
And we should think about this as a quiz, all right.
Because it is preferable.