Okay now for
something a little more hands on.
I want you to analyze one of
the Android Wear samples and
answer some questions
about how it works.
So you will need to use the input
sample feature of Android Studio and
search for Data Layer.
You should build and install the sample
to both the phone and a wearable or
a phone and an emulator.
When it's running, you'll see
things happening on both sides.
Once you've got that working,
I want you to review the source code and
then we're going to answer
the following questions.
First one, is what transmission
mechanism is used in
the send start activity
message on the phone side?
This method here is used to launch
the activity on the wearable.
And the second question is what
thread does the send start
activity message run on?