Here I have 3 files containing a corpus of text in each of the languages that I want to classify into,
and imagine these are much longer, so it gives you a good sample in text in
English, German, and Azerbaijan.
Now I have a new piece of text that I want to classify against each of these possibilities.
Well, I can do that using the gzip command.
So I could issue this Unix command that says
"concatenate together the new file with the English file,
gzip them, compress them, then count the number of characters,
and do the same for the German and Azerbaijani,
and then figure out which one is shortest.
In fact, when we do that with the files I've collected, it gives me the right answer.
Now how does it do that?
Well, you have to understand a little bit about how compression algorithms like gzip work.
What they do is they take a file like this and they look for common subsequences,
and they represent that in less than 1 byte.
For example, I-S-SPACE would be represented by 3 bytes in an ASCII encoding,
but in compressed encoding you could say,
"Hey, I see that sequence here. I see it here again. It's going to show up many times."
So maybe I can represent those 3 bytes just in terms of one,
saying this is a common subsequence that I'm going to see again and again.
Once we've done that for English, we come up with common subsequences in English.
Then if we add in another file that has a lot of the same common sequences,
like here it has I-S-SPACE again,
then that's going to compress well with respect to this.
It's not going to compress very well with respect to the Azerbaijan,
because that won't have built up a code for I-S-SPACE.
That will have built up codes for things like R-B-A rather than for I-S-SPACE.
So it turns out that the ideas of compression and learning are actually very closely related,
and they're related by information theory and this idea of entropy of an expression
or the information content.
That wasn't discovered until fairly recently.
The two fields had developed independently, but now they've come back together,
and we understand how they relate.