There was a more recent application of SIFT.
Very explicit.
You guys, I don't know how old you are anymore, but
maybe you remember the Sony AIBOs, the dogs that used to go around and
would recharge themselves and live in your house.
It was sort of an experiment that Sony did for a while.
It was kind of successful, but eventually they stopped making them,
because I think, I think they were learning from it and moving from there.
Well, one of the things that the dog could do, well there were two things.
It could recharge itself and you could show it cards and
it would do the commandment based upon what was draw on the card,
what was printed on the card.
And the way it did that was using SIFT features.
All right?
So the charging station had a pattern on it, and as the dog walked around and
just did kind of whatever it did,
whatever little robot dogs do, it would see this pattern.
It would be oriented,
it would be translated off to the side somewhere at a different scale.
But remember, SIFT is translation, rotation scale, and variant.
So it could find the charging station.
Also, they had these what were called visual cards.
And they were things like this.
And it doesn't really matter at all what's on the cards as long as
they have gradients distributed all over them.
The dog can recognize which card you're showing it.
You know, I said it doesn't matter at all what's on it.
It does matter a little.
It has to not look like anything the dog would see otherwise.
So if you wonder why do these cards look so
strange, it's because it can't look like my dining room table.
Because if it looks like my dining room table, my dog will look see
my dining room table, and roll over and play dead or whatever robot dogs do.