And in computer graphics and in computer vision,
what we often do is we combine that diffuse and the specular.
And it's referred to as the Phong model because Phong was one of
the first people to do it.
Then there's the Blinn Phong model.
And there's lot of models that have increased beyond that.
But the idea, basically, is that you say that.
You can model the BRDF of lots of surfaces,
as a combination of a Lambertian plus a Specular.
So we have the Lambertian which is the,
you know, everything looks equally bright from all directions.
That's what these equal sized arrows are meant to show you.
Remember, the light doesn't go out equally.
It just looks equally bright.
Plus the Specular Model whose sort of blur amount is defined by that fall off.
And when you combine those you can get sort of the Matte plus the Specular.
And here's an example of some recovered imaging where here you
have a original image, and here you've sort of broken it down into the.
Matte components and the sepcular components.
Likewise here you have this object that has the, the matte surface.
That's the paint itself, plus the glossiness of the varnish.
Or whatever it is.
When you, what, what is it you put on top of ceramics to make it glossy?
>> Gloss? >> Gloss, thank you very much.
Okay, and the idea is that this is the matte component and again,
this is the specular component.
And the ability to pull those out, is a computer vision problem.