We're going to want our learning
algorithms to return optimal policies.
>> Right.
>> But to do that, we're going to
have to say what we mean by optimal.
So I know we talked about this in the
context of MDPs, but I thought it might
be worth revisiting just to see that
there's different choices we could make.
And the choices that we make have
implications about what it means to be
optimal.
>> Okay.
>> So here's, in particular,
what I want to get at,
let's say we have some particular
policy that we're going to follow.
By following that policy
from some initial state,
we're going to have a sequence
of states, actions and rewards.
But there's actually multiple possible
sequences of state, actions and
rewards that can happen because
the domains are stochastic.
>> Right, right.
>> So let's say that we've got some
particular policy that we want to
evaluate and it generates this sequence
of states with this probability,
and this sequence states
what this probability, and
this sequence of states
with this probability.
How do we turn all that possibilities
into a single number so that we can say,
oh, this policy is this good,
has this value, and
the other one is a smaller value so
I like this one better?
So here's this four steps
that we need to do to take
what was once a sequence of sequences,
or
a set of sequences of states, and
turn them into a single number.
So the first step is, for
each of the state transitions,
we need to turn it into actual numbers,
the immediate rewards.
>> Sure.
>> So in this case maybe landing
in a red state gets us -0.2 and
landing in a green state gets us a +1.
What is it in the definition of the MDP
that allows us to translate between
state transitions, from some state
via some action to some next state,
to actual values,
actual numbers for that transition?
>> Oh, it's our reward function.
>> Exactly, that basically just
gives us strings of numbers.
Right, so what was strings of states
now becomes strings of numbers.
And those are infinitely long, right,
because this process can
continue in an unbounded way.
If we're talking about the infinite
horizon, we just leave it that way.
But if we're talking about some kind
of finite horizon, like I don't know,
say truncating it at 5 steps, we can
actually take the sequence of numbers
that results and
cut it off after just 5 transitions.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Now we need to take that list
of truncated numbers, and for
each of the sequences, turn it into
a single number for that sequence.
It's called the return for the sequence.
So how do we do that?
Yeah, often what we'll do is
actually add them according to some
kind of discount factor.
>> Mm-hm.
>> If r sub i is the reward that
we got on step i of the sequence,
we might want to actually sum
up the discounted rewards.
>> Right, and my recollection is
that that's a geometric sequence so
it allows us to do infinite
sequences in finite time.
Or at least infinite numbers and
make it a finite number, so to speak.
>> That's right, and
that's a good point actually because
we might be doing this finite or
we might be doing this infinite.
In general, we do it up to
the length of the horizon.
>> Mm-hm.
>> All right, and so
let's just say for concreteness,
you can imagine having
a discount factor of 0.8.
And that gives us a way of summing
up the numbers that have been
generated by these states and getting
a single number for each sequence.
And then finally, we have to take
those multiple numbers, one number for
each of the sequences, and
turn it into a single number that
summarizes across all of them.
>> I see, so
you would just average them according
to how likely the sequences are.
>> Good, so it's also taking
the expectation, all right.
And so I've annotated these
sequences with their probabilities.
So what you should be able to do at this
point, is actually, according to these
parameters that I filled in,
say what the value of this policy is.
Assuming that these are the three
possible trajectories that could result,
what is the single number that actually
summarizes the outcomes of this policy?
>> Right and so that's what,
when we talked about MDPs,
is long-term expected reward.
>> That's right, or value or utility.
>> Mm-hm.
>> All right, so can you work
out what it is for this case?
We're going to make that a quiz.
>> Oh, okay, let's pretend,
oh wait, I've got one more thing.
I think I know what the answer is, but
just to force you to be
absolutely concrete.
I know what happens when you hit a red
circle, I know what happens when you hit
a green circle, what happens
when you hit a white circle?
>> Good question.
[LAUGH] They look like 0s,
let's just make them 0s.
So they're not going to come into play,
except for the fact that they're 0.
>> I like it.
>> All right, so you should be able to
reduce this entire sequence to a single
number, and
you can put the number in the box.
>> All right, sounds good, let's do it.
Go.