[BLANK_AUDIO]
When you're starting out on
a new machine learning problem,
one of the first questions that you've
come to once you've prepared the data
and made it suitable for
input into machine learning algorithm is
what methodology or
what algorithm do you start off with.
And there's a really good
rule of thumb for that.
If you're working on a problem like
computer vision, where it's a really
rich hierarchy structured and
complex natural data, then deep-parsing
is the best sort of methodology is to
use and approach the problem with.
A library in Python called Keras
makes deep-learning really easy and
flexible to use.
For any other problem that doesn't fit
that category of things like image data
with a natural rich hierarchical call
structure to them, then you the best
tool in your tool box to try first
is gradient boost machines and
extreme boost which you can
access through python or
through our is a great
toll to start off on.
And that includes problems like you
have a numeric feature matrix and
you're trying to predict a classifier
regression on that target or
if you're trying to rank ads or
you're trying to predict whether or
not a customer base satisfied based
on different information about that
customer things along those lines.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
There's two things to cracking
the Kaggle competition.
The first is to take the same standard
set of approaches many people
in our community will be taking, which
is understand a problem by iterating
rapidly on it trying to throw many
machine learning techniques and
future pre-processing techniques and
things like that on it and
see what the result is.
So that will get you to
a strong competitive position.
To really do a great job
in the competition and
win, what you need to do is find
a competitive edge in some way.
And in many cases that competitive
edge is materialized by
understanding the distribution
of the tray and test sets and
that’s how they might
defer the best test.
So really coming up with the good
internal mechanism for validating your
performance in the problem whether it's
via something like cross validation
where you randomly split the problem
into a series of faults and
then trade on some of the faults and
evaluate on other faults and
then use that as your score or
another validation strategy.
Having a really good internal validation
strategy that's consistent with how
we're ultimately making the final
ranking on the hidden test set
is crucial.
And then creatively thinking
about the domain and
exploring a large number
of different features or
ways that could approach the problem,
is another approach.
There's no shortcut to it, but
you can do a great job with
a lot of both a combination
of effort and creativity.