Now, at this point, you know just enough
about the SQL language to be dangerous.
So, let me give you a few quick tips and
insights to keep you out of
trouble as you pick up the basics.
First of all, all SQL statements
should end in a semicolon, so
you might have noticed if you type but
omit the semicolon you get
a set of little ellipses.
Let me show you what that looks like, so
here I am in the Command Prompt
inside the SQLite3 program.
For here, I'm going to type
a statement to create a table,
and don't worry if the statement
doesn't make sense all just yet.
We'll type more into detail about
what the statement means and
what the parameters mean, but right now
just focus on syntax of the semicolon.
Say I finish my create table statement
and I just hit Enter here, so
without the semicolon at the end, the
prompt becomes these three ellipses, and
that's SQL's way of saying,
go on, keep typing.
I'm expecting you to say more, but
it doesn't know you've finished your
instructions already until
you end with that semicolon.
Let's type it in here and type Enter,
so we can take advantage of this
by typing out a single statement
into multiple lines if we need to.
For example, let's create another table,
I'll just call it pets2 this time.
But rather than typing it all out into
one line, I'm going to break it up into
multiple lines and so that semicolon
completed this entire statement.
Quick tip number two,
you'll notice that not all statements
need to end in a semicolon, though.
So, there's a difference between what's
called a dot command, like we always saw
with dot quit or dot tables, and these
SQL commands, such as CREATE TABLE.
Dot commands are SQLite3 specific,
so they're instructions for
the SQLite3 software,
such as to open a file or
to quit the program, but
they're not part of the language of SQL.
Statements that end in a semicolon are
part of the structured query language,
and that's what you'll be interacting
with to interact with your tables and
various ways.
It's also important to call that
dot commands are case sensitive.
That means, typing dot help a lowercase,
it's different from typing dot
HELP capital, so let's try that.
Notice that SQLite does
not recognize that, so
third tip I have for you is that
SQL keywords are case sensitive.
For example,
our CREATE TABLE statement here,
we could have written
it as CrEAte table.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So, say I'm creating
a third table called pets3.
Even with this inconsistent
capitalization here, the statement would
work, but as convention I'm going to
always capitalize the keywords just to
make it easier to read and
I suggest that you do as well.
The final suggestion I have for you is
that hitting the Up and Down arrows will
allow you to scroll through back and
forth through the previous commands.
So, let's hit Up, and it brings in
the command that I typed in earlier.
If I keep hitting up again, notice that
it's pulling in previous commands, so
I just keep hitting up and these
are all the previous things I've typed.
I can also hit down to grab in
the latest stuff, so the Up and
Down keyboard shortcuts
also work in a terminal.
So, say I quit out of
the SQLite program and
hit Up, the most recent command
that I typed in is pulled right in.
I suggest trying out these
four quick tips on your own
before moving onto the next video.