Now that we know what Firebase can do,
you might be eager to
see how it really works.
So you're going to start by downloading
an unfinished copy of the FriendlyChat
app.
Then you'll set up a Firebase project.
You can use a Google account
if you already have one, or
you can just create one
easily if you don't.
So don't worry.
Next you'll create a Firebase
project in the Firebase console.
This project is the home base for the
Firebase features that you'll use for
Android, IOS, and
web versions of your app.
Then we'll link the Firebase project and
dependencies to this app, so
that we can use the Firebase
features in the app itself.
Finally, we'll run the app just to
see what it looks like right now.