So, to summarize, I've basically introduced the whole concept of
feature detection that could be used for matching between two images.
I discussed variety of characteristics, four specifically,
of what makes a good feature.
Briefly introduced Harris Corner Detector and
SIFT, again, some things we will cover in detail a lot more, in the future.
Further reading is available on the website.
But you can look at them here.
And these are a variety of papers that have existed.
These are a variety of papers that
I've come across in the area of computer vision, for doing feature detection.
Includes Sift, and also for example, Harris Corners.
Also I encourage you to look at descriptions like features and
open CV or Matlab sites.
Further lectures will cover more details on SIFT and how we can
apply them to various types of image alignment and image matching approaches.
Again, thanks to a variety sources I picked up information from.
And we'll continue discussing these types of concepts in future lectures.
Thank you.