Now we have a list of weather data
that scrolls in our activity.
Great job!
You've already come so far.
You've accomplished a lot
in this first lesson.
You started with nothing
more than Android Studio and
the hope of one day writing
your first Android app.
Now you've created your first project.
Built and deployed it to virtual and
perhaps actual devices.
And even created a simple scrolling
text based UI that's populated from your
application code.
You also learned a little about what
makes mobile, and Android in particular,
a different environment to develop for
then desktop, web, and server.
But we've only gotten started,
the app that we've got so
far is using static mock data.
So join us in lesson two to learn how we
can hook it up to data from the network.