This one is easy to calculate for SPAM and HAM.
For SPAM, it's 2/5,
and the reason is, we had previously
3 out of 8 messages assigned to SPAM.
But thanks to the Laplacian smoother, we add 1 over here.
And there are 2 classes, so we add 2 times 1 over here,
which gives us 4/10, which is 2/5.
Similarly to get 3/5 over here.
Now the tricky part comes up over here.
Before, we had 0 occurances of the word "today" in the SPAM class,
and we had 9 data points.
But now we are going to add 1 for Laplacian smoother,
and down here, we are going to add 12.
And the reason that we add 12 is because
there's 12 different words in our dictionary
Hence, for each word in the dictonary, we are going to add 1.
So we have a total of 12, which gives us the 12 over here.
That makes 1/21.
In the HAM class, we had 2 occurrences
of the word "today"--over here and over here.
We add 1, normalize by 15,
plus 12 for the dictionary size,
which is 3/27 or 1/9.
This was not an easy question.