hey there it looks like you have a
pending resubmission so I'll help you
understand what resubmissions are and
why we have this process in place also
give you some suggestions on how to best
prepare your project for resubmission if
you haven't watched this video before
going to stick around see you have the
right mindset going forward
first of all
resubmissions are not a bad thing here's
what I mean developers in companies no
matter what their skill level are
subject something that we call code
review
it's a process that we have to catch
mistakes and to double check that our
solutions are the best that we can do
and just re-emphasize even the most
senior developers on a team go through
this process
why because everybody makes mistakes
doesn't matter who you are
everybody's human now your reviewers are
here to make sure that your code or
write ups are solid and well written
this helps you catch any mistakes you
might be making and it's a process that
you can learn from
if you get any feedback that doesn't
make sense to you reach out to us
directly and we can help you out
three
if you don't know how to do what your
reviewer is suggesting reach out to your
community of students for help while the
classes will get you most of the way
there sometimes you'll have to research
things on your own
also remember that you and your fellow
students are in this together
so work with each other in the forums
share your research working and
researching with each other is great
practice for when you're in your next
job for
there are several categories of feedback
that you'll get now the highest priority
items are definitely things you should
address but don't stop there
even if you get feedback that feels
nitpicky to you like your indentation
isn't consistent
although it may feel unimportant you're
getting that feedback for a reason
your code should always be clean and
consistent with best practices
there also might be certain places where
you get certain feedback once but it
actually applies throughout your project
the mixed white space feedback could be
an example of that it's fairly common to
make a mistake that has ramifications
throughout your project
now what's considered nitpicky feedback
by one reviewer might be a pretty big
deal to another and that brings us to
five different submissions might be
reviewed by different reviewers and this
is actually a good thing because it gets
your code in front of a lot of different
people's eyes and brains
they may even disagree with each other
but that's okay too that's good
this gives you more opinions and more
chances to learn from people plus having
multiple reviewers helps us get your
review back to you in record time
finally with all of this said
let's talk about mindset these reviews
are not hurdles that you have to jump
over don't think of him that way
there are opportunities for you to
improve your goal is not to get through
the project at all costs at top speed
remember that your goal should be to
become an awesome developer so keep that
in your mind when you're working through
these suggestions
thanks for watching and have fun making
your project better and better