And, and this is another link related to like the dashboard.
So we had the situation where if we were pushing too much data out,
then the website that was displaying it wouldn't update in time.
And it would sort of be a, the data was coming in so
fast that the browser was constantly updating, rather than,
sort of rendering, because it was too large a render for it.
>> Oh, okay. >> And I just wondered if there was a trick for that.
>> That depends on,
how much you want to pick it up on all frequently refreshing the webpage too.
>> Okay.
>> Because, the thing is like, if you could,
I mean, take the example of a radius, right, and
if you have a scan into a radius, like, let's say your display is going to,
display a brand trend, over like ten days or 20 days, or whatever, right.
So after a five minute interval, then you might want to do,
fetch 24 hours divided by five minutes multiplied by ten days, right?
So that many data points that you would pick up every time.
>> I see.
>> So what I would suggest is like, the page has data for
all the, the time and trouble that you have, and then you fix that a lot.
>> Yes. In the last five minutes only, and then update it internally.
Then throw away that last one.
. And then begin different importing.
>> Like a role model.
>> Yeah.