All right Charles, let's work this out.
>> We're going to work this out?
>> Well, you're going to work this out.
>> Ok well, so I'm looking at this.
I actually think this ones pretty
straight forward to do once
you have the first insight.
The first insight is,
you want to go backwards.
And the reason you want to go
backwards is because I already
know what the answer for the final state
is, and I can go back one step and
use that to figure out what the states
before are, and so on and so forth.
So with that, why don't we actually
be explicit about it then.
So.
>> Yes.
The value of s of f would be zero.
That's a given,
that's pretty easy, okay.
So then I can ask,
well what would be the value of s4 say.
So s4 is the reward you get for leaving
that state and taking the action.
Plus gamma times the state
you're going to end up in.
Well, so that would be 1 + gamma x 0,
which is 1.
Well, that's pretty good.
Okay, and then for
S5 I can do the same thing.
In this case it would be 10 + gamma x 0.
Which of course is 10.
All right, am I right so far?
>> You are right so far, but that's not
the question that was asked, it was S3.
>> Oh, okay.
Fair enough.
All right, so let's do S3 then.
So S3 would be the reward that I get,
which is be 0 + gamma times.
The value of the state that I end up in.
Well, if I end up in state 4,
that would be 1, but sometimes,
I'll end up in state 5,
and that would 10.
So 90% of the time I end up in 1.
10% of the time I end up in 10.
So I multiply the first one by 0.9,
the second one by 0.1.
And then I add them up and
we go from there.
And that number is .9 + 1 is that right.
Which is 1.9.
And that was easy because gamma was 1.
>> Nice very good.
>> So I think actually might
as well go ahead what S1 and
S2 would be then because why not.
>> Okay.
>> All right the value of S1 would be 1
>> Plus
gamma times the value
of S3 which is 1.9.
And so that would be 2.9.
And S2 would be 2 + 1.9,
which is 3.9, so this is good.
So if there was some state zero,
and I had a choice between going to
state one and and state two from it,
I should go to state two.
>> Yes, because it's just the same
expect you get that extra one bonus
going out of state two.
>> Right, okay that makes sense.
>> Great.
Nicely done.
>> Thank you.