Let's use a simple six move isolation
game board to illustrate the ideas.
We'll add green circles to
show probability nodes.
It's O's turn and
it has four possible moves.
The first node we'll explore is the one
where O tries to go to the left most
top position.
But if it tries,
it will only succeed 90% of the time.
>> And 10% of the time, we will end up
at the position to its mediate left.
>> Yep, its other moves are to
try to go one move to the left,
which will do 90% of the time, and
10% of the time, it will overshoot.
>> But
if it attempts to other two positions,
it has no chance to overshoot or
undershoot, so those will be easy.
>> Yep, but let's concentrate
on the left most branch first.
When it's X's turn,
it will have three possible moves.
>> It can try to go immediately right
with 90% chance of being successful and
10% chance of overshooting.
>> Similarly, if it tries to
go the whole way to the right,
it will make it 90% of the time and
undershoot 10% of the time.
>> And if it goes diagonally up and
right, it will hit in 100% of the time.
>> So
now we are ready to do some calculation.
Using our standard number of my moves
evaluation function, O has one move
available to it in this game board and
two nodes available to it here.
That means the expected value of this
branch is 0.9 x 1 + 0.1 x 2, or 1.1.
>> Then for the next node over, we have
a value of 2 for this node times 0.9,
plus the value of the right
node which is 1 times 0.1.
>> But notice, we don't have
to evaluate the right node.
Since this level is a min level,
as soon as we saw the 0.9 times 2,
we have 1.8, that's already bigger
than the 1.1 we had on the left side,
so we know we're never
going to use this node.
We don't have to evaluate
this node at all.
>> That's okay in this case because we
know the evaluation function can't go
below zero.
But, what if our evaluation
function could go negative?
>> Well, then we couldn't prune.
In general, with expectimax, you can
only prune when you have known bounds on
the values that will be returned
by the expectimax function.
>> Okay, so here we'll actually choose
the next branch because its value is 1
and its probability is also 1.
>> So, our expected value for
this node is 1.
Let's try the next sub-tree over.
>> This one is easy.
Looking at the bottom nodes,
everything evaluates to 2, therefore,
all branches will evaluate to 2,
and this node's value is also 2.
>> Great, let's try the next sub-tree.
>> Here again, all the lower nodes
are 2s so the node's value will be 2.
>> The next one over is
a bit more interesting.
The left most bottom node has
only 1 move remaining for O, and
that's multiplied by a 0.9.
Added to that is the 2 times the 0.1,
the node over in case X overshoots,
that leads to a sum of 1.1.
>> Looking at the next branch,
if X tries to go the whole way to
the right, we get a 2 times 0.9 or 1.8.
We could prune this other branch now.
>> Let's calculate it out for
illustration purposes.
>> Okay, well the evaluation function
number of my moves which turned 1 here,
so 2 times 0.9 plus 1
times 0.1 would equal 1.9.
>> But the last option is the best.
It returns a 1 with
a probability of 100%.
>> So the value of this node would be 1.
>> The next option is pretty easy to
calculate, everything comes up 2s.
>> The one after that is also easy
as all the moves are 100% accurate.
Since it's a min node, we'll choose 1.
>> Great, now that we have all
the values calculated, we can choose
the branch with the highest value
at the top of the max node.
>> It looks like this branch wins.
>> Yup, though it won't help
O in this example game.
O is going to lose unless X makes
a bad choice or is unlucky.
>> But if we know our
player O is going to lose,
why shouldn't we try to choose a branch
that was still have the possibility for
X to be unlucky or choose poorly?
>> That is a good point.
In fact, if we use this algorithm and
search to end game,
the algorithm might choose a branch
where X could be unlucky and lose.
Unfortunately, our simple
number of my moves,
evaluation function is not really
capturing that possibility.
Searching deeper than end game
should solve the problem.
Would be a good exercise to do but
now that we've covered everything,
I'm excited to get back to the challenge
question we started at
the beginning of this section.