[Thrun] Now, at this point I would love to go deeper into structure from motion
and tell you more about how to solve it.
But, unfortunately, this is the Introduction to Artificial Intelligence class,
so I really want to leave it at a level that covers the typical material I cover at Stanford.
If you're interested, take a computer vision class.
It's a fascinating subject area.
This finishes my survey of computer vision.
Congratulations. You made it through the computer vision classes.
I think you now understand the very basics of computer vision,
you understand how images are being formed,
how features are being extracted,
and how we can do some very basic 3D inference about the world.
This is just a teaser.
The field of computer vision is of course much richer.
I used to teach the class at Stanford,
and I hope to be able to invite you in the near future
to an actual online 3D computer vision class.