Open up the first exercise
in the second lesson,
T2.1-exercise-createlayout in
Android Studio.
Just as before, you want to do this
instead of continuing with the project
you just created.
You may wonder why we have you create
a project and then immediately ditch it.
We thought it was very valuable to at
least have you walk through the creation
process a couple of times.
>From here on out, we'll be starting
with projects where we'll have
already done a little work for you.
We're going to create the layout for
a Get Help query application.
There are lots of steps here, but
of course, there are also plenty
of to do's to help you out.
You've done some of this before.
We're going to start by replacing the
constraint layout with a vertical linear
layout which, as we've mentioned before,
is useful for stacking views.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We're also going to remove the text
view, add some padding, and
clean things up a bit.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Then we'll add an EditText
to our LinearLayout.
We'll give it an ID, set the text size,
tell it to wrap its content, and
give it a hint.
A hint is some text that displays
when the EditText is empty.
It indicates they should use this
box to type their Get Help query.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now, let's add a text view to display
the URL that we're going to enter.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Since we need to access this text
view from Java, we'll give it an ID.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We'll also set the text size to
help it wrap its content, and
give it a margin to
make things prettier.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Next, we'll reuse something we
learned from the previous lesson,
how to make text scroll.
In this case, we're going to just
make part of the layout scroll.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
To do this, we'll add a ScrollView
to our linear layout and
place a TextView inside of it.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We'll set the text size of that
TextView and give it an ID, so
that we can get to it in Java.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Speaking of getting to the views from
Java, let's go to main activity and
add member variables for our search box
EditText, our URL display TextView, and
our search results TextView.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
One thing to note, if you get red
squiggly lines under TextVew and
EditText, simply hover over them and
click Option and Return on Mac, or Ctrl
and Enter on Windows to have Android
Studio add import statements for you.
After we've declared our variables,
we find each one of these views by ID
in our onCreate and
set them to the member variables.
Notice that Android Studio is once
again warning us with those red
squiggly lines.
To fix this we need to cast the generic
view return by findviewById to
the type of view that we expect.
In this case either EditText or
TextView.
Finally let's remove the unneeded
reference to the constraint layout
library from build.gradle.
Once you remove the reference,
Android Studio will warn you
to sync the project again.
Go ahead and do that.
So, now it's your turn.
Create the get hub query layout and
attach it to your Java code, have fun.