[Thrun] So C is not independent of A.
In fact, A influences C by virtue of B.
But if you know B, then A becomes independent of C,
which means the only determinate into C is B.
If you know B for sure, then knowledge of A won't really tell you anything about C.
C is also not independent of D, just the same way C is not independent of A.
If I learn something about D, I can infer more about C.
But if I do know A, then it's hard to imagine how knowledge of D would help me with C
because I can't learn anything more about A than knowing A already.
Therefore, given A, C and D are independent.
The same is true for E and C.
If we know D, then E and C become independent.