For the span, the answer is log squared.
This outer loop does
log sequential steps.
In each of update ranks and
jump list consist of parallel
fors which have logarithmic span.
What about the work?
The work is actually m log m.
This outer most loop
contributes the log m part.
And since updateRanks and
jumpList visit every node in every
iteration, we have linear cost.
So the total is m log m.
Now seeing this result you
should be disappointed.
Although the algorithm is parallel
it does not work optimal.
Remember the naive sequential
algorithm only has linear costs.
In addition the constants are very low
because it really just touches every
node just once.
So this log m cost and
all these extra buffers really add a lot
of additional overhead to this ranking.
This means you need
a really long list and
lots of processors to see
any speed up in practice.
Now there are ways to do work optimal
list ranking and get decent speed ups.
I'll put a link to one or two of these
algorithms in the instructors notes.