Now that we've got our project
skeleton together, for GigaGal,
let's get to the point where we can
start drawing sprites to the screen.
The first thing to do is going to
be setting up our texture atlas,
which means setting up the pack textures
task in our Gradle Build build file so
we can generate our atlas.
The biggest part of this exercise
is going to be setting up this
Assets singleton class.
Now using the find texture region
method is actually quite slow.
And we want to set up where we only have
to ever do this once for each texture.
Setting up a singleton is a pretty
efficient way to do that.
As part of setting up
our asset singleton,
we'll also create this GigaGal assets
class that will hold onto the specific
regions of the texture outlets
that we'll use to draw GigaGal.
Then over in GameplayScreen,
we'll create all of
the drawing infrastructure we're used
to, like a SpriteBatch and a viewport.
Then down in render,
we'll set the background color,
setup the SpriteBatch's
projection matrix, and
then go grab the texture region out
of our GigaGal assets in our class.
Finally we'll draw that
texture region to the screen.
And here we go,
we've got our first glimpse of GigaGal.
As always, the to-dos in the course code
will show you exactly what you need to
do to setup Asset Loading.
Good luck.