So for Step 6, on the activity itself,
create a class variable
called mSignInProgress.
And three constants, STATE_SIGNED_IN,
STATE_SIGNING_IN and STATE_PROGRESS.
And give these the values 0,
1 and 2 respectively.
Then in your OnConnected override,
which you need to implement,
you're going to manage the buttons.
So this disables the sign-in button and
enables the sign-out and
the revoke buttons.
Then also you want set
the mSignInProgress,
this value, to STATE_SIGNED_IN.
because you've just signed in.
And then finally use the Plus.People.Api
to get the user's name.
And set the status control
to the user's name.
And when you've done all this,
check this box.