Mike, how times have you heard somebody say,
wow, this was a lot harder than I thought
it'd be. — Oh, all the time. I think I heard you
say this morning. — I think I say it a few
times a week, I mean, coding, no matter how
long you've been doing it, there's always difficult
problems come up. — That's true, in
reality, the sign of a good developer
isn't someone who's very smart,
it's someone who's good at solving
problems and can persevere. You're going
to run into problems, you're going to get
frustrated,
there will be times you are confused and
you're going program yourself into a
corner that seems inescapable. Whenever
you run into these situations, it's
important that you keep going.
Not only keep going in the sense that
you just bang your head against the wall
and get more and more frustrated. I mean
going in the sense that day after day,
little by little, you just make some
progress. That's how you can get through
any problem. To help out, here are a few
problem-solving strategies.
First off, there's sleeping on it.
Seriously, it's helpful take a break, come
back fresh, and you'll be surprised to
find how much easier some problems get.
You also have google and Stack Overflow
to help out. Most of the time, your errors
are going to have messages. Copy and
paste those messages into Google, and
you'll be surprised to find out how
quickly you can get answers to your
questions.
Stack Overflow is awesome because people
vote on answers,  so you can get a sense
of what strategy the community thinks
will solve a problem. Seriously,  this is a
great strategy and will solve lots and
lots and lots of problems for you. But
hey, speaking of community, try asking the
community. You aren't alone, remember
you're going to be learning alongside a
lot of other people. Reach out and ask
for help. If you're lucky enough to know
some web developers in real life, talk to
them too. They might be able to point you
in the right direction. And sometimes you
might need to rethink what you're doing.
When I'm working on something
complicated, I like to draw a picture.
This picture is an actual drawing I made
the other night for an actual project.
It's not very pretty, it's just pencil on
graph paper, but it really doesn't have
to be. Shapes,
words, and arrows are often good enough.
This drawing turned out to be super
helpful for me, and wound up saving me a
lot of work later. So, it's often helpful
to get your ideas on paper and stop
juggling them in your head. You'll be
able to make better decisions if you can
see the whole picture. And lastly, I want
you to look at your mistakes and
missteps as learning opportunities, look
at it like this:
you're never really wrong, you just
aren't right yet. That's really solid
advice, I think I've done all of those
things throughout my career.
Yeah I think we all have. To me as you will
know, the best thing is at the end of the
day, feeling is just absolutely
incredible when something starts to work.
We want you to keep these techniques in
mind as you work on your nanodegree and
beyond.