One important aspect of distributed
shared memory systems is,
how do we determine where
a particular page is?
In order to do this the DSM component
has to maintain some metadata.
First, let's see how is a page
identified in this system in
the first place.
Well, the page has its address.
And that may be some notion of
the node identifier plus the page
frame number locally at that node.
And we said that the node
identifier also identifies the home
node of the system.
Considering this address format then,
we see that the address itself
directly identifies what is
the manager node, the home node.
That knows everything about
that particular page.
Every single node in
the system just by looking
at the address of a particular page.
Can uniquely determine what is
the manager node for that page.
So it's as if the manager
information is available on
every single node in the system.
This could be captured via a global
map that has to be replicated
that will tell us how for
a particular object we find the manager.
What that means is that the information
about the manager is available on
every single node.
So it's as if the information
about the manager is
available on every single node.
Since whenever any of the nodes in
the system wants to access a particular
address, they just need to
look at the node identifier.
And we'll be able to get to the specific
manager, the specific home node for
that address.
This information, that captures
the translation from an identifier of
an object, a page in this case.
To the management node of that object.
Represents a global map.
And this needs to be replicated.
It needs to exist.
This information needs to be available
on every single one of the nodes.
Once we get to a particular manager,
that's the entity that will have
the per-page, or per-object, metadata.
That's necessary in order to perform
this specific access to that page or
to enforce its consistency.
What this means is that in
the DSM system, the metadata for
individual objects or individual pages.
It's partitioned across
all of the home nodes.
All of the management
nodes in the system.
But in order to quickly find where the
manager for a particular data item is.
It is necessary to maintain
an additional data structure,
a global map, that will be replicated
on every single one of the nodes.
That will in some way take an object
identifier and map it to that manager.
One final note,
in the example that we discussed so far.
We somehow implied that
certain bits from the address
are used to identify
the node identifier.
And that means that for
every single page,
there will be a fixed manager uniquely
identified from that page identifier.
If we want some additional flexibility,
we can take that object identifier and
then use it as an index
into a mapping table.
This mapping table is the one that
will be used at every single node for
the global map.
And every entry in that mapping table
will actually encode a manager node.
So for a particular object or
a particular page identifier,
we will first index into
that mapping table.
Using some bytes from the object id or
some hash function.
That's applied on top of this object id.
And then, the entry at the particular
location at the mapping table will tell
us what the manager node for
that page is.
What's nice about this approach is.
If for any reason, we want to
change who is the manager node for
a particular object or
of a particular page.
Whether the original manager field or
whether we need to rebalance
the system or any other reason.
We just need to update
the mapping table.
There is no need to consider
making any kind of changes for
the object identifier.
The object can remain identified
in the exact same way
as it was before we chose to make
a change into the manager nodes.