In order to assist our users, we should
give them helpful information when
the database is empty, and the screen
would otherwise display nothing.
We'll take advantage of
the built in capacity for
list view to display an alternate
view when the list is empty, so
our user doesn't see an empty screen.
This functionality is actually part
of the adapter view parent class.
Typically, you place the list view
into a frame layout that contains
the list view and an Empty View, and
then you call the set Empty View
method on your list view.
For now, add a No Weather Information
Available message to your application
when there is no data by using the set
empty view function on your list view.