We just made our app write
messages to the database.
Now, it's pretty cool to see those
messages showing in up the database
console, but for
Friendly Chat to actually work,
our friends need to be able
to read those messages.
Right now,
it's just a plain old empty app.
When we add a message,
it looks like your messages disappear
off somewhere into
the ether of the cloud.
Now in reality,
they are really stored in a database.
But unless our users actually
visit the database console,
which they don't have access to,
they won't see them.
We need to add code so that our app not
only writes data to the database but
also reads and displays data from
the Firebase database back in the app.
Now, reading in Firebase is done
a little bit differently than
the traditional method.
What I mean by traditional method
is that usually, if you want to
read some data, you'd send a request
to your database to read that data.
And the database would reply back
giving you the data that you needed.
Now, if you think this
data might change often,
such as the contents of
a chat message list,
you need to keep checking the database
to see if there are any new messages.
The Firebase real time
database is different,
because it'll actually tell you
proactively when changes occur.
Instead of repeatedly asking if
there are any changes to our data,
our code will automatically be
informed when data is available.
With a single API, Friendly Chat handles
both downloading the existing database
data as well as syncing any
future data updates in real-time.
And it does this through
listeners that are attached to
specific locations in the database.
These listeners are triggered once for
the initial state of the data, and
then again anytime the data is changed.
You'll write some code so that
whenever the listener is triggered, it
will complete the tasks written in the
body of the code that you've written.
Now let's see an example of what one
of these listeners actually looks like
in our Friendly Chat app.