In addition to paging, we said that
virtual to physical memory mappings can
be performed using segments.
So the process is referred
to as segmentation.
With segments the address
space is divided
into components of arbitrary
granularity, of arbitrary size, and
typically the different segments will
correspond to some logically meaningful
components of the address space,
like the code, the heap data, etc.
A virtual address in the segmented
memory mode includes a segment
descriptor, and an actual offset.
The segment descriptor is used in
combination with a descriptor table,
to produce information regarding
the physical address of the segment and
the two are combined.
That information along with the offset,
they're combined to produce the linear
address of the memory reference.
In its pure form,
a segment could be represented with
a contiguous portion of physical memory.
In that case, the segment would be
defined by its base address and
its limit registers,
which implies also the segment size.
So we basically can have segments with
different size using this method.
In practice segmentation and
paging are used together.
What this means is that the address
that's produced using this process and
that one we call the linear address,
is then passed to the paging unit so
it will be passed to a multilevel,
hierarchical page table.
To ultimately compute the actual
physical address that
is used to reference
the appropriate memory location.
The type of address translation that's
possible on a particular platform,
that's determined by the hardware.
For instance, if you look at the Intel
platforms, the x86 platforms,
on 32 bit hardware both segmentation and
paging are supported.
For these platforms on Linux
allows up to 8000 segments to be
available per process and
then another 8000 global segments.
At the same time, on 64-bit Intel
platforms, segmentation and
paging are supported for
backward compatibility, however
the default mode is to use just paging.