Of course,
one interesting way of visualizing these
stereo pairs has been something
referred to as an Anaglyph.
Where you take two images of a stereo
pair, and I'm basically showing you
a very classic image here and it encode
parallax just in a single picture.
What it does, it take two slightly
different perspectives of the same
subject and superimposes them on top
of each other in contrasting colors.
It basically produces
a three-dimensional affect which in mut,
mutual, corresponding set of color
filters gives you a perception of depth.
So for example, these two merged images
here can be now viewed through a red
cyan glass set like this one, and
it will allow you to capture or
at least perceive from this
stereo pair a depth image.
Of course, you've seen enough of
these types of green cyan glasses.
Here is one simple one, and if you just,
were able to look at the scene from
this, you would actually see depth.
Let's look at a little bit more of
these Anaglyph types of images.
Here is one that you
may have seen you know,
there is a lot of these types of
images came up after the Mars Mission
where basically they generated a lot
of these nice Anaglyph images.
Another one again a very well known
classic example of Anaglyph images.