We're going to do another
programming exercise here.
Now this exercise will
be pure JavaScript.
Are you familiar with
what a palindrome is?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
So a word that can be spelled forward
and backward the same way.
>> Yeah.
>> I would like you to build a function
that returns true or false.
If a string is a palindrome.
>> Okay, how detailed do you
want the JavaScript to be?
Can I write pseudocode?
Or do you want me to see
the actual JavaScript code?
>> Eventually, we would like to
see the actual JavaScript, but
if you want to step through
pseudocode first, that's fine.
>> I always like to step
through pseudocode myself,
just to tell you my thinking process.
>> Okay.
So basically.
I will have a function here.
[NOISE]
Is palindrome.
And it will take a string.
Okay?
>> Okay.
>> So that's my silica.
And I'm going to do Then it's like
how I would approach a palindrome.
Because.
Let's just confirm
the definition of a palindrome.
Palindrome is basically
if I have a string here.
Say gog.
Backwards or forwards.
It will be the same right?
>> Correct.
>> So
if I were to somehow transform this.
If I were to reverse this.
And then do an if statement.
So, if gog is the equals of reverse of
gog, that's my logic, that's a palantir.
>> Okay.
>> So,
what I would do is I would need to
figure how to reverse the strings.
So, I'll probably do a reverse string,
I'll call it a function.
So are reverse string,
equals reverse string.
My string.
So if So, what's at my reverse rate?
So, if string equals reverse
string, return
true else return.
False.
Okay so this logic is done.
I always need to make sure
you need to figure out this.
So how do I do that?
So I will write,
already with my pseudocode
to space the code as well I
would write when you see this.
I would write.
A function on top here
called reverse string.
Reverse string.
Takes a string variable and reverse it.
So, I know that there is no,
correct me if I am wrong
there is no library,
in the stream library there
is no way to reverse it.
>> A stream has a native of method for
reverse.
>> So there is a [INAUDIBLE] method.
>> So let's kill off this here.
>> Ok.
And we'll just do.str.reverse.
>> Okay.
>> But that's not something you would
look up anyway in documentation so.
>> Right.
>> Okay, got it.
>> So, this is your test case here.
Right?
>> Right.
>> So I'm going to introduce
another test case.
>> And want to ignore punctuation
>> I see.
>> And actually let me, another case.
We would like to ignore punctuation and
case sensitivity.
>> Okay.
So does your current solution meet that?
>> No.
>> Okay.
>> Of course not, so my current-
>> So how would you change it?
>> How would I change it?
Okay, so now this would probably
be good for me to actually.
Rename my reverse clean,
reverse clean up.
>> [LAUGH]
>> [LAUGH] I would do that.
I would name this to reverse
clean up string.
I'll keep this whole logic
because it's a good logic.
To follow.
And I'll go back up here.
And figure out how to get
rid of my punctuation here.
Reverse cleanup.
All right so the first step already
is like I'm basically going to
reverse this first string.
So reverse string
equals string reverse.
Now, I know that string will has some
new best methods called lower string to
lower to lower stress.
So, I need to look up the exact
definition but basically reverse String.
Equals rough string
to lowercase.
Now I need to figure out these
punctuation marks there.
How would I do that?
So let's let's think about I
need to write all these test
cases like what makes a punctuation,
what are these punctuation marks?
So puncts.
Period, comma, semicolon.
Shoot.
Yeah-
>> [INAUDIBLE]
>> Quotes, double quotes, single quotes.
I have comma already.
Comma, let me see, let me think of
other punctuation, yeah, question mark.
Back tick,
all the things that is not alphanumeric.
So I'm going to ask you.
Can I assume that I
have alpha characters,
can there be numeric characters as well.
>> We will say no numbers, just alpha.
>> Just alpha.
So I know that I'm going to
use a reader expressions.
>> Okay.
>> Probably,
so probably
>> Oops in.
I want you to look this up
>> That's fine.
>> My new expression.
I just knew that i would
know that i would choose
something probably the W word.
>> Okay
>> I would need to figure out where
the word has two merits if not
then actually I think includes.
Yeah im glad i use it.
Right now expression, a to z, and
do probably
>> That's fine.
>> Yeah.
>> You're on the right track.
>> Yeah, I did a to z and we'll to do
some sort of regular expression like,
re match.
Last string..
So I'm rusty a moderate of expression.
No, that's fine.
We'll just.
>> Yes so
basically I use regular expressions and
then find find the ones that are not.
Belong to A to Z and then reply and
didn't get rid of them or
replace them in a way.
And then, that will get rid of all
our punctuation because based on just
looking for
all instances of characters A to Z.
>> Right.
So I see a potential for a bug here.
>> Okay.
>> Use the var statement here but you're
not using a var statement up here,
what is the significance
of that var statement?
>> The var statement is
actually really crucial so
I would actually correct them,
correct my statement.
Because that will guarantee that
I'm creating a local, variable.
>> Without the what happens?
>> It will first try to access any
global variables that it sees.
If not, it will create the current
global variable which is that there.
[LAUGH] Okay overall this
looks good just I guess to
explain a little better,
these functions here.
We'll illiterate over the entire
string every single time.
So, this isn't the most efficient way,
but it does get the job done.
>> Right.
>> So,
what we should do is this would
iterate over the whole string, then.
And then you'd get iterate
the whole string again.
>> Again.
>> And then you'd iterate it
again trying to get your matches.
>> Yeah.
>> A more efficient way to go
about this, the red x is correct
>> You could match that way, and
then you could iterate over the string
forward using left and backwards, and
just check character by character.
And then you're only iterating
over the string one time, but
this works perfectly fine.
>> I see.