After the data is prepared, the next
step is to perform the analysis and,
if appropriate, model the problem.
There are a number of different methods
available for performing the analysis.
In the next lesson of this course,
we'll go into detail on how to select
the methodology and modeling method
that is best suited for your scenario.
Let's us our electricity example
to elaborate on this step.
Earlier, in the problem
solving framework,
we determined that we needed
to predict the temperature for
the next day using some of
the factors we identified.
And then, we are going to predict the
electricity usage using the predicted
temperature as well as other factors.
So we start by building
out a predictive model
that helps us predict
the temperature for the next day.
We have identified a number of
factors that may be good at predicting
temperature.
But we'll start with one to
create our initial model and
learn during the process.
Once we have created our first model,
we'll validate it and
then determine if we need to update
the model with additional information.
Once we have a model that we can
confidently predict temperature with,
we'll repeat the process to
predict electricity usage.
After creating a model that
we're comfortable with,
one that predicts electricity usage for
a given hour on the next day,
we need to perform our analysis.
This may include the number of
electricity plants that we need for
any given temperature, as well as
the thresholds when we need to activate
additional plants or
purchase electricity on the market.
We'll probably perform
the analysis step multiple times
until we have confidence
in our analysis.
So let's discuss how we get the level
of confidence that we need.