All right, so let's take a look
at some Traceview output.
Notice this big section
pf activity here, but
let's talk about a few observations.
You might notice that the top
function here is the most
resource-intensive when sorted.
Now, there are a few others,
such as this nativePullOnce.
But these are system
methods that we don't own.
So if we go down a little bit further,
notice that we have this nativeSetPixel
and this nativeGetPixel.
So let's see where they're coming from.
Let's go ahead and expand a little bit.
Ah-ha, here we go.
So setPixel looks like it's being called
from something within our busy UI
thread activity,
which is from the sample app code.
And the same is the case for getPixel,
which also seems to be coming
from our busy UI thread activity.
So now that we've identified
that setPixel and getPixel
come from our busy UI thread activity,
let's go ahead and explore them further.