Using heap viewer, we can see that after
the first GC, only 1.39 megs is free.
This may indicate that the garbage
collector wasn't able to reclaim much
memory due to a leak.
After a second GC event, heap viewer
indicates that the system has decided to
accommodate a larger memory footprint
for this app by allocating more memory.
Increasing the heap
size to 32 megabytes,
which is up from 20
megabytes in the first GC.
This time,
we have 12.9 megabytes free in our heap.
At this point, the system is
dynamically accommodating for
the larger memory footprint of this app.
If the expansion repeats, this may lead
to an app crash if the system can no
longer allocate more memory for the app.
So remember, memory leaks are slow and
they're insidious and require time and
the proper test environment to confirm.
Also, keep in mind that
sometimes a pattern like this
might represent
a legitimate use of memory.
For example,
imagine an application that was designed
to manipulate large graphics or photos.
The takeaway here is be on the lookout
for slow leaking memory, but
always weigh the data you collect,
against the memory implications
of your app's core functionality.
Now at this point, you should understand
how memory leaks manifest in the SD.
At this point, you should understand how
memory leaks manifest in SDK provided
tools such as Memory Monitor and
Heap Viewer.
But you might not know
where they originate.
Here are some best practices
you can take to avoid a leak.
Track the life of your objects
throughout your code and
clean up references when
you no longer need them.
Okay, so in the next slide,
we'll identify what might
be causing this leak.