So the intention for
this task was to give you practice
with reading a tutorial on the web and
seeing another example of JSON
parsing in action for Android.
This example starts assuming a specific
JSON response is stored in a string
called STR JSON or STR JSON for short.
You may notice that the string also
has the back slash characters included
wherever there's a quotation mark.
But normally it would look
like the JSON we've seen.
Okay, so let's go and
examine the code here in this example.
The first thing I'm going to do is
actually copy and paste this block of
code out of this small middle window so
it's easier to read.
And then we can examine it from there.
So all I've done here is copy the code
example into a simple text editor.
In this case I'm using Sublime text
edit, but any text editor would work.
So let's go ahead and talk about
the code that's here in onCreate.
So you already know about
the string STRJSON,
which contains a raw JSON,
and the main code
that we're trying to look at here is
actually in our try block right here.
So let's examine
the lines one at a time.
The first thing we do is
we create a new JSON object
from the JSON string
that we created earlier.
Then the next thing that happens is
we find the employee's jsonArray
by looking for the key called employee.
Now, instead of using a getter
method such as getjsonArray,
you see a method called
optjsonArray used.
This is simply an alternative
way to get the JSONArray back.
If you were to check the official
android documentation At
developer.android.com, you'd see
that the method optJSONArray
needs to return a JSONArray if
it exist for a given key name.
Now if the array doesn't exist, then
the method will return no otherwise.
All right, so the next major thing
that we do is we create a loop
to iterate thought each
element in the array.
Now, in this first line here, we're
extracting the individual element of
the array happens to be
a JSON object in this case.
By calling the method get
JSON object with the index i.
Then we extract out the integer ID,
the string name, and the float salary.
Which in this case is a decimal value,
then we can calculate all these
values into one long string.
And then later display all
the texts in a text screen.
You probably noticed that there's
a tri catch blocks surrounding
the JSONEparseInt code.
Which actually prevents the app
from crashing if there's a problem
with parsing.
But don't worry, we'll talk
about this more in detail later.