the data is prepared the next step is to
perform the analysis and if appropriate
model the problem
there are a number of different methods
available for performing the analysis in
the next lesson of this course will go
into detail on how to select the
methodology and modeling method that is
best suited for your scenario let's use
our electricity example to elaborate on
this step
earlier in the problem solving framework
we determined that we needed to predict
the temperature for the next day using
some of the factors we identified and
then we're going to predict the
electricity usage using the predicted
temperature as well as other factors
so we start by building out a predictive
model that helps us predict the
temperature for the next day we have
identified a number of factors that may
be good at predicting temperature but
we'll start with one to create our
initial model and learn during the
process
once we have created our first model
will validated and then determine if we
need to update the model with additional
information
once we have a model that we can
confidently predict temperature with
will repeat the process to predict
electricity usage
after creating a model that we're
comfortable with one that predicts
electricity usage forgiven our on the
next day we need to perform our analysis
this may include the number of
electricity plants that we need for any
given temperature as well as the
thresholds
when we need to activate additional
plants or purchase electricity on the
market will probably perform the
analysis step multiple times until we
have confidence in our analysis
so let's discuss how we get the level of
confidence that we need