So, that was an operation.
Now, try it yourself on requirement
four, which is the one that
says children, and that was age 12 and
under, have a special restriction.
They can only check out
five items at a time.
So, I'd like you to try and
write that and
I'll give you a couple
hints along the way.
You're going to have to specify
a pre-condition for this one.
And remember preconditions indicate
what must be true in order for
the checked out operation to execute.
And be aware that this is
not going to be a complete
specification for checked out.
We saw part of it in
the previous exercise.
And there's lots more
to checking things out.
We're just concerned with the part
of checkout that has to do with
the children.
So, see if you can specify for
this particular part of it
what the constraint is.
>> So, before I get started I had a
question in regards to, this requirement
almost sounds to me more like
an invariant than it does a pre or
post condition of checking out.
I don't know if there's a check out
limit, so to speak, for patrons,
but is this one of those
situations in which there
could be differing ways to
express this requirement?
>> So, first off, there's no check out
limit for patrons in the requirements.
>> Okay.
>> Other than for children.
And I'll disagree a little bit.
This is the number of items
that are checked out,
is something that varies for
children or for patrons as a whole.
And It varies depending upon
has the operation executed?
So, every time that child wants to check
something out, it has to be checked.
I think that it feels better to have it
associated with a particular operation
than its invariant because, I mean,
as a statement of truth,
it doesn't vary.
But our need to check it
is associated with this operation
of checking things out.
See if you can do it with operation.
>> So, is this context the patron?
Is the child association or
a generalization of the patron class?
>> So, recall when we did the original
analysis, that we had a choice.
We could've had a subclass
child of patron.
Or we could have,
essentially, an attribute.
And recall that the issue that
arose was little Timmy, today,
is 11 years old and
having a birthday tomorrow.
And they would change from being a child
class to a full adult patron class.
Now, there are ways of
modeling that in UML.
But, in general,
in object oriented languages, you
can't change the class of an instance.
So, we decided, in this case,
to use an attribute.