Now I want to get at the idea of reducing b, the branching factor.
How is it that we can cut down on the number of nodes that we expand
in the horizontal direction while still getting the right answer for the evaluation of the tree?
Let's go back and consider that during our evaluation, if we get to this point,
we've expanded these three nodes, we figured out that the value of this one is 3,
we looked at this one so far and found its value was 2,
and now, without looking at these, what can we say about the value of this node?
Well, it's a minimizing node, so the least it could be is 2.
If these are less than 2, it'll be less than that, and if these are more, it'll end up being 2.
We can say that the value of this node is less than or equal to 2.
Now if we look at it from Max's point of view,
Max will have this choice here of choosing either this, this, or this,
and if this one is 3 and this one is less than or equal to 2,
then we know Max will always choose this one.
What that tells us is that it doesn't matter what the value is of this node and this node.
No matter what those values are this is still going to be less than or equal to 2,
and is not going to matter to the total evaluation,
because we're going to go this way anyway.
We can prune the tree, chop off these nodes here, and never have to evaluate.
Now, with this particular case, that doesn't save us very much,
because these are terminal nodes, but these could have been large branches--
big parts of the tree, and we still wouldn't have to look at them.
We've made a potentially large pruning without effecting the value.
We still get the exact correct value for the value of the tree.