[Thrun] And the answer is that while K-means will go all the way to the extreme, A,
which is this one over here, EM will not.
And this has to do with the soft versus hard nature of the correspondence.
In K-means the correspondence is hard.
So after the first situation, only these 2 data points over here
correspond to cluster center 1,
and they will find themselves straight in the middle where A is located.
In EM, however, we find that there will still be a soft correspondence
to these further away points which will then lead to a small shift of the cluster center
to the right side, as indicated by B.
That means K-means and EM will converge at different models of the data.