From these options,
the only correct option is the file on
the remote server has been removed.
The file is outdated really implies that
the file has been written by somebody
else potentially, since a particular
client acquired the file handle.
So that may be a consistency
related problem, but
it really doesn't return a stale handle.
The fact that the remote
server is not responding,
that's really more of
an RPC layer error.
If the server is not responding
that has nothing to do
with our ability to access a file at
some point or another on that machine.
It may simply be a network error.
And the final option is also wrong, the
file handle will not become stale just
because a file was open for too long.
There may be some distributed file
systems which provide only time places
where a client is only allowed
to keep a file open for
a period of time, but
NFS is not one of them.
So for
that reason this answer is not correct.