For completeness, I want you to work
out the total overall running time of
a distributed Bitonic sort.
Let's start with computation and
ignore communication.
Here's a picture to remind you of what
a whole Bitonic sort looks like in
the circuit model.
In this case, for an input of size 16.
Now consider this first stage,
you'll notice it's a bunch of Bitonic
merge operations on pairs of inputs.
Now what this stage will produce
are Bitonic sequences of length 4.
So that's stage 2.
Let's look at stage 2.
It similarly consists of Bitonic merge
operations, this time of length 4.
And of course what it produces
are Bitonic sequences of length 8.
And, of course, this pattern repeats.
This third stage uses
Bitonic merges of size 8
to produce a bitonic
sequence of length 16.
Now, what about the last stage?
The last stage is just a single
Bitonic merge of length 16.
What it gives you is the sorted output.
Now, notice there are log
n merging stages.
And remember what each box looks like.
So let's consider some stage K.
In this case, K equals 3.
It performs simultaneous
merges of size 2 to the k.
Now suppose there are p processes and
you use a block distribution scheme.
In this example, P equals 4.
Each process owns n over P elements.
Now the kth merging stage performs
K x N over P comparisons,
and if each comparison
costs tao time units,
then the total time to do
the comparisons is tao n over P x K.
That, of course, is at merging stage K.
Now recal there are log and
merging stages.
So you need to sum this
cost over all stages.
And if you work it all
out you should get this.
This cost makes sense, right?
For instance, you already knew
that bitonic sorting was not work
optimal by a factor of log n compared
to the usual n log n comparison scheme.
But at least all the comparisons
are perfectly paralyzable.
Hoot.