Cramer's V then would be 7.78 divided by 150 times k which is 2 minus 1, which
is just 1. This comes out to about 0.23. What does this mean? Well, remember
Jacob Cohen, you calculated Cohen's D before. He's a very renowned
statistician. He established some guidelines for Cramer's V, which help us
decide if this is a large, small or medium effect size. This table provides his
standards for interpreting Cramer's V as k increases. However, Cohen is quite
cautious in his suggested use of these values. He treats them more as labels to
aid future power analysis rather than hard and fast descriptors. But these can
kind of give us the idea that the value we got for Cramer's V is a small
effect.