All right, let's find out the size and class.
Octave prints out the height of the image first, and
then the width, height is 320 and width is 500.
On the next line we see that the class of the image is uint8.
If you type these values in correctly good job.
So the height and width turned out to be 320 and 500 respectively and
the class was uint8.
Now what does uint8 mean?
Some of you may know this already, u stands for
unsigned, which means this data type cannot represent negative numbers.
Int stands for integer and eight refers to eight bits or one byte.
This is sometimes known as the bit depth.
It indicates the number of bits allocated to store each intensity value.