For the first project you'll build a
neural network to predict bike-sharing
rides. Imagine yourself owning a bike sharing
company like Cycle Hop. You want to
predict how many bikes you need because
if you have too few you're losing money
from potential riders. If you have too
many you're wasting money on bikes that
are just sitting around. So you need to
predict from historical data how many
bikes you'll need in the near future. A
good way to do this is with a neural
network which is exactly what you'll do.
In this notebook, you'll implement a
neural network and train it on
historical data to make predictions.
First, load and prepare the data. We
provided the code to prepare the data
but you'll be learning how to do all
this in a future lesson. So feel free to
read it over but you'll just need to run
through the code.
This is where you'll build your network.
We provided some of the code for the
network but you'll be implementing most
of it. And down here is where you'll
train the network and view its
performance as it's being trained.
Finally you'll compare your networks
predictions with actual data. If you
build your network right you should find
the network does a really good job, for
the most part. Right! It's time for you to get
started on your project.
Good luck!