Before I came to Udacity, I was an
elementary school teacher and there are
a lot of things I liked about it. But it
just wasn't the right job for me.
So after that, I really started to try to
go back to school and I wanted to do
something in computer science. But I find
it was really difficult to balance class
and working full time. I was looking for
a program that that could work on my
timeframe and my schedule. I wasn't
able to leave my job, I couldn't, you know,
go away for nine weeks and doing
bootcamp or anything like that. So I was
like, I have to find something that's
either online or in the evenings. And so
that narrows it down quite a bit. I
discovered Udacity from developers
that I interacted with on a regular
basis. I kept pestering them to learn
what resources they used to grow
themselves professionally and personally.
And eventually a developer
pointed me towards Udacity. He said
this is a great resource for someone
like you. I went with iOS. I like
the mobile aspect of it specifically,
because I really like the portability
aspect. And you can build an app
really pretty quickly and get it
onto your phone and have it with
your finger, you know at your fingertips
at any time. I think that's really cool.
Udacity provided that platform of clear
structure and being able to learn the core
elements of iOS within a very quick
time and build on it rapidly. I went from
no coding ability nine months later to
building iOS apps. Udacity is what gave
me the confidence to be like I can do
that, I can figure out how that works.
I had tried other online college programs
before and it's very easy easy to start
feeling like you're isolated. And with
Udacity, not just when you got stuck on
something, but there's also a lot of
other opportunities to communicate with
your peers.
Here's the project you need to do,
here's what we require. It's almost like you
know working and building apps that have
like design requirements. Providing the
community to really like tackle some
problems. Like hey I don't know what I'm
doing here, can someone help me out.
And then also to begin providing some
contributing back and help answer other
people's questions. Like hey I grappled
with the same thing, here's how I did it.
I've seen a transition from the point
where my business was an idea to when I
had a product to just on my phone. So when I
have a product in the App Store.
it's fun talking to people and
seeing how the reactions have changed
throughout all those steps.
I would recommend this Udacity Nanodegree to everyone.
I am using the skills that I've
learned at Udacity every day. Not just
the very specific things they taught me,
but learning to find the answers on my own.
Because there's so much more to know
and what Udacity provides is that
foundation and the skills you need to go
out and learn those new things.
I now work at Audible as an iOS developer.
A lot of the skills I've learned, I've
already so totally totally totally worth it.
If I met someone in a party and I
wanted to tell them about what the iOS
Nanodegree was like, I would tell them
that it is definitely a challenge, but it
is so worth it, because you end up with
the skills that you need to get a job in
iOS development. It's just remembering
where you want to get to and not being
too daunted by it and just staying on
that journey. And just every day you're
going to learn something new and
sometimes maybe you don't want to pick up on
this but because you want just continuing to
just push forward and learn new things
and when you get to that point that you
have your app in the App Store, it's it's
it all it all be worthwhile then.
But don't don't wait. If this is what you
want to do with your life, start right now.
we're so proud of our students and
we can't wait to see what you'll build.
Let's get started