First, reduce false alarm rate,
while detecting as many
intrusions as possible.
This is true.
Obviously, we want to detect
as many intrusion as possible.
We also want to reduce
the false alarm rate so
that we don't burden
the systems with false alarms.
Second, apply detection models at
all unfiltered packet data directly.
This is false, because most likely,
the base rate at this level is very low.
Therefore, the IDS will have
a low Bayesian detection rate.
Third, apply detection models
at processed event data
that has higher base rate.
This is true, because as long as
we can keep the intrusion evidence
in the event data, the event data is
gong to have a higher base rate and
therefore, the ideas will have
a higher Bayesian detection rate.