Famous computer scientist
Edsger Dijkstra said,
if debugging's the process
of removing software bugs,
then programming must be
the process of putting them in.
There's a lot of truth to that.
When we're programming, we're bound
to introduce errors in our code.
Even the best apps on the app store
have their fare share of software bugs.
So as developers, we can expect we'll
be spending a lot of time debugging and
fixing our problems, whether it's
our own code or even someone else's.
But trust me,
it's not as bad as it sounds.
Debugging's just part
of being a programmer.
And thankfully for us,
Xcode makes this process easy and fun,
once you know what you're doing.
My name's Jared Parks, and
I'll be the instructor for this course.
Let's get started.