To optimize your user experience on
different screen sizes, probably
the most useful resource qualifier would
be the smallest width or sw qualifier.
This allows you to create
different resources for
devices based on the smallest dimension.
Let's see how this is used in
an example directory structure.
Here you can see that there are three
different layout folders within our
res directory, layout,
layout-sw600dp, and layout-sw720dp.
The first layout folder
should look familiar.
It's the default folder for
all of our activity layouts.
Next, you can see that the sw600dp and
720dp folders have layouts
like detail activity and
list item, that have the same name
as those in our default folder.
And these layouts will override
the default resources if
a device has the smallest widths,
meaning 600dp or larger for
layout-sw600dp, and 720dp or
larger for layout-sw720dp.
So, say your app is on a Nexus 5,
which has dimensions 360 by 640dps.
Android knows that the smallest width,
no matter the orientation
of this device, is 360dp.
And we use this number to compare
against the folder names.
Since 360dp is smaller than 600 or
720, this device
doesn't satisfy the minimum requirement
for any of these smallest width folders.
And so this device will retrieve all of
its layouts from our base layout folder.
Let's look at a larger device.
For the Nexus 7 2013 version,
the dimensions are 600 by 960dps.
Android sees that of the two dimensions,
the smallest width here is 600dp.
This is exactly equal to 600dp, so
this will go to our layout-sw600dp
folder to retrieve the layouts for
the detail, activity and list item.
However, when it comes to the main
layout, activity_main.xml, it doesn't
see a layout in the 600dp folder, and so
it defaults to a less specific folder,
in this case, the base layout folder and
uses the activity_main file from here.
What about for
an even larger tablet like the Nexus 10?
Its dimensions are 1280 by 800dp.
Out of these two dimensions,
the smallest width is 800dp.
This is both bigger than 600 and
720dp, and so
it matches the qualifications for
both of these folders.
And the system will choose the most
specific layout folder to use first.
So, this will use the list_item
layout from inside
the layout-720dp folder over
the two other list item resources.
Then, because that's the only one
defined in the layout-sw720dp folder,
it will get less specific when it
looks for the other two layouts.
It will look at the next closest folder,
the layout-sw600dp folder,
for the detail_activity.xml.
And finally,
it will retrieve its activity main
layout from the base layout folder.
Each time, it gets less specific as
it tries to find layout resources.
So, by using the smallest width
qualifier on new layout folders,
Android lets us create
alternate layout resources for
each of these devices
based on their size, and
it lets us pick which default
layout resources to override.
You can also use the smallest width
qualifier to create alternate
values resource folders.
So this is a really useful tool for
building responsive layouts that look
good across all types of devices.