Using D3.js you can add, remove and
change DOM nodes programmatically.
I'll show you how to change the
background color of this navigation bar.
First I'll right-click on
the element and click Inspect.
Now, sometimes you might not
get the element you intended,
because the element you click on is
a child of the element that you want.
You can check this by looking
at the highlighted element and
the HTML tag in this HTML panel.
You want to be sure you
have the right element.
Now, looking at this,
it looks like I have a child
element of one of the parent ones.
So I have this navbar header which
doesn't quite grab the entire navbar.
And I can see this by hovering
over the DOM element.
Here's a nav container, and then here
it looks like I have the entire navbar.
So let's use one of the classes
here to select the navbar element.
So I'll select this navbar by using the
.navbar class in my select statement.
I noticed a D3 arrays is returned
which contains our DOM node.
And hovering over the DOM node
highlights the element in
the View window.
Now if we want to change
the background color,
we'll need some sort of D3 method to
adjust the style or the CSS properties.
Let's go to the documentation.
So in Selections,
we're going to look for
something that can
adjust CSS properties.
And it's looks like this one, style,
will do it, get or set style properties.
The style method allows you to change
the styling of a particular element on
the page, by passing in a CSS
property and a corresponding value.
Also, notice that the style property
operates or acts on a selection.
This is important for
the chainable nature of D3,
which you'll see in just a minute.
Also, notice that we can set
more than one property at once.
We can pass in an object literal,
which is just the notation
of a JavaScript object.
And we pass in the properties
that we want as the keys
in the corresponding values.
Let's try this out on a console.
So with my selection I'm going to
pass in a key of background color.
And recall if I don't pass in any value,
then I'll just get what's currently
set as the background color.
And now if I'd like to
change the background color,
I want to pass in a corresponding
value as the second argument.
Now, there's two important
things to notice here.
First, the background color on the nav
bar did actually change, I mean,
that's what we wanted to do.
And second,
the code returned another array, and
let's look at what was returned.
It looks like a selection.
It turns out it's the same
selection we had before.
And this is why many of
D3's methods are chainable,
most methods defined in D3 return
whatever object they were called on.
So in this case, D3 finds and
returns a selection and
then passes that selection
to the next function.
So, before we were saving our selection
into our variable called elem, but
we actually don't even
need this variable.
We can just use our first selection and
then chain on the style function
to work on that for selection,
and this is what I mean by
the chainable nature of D3's API.
You can use multiple functions to
operate on different selections,
or in different objects,
that are D3 objects.
So again if I would like to
change the nav bar, all I need to
do is select the nav bar first and
then style the background as I'd like.
This second method operates on
the first selection that we created.
And this entire function, or this second
method, returns a new selection for us.
[BLANK_AUDIO]