Let's talk about answers to these
questions we have ,about how many
vulnerabilities do we know about in
software that is running on our systems.
So, first there's how
many vulnerabilities
do you think are there in the NVD?
Unfortunately, the number is
the largest possible that we have
is the answers is close to 70,000.
The last time I checked
it was 69,000 something.
We're talking about tens of
thousands of vulnerability.
To that there is millions and million
of lines code out there, that have been
developed by all kind of people and
companies and things like that.
But these vulnerabilities that can
be exploited by attackers are not
necessarily very rare,
we know about lots and
lots of them so that's answer is 70,000.
So then we going to focus
just on buffer overflows,
we know what exactly
buffer overflows are.
We going to do our,
fix our vulnerability for checking or
things like that.
We know we can make them go away.
Well, the last three months if you look
at, and this is sometime in middle
of March in 2015,
we actually have close to 100, actually
the number was 107 I think, buffer
overflow vulnerabilities that have been
reported to the National Vulnerability
Database in just the last three months.
If you look at the last three years,
the number is about 1,000,
a little over 1,000,
which means the rate at which these
come at us not necessarily decreasing.
Because in three months,
if you have close to 100,
in a year you'll have about 400.
In three years we'll have 1,200,
so it's in the range.
Looks like we're seeing this
vulnerabilities becoming known
at the rate that doesn't seem
to be going down significantly,
compared to two years ago or
something like that.
So the answers are that even when we
focus on buffer overflow ,we seeing
almost a vulnerability everyday.
Close to 100 over three months.
That's about 90 some days.
So we're seeing almost a new buffer
overflow vulnerability every day,
leading to thousands of those or
close to 1,000 in the last three years.
So the takeaway here is that
software vulnerabilities.
Now we know how they get exploited.
They are out there and
they provide a very viable path for
attackers to craft attacks and
gain control of our systems.
And we know that, we discovering
them almost on a daily basis.
And the attackers
perhaps know about them.
They discover them before you do, and
then they're able to exploit them.
Because you don't have any defenses or
any widely deployed patches to fix them.