Okay, we've done this
a couple times before, so
I'm going to move pretty quickly.
But I've linked to the original video
if you want a slower walk-through.
All right, click Start a new
Android Studio project.
Our app is going to be
called Court Counter.
And as long as you
haven't changed anything,
your company domain should be
the correct android.example.com.
And then I'll let you decide where
you're going to locate your project.
Downloads is probably not a good place,
so I'm going to change that for myself.
Okay, we'll put it in Documents.
As with before, we're designing only for
a phone and a tablet, and
we're going to use API Level 15.
And we'll stick with what we know, use
Blank Activity, and keep these defaults.
All right, it's going to load for
a little bit.
Okay, great, and
there's my new Court Counter app.
Move on and we'll make this more
than just a Hello World app.