This class is all about 3D vision.
There's a scene somewhere here, and there's a camera over here,
and the scene is projected into the camera plane.
Obviously, the camera image is only 2D. The scene is 3D.
3D vision vision attempts to recover the full 3D information.
The most important missing thing is called the range,
sometimes called depth or distance to the camera plan.
Cameras are deficient in that they can only recover 2D information-
a perspective projection of the image.
The question right now is going to be can we possibly recover the full 3D information
about the scene outside the camera just as single or modular camera images.