I'll start off by enabling the
JavaScript profiler, I'll hit record and
then I'll hit both buttons.
There's 1, and there's the second.
To give myself more space I'll
pop this into a second window.
WIth the flame view enables it's pretty
obvious to see what's going on here.
Here's the first click and
here's the second 1.
As a child of the first
click event on sort 1 run.
And, as a child of the second
click event on sort 2 run.
And just looking here it's
pretty obvious that answer 1
took longer to run.
Before I move on,
I want to point out some interesting
bits in this little sample.
If you're in the flame view and
you click on the top-level click
record like this one here,
you can pull up the details pane for
some useful information.
This pie chart gives you an idea
of how much time it took
different events caused
by this function to run.
You can get the scripting time for
this function itself,
which tells you how long it
took just this function to run.
And if this function called any others,
which this one did, then you can see
how long it took it's children to run.
In this case the function
that ran on the click called
other functions including
the bubble sort one,
which is included in this
children scripting time.
I've changed over to
the second click event for
the second event and you can see that
the scripting time for its children,
is only 260 milliseconds,
which is about half of answer 1.
I want you to notice one other thing.
After the first click there
is a recalculate style and
then a layout event, and
after the second click there is another
recalculate style and
another layout event.
These two pairs of recalculate style and
layout are essentially the same length.
This is a clear indication that no
matter how you sort the data in this
example, you still have to write
out the whole table of results,
which is going to require recalculating
styles, relaying out the page, and
repainting everything.
So with all that in mind,answer
1 took longer to run.