Let me use this concept to introduce
the basic premise of what is called
Image Morphing.
Here, you basically see,
now a sequence of images generated,
to be able to go from one frame to
the other, which we actually captured
separately the rest of them were
basically generated, on their own.
So, this created and animation
that basically changes all morphs.
One image, and
it could be shaped also into another
through a seamless transition.
This is widely used in movies and
is actually a very well known concept
in even trying to understand shapes.
And in fact this very famous
book I recommend anybody
who's interested in shape and
form to look at this,
that talks about biological phenomenon
that could be tested to this.
And talks about we can, basically,
take a simple surface like this.
And by changing the regions and
the warp itself, generate other types
of fish that actually, you know,
have the same kind of structure but
of course, now have different shapes and
stuff like that.