I need to also spend a few minutes to kind of tell you a little bit more about
how this field of computational photography relates to other disciplines.
So, in essence,
what we're interested in generating, traditionally images which are 2D.
And of course, the world has got a lot more detail.
Which has 3D geometry and shapes and, of course, photometry like how
the colors and the appearances of different things are different for the scene.
So computer vision is really about trying to take imagery of the real world and
infer things like what's the geometry of it and also the appearance and
photometric inferences of this thing.
So basically from 2D world we're trying to infer more things about the 3D scene.
Computer graphics on the other hand is about taking this kind of stuff and
generating nice 3, 2D images.
kind of the inverse of this.
Both of them are essential in our understanding of computational photography.
Because we want to leverage both processes, because we're interested in
analyzing, but we're also interested in capturing information in the real world.
Image processing and optics also play a role in all of this.
So for example, we want to do things like image processing to
enhance the quality of images that are available to us for
both knowing what, the kind of camera we're using or how we want to display it.
But, on the other hand, optics and sensors help us design better sensors and
displays and the kind of stuff we want to to do capture the environment.
All of these four, computer vision, computer graphics, image processing, and
optics and sensors are widely used fields and computer vis-,
computational photography leverages all of them.
It also now has begun to leverage other disciplines like machine
learning and robotics.