We label these terminal node
in our game tree with the +1
if our computer player wins,
and a -1 if it loses.
We've used squares to indicate
the terminal nodes, and
put their scores inside them.
We are going to assume that our
opponent X is really smart,
who will always play to win.
In other words, we will assume that
X will always minimize O scores,
while our computer player will
always try to maximize its scores.
To show that idea, we're going to mark
the game tree with a triangle pointing
up, to indicate turns when our computer
player is trying to maximize the score,
and the triangle pointing down when
the opponent is trying to minimize
the score.
Since our computer
player is going first,
we start with a maximization level.
In general, since we are only searching
from our computer player's perspective,
they can only affect the game
when it is its turn.
The top of a minimax tree is
always going to be a max level.