The correct answer is the first one.
Information flow is the reason
why we have this requirement.
Let's say your label can change,
then let's say you were,
some full example is that you are top
secret, so you were reading top secret
information, and then your label
changes to secret light set.
You are the user.
Well, now you can write
at the secret level,
so top secret information that
you could read previously
can now be written to documents that
only have secret classification level.
Then the user, later on, who's
cleared at secret level, can come and
read this document into
which information might
flow from top secret
to the secret level,
as a result of the change that happened
in the label during your session.
So, if you do that and
sort of do a couple of other examples,
labels change during a session.
Then, where you were reading,
where you can write, all that changes.
And because of that, we could have
information flow from a pierce object
02 that we have in the example to a
secret object 01 and we don't want that.
So, information flow is the problem.
To reduce overhead associated with
change of classification level,
you do not change the labels,
and the reason for
that is nothing to do with overhead
associated with changing them.
It really has to do with
information flow, and
the information flow that may
violate the model that we have.