Initially there is only A,
and the maximum likelihood we get the probability of A being in the first place is 1,
and all the other ones are 0.
There are 7 transitions out of A as indicated by the lines under the As over here.
In 3 cases, A is followed by A--over here, over here, and over here.
This gives us 3/7 for the maximum likelihood estimator.
A flows into B in another 3 cases--over here, over here, and over here--again, 3/7.
There is 1 instance where A moves into C--1/7.
There are 4 transitions out of B--
3 go to C, and 1 goes to B over here,
which gives us 0, 1/4, and 3/4.
Then there are 4 transitions out of C--one, two, three, four--
3 of which result in C, but one goes into A over here.
These are the results--1/4, 0, and 3/4.