Let's look at the answer
to this question.
So first, given that we have
a shortest job first algorithm and
these are the execution
times of the tasks,
what is going to be the execution
order of these tasks?
Clearly they'll have to
execute in this order.
So T1, followed by T3 or the other
way around, and then followed by T2.
Now that we know the order of the tasks,
we can actually compute
these three metrics.
To compute the throughput,
again we have three tasks in the system,
all of the three tasks get
processed in 12 seconds.
So 1 plus 10 plus 1.
So we have a total throughput
of 0.25 tasks per second.
So nothing has really changed
compared to the first come,
first serve algorithm here.
Now if we look at the average
completion time, the first task T1,
completes in 1 second.
The second task T3, that one completes
in another 1 second so in 2 seconds.
And then the third task, T2, well that
one will need another 10 seconds, so
it will complete at time T12.
So the average completion time
is 1 plus 2 plus 12 over 3.
That's five seconds.
That's already way better than
the eight seconds that we
saw in the first come
first serve algorithm.
If we look at the average wait time,
the first task, T1,
it then waited,
always started executing immediately.
T3 had to wait one second,
T2 had to only wait two seconds,
since both T1 and T3 are short.
So, the average wait time in
this system is only one second.
That is way better than the four seconds
that first come first serve resulted in.
So if we care about
metrics such as these.
Clearly shortest job first would
be a better algorithm than first
come, first served.