Another thing about RPC is that the
client and the server don't need to be
developed together as part
of the same application.
They may be completely independent
processes written by different
developers, written even in completely
different programming languages.
But for this to work there must
be some type of agreement so
that the server can explicitly see what
are the procedures that it knows how to
execute and what are the arguments that
are required for those procedures.
The reason this information is needed
is so that, on the client side,
the client can perform decisions, which
particular server it should bind with.
Standardizing how this information
is represented is also important so
that the RPC run time can
incorporate certain tools that will
automate the process of generating
the stub functionality.
To address these needs RPC systems rely
on use of interface definition
languages, or IDLs.
The IDLs serve as a protocol of how
this agreement will be expressed.