This is a somewhat trivial example so
the answer yes.
This is a sequentially
consistent execution.
Any of the updates in the system
are all performed from processor one.
We know that sequential consistency
requires that all of the updates from
a single processor,
that they be visible in the same order.
And if we take a look at P2, yes indeed.
The fact that the memory location m3
was updated to value y only becomes
visible after we have seen that on P2
that the value of m1 has become x.
If we had a situation where these reads
here to m1 were still returning zero.
So, this write was not visible however,
this read from m3
already returned y so this write became
visible that would've been the problem,
but that's not the case
in this scenario.
So this is the correct answer.