Let's add delegation to the
RecordSoundsViewController. First we have to
tell Xcode that our RecordSoundsViewController
conforms to the AVAudioRecorderDelegate
protocol. That is to
say we will implement a function
described in that delegate protocol, and
our ViewController can act as the
delegate for the AVAudioRecorder.
In our RecordSoundsViewController.swift file,
go to the class declaration
and indicate that we conform to
the AVAudioRecorderDelegate by adding it
here, after UIViewController. A class in
Swift can only inherit from one single
superclass, but it can conform to as many
as protocols as we want. You just have
to list them, separated by a comma.
Ok now that we have that in place,
the next thing to do is tell
the AVAudioRecorderDelegate that
the RecordSoundsViewController can act as its delegate.
In the recordAudio function, we want to set
this View Controller as the delegate of the
AVAudioRecorder. All we need to do is
add this line.
Ok, let's make some space before the last
curly brace, because this class conforms
to the AVAudioRecorderDelegate. Xcode
knows that if we start typing, it can
show us functions available in that
delegate, including audioRecorderDidFinishRecording,
and that's exactly what
we want.
let's hit Enter and let Xcode fill out
the function for us. Now this is the
function we're going to use to call the
stopRecording Segue that we set up
earlier and move to the audio playback scene.
For now let's just add a print
statement to let us know when the
AVAudioRecorder has finished recording.
Let's run the app and see what happens.
I’ll record something. “The quick red fox
jumped over the brown log.” And I’ll hit
the stop recording button. This time the
Segue doesn't automatically happen when
pressing stop and that's the behavior we want.
And in the console, our print
statement indicates that the record
audio has finished and is saved.