Nice work!
You should have found all of
the functions in your app.js file.
The function that gets the weather
forecast from the API is called
getForecast.
The function that updates the forecast
card with the weather data is
updateForecastCard.
The function that hides and shows
the Add City dialog is toggleAddDialog.
And there are two buttons that
have aria-labels in index.html.
Building accessibility into your
progressive web app is an important
part of the process and not something
that can be tacked on at the end.
Be sure to check out the web
accessibility course
linked in the instructor notes below
to learn more about web accessibility.