You've heard me say,
do the stupid thing first,and only
add intelligence when necessary.
It turns out that there
are a whole class of problems
where just adding a little
bit of intelligence and
iteratively improving the solution gets
you very close to an optimal solution.
>> Like what?
>> One of the classic ones is
the Traveling Salesman Problem.
Imagine you're a salesman.
>> That might be nice.
I'd probably make more money
than what you're paying me.
>> [COUGH] As I was saying.
Imagine you're a salesman, and
you have five cities you want to visit.
You can start at any city, but
you have to fly to all of them
before your tour is over.
And you have to come back to
the starting city in the end.
What is the most efficient order
of flights to minimize overall
distance flown?
>> This problem sounds NP hard.
>> What do you mean?
>> Well, NP actually means
nondeterministic polynomial time.
But people commonly talk about
non-polynomial algorithms as all being
about as hard as each other, or NP hard.
This problem seems exponentially
difficult in the number of cities
considered, and so it seems just as bad
as our game playing or search problems.
>> Precisely, but
like with our other problems,
we're going to figure out tricks to
help solve the problem efficiently.
First, we're going to
connect the cities randomly.
>> How about like this?
>> Great!
Next, we are going to look at
any place where the paths cross.
We'll show them in the red here.
>> I get it.
We need to revise the figure
to uncross each situation.
That should reduce
the distance traveled.
>> Yep, and for large problems,
we can do the process iteratively
until there are no crossed paths.
You can do this simple process
with thousands of cities and
get a result that is within one
percent of the optimal solution.
>> But that seems like a hack.
How does this technique generalize?
>> That is the subject of this section,
iterative improvement algorithms.
Let's start out with
our challenge question.