Looking at our TV sales XLSX, you can
see the number of toothbrushes sold
in column B will now calculate
the first difference in column C.
The first difference of a time series
is a series of changes from one period
to the next.
To calculate this, you take the value
in the current time period and
subtract it by the value
in the previous period.
This difference will provide us a look
at whether we have a constant mean and
variance overtime.
Plotting the different series in
a time series plot, we can see that
the difference revolves around
the constant mean of almost zero and
has a relatively constant variance.
If the first difference of the series is
unable to transform the data stationary,
we would calculate the second
difference, third difference and so
on until the series is
rendered stationary.
Note that the second difference is not
the difference from two periods ago,
rather it is the first difference of
the first difference as calculated here.
The third, fourth, fifth difference,
etc., would be calculated the same way.