I chose to create a new field
in the data called has_visited.
Now there's a couple of choices for
where to add this field.
The latest I could possibly add it is
to this engagement_by_account data
since that's where I'll need it.
On the other hand, then that field won't
be available in all the other lists of
data that I have,
which could annoy me later.
Another option would be to add it at
the very beginning of the notebook
when I first load in the data and
then reevaluate all the cells.
But some of these cells take
a couple seconds to run and
I'm not really excited about doing that.
As a compromise I decided to add
it to the paid_engagement table
after I had removed
the free trial cancels but
before I had separated out just
the engagement data for the first week.
To do this I looped over each engagement
in the paid_engagement table.
Then if that engagement record
showed that more than zero
courses were visited,
I set the has_visited field to one.
Otherwise, I set
the has_visited field to zero.
Remember the reason that I'm making
this field numeric, zeros and
ones, is so that I can add this field up
to get the total number of days that
the student visited the classroom.
Now I'll need to run this cell, as well
as rerun all the cells below it, to make
sure that the has_visited field gets
added anywhere it needs to be added.
Then I can analyze the
days_visited_by_account using code very
similar to what I had previously.
Again, I'll start with the engagement
data grouped by account and
then I'll sum up the has_visited
field for each account.
And again, I'll describe my data.
And when I run this cell I
see that the mean number of
days visited in the first week
is a little less than three.
The standard deviation
is a bit more than two.
The minimum is 0 and the maximum is 7.
The minimum and maximum in particular
are exactly what I expected.
In fact, I would be pretty surprised if
there weren't at least one student who
visited 0 days in their first week and
at least one student who visited all 7.