Thus far we've talked at
length about activities,
content providers, and services.
So you might be wondering,
what about that mysterious
fourth Android component,
the broadcast receiver?
When things happen on your phone,
Android issues special intents
known as system broadcast intents.
Here are some examples of broadcast
intents sent by the system.
Looking a little closer, here's one, for
example, when a download is complete.
And here's another for
when the headset is plugged in.
If you're creating an app that needs to
know about one of these state changes on
the phone and then run some code, you're
going to be using a broadcast receiver.
A broadcast receiver is a core Android
component that enables applications to
receive intents that are broadcast by
the system or by other applications.
A broadcast receiver can be triggered
even when the app is not running.
For example, say that you have
an app that needs to change its UI
depending on whether the device
is online versus offline.
A broadcast receiver is what you'd
use to be triggered when the change
has occurred.
You specify which request
the receiver is interested in,
using something known
as an intent filter.
An intent filter is an expression
that says what intents
should trigger your component.
Intent filters are commonly used
in the app's manifest file.
It should be noted that intent filters
are not specific to broadcast receivers.
For example, the first activity in
your app always has an intent filter.
This intent filter uses the action Main,
and the category LAUNCHER, as seen here.
This signals that this is the main
entry point for your app.
And when the launcher starts
an intent to launch the app,
this is the activity that should
be triggered by that intent.
If you want to create
a broadcast receiver,
there are basically two ways to do it,
either statically or dynamically.
The difference is that
static broadcast receivers
are triggered whenever
the broadcast intent occurs.
The receiver will be triggered
even if the app is offline.
This is opposed to dynamic
broadcast receivers,
which are tied to the app's life cycle.
Generally, if possible, it's better to
create a dynamic broadcast receiver, or
to use job scheduling, if you can.
Relying on static broadcast
receivers can be problematic.
Let's see why.
So if you look at how you statically
define a broadcast receiver,
it involves registering
the receiver in the manifest, and
using the XML intent-filter tags.
For example, this is how you'd
statically define a broadcast receiver
in the Android manifest.
And this would trigger
a broadcast receiver called
NewPictureBroadcastReceiver anytime
a new photo is taken.
The corresponding
NewPictureBroadcastReceiver class would
look something like this.
It would be a class that
extends BroadcastReceiver and
implements the onReceive method.
onReceive takes a context and
the broadcast intent that
triggered the broadcast.
Because this is a static broadcast
receiver that was defined in
the manifest, this broadcast
receiver would be triggered
whenever a photo was taken,
even if your app isn't running.
Now, this is very powerful, but
it's also very easy to abuse.
Just think of what would happen if
the user had downloaded ten apps
that were all using the new
picture taken broadcast.
Whenever a new picture was taken,
suddenly a bunch of
apps would be triggered, and
the device would slow to a crawl.
Because of this, some broadcast intents
won't even let you statically define
a broadcast receiver.
Specifically, intents that have
the FLAG_RECEIVER_REGISTERED_ONLY.
Specifically, intents that have the
FLAG_RECEIVER_REGISTERED_ONLY flag set.
So if you need to execute code
when your app isn't running,
schedule a job if possible.
Jobs have constraints for
the most common situations, as we
mentioned, such as Wi-Fi and charging.
And jobs are set up to be
very battery friendly.
That said, in some cases, you will need
to register a static broadcast receiver.
These are usually cases where you need
to catch certain specific intents
on older devices when
the app is not running.
But if you need to listen for system
broadcasts when the app is running,
dynamic broadcast receivers
are your best option.
The actual broadcast receiver class for
a dynamically registered
receiver looks the same.
But instead of defining the receiver
in the manifest, you register and
un-register the receiver during
the activity's life cycle methods.
In this case,
we're using onResume and onPause.
This example's some
code that listens for
whether the headphones are plugged in.
Now, in this example, because it's
a dynamic broadcast receiver,
this listening will only happen when
the activity is open and visible.
Now that you know a little bit
more about broadcast receivers and
when to use them,
let's add one to your app.