Now, in some sense, you've learned all you need to know about reinforcement learning.
Yes, it's a huge field, and there's a lot of other details that we haven't covered
but you've seen all the basics.
The theory is there and it works.
But in another sense, we haven't gone very far
because what we've done works for these small 4 by 3 Grid Worlds,
But it won't work very well for larger problems:
dealing with flying helicopters or playing backgammon--
because there's just too many states
and we can't visit every one of the states
and build up the correct utility values, or Q values,
for all the billions or trillions or quadrillions of states we would need to represent.
So let's go back to a simpler type of example.
Here's a state in a Pacman game
and we can see that this is a bad state,
where Pacman is surrounded by 2 bad guys,
and there's no place for him to escape.
And so reinforcement learning could quickly learn that this is bad.
But the problem is that that state has
no relation whatsoever to this state.
Where conceptually, it's the same problem--
that the Pacman is stuck in a corner
and there are bad guys own either sides of him.
But in terms of a concrete state,
the 2 are completely different.
So what we want to be able to do is
find some generalization, so that these 2 states look the same,
and what I learn for this state--
that learning can transfer over into this state.
And so, just as we did in supervised machine learning, where we wanted to take
similar points in the state and be able to reason about them, together,
we want to be able to do the same thing for reinforcement training.
And we can use the same type of approach.