Finding the shortest path on a map
is a very useful ability and
that heuristic is a nice trick.
But it seems more like
an optimization problem to me.
I'm not sure if I'd consider
that a sign of intelligence.
>> Mm, okay, how would you characterize
an intelligence system or agent?
>> Well,
unlike the route finding domain,
many real world problems require us to
react to changes to our environment.
Maybe, changes caused by
things like other drivers.
I would expect an intelligent agent to
be able to react to such changes and
maybe even anticipate them.
>> Hm, what if we could adapt similar
search strategies to solve problems that
involve other agents?
>> Like, playing games?
Yea.
>> I guess we've seen that before, and
there are lots of famous examples of AI
agents winning games
from Chess to Starcraft.
>> Let's try to figure out
a way to implement them.