To answer this question
we will need to add up
the sizes that can be addressed with
every single type of the different
pointers that are included
in the inode data structure.
This includes the 12th direct
disk block pointers, and
then the one single indirect pointer,
the one double indirect pointer, and
the one triple indirect pointer.
The answer to the first
question is 16 gigabytes.
Remember, we have 1 kilobyte blocks, and
every single block pointer is 4 bytes.
So, with a single block, again,
we address 256 pointers.
Now, if we think about what is
the total number of file blocks
that are addressed, their direct
pointers will address 12 file blocks.
Then the single indirect will
address another 256 of those.
The double indirect will
address 256 square.
Triple indirect 256 cube.
And all of that needs to be multiplied
by the actual size of the blocks.
So that's 1 kilobyte.
That will produce a maximum
file size of 16 gigabytes.
The answer to the second
question is 64 terabytes.
Remember here we have 8 kilobyte block
sizes, and given that the pointer size
again is 4 bytes, each one of
the blocks can contain 2k pointers.
Now if we do the math to compute what
is the total number of blocks that
can be addressed with this inode, we
will come up with this calculation and
multiply that by 8 kilobytes again,
that is the block size will produce
the answer of 64 terabytes.
So, although we've only increased
the block size from 1 kilobyte
to 8 kilobyte, because of this
non-linear data structure that's used to
address the blocks,
we're able to achieve much larger
file sizes that can be
supported by these classes.