For the new Mad Libs generator
we're going to build,
we're going to have to turn the string
passed into our function into a list.
Now, I won't get into the details
of why we need to do this just yet,
I'll explain why we'll need to make
the conversion in the next quiz
question video.
But, for now, I want to show you
a new function called split,
which turns the words in a string
into a list of those words.
If you remember the function, randint,
from the last work session, you'll
see that split looks pretty similar,
but it's even easier to implement.
This is the basic structure
of the split function.
As you can see,
split takes in one argument,
separator, which is what your
string will be split on, and
is preceded by this string_to_split
variable which is self-explanatory.
However, the separator argument is
optional and, if we leave it blank,
we'll split on single space characters,
which is actually what we'll
be using this function for.
Let's run through an example.
Let's say I have this string, and I call
the split function on it, and notice how
I left the inside of the parenthesis
blank, I'll be returned with this list.
"I", "am", "a", "Noun".
Simple enough.
In the following quiz you'll be asked to
use a split function on a couple other
strings so you can get a feel for it.
Feel free to experiment with what
you put in for the parenthesis, but
note that we just want the words to be
split on the single space character.