Okay.
To get more information on the state of
our memory and
the objects that are taking up space, we
can use a handy tool called Heap Viewer.
Now with Heap Viewer,
you can see how much memory a process
is using at certain points in time.
Now as before, if you want to follow
along, go ahead and start Android Studio
and bring sunshine to the foreground
on your connected device.
In order to start Heap Viewer, you'll
want to start Android Device Monitor
first and
there are a few options to do that.
One way is through the tools menu
where you can click on tools, android,
and android device monitor.
Or, you can click on this nifty android
icon here in your tool bar at the top.
So I'm going to do that and
android device monitor is starting,
then we're going to want to go ahead and
click the DDMS tab.
The heap viewer is one
of the DDMS tools and
we're going to go over here to the left.
And we're going to select
the app we want to profile, so
we're going to select Sunshine now I'm
going to pull up this panel down here.
So once you have Sunshine selected
you're going to want to select this heap
tab to get more information.
Now initially you might not see much,
but you notice this little.
Hint here at the top that reads Heap
updates will happen after every GC for
this client.
Why don't we go ahead and click on this
and cause a GC to update your data.
Whoa, look.
We have all this new information now.
Now the table updated and shows you
what data is currently available and
alive on the Heap.
If you want to get some more details
go ahead and select a single data type.
I'm going to click this class object.
Now you'll see a lot of data will
update in the panel down below.
You can now see a histogram for
the number of allocations and
also the specific memory size for
that data type.
In this case we're talking
about the class object.
Now the heap viewer is
really helpful to see what.
Types of objects your
application has allocated,
as well as how many and
what sizes they are on the heap.
Again here, see we see the total sizes.
Of particular types on our heap.
Like for example there's over 1400
two biter arrays on our heap,
that's taking about 120 kilobytes.
Whereas there are only
27 one byte arrays and
it's roughly only taking
up about two megabytes.
Now the heap viewer is really helpful
to see what types of objects.
You application is allocated.
As well as how many, and
their respective sizes on the heap.
For example, if we look here we
have 27 one byte arrays that are taking
up roughly two megabytes of data.
And then we have about 2000 four
byte arrays that are taking up
currently 228 kilobytes of data.
This information is super helpful
when you're trying to track down
memory leaks.