So believe it or not, that's the end of this first lesson.
why, well I want to cut you a break a little bit.
Actually the real reason is the next lesson's got, shall we say a,
modicum of equations on it.
And to do this and then all of that, boy that would be too much, so here we are.
But the idea is that we've motivated what it means to be a feature, and
a good feature.
Features are being used to match one to the next.
The two main properties that we talked about is repeated detectability.
That is, if I find them over here,
I'd like to make sure that I'm going to find them over in this image.
And they also should be good for recognition one to another.
That is, you can think of them as having a signature.
And that signature should be distinct, right?
Bob, Carol, Ted, and Alice.
Alright.
But robust.
Right? So Edward might become Ed but
nothing significantly different beyond that.
Turns out that this notion of being both distinctive and
robust sort of works against each other and, and we'll talk about that.
So going forward, we're going to introduce about what it means to
be a good feature, what it means to be a good interest point,
and we'll break that down into two parts.
Detecting of interest points, and
then characterizing the descriptor around those interest points.
So sharpen your lead pencil.
You guys even see lead pencils anymore?
Don't use a lead pencil on your iPad.
It's probably a bad idea.
Anyway and we'll do some interest point operators, and
how those function mathematically.