[BLANK_AUDIO]
One of the most surprising things about
seeing the results of the hundreds and
hundreds of competitions isn't
the competitions themselves, but
who won them.
If you were following machine
learning a decade ago,
then you'd think that people doing
interesting work in machine learning
were limited to a couple of large
companies that operating online,
a couple hedge funds, and
some top academic labs,
but running hundreds of competitions
exposed that's not the case whatsoever.
People great at machine learning come
from a really diverse array of different
backgrounds and different countries.
Most of our winners actually
are from outside the US,
so many different
countries around the world.
Many of them aren't bright eyed,
fresh machine learning
phd students better, instead people
who have worked 40 years in another
career, such as computer science or
physics or electrical engineering.
And they've read a lot
about machine learning and
AI, which piques their curiosity.
They became passionate about it.
And they spent several years of their
free time to really grow their skills
there and
grow deep into machine learning.
So the diversity of the people
who win competitions is
the single most surprising thing to me.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Right now, machine learning is still
in its very much in its infancy.
It is difficult to get machine
learning algorithms to work well and
to work reliably, and
on a decade long time horizon,
that is going to completely change.
Right now, if I want to spin up a new,
reliable web service,
it's a really straightforward thing from
an engineering perspective to go and
spin up a new web app or
spin up a new iPhone app that which
works well and works effectively.
Machine learning is going to become just
as easy to create and use as an iPhone
app is or a web app is, so it's not
going to be this magical thing that
requires a small number of really
specialized experts to create and use.
So it would be access to machine
learning will become much more
commoditized and democratized, and
that's really going to enable
a huge wave of new applications.
If you think about the tasks that
most people do on a day to day basis,
whether it's things like driving a car,
entering data,
verifying data, asking a set of
questions to triage a patient
to understand who they should see or
things along those lines.
Those are highly repetitive tasks and
are the types of tasks that machines can
excel at, so expect over a longer time
horizon all the jobs that are highly
repetitive to ultimately be done more
efficiently by machines enabled by
machine learning algorithms in AI.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Kaggle's mission is to help
the world learn from data.
We started off by enabling
vast scientists to
access a really fascinating set of
use cases through a platform and
through machine learning competitions,
as well as to demonstrate and
have very standardized setting,
how well algorithms perform.
We're going to stand much more
proudly from that as per for
our next focus for
helping the world learn from data.
We think that data science tools and
workflows are three decades behind
their software engineering equivalents.
Data scientists already have good
tools for collaboration right now.
They spend most of their time doing
ground worker repetitive tasks
that are the types of things that can
be abstracted out and made much more
efficient, sort of providing tooling
to help with their repetitive tasks and
collaboration on that,
in the same sense that suffer generis
have tools like Git for version control,
GitHub for collaborating on top of
called continuous integration surveys
to prove that the code works well, etc.
We're going to provide a mirrored set
of tools for data scientists to make
them much more productive and
to make the world very efficient for
the world to, as soon as a new data
sample or new data point comes in,
to learn everything possible
from that data point.