Here are a few more things that you should know about masks.
Interrupt masks are maintained on per CPU basis.
What this means is that if the interrupt mask disables a particular interrupt,
the hardware support for
routing interrupts will just not deliver that interrupt to the CPU.
The signal mask, however, that depends on what exactly is the user-level
process, for instance, the user-level thread, doing at a particular moment, so
we say that the signal masks are per execution context.
If a signal mask is disabled, the kernel sees that, and in that case,
it will not interrupt the corresponding thread.
So it will not interrupt this execution context.