The correct factorization of this trinomial is 5y squared times 5x minus 4 times
2x plus 1. That was a pretty tough problem, How do you do? If you got it right,
you are on your way to being a factoring genius. Let's see how we got this
answer. Remember, when I'm factoring any polynomial, I want to check to see if
there's a greatest common factor. When I look at these three terms, I notice a
couple of things. The first thing I notice is all three terms have a y-squared.
In that case, I should be able to factor out a y-squared. The other thing that I
notice is that each of the three terms is divisible by 5. So this polynomial has
a GCF of 5 y-squared. When I factor out the 5 y-squared from each term, what am
I left with? When I factor out the GCF, I'm left with 10 x squared, minus 3 x
minus 4. 5 y squared times 10 x squared gives me the 50 x squared y squared. 5 y
squared times negative 3 x is negative 15 x y squared, and negative 4 times 5 y
squared gives me the negative 20 y squared. After I factor out the GCF, I need
to look at the remaining polynomial, 10 x squared minus 3 x minus 4. Now I have
to factor this trinomial. Remember when there is a coefficient in front of the x
squared variable, you have to multiply the coefficient of the x squared variable
by the constant term. To factor this polynomial, I have to look at the factors
of 10 times negative 4 which is negative 40, that add up to negative 3. There
are a lot of different factors that multiply together to get negative 40, but
the factors that multiply together to get negative 40, and add together to get
negative 3, are negative 8 and 5. Negative 8 times 5 is negative 40, negative 8
plus 5 is negative 3. Now we need to rewrite the middle term, using these two
factors. When I rewrite negative 3x using my factors, I get 10x squared minus 8x
plus 5x which gives me the negative 3x minus 4. Now I can factor by grouping.
When I factor by grouping, I notice that the GCF of the first two terms is 2x,
and I have 5x minus 4. 2x times 5x is 10x squared. 2x times negative 4 gives me
negative 8x. Now this is an interesting situation. Here I have 5x minus 4, and
that's what I want my second binomial to be. So what do I factor out? There is
no GCF here. Well, technically there is a GCF, but the GCF is simply one. 1
times 5x, 5x. 1 times negative 4 is negative 4. Now I see the same binomial in
both places, so I can now factor that out. Don't forget to bring along our
overall GCF, 5x minus 4 times 2x plus 1. That was a pretty difficult problem.
Great job if you got it right. If not maybe try it again.