All right, so that was the quick and
dirty tour of the debug bar.
Let's talk about stepping
through our code.
Right now, we believe that spiders are
not being drawn to the screen because
the max bug value is set to zero,
and this is keeping us
from actually entering the if
block that creates spiders.
So if we use Step Over,
we can find out if this is really true.
What Step Over is going to allow us
to do is execute the current line of
code as if it were a black box.
By black box, I mean you don't know
what's going on inside of the box, or
inside of the line of code
that you're executing.
You just see what happens on
the outside, or as a result.
So, you might see the return
value of the function or
the result of the computation for
this particular line of code.
For example, if line 33
happened to be a function call,
then by clicking Step Over we will
not go inside of the function,
it'll just go ahead and
try and execute the function.
So I'll click Step Over, and
it runs the current line of code.
So with the green arrow at
the final closing brace,
this is indicative that the function is,
or the method is, ready to return.
So let's stop the app now and
change our max bug values to 100.
Scroll up.
There's max bugs.
Change it to 100.
And let's rebuild and run the app again.
Go to the break point
debugging scene and we'll tap.
And let's click Step Over.
Or instead of clicking the button each
time, you can use the hot key, F6.
This time Stepping Over drops
us right into the if block.
So with our change, we've insured that
we've at least entered the if block.
The next button we want to
talk about is Step Into.
Step Into allows us to step inside or
into a function call in order
to examine it's execution.
The hot key for Step Into is F7.
So let's step inside this line to see
what's happening when we call the bug
factories create bug method.
And we can see that X code that
automatically redirects us to
the bug factory's create bug method.
And we can step through this method
line by line using Step Over.
Now it's going to be
a lot of Step Overs,
because this particular method
has a lot of lines in it.
And if this method was
hundreds of lines long,
then stepping through each line
would get kind of tedious.
So that's why our third
button Step Out exists.
Step Out will jump us all the way
out of the current function,
in this case the function
method create bug.
The hot key for Stepping Out is F8.
Once we step out of create bug,
notice that our new bug
now has a memory address.
And by the fact that it
shows a memory address,
we can assume that a bug was created and
it contains some properties.
So let's go ahead and click the continue
button to see what happens.
Hmm, now that's weird.
When we try to click continue, it
appears that we've hit the create bug or
the add bug to view break point again.
And this suggests that we may be
creating multiple bugs each time
the user tabs.
So this is actually
a separate problem and
we're going to address it later
using another debugging tool.
For now, let's just stop the program
and, if you remember from the print and
debugging example, in this example,
I'm also neglecting to add bugs to
the view after they're created.
So let's go ahead and add that back.
And let's disable this break point.
And I did that by right clicking.
You can right click as well,
or just toggle.
And let's play.
I'll tap and
it's a little laggy and whoa, okay.
So I knew this was going to happen
because I looked at it ahead of time,
but we have an issue here and
we're creating way too many spiders.
That's actually kind of neat,
I think some people may be
inclined to call this a feature.
But all jokes aside,
this is another bug.
For now, let's leave the app
in this broken state, and
we'll get some more practice
stepping through our code.