Here are some of the coding steps that
we'll need to do in the quick report app
to get the network
request set up properly.
First of all, should remove the hard
coded JSON response in QueryUtils.
Then, you're going to need to add
helper methods in QueryUtils to create
a URL object, perform a network request,
convert the InputStream to a string and
then parse the JSON.
Then, you going to need to modify
the JSON parsing method to
extract a list of earthquakes
from the web server response.
Declare EarthquakeAsyncTask as
an inner class to MainActivity.
And create and
execute an EathquakeAsyncTask in
the MainActivity onCreate() method.
Finally, you'll need to
add internet permission.
If you provided more details,
then good for you.
That shows that you're
really able to think ahead
on what code you need to write for
a given task.