[BLANK_AUDIO]
Welcome to your first day.
I'm Kelly and I'll be your
mentor as you get settled in.
&gt;&gt; Hi Kelly, nice to meet you.
So, what does a mentor do?
&gt;&gt; Basically it means I'll be assigning
you projects, giving feedback, and
connecting you to
the resources that you need.
I was in your shoes when I joined
the company a few years ago and
I know the first few weeks can be tough.
But don't worry,
I'll be with you every step of the way.
Come, I'll show you your desk.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Hi.
&gt;&gt; Hey.
&gt;&gt; Thanks for joining me.
&gt;&gt; Glad to be here.
&gt;&gt; So, we've been pretty busy lately.
One of the reasons we've had so much
work is that we specialize in a certain
type of analytics called
predictive analytics.
&gt;&gt; What's predictive analytics?
&gt;&gt; It's all about finding trends and
patterns in existing data to help
make predictions about the future.
&gt;&gt; Tons of different companies
are using predictive analytics
to make better decisions
about their marketing,
finance, production,
really anything else.
&gt;&gt; Okay, so what you're saying is
you use data to predict the future?
What does that look like in practice?
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH] Good question.
Well, check out this
recent project we did.
Our client was a manufacturing firm, and
they were losing a bunch of money,
because of unexpected machine failures.
So we worked with them to predict
when their machines might fail, so
they could the repairs beforehand.
They ended up reducing the impact
of machine failure by over 40%.
&gt;&gt; Wow.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, and now they've hired
us to do a few more projects.
&gt;&gt; Well,
sounds like I have a lot to learn.
How do you suggest I get started?
&gt;&gt; Great, thank you.
Our manager thought this
would be a great project for
you to get started with.
I'm excited to see
what you'll do with it.
It'll give you a good sense of the
process we go through as we're working
on projects.
After you turn it in I'll
give you some feedback.
And don't worry about it too much,
think of this project as a warmup.
You ready to get started?
&gt;&gt; Definitely.
[BLANK_AUDIO]