First, Kerberos provides
authentication and access control.
This is true.
Second, Kerberos also
distributes session keys.
This is true.
Third, to avoid over-exposure
of a user's master key,
Kerberos uses a per-day key and
a ticket-granting-ticket.
This is true.
Fourth, the authenticators
used in requests to KDC and
application servers can be omitted.
This is false.
These authenticators are used
to authenticate the senders.
And authentication is
an important goal of Kerberos.
Therefore, these authenticators
must not be omitted.
Fifth, access to any network resource
requires a ticket issued by the KDC.
This is true.