So the highest port number is 65,535.
That's not an arbitrary
limit by the way.
But there were a few more things
we should talk about before
getting into that.
We'll talk about it in more
detail in the next lesson.
On most systems the lowest 1,024 ports
from 0 up to 1,023, are reserved for
programs that are started by the system
superuser account or root on Unix.
It's like those ports
are reserved parking spots.
That's why when you start up a web
server which runs on port 80 you
have to do it as root or
with the sudo command.
For security a web server gets rid of
its root privileges once it starts up.
But it needs to start with them so
it can listen on port 80.
So if you use sudo to run nc as root,
it can listen on port 1,000 just fine.
But what happens if you tell it to
listen on a port where your SSH server's
already listening or
if you tell two different ncs to
listen on port 2,000 for that matter?
Mark whichever of these you
think is a reasonable outcome.
Is it that the program that
was previously listening for
instance the SSH daemon will exit?
Is it that netcat will
give you an error message?
Is it that both can
listen at the same time?
Is it that your computer crashes, or
is it that the internet explodes?
By the way, the result you get may
be different if you run netcat
on an OS other than Linux.
Try this out on your Linux system
to see the intended result here.