To make the words appear
in the other activities,
we can follow the first
hint which was to copy and
paste the code that we already
have in the numbers activity.
So let's copy all this code
here from the NumbersActivity.
And then first we'll paste
into the ColorsActivity.
Before I paste this bucket code in, the
ColorsActivity was using the activity
under pseudo colors.xml layout file.
As the content view, so
we could change the colors activity
to refer to this layout file again.
However, we would also need to change
the layout file to have a list
list view XML layout instead
of a relative layout.
In the quiz we give you hint number two,
which is all the activities
can use the same layout file.
Which has a List item element in it
since activity_numbers.XML already
has the correct layout.
Let's just go ahead and use that.
Delete this tools context attribute
which says which file
the layout should be used in.
Because now this layout will be used for
four different activities.
Next we'll want to rename this file so
that it's not number specific.
So to do that we'll right-click,
head to Refactor and then Rename.
So how about something like.
Word, underscore, list, dot XML.
So refactoring here will update
all locations in the code.
That refer to the old name.
And update it with the new name now.
Back in the numbers activity.
We refer to the activity underscore
numbers layout but notice here it now
refers to the words_List XML file which
is the new name for the same file.
And then we'll move over to the colors
activity we can set the content view to
also be the word's list XML file
which contains a list item view.
So then in the colors activity
we can set the content view
to also be the word list Excel file,
which contains a list view element.
All right so let's make sure all
your code in the colors activity is
correctly referring to
the colors category,
and we don't have anything left
over to store the first numbers.
So the most apparent one here
is the English and translations.
Let's update that to
reflect the color words.
So the remaining code in
the onCreate method looks correct.
So we created a word adapter
from this list of word colors.
Then we find the list view with
the view ID list in the words_list.xml.
layout, and lastly we set
the adapter on to this list view.
So now there is no errors in our code.
So let's run the app on a device.
So when the app launches and
I click on the colors category.
We see the list of color
words nice it's working.
So the mihwa colors on top and
the English word is below it.
Now we'll repeat the same thing
with the family activity.
I copied over the file from
the colors activity and
updated the list of family words from
the provided dictionary document.
And when I run the app on my device,
it looks like this.
Now, excellent job.
All the categories are properly
displaying the me walk and
English translations for each word.
Now there's one last cleanup
step we could do that
would be nice to fix our code.
Since we're just using
a single layout file.
Our word list XML file.
For all four activities,
we can delete the unused layout files.
I'm going to go ahead and delete the
layout files for the colors, family, and
phrases.
Whenever you delete files, you should
test the app one more time to make sure
it's still working and you didn't delete
anything you actually might need.
So after running the app on my device,
it looks like it's still working.
So take a step back and
congratulate yourself.
You just finished the coding
task in lesson two.
That's a really big milestone.