Here's an example tree.
Suppose you wish to compute the depth or
the level of every node in the tree.
The level of any tree node is
the minimum distance to that node
from the root.
For example, here are the levels
of the nodes of this tree.
The root is a distance
0 away from itself.
Its children are all one away.
Its grandchildren are all two away and
so on.
Now suppose to compute the levels,
you decide to apply
the Euler tour technique.
Recall that the first step is
to compute an Euler circuit.
That gives you a list, which is
effectively a traversal of the tree.
Here's what I want you to do.
I want you to initialize
the nodes of the list.
So that a listed scan computes
the level for each node.
You'll put your initial
values in these boxes, and
I filled in a 0 for
you to help you get started.
Now I want you to choose the values,
so that when you do a list scan.
The level of every node ends
up in the starred boxes.
The starred boxes are exactly the source
nodes for child to parent edges.