The second thing to decide about in coming up with a constraint
is whether the constraint is associated with the system or
a part of the system that is a class. Or whether it is associated with
an operation. If it's associated with a system as a whole or with a class then
we're going to use an invariant. Saying what must be true about the system or
what must be true about the class. Whereas if it's associated with an operation,
then we talk about the pre-conditions for the operation and the post-conditions
for the operation and we will use the pre and post keywords to express those.
Okay, in this, in this case, when we're talking about the check out period,
does it sound to you more like it's an invariant or as an operation.