[Norvig] We've seen how to do enumeration to solve the inference problem
on belief networks.
For a simple network like the alarm network, that's all we need to know.
There's only 5 variables, so even if all 5 of them were hidden,
there would only be 32 rows in the table to sum up.
From a theoretical point of view, we're done.
But from a practical point of view, other networks could give us trouble.
Consider this network, which is one for determining insurance for car owners.
There are 27 different variables.
If each of the variables were boolean, that would give us over 100 million rows to sum out.
But in fact, some of the variables are non-boolean,
they have multiple values, and it turns out that representing this entire network
and doing enumeration we'd have to sum over a quadrillion rows.
That's just not practical, so we're going to have to come up with methods
that are faster than enumerating everything.
The first technique we can use to get a speed-up in doing inference on Bayes nets
is to pull out terms from the enumeration.
For example, here the probability of b is going to be the same for all values of E and a.
So we can take that term and move it out of the summation,
and now we have a little bit less work to do.
We can multiply by that term once rather than having it in each row of the table.
We can also move this term, the P of e, to the left of the summation over a,
because it doesn't depend on a.
By doing this, we're doing less work.
The inner loop of the summation now has only 3 terms rather than 5 terms.
So we've reduced the cost of doing each row of the table.
But we still have the same number of rows in the table,
so we're going to have to do better than that.
The next technique for efficient inference is to maximize independence of variables.
The structure of a Bayes net determines how efficient it is to do inference on it.
For example, a network that's a linear string of variables,
X1 through Xn, can have inference done in time proportional to the number n,
whereas a network that's a complete network
where every node points to every other node and so on could take time 2 to the n
if all n variables are boolean variables.
In the alarm network we saw previously, we took care
to make sure that we had all the independence relations represented
in the structure of the network.
But if we put the nodes together in a different order,
we would end up with a different structure.
Let's start by ordering the node John calls first
and then adding in the node Mary calls.
The question is, given just these 2 nodes and looking at the node for Mary calls,
is that node dependent or independent of the node for John calls?