Just to help you practice for this, I'd like for you to try out
a simple quiz in the same, same kind of a setup as the previous one.
Remember what we were doing is, we were basically going down,
from one column to the other and finding another value of indifference it, be
able to then find what would be the first derivative by just simple differences.
In this case, we are going to just look at absolute values, so
we are going to drop the negatives, so
for example here, between those two, the value should be 0.
Similarly, between 0 and 9, the value should be 9.
Just fill the rest of it out and then use this to kind of extract from it,
what you think are the most appropriate extrema points, I'm just also drawn here
the curve for the same thing here, right, 0, 0, goes to 9, comes to 9,
and then again 8, and of course this is approximate, comes down to here.
And this is just my 1-D profile, of what the signal looks like, and we're
just looking at this in one 1-D, also, check marks here as to where the extremas
would be, so that of course will the edges be for this image example.