Here's a picture, a very famous picture, and the question is, what do you see?
All right, so most people probably first see a,
the kind of stylistic drawing of a naked woman, and then maybe if you
look you'll see down here there's a picture of Abraham Lincoln.
But if you take a look at the title of the picture, this is a painting by
Salvador Dali and its Gala Contemplating the Mediterranean Sea which at
30 meters becomes a portrait of Abraham Lincoln, now you don't actually have to
step back 30 meters we can just blur the picture and when, when, and when I
blur the picture, it looks like that, and uh-huh, there's Abraham Lincoln.
And so the question is, what's going on there?
All right.
And, loosely the, the answer is that at this image there's all this
hig frequency information that's showing you all these squares and you see the,
the outline of the woman and you can see the, the, the, what she's looking at
something in the distance, and you can see that picture of Abraham Lincoln, but
at the low frequency, it actually is a reasonable picture of Abraham Lincoln.
And the idea is that images can be decom,
actually any signal can be decomposed into a set of things that describe it.
And, we're going to get to frequency, but
really what we're talking about is what's referred to as a basis set.