Here's a technique for thinking about
lower bounds on memory transfers,
which is inspired by information theory.
I want you to think
about it by example for
the problem of search given
an ordered collection.
In this problem, you're given a sorted
array A containing n unique elements.
You want to find the largest
index i such that A sub
i is less than or equal to v.
The standard binary search
algorithm does big O of log
n over L transfers in the worst case.
Now let's think about what you're trying
to compute a little bit differently.
To store the index i takes about
log n bits, would you agree?
Now let's say that when you
read a block of L items from A,
you learn at most x bits of
information about this index.
If you had an upper bound on x,
then you could get a lower bound on
the number of ios during the search.
It would just be the number of
bits you're trying to learn
divided by the number of bits you learn
each time you do an L-sized read.
Now for the question.
What is x in a big O sense?
I want you to type your answer
symbolically in this box.