What actually happens in Lambertian shading is the following.
Okay, when the light is reflected out, basically it falls off, so
there's, it, it's sort of equal area here.
So you see this amount?
So more light is reflected perpendicularly out than is reflected sideways.
Okay? And in fact,
as you fall off this thing goes down by the cosine of the angle.
So that actually almost no light at all goes out sideways.
So a lot of light reflects back up and almost no light at all reflects sideways.
So you might ask.
Get ready Megan.
Well why does it look equally bright from all directions?
>> Well why does it look equally bright from all directions?
>> I love it when stuff works.
It's that same foreshortening effect, but
this time it goes the other way around, right?
If I've got sort of a pixel having a particular angle, so that's what
this is meant to be, a pixel having an angle, when I look down through here.
It has a smaller area.
It's drawn sort of wrong here.
Than when I look this way.
Think about it this way.
If I had a camera out here, the same angle,
right, would now get a much bigger area coming into the same pixel.
So if I understand the math right, and
I think I do, what this means is, is that.
The amount of area that I see on the surface grows by the cosine of that area.
Or I should say one over the cosine of that angle.
So as that angle gets smaller and gets closer and closer to 90 degrees,
right, I start to see an infinite amount of patch in the same little pixel,
but over here I'm putting out smaller and smaller and smaller light.
And these cosines, in fact here they are here, this one and that one.
They cancel.
And that's why it looks equally bright from every direction.
So, I think I got that right.
I'm sure my computer vision colleagues are going to send me email, or
just make fun of me on the web if I got that wrong but I'm pretty sure that,
that's the way it works.
What you need to know is that it appears equally bright from all directions.