Now let me show you a bit of code for
the scale and
shear transformations
applied to an image.
The usual preamble of loading
computer vision and numpy, and
wrote reading the image.
And here basically what we do now is
we want to actually be able to apply
a resize scale,
by basically what we're applying is,
transformations in x and y, 1.5.
These are various types of,
additional information we can to our
resize function to be able to scale it.
And that basically allows it to
kind of change the image and
scale the image here.
And I can, of course,
just show the image, by just scaling it.
This one of course if you notice,
I didn't spend time building
a transformation matrix because this
piece of code already takes
care of this kind of stuff.
The next example is where
we can apply a shear or
a skew in the horizontal axis only.
So of course now, for this,
we will create a matrix,
the diagonals are still ones.
We don't want to do any
kind of scaling here.
But of course now I'm applying
in the off diagonal terms,
a small scale in this case,
just in the x direction.
And I've given it a 0.5.
And using that now you've
actually computed a or or
come up with a new
transformation matrix.
You can print it and then apply it using
again our affine, warpAffine function,
take the image, and now here, we
basically just do some different types
of transformations, apply it,
and of course, can see the image.
Let's see what this looks like.
Here is just the printout
of the shear matrix.
This is the original image.
This is the original image scaled by 1,
1.5, that is, basically we've just
added a little bit more size to it.
And this is the output of a shear
transformation where we basically have
applied a 0.5 shear just in
the horizontal direction.