So far so good. But we need to figure out
a couple things. Mainly dealing with
sending the audio to our second View
Controller which are about to build.
If we think about this, we have two problems
at hand.
First we need a way to pass the audio
file from the first View Controller to
the second View Controller, so that it
can play it back.
The second issue is answering the
question to what happens when we record
a really large file and transition
before it's been written out the storage.
In other words, we need to only move from
the first View Controller to the second
View Controller once the AVAudioRecorder
has finished saving the
recordedVoice.wav file.