Let's discuss some attacks on
packet filtering firewalls and
the appropriate countermeasures.
The first attack is source
IP address spoofing.
Here the attacker transmits packets from
an outside host, but with a source IP
address field containing
the address of an internal host.
That is, the attacker spoofs the packets
source IP address as if it is from
an internal host.
The attacker hopes that
the use of a spoofed
internal source IP address will allow
the firewall to let the packet pass.
The firewall is typically
configured to let
traffic from one internal host
to another to pass through.
The countermeasure is to discard
packets with an inside source IP
address if the packet arrives
on a external interface.
In fact, this kind of measure is
often implemented at the router,
external to the firewall.
That is, when the router receives
the packet from the Internet,
it would check whether the source
IP address is correct.
If the source IP address
is an internal IP address,
the router should know that this IP
address is spoofed, because the router
just received this packet from
the Internet, meaning an external host.
A related attack,
is a source routing attacks.
Here, the attacker specifies
the route the attack should take
as it crosses the internet.
And the attacker hopes that this
will bypass security measures and
checks along the way.
A countermeasure is for the firewall or
the router to discard all
packets that use this option.
Another attack is
a tiny fragment attack.
Here, the attacker uses the IP
fragmentation option to create
extremely small fragments, and
forces the TCP header information
into separate packet fragments.
This attack is designed to circumvent
filtering rules that depend on TCP
header information.
Typically, a packet filter
will make a filtering decision
based on the first fragment of a packet.
The attacker here hopes that
the filtering firewall examines
only the first fragment and that the
remaining fragments are passed through.
This attack can be defeated by enforcing
that the first fragment of a packet
must contain a predefined minimum
amount of transport header information.
If the first fragment is rejected,
then all the subsequent fragments
should also be rejected.