As well as the number of
elements that are involved,
you have to factor in selector matching.
Selector matching is
the process of figuring out
whether some styles should actually
apply to any given DOM element.
It's possible to select this div,
either with its class, like this, or
with a more complex selector like this.
It's complex, because in order
to know if the style applies,
it has to figure out if this is
the third child, whereas with this,
it can simply use the class name.
Now you may be thinking
that this shouldn't matter.
And actually for matching a single
element, it really doesn't.
And this is a pretty simple example.
It's only going to take a browser a
fraction of a millisecond to figure out
the match in both cases, but if you have
a large number of elements affected by
a style change, then the complexity of
the selected can really start to matter.
One approach that works very well is
BEM, or block, element, modifier.
And it's a way of writing your CSS.
It uses single class
names to style elements.
And not only does it provide
more modular, reusable, and
readable styles, it is advantageous
to performance, since class matching
is often the fastest selector
to match for modern browsers.
In the case of the example we just had,
you could probably use
a class like this.
It's a box which
would've been the block.
There isn't any element, but
the modifier would be, say three,
to show that it's the third box.
If you want to know more about BEM, take
a look in the instructor notes below.
You can use any number of methodologies
for keeping your CSS tidy.
So if BEM isn't your thing there
are plenty of others you can try.
The key thing is, where you can,
keep your selector matching simple.