Great job finishing lesson two stage one.
Remember that in your terminal you may need to control C
in order to get your command prompt back.
I like to clear my terminal to have a clean working space.
Now, similar to lesson one,
you will connect the random sentence spout to your topology.
However, now we are going to count sentences.
Here's a thought question.
When updating your topology what string grouping is
needed to insure sentence copies are sent to the same count bolt?
You'll be implementing this soon.
In part one, navigate in your favorite text editor, again I'm using Atom,
to lesson2 > stage2.
Source > jvm > udacity > storm.
First, you will copy and
duplicate your word count topology to create a sentence count topology.
Following the Java convention you'll need to update the required class and
constructor names to match the file name.
In part two, in your new file SentenceCountTopology.java.
Write an import statement for
the spout random sentence spout that I've included here.
Notice that this is under udacity, storm, spout, random sentence spout.
In part thee in your topology builder, scroll down and
remove the word spout and connect the random sentence spout with an ID.
Sentence-spout.
In Part 4 in your Topology Builder, connect the sentence spout to the CountBolt.
Here again, what connection is needed to count individual sentences.
Similar to the word count topology, what field does this require?
Remember that you must check the random sentence spout declaration for
the correct field.
Finally, in Part 5, using Maven, package your Storm program.
And submit your topology.
Notice that the visualization will run because the report bolt is
already connected to the count bolt.
Once you have a build success, you can submit your storm as usual.
Remember to use the dependencies jar.
And making sure that your flask server is running,
you'll see that the sentences now are being displayed.
And as the count increases, the sentences should increase in size.
And there it goes.
Remember after your visualization is running,
why don't you go into the random sentence spout and change the sentences so
that you either let us know what you're thinking about the class.
Or letting us know how you're feeling.
Or even just entering some of your favorite song lyrics.
After you get your visualization running, take a screen shot and
post it to the forum.
And comment on two other of your fellow learners' postings.
Lastly, if you already have a Twitter account,
why don't you tweet a screen shot to your followers.
Your code should now match lesson two, stage three.