The last method will
look at accounts for
all three components,
that can be found in the time series.
The Holt-Winter Seasonal Method
comprises of forecast equation with
three smoothing equations, one for
the level, one for the trend,
and now, one for the seasonal component.
Again, we can use the two variations
of application in the method,
both additive and multiplicative.
To review, the additive
method is used when seasonal
fluctuation does not change
in magnitude over time.
Whereas the multiplicative method is
used when seasonal fluctuation changes
in magnitude.
The Holt-Winters Seasonal Method can
also be used with a damped parameter,
and is one of the most widely regarded
methods for forecasting seasonal data.