So let's take a look at
the implementation of the MyApplication
class.
So here's where I defined the mTracker
variable to hold the tracker.
Then I have the method startTracking.
Just going to initialize the tracker.
First of all,
check if it already exists.
Simple check for now.
If it doesn't then create
the Google Analytics
instance by calling getInstance
on the Google Analytics class.
And then we create the tracker,
newTracker,
passing in the tracker
configuration file right here.
And then we enable autotracking,
ga.enableAutoActivityReports.
So that's all there is
to start tracking, and
getTracker is actually even simpler.
ALl we have to do is call startTracking,
and the startTracking method takes
care of checking,
does the tracker already exist or not?
And then we return the tracker.
Okay, I hope you all got that.