All right, so there's a lot of
different types of loops, and
the first one we're going to
learn about is the while loop.
In this next quiz, you'll write code for
the while loop, and
the while loop will help
us create text view for
each element of the words list,
and add it to the layout.
And by the end of this coding task,
your app will look like this, so
while is a special Java keyword.
It means that we should keep
executing a block of statements
denoted by instructions in this diagram,
as long as a certain condition is true.
So we continue to execute
the set of instructions,
while this condition is true.
And essentially move
through it in a loop.
So to go into more detail,
while the condition between
the parentheses is true, we execute
all the instructions in this block of
code that lies between these two braces.
And then after that we go back to the
condition again, and then check to see
if that's true, and if it is true we
execute these set of instructions again.
Then we go back to the condition.
Check to see if it's true and if it is
execute the set of instructions again
and then if we go back to the condition.
And at any point it's false, then we
skip over then set us and truculence,
and exit the loop and continue with
the rest of the code comes after it.
So this condition determines
how many times the code
inside this wild block will be executed.
Often the condition will be
testing the state of a variable.
So we can set up a counter variable
before we begin the loop, and I thought
end of each iteration, so movement
through we can update that variable.
And at some point we're going to update
the variable such a the condition will
be false, and
that causes us to exit the loop.
So here's an example
of the while loop and
it corresponds with the place sound
example that we mentioned earlier.
How do we ever arrive at this code?
Whatever we're debating with ourselves
whether to write a loop or not so
we can ask ourselves three questions.
What tests are we
trying to do each time?
How many times do we
need to repeat the loop?
And as a result what is
the condition of the loop.
So in this case for
the first question what is the test we
do each time we need to play a sound.
To figure out the condition we ask
ourselves the second question.
How many times do we repeat the loop?
And for example,
say we want to repeat it three times.
If that's the case,
we can make the condition to be that the
count variable must be less than three.
So this is assuming that the count
variable is initialized at zero and
then is updated each time.
So see how this while loop is run.
Let's keep track of our variable count.
So first the count variable
is initialized at zero, and
then we enter the while loop.
Now we determine if the condition
is true or false, and
this condition says that count
needs to be less than three.
In our case, zero is less than three,
so the condition is true.
That means we can continue
into the while block and
execute these lines of code.
So we call the method playSound, and
imagine that playSound as a valid
method defined somewhere else.
That plays a sound on the device.
Afterwards we update
the count variable by 1, so
now count has a value of 1 and
we move back to the condition.
So we check our test condition and
check if the count variable
is still less than 3.
Well, 1 is less than 3 so
we're good to go, and
continue back into the while loop.
So we execute these set of instructions
again, we play sound, so ding!
And then we update
the count variable to 2,
now the test condition is still
true because 2 is less than 3.
So we play the sound again,
now we update the count variable to 3,
and when we go back to the condition,
this time the condition fails.
Because three is not less than three.
So once the condition is
false we exit the loop and
continue with the code
that comes after it.
So to summarize we've executed the code
inside the loop three times and
that means we've played the sound
three times on the device.
So as you can see a loop allows us to
repeat behavior with a concise number of
lines without copying pasting
the same code over and over again.
So here's one more example while loops
before I send you off to write your own
assume the code they will be
talking about will be run
inside the numbers activity after
you created the words list.
So I've set up an example scenario where
the task I want to repeat is to print
out a long statement for a specific item
in the list, based on an index variable.
And say I want to repeat
the loop four times.
So that the condition is that
we keep repeating the loop
as long as the index
variable is less than four.
Assuming that the index
variable starts off at zero and
then increments one at a time.
So to write out this code,
we create the index variable first and
initialize it to zero.
So this line of code will
live outside the loop.
When we start the while statement we
need to use the while he would in Java
fall by parentheses for the condition.
So the condition is that the experience
should be less than four and
if we want to repeat of four times.
It should repeat once for index 0,
again for index 1, again for index 2,
then lastly for
index 3 before exiting the loop.
Now inside the while loop,
we can write instructions for the task.
We want to print out a log statement for
a specific item in the list
based on the index value.
This log statement has
the tag NumbersActivity.
And the messages index, followed by the
index variable, along with the value.
Followed by the string value at
that position in the words list.
And that's all the instructions
that we need for this task.
Alright, so lastly,
within the body of this while loop,
is that we need to update
the index variable by one.
So we haven't seen this
syntax before of index++.
But this is a shorthand that means
the same thing as setting the index
variable to be index = index + 1.
All right, so
now you're intimately familiar
with how to write a loop in Java.
Go ahead and apply what you learn
to fix out me walk up code.
To create a display, text me for
each element in the worst
list using a while loop.
So pick up where we last left off in the
numbers activity where we're manually
creating three text views, and adding
them to the linearly out without a loop,
and modify it to use
a while loop instead.
So now we're going to update
the Miwok app to use the while loop.
So for the first task remove the log
messages in number activity and
on create method.
For the second task modify
activity underscore numbers
to change the relative
layout into a linearly out.
Then set the linearly
orientation to be vertical, and
then add a view ID called rootview.
Lastly, modify the numbers
activity oncreate method so
that the code uses a while loop to
create and display a textview for
each element in the words list.
Remember you can start off where we last
left off with the code for the numbers
activity, which creates three text to
use manually without using a loop.
So after completing
steps one through three.
The numbers activity in your
app should look like this.
So, if you need a hint.
I've added an example of
the while loop down below and
there is an example of
the output as well.
So, good luck.