I want to introduce one more problem
that can be solved with search
techniques.
And this is a sliding blocks
puzzle called the 15 Puzzle.
You may have seen something like this.
So there are a bunch of little
squares or blocks or tiles and
you can slide them around, and the goal
is to get into a certain configuration.
So we'll say that this is the goal
state where the numbers one to 15
are in order, left to right,
top to bottom.
And the starting state would be some
state where all the positions are messed
up, now the question is, can we come
up with a good heuristic for this?
And let's examine that as a way of
thinking about where heuristics come
from.
Now the first heuristic we're
going to consider, we'll call h1.
And that's equal to,
the number of misplaced blocks.
So here, 10 and 11 are misplaced,
because they should be there and there,
respectively.
12's in the right place,
13 is in the right place.
And 14 and 15 are misplaced.
So that's a total of
four misplaced blocks.
The second Heuristic h2,
is equal to the sum of
the distances that each block would have
to move to get to the right position.
So, for this position, 10 would have
to move one space to get to the right
position, 11 would have to move one so
that's a total of two so far.
13 is in the right place,
14 is one displaced.
And 15 is one displaced.
So that would also be a total of four.
Now the question is which, if any,
of these heuristics are admissible.
Check the boxes, next to the heuristics
that you think are admissible.
[BLANK_AUDIO]