There is one more thing to deal with when we have to talk about games--and that's chance.
We want to move from purely deterministic games to stochastic games
like backgammon or other games that introduce dice or other parts of random action.
That means that the actions that an agent takes
are not specifically specified to have a single result.
Let's see how we can deal with stochastic games
by looking at our value function and modifying it to allow for this.
Here we have our valuation function, and we're dealing with four types of nodes--
one, nodes that we decide to cut off on our own, because we reached a certain depth;
second, nodes that are terminal according to the rules of the game;
and third, max to move and min to move.
Now I'm going to add one more type, which is a chance node.
We say if the state is a chance node, then we want to return the expected value of S
and carry along these bookkeeping variables.
What we're saying here is if it's at the point of the game where it's time to roll the dice,
then we're going to role the dice, and we're going to take the expected value
of all the possible results rather than the max or the min.
Here we have a schematic diagram for a stochastic game--a game with dice.
We start out. The chance node or the dice-rolling node is first.
The dice is rolled--one of six possibilities.
Then the next player gets his move.
In this case, we've let Min move first, and Min has various moves possible to make.
For each one, there is then another role of the dice, and then Max gets to make his move.