Quick look is a visual debugging feature
that was introduced in Xcode five.
You may have seen it before if you
pressed space when you selected
a variable in the variables view.
Let's take a quick look now.
So I'm going to run the application and
this time instead of selecting
the Break point Debugging scene.
Let's go to the visual debugging scene.
And tap.
And that's strange.
It looks like something's
being added to the screen.
It looks like our spider, but
it's not crawling onto the web.
So let's add a breakpoint,
and addBugToView for
the visual BugViewController.
Go back and tap.
Let it fall into our breakpoint.
If we go to the variables view.
We can bring up a quick look
by selecting a variable and
then pressing the space key.
I'll select self and press space.
The quick look for
this object's fairly limited.
It gives us the same information
that we've seen before.
It tells us the type and
just gives us this value which
is a raw memory address.
But lets try something that's
more visually oriented.
So lets go the bugs array, and
we'll take the first
element in the bugs array.
Since it's a UI image view,
and press space.
And this is much nicer.
It actually shows us the image that
is displayed in the UI image view.
So lets have a little fun with this.
And we can actually change
the image in LLDB and
see how it affects the quick look.
So I'll type expression and then bugs.
Element zero.
And then for the image we'll change it
using UIImage name, named: settings.
Enter.
And this command updates
the element at index zero to
use the settings image
instead of the spider image.
And if we go back to the quick look,
hit space.
We can see that that
image has indeed updated.
And if we run, it's hard to tell, but
it could be the case that that's also
changed, and that's our second bug.
Now we're going to fix this crawling
issue in the next exercise.
But for fun I want to show you how
to make a custom quick look for
any class that you may have.
So i'll go ahead and stop the app, and
let's scroll down to the bottom of
the VisualBugViewController class.
And the process for creating a custom
Quick Look is the same for every class.
It just depends on your implementation.
So you have to implement this
method called debugQuickLookObject.
So I've gone ahead and we're
going to do this in an extension for
the "VisualBugViewController".
We're implementing
the debugQuickLookObject method.
And it returns an AnyObject?
Optional.
The key is, is that this any object that
we return is something that X code knows
how to display.
So for instance it was able
to display a UI image view.
We saw that just a second ago.
So that's one type that we could return.
But for the other types, I've posted a
link to Apple's listing of all the other
supported types that you
can use in this case.
For this particular example we're
going to return a UI image.
I've written this code ahead of time,
and
what is essentially does is it
loops through our bugs array.
And it creates an image with
colored squares indicating
each bug that's in the bugs array.
Now you can step through
this code if you like, but
the purpose here is to show you
that we can actually do this.
So disregarding this code, we return
an image at the end of the day.
And that's going to be our quick look.
So let's run the app and
see what this looks like.
So we'll go to the visual
debugging scene.
And let's go ahead and
spawn a couple spiders.
Whoops.
So let's deactivate that first.
Create some blue ones.
Create a red one or two.
Green one, black one, and
we'll re-enable this.
And now if we press space on the self,
we can see our image.
And this image gets it's colors
corresponding to the bugs that
are in the array.
And there you go.
That's a custom quick look.