To quickly summarize, basically
introduce the concept of light field,
to kind of let us get away from the
whole concept of just pixels in cameras.
We talked about the plenoptic function,
and the parameters that could be encoded
in the plenoptic function,
how we would represent them.
We talked about different
types of light fields and
what dimensions they captured from
holograms to simple panoramas.
We looked at how a pinhole in a lens
system can be used to analyze
the scene and capture more
than just pixel information.
I showed you just by creating
an eccentric aperture
we can actually encode more information.
And also that combining a lens with a,
an array of pinhole cameras,
we can encode direction and
intensity of the rays of light.
And, using these concepts, and, again,
basically a lens and micro-lens arrays,
lenticular arrays and stuff like that,
we can build a 40 light field camera.
And I demonstrated at least one of them.
The premise of all of this was to,
basically, kind of now ask us to
push beyond the simple metrics
of cameras as we know them.
And start thinking of cameras that
capture a lot more light fields, and
that could be used to generate images by
combining information from the different
types of sensors.
Further reading on this one
available through the papers that
I'm listing here.
Some of the earliest work on defining
the plenoptic function comes in 1991,
including the first
system to do it in 92.
And then of course, the graphics people
developed these approaches to kind of
render and capture light fields.
And then of course,
a light field camera itself.
Much more work continues
to happen in this space.
I encourage you to look it up,
a very exciting discipline on its own.
>> More information is available
elsewhere including the book that we're
looking at and also at the Lytro site.