Let's look at this pipeline again or
these elements again in the context of a panorama.
[INAUDIBLE] panorama, basically, we are going to be able to look at the optics,
the sensor, processing, the display, to a user, to get a pretty panorama.
So for example, here are the images, I'm showcasing seven images,
of a cricket ground, the famous Lord's Cricket Ground in London, England.
And if you notice, this was taken by a camera as the camera was
being panned from left to right.
So we have seven images, one, two, three, four, five, six, and seven.
The goal of panorama building is to take this image and generate an image like
this, which basically is a seamless image that basically shows more detail and
space than an individual image there.
Just looking at the numbers, these are seven pictures, each picture was
about seven megapixels, so this is 7.1 megapixel each image, okay?
This is the panorama, this is 11,000x2,000 pixels, so that's 31 megapixel, and
more appropriately, the field of view is 151 degrees wide, and 24 degrees high.
Individually of course, you can imagine that, the vertical field of view for
each and every one of these images is the same, approximately as that, but, of
course this shows a lot more space because it's got a much wider field of view.
We'll talk about the concept of field of view a little later, but, right now,
basically think of it as this showing more, angular space, then each and
every individual one which is most really just this much,
going spreading out this way.