You can see the earliest and latest start times filled in for all the states.
Here's an alternative method for visualizing this.
Here I've given names to the various actions--
the three on the top and the three on the bottom.
They have a duration along a time line, and we can see the time line there.
Notice that these three actions have no slack between them.
One has to start after the other.
We say that these are on the critical path in that if any of these slip in the schedule,
then the whole schedule will slip.
Whereas these three actions have some slack.
The could occur anywhere within this gray window,
and if this action slipped to the right, then the others would slip to the right
without affecting the final schedule.
I should say that over the years the field of scheduling has moved
in and out of the artificial intelligence.
Some people have worked on it, but most of the work on scheduling
has been done in the field of operations research-
a closely related field to artificial intelligence.