When we had just one single process control block,
it was a large contiguous data structure.
We have to maintain separate copies for
every single thread, even though they may share some information.
Whenever we need to context switch we need to save and
restore this entire data structure, and it is large we said.
And finally, it's just this one data structure that's used for so
many different operations.
For scheduling, for memory management, for synchronization.
If we want to customize any aspect of that, we are potentially going to
affect multiple OS services, and so it makes updates a little bit challenges.
So all in all, there are multiple limitations to this approach of
using a single process control block structure to
represent all aspects of the execution state of a process.
Scalability is limited due to the size.
Overheads are limited because they need to have private copies.
Performance is affected because everything has to be saved and restored.
And then flexibility is affected by the fact that updates are a little bit
more difficult.
In contrast, when we have multiple data structures, we actually end up with mu,
multiple small data structures.
The information that was contained in the original process control block,
is now maintained via pointers by pointing to much smaller data elements.
Then it becomes easy to share portions of that information.
We will point to the same data structure for
those components of the state, which are identical across threads or processes.
And we will create new elements when we need to have different information.
On a context switch, only that portion of the state that actually needs to
change will be saved and restored.
And then both,
any kinds of modifications will impact only subset of the data elements.
And then the interactions between the user-level library and the system will
also be carried out through a much smaller more, more confined interfaces.
All in all, this trend to use multiple data structure leads to
improvements across the board.
We gain on scalability,
on overheads because we don't have to have separate copies for, for everyone.
We have improvements in performance because context which time can be reduced,
and we have more flexibility.
As a result, operating systems today typically adapt this type of approach for
organizing information about their execution contexts.