So this is how I did it.
.map returns an array so
I create an arrayofPromises by
passing all of the URLs to getJSON.
Now remember at this point,
because they've been mapped,
this function immediately
runs against every URL.
So in reality, I have an arrayOfPromises
that are basically already executing,
and then I simply pass them into .all.
Once all of the promises settle,
then the next link in the chain runs.
In this case the .then
receives an arrayOfPlanetData,
which is in the same order as
the array of promises and then for
every planet,
I create a planet thumbnail.
Very cool.
Looks like I left out a semi-colon.
Incidentally, I could make this
section a little bit more terse.
Let me show you how.
First off,
I don't need this anonymous function.
This is the same, because remember this
function will receive the same argument
as the anonymous function.
And of course I don't actually
need to create a variable,
I can simply pass the array
created by map straight to all.
Anyway, lets see how this looks.
All right, the planets are once again
there in the correct order, and
I'm seeing all of the requests
happen in parallel.
The cool thing is because all guarantees
the order of the resulting array,
I know that all the thumbnails ended
up on the page in the correct order,
so that's pretty nice.
There is one more performance
optimization that's possible
with this code.
Some people may or
may not think it's a good idea, but
it's definitely a good challenge.
So after this course is over,
at the very end of it,
there's a bonus challenge for
you to optimize this code even further.