I could also write a slightly
different variation of the function
reverseAndPrint like this.
Here, forwardString is a second name for
the parameter being passed in.
Now, you might be wondering,
why does this parameter need two names?
String is the local parameter name.
You can see here that it's used
locally inside the function itself.
This other parameter name,
forwardString,
is the external parameter name.
It's used externally.
In other words, when the function
is called in the function call,
the external parameter name
would be used like this.
And here's where
the underscore comes in.
If I use the underscore as in
the first version of reverseAndPrint,
then I don't have to include
a parameter name in the function call.
The underscore specifies no
external parameter name needed.
Down here, you can see that this
first call to reverseAndPrint
is taking advantage of the underscore.
We'll see more external parameters in
a minute when we talk about how to call
functions.
So, to update our model, functions
can take the general form when you
see a name on the left with no colon,
that's the externalParameterName and
the localParameterName is here.