in this tutorial we started by curating
a data set of movie review and label
pairs then we trained neural network on
these movie reviews and found that x by
itself it actually could not converge on
the data set so we adjusted the
parameters and got to start converting a
little bit but learning was incredibly
slow and only actually reached accuracy
around sixty percent is not that much
better than random after understanding
the fundamental pattern over trying to
discover we were able to significantly
reduce the noise in our dataset increase
the signal so that are known that was
able to discover our pattern much more
quickly like iterating several times to
the course of these different six
projects were able to achieve an
accuracy it was much higher in a
training speed was much much faster than
we started with
I hope you will find these techniques
generalized to pretty much any problem
you're interested in attacking the
neural networks will be incredibly
useful to you out in the real world