Here's one more topic.
We're going to talk about how to extend classicial planning to allow active perception
to deal with partial observability.
Here's a problem description.
There's a table and a chair, and there are two cans of paint.
The table is within our field of view,
and our goal is to have the chair and the table have the same color.
Here's the actions.
We can remove the lid from a can, making it open.
We can paint one thing with that can if the can is open.
We also have an active perception action,
which is we can look at something.
If it's in view, we can look at it,
and then we're looking at that one thing, and we're no longer looking
at whatever we were looking at before.
Now, here's the big extension that in addition to actions,
we now have percept schemas.
Action schemas and perception schemas,
and we can perceive the color of something if it's an object.
Here the objects are declared to be the table and the chair,
and if it's within our field of view.
Notice that here we're introducing a new variable.
We never did that before in planning.
Before all the actions in planning, all the variables,
were predefined by matching against the precondition.
Here we're introducing a new variable.
We're saying if these preconditions are true,
then you can perceive something, and you'll learn something new.
You'll learn the value of this variable.
Here's a question. How can we achieve this goal?
The first thing I want to ask is, without even thinking about the percepts,
is there a conformant plan that is a that doesn't do sensing
that will allow us to achieve this goal?
Is there that type of conformant plan?
Tell me yes or no.