Let's pull just one of these
commands out to start.
8.8.8.8 is the address of
a particular service at Google.
And ping is a command for testing
whether your computer can send and
receive network traffic
with that address.
And -c3 means to send three test
messages, then quit and print results.
All traffic on the Internet is split
up into messages called packets.
A packet is just a short message sent
from one computer to another with
the addresses of the sender and
the recipient on it.
You can imagine that network traffic is
made up of a stream of little postcards
going back and forth, carried over the
various media like Wi-Fi, and ethernet,
and cable modems and so on.
The ping command sends and
receives individual packets to
test whether traffic can get from
one address to another and back.
So if you ran ping -c3 8.8.8.8,
pinging this service at Google.
And you got results that looked
like these, specifically,
3 packets transmitted,
3 received, 0% packet loss.
Which of the following
conclusions seem reasonable?
One, that your computer
has Internet access.
Two, that the computer at
8.8.8.8 is up and running.
Three, that there is a website you
could access at http:// 8.8.8.8.
Four, that your computer is
directly on Google's network.
Or five, that your ISP knows how
to send traffic towards Google.
Check whichever ones of these apply.