There are a couple of cool little properties of BRDF.
One named Helmholtz, after the guy Helmholtz, basically light
doesn't know which way's up, or another way of saying it is it's a reciprocity.
That is, if a light source is coming this way, and
the camera is going that way, and I swap the camera and the light source,.
I get the same, reflectance function, right?
So, it doesn't matter whether the light comes in this way and
goes out that way, or comes in this way and goes out that way.
There is no light diode, for the nerds among us, all right?
There probably are, you probably could build active light diodes, but
for normal properties you don't get that for our purposes,
there's another important property which is referred to as rotational symmetry.
And the way of thinking about that is.
If I rotate the surface, about the normal, nothing's going to change.
All right.
And what that, essentially means is is that I only have to
worry about the little tangent plane right at the point that I'm looking.
And so the only thing that matters, is the relative direction between these.
Not just in, in terms of here I want to talk about the amount around the angle.
So the absolute, angle doesn't matter just the, relative distance between them.
And that's written like this.
The absolute angle in terms of the tilt still matters, okay?
And we'll, we'll show you that in just a minute.
But the, the rotation around, is only relative.
Around the normal.
Bidirectional reflectance distribution functions for
real objects, can be incredibly complicated here's a sort of,
little panoply of different types of reflectance functions.
We're not going to talk any more, about those.
If you want to do,
take a computer graphics course and learn how to render hair or.
See this bird down here by the way.
I think it's peacock feather.
It's actually not dye, but
it's refractive so bird feathers are actually not painted if you will.
But they refract the light through the material that's in it.
It's a very complicated BRDF.
We're not going to talk anymore about that, because we're going to talk about.
Two specific reflectance functions, that are special cases of BRDF's, and
that you can combine them to sort of make most normal types of objects.
Namely we're going to talk about what's called diffuse, or
matte reflection, plus specular reflection.