So far the connectors we have been talking about have been simple connectors.
It's also possible to put connectors together; that is, to compose them,
make it more complex connectors.
One example I'd like to give is a science data server.
Whether you're aware of it or
not, there's lots of data being generated out there.
Think of all the land sat photographs being taken.
Using different frequencies of light they can record all kinds of
information that's stored away on data servers.
Then there are clients for these servers.
The clients may be synchronous or asynchronous.
That is, they may have specific requests or
they might want to get a stream of data themselves.
Okay, and we need to be able to build a composite connector to provide this
overall capability.
It may involve event connectors, data acc, certainly will involve data
access connectors might be streaming of data, and it might be distribution.
There are different policies that we might want to enforce for delivery.
We might, we almost certainly will have multiple producers and consumers.
There's going to be almost certainly some data transformation going on and
the access may be public or it may be, may be private, okay?
It may be transient, or
it may be persistent, persistent depending upon the policy of the data server.
It might be packaged into streams or it might be packetized, okay?
And there might be a naming registry involved so
that they information can be accessed via a specific query.
Another example of a composite connector are various FTP applications,
such as Globus, bbFTP, and GridFTP.
These combine procedure call, data access, steam, and
distributor simple connectors.
Therefore moving and distributing large amounts of grid data.
Could be hierarchically or flatly named.
Typically synchronous.
Using web protocols such as SOAP might involve time-outs,
authentication would prevent unwanted access to the data.
There's parameter passing.
The data might be transient or
it might be persistent might be public or it might be private.
And it might be at the level of byte stream or
the underlying bytes might be raw or structured.
Probably one exactly-once deliver, a bounded buffering, and
unicast, that is, point to point transmission.
The third example of a composite connector is client-server based distributed
distribution connectors that involve things like REST architectural style,
HTTP protocol.
Remote messaging vocation.
CORBA, FTP, SOAP, this particular kind of connector,
kind of composite connector might use procedure call connectors, data access,
stream and distributor connectors.
Involve revoke procedure call, would name parameters, persistent and
transient data, and naming registry, and typically unicast type connections.
The final example of composite connector is peer to
peer based data distribution connector such as BitTorrent.
Here there is a combination of arbitrator, data access, stream, and
distributor connectors.
Typically peer-to-peer is, major facility is controlling the flow of, of things.
And that is, control flow redirection.
If one of the peers is not available,
you go to another peer to provide the information.
There may be negotiation of protocols, scheduling and timing.
There may be voting involved,
depending upon circumstances might use either rendezvous or transactions.
The data may be transient or persistent.
typically, streams are what's what, what's used.
They may be buffering involved.
And for these types of applications, typically it's at least one semantics.
You don't want to deliver more than once