So let's look at an example.
Again, Einstein meets Tigger.
Now, our goal is to blend them that half of the image comes from here and
half, the other half comes from here.
And of course, just to doing a sharp blend like this,
if we were just to put them next to each other, we would get a sharp line.
What happens if we actually went through the process I discussed earlier?
Notice there is no sharp line anymore.
Because what we did was, we actually deconstructed into different pyramids.
We blended, again, with this 90 this kind of half cut between both the images.
Took pixels from both of them.
Well when we reconstructed it, this frequency mixing going on, and kind of see
the Tigger skin merging with with the Einstein skin, the eyebrows and
all of that kind of stuff are merged at least at these boundary lines.
Now, this is, of course, a simple case.
What happens if we wanted to do this kind of blending for
a specific case where you wanted to actually have the blend happen just for
specific regions of the image.