A nanodegree is an exciting commitment.
It can help you prepare for
an entirely new stage of your
career in a matter of months.
>> But it's also a big commitment, and
we want to make sure
that you're ready for it.
>> So we've designed
a readiness assessment for
you to take to help you figure out
if right now is a good time for
you to start the program.
You'll see some questions
about time commitment and
some about your existing knowledge.
>> Right.
And
respond honestly to each
of these questions.
After you submit each response,
you'll see some feedback show up.
And remember, you're never going to
be evaluated based on your responses.
We just want to help you figure
out if now is the right time.
So, if any of that feedback suggests
that now is not the right time,
go ahead, listen to the advice,
and come back when you're ready.
>> And otherwise, you are ready.
You can get started right now.
However, that doesn't mean that this
program will be a total breeze,
it just means that your prepared for
the challenge ahead.
>> So go ahead, get started and we will
see you after the readiness assessment.