As we've seen,
Xcode provides great tools for
stepping through our code and
fixing issues.
With features like quick looks and
view hierarchies,
we can even examine our
applications visually.
But remember,
regardless of what tool you're using,
debugging always involves
the same basic steps.
You have to reproduce the problem,
gather any debugging information,
determine the fix, make the change, and
then try to reproduce the problem again.
If everything goes well,
the problem will be fixed.
In closing, none of us will
ever write perfect code, but
by becoming better debuggers, we'll know
how to fix problems when they arise.