What is the Gittins index?
>> What is the Gittins index?
I think it comes down to if I gave
you the choice between this arm and
something with a known payoff, how high
would that known payoff have to be for
you to forego ever trying
the uncertain arm?
So if I could pay you off and
say you're never allowed to
choose this bandit again.
How much money would you expect for
me to do that?
What expected value of
a pay off would you need so
that you don't even ever
need to try this again?
And so it ends up being greater than the
expected value of the arm itself right?
So the arm has paid off 0.2 on average,
but we've only tried it 20 times
then this index value is
going to be bigger than 0.2.
because I wouldn't be willing
to just take a sure thing
of 0.2 instead of this one because
I could pull this a couple times,
discover that it's actually higher
paying and do better than the 0.2.
>> So, somehow the index has to
compute some kind of confidence on
the probability that this is higher or
lower than the expected value or
something by some amount?
>> Yeah, so it actually, ultimately
combines this notion of the maximum
likelihood and
the low confidence, right?
So if you have low confidence
then you get an extra bonus for
pulling this arm because it may
reveal something really valuable.
>> Right, okay, so there's magic you can
do that computes this and stuff happens.
>> Right, and so
I want to caution you though is the
Gittins index is extremely seductive.
>> Yeah.
>> In that it's just this beautiful
idea that works incredibly well for
bandit problems and
feels like it should generalize.
And people have not been
able to generalize it, but
they've wasted a lot of time trying to.
So I would caution you
don't go down this road.
>> Unless you think you
have a fundamentally new
way of doing the analysis,
the Gittins index thing seems to be
pretty specific to bandits and therefore
won't be helpful to us when we're doing
more general reinforcement learning.
>> Okay,
I've gotta say that's very meta.
>> Oh.
I see what you did there.
because I'm talking about thinking about
different research topics as if they
were bandit arms and
trying to argue about well,
this one has been tried an awful lot.
And so the payoff seems high but once
you know that it's been tried over and
over again, the expected
value is actually quite low.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And so, I'm just trying to help you,
give you experience so
you don't have to pull this arm.
>> Yeah, very meta.
>> That's cute,
I wasn't thinking that way.
>> I'm about helping others.