So, here is what your completed
code should look like.
As you can see here, I've code for
the Button Map object,
the Button Satellite object,
and the Button Hybrid object.
For each of these,
the process is the same.
So, for the btnMap object,
I findViewById,
the button that I had called btnMap.
And once I found that,
I set its OnClickListener.
And within its onClickListener,
if the map is ready,
then I am going to set the map type
to be GoogleMap.MAP_TYPE_NORMAL.
As I mentioned earlier on, you'll
find the types within the GoogleMap
object itself, and here you can see I am
just saying GoogleMap.MAP_TYPE_NORMAL.
Similarly for the satellite,
I find the btnSatellite object.
I set its OnClickListener, and
within its OnClickListener,
I set the MapType to be
GoogleMap.MAP_TYPE_SATELLITE.
And for the hybrid,
I do the same thing, findViewById.
I get the btnHybrid.
I load it into this
button called btnHybrid.
And then I set its OnClickListener.
And if the map is ready, then it
will set it to be a MAP_TYPE_HYBRID.
It's as simple as that.
And then one final thing to add is,
just remember, mapFragment.
You're going to get the actual fragment.
And you're going to get an Async map for
this mapFragment.
And this is all the code that
you need to be able to create
the application that we've just seen.