The answers are, first, yes, it is a problem that it's easy to emit good parses.
So for example, in the small grammar we had, we only had one rule for a noun phrase starting with a determiner,
and so we missed some perfectly good parses.
Secondly, it is easy to include bad parses as well. We want to allow the possibility, say,
of having a verb have both one direct object or an indirect and an indirect object, or be intransitive and have no objects whatsoever.
But if we aren't careful, then every verb will have that possibility, even when it shouldn't.
And we have to go back in and be careful to take away some of those possibilities.
I don't think it's a good idea, or I don't think it's a problem that the trees are unobservable.
Yes, it is true that they are unobservable, but we can still reason with them, even though we don't see them.
For the solutions, it is a good idea to add probabilities to the trees.
It's very difficult to make a call whether something absolutely should be part of the language or not.
And easier to make a probabilistic call. That way we just have to enumerate all the possible parses,
and we can choose among them using probability to help us, and we don't mind if we throw in an extra rule
which will generate some additional parses, as long as they get generated with low probability.
Secondly, it is also a good idea to bring back the word associations.
I mentioned the problem with verbs being transitive or intransitive. We want to know which verbs go with what,
both syntactically--do they take a direct object or not?--and semantically--what types of things do these verbs operate on?
And finally, it would be great if we could make grammars for natural language unambiguous,
but it just isn't going to happen because natural languages inherently are ambiguous.
When we have a perfectly normal sentence, like say, "They are flying planes," "they" can refer either to the planes
or to the pilots, depending on how you interpret the sentence. And either one of those interpretations is good in a particular context.
So we can't rule one out and arbitrarily choose between them.
We have to be able to deal with the ambiguity, not make it go away.