Hey, welcome back.
Hope you enjoyed the last unit. You guys have been doing great.
You've been doing amazing work, getting a lot done,
doing a really good job of answering the questions.
I've been looking at this book here.
This is a book from my father's collection.
It's called "Introduction to the Theory of Games" by McKinsey.
It was published in 1952,
4 years before the start of artificial intelligence.
And so game theory and AI have kind of grown up together.
They've taken different paths,
and now they've begun to merge back together.
We've talked about games already in a previous unit.
We talked about mostly turn-taking games
where 1 player moves and then another moves,
and the trick is how to work against an adversary
who's trying to maximize his own utility
and thus minimize your utility.
Game theory handles those types of games, but it also really focuses
on games where the 2 moves are simultaneous,
or another way to think about them is 1 player moves
and then the other moves, but the second player doesn't know
what choice the first player made, so it's partially observable.
And it's this back and forth of trying to figure out what should I move
given what I think he's going to move and what does he think about
what I'm going to move that gives game theory its special status.
We're going to talk about how that works for AI,
and 2 problems are studied.
The first is agent design.
That is, given a game, find the optimal policy.
And the second is mechanism design.
That is, given utility functions,
how can we design a mechanism so that
when the agents act rationally the global utility will be maximized in some way?
Let's take a look.