In an experiment,
we also have an experimental variable,
sometimes called a treatment variable,
or an independent variable.
This is the variable that you change to
see how it affects the target variable.
In the new product introduction
experiment that we're setting up,
the experimental variable is
the sale of the new candy.
The other variables or
data that we have about the units
are called control variables.
These are now just the predictor
variables in modeling.
They are the variables that
are most influential on
the outcome of the target variable.
In our experiment there could
be other information about
the stores that are available
to us as an analyst.
The other variables or data that we have
about each such as sales, customers,
demographics or location would
be known as control variables.
Control variables are treated a little
differently then predictor variables.
They're not going to be used to build
an equation to make a prediction
on a future value.
We already know we don't have
enough information to do that.
Instead, control variables are used to
make sure that the treatment units and
control units are as similar
to each other as possible.
This allows for
the comparison of the target variable
to be as accurate as possible.
For instance, in our experiment, we
want to know the effect of adding a new
product to the set of products
that our brand sells at a store.
We look at the effect and
adding the product to the whole set
of products that the brand has.
Because if people buy the new product
instead of the one they would
have bought anyway,
then the new product could have more
sales because loses in other products.
In order to compare a store that
is going to sell the new product
to one that is not we need to make
sure they're similar as possible.
For example,
we want stores of similar sales levels,
geographies, customer demographics etc.
This is super important because we want
to measure the impact of the product
launch independent of other factors.