In a relational database, we store
all our data in the form of tables.
So, here's a table with some data in it.
You probably already know how to
answer a lot of questions using data
and tables.
Database tables aren't all that
different from tables you might find in
an infographic or reference book.
Looking at a table like this,
you can tell things like,
say, the population of Brazil or
the literacy rate in Argentina.
So, even before we get into
databases in any kind of detail,
you can probably already answer some
questions about how tables work.
Don't worry about getting
these questions right or
wrong, but take a moment to think
about your answers before we go on.
So first,
when we look across a row like this one,
what do these values have in common?
And second, when we look
down a column like this one,
what do the values there have in common?