Here is an example solution.
We take the exponential of
the scores and we divide by the sum
of the exponential of the scores
across the other categories.
Let's see the drawing.
Here is the result.
Notice that the probabilities
do sum to one.
Let's add some legends to make
this a little bit more clear.
As you can see, the probability of the
class one increases with the score x.
It starts near zero and
it ends close to one.
At the same time, the probabilities of
the other classes start pretty high, but
then go vanishingly down to 0.
Feel free to go back and
play with the softmax function.
For example you could draw a bar
chart to convince yourself
that the probabilities do sum to one for
every value of X.