Lets look at an example of
using variable reduction.
Say we are analyzing an employee
survey where the employee has to rate
with the response from one to seven,
the following questions.
My boss treats me with consideration.
My boss gives me recognition
when I do a good job.
My boss consults me when there
are decisions to be made about my work.
Now, in reality,
these are all similar and
could probably be categorized as
employee satisfaction with supervisor.
An analyst could choose
to leave them all in,
but again, if they're already dealing
with a number of other variables,
it might make it simpler to
just have a single variable
that captures most of the variance in
the response of these three variables.
Again, much easier to communicate
the concept of employee satisfaction
than to identify each
questions results separately.
One negative aspect to variable
reduction is that while it does reduce
the number of variables in the analysis,
depending on the method used in
the data, it can make the interpretation
of the model more difficult.
If the variables you are combining
aren't necessarily related, for
example, population totals and
income levels,
the component variables that
are created might be hard to explain.
It's a good practice to try
to use variable reduction
when the variables are somewhat related.
We see this in the example data we built
out in the exercise from the previous
lesson.
We have 12 months each of temperature,
snowfall, rain and precipitation data.
I wouldn't want to use variable
reduction methods to combine all 48
variables at once, but it would make
sense to create component variables for
each category of climate.
This way, snowfall is kept
separate from temperature.
So, as an analyst, you need to weight
the benefit you can get from reducing
the number of variables you use in
the clustering analysis, with the all
important aspect of needing to be able
to explain the basis for the clusters