Devices interface with the rest of
the system via controller that's
typically integrated as part
of the device packaging,
that's used to connect the device
with the rest of the CPU complex
via some CPU device interconnect.
Whatever off-chip interconnect
is supported by the CPU
that different devices can connect to.
This figure that's adapted
from the Silver Sheds book
shows a number of different
devices that are interconnected
to the CPU complex via PCI bus.
PCI stands for
peripheral component interconnect and
it's one of the standard methods for
connecting devices to the CPU.
Today's platforms typically
support PCI Express interconnect,
which are technologically more advanced
than the original PCI or PCI-X bus.
So, PCI Express has more bandwidth and
it's faster, has lower access latency,
supports more devices.
In all aspects,
it is better than PCI-X which was the
follow on on the original PCI standard.
For compatibility reasons, though,
today's platform will also include
some of these older technologies,
typically PCI-X because it's compatible
with PCI, PCI-X stands for PCI extended.
Note that the PCI bus is not
the only interconnect that's
shown in this figure alone.
There is also a SCSI bus
that connect SCSI disks,
there's a peripheral bus here shown
that connects devices like keyboards,
and there may be other types of buses.
The controllers that are part
of the device hardware,
they determine what type of interconnect
can a device directly attach to.
And, there are also bridge and
controllers that can handle
any differences between
different types of interconnects