Here's the scenario. We've obtained access to a file belonging
to some enemy, and we want to do some sabotage.
The files stores a table of key value pairs, both
of them ints, and the whole file is in binary.
It just goes key, value, key, value, key, value, all
the way through. Your task is to write a program
that will change the value associated with a particular key.
So the perimeters to your program will be file name,
the key who's value we want to change, and the new value we want
to associate with that key. Now our
enemies engineers weren't very clever. So the
keys in the file are in no particular order. You just have to search
there. Consult the man pages for open,
read, write, Lseek, and close. And Good luck.