You've completed the first step
in adding a recycler view,
adding the dependency and
adding the recycler view to the layout.
The next step is to craft the items
that will be displayed in it and
create an object called a view holder
that we'll use to store references
to that item.
In this app,
the list scrolls vertically so
each item corresponds to a row of data.
However, as we learned earlier,
recycler view can display these items
in a horizontally scrolling list,
which whould make the item a column or
in a grid.
Because of this, I'll use item
when talking about the row layout
because that doesn't suggest
a specific layout preference.
All right, we begin by opening
up exercise two view holder.
You notice the first to-do is to
create a layout resource called
numberlistitem.xml.
So we go to new layout resource file and
create numberlistitem.xml.
That was fun.
And the second to-do here is to make
the root element a FrameLayout, so
we'll do that.
Android Studio has nicely set
the layout_width to match_parent and
the layout_height also to match_parent.
Let's add 16dp's of padding,
create a single TextView as the child
of the frame layout, set the height and
the width to wrap content.
Lastly, set the font family to
monospace and the text size to 42 SP.
Note, we've used SP and
DP when we've referred to
dimensions in Android layouts.
These are both not
actual pixel sizes but
are automatically scaled to be
the same approximate physical size,
regardless of the density of
the pixels on the screen.
The first Android
phones were 160 dpi and
1 dp would actually equal
1 pixel on these devices.
The conversion of dp units to screen
pixels is simple, px = dp * (dpi / 160).
Many modern devices have 480 dpi or
more.
SP work like DP but are also scaled
based upon user preferences,
typically the text size preference.
If you want you want your text to
scale up with this preference,
which is important for accessibility,
make sure to use SP for fonts and
widgets that have hard coded
sizes that contain fonts.
We're halfway there.
We've created the layout for our item.
Now let's build the code that will hold
reference just to these views we've
created.
The rest of the code is inside
of the green adapter class.
We begin by creating our ViewHolder
class in an inner class of green
adapter.
We call this class NumberViewHolder.
Since we only had one
TextView in our layout,
we'll create a single
TextView member variable.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We'll then create a constructor for
NumberViewHolder that accepts a view
called itemView as its parameter.
Within that constructor, we'll pass
the itemView to the superclass and
set our TextView member using a cast
in findViewById and itemView.
One of the most important
things a view holder does
is cache these references to the views
that will be modified in the adapter,
since findViewById can get expensive.
We'll then add a convenience
method called bind,
which helps make our
code a bit more readable.
It takes an integer and
calls set text using, and
this is very important, the string
representation of our list index.
Our code uses value of.
The setText function on text views,
has several different signatures.
The first one here takes an integer,
but that's not the one we want to use.
If we pass in an integer, Android
assumes we're giving it a reference to
a string resource from
strings.xml to display.
In the best case it'll
display incorrect text,
in the worst case it will crash our app.
We want to print the actual
integer itself, so
we need to use this
signature of the function.
There are several ways to do this.
We can use value of on the integer
wrapper class to get an integer object
and call toString on that object, or
we can rely on string concatenation.