Well, clearly this is an admissable heuristic because the distance to the goal is strictly underestimated.
From here it would take one step; from here it'll take one-two steps, so the answer is yes.
Now, to understand a star, let me also draw the G function for the relevant part of this table.
Clearly, G is zero over here. To understand which node to expand, this one or this one, let's project the G function,
which is one, and we'll see that B+1 is smaller than four plus one.
Therefore, this is the second node to expand, which is B1.
Now, let me, for the next step, expand the G function from this guy here, two and two.
So two plus two is four, versus three plus two is five. So we expand this node next, which is C1.
And finally, the G function from here would go three and three.
Three plus one is better than three plus two, so we will expand D1 next.
And notice how, in the sum of G and H, this node over here, which has a total of four, is better than any other node that is unexpanded.
So in particular, four plus one is five, and three plus two is five as well, and two plus three is five as well. So this is the next one to expand.