So, how well does it work?
Well, here's a nice example of finding both the telephone and the shoe.
So here is the original phone and here you can see the outline.
And here are the modest number I don't know one, two, I don't know.
About 15 key points that have been matched.
Now remember, you only need three to find the affine, so by finding more than
three, you get a much more robust solution to the transform.
Likewise, see so here we have our green shoe and
here you can see where it's found.
And again, you can find the set of feature points, key points,
that were matched.
But's also pretty cool.
I only need to find three points from one object in the corresponding place, and
then I can predict where the rest of them go.
So that means, I don't have to see the whole object.
So here you see an example.
Here is the shoe.
I'm going to draw inside so you can see this right.
But you'll notice it's being occluded by this box of whatever the groceries are.
Okay.
Only the front part and the back part of the shoe were found.
All right, but I only needed three matches to find an affine transform, so
I didn't have to see the whole shoe.
I only had to see enough of it to do what's called the alignment.
Same thing is true of this telephone here.
The whole back end of the telephone is missing, but
we're able to recognize it by just finding features within the front part.
That's pretty impressive robustness with respect to occlusion.
Here's another one.
Now you can see the again, David had this thing about teddy bears,
shoes, and telephones.
I'm not exactly sure why.
Anyway here you can see the shoes behind the teddy bear,
only the front part is visible but you can see it.
Same thing with the phone.
So the idea is that as long as I can find these,
a small number of these local matches, I'm able to do the recognition.
oh, and here's one you, you saw before.
Remember the, the, the totem poles?
He's at UBC, University of British Columbia.
They got a lot of Native American, Indian stuff up there, so
I'm guessing that's what this is.
And you remember the thing just works.