Just to recall again, let's take our favorite panorama image.
We want to be able to take an image like this and again,
there are lots of images, in this case the panorama was scanned this way.
And what we want to do is basically find, to generate a novel image
the pixels from one image and the overlapping image beneath it and
give you best possible pixel value within it.
Today, we're going to look at another method to do that.
This basically shows the example where blending can be done to
generate a novel image like this.
And with the right proper thing, you get a beautiful image like this.
In a past lecture, we had looked at how to do this by cross fading different
images, and looked at different sizes.
If I looked at the whole size here by putting two images on top of each other,
doing some sort of a cross-fade.
I get a little bit of a ghostly artifact, I can do this for
a smaller window and I get the artifacts right here.
Or you want a smaller window.
And we looked at various methods to actually figure out how to use the frequency
information to look at the size of these types of windows.
But when we do any type of pixel and pixel merging from one to the other,
you will always have some ghostly artifacts.