Welcome back.
Today we are going to talk
about projector camera systems.
Remember, when we started talking
about computational photography,
I talked about capturing
an illuminated scene, and
being able to generate
a novel image from it.
Now in that pipeline, I did talk about
the fact that you could actually control
the illumination, the optics, and the
camera, and the processing all together
in the pipeline of computation
photography, to generate novel images.
Today we are going to talk about
a specific set of instances where we're
going to merge, couple, for example,
a camera and a projector system.
A projector is, of course,
where we can actually control light.
Remember the example of dual
photography we covered initially,
in the class, where being able
to illuminate a scene, and
being able to control it with a camera,
allowed us to actually see newer things.
Well how, now I'm going to actually
show several different examples
of techniques people have used,
of coupling cameras and
projectors together,
to generate novel forms of images.