In the last video we saw how we
can take string literals and
combine them with integer literals
using the concatenation operator.
This expression evaluates to the string,
I need two cups of coffee on Monday.
The powerful thing about concatenating
different parts of the text together
is that you can swap out different
parts if they need to change.
For example, the number of
cups of coffee might change so
instead of a literal value here,
we can change it to be a variable.
Now I've removed the two and
replaced it with a quantity variable, so
when we evaluate this expression,
we'll always get the latest
value of the quantity variable.
If the variable is holding the value 2,
then it'll pronounce something like,
I need 2 cups of coffee on Monday.
So these parts of the string stay
constant and they don't change,
whereas the quantity is free to change
and will always get the latest value.
I'm going to try it
out in Android Studio.
Since quantity happens to be
a variable that we already have
declared in the MainActivity, I can just
use it directly in submitOrder method.
I'm going to make up a string
like Total Item Count, and
then add quantity, and then coffees.
This isn't really related to price, but
I just want to show you that you can
concatenate strings with variables.
Let's run this to see
what it looks like.
If I change the quantity and
then hit the order button then it
shows total item count, 3 coffees.
I forgot to add the space right
after the 3, but before coffees, so
we should go and add that in.
I am going to add a space here so that
it appears right after the quantity.
Notice that quantity here
is not in double quotes,
if it was then it would literally
show quantity on the screen, but
we want the value of this variable so
we don't put it in quotes.
Now that it has an extra space
here let's try to run it and
make sure it's correct.
Now when I change the quantity to 3 and
hit the Order button it says,
Total Item Count 3 coffees.
It correctly has a space before and
after the quantity value.
Taking a step back, when you look at
this line of code it can be a little
overwhelming because there's quotation
marks everywhere and plus signs and
spaces in weird places.
Just imagine that the plus
signs disappear and
everything in the quotes
gets squished together and
that the quantity variable gets
replaced with an actual value.
Because it's not that easy to read,
it's common to have mistakes here.
You might miss an opening or
closing quotation or
put the plus in the wrong place or
accidentally put a variable in quotes.
Just read through your code carefully to
make sure it's doing what you expect.
You can also do math expressions.
You can have quantity times five
in parentheses and this will
turn into a single integer value and
that will get concatenated to Price.
A string plus an integer turns into
a string and that gets stored in
the variable priceMessage and
that gets displayed on the screen.
When I run this on my device
It shows up as Price 15.
If you want the dollar sign or
the currency symbol to show up,
you need to make it part of
the string literal, like this.
The integer only holds the number part,
not the currency symbol.
If I run this on my device and
then hit the Order button,
now I see the currency symbol.
Following the pattern that I've
been showing you, go ahead and
modify the submitOrder method so
you can practice displaying
different messages on the screen.
First, try to display Amount Due
$10 on the screen when you
hit the Order button.
Once you get that working,
then change it so
that you display this string
when you hit the order button.
Repeat the same for
each of these different strings.
You should only see one of these
strings on the screen at one time.
Remember to concatenate
the strings with variables so
that the quantity and price values are
accurate based on the quantity picker.
So, if I change this to quantity
of five cups of coffee,
then the amount due should be $25.