Let's take another look at
our coconut moving code.
Remember how we multiplied
-2.5 by Time.deltaTime?
Let's talk about that.
Remember that the Update Method
is called every frame.
That means, if we're running
at 60 frames per second,
it gets called around
every 16 milliseconds.
For VR, update might be called 60
times a second, 90 times a second, or
even 120 times a second.
You really can't be certain how
often update will be called.
Since we don't know how
often update will be called,
we have to use Time.deltaTime to
smooth out the motion over time.
Time.deltaTime gives you
framerate-independent animation.
It contains the fraction of a second
that it took the previous frame to draw.
That's why I can just multiply
it with a factor like 2.5 to
achieve a constant motion.
The reason is if my frame
takes double as long to draw,
I should move the object double as far.
It's a smart idea, right?
This means that even if you run
it at 300 frames per second,
your coconut will always fall
at 2.5 meters per second.
No faster, no slower.
Okay, now you know how to program
smooth animation over time.