My final question is a simplified self-driving car question,
that is usually solved using dynamic programming.
But I have to warn you, the state space shown here
isn't the full state space.
The orientation isn't really made explicit, in this state space.
But suppose you have a road environment,
that has a straight street over here,
you can turn left, go straight, or turn right over here,
and similarly you can turn left or right over here.
And we assume that moving from one grid cell to the next
has a cost of '1'.
Turning left has a cost of '14'.
And turning right has a cost of '1' as well.
Let's assume the robot when it turns,
stays in the same grid cell, but it only can turn once.
After it turned, it has to actually move.
So it's impossible, for example, to turn right three times
just to avoid the cost of a left turn.
I would like to know,
what is the minimum total cost
of going from the start location, over here,
to location 'A'.
I realize that there is many ways to get there.
I'd like to know the minimum.
So what's the minimum cost to get to 'A',
irrespective of what orientation you assume at 'A'? I don't really care.
The same from the start location to 'B'.
And from the start location to 'C'.
Please enter your best guesses on the right side.