In the un-marshalling code in contrast,
we take the buffer that's
provided by the network protocol.
And then based on
the procedure descriptor and
the data types that we know are required
for that procedure descriptor,
we parse the rest of the byte
stream from that buffer.
We extract correct number of bytes and
we use those bytes to initialize
data structures that correspond
to the argument types.
As a result of the un-marshal
link process, these I and
J will be allocated somewhere
in the server address space, and
they will be initialized to
values that corresponds to
whatever was placed in the message
that was received by the server.
Now again, the marshal link and
un-marshal link routines aren't
something that the developer
will explicitly have to write, instead
the RPC systems typically include
a special compiler that takes an IDL
specification, a specification that
describes the procedure prototype and
the data types for the arguments.
And from that it generates the marshal
link and the unmarshal link routines
that are used in the steps to
perform these translations.
These routines are also responsible to
generate the appropriate
encoding related actions.
So exactly how will
an array be represented
when its encoded in a byte stream.
That's an example what will take place
in these auto generated routines and
there are other examples of
what constitutes encoding.
For instance, converting
integers like this value i from
one NDN format another NDN format,
like from big NDN to little
NDN depending on what's required by the
server or by the client for the results.
That's an example of a automated
action that would be incorporated
into the marshal encode.
Once this IDL is compiled and all of
the code is generated that provides
the implementation for the marshal
link and un-marshal link routines,
all the developer needs to
do is to take that code and
just to make sure that it links it.
With the program files for
the server, or
the client codes when
generating executables.