Responsive design.
I know it's fun to resize
your web browser and
see which sites resize gracefully and
which sites remain defiantly large
with gross horizontal scroll bars.
But responsive design is not just for
the web.
Today, the lines between phones and
tablets are disappearing.
So it's important to think about how
your reliable scale in our multi-screen
world.
Don't be overwhelmed.
Just like designing responsive layouts
for the web, build your layouts to be
reasonably flexible for
within a common device size.
Well then you can set break points,
providing alternative layouts for
those various sizes.
Think about it this way,
small phone, large phone,
medium tablet, and large tablet.
FrameLayout, LinearLayout and
ConstraintLayout,
are three of the most common layouts
you'll use when building up your UI.
And these all descent for the view
group class, designed to contained and
give order to child views.
They each of their strengths and you
should always try to use the simplest
layout that will get the job done.
Frame layout is great for simple layouts
when you only have one child view,
like a list view that fills
the entire content area.
If you add multiple items to it,
they overlap.
You can tell it to position other views
relative to itself such as in the upper
right hand corner or
lower left hand corner.
Linear loud is perfect for
stacking views vertically or
horizontally one after another.
It also has powerful features to
breakup the display proportionally.
Constraint layout is powerful, but a bit
more complicated compared to the others.
Throw bunch of views inside
a constraint layout,
then you can figure each view's
position relative to the parent,
the constraint layout, or the sibling
views, tons of possibilities.
We'll explore these layouts in greater
detail when we build more complex
screens.