So the whole photo tourism pipeline
that we actually looked at starts with
a bunch of input photographs.
And actually, what's exciting in this
one is you can actually get those
pictures from, you know, public sources
where people have taken pictures.
And of course this works very well for
well known historic sites and
tourism sites.
Using those pictures we can
actually need to do a little bit
of scene reconstruction.
That is how we can actually
model the environment.
And this actually gets into a whole lot
of stuff called structure for motion and
we'll talk more about that in a bit.
So the goal here is basically
doing scene reconstruction to get
the 3D cloud points that are best
captured from the scene and
also locating the camera positions for
each and every one viewpoint.
So, what we really need to figure out
is the relative camera positions and
the orientations of each camera,
generate a point cloud and
also correspondences
between all of them.
So, so far, we have looked at
information about how we can actually
understand and model relative camera
positions when we do panoramas and
also sparse correspondences.
But we never went towards the whole
world of trying to create a 3D geometry
of the scene in any of the work
that we so far have looked at.
And of course,
a beautiful part of their work was
this interactive explorer mechanism,
if we doing track with the photographs,
annotate and all of that kind of stuff.
I'm not going to talk much about that,
but
we're going to showcase some
examples of this for sure.