Let's talk a bit about planning.
One of the key problems is that these robots have to decide what to do next.
I'll address the planning problem at multiple levels of abstraction.
The easiest happens to be to look at a city level of abstraction.
Suppose we have a road like this over here,
and my car is located down here in the beginning.
I wish to get to this point up here.
Let me draw in an abstraction of the state space,
and discretize the states as shown with these red lines over here.
So you see a maze with lots of discrete states.
I'm going to ask you given that you traversing from grid cell to grid cell costs you 1,
or -1 using the definition of the MDP lecture before.
Suppose the goal state has a value of 100.
What's the value of the start state assuming deterministic actions?