The training phase essentially
consists of extracting features for
each sample in the training set,
and supplying these feature
vectors to the training algorithm,
along with corresponding labels.
The training algorithm
initializes a model, and
then tweaks its parameters using
the feature vectors and labels.
Typically, this involves an iterative
procedure where one or more samples
are presented to the classifier at a
time, which then predicts their labels.
The error between these
predicted labels and
ground-truth is used as a signal
to modify the parameters.
When this error falls below a certain
threshold, or when enough iterations
have passed, you can consider the model
to have been sufficiently trained.
Now, you can verify how it performs
on previously unseen examples
using the test set.
The error on the test set is typically
larger than that on the training set,
which is expected.
Also, both errors typically decrease
the more you train your model.
However, you have to be
careful about one thing.
If you keep training beyond a certain
point, your training error may
keep decreasing, but your test
error will begin to increase again.
This is known as overfitting.
Your model fits the training
data very well, but
is unable to generalize
to unseen examples.
One thing we haven't talked about yet
is the choice of what classifier to use.
That's because it might require some
experimentation to figure out what
classifier works best for
a given problem.
In this case, we're going to start
with support vector machines,
which have been shown to
work with HoG features.
But you're free to choose what
classifier you ultimately use.
It could even be a combination or
ensemble of multiple classifiers.