Let's look at some examples additional
examples of how they've done this.
>> Here's the input video for
another scene played at high speed.
And here's the panoramic video
texture created from the input.
This entire grove of trees
is one dynamic region
Notice the rippling
lake in the background.
The middle portion of
the scene is static.
One frame of this panoramic video
texture contains over 9 million pixels.
The two trees form
a single dynamic region.
Finally, notice the gentle
waving of the trees in the left.
Here is another input video,
played at high speed.
And here is the output.
The entire region of flags,
as well as the highway in
the back is one dynamic region.
The motion of the vehicles on
the highway is visually seamless,
though they often disappear
behind the occluding boat masts.
Here is the input video for
our final scene.
And the final result.
This scene is composed of one
large water region, flags, and
tarps covering some of the boats
that blow in the wind.
In conclusion, we present a method for
creating high-resolution panoramic
video textures of a location.
Panoramic video textures combine
the wide field of view of panoramic
photographs with the infinite
length of video textures.
The result is an immersive
experience of being there.