Now, in addition to doing an and/or search,
sometimes we can solve an abstract hierarchical task network planning problem
without going all the way down to the concrete steps.
Let's talk about how to do that.
Here we have a description of a state space.
The start state is here, and the goal state is outlined in gray here.
We have one abstract action, and we're shown a set of possible states
that can be reached by that abstract action,
if we refine the abstract action, using one concrete action or another.
This is like when we were dealing with belief states
where we would move, because we had a stochastic action,
from one state to several possible other states.
Here we have several possible states that we'll end up with,
not because the actions are stochastic,
but because we haven't decided yet which refinement we're going to use.
This would be a single step that would bring us to this belief state,
and then when we add a second step, we get to this belief state.
Now we can check to see if we can achieve the goal with this two-step plan
just by checking if there is an intersection between the reachable state and the goal state.
In this case, there is.
We know that we've achieved the goal,
and now if we want to find a refinement that actually works,
the way to do it is to search backwards rather than forward.
If we search forward we'd have a large tree of possibilities,
but if we search backwards, we know the intersections here.
What could have brought us to here? Only this refinement.
And what could have brought is to this state? Only this refinement.
That's the plan that is a refinement of this abstract plan that achieves the goal.