In this challenge,
you will create your own API Mashup.
Write a function called findARestaurant
that will take an extreme representation
of a mealType and location.
This function should first
geocode the location and
then pass in the latitude and longitude
coordinates to the Foursquare API.
After that, it should parse the JSON
response, such that it returns the first
restaurant in an easy to read format for
the user.
You will have to explore the Foursquare
documentation a little bit to figure out
a way to retrieve an image of your
restaurant if Foursquare has one.
If no image is available, then provide
a default image for the restaurant.
The image should be sized
to 300 by 300 pixels.
A starter template is provided
in the instructor notes.
I have added the following lines of
code such that non non-ascii characters,
or characters not common
to the English language.
Also render properly in your code.
I also strongly recommend
using the browse parameter
when you send off your
URI to Foursquare.
This will search in a much wider
vicinity than just the latitude
longitude coordinate
you provide the API.
Your code should print
the results to the terminal,
when run from the command line.
And also return a dictionary with the
restaurant's name, address, and images.
This challenge is intended to be tough,
but don't give up.
Use your resources and other students
if you get stuck or have any questions.