Just like Firebase, real time database,
Firebase storage provides a set of
security rules so that you can
authorize access to storage.
Let's consider an example, friendly
chat storage contains photos, and
these photos were only meant to be
sent to other friendly chat users and
not the whole world.
What might happen if anyone can
see all of your photos, and
maybe even change them?
What if you wanted to share a video
of your top secret prac technique for
your award winning recipe for peach
cobbler and you wanted to only share it
with your family but
instead the whole world got to see it?
Users expect that you
will protect their data.
Firebase Storage security gives you
the tools to keep their data safe
as well as limit what kind
of data can be stored.
By now you know why data
security matters so
let's take a look at how fire
based storage rules work.