So making the business car app complete with OCR is a bit out of the scope for
this lesson.
We're going to start with a much simpler introductory exercise.
Ever think that a word should be part of the English language?
For a long time I've been using my own custom spelling of the word dude.
Which relates to an obscure Japanese media reference.
That's my own strange word quirk.
Perhaps you've been chatting with your friends about how udacious your new
content provider will be.
When you're using custom words like this,
you can save them to the user dictionary.
All you need to do is click on the word and then click Add to the dictionary.
For the rest of this lesson,
we'll be working with Android's User Dictionary Provider,
which is a list of your custom words.
At the end we'll have a good example of how to work with a standard Android
content provider to print out some data.
Let's get started.
Your app relates to the User Dictionary a bit like this.
I want to take a look at the data source here.
So, we can think of that User Dictionary data like a table.
There are a couple of columns in this table.
An ID, a word column,
a frequency column, a few other miscellaneous columns over here.
As you can see the word column, we have the words that I typed into the phone.
The frequency column is a number between 1 and 255,
which represents how frequently I used the word.
The more frequently I used the word, the higher the number.
So, 255 would be the most frequent.
So we have all this juicy data in the data source, and
we're going to need to use the content provider to get access to it.
If you haven't done so already, go ahead and
save some words to the user dictionary just like I did.
If you're working on an emulator, you're definitely going to want to save some
words in a default messaging app or email app.
Just type the word and give it a click and you should be able to save it.
In this lesson we're going to make a simple app to read out the entries of
the user dictionary.
The end product will look a bit like this.
When you're ready click Continue for a tutorial on how to start making this app.