All right. Welcome back to computer vision today and the next couple of lessons.
We're going to just a little bit of time on the whole light reflection process
that results in photos essentially hitting our camera or our retina.
The idea this is how the physics of the imaging or
the creation of the light that the imaging is going to make a picture of.
And there's actually a huge amount known about, and, about this area, and
it comes from both, sort of, the material science, where we study the materials,
but the big, motivator has been computer graphics, right?
Computer graphics, the idea is I have some model of of an object and
its surface type and I have some model of the light.
And I'd like to produce an image as if you were actually looking at
the real object.
So to do that, I have to understand how light interacts with these objects.
Now in the old days and when I say, the old days.
I mean, like 20 to 40 years ago.
There was this view that computer vision was
just inverse computer graphics, right?
I mean, computer graphics, you have model of the object and a model of light and
you make a picture.
And computer vision was thought of as well,
given a picture, can you tell me about the light and the object that's there.
And so there was a lot of focus on recovering image prop surface properties and
object properties and light and conditions as it's sort of an inverse problem.
And to do that,
we had to have a lot of understanding of the physics of how images were formed.
Now more recently in computer vision a lot of what we've talked about here,
there's been more of a focus on really the geometry of sort of
where features get located and
that relates to sort of the, the shapes of objects and the relation and
you didn't have to worry quite so much about the precise physics.
And then also a lot was saying,
let's lump all together, the lighting, the shape.
The texture, the imaging, the camera, et cetera.
We just get out pictures and we use machine learning or
recognition techniques for to trying to do labeling.
And we talked and when we will actually be talking about that in the future.
But it is it's still important to understand something about how the physics of
light works with respect to making images.