What we need to do now is figure out how to
turn off or disable the stopRecordingButton.
We know that the stopRecordingButton
is a UIButton. But if we
look at the documentation for UIButton,
it's hard to find anything about
enabling or turning things on and off.
So how do we proceed? Remember that when
you look at the documentation for a
class like UIButton, you should always
check what functions and properties that
class inherits from its parent class.
If you scroll to the bottom of this
documentation, you'll find the
Relationships section, I’ll give you a hint.
You'll find what you're looking for
if you dig into the UIControl class
that the UIButton inherits from.
So try diving into this documentation and see
what you find.