To detect lines in an image,
we first need to find edge pixels.
So let's load an image,
convert it to grayscale, and
find edge pixels using
the Canny Operator.
Let's see what these look like.
Here's the original image.
As you can see, it has some lines in it.
The grayscale version, and edge pixels.
Now we'll apply the Hough
transform method to find lines.
For this we'll use the Hough
function in MATLAB.
Find out more about this function
in the MATLAB documentation.
The equivalent function
in Octave is houghtf.
The first returned value
is the accumulator array.
The second is a vector
of theta values or
angles and third is a vector
of radius values or rho.
Let's see what this looks like.
We pass in the theta and
rho values to properly label each axis.
Rho or distance from origin
is along the y axis.
And the angle, theta, is on the x axis
ranging from minus 90 to plus 90.
Okay, so let's find the peaks
in this accumulator array.
We pass in 100 as the maximum number
of peaks we are interested in.
Note that a similar function called
immaximize needs to be used in octave.
Let's plot these peaks on
the hough accumulator array.
Note that we need to use the theta and
rho values to plot the peaks correctly.
The peaks are marked by small red boxes.
The size of the peaks matrix is 13 by 2.
13 peaks were found.
Each row contains
the location of a peak.
The first column has row values,
or y values.
And the second one has x values.
Using these peaks,
we can find line segments using
the hough lines function in MATLAB.
It looks like 28 line
segments were found.
Each element in line_segs is
a structure where the two end points,
the theta and the rho values.
Let's plot these line segments.
As you can see, most of the longer
line segments have been detected, but
a lot of spurious line
segments also show up.
Okay, so how can we get better results?
Let's take a look at
the edge pixels again.
We notice that there are breaks along
the longer lines in some areas.
There is also this dense grouping of
curves that could throw the Hough
detector off.
To find a set of cleaner, or
more meaningful lines,
we can do multiple things.
For instance, we could increase
the threshold parameter for hough peaks.
To understand what
these parameters mean,
let's look at the documentation for
this function.
So threshold is the minimum
value in the accumulator array
that is the minimum number of pixels
that support a line required for
that line to be counted
as a valid candidate.
Any possible lines with less
pixels will not be considered.
Here we set it to be 0.6 times the
maximum value in the accumulator array,
the default being 0.5 times max.
Neighborhood size defines
the region over which
local maxima will be computed.
Note that this is not
a region in the image.
We are computing local maxima
in the accumulator array, so
the size of the neighborhood is
defined in rho and theta dimensions.
A neighborhood size of five degrees
along the theta dimension means that
a strong line will suppress
other lines that are similar but
slightly off in direction.
Recall that we found 13
peaks in our last attempt.
This time we have only seven peaks.
Let's see where these peaks are.
Looks like we might have
cleaner results after all.
Let's compare this with
the previous accumulator peaks.
We see that a lot of
the previously found peaks in this
dense region are now gone.
The new peaks are clustered
around three major locations.
Okay, what more can we do?
We could play with
the parameters of houghlines.
How about we increase
the fill gap parameter to 50?
This is the maximum number of pixels
allowed between two segments for
them to be counted as one if
they lie along the same line.
To focus on longer lines, let's increase
the minimum length to be 100 pixels.
For a better understanding
of these parameters,
take a look at the documentation for
houghlines.
Okay, let's see what
the new segments look like.
Compared with the previous results,
we see that the false positives
have been mostly removed.
Some of the previously broken
segments have also been joined.
Obviously you can do a better job
by playing with the parameters,
especially here.
So feel free to play with
the huff transform functions.