So you can think of
Logistic Regression as a ninja,
who will look at your data and
cut it in half, based on the labels.
And we can think of a Support Vector
Machine, as a slightly pickier ninja
who will carefully look at
the points on the boundary and
make the cut based on those.
And in the same fashion, we can think of
a Neural Network as a team of ninjas,
who will look at your data and
cut it into regions based on the labels.
And we can think of
the Kernel Trick as another ninja,
who's slightly confused trying to
split some apples and oranges.
Suddenly, she comes
up with a great idea,
the idea consists of
moving the apples up and
the oranges down and then successfully
cutting a line through between them.
Now here's an exercise for you.
How would you solve the XOR problem?
That is,
which of the algorithms we learned
would you use to separate
these four points?
There's more than one solution.
Give it a try.