The problem with everything that I just showed you,
is it would be very difficult to turn it into code.
Why do I mean that?
What I mean is, I've been showing you everything in terms of geometry, right?
I'm like waving my hands, and we've got points, etcetera, whatever.
Computers don't do so
well with, waving hands and, despite what my undergraduates say.
Okay?
What we need to do is we need to go from the geometry, to algebra.
Because believe it or
not, computers are fine for algebra as long as you know what you're doing.
That is, you can convert, algebraic expressions into computations.
In fact, we talked about that earlier.
But, it's very hard to go from geometry to computation.
And the way we're going to do that,
is we're going to take the geometry and then convert that to algebra.
So we're going to start off, today with a pair of calibrated cameras.
Okay, so here's my pair of calibrated cameras.
I have two camera centers, Oc, and Oc prime,
and they're both looking at some world point, X.
And it's viewed in the two images, and it's seen here.
Because these are calibrated cameras,
I'm going to assume that I know the translation T, along the baseline.
It. Sorry T is the vector that is the baseline right so,
if I have to shift you know, two, seven, nine.
To get from one camera to the other in XYZ, that's what my translation would be.
And I also know R, I know the rotation matrix though, you would have to
rotate one camera center to become aligned with the other camera center.
That's what it means to be calibrated.
So we write this, this way, okay?
It says from geometry to algebra, we're not quite there but, but
we're almost there.
But basically what we're saying is,
the location of the point X in the prime frame, can be expressed by
rotating X as appearing in the non prime frame and then translating it by T.
That's just the equations we had before.
I know this is not the homogenous version, it's okay,
in a minute we'll make everything beautiful.