>> Hey Catherine, do you think Tommy likes
our mock-ups? >> I don't know he's being
really quiet.
>> Yeah, he's usually really a tough critic.
>> Yeah, how about I just ask him.
Hey Tommy, do you like our mock-ups? You think
they're user-friendly? I'm gonna take
that snap as a yes.
It comes with that. I'm going to catch up
with the organ and we did some
brainstorming with our designer here at
Udacity, and came up with these mock-ups.
So we'll be making an app that the pet shelter
can use to keep track of their pets.
And we'll walk you through the designs now.
Hey actually, Tommy do you wanna help
take the lead? Alright, so when you open up the
app, you'll see a list of existing pets,
and if a new pet arrives at the shelter,
you can add it by clicking the big red
button on the bottom right corner. So
clicking that button takes us to the
editor activity we can fill out
attributes about a new pet, including its
name breed gender & weight. There will also be
a different version of the interactivity
that will build, which allows us to
update an existing pet. For example, if
Garfield already exists in our database,
and gain a little bit of weight, we can
go ahead and update his weight here.
Styo note that we're starting out with a
minimum viable product that has only a
couple of pet attributes. And we're doing
this so that you can focus on understanding
the key concepts of data storage. Moving
forward, you can imagine extending the
app to support many more data fields
about each pet and even adding photos
for each pet that you insert. In this
course, we will be building this pet app
across four lessons, in Lesson one we'll
focus on what data persistence is all
about, as well as how we can sort text
data in a database. Then, in lesson 2, we'll
begin to add the databases inside an
Android app, and get to start interacting
with it by inserting and reading data
from that database. Next, lesson 3, we'll learn
about something called a content
provider, and learn how to use it to help
us insert and read data from our
database. And lastly, in lesson four, we'll
close out finishing the app by
implementing the UPDATE and DELETE
functionality.