So one of the ways of doing this is of course cross fading
between the two images.
As I go from one side of one image,
let's say from here to there, and on this image I go from here to there.
So this is left image and the right image.
I would basically cross fade this direction on the left image and
this direction for the right image.
So, in that, in essence what that means is, we will cross fade this way here,
and cross fade this way here, and generate a new image.
So to help us do this, let's imagine that now I can create a small ramp.
This ramp has a value of 1 here, and 0 there.
And then the other one, the value of 1 here, and 0 there.
And what I’m interested in really is being able to now go and
take information, all of the information, from this part here, from this image,
but reduce it as a go and traverse down this way.
And similarly, take all of the value from here, and
reduce it as I go down there.
And if you notice, the mixture of these two basically would kind of start having
blended values in the middle all over here starting from the first.
Our first column here and the last column here.
Of course one of the ways of doing this,
if you remember our approaches of trying to do this with simple point
arithmetic, is creating a ramp image like this, all whites, all blacks.
And similarly the transpose of the opposite of this where all white here and
black here, just doing this multiplication plus some operations will
give us an image like this.
Again, notice this is cross-fading.
All of the information for this image is going down to 0.
And this one from 1 to 0 and here of course we see a little bit of blend here.
50/50 is showing up here.
So this is basically a simple technique of cross-fading between two
images along this direction.
This direction for this one, this direction for that one.
And we get a blended image.
On this side, of course, you see more of this image.
And on this side you see more of this image.
Now of course, there is no reason for
us to have just ramps that are linear in this manner.
We could actually also play around with this,
and have them have different types of, of functions perhaps even step
functions to give it more emphasis in one region, less emphasis in the other.
So what does it mean for these two images?
Again the left and right image can generate our target.
But now I want to play around with how I do the blending, or
the cross-fading between those two.
Again, lets look at our ramp functions.
And this time around, I have one, but when I get to this point is when I
actually start giving it less values from this one, basically the opposite here,
up to here, and then all of sudden I can use a step function or a ramp that
starts off a little later to actually do the blending from one to the other.
So, in essence, now what we will see is the entire effect of this blending will
only be restricted to this region of the image or to this region of this image.
So this would be what I would refer to again as the window,
the size of the window where I would actually do the blending.
I don't want to do any here and I don't want to do any here, but
I just want to do it in this small window between these two left and
right images to generate a target.
Of course, in this case,
I could simply create again the simple ramp images to a simple point arithmetic,
between those two, and again, this ramp is basically exactly.
On this profile here, this ramp is based on this profile here.
The output of this one is this image.
Again, if you notice, and look at it carefully here,
that these are the lines where most of the blending is.
This is originally the same image here.
This is originally this image here.
Most of the blending is in this region.
So in essence, we've created now a ramp function or
a cross fade here where the value of blue from here on this side of
the left image is exactly the same, crosses over and becomes 0 here.
And similarly on the other side the green which is representing the right image,
goes up in here, crosses over and
becomes 0, so most of the blending is right there.
We can play around with these types of how big the window size would be.
So the same process, except now my window is much narrower.
So this would be the size of my window that I actually have that I
want to do the cross-fading in.
And again, look at the same examples as previously,
we've just done a ramp with a little bit of change in the middle.
And this one you'll notice, this,
this is exactly what the ground functions look like, black, all zeros here.
Quick jump from 0 with a little bit of gradation and
colors to white and that's what we see here, and that's what we see here.
Doing the same arithmetic, we get this image.
And here you notice, again, most of this image is like this one,
most of this image is like this one.
And here there's a little bit better example of blending.
Now, you can still see a little bit of sharp edges here.
So the question now comes up as, what's the right size of this window?
So one of the things now we need to start looking at is how do
we best determine the size of this window to give us the best results of
doing these cross faded or blended images.