The answer is that you can
eliminate B but not A.
Now there's both an intuitive
way to see this fact,
as well as a formal way to see the fact.
What I'll show you where is
the intuitive argument and
I'll show you the formal
way after the quiz.
The intuitive argument is
based on this picture.
Let's call the two spawns A and B and
lets suppose you keep them both.
In the DAG, A and
B appear here, and here.
Now notice that this picture
has three paths in it.
The three paths are important because
they're all potentially critical paths,
so we need to understand how they grow.
The first path essentially
follows the spine of the DAG.
Now what you should notice,
is that there's actually a constant
number of nodes along the path.
That means it's probably
not our critical path.
The second interesting
path follows the A branch.
Now, what's interesting about this
path is it goes through this subgraph.
And since the subgraph involves
a bunch of recursive calls,
that's where you'll see the growth
in the length of a path.
So this will be an important
path to keep in mind.
Now the third interesting
path follows the B branch.
And notice, just like the A branch,
it goes through a piece of sub graph.
Now, lets consider some
hypothetical scenarios.
Suppose I eliminate the first spawn,
that will change
the structure of the DAG.
So in particular, this edge goes
away and this edge goes away and
a new dependence edge goes from the end
of the sub graph to the next spawn.
This follows from the fact I have to
execute this reduce before proceeding to
statement B.
So, now this DAG really
has two interesting paths.
The first one which
follows the A statement.
The second one goes
through the B Statement.
What I want you to notice
is that both the A path and
the B path overlap substantially.
The overlap occurs here.
That's the part that involves
recursive calls and so
that subgraph could expand and
could be very long.
Now notice that the B
path continues along and
goes through its own recursive subgraph.
The critical observation is that
now with this transformed DAG,
this recursive subcall
happens before this one does.
And so that means there's basically no
concurrency between these two subgraphs.
So basically what this says is if
you eliminate the first spawn,
you've eliminated the concurrency.
So eliminating the first
spawn is a bad idea.
What about eliminating the second spawn?
Let's do the same exercise and
transform the DAG.
Now let's follow the two paths.
Now notice that even if you eliminate
the second spawn that is the spawn
associated with statement B, these two
subgraphs can be executed concurrently.
So this is saying that if you
eliminate the second spawn,
you won't materially change
the span of the graph.
So eliminating the second spawn is okay.