Still don't think keyboard
shortcuts are a big deal?
Let's put them to the test.
For this quiz you'll be competing
against yourself in a timed challenge,
to see how fast you can type with and
without keyboard shortcuts.
In the notes below,
I've provided you with two files.
The first file is called start.html, and
the second file is called finish.html.
I want you to download both files and
place them side by side in
the text editor, like so.
If your screen is not big enough,
print out finish.html and
open start.html in your text editor.
Next, using only your keyboard and
no shortcuts,
try fixing the start.html file
to match the finish.html file.
Make sure to time yourself and
see how long it takes.
Then I want you to repeat
the same exercise but
this time, use keyboard shortcuts.
I think you get where I'm going with
this, but your time should get better.
Since this is a timed challenge,
you'll need to have a stopwatch.
If you have a smartphone, it should
come with a stopwatch feature, but
if not, just use Google stopwatch.
There's a link in the notes below.
Feel free to complete the challenge
as many as times as you'd like to
improve your time.
Remember, only use your keyboard.
And don't just copy and
paste the code from the second file,
that'd be cheating.
When you're done, click continue
to quiz to enter your best times,
with and without shortcuts.
Have fun.