If all this sounds exciting to you,
you're in the right place.
This nano degree program is organized
into two parts, starting with this term.
>> Here in term one, we'll cover
the fundamental principles of AI,
search optimization, logic,
planning, probability, and so on.
No matter where you go in AI,
these form your vocabulary, and
foundation in artificial intelligence.
>> We've previewed many of
these ideas in this lesson.
And throughout term one,
we'll get into them in far more depth.
>> Throughout the term, you'll watch
lectures taught by some of the world's
foremost authorities in the field,
like Peter Norvig, Sebastian Thrun, and
Thad Starner.
We'll also check in with
other authorities, and
hear how AI is used to solve current,
real world problems.
>> Supplemental readings will be
assigned throughout the lessons
from this book, Artificial Intelligence,
A Modern Approach, Third Edition.
Written by Stuart Russell and
Peter Norvig, it is the most popular
textbook in AI, and highly recommended.
>> Then in term two, you'll be able to
choose an area of concentration for
further in depth study, such as computer
vision, natural language processing, or
speech recognition.
>> Created by experts from academia and
industry, these courses will teach
you additional techniques, and
practical aspects of designing
intelligent systems.
Here you will build a capstone project
that addresses a challenging problem
from that domain.
>> We can't wait to see what you build.