The second way how clouds
are commonly differentiated is based
on the service model they provide.
Here's a great image that depicted
the differences between the different
service models.
Without the use of cloud computing,
you run your application on premise, and
that means you have to take care of all
of these different layers yourself.
You manage them personally.
The applications, the data, the runtime,
middleware, O/S, so different
components of the software stack
including the virtualization technology.
And then the lower level, all of
the components of the hardware stack.
In the other extreme, you can use cloud
computing services and then directly
leverage the fact that cloud computing
can provide you with an application.
So this is a model called
software as a service.
And this resembles
what Gmail offers you.
You don't have to run your mail server,
install quotas,
manage security patches, etc., for
the employees in your company.
You can just force them to
use Gmail and, in fact,
can just contract Gmail to run
the email services for your company.
In the case of Gmail, everything
is run by Google in this case.
It's their hardware, it's their
software stack, system software.
They own and manage the data,
they run the application, configure it.
Update it, upgrade it and
everything else that's necessary.
So this is the software as a service,
or SaaS model.
A second model is where the cloud
service can provide you certain APIs
that you can access to develop
particular types of applications.
The cloud service provides
a development or execution environment.
And that includes the operating system,
various libraries, various tools that
are necessary for the applications
that need to run in that environment.
One example is the Google App Engine and
this is called platform as
a service offering, or PaaS.
In the case of the Google App Engine,
the platform as a service offering
is that it offers everything that's
necessary to develop applications for
Android platforms, for instance.
Windows Azure was originally purely
intended as a pass offering for
developing and running .NET
applications, and more recently
another type of extension was added to
the Windows Azure portfolio services.
Finally at the lowest level, clouds
can provide infrastructure instances,
like compute instances that consist of
the CPUs, or rather virtual CPUs with
accompanying memory, or
storage, or the necessary
network resource in order to form
a cluster of such compute instances.
Amazon's compute cloud is an example
of such an infrastructure as service
cloud computing model.
This can also include other types of
hardware resources, like GPUs, so
you can rent from Amazon
instances with GPUs for instance.
Again know that these types of clouds
don't really provide you with
the physical resources directly.
Instead, the resources are virtualized.
And so it may turn out that you
are using independently some subset of
the physical resources
available in that cloud system.
But it's quite possible and
likely that you're sharing
the resources with other tenants.
An exception to this is that,
in particular of the case of Amazon,
they do provide some high
performance instances.
So if you're renting through Amazon,
a cluster of VMs or
virtual cluster or virtual high
performance instance, you will in fact
end up at a virtual machine that runs
independently on physical hardware.
The same thing happens
when it comes to the GPUs.
Your GPUs won't be shared in this case.
But that's just because of some
technical challenges in terms of how to
get sufficient performance level
in a virtualized environment for
these high performance instances or GPU
enabled instances that Amazon provides.