As you're hopefully coming to realize,
everything starts with a route, so
the first step is to
create the bricks route.
According to Ember's documentation,
we need to pass an object with a path
property as the second
argument to the route.
This path property is what
the URL will match against.
This is what needs to be Legos,
not this.
So the Legos path uses the bricks
route file and the bricks template.
In the bricks template I've added
the required HTML and I'm done.
Making Ember load a template that's
named differently from the URL
is straightforward but has always
seemed a little backwards to me.
Make sure you don't get tripped up
between the order of the two of these.
The first are the route file and
template that will be used,
while the second is what
the URL will match against.