The Wagon Pool app falls
responsive design principles, so
the app fits on different devices.
The app also has a simple
user interface so
that all the features are intuitive and
easy to use.
But Wagon Pool app doesn't
connect with an external server,
the only data that is
used is the user's input.
And finally this app doesn't
utilize any mobile device hardware.
It doesn't connect with a camera or
a microphone,
because there's no need for it.
It's a simple calculator.
Depending on the type of app you need
to create, you may end up using some or
all of these elements.
Let's read a little bit more about the
different types of mobile programming.