So Travis, it appears in the My Favorite
Movies app, we'll need to use a sessions
ID in order to add and
remove movies from our Favorites List.
Can you tell us a little
bit about how this is done?
>> Yeah, sure.
So basically, you know,
to get a lot of the account
features available on the API, so
letting an account create a movie, add
them and remove them to your watch list,
create custom lists, etcetera you
need to get a TBB user account.
So, once you have an account
on the website you're
able to go through a off flow
on the API that lets you [COUGH]
create a session that let' you do
these account features via the API.
>> Cool.
Sounds like sessions
are definitely the place to start.
In this lesson, as we build My Favorite
movies, we're going to learn how to use
the first of two off flows that the
movie database makes available to us.
Then in the next lesson,
we'll switch up the flow so
you'll get exposure to both forms.