The first one, known-Plaintext attacks.
The answer is d.
In this attack, a specific known
plaintext is compared to its ciphertext.
Second, chosen-Plaintext attacks.
The answer is c.
In this attack method, the attacker
can choose randomly some plaintext and
obtain the corresponding ciphertext.
Third, differential cryptanalysis.
The answer is b.
In this attack, the attacker
controls a changes of the input,
meaning the input plaintext.
And then observe the changes of the
output, meaning the output ciphertext.
Four, linear cryptanalysis.
The answer is a.
In this attack method, the attacker
models the relationship between
plaintext, ciphertext, and
the key, using linear equations.
And then he uses the known ciphertext,
plaintext pair to derive the key bits.