So this quiz is about how common
are these vulnerabilities, or
how many vulnerabilities are known.
So remember that vulnerabilities
we don't know about.
Okay we come to know about them
only after we are exploited.
And those are called
zero day vulnerabilities.
We had no time to fix them or
patch them before they got exploited.
But known vulnerabilities,
you patch your systems to make
them go away in things like that.
So we're talking about what systems
actually have known vulnerabilities.
So the data about this is maintain this
National Vulnerability Database or
NVD, so you will need to access
that to answer this quiz.
And it has lot of Information about
vulnerabilities that are numbered
through what is called CVEs and
it tells you what system nature of
the vulnerability what can happen and
things like that.
But here rather than go into those kind
of details we're just talking about
how many of these are there.
So take a few minutes to think about
these questions and take answers and
then we'll come back and
discuss what the correct answers are.