You could say, well, instead of using small windows, use a slightly bigger
window, so this is question of, how should we pick the window size, and just
like when we were talking about scale, there's not going to be any easy answer.
Here's an example of another stereo pair, I'm only showing you the left.
So if I do a sliding window stereo, well, for a small window size,
well I, I get the branches pretty well, of the tree, but you'll notice
there is all this I think the technical word is crap, all over everywhere else.
That is you know, this is a disparity image, and, and my ground should be
going from near to far, and there shouldn't be all this junk all over it.
So what do I do?
Well obviously, because of noise and
things, I need to make my window bigger to get a more robust match.
So if I make my window bigger, I get this nice ground pattern here, right,
you can see that it goes from near to far, okay, and
the trees back here are farther away.
But notice what happens to the tree branches there.
Okay?
The window is too big, and when you put it over a branch,
it gets both the branch and the background, it doesn't know what to do.
Just as I said earlier in this course, scale is always an issue,
there's no magic answer.