In our introductory lecture on threads and concurrency, we talked about the fact
that threads can be implemented at the kernel level, at the user level, or both.
In this lesson we will re-visit that statement and see what it is that is
necessary in terms of data structures and mechanisms from the operating system.
In order for
us to be able to implement threads at both the kernel and the user level.
During this discussion,
we will also look at two notification mechanisms that are supported by OSs.
And that includes interrupts and signals.
To make the discussion in this lecture more concrete,
we will use two older papers,
the Eykholt paper Beyond Multiprocessing: Multithreading the Sun OS Kernel and
the Stein and Shah paper on implementing lightweight threads.
These are older papers, but they provide us with some historic information on
how threading systems evolved over time.
There are links to both of these papers in the Instructor's Notes.
We will end this lecture with a brief summary of the current threading model in
the Linux operating system.