So you want to help us
through what this could be?
>> Yeah so I think I know the answer
because I think I know how to get the
answer because I think it's like other
times we've done this sort of trick.
And the key part is noticing
that we are adding and
then subtracting off
the things that we just added.
And then adding the thing we just got
and then subtracting that off and so
every time we go through
a state action reward,
state action reward, we're going to
end up adding a potential and
then subtracting the same
potential on the next step.
>> So
here's a useful way to visualize that.
So we're going to go through some
sequence of states, S, S prime,
S double prime, S triple prime,S
quadruple prime, and so on.
And in this Q version of the Q function,
we're getting the sum of the rewards for
those states.
So we have like a reward
that happens here, and
a reward that happens here and
a reward that happens here, but
these are going to be discounted and
summed up to get our Q.
And now we're wondering well what
happens if we replace this R with this
new R prime.
It still has R in it but now it's
going to have this take away psi,
give me some gamma psi prime.
>> Give me some psi, give me some psi.
Yeah exactly.
High, low, on the side.
All right.
So, this first reward in addition to the
R part we're also going to get the minus
side and the plus gamma side, so
let's just add that in here for
the transition from S to S prime, but
we'll also have to add it in there for
the transition from S
prime to S double prime.
So, the second reward Is gamma
times whatever that reward is,
which is what it used to be,
minus the psi S prime plus the gamma psi
S double prime, and so on for
each of these rewards,
is going to get replaced by what it was
plus the discounted psi minus the psi.
>> Right.
So if we look at that, so good, so
writing that down
confirmed my thought so.
First thing you notice is that things
start cancelling each other out.
>> Right.
So in particular this
gamma psi S prime and
this gamma times negative
psi S prime disappear.
>> Right and
then that's going to happen again.
>> It's going to happen
again on the double prime.
Right.
[SOUND] [SOUND] And
the triple prime [SOUND] [SOUND],
and the quadruple prime, [SOUND].
And so forth, and then all we're
going to be left with are the R's
themselves, which we are writing as Q.
And this weird little extra-
psi(s) in the very beginning.
>> Right, so
then I think that we can write
Q'(s,a) = Q(s,a)-Psi(s).
>> Nice.
>> And there's only one little
bit of bookkeeping we have to
argue our way out of.
And that's the fact that we are getting
rid of everything in the middle
except the things at the beginning and
the things at the very end,
the thing at the very, very end.
>> Right, so there's some
kind of gamma to the infinity
psi of S infinity kind
of thing at the end.
>> Right.
But, if gamma's less than one,
then something less than one
to the infinity is just 0.
>> Right, as long as our psi guess
is bounded, which we didn't say,
but it's true.
>> It better be bounded, so then it's 0,
so we can ignore it [SOUND].
And that's cool,
because that's what always happens
whenever you have a telescoping sum.
>> Yes.
Even though this was
an infinite telescoping sum.
Very cool.
Does this make some intuitive
sense at the end of the day?
Are New Q function is just like our
old Q function except it shifted
downward by psi s.
Like this downward kind of
bothers me a little bit.
>> Well, it's bothering me too, but
actually I think it
doesn't bother me now.
So what your saying is the true value of
being in a state and taking an action is
actually whatever the value is minus
the potential you're going to lose.
Because you need to account for
everything.
You need to account for not just the
reward you get for being in a state and
all the discounted reward you're
going to get thereafter, but for
any potential that you're
going to lose along the way.
So psi is that potential that you're
going to lose by leaving this state.
So Q basically captures what you're
getting for being in a state and
then what you're going to
get from that point on.
Right?
Assuming you behave in a particular way.
Well what's going to
happen from this point on?
Well you're going to get the reward
that you got in the state, like before.
But then you're going to lose
whatever magic psi we gave you for
entering into the state.
So we have to account for not just
the present, but also the future.
>> Right.
>> So the future requires getting rid of
the potential, so I think that's fine.
It kind of makes sense to me,
I kind of wish it weren't that way but
it does makes sense if
the reward is actually,
you're going to get a little
bit of extra bump in bonus.
Another way of thinking about
it is you got R' (s,a,s')
= R(s,s)- psi(s) + gamma psi(S').
Well if you were to write
down what R'(s,a) was,
it would just be R(s,a)- psi(S) if
you were to ignore the S prime part.
because the S prime part only
matters with the discounted future.
So then Q prime is just
the rewards that you would get,
minus the potential that
you're about to lose.
So I think it works out just fine.
It makes
>> I guess so.
I guess I just wondered,
why wouldn't it be plus?
[LAUGH] Why wouldn't it be
the case that the Q value for
being in a state is what it used to be?
But we got this extra bonus for
having gotten to s in the first place.
>> Because we're
going to lose the bonus.
We're going to lose the bonus,
and so we have to pre-lose it?
>> Well I don't think you're
really pre-losing it.
I mean what's really kind of
happening I think is that you've
kind of got a new R of s of a.
And that R is including the psi, and so
you've gotta subtract it off to
get back the original R you had.
>> All right, so let's just,
just to be certain that we're
comfortable with this, maybe we should
do the algebra to make sure that
this all really does balance out.