Finally, and this is the half bit that I was telling you about,
there's an alternative way of doing calibration, which is pretty cool.
And in fact, it's really what everybody is using today,
because typically you don't have all these points.
And it's a way of getting the intrinsics, and
then if you know where you put these checker boards it's extrinsics.
Basically what you do is you take a checker board and you move it around.
And you can end up calibrating the camera, with respect to that checkerboard.
The reason everybody uses that, these days, is that there's.
First of all, you can print out a checkerboard and it the checkerboard has to be
on a plane, well that's easy you print out a checkerboard.
You gotta make sure your printer doesn't screw things up,
you gotta make sure that it actually comes out that squares are squares.
You mount it on something that's a nice piece of rigid cardboard or foam core.
And you don't have to know the positions and
orientations in order to get the intrinsics of the camera.
And later you can get the intrinsics as well.
And why does everybody use this?
Because the code is easily available online.
OpenCV supports this directly.
We list here a MATLAB version of it.
If you go to Zhengyou Zhang's web site, he's like doctor calibration.
He did spectacular work for us, thesis etc, in calibration.
I'll also tell you that there's something cool you can do, and
in fact, the a student of mine, Kelsey Hawkins did this.
And I, I think the code is made publicly available.
If you take a checkerboard and you mount it on the end of a robot arm.
And remember, a robot knows where its arm is in terms of its coordinate system.
If you also know let's say the offset of that checkerboard from the the end
effector, the hand.
Then what you can do is with a camera you can just move that
checkerboard around using the robot, and of course we know the 3D
location of the checkerboard at every point in time that we take an image.
And so, by taking those images of the checkerboard,
you end up calibrating the camera to the robot's coordinate system.
So, it's a cool use of doing this directly within robotics.