For the first option,
distributing memory between processes, that's an arbitration.
This is something an operating system does as a result of its effort to
manage the memory and determine how multiple processes will share.
The second option,
supporting different types of speakers, that's an abstraction.
It is because the operating system provides abstractions such as
this one that you can plug in one set of speakers, and
if they don't work, exchange them with something else.
In some cases, drivers are required, which enables an operating system to
control the hardware device without knowing details about that
specific hardware, so the device driver will have the knowledge of
the specific actual hardware element, like the specific speaker.
And along similar lines, the ability to interchangeably access different
types of storage devices like hard disks or
SSDs is again an example of an abstraction just like the example above.
Again, because of the use of the storage abstraction that operating systems
support, they can underneath feel the different types of devices and
hide that from the applications.