Recall the length eight
bitonic splitting network.
Given an input sequence that's bitonic,
it computes two bitonic subsequences.
Notice that the elements of the first
subsequence are all less than or
equal to the elements of
the second subsequence.
Now you could view this circuit as
a DAG of independent comparators.
Here are the nodes.
Here's the corresponding DAG.
Now from this observation, you can write
down a very natural parallel scheme.
Your scheme takes an input sequence
of length n, and for simplicity,
let's suppose that n is even.
You then iterate over
all pairs in parallel.
For each pair,
you determine the min and the max and
you override the corresponding
elements of the output.
Easy.
There is one subtle point.
In the work-span model, the fix size
circuit has a constant depth or span.
But remember that for general and
our convention was to assume logarithmic
span for things like parallel for loops.