Alright, here I am in
the downloads section.
So I'll click on this madlibs_generator
link, which will open up a new tab and
I'll highlight all this text right here,
by scrolling or I can also do command a.
Now I'll open up Sublime or
your text editor that you choose.
Now I'll paste it all in by doing
command v, or I can also right click and
hit paste.
Now you can see all this raw
text in the Sublime window.
And so what I want to do is
I want to save this now so
I'll go to file, save,
I'll type in madlibs.py.
All right, so now I'm going to
save this on the desk top, and
it's important to use
this .py extension,
because it tells the computer that this
is a python file that we want to run.
Okay.
So
I'll save this onto
the desktop by clicking save.
And now all this highlighting comes up,
so
we know this file is
saved as a Python file.
So now that we have our Python
file saved on our desktop,
let's run it locally.
To do that, I’m going to open up my
terminal which I’ll do by going to,
click on the terminal.
Since my madlibs file is on my desktop,
I’m just going to type in
cd Desktop to find it.
Now that I'm in my desktop,
I'll type LS,
which means list all the current files
inside this folder, which is desktop.
And there we have our mad_libs.py file,
so
to run it, all I have to do is type
Python and the name of the file.
So I'll do python mad_libs.py,
there we go.
We now have our mad libs generator
running on our local machine.
So let me play a quick round so,
an adjective, let's try blue.
Run, occupation, let's do teacher,
verb skateboard.
Place, San Francisco.
There we go, what a blue day.
I can run the day off
from being a teacher, and
go skateboard in San Francisco.