In this lesson, we'll be looking
at some components we haven't yet
used in Unity, and
using scripting to customize them.
&gt;&gt; Right, and specifically we're
going to be looking at the physics
systems and the audio system.
&gt;&gt; So with physics what we'll be
able to do is stimulate real forces.
So for example we can have gravity,
or pull and push objects.
&gt;&gt; And with the audio system,
we'll be handling 3D positional audio,
which is really important for
virtual reality because you need to
direct the attention of your viewer.
And you don't necessarily know where
they're looking at any given moment, so
you can't use visual cues.
If they're looking over here and
you want them to look over there,
you can only use sound to
draw their attention and
so, this is a really powerful system.
&gt;&gt; So yeah, by the end of this lesson,
we'll be able to use both these engines
to really make our projects feel and
sound great.
&gt;&gt; And it's excellent scripting
practice, so let's get started.