A good exercise for understanding the perils of deadlock
Its the famous Dining Philosophers Problem originally posed by Dijkstra.
There are five philosophers setting around the table. Plato,
Aristotle, Rousseau, Nietzsche, and Allen Bloom would be my choice.
And being philosophers, they like to think. But they
also have to eat every now and again. Each philosopher
gets his own rice bowl. But there are only
five chopsticks. One made between each pair of neighboring philosophers.
For permission to eat, a philosopher has to pick up the
chopsticks on either side of him. For permission to think, he
places the chopsticks back in their place for his neighbors to
use. The main loop for a thread representing a philosopher therefore,
looks like this. Your task is going to be to implement the
pickup chopsticks and put down chopsticks method by filling the code
in where indicated in the template that I'll give you. The
output should read like the directions for a play where the
action involves philosophers thinking, picking up chopsticks, eating, and
putting them down. The directions for the play must be
valid. That is, a philospher can only pick up a
chopstick that's next to him and he can only put
one down if he already has it. So equally important
is that no philosopher should be starved. A particularly bad
situation is deadlock, where all five philosophers pick up the
chopsticks to the left. So Rousseau might grab this one,
Nietzsche this one, Allen Bloom this one, Plato this
one, and Aristotle this one. And then, they would wait
for the one to their right to be set
down, so that they could pick it up. Of course
this chopsticks will never be put down because another
philosopher is holding it waiting for the one to his
right to be picked up. In this deadlock situation the
philosophers starve. Take care that your program avoids this problem.