There are a few different
ways to complete this one,
how did you do it Jay?
>> Well as the easy way, and
there's the scalable way,
we're going to look at both.
>> Here's the easy way.
I change the theme c.s.s
to the green theme.
Then I bump the version number of
the static cache in the service worker.
Then I use the activate event to remove
the v one cache, the old cache cache.
Now I can refresh the page and
in DevTools, I see this new
version install, and wait.
If I look at caches in DevTools,
I can see v1 and v2,
which is what we want right now.
If i navigate away,
the new service worker activates.
So if i click back
the theme has changed.
As I said that's the easy solution.
But it's perfectly good in this case.
If it's what you did, you got it right.
But what about when we
get to version twenty?
We can't just remove version
19 in the activate event.
Because the user might be updating from
an older version, maybe 18, maybe 17.
Calling delete on every old cache
name is going to be a bit messy.
And that code's only keep getting
bigger and bigger over time.
Instead, I'm going to maintain a safe
list of cache names I want to keep and
remove the others.
To do that I'm going to store the name
of the static cache in a variable.
Then in the activate event, I'm going to
get all of the cache names that exist.
I'm going to fill up
that list of cache names.
I'm only interested in the cache
name begins with wizard dash.
But isn't the name of a static cache.
That gives me a list of wizard
caches that I don't need anymore.
So, I'm going to map those to promises
returned by caches dot delete.
Then I'm going to wrap all
of that in promise dot all.
So we wait on the completion
of all of those promises.
Checking the cache starts with with
wizard dash means we don't delete caches
from other apps that might be
running on the same origin, for
example some other static v1.
That isn't really necessary
here as we only have
one service worker on the origin.
But on sites like GitHub pages you
might have many service workers sharing
the same origin.
When updating the cache remember that
the requests are going via the standard
browser cache.
So if one of these resources
had a cache time of say a year,
the update would just be
fetched from the HTTP cache.
So you wouldn't get
any changes you made.
In the development server, all the
resources are set to have a cache age
of zero as in they don't cache.
In production, I strongly recommend
having versioning as part of your
resource names Like this.
Where the version number is generated
from the content of the file.
Then you can give these resources
a cache time of a year or more.
So if you update your CSS,
a build script could automatically
update your service worker,
changing the URL to this the CSS.
Your cash version number could also be
all generated based on the things that
caches.
Versioning resources like this and
giving them a long cache time isn't
advice specific to service workers.
It's just general good caching practice.
You can work around not to call
caching with service worker.
You pack pretty much anything.
But things are so much easier if
you work alongside good caching.
For example, in this model if i
update my CSS the CSS URL changes,
therefore cache name changes.
Now when the browser fetches all these,
it can get everything but
the CSS from the browser cache because.
They haven't changed.
The only thing that special
the network is the new CSS.
Okay, I think we can say we've
successfully delivered unobtrusive
updates.
Next we'll look at making sure the user
gets these updates quickly and
painlessly.