A tricky issue when it comes
to RPC's is the use of
pointers as arguments to procedures.
In regular procedures it makes perfect
sense to have procedures like this foo
that takes two arguments,
an integer, and
the second argument is a pointer to
an integer or even an integer array.
When this procedure is called.
The second argument,
is a pointer to some address,
in the address base of
the calling process,
where the particular,
the area about this argument is stored.
However, in RPC, passing a pointer
to the remote server makes no sense.
Since this pointer points to some
location in the caller address space,
the server cannot possibly get to
the contents that are stored at this
particular address.
To solve this problem, RPC systems
can make one of two decisions.
The first decision is not to allow for
pointers to be use this
argument of any procedure that
an RPC procedure that will be exported
and can be called in remotely.
The second solution is to
allow pointers to be used but
in the RPC run time to ensure that
the marshalling code that gets generated
understands the fact that
the argument is a pointer.
And that,
instead of just taking that argument and
copying it into the send buffer,
that it actually serializes the pointer.
What that means that it
will copy the reference,
the pointed to data structure,.
Into the data buffer into
one serial representation.
On the server side,
the RPC runtime will first have to
unpack all the data to create
the same data structure.
Then it will record the address to this
data structure and that is the value
that's the pointer that it will use as
an argument when it makes the call to
the actual local implementation
of this particular operation.