Now that we've described the shared
memory mechanisms in a general way,
let's look at the specific details
of the system five Unix API.
First the operating system supports
segments of shared memory,
that don't necessarily have to
correspond to contiguous physical pages.
Also, the operating system treats
shared memory as a system-wide
resource using system-wide policies.
That means that there is a limit on the
total number of segments of the total
size of the shared memory.
Presently, that's not so
much of an issue as, for
instance, currently in Linux,
that limit is 4,000 segments.
However, in the past it used to
be much less and in certain OSs,
it was as few as six segments.
More recent versions of Linux
had a limit of 128 segments.
The operating system may also impose
other limits as far as the system wide
shared memory.
When a process requests that
a shared memory segment is created,
the operating system allocates
the required amount of physical memory,
provided that certain limits are met.
And then it assigns to it, a unique key.
This key is used to uniquely identify
the segment within the operating system.
Any other process can refer to this
particular segment, using this key.
If the creating process wants to
communicate with other processes using
shared memory, then it will make sure
that they learn this key in some way.
By using either some other form of IPC,
or just by passing it through a file,
or as a command line argument,
or maybe other options.
Using the key, the shared memory
segment can be attached by a process.
This means that the operating system
establishes valid mappings between
the virtual addresses, that are part of
that process virtual address space, and
the physical memory
that backs the segment.
Multiple processes can attach to the
same shared memory segment, and in this
manner, each process ends up sharing
access to the same physical pages.
Reads and writes to these pages will be
visible across the processes just like
when threads share.
Access to memory that's part
of the same address space.
And also,
the shared memory segment can be mapped
to different virtual address
in different processes.
Detaching a segment means invalidating
the address mappings for the virtual
address region that corresponded to
that segment within the process.
In other words the page
table entries for
those virtual addresses
will no longer be valid.
However, a segment isn't really
destroyed once it's detached.
In fact, a segment maybe attached and
detached then reattached multiple times
by different processes
during it's life time.
What this means is that once a segment
is created it's like a persistent
entity until there is an explicit
request for it to be destroyed.
This is similar to what
would happen to a file.
We create a file and then the file
persists until it is explicitly deleted.
In the mean time, we can open it and
close it and read it and write it, but
the file will still be there.
This property of shared memory,
to be removed only when it's explicitly
deleted or when there is a system
reboot, makes it very different
than regular non-shared memory,
that is Malloced and then it will
disappear as soon as the process exits.