Let's suppose that when I list the current directory,
I see the following - a directory dir, owned
by me with these permissions and a file foo.txt
owned by some other user with these permissions. And
if I look inside this dir. director, I see
that there's a file bar, owned by me, and
having these permissions. Notice that I used the super
user privileges to list the files in this directory.
Access to this metadata requires passing through the
directory in a way that is only allowed if
we have execute permissions on. So my question to
you is, which of the follwing Unix commands will
result in a permissions error. Cat I should
say is just reading the file and printing it
to a standard app. And touch is trying to
create a new, empty file. Check all that apply.