Hopefully you successfully
created your tracker config file.
It should be in the XML
folder in the RES folder.
A little hard to see, but
this is RES/XML, and this is the file,
this track_app.xml.
And again, you could have called your
config file whatever you wanted.
So here's my tracking ID
in the ga_trackingId.
Here's where I set autoActivity to true.
So I'll get the usage data any time
a user goes to any activities in my app.
And here are the different
screen names that I've set.
I've got the Main Screen,
the Order Dinner screen,
the Eradicate Dinner screen.
And these are names that were going to
appear in the Analytics dashboard.