We've just completed the lesson
randomized design experiments.
Let's review what we've
covered in this lesson.
First, we provided an overview
of randomized design.
Second, we discussed
the selection of variables for
the experiment, and then we covered
the design and setup of the experiment.
Using the data that was gathered in
the experiment, we prepared the data for
analysis, and
then performed the analysis.
And lastly, we discussed
the meaning of the analysis, and
created a sample presentation for
communicating the results.
Even though this was a shorter lesson,
we covered a lot.
You're now able to set up
randomized experiments, and
analyze the results to
determine business impact.
We're now ready to move on to
matched pair design experiments.