I've mentioned before, there are two ways
to add constraints to our Record button.
This is just another way to show you how
to accomplish the same AutoLayout task.
And you're not required to do this step.
First I’m going to delete the two
constraints on our button by selecting
them and pressing the Delete key.
Then with the Record button selected in the
document outline, I’m going to hold down
the control key and click drag to the View.
so I click and I'm holding down the
control key and I can drag my mouse
around and I want to drag from the
Record button to the View and then
let go.
This shows me a dialogue that allows me
to select for different options for
setting constraints. If I hold down the
shift key I can select multiple of these options.
So I'll hold down shift and I’m
going to select Center Horizontally in Container
and Center Vertically in Container.
And then we'll Add Constraints.
This adds the exact same constraints we
did earlier with the align button. Now I
know this may seem like a bit of work to
just start understanding AutoLayout and
to get our button to be in the center of
the screen. But as the saying goes, you
have to learn to crawl before you can walk.
Next we're going to wire up the
button to our code in the
ViewController.swift file and make the
Record button actually do something.