We've said multiple times,
that services are great for
long running background tasks.
There's one fact though that
confuses a lot of developers.
All Android core components
start on the main thread.
This means that Activities, Content
Providers, Broadcast Receivers, and
yes even Services, start their life
on the main application thread.
To be clearer, this based service
class that I'm showing you here,
is started on the main thread.
And it will block your UI if
you run a long running task.
To get around this, you'll need
to create a background thread, or
AsyncTask, from within your service.
So what's the general
process behind this?
How do you do this?
>From a high level, services like
activities, have a lifecycle.
Their lifecycle is different
from an activity's, though.
For a simple started service,
the service is created when a context,
such as an activity, calls startService,
passing in an intent.
This is very similar to how you
start an activity using an intent
using startActivity.
What this does is trigger
the service's onCreate method.
Just as with an activity,
onCreate is responsible for any setup.
After that, onStartCommand is called.
And inside the onStartCommand method
is where you should actually do
whatever it is that your service does.
When your service is done,
you can signal this by calling stopSelf.
Note that you, as the developer,
are usually the one who will
be calling this method.
Note that if you're using just
the service class, you, as a developer,
will need to call this method.
Calling stopSelf will then
trigger onDestroy and
the service will be destroyed.
So if you're using a service class,
you can create an AsyncTask or
thread in onStartCommand.
And then inside the AsyncTask or
thread, you can run your code.
Now running time consuming tasks from
a service in a background thread
is a fairly common thing to do.
So the Android framework actually
contains a helpful subclass of service
called IntentService.
Let's take a look at IntentService next