Now it's time to start working on
the Conference Central application.
Hopefully you've already cloned or
downloaded the code from our repository
but if not just follow the link in
the instructor notes and do so now.
We provide starting code for
each lesson.
You can start with the code for
this lesson and
keep working on it throughout the
course, or, at any point, if you need,
you can download the starting code for
the lesson that you're in.
You might want to do that, for example,
if you don't finish all the coding
exercises for a previous lesson.
As you can see the project layout is
similar to the hello endpoints project.
There are some more static files for
the front end however and the backend
is split up into several files.
Settings.py for the project specific
configuration to web client idea.
Models.py for the ndb model, and
protorpc message definitions.
Conference.py for the main application
logic, and app.yaml provides
the application settings,
same as in the hello endpoints app.