For show restaurants,
I'm only going to differentiate
whether a user is logged in or
not logged in, since the only option on
this page is to create a new restaurant.
So, using the same logic to see if
there is a username value inside
the login session,
I'll render one template or the other.
For the show menu item,
it's a little bit more complex,
since now I need to protect each menu,
based on whoever created it.
So if the user isn't logged in, or
isn't the original creator,
let's render the public menu.
Otherwise they are logged in and
are the creator.
So we can go ahead and
render the original menu.html.
I also added alert messages to
protect my create, edit and
delete functions, just in case the user
tries to visit a url that they
aren't authorized to access.
All of my code additions can be
found in the instructor notes.