If you browse the kthread.H header file,
you will see in line 66 that there is a structure ktread_worker.
This data structure, as well as the various functions that are defined in
this file, provide a simple interface for creating and stopping kernel threads.
You can see that within the kthread_worker data structure,
there are four members.
The stem lock data structure is definitely not the one that's used to describe
a process, nor is the list head that points to a list of kthread_workers.
If you click on the next one, task_struct, you will see that
it's a holding place for tons of important information regarding a process.
So our answer now is at task_struct.