And the answer is both of them are false.
We already saw that conditional independence, as shown over here,
doesn't give us absolute independence.
So, for example, this is test #1 and test #2.
You might or might not have cancer.
Our first test gives us information about whether you have cancer or not.
As a result, we've changed our prior probability
for the second test to come in positive.
That means that conditional independence does not imply absolute independence,
which means this assumption here falls,
and it also turns out that if you have absolute independence,
things might not be conditionally independent for reasons that I can't quite explain so far,
but that we will learn about next.