There's one more app engine
system tool I'd like to show you.
This is a tool that helps you understand
your application's performance in great
detail, much more than the logs do.
It's called App Stats, and
this is what it looks like.
App Stats let's you find out
what's going on behind the scenes
with each request that your app handles.
It shows you how many requests your app
is sending to data store memcache or
other backends for
each request that your app takes in.
It shows you latency details.
If a request was slow,
what was it doing all that time?
And when you expand beyond
the free service tier,
App Stats also shows you
the cost of all these requests.
So App Stats is a tool for profiling
your app, finding out which requests
take the most time or computer power,
or cost the most money.
Then you can use this information
to optimize your application.
For instance, by adding caching
to reduce API queries, or
by bundling requests into fewer
RPCs like we did with ndb.get_multi
in lesson four or by reducing
dependency on expensive services.
Setting up App Stats in Python requires
that you make two changes to your app.
You don't need to make any code changes,
but
you do need to tell App Engine
to collect the data.
And you need to turn on the built-in
URL handler to allow you to
access the App Stats console.
For the instructions, see the docs
linked in the instructor notes.
So let's take a look at the data
the App Stats gives you.
The RPC stats table shows
statistics of each RPC,
each request that your
app sends to a back end.
For instance, here you can see
data store get operations.
You can see the number of calls,
the total cost and the percentage cost.
All the other back end calls are listed
here too, like memCacheGet, and
datastoreRunQuery, and mail.send.
If your app has accessed another API,
like the translate API,
you'd see that here as well.
Over here is the path stats table.
It shows you more or less the same
information, but broken down by
the URL paths in your application,
instead of by back end calls.
So if we expand query conferences,
for instance, we can see that
query conferences makes calls to data
store run query and memcacheget.
Further down the page you'll
see a request history.
This shows information about each
individual request that your app
has received recently.
For instance, here,
query conferences was called.
And here's the time.
And they made requests
to these API methods.
And if you click on one of these
requests, you'll see the RPC
timeline view, which shows which
specific RPC calls were made, and
how long each of them took to process.
So you can see here, for instance, that
user.GetOAuthUser took 17 milliseconds.
This sort of thing is very important
to understanding your app's latency to
users.
This information may not
look very critical now.
But imagine that you're running
a service that takes hundreds or
thousands of requests every second.
That's not at all unusual for
a busy and popular app.
And you want to understand
which requests are slow and
which requests cost you more money and
where you should focus your attention
to make your app faster and cheaper.
App Stats is exactly the tool
you'd use to do that.