Now I want you to calculate some
metrics you're interested in for
both groups of students.
Students who pass the subway project and
students who don't.
For example, a good starting point would
be the three that we looked at earlier.
The number of minutes students spend
in the classroom, the number of lessons
they complete, and the number of
days that they visit the classroom.
Try to think of some other things
to look at as well, though.
You might look at whether these students
are more likely to go on to complete
other projects.
Or you might try looking at some
of the more granular data in
daily_engagement_full.csv, and see if
there's anything you can do with that.
Be creative here.
There's a lot available in this
data that you could explore.
Do the results surprise you?
Do you notice anything
interesting about them?
Choose the metric where you think the
difference is the most interesting, and
share what you found on the forums.
Also select which metric you shared here
and enter the mean for students who pass
in this box and the mean for
students who don't pass in this box.
If your most interesting
finding was non-numerical,
you can leave these boxes blank.
I'm hoping you came up with your own
idea for something to explore and
that you'll check the other box, but you
might also want to enter your value for
say minutes spent to check that
your code is working correctly.
Also check this box once
you've posted on the forums.