So, how do we do pyramid blending?
Again, my original image here, and what we have is this pyramid representation.
Of course, I can compute, just as I showed you before, the Gaussians for
this and the Laplacians for this.
So just to make it interesting in this example next to the Einstein,
I'm going to use this Tigger image and we're going to do blending between those.
Let's actually go ahead and showcase all of the, the Laplacian and
the Gaussian pyramid levels for this image also.
So now we have both the pyramids again we're going from coarse to fine.
Now if you were going to do any blending between this image and
that what we could do is.
Again, learned something with it before.
And just cross-fade at each and every level.
Right?
I can take parts of this,
parts of this, and merge these together to generate a blended image.
And remember when we talked about cross-fading images,
we basically said let's do it at the different frequency bands.
In essence, that's what we're doing here.
That we're going to look at the different frequency bands and
do cross-fading individually at those frequency bands,
octaves and of course merge them together.