All the task data, is stored in
a SQLite table that looks like this.
The table is named Tasks, and
each task in the table has three
pieces of data that describe it.
The first is the task id,
which is a unique integer that
identifies a row of data.
Second, is a description of the task,
which is stored as text in
a column named description.
And third, is the priority level of
the task which is an integer 1, 2 or 3.
So each of these pieces of data,
is a column in the tasks table.
And each row contains data for
individual tasks.
Multiple rows of data,
are generally called a directory.
And a single row of data
is often called an item.
And you'll hear me use these
terms throughout the lesson.
The name of this table and its columns,
are all in the TaskContract class.
Stored as constant strings.
They declare this constants because
you'll be referring to them in your code
multiple times and
you want to stay consistent.
Next, I want you to open up and go
through the code in TaskContract class,
and identify these constants
by their variable names.