An interesting phenomenon
called priority inversion
happens once we introduce
priorities into the scheduling.
Consider the following situation and
we'll use the shortest job for
scheduling to illustrate what happens.
We have three threads,
the first one has the highest priority.
And P3 is the lowest priority, so
T1 is the highest priority,` and
T3 is the lowest one.
For this example we have
left out the execution time.
Just assume they take some longer
amount of time all these tasks and
that the time graph
continues into the future.
Initially T3 is the only
task in the system.
So T3 executes, and
lets say that T3 also acquired a lock.
Now T2 arrives,
T2 has higher priority than T3, so
T3 will be preempted and
T2 gets to execute.
Now time 5,
T1 arrives, it has higher priority
than T2, so T2 will be preempted.
And then T1 executes for two time units.
And at that point,
it needs to acquire a lock, and
this happens to be the exact same
lock that's already held by T3.
Unfortunately that won't happen.
T1 cannot acquire the lock so
T1 at that point is put on a wait
queue associated with the lock.
We schedule the next highest
priority task that's runable,
that's going to be T2.
And then T2 will execute
as long as it needs.
And let's say in this case,
we're locked out.
T2 really only needed to execute for two
more units, at that point, T2 completes.
We schedule the next highest
priority runnable task.
The only runnable task
in the system is T3.
So T3 will get to execute.
In fact, T3 will execute for
as long as it needs to,
until it's releases the lock.
Only after T3 re, release the lock
will T1 become runnable and
then once T1 becomes runnable again.
It is the highest priority thread.
So T1 will preempt T3 and
T1 will continue it's execution.
So it will acquire the lock and
continue executing.
So based on the priority in the system,
we were expecting that T1
will complete before T2, and
then T3, the lowest priority thread,
will be the last one to complete.
However, that's not what happened and
the actual order of execution was
as follows: T2, the medium priority
thread; followed by T3, the lowest
priority thread; followed by finally T1,
the highest priority
thread last in the system.
So the priorities of these
tasks were inverted.
This is what we call Priority Inversion.
A solution to this problem would've been
to temporarily boost the priority of
the mutex owner.
What that means is that, at this
particular point when the highest
priority thread needs to acquire a lock
that's owned by a low priority thread,
the priority of T3 is
temporarily boosted to be,
basically at the same level as T1.
Then T1 could not have proceeded
just as before given that the log
is down by somebody else,
however, instead of scheduling T2,
we would have scheduled T3.
Priority would have been temporarily
boosted to that of T1, so
it would have been higher than T2.
And then T2 would have completed, and so
at least we would have been able to go
ahead and start executing T1
at this particular point.
And then we would not have had
to wait for T2 to complete for
the medium priority threat
to get in the middle.
This technique of boosting the priority
of the mutex owner, this is why, for
instance, it is useful to keep track of
who is the current owner of the mutex.
This is why we said we want to
have this kind of information
in the mutex data structure.
And obviously if we're temporarily
boosting the priority of the mutex
owner we should lower its priority
once it release the mutex.
The only reason why we were boosting
its priority was so as to be able to
schedule the highest priority
threat to run as soon as possible.
So wanted to make sure that the mutex
is released as soon as possible.
This is a common technique that's
currently present in many operating
systems.