As Dan demonstrated, building something
that looks great in the visual layout
editor is the easy part.
You also need to consider different
screens and orientations.
As you begin to layout your UI, there's
a temptation to build it pixel perfect
for the device you happen to be using.
This is re-enforced by the fact that you
Apps window doesn't generally change
size while it's running.
So you can't just grab the lower
right corner and grow and
shrink your app to see how it behaves.
But if you've ever developed for
the web or
a desktop, you know that
the static approach is a bad idea.
When Android first launched HVGA,
which are 480 by 320 pixel
resolution screens, were standard.
As we began exploring how to build
engaging user experiences on them we
could use absolute layouts to define the
exact location of each screen element.
But within a year the first WVGA android
phones were released with a different
pixel width.
And now android runs on everything from
phones to tables, TV's and wearables
with any screen size resolution and
aspect ratio you can imagine.
So just like on desktop or web,
where you might use panels or CSS,
your Android UI needs to scale based
on the screen it's running within.
And this is why absolute layout was
deprecated in favor of layouts like
linear layout, constraint layout, and
grid layout that can dynamically resize
and adapt to any screen following
the principles of responsive design.