Hey great job working
with the while loop, and
as you can see they make life so
much more convenient.
So we don't have to rewrite the same
line of code over and over again.
But let me tell you something,
there's even better news,
because I'm going to show you another
type of loop in Java, the for loop.
We can use it to rewrite the while loop
to become shorter and even more compact.
So here's the general
structure of a while loop and
a for loop, to help us understand
the similarities and differences.
Now notice that the for
loop condenses parts of the while
loop into just a single line.
In the for loop, we start the initial
set up of the counter variable
the test condition which determines
when we exit the loop and
then a spot to update
the counter variable.
Now we tend to use while loops
when we want to repeat a task
until something happens
the condition is no longer true.
So while loops can have
an indefinite number of iterations.
So a real world example of
a while loop is to keep opening
all files in a particular folder while
there are still files to be opened.
So we don't care how many files
in that folder there are,
we just keep doing it while
there are files there.
Now we tend to use for
loops when we want to repeat
a task a specific number of times.
So an example of a for loop is to open
the first five files in a folder.
So even though there might be
other files left in that folder,
we only want to do it four or
five times.
Now here's some code examples
of these two types of loops.
So, you're familiar with this code on
the left already, of the while loop.
But this is the first time
you're seeing a for loop.
Now both blocks of code do the same
thing; they print a log statement for
each element of the words list.
Now let's take a closer look at
these two types of loops and
then I'll point out parts that
you know in the while loop and
show you where they exist in the for
loop.
So before in the while loop,
we set up the index variable to be 0.
And in the for loop we can also
set up the counter variable and
we set it as 0 as well here.
And in the for
loop the set up comes in the first part
between these two parentheses,
so before the first semi colon.
Now this in the for loop is called
the initialization statement and
it will only be executed
once before the loop starts.
Then in the while loop,
we have the test condition that
goes within the parentheses.
So the loop will keep looping
until this condition is false.
So in this case,
when the index variable is no longer
less than the length of the word's list.
So similarly, in the for
loop, with the test condition follows
the initialization statement, and
is separated by semicolons before and
after it.
Now the body inside the for
loop will keep getting executed
until this test condition is false.
At the end of our while loop
we have this update statement,
to update the index variable by one.
So this helps us make sure that the
condition will eventually become false.
So likewise, in the for
loop, we can write the update statement
right after the test condition.
And so
it comes after the second semicolon.
So this update statement
will get executed
after each iteration of the loop.
Meaning we execute all of
the code in this block.
And then run the update statement.
Then we check the test condition.
And if it's true we have to take
the loop again and then and
check the update statement and
then check the test condition again.
So here's how the for loop works.
So we enter the for loop.
We set up the counter variable and
remember we only do this once.
Next we check the condition and
if it's true then we enter the for
loop body and
we execute whatever code is in here.
Afterwards, come out here and
update the counter variable.
After that, we check the test condition,
and if it's true we enter the body and
execute these instructions.
Come up here,
update the counter variable.
Go back to the condition.
Check if it's true, and
if it is complete this again.
And then go back up here.
And update the counter variable again.
And then after which when we
go back to the test condition,
if it's ever false then we
just completely exit the loop.
So remember the index plus
plus is a shorthand for
index equals index plus one.
And this just increments
the index value by one.
So to summarize, the syntax of a for
loop combines three parts of a loop into
a single line between these parentheses.
And each part is
separated by a semicolon.
So the first part is
the initialization statement,
which only gets executed
once before the loop starts.
The second part is a test condition,
which gets checked before we do
another iteration of the loop.
And the third part is
the update statement,
which gets executed at the end
of each iteration of the loop.
So now that you've seen example before
loop, try practice writing a for
loop in your me walk up.
So in this exercise I'd like you to
place writing a while loop with a for
loop and this will allow your
code to become more concise.
So the loop should behave the same and
by that I mean
adding a new text view to the layout for
each element in the words list.
And the output should
also look the same.
So here's a screenshot
of the numbers activity.
And remember as a hint,
I've included an example of the for
loop in the text below.
So go ahead and
check this check box when you're done.