I guess we've already
seen one optimization.
>> How so?
>> Well, if I choose the least
constraining value for Queensland,
we would not have had to back up.
Let me show you.
We started with
Western Australia being orange.
Then the Northern territory was green.
Since Queensland is not next to Western
Australia, I can use orange again.
That will leave blue unused.
>> Okay, so orange was the value that
least constrained our future choices.
>> Now, you get it.
>> Another optimization is to choose
to assign the variable with a minimum
remaining values next.
>> If we start with
assigning Western Australia,
then the Northern territory colors, the
variable with the least number of values
remaining is South Australia, so we
should choose that one next to assign.
>> What if I have a tie?
>> What do you mean?
>> In this example, we have assigned
Southern Australia a Northern Territory.
There are two regions that can be
only assigned orange, Queensland, and
Western Australia.
Which do we chose?
>> Choose the one with
the most constraints.
>> You mean Queensland in this case
because the border is New South Wales,
as well as a Northern Territory,
and Southern Australia.
Western Australia, only borders,
Norther Territory in Southern Australia.
So it's not as complex.
By choosing the one that's more
constrained in the future,
we'll appeal to running the problem
sooner rather than delaying them.
>> Correct.
>> Okay, well how much do these
improvements to backtracking help?
>> Remember our end queens problem?
>> Yeah.
>> Well it is another example of
a constraint satisfaction problem.
>> Okay.
>> And
using the least constraining value and
minimum remaining values heuristics, the
improved backtracking search will allow
us to do the thousand queens problem.
>> I don't think I could
ever do that by hand.
That's impressive.
>> You haven't seen anything yet.