The first statement,
set the IDS level to the highest
sensitivity to detect every attack.
This may appear to be a good idea, but
in practice, this may lead to
a large number of false alarms.
Second, monitor both outbound and
inbound traffic.
This is a good idea.
Because there will be a tech
traffic in both directions.
Third, use a shared network
resource to gather NIDS data.
This is not a good idea, because
an attacker can disable the IDS or
modify the alerts that sent.
Fourth, NIDS sensors
are not turnkey solutions.
System admins must interpret alerts.
This is true, because network
IDS can produce false positives.
Therefore, the system admins
must interpret the alerts and
take the appropriate actions.