That's right, this layout on the left
would be better if we have decided that
posting is the primary
focus of our platform.
It allows the user to perform
that action from the home screen
while giving them the option to go to
another screen to perform other actions.
It's important to note that the design
on the right is not a bad design either.
But focuses on a different
primary action,
reading content from other sources.
There are even platforms which allow
you to do both on the main page,
which is primarily useful for social
networking sites like Facebook, Tumblr,
or Twitter, where interaction between
content creators is the primary purpose.