But what if we missed things going on between the samples,
what if we don't have enough dots?
All right.
Well, not surprisingly something's getting lost, right,
some information is getting lost, right, so here we're showing you right so
I've got a dot here, I've got a dot here and there's all this change going on in
between, that is not realized or I should say not captured.
Perhaps, the surprising result though, is that actually
this is indistinguishable from a lower frequency, okay, so
here what's drawn in is, this the same set of dots, that we had before, but
there's a low frequency sinusoid that fits through there, 'kay.
Continuing with that, with sort of a surprising result is that,
the low frequency that was always indistinguishable from those high frequencies,
if you only gave me a small number of dots.
Okay, that is, I can't tell, whether or not it's a high frequency or
a low frequency, and that's the definition of aliasing, or
I should say that's an example of aliasing, the definition is it's the signal
that travels sort of in disguise of another signal or of other frequencies.
All right.
Now we're going to make this formal in just a minute, but that's what's going on
in aliasing is that I've got a signal and I can't distinguish between a low
frequency that was in there and actually a high frequency