The next homework problem was "Log in"
which generated a form like this and it had a couple of properties.
If you type in a name that doesn't exist and an invalid password
and click "Submit," you get an error message.
But if you type in a name that does exist and a valid password,
you get redirected to that same Welcome page.
So let's talk about the code that makes this work.
It's actually going to be 90% of the code we just saw for user registration,
so it should be pretty quick.
We have slash Login which goes to the Login Handler. Let's look at that.
Okay. So if you go to Get, it does Login from that HTML.
I'm sure you can imagine what that looks like.
It's just the basic form with the one error field and fields for user name and password.
Nothing magical there.
Out of the request we get the user name and the password.
Then what we do is we call this function "Login" on the user objects.
We'll go look at that in a sec.
Basically it returns the user, if this is a valid user name and password combination,
and "none" if it's not.
So if you recall the login function, which we'll look at also in a sec,
which sets the cookie just like it does for "Register."
You can actually see the "Register" code up here.
We log in the user and we redirect to the "Welcome page."
If it's not, if there is no "U," we rerun to the form
with an error message.that says "Invalid Login."
Let's look at this Login function here on the User Object,
and then the Login function here on the Log Handler.
And I realize I probably could have named those a little better
so they're not quite so confusing.
But these are actually different functions even though they have the same name.
First is the User Object. So here's the User Object and it has a class method called Login.
So we can say "User dot Login."
And what this does is it says Class By Name which just refers to itself.
It refers to the User Class so it's actually going to call this Function.
The reason we say Class by Name here and not User by Name
is so that we can overwrite this function later.
You can actually see I haven't been consistent about that.
This should really be Class. All of these should be CLS and not Upper Case User.
Since I haven't inherited this Class it's not a big deal, but that's a bug waiting to happen.
So now you get to see how bugs happen in the real world.
We call it By Name, which calls this function By Name which looks for a user of that name.
If it exists and it's a valid password, which is the Quiz Function we wrote before,
If the name and password entered in match the password hash,
from the object with that name in the database,
we return the user.
So that's that first login function which basically checks to see,
is this name and password combination valid?
If it is, we go up here to our Handler and we call this Login function.
Remember, down before we called Self that login?
Well, this is what it refers to--this function here.
And all this function does is it sets a secure cookie, user ID, and it equals the user's ID.
And this is how you get the user's ID and datastore.
Remember on our next request to the Welcome page,
we're going to call Initialize, as every request calls Initialize.
What this does is read a secure cookie called user ID and,
if that is valid, it sets Self dot User to dot User.
That's how Login works.