[Male narrator] Here are the truth tables for all the logical connectives.
What a truth table does is list all the possibilities for the propositional symbols,
so P and Q can be false and false, false and true, true and false, or true and true.
Those are the only 4 possibilities,
and then for each of those possibilities, the truth table lists the truth value
of the compound sentence.
So the sentence not P is true when P is false and false when P is true.
The sentence P and Q is true only when both P and Q are true and false otherwise.
The sentence P or Q is true when either P or Q is true
and false when both are false.
Now, so far, those mostly correspond to the English meaning of those sentences
with one exception, which is that in English, the word "or" is somewhat ambiguous
between the inclusive and exclusive or,
and this "or" means either or both.
We translate this mark into English P implies Q; or as if P, then Q,
but the meaning in logic is not quite the same as the meaning in ordinary English.
The meaning in logic is defined explicitly by this truth table
and by nothing else, but let's look at some examples in ordinary English.
If we have the proposition O and have that mean 5 is an odd number
and P meaning Paris is the capital of France,
then under the ordinary model of the truth in the real world,
what could we say about the sentence O implies P?
That is, 5 is an odd number implies Paris is the capital of France.
Would that be true or false?
And let's look at one more example.
If E is the proposition that 5 is an even number
and M is the proposition that Moscow is the capital of France,
what about E implies M?
5 is an even number implies Moscow is the capital of France.
Is that true or false?