So far we've seen that HTTP
can be used to request content
like what's in a web page,
images, text, video.
But for the apps that we'll be writing,
we'll use HTTP in
a slightly different way.
Instead of using URL's like Udacity.com,
we'll use special URL's that correspond
to methods like getImageData,
that are made available by web services.
Web services sometimes are also referred
to as APIs but don't get confused,
they mean the same thing.
I'm going to take a look at
an example from the Flickr API.
We're going to look at
flicker.people.getPublicPhotos.
This method returns some kind of image
data back to our client or an app.
We're going to look at flickr's
documentation for this method now.
I posted a link in the instructor notes.
So this is the documentation for get
public photos and there's something I
want to draw to your attention first,
and that is the use of arguments.
So the arguments listed here are a lot
like the arguments that you'd see for
a swift function call.
And you'll also notice that some
of them are required like APIK
while others are not like safe search.
Now, this is really cool here at
the bottom, this is the API explorer.
Not all API's have this, but
flicker does and it's extremely useful.
The API explorer allows us to test
the API's methods before using them
in our apps.
For this method, it shows the only
required argument is the user ID.
This is only a half truth,
the API key is also required but
in the API explorer, it automatically
includes a test API key for us.
For the user ID argument,
I'll go ahead and
use my user ID that I've
copied ahead of time.
And then under the extras argument,
I'll type url_m.
If you read the documentation,
the url_m option specifies that we want
the result of this method to
include URL's for medium images.
You'll see that in just a second.
And last, we want to change the output
to JSON, our JavaScript object notation
which we'll talk about
more later in this lesson.
And let's call the method.
And after it's called,
we can see the results below.
In the results we see this
information about photos and
then within photos it looks like
there's a group of individual photos.
And judging by the total
value we see here of 13,
it appears there's
probably 13 total photos.
For each photo we can see this owner
ID which is the same as my user ID.
And we also see an ID for the image.
If we keep scrolling to the right
there's more values, and
here is the URL underscore in value that
we specified in the extras argument.
If we copy one of these, we can paste
it into the browser to see the image.
The URL seems to be not working.
And I think it's because these extra
slash characters that have been added
before each of the forward slashes.
So let me remove these.
And I'm removing them manually now,
but normally,
these slash characters will get removed
when we create an NS URL in code.
And let's try this.
Nice!
This is a picture of Eloise,
this is my wife's cat.
I actually didn't really like
Eloise very much at first, but
she's kind of grown on me over time.
Back in the API explorer,
let's recap on what's happening.
The results being returned by this, get
public photos method is this Jayson data
representing the photos in
my public photo stream.
And, they're being returned as Jayson
because that's what we specified
here, in the output.
If we scroll all the way to the bottom,
we see this really long and ugly URL.
I'll copy this and
paste it back into our browser.
If we visit this link,
we get the exact same thing that
we saw in the API explorer.
In fact,
the URL that we're using here is
extremely similar to the URL our app
will use to receive data from Flickr.
Now if we look more
closely at the URL itself,
we can see the arguments
that we passed in.
We didn't pass in the method argument
that was implicit in the explorer.
But if we keep scrolling here
to the right past the API key,
we can see my user ID here.
And then we can see the extras
argument and the url_m.
There are also these ampersands
that seem to separate the different
argument values.
So there's one there, there's one there,
and you can see them continuing on.
Now the ampersands themselves
are part of a standard for
how arguments are sent in an URL.
Speaking of standards,
I should note that URL's can
only be sent over the Internet
using the ASCII character set.
The ASCII character set is a simple
way of representing characters on
a computer, where character values can
also be represented using a number.
Here are some example ASCII characters
and their corresponding values.
I've posted a link in the instructor
notes if you want to read
more about them.
In some cases we may want to use
URL that contains characters that
are considered unsafe asking
characters such as the plus sign.
When this happens we have to encode or
escape these unsafe characters into
valid ASCII characters in the URL.
The escape version of a plus
sign is percent sign, two B, and
each of those characters, the percent
sign, the two and the B are valid,
safe ASCII characters
Here's another example.
This is a URL that uses Flickr's
flickr.photos.search method.
One of the arguments in this
message is called text,
which is a string
representing a text search.
In this URL the text is equal
to red percent, two, B blue.
This is the escaped or
encoded version of the actual
text which is red plus blue.
Since the plus sign is considered unsafe
ASCII it's escaped with the characters
percent, two B.