The general GI section only has four
properties that we can play with.
Indirect intensity and bounce boost
are pretty self explanatory in
that they control how intense indirect
light stored in the light map and
how much light should bounce
in the scene respectively.
Then, there's the default
parameter that lets us control
a lot more specific properties
in the baking process.
Check out the Unity documentation for
how you can control these properties.
And lastly, there's the directional
mode, which is a drop-down of three
choices, non directional, directional,
and directional specular.
From the materials lesson, remember
the terms diffuse, normal, and specular?
These modes are all ways to capture
light information when baking
that brings out the best
in our materials.
Nondirectional mode
stores light information
as if materials were purely diffuse.
Directional mode stores the same
information as non-directional mode, and
also stores the direction
light hits objects
to make the most out of normal maps.
And as you can probably guess,
directional specular stores directional
mode information as well as indirect
lighting information to use for
the specular property on materials.
Given this information and the fact
that we're targeting Google Cardboard,
what do you think is the correct
directional mode we should use?