Now all of this is well and good.
We need to also remember, at least in my opinion, what is the ultimate camera.
The ultimate camera does remain to be the human vision system, and
all of the work we've done with photography, or
computational photography, attempts, to some extent, recreate it.
Now, of course, we are also generating newer and novel forms of
images that the human vision system does not actually capture or relate to.
That's also true, but we're trying to build cameras that can help us
see more information in the environment.
So, in essence, if you look at it, the relationship between a human eye,
which is aimed at capturing the rays of light onto a retina.
Is not much different than that of a camera.
Basically, again has a lens and it either goes onto a film or a sensor.
So computational photography in my opinion, also does yield us to
understand more about how we actually will be doing things,
like building sensors to capture the environment we're in.