So are you familiar
with K-armed Bandits.
>> Let's pretend I'm not.
>> All right, so let me tell you
a little bit about K-armed Bandits then.
So here's the basic idea.
You have K bandits and
each of them has an arm.
>> So wait,
why isn't it K armed-bandits then?
Why isn't the dash between armed and
bandits?
>> Oh, K armed-bandits.
Yeah, because each one is an armed
bandit and there's K of them.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
That works, but
I think we're supposed to think of it,
the important thing is that
there's K different arms.
>> [LAUGH]
>> Okay.
>> And so the bandit,
this comes from terminology
having to do with slot machines.
They named this model back in
the I'm going to say '50s.
So, we don't have to necessarily
understand it anymore.
That was ancient history.
But the fact of the matter is
sometimes people will call
a slot machine a one armed bandit.
In a slot machine, you get to make
a choice at each moment in time,
which of the one arms to pull.
Which, of course, is not a very
interesting decision problem.
So, the idea of a K-armed Bandit is,
you've actually got, in this case,
what K is 7?
And each of these arms has some
probability of paying off.
So, you pull on it and you either get
jackpot, or you don't get a jackpot.
Now usually in a casino these
would be rather low payoffs.
In fact, I think it's not so
uncommon in the casino for
them to have not even
necessarily different payoffs.
But here for this,
it's going to be interesting to have
each of the arms have
a different payoff.
Or at least we don't know what the
payoffs are, they could be different.
>> Okay.
>> So which arm do we want to pull?
>> The best one?
>> Yeah, which one is that?
>> The one that has the best
chance of giving you money.
>> Here, I'll make it easier for you.
Okay.
>> I'm going to give each
of them a name.
All right, now which one do you pull?
>> The letter that has the most
money associated with it.
>> Okay, all right, so
I think you're making a valid point,
though you're making it
in a frustrating way.
And that is that we don't know which
arm to pull because we don't know
what the payoffs are.
So if I tell you the payoffs this
problem becomes really easy right?
>> Yeah.
>> We just do argmax right?
Whichever one has the highest payoff,
we just choose it all the time.
But, what makes
the K-armed Bandits problem
interesting is that we
don't know the payoffs.
Let's say instead what we know is
that each one has some probability of
giving a pay off.
And the payouts are all the same,
let's say they're all 0/1.
And each bandit has a probability
of paying off a one.
But, we don't know what it is at first.
And, in fact, if we pull arm A and
it doesn't pay off, does that
mean that A is not the best one?
>> No, I mean, how would we know?
We don't know what anything else is.
>> No, right, right.
So, therefore, we can prove that one arm
pull is giving us some information, but
not an awful lot.
We actually have to combine information
across a whole lot of pulls to start to
really appreciate what
the best thing to do would be.
>> Okay, so we have to explore.
>> Yes! Good.
Way to connect it back to the topic.
All right, so let's think about what
that problem might actually look like.
So, I wrote down the observed
payoffs for each of these arms.
Associated with each one of these arms
is the number of times that we've pulled
that arm: 10, 20, 40, 5, 10, 20, 40.
And of those times that we've pulled it,
the number of times it
actually paid off for us.
So, this arm, we pulled 10 times and
we got a payoff of 1.
This arm, we pulled 10 times, and
we got a payoff twice, two payoffs.
So between a and e,
if we had to choose one,
it seems pretty clear that
e has been better so far?
>> Yeah, so far.
>> Yeah, and let's say between a and
d they both paid off once, but d gave
us the payoff after only five hits.
Or in the context of five hits,
five pulls.
And a in the context of 10 pulls.
So d is a bit better than a as well.
So, what I'd like us to do is
think about two different things.
One is,
given the data that we've gotten so
far, which arm has
the highest expected payoff?
And, of all the different
arms that we could pull,
which of the estimates
are we most confident in?