Hey, glad you're back.
Let's talk about another useful tool
that'll help you gather data and
get better insight into how
your applications using energy.
It's called Battery Historian.
Basically, you're going to use
ADB to dunk data from your phone.
And then use the Battery Historian
tool to convert that data into a nice
HTML table that you can
view in your web browser.
Now Battery Historian is a separate
open source python script
that you're going to need
to download from GitHub.
So.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Okay.
So here we are at the GitHub page for
Google's version of Battery Historian.
Now in order to download this file,
we want to come down here to lower right
and click this download zip button.
For this demo we're going
to work from the desktop.
But you can use any
directory of your choosing.
Now to get started let's go ahead and
double-click this zip file which is
going to extract the folder with
the python script that we care about.
Okay.
Let's go ahead and open the folder.
As you can see there's a license file,
as well as the historian python script.
Let's go ahead and
drag this script to the desktop.
Okay, that's it for setup.
We should be all set to
use Battery Historian.
Now the next thing you're
going to want to do,
is make sure you connect
your phone to your computer.
Also make sure that USB
debugging is turned on.
I'm going to go ahead and
run ADB devices just to confirm.
All right, the next steps will
work from any terminal window.
But if you have Android Studio
opened like I do,
you can actually open a terminal
right within the ID, like so.
Go ahead and cd to your desktop.
Now as a precaution, we're going to go
ahead and shut down our ADB server.
The way you do this is by
typing adb kill server.
Now this is an important step
because while we're developing,
lots of stuff can be turned on
that might cause conflicts,
while trying to do battery recordings.
So to be safe here,
we want to start ADB clean.
All right.
So I'm going to go ahead and
type ADB devices.
As we can see, ADB is restarting,
and our phone is attached.
If you don't see any devices,
make sure your phone is connected and
your USB debugging is turned on.
Then go ahead and kill and
restart ADB once more.
Now the next thing we want to do is
reset the battery data gathering so
you can start from a blank state,
we do it like this.
So I just type this command adb
shell dumpsys batterystats,
With the reset option.
This is going to go ahead and
reset all the battery gathering data.
Now if you don't do this,
you're going to get a lot more data
than is actually useful or relevant.
In other words, you're going to see a
lot more noise than you want when you're
reading your battery stats.
All right.
So now you can go ahead and
disconnect your phone
from your computer.
When you go ahead and
pull this cable out right here, so
you don't draw any current from your
computer instead of the battery.