So next you'll need to bring
in two utility functions.
formatFilters and
getQuery from todo5conference.py.
Lets take a look at those.
The formatFilters function takes
the user separated values and
creates a filter in a format
that app engine understands.
It also makes sure that users are not
trying to run impossible queries,
by using an inequality
filter on two fields.
And the getQuery function uses
the formatted filter to form a query,
including using proper ordering,
when necessary.
So to make your app actually
take user filters into account,
you'll also need to change the query
conferences method in conferences.py.
To use the getQuery method
to get the query, and
then return the result as before.
Now, go ahead and
make the changes necessary to enable
this functionality in your app.
After you've done that,
check off these boxes,
then make a couple of
conferences in your app.
Make one of them named Udacity.