In your Pitch Perfect Xcode project,
select the Main.storyboard file.
This is your storyboard file where you’ll place
and set up your entire user interface.
Right now the interface looks pretty
bare, but eventually you'll see the
entire interface, all of the elements and
the view controllers associated with
this particular project. Right now this
app only has one interface called the
View Controller. A couple of key things to
notice. The first is this gray arrow and
I selected it, so it's blue. But if I
deselect it, it goes back to gray. That's on
the left side of the view. This signifies
that it is the initial view controller
for this storyboard and in fact for the
entire application. When a user starts
the app, this is the first view
controller and view that will load. Want
to drag out to give us some more space.
And here in the bottom right hand corner,
we see the library selector with the
different types of UI elements that we
can drag in. If you don't see the library,
make sure this third icon from the left
is selected, the one that looks like a
square surrounded by a circle. We can
also hide the debug and navigator panels
to give ourself some more room while
we're working on the interface. Before we
drag a button in, this view needs to be a
hundred percent zoomed in. So if you're
zoomed out, double click on the view to
zoom in.
Let's start by dragging in a button to
this UI interface element. In the filter
at the bottom of the library, start
typing “UIButton”
Drag the button to the center of the
screen and use the two blue guidelines
to Center it horizontally and vertically.
And let go to place it. Now we've come to
the first problem most beginning iOS
developers face. The background of this
button is white and the UI view behind
it is also white. If you click away,
how can you tell how big the button is.
So we've clicked away from the button
and now I have no idea how big it is.
One trick that I can use is to temporarily
change the background of the button, so I
can easily determine how big it is
compared to the rest of view. This is also
a great chance for you to play around a
little bit with the attributes inspector.
with the button selected in the document
outline, click on the attributes
inspector in the inspector panel.
It's the one that looks like a downward
facing arrow. Scroll down until you see
the Background option. Select the
drop-down and then go down to Other，
So we can set our own custom color.
I’ll pick this bright green color for the
background. The more visible the better.
You're not going for aesthetics just yet.
Now we can see that our button is pretty
small and we can easily see what would
happen if we resized it.
Let's click on the button again and then
in the inspector panel, scroll up to the top,
and we're still in the attributes
inspector by the way. And let's change
the button’s text. Let's set it to the
word “Record”. And here we have the button.
Let’s drag it out, so it displays the
entire word. The next step is to set up
the layout for the button. And for that,
we need to talk briefly about
AutoLayout.