To give you an example of how we set up
a Kaggle competition,
I'm going to start off with a
really simple use case. Let's say that
someone comes to us, and says, I want to
predict the sales price of a home.
I have that price the home sold for, as
well as a couple features describing it.
I have its location,
I have the number of bathrooms, I have
the number of bedrooms it has, I have the
square footage, and I have
whether or not it's an apartment or
condo unit or it's a home.
Let's say that asset had 10,000 rows in it,
we take those 10,000 rows and the first
thing that we do, is we split it up into
a training set and a test set. Value
seventy percent of the data, seven
thousand rows for the training set. And
three thousand rows for the test set.
We'll then release the training set in
its entirety, so both things like the
number of bedrooms as well as the sales
price to our community.
So our community can use their seven
thousand examples to learn the relation
between the size of a home and the sales
price of the home.
Well then I also release everything
on the test set, except for the sales
price. So I'll release the number of
bedrooms the home had and their location.
We'll not tell our community the sales
price of the homes for that test that
they then take the lessons that they
learned in the relation between the
number of bedrooms in the sales price,
the relation between the location of the
sales price etc on the training set, and
apply that to the test set, make
predictions for the sales price on the
test set and send us those predictions.
We then take the predictions they sent
us, and compare those and calculate the
differences between those predictions
and the solution to the test set so the
actual sales price of those three
thousand homes.
We then compute two scores from that, we
can be at a private leaderboard score
based on about 2,500 of those homes that
we use for file scoring and evaluation
that we do not show the participant
until the end of the competition. And we
compute public leader board score, based
in about 500 of those homes that we show
immediately to the participant on a
real-time leaderboard, that not only
shows them their own score, but also
compares how they did
with every other people person who
submitted so far in that competition. And
that's real timely reward, that enables
people to go back
think about the prom again, try making
improvement, submit again, to validate whether
or not it was actually an improvement.
And then see how other people have
improved along with them.
The domain name was available.
>> Who came up with the name? >> Anthony.
>> OK. >> He wrote a script that search for a
lot of phonetically similar domain names
that were available or phonetically
reasonable to me, names that were available.