So here now we can see we
can get the transition type
using
geofencingEvent.getGeofenceTransition.
This is going to return
an integer to us.
Now, the geofence object contains these
constants GeofenceTransitionEnter and
GeofenceTransitionExit.
So all we have to do then is if
the geofence transition is this or
the geofence transition is this,
then we're going to run a block of code.
We'll see what that block of
code is in a few moments, but
this is all you'll have to do to check
the transition type if you're
entering or if you're existing.
Of course, it's up to you how
you build your application.
If you want to build it so
that events only happen when you enter,
then you don't need to check for the
geofence transition exit and vice versa.