To go in a little bit deeper
into the special device files,
Linux also supports what are called
pseudo or virtual devices.
These devices do not represent an actual
hardware and are not critical in our
understanding of I/O management,
but are useful nonetheless.
As a quiz, I will ask you to look at
the following function descriptions and
name the pseudo device that
provides that function.
First, what is a device that accepts and
then discards all output without
actually producing anything?
Second, what is a device that
produces a variable-length string of
pseudo-random numbers?
For your answers, please fill them in,
in these boxes, and
also use the full path to the device
to specify what is the correct answer.
For instance to answer that
the devices line printer is here up,
use path /dev, /lp0.