Now, throughout this class, we've been
giving you sample code to work on.
Now I've got a little
interesting opportunity for you.
Now it's your turn to apply what
you've learned to your own apps.
So your final mission is to profile
your app using battery historian.
In number one, go ahead and identify
opportunities to use the JobScheduler.
For example, look for
inefficient wake lock and
network access that you can reduce.
Number two, go ahead and
generate a report and battery string and
take a screenshot.
Make sure to keep your
raw HTML file as well.
Third, go ahead and make improvements
to areas in your code that you've
identified as potentially inefficient or
problematic.
Number four, go ahead and
re-profile your code, then go ahead and
generate a new report in battery
storing and take a new screenshot.
And then when you're done, go ahead and
share the before and
after screenshots on the forum,
and then call out any specific
improvements that you see in your graph.
Or if you don't see any real clear
difference in the before and
after screenshots,
post us to why this might be the case.
We'll be checking
the forums periodically and
we want to see what
you guys come up with.
All right, cool, so this wraps up our
course and I want to thank you for
all your hard work, it's certainly
been a pleasure to come along and
assist in your journey.
I hope you learned to always
apply performance mind set,
when writing your code and
maybe hope you had a little fun too.
Take care and we'll see you soon.