Now, Swift provides two standard
protocols, printable and
debug printable that can greatly
benefit your print debugging.
The printable protocol requires a class
specify a description property, and
the debug printable, not shown here,
requires a debug description property.
Before we use either of them,
let's see how our current
print statements are lacking.
I've added two print statements that
print self when new bugs are being
added to the view for this addBugToView
method, so one here and one here.
And we know the value itself is this
instance of
the PrintBugViewController class.
One might assume that printing self
will be a good way to get information
about the entire view controller,
seems like a perfectly valid assumption.
For example, the print statements could
tell me the current count of bugs and
any data that's specific to this view.
But, when I run the app and
create some bugs,
the default output of this statement
is just the name of the class,
PrintBugViewController, and
the memory address.
And this isn't particularly useful but
we can do much better than this by
implementing the printable and
debug printable protocols.
So let's stop the app and
I'll hide this for a minute and
let's scroll down to the bottom.
To keep things clean and
readable, let's implement these
protocols in an extension.
For the description, let's return
the number of bugs in the bugs array.
So you can see for this we need to
override the description property.
And we must specify,
because it's a computer property,
that it's string type.
And then you simply return string.
So we can see that we're returning
PrintBugViewController contains
the number of bugs in the bugs array.
Then for the debug description,
let's return the number of bugs and
also the positions of each bug.
So for this particular description,
we will start with
the number of bugs again, and then we'll
iterate through the bugs array, and for
each bug we'll add the bug,
index number and its frame information,
and then we'll return the entire string.
So let's rebuild and run this.
And I'll go to print debugging and
tap, and
now when our print statements are
reached, we can see the number of bugs
instead of just the name of
the class and the memory address.
Now, if we want to use, and this right
here is our description property,
if we want to see the debug description,
iInstead of using printLn, stop,
we'll use the debugPrintLn.
There we go, here, for
both of our print statements.
One more time.
Click, tap, and there we go.
Pretty slick, huh?