Back to where we were.
Remember this equation, 0 is equal to X'.(T x RX)?
We just rewrote that again.
So, now I can get rid of that whole cross product thing, right, and put that
cool, little funky cross product notation in there, right, right, all right?
So, let me do a substitution.
I'm going to let E.
Be just this, T cross R, okay, so it's just this substitution in here.
Well, as soon as you do that, you realize, I have this really beautiful elegant
expression that says X' prime transpose EX equals 0.
And E is what's called the essential matrix.
And what's cool about the essential matrix is that, it relates the point X and
the same point, but it described in the other camera frame.
And note that these are world points.
In these frames for these calibrated systems.
In a little bit we'll talk about the relationship between, world points and
the image points.
And it's a little bit closer than you might think,
because of the projective geometry.
In fact, one way of thinking about this really easily is
this is equal to 0, right?
So what if I multiplied X by some value A?
Would the equation still be true?
Of course it would.
So not only is it true for
the point out here, as expressed in this coordinate frame, it's true for
every point along that ray, expressed in that coordinate frame.
Likewise for every point along that ray.
Expressed in that coordinate frame, ooh.
That means, it also talks about image points, but we'll get there, all right?
One last thing, and this is going to, you're not going to totally get
that this time, but that's okay, you're going to get it next time, all right?
We said that this works for sort of, any point along that ray.
And, so you can think of that as the homogenous representation of all
the points along that array.
So this, so our E is our 3 by 3 here, times this 3 by 1, so
this is another vector here.
All right, we'll just call that L, okay.
Why am I calling it L?
What does L stand for?
Well in some weird language, we said it stood for
point, but in our language, it stands for line.
So remember that X transpose L, or P transpose L,
or L transpose P was the definition of a line in projective geometry.
So what this means is, if I knew where some point was in the image.
So I know what ray it's along in the image.
So I know where it is in the image.
I could put that point into this equation.
And I would have this L, which defines for me a line, in the other frame.
Just X prime transpose L equals 0,
that was the, the definition of a line in our projective geometry.
So in other words, if I gave you a point in one image of a calibrated set of
cameras, there's a line in the other image that that point must lie on.
What's that line called?
That's the epipolar line.
But notice, that everything on this side of the slide is algebra, right?
Forget all the geometry stuff.
So what we've done is we've now converted the epipolar constraint into
an algebraic expression.
Thank you very much.
No. That's what we're going to use, okay?
Great.