All right, you're done.
I'll show you what I did.
All right, so the first thing we did
was update our list item forecast
to have left and right extra padding.
We added a dimension file for
sw600dp portrait.
Note, we can have I've really,
really wide padding there,
because remember tablets
are just huge in that direction.
SW720dp is even wider, but
we're not actually going to
increase the padding at all.
So we also took the grid layout
of the fragment detail and
moved it as a detail extras grid.
That's pretty easy because well,
we just literally moved it.
All we needed to do was make sure that
we added these name spaces in correctly.
Under Refs, we've now created this
fragment detail start layout reference,
which is pretty cool.
We've created it for
every single size and orientation.
It's always pointing to the right one.
Now we use this layout inside a detail
fragment rather than referencing
the layout by name.