Here's a search tree for a version of Pacman in which there's only four squares.
There's a little Pacman guy who can move around,
and there are food dots that the Pacman can eat.
Maybe someplace else in the maze there are opponents,
but we're not going to worry about them right here.
We're just going to consider the Pacman's actions.
He has two actions--to go left or right
If he goes left, he goes over here and eats that food particle
and then moves back right--that's his only move from that position.
Or if he moves right then he has two other moves.
Now let's assume that we cut off the search at this depth,
and we want to have an evaluation function,
and the goal is for Pacman to eat all the food.
The evaluation function will be the number of food particles that he's eaten so far.
What I want you to do is tell me in these boxes
what the evaluation should be for each of these three states.