All right.
So to do that,
is just a little bit of math,
it's not a horrible amount of math, it's
just sort of pretty straight forward.
So here's our line, and let's set
our line to be wx plus b equals 0,
and that's going to go down
the middle of the line.
I'm sorry, down the middle of the set,
that's going to be our
separating boundary.
Now, what we can do is we can say the,
the lines that are the,
the margin lines,
the ones that hit the nearest points,
we can say that the value on one
side is w.x plus b equals minus 1,
and on the other side
w.x plus b equals 1.
Now you might ask,
how come I can set them equal to 1?
>> How can I set them equal to 1?
>> Megan's asleep over there,
but she got to it eventually.
Well, remember I could scale,
w and b, right?
And still have wx plus b equals 0.
So what I can do is I can scale
them up to make it so tho,
those distances are 1.
What we want is, we're going to define
a little auxiliary variable called y,
corresponding to the xs, and the idea
is that when I have a positive x,
we're going to find y to be plus 1.
When we have a negative x, and what I
mean positive, is a positive example and
a negative example, you know, this is
a baseball, this is not a baseball.
All right, so when y equals minus 1,
we've got x.w plus b to
be less than minus 1.
So that's a way of saying that, you
know, we want all the positives to lie
over here, and we want all
the negatives to lie over there, okay?
Notice, that on this drawing, there
are a couple of special points, okay?
Now, in today's age, we like to tell
points, all points are special.
But in reality, just like real life,
only some of us points are special,
okay?
In particular, this point is special,
this point is special, and
this point is special,
because they define our margin.
All these other points out here,
they don't impact our margin, all right?
And this is part of why discriminative
classification is, is sort of better,
not sort of,
is in some sense better than generative.
We don't actually have to worry about
representing all these points out there.
We're just representing the boundary but
getting back to what we're saying,
that we have these three special
points that define what our margin is.
And those, are referred to as our
support vectors, these are vectors,
right?
They're points in our feature of space,
so you can think of that as a vector,
and these are called support vectors
because these are the ones that sort of
define for us that,
that best separating plane.
So those are support vectors, okay?
So at our support vectors, x.w plus
b actually equals 1, right, okay, and
the distance between those lines, that's
going to be referred to as our margin.
So we can compute, the size of M,
as a function of these values, right?
So we have the same
equation we had before,
the distance between the point and the
line, x.w plus b normalized by w, okay?
That's the, that's the, the,
the distance between a point and a line.
Well, so for support vectors, w.x plus b
is just either plus 1 or minus 1, okay?
It's plus 1 on one side,
minus on the other side,
divided by the magnitude of w.
So that means that M is just,
you know, 1 minus negative 1 over w,
because of that value, right,
and so it's just 2 over w, okay?
So the margin M is just 2 over w.
What we need to do is we
want to find w that does what?
We want to maximize the margin