Here's a quiz that's very similar to
the one that you recently took on
XDR data types except this time,
we're concerned with the data
being transmitted over the network and
the encoding cost of such transmissions.
Let's again assume that an RPC
routine uses a variable-length array
of integers and that the array is full.
For that situation,
answer the following.
How many bytes are needed to
encode this five element array so
that it can be sent from a client to
a server where both the client and
the server are 32-bit machines?
In your answer, please do not
include any bytes for the headers or
the protocol related information.
And provide your final answer concerning
this encoding of this data structure
in bytes.