[Thrun] And the answer is 1/3,
as you can easily see if you call X the probability of rain in time T
and also the probability of rain, T minus 1.
These 2 must be equivalent because we're looking for the stationary distribution.
Then we get, by virtue of our expansion of the state at time T,
the probability of transitioning from rain to rain is 0.6,
the probability of having it rain is X again,
the probability of transitioning from sun to rain is 0.2,
and the probability of having sun before is 1 minus X,
so we get X equals 0.4X plus 0.2.
Or, differently, we have 0.6X equals 0.2,
and when we work this out, X is 1/3,
which is the probability of rain in the asymptote if you wait forever.
One of the interesting things to observe here
is that the stationary distribution does not depend on the initial distribution.
In fact, I didn't even tell you what the initial state was.
Markov chains that have that property, which are pretty much all Markov chains,
are called ergodic.
You can safely forget that word again, but people in the field use this word
to express Markov chains that mix.
And mix means that the knowledge of the initial distribution fades over time
until it disappears in the end.
The speed at which it gets lost is called the mixing speed.