Let's look at this whole concept a bit
more in detail with real camera paths
and stuff like that.
Let's first look at four degrees
of freedom in the image itself.
Here basically we're going to
look at the same video here and
let's look at translation
just the changes in x.
So this is the path
that changes in x and
I'm basically traversing it over here,
and you saw happened.
Also, we can do this for y.
We can look for translations in y.
Again, y is changing as I move from
number of frames down this way.
We can do the same for scale.
This basically says the scale is getting
you know, smaller and getting bigger.
It was much bigger here,
and then, finally,
we can also look at
things like rotation.
So, this basically starts saying is that
these are the four parameters that now
we can model purely by looking at the
whole region and going into a degree of
freedom calculations, and being able to
model the transformations of the image.
This gives us the path
that we are interested in.