Now, I've chosen to say that only robotic soccer and hide-and-go-seek are stochastic.
By that I mean if you have an action like go forward 1 meter,
the result of that action stochastic. You may not go forward exactly 1 meter.
You could also analyze games like poker and cards and say that they're stochastic
in that the next car is random, and so the action of flipping over the next card is stochastic.
You don't know how that action is going to result.
I've chosen to model that as partial observability.
What I've said is it's not that you pick randomly from the next card,
it's that the cards are already arranged in some order.
It's just that you don't know what that order is.
There's partial observability that gives you the next card.
Partial observability also shows up in the real world sports
or of robot soccer and hide-and-go-seek.
Obviously, that's kind of the point of hide-and-go-seek that it's partially observable.
Now, in terms of unknown, I've said that only hide-and-go-seek satisfies that.
In everything else, the world is well-defined.
Even in the real world in an environment like robot soccer,
you only have the known field to deal with.
Whereas in hide-and-go-seek, someone could be hiding anywhere
in a room or location that you don't know about yet.
Notice that many games are adversarial, but some games are not.
Solitaire games are not adversarial.
You could mark that down as saying, well, I'm playing against the game itself,
but we don't count that as adversarial, because the games itself is not trying to defeat you.
The game itself is passive.
Whereas in these games and what adversarial has come to mean is that
the opponent is taking into account what you are thinking
when the opponent does their own thinking and tries to defeat you that way.