In the first case, the answer is 0.2. And the way I got there is the property of measuring white for A is 0.6, which is the number over here.
But we have to normalize. And we find out that two particles get the white value, which is 1.2, two times 0.6.
And all the other six particles have to get a non-normalized importance weight that is 0.3, which is one minus 0.7.
So six times 0.3 is 1.8. So the normalizer in total will be three.
And 0.6 divided by three equals 0.2.
In the second question the answer is 0.08.
Because you measure black, A gets a non-normalized importance weight of 0.4, which is one minus 0.6.
There are two particles that get 0.4, which adds up to 0.8.
And six particles that get 0.7, which adds up to 4.2.
If you add this together, it's 0.4 divided by five, which is 0.08.