Hi and welcome to the first
lesson of the Udacity
artificial intelligence
nanodegree program.
My name is Luis Serrano and I'm one
of the instructors here at Udacity.
Before being here I used to work
in machine learning in Google.
I'm the team that generated your
YouTube video recommendations.
In this lesson we'll learn two
very important concepts of
artificail intelligence,
constraint propagation and search.
We'll do this in a very fun setting
without going into too much detail
as we'll be studying these
concepts later in the course.
The setting is creating an AI agent
that will solve any Sudoku puzzle.
As you may know, a Sudoku puzzle
consists of a nine by nine grid
filled with the numbers
from one to nine.
The only rule that applies is,
in each row, column and three by three
sub-square, all the numbers from one
to nine should appear exactly once.
For example, here's a Sudoku puzzle and
here's its solution.
The goal of this lesson is to build and
code an AI agent that solves any Sudoku.
The algorithm fully used are based from
the great blog post of Peter Norvig,
one of these nanodegrees instructors.
You can find the link in
the instructor comments below.
At some points throughout this lesson,
I'll be doing the work.
And others, you'll be jumping
in to answer quiz questions and
to actually call some of
these functions in Python.
After the lesson, you'll complete
a project that allows you to more fully
develop and code a number of
extensions to the algorithm.
When you submit the project you'll get
a code review with feedback from one of
our talented reviewers.
Here is what the final
output will look like.
Pretty cool, right?
So, what do you say?
Let's get started.