Let's revisit our donuts
array from earlier.
If you recall,
we created an array of strings where
each string represents
a donut in our donuts array.
Now, another way of saying
this is that each string or
donut, is an element
in our donuts array.
The element is kind of an overloaded
word because it's also used to talk
about HTML elements or tags but
elements in arrays are different.
The word element is used to signify the
individual pieces of data in an array.
Also, we have a way to access
each element in an array
by referencing its
location in the array.
The name that you used to refer to
an element's location is its index.
If you remember back to our
lesson on data types and
variables, we could refer to a specific
character in a string by its index.
Arrays work the exact same way, so
just like strings, each element in the
array is numbered starting from zero.
And we can just use those
numbers our indices,
to access whatever value
we want in the array.
For example, the first element
in the donuts array is glazed,
the second element is chocolate frosted,
the third element is cinnamon.
And this process is going to
continue until we get to our last
element in the donuts array,
which are these chocolate donuts holes.
Now the syntax for
this is just the name of the array.
The opening and closing brackets, and
the index of the element
we want to access.
This gives us a much
better way to organize and
keep track of all
the donuts in our shop.