So here's my getGeofencingRequest method
that returns
a GeofencingRequest objects.
I'm going to create
a GeofencingRequest.Builder called
builder.
And to this I call two methods.
First is to set the initial trigger.
And I'm going to set that my initial
trigger is an INITIAL_TRIGGER_ENTER,
which is a notification when
the Geofence is added and
if the device is already
inside that Geofence.
Then I'm going to add the Geofences
that I want to monitor and
that's just my mGeofenceList.
I call addGeofences to add them to it,
and
then I returned builder.build to get my
GeofencingRequest back to the caller.
It's as simple as that.