So the main steps again are in video
stabilization are estimating camera
motion, stabilizing camera paths and
then being able to resynthize them.
Let's look at each one of them.
So let's start off with first
step estimating camera motion.
Here we will actually talk a process
that we've looked at before.
To estimate camera motion,
we need to find features and
then we need to take those features and
track them over time.
So, again, what we can do is we
can basically find image corners.
Remember, what we did and
we were talking about feature detection.
Look at points that have a high gradient
in both x and y, that's a corner.
And using that corner with the fact that
we want to do is we want to track hem
over time.
And here, you basically see
a lot of these green lines.
Basically, these green lines are saying
is okay, this point was here in this
frame and moved to this one and
that starts, if you're noticing,
give me very good motion,
even when I'm zooming in and out.
You can see motions very
clearly going on as to where
the different parts of the region are
changing with respect to how I'm moving.
Or in this case,
even zooming the camera in and out.
Of course, the camera's going through
translation, some rotation and
scale here.
Couple of things we have
to note when we do this,
we have to start differentiating between
background motion and foreground motion.
So for example, in this case, if
you'll notice there's a car coming in.
We want to be able to differentiate
between the motion of the background
itself and
some of the foreground elements.
We don't want our camera to be
dominated by the car moving.
We want to be able to lock in do
the background pixels itself, so
we have to do a little bit of
separation of foreground and
background in this analysis.
So we only, I want to estimate
the motion of the background,
because that's the one
we want to stabilize on.
And we want to basically be able to kind
of create some sort of way to separate
out the foreground by,
with the background by giving
more weight to the background.