There are other possible metrics,
there's a very long list
of possible metrics.
But I just wanted to throw down one
more, which is, let's say that we want
to pull down a non-near optimal arm,
epsilon, no more than tau double
prime k, epsilon, delta times
with high probability, 1-delta.
So basically the number of times that
you pull an arm that's not nearly
optimal is small.
And there's over no
particular time window.
It could be over a very very long
time window, but the number of pulls,
the number of mistaken
pulls is really small.
>> Okay, well that makes sense so
basically I want to minimize
my mistakes kind of.
>> Yes,
that's a good way to think about it or
at least bound, this is mistake bound.
This is number of reward and this is,
you know, identifying your output more.
And it turns out that all of these
guys are actually equivalent
in a sense that an algorithm for one
gives us an algorithm for the other two.
>> Oh, well that's good.
>> All right,
let me tell you about that then.