[Thrun] Remember in Laplacian smoothing our best estimate
is the count of the occurrence of the words divided by N,
but we add our Laplacian smoother over here,
and down here we add K times number of classes.
For the movie prior we have 3 examples of movie titles over 6 total titles,
which gives us 3 over 6.
We add our Laplacian prior, 1 over here.
There's 2 classes, movie and song, 2 over here.
We get 4 over 8, which is a half.
The same is the case for song.
It gets more interesting for this probability over here.
In our movie class there's 2 occurrences of the word "perfect" out of 8 words,
so we get 2 over 8.
But in adding the Laplacian prior, 1 over here
and 1 number to add down here,
the number of classes here is the size of the vocabulary.
In total for this model there is 11 different words.
There are 16 total words in both titles,
but because of repetition there's only 11 distinct words:
a, perfect, world, my, woman, pretty, day, electric, storm, another, rainy.
So we add the number of classes over here, which is 11.
We obtain 3 over 19.
For the song class there's 1 occurrence of perfect.
Adding 1 we get 2 over 19.
There's no occurrence of storm in the movie class.
However, our Laplacian prior gives us 1 over 19.
And there's 1 occurrence of storm over here, which gives us 2 over 19.