One of the neat things you can do with
this kind of analysis is to inform
the design of computer architectures.
Let's look at a simple example.
Suppose your computer architecture
colleague wants to build a machine that
does deep learning better.
As you probably know, deep learning is
kind of a synonym for neural networks,
which pop up in machine learning.
Take my OMS class on machine learning.
It's totally deep, man.
So, suppose you have
machine that's really,
really good at matrix multiply
at a particular size.
Now, suppose that in the next generation
machine, the balance doubles.
Recall that the machine balance is
defined to be alpha divide by tau.
Alpha is the time to a transfer
from slow memory to fast memory.
And tau is the time to do
an operation once the data is local.
The fact that balancing
has doubled is bad.
It means you have to be able to do
twice as many operations locally on
the processor, in the time that it takes
to move data from slow to fast memory.
So, if machine balance doubles then
your computation might slow down,
unless you compensate.
I claim you can compensate by
increasing the fast memory size.
My question is, by how much does z have
to increase in order to compensate for
the machine balance doubling?