In past lectures,
we have talked about the whole
concept of image transformation.
That is taking an image and
being able to transform it.
One standard way of doing that was by
doing filtering and of course what we
talked about was image warping, or
transformation in the last lecture.
Image filtering was aimed at taking the
information of the intensity values and
changing it.
While image warping or
image transformation was basically
changing the number of rows or
columns off the image, that basically
means the range of the function f,
in case of filtering, we were basically
changing the domain of the function.
So, just a recap, image filtering was
when we basically took an image, and
changed the range of the image, that is,
the intensity values to be
able to kind of change it.
In this case,
I've made it much more whiter.
And image warping or
transformation, basically,
we applied a functions
actually would change the,
the size of the image itself, the range
of the domain of the image would,
in this instance, means the number
of rows, the number of columns.
Domain basically,
is inside the size of the image itself,
while the range was
the values of the intensity.
So, basically, now we're actually
applying this to insides,
while in this case, we're applying it
to the function of the image itself.