Stuxnet, we're going to talk about
when we talk of malware,exploited some
zero day or vulnerabilities that
were not known at the time.
So the exploit zero day of course in
every system is not going to help you.
So it's not the first case.
It's not easy to guess passwords,
because you can't remotely access it you
had to physically get into the plant.
So it has to be the second option here.
It was an isolated network, so
the only way you can breach the air gap
is through a humans helping you do that.
So either it's poor
judgement by an employee or
an employee who was
a spy of somebody else.
So you really had to breach the air
gap to access the computers and
that requires that people
participated in this.