[Thrun] Particle filters are really easy to implement.
They have some deficiencies.
They don't really scale to high-dimensional spaces.
That's been recognized because the number of particles you need
to fill a high-dimensional space tends to grow exponentially
with the dimensionality of the space.
So for 100 dimensions it's hard to make work.
But there are extensions.
They go under really fancy names like Rao-Blackwellized particle filters
that can actually do this, but I won't talk about them in any detail here.
They also have problems with degenerate conditions.
For example, they don't work well if you only have 1 particle or 2 particles.
They tend not to work well if you have no noise in your measurement model
or no noise in your controls.
You need this kind of to remix things a little bit.
If there is very little noise, you have to deviate from the basic paradigm.
But the good news is they work really well in many, many applications.
For example, our self-driving cars use particle filters for localization and for mapping
and for a number of other things.
And the reason why they work so well is they're really easy to implement,
they're computationally efficient in the sense that they really put the computational resources
where they are needed the most, and they can deal with highly non-monotonic
and very complex posterior distribution that have many peaks.
And that's important. Many other filters can't.
So particle filters are often the method of choice when it comes to building quickly
an estimation method for problems where the posterior is complex.