The first pair of equations
define the same plane.
In fact, you can obtain the second
equation from the first
by multiplying through by
the common factor negative 2.5.
The second pair of equations
are neither parallel nor equal.
The coefficients of the variables
in the first equation cannot
be transformed into the coefficients
in the second equation
by multiplying by a common factor.
So the normal vectors for
the two planes are not parallel, meaning
that the planes are not parallel.
Since equal planes must be parallel this
means the planes aren't equal either.
The third pair of equations
define parallel planes.
If you just consider the coefficients
of the variables in the first equation,
dividing them each by a factor of three
will give you the coefficients of
the second equation.
This means that the planes have parallel
normal vectors, so they are parallel.
However, the planes are not equal.
Now the fun part of this is
that the code I wrote for
this problem is almost exactly the same
as the code I wrote for the lines.
The only difference I made is that
I use the variable P to stand for
plane, instead of L to stand for a line.
But, logically, my is_parallel_to and
eq functions are equivalent to
the functions for the line class.
And here's the test code I
used to answer the questions.
Running it gives me
the answers I showed earlier.