Here the example was this is my smaller images and
I want to generate a larger images like this.
Now, here we do a couple of additional things.
The idea here is you want to generate a larger image,
but we also want to capture the perspective.
There are only two flowers in this image which you can see them replicated here.
Replicated different ways here, but this allows us to
just like the strawberry image, we can actually do this across the thing.
But how do you make them smaller?
Well, what you can do is you can actually make smaller images of this.
Remember the pyramid representation that allowed us to look at different
aspects of different scales of an image.
Here we can actually now find smaller images and
add them into the representation and basically add a function that says,
as you go away on top, make the shorter one show up there,
because the four short mingle perspective is visible in that axis.
And that way now I can generate a much larger image, and
as I go further into the scene, the flowers get smaller.
And of course, you do see they are the same flowers, just merged differently.