Before we add a CursorLoader to our app,
let's first take a look on an example.
Here in the Android
developer documentation,
in the Running A Query with
a CursorLoader tutorial,
there's a quick example about
how to use CursorLoaders.
Our first step, is that when you
say define the activity that uses
CursorLoader and this means that we
need to modify the activity class so
that implements
the loaderManager.LoaderCallback.
Loader callbacks is a generic class and
that's why we need to specify
cursor here in between these
two angle brackets, and
that's because we're expecting a cursor
back as the result of the loader.
Next we need to initialize the query,
and
this can be done on either onCreate,
or inside the onCreateView methods.
This example shows it being
done inside onCreateView.
Inside this method,
we initialize the CursorLoader
using getLoaderManager.initLoader.
This method takes in the loader ID.
And this loader ID is simply
an integer that defines the loader.
In this case we define
the loader to have the value 0.
We could have used any
value in this situation.
Next up, we need to start the query.
In order to do so,
we need to implement the loader callback
methods required by that interface.
Remember that interfaces have certain
methods that need to be implemented
if we are to use them, and so far,
the set that we've seen looks
really similar to setting
up the AsyncTaskLoader.
Now the major difference Lies
in discreeting a loader.
Back in our AsyncTaskLoader example we
had a custom loader class that extended
AsyncTaskLoader.
And that's because it was a framework
class that was abstract and
that meant we need to extend from it.
Well in this situation,
works using CursorLoader.
And luckily the CursorLoader class
is not an abstract class and
that means we can directly use
it without subclassing it.
All we need to do here, is to create and
return a new CursorLoader
object instance inside
the onCreate loader call back method,
so similar to the code that's done here.
The input to the CursorLoader
constructor, this code here
looks a lot like the input to
the contact resolver query method.
Notice that we pass then a UI,
a projection, and
we could even pass in selection
details and assort order.
All this information is used
to define the exact data
that your CursorLoader
will eventually load.
What happens after concrete loaders
column and the query has started and
we get the information back.
Well it says down here.
Once the background framework has
the object, it starts a query in
the background and when the query is
done, the background framework class
calls onLoadFinished and this is
further described in the next lesson.
As noted down here, after the loader
has finished querying the data,
then this system will
call on load finish and
one of its inputs to onLoadFinished
is the cursor result from the query.
Let's take a look at what
happens when the query is done.
I'll click down here to
handling the results.
Earlier we just discussed how
an activity uses a CursorLoader using
the loader callbacks interface to
run a query in the background.
Now when that query is done, the cursor
result is returned back to the activity
via our onLoadFinished method.
Now, more specifically, if there's
an adaptor and a view in the activity,
the cursor is returned to the adaptor
to be displayed in the view.
This is what this code shows here.
Now, the last part of all this,
is deleting old cursor references So
the last part of this whole sequence
is that the CursorLoader needs
to be reset whenever its
cursor becomes invalid.
When does it become invalid?
Well it happens whenever
the cursor's changed.
For example,
if a pets weight is updated or
maybe a pet is deleted from the table.
Now before we query for the data,
onLoaderReset must be called and
this method removes any references
to the current cursor and
prevents memory leaks.
Remember that we need to
set up onLoaderReset so
that it can be called and it clears out
the adopters reference to the current
cursor helping to prevent
any memory leaks.
Now after onLoaderReset finishes
the framework can happily recreate its
data again.
Let's discuss everything we just
covered in a visual manner,
by summarizing how we run a query
with the CursorLoader and
handle the results
once we get them back.
Now, given an activity that implements
the LoaderCallbacks interface,
inside its onCreate method,
we're going to call initLoader.
The getLoaderManager.initLoader method
is put inside the onCreate method
when you want the load to start.
As a result, the onCreateLoader
callback method is called and this
is where you make a loader specifically
designed to return the correct cursor.
So, onCreateLoader creates
the CursorLoader for us and
in doing so, defines the data that we
want to query from the content provider.
This loading is actually done for
us off the main thread.
Now, after this happens, and
when the loading is done,
we trigger onLoadFinished.
This callback method, returns back to us
the cursor containing the loaded data.
From here, the cursor that we get back
can be passed into the cursor adaptor
using the swapCursor method.
So, swapCursor allows
you to change the cursor
that the adaptor gets it's data from.
And lastly, remember you need
to implement onLoaderReset.
This method is called when the current
loader is being destroyed and
the data in the most recently
provided cursor is invalid.
Hence, inside of onLoaderReset
you should call swapCursor
passing a null reference, so
that way the adaptor isn't left pointing
to a cursor left with old data.
Now it's your turn, and I want you to
make a CursorLoader for your pets app.
Here's how you get started.
In the CatalogActivity, after
extending from the AppCompatActivity,
use the implements keyword and
implement the LoaderCallback interface.
Now, after you implement this interface,
you might see Android Studio
throwing this error.
And remember this is because we are
implementing an interface which means
contractually we're tied to building out
certain methods from that interface.
And we haven't done that just yet.
To find those methods,
click on this red light bulb here.
Go to implement methods and
then this pulls in a list of
all the required methods.
Select those defaults and click OK.
What that did for us was pull in these
three methods here; onCreateLoader,
onLoadFinished, and onLoaderReset.
Now these are currently blank and
I'll leave these for
you to fill out in this quiz.
Now before I move on to
discuss the exact steps for
this quiz, let me go ahead and
show you what this finished product will
look like by the end of this exercise.
When we finish with this exercise,
this is what the app will look like.
Now I want to call it a certain thing.
When the app is running and
you go to the Menu, and you go to
insert dummy data, if you click on it,
the list won't automatically update.
This is because we'll need
to do a few more things
which we'll cover in the next
task to make sure that our loader
is smart enough to know when
to actually reload the data.
Currently in this state,
the list will only rerun if we
kill off the app and rerun it.
Let me show you.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Notice the dummy data was only inserted
after I killed off our app, and
then we run it.
And then this list updated.
Now for this quiz exercise,
I you go ahead and
switch to using a cursor loader
to help us load the data.
In order to do that,
follow these three steps.
First, modify the CatalogActivity so
that it implements the
loadermanager.loadercallbacks interface.
And remember to pass in
cursor as the generic type.
Secondly, implement these three loader
callback methods: onCreateLoader,
onLoadFinished, and onLoaderReset.
Also when creating a loader,
remember to use the pet content URI and
remember that projection should include
the id, name, and breed columns.
Lastly, I could modify
the CatalogActivity by
removing the displayDatabaseInfo method,
and initializing the loader
directly from the onCreate method