So now, we could do the total rigid transformations.
So a total rigid transformation, if I have some point in the A system,
I first have to rotate to get aligned in the B system, and then I
have to offset it by whatever the offset of the A system in the B system is,
that's what this equation says.
Using homogeneous transformation, or
homogeneous coordinates, we can do this all in one step.
So here, we have a rigid transformation and it's really nice, right?
We have our point here.
We've rotated it, and then we've translated it.
And what that says is we have this single matrix.
Right? This part here is a three by three.
This is a three by one.
This is a one by three of 0s.
This is just a 1.
So our total transformation matrix is a four by four.
And it does the, both the rotation and transfer, and, and translation.
Cool, right?
It gets better.
Thank God.
So here I've written what we had before.
We have P in the A frame, expressed in homogeneous coordinates.
Here is our four by four transformation matrix.
Here is B expressed in the B frame.
And I'm just going to write this as transformation from A to B.
But suppose I wanted to go from B to A?
Well, that would be written as transformation from B to A, and
I'd have the point P in the, in the A frame.
But the way to get that transformation is to
just invert the A to B to get me the B to A.
And then, this transformation takes the,
the value from the B frame back to the A frame.
And the idea is that our transformation matrices are,
homogeneous transformation four by fours, are typically invertible.
And so, once we have one that goes from, say, a camera to world frame,
we can go from a world to camera fame or, or, or the other way around.
And this invertibility of homogeneous transformations is very powerful and
used all the time.