Let's play with this Softmax
function for a little bit.
Let's say you have a classifier which
outputs three scores for three classes.
My question is, what probability
does the Softmax function give you?
Define the function softmax(x) to
compute the softmax probability values
given this set of scores.
Let's plot how the probabilities
vary as we modify the scores,
for example, of the first class.
Note that the scores that
are passed through the softmax here
can be an numpy array with one row for
each score, three in this case.
And some arbitrary number of columns,
one for each sample.
Your function should be able
to handle such input and
return a numpy array of the same shape.