It's just let's quickly review
the how to make an anaglyph image.
First take a greyscale stereo pair.
We copy the left image to the red
channel of the new image and
then copy the right image to the green
and blue channels of the anaglyph image.
That's cyan.
With, view through a red-cyan glasses,
left eye only sees the left image.
Right eye sees only the right image and
the brain fuses to form 3D, simple.
Now of course some of
you might be curious
as to why the glasses that we use in
watching 3D movies are no longer.
They used to be for
those of you who remember from
days earlier are red and cyan.
Nowadays they're different.
I encourage to start looking up that and
ask that question.
And figure out why that's the case and
what's different
nowadays in the cameras.
Both and also the display mechanisms
that actually work with different types
of classes.