If you've taken the OMS class in high
performance computer architecture,
then you might already know
the answer to this question.
Let's say I give you two
possible chip designs.
The first one runs at 4 gigahertz and
consumes 64 watts of dynamic power.
Let's also suppose that if you
run some program on this chip,
it finishes in a given time,
let's call it t.
Now suppose I give you
a different design,
the main difference is that it's slower,
it runs at 1 gigahertz instead of 4.
Now I want you to tell me two things,
what is the dynamic power of chip
two and what is it's execution time?
In terms of execution
time on the first chip.
For the dynamic power
consumed of chip two.
Express your answer in watts.
And for time, again, express your
answer symbolically in terms of T1.
As needed, assume that all other factors
between the two designs are equal.