First.
Symmetric encryption can only be
used to provide confidentiality.
This is false because symmetric
encryption can be used for
other security services.
For example it can be used for
authentication.
Suppose Alice and Bob share a secret.
Then Alice can use the shared
secret as the key and
encrypt message using symmetric
encryption algorithm and
send the message to Bob to
prove that she's Alice.
Second, public-key encryption can be
used to create digital signatures.
This is true.
Given a message we can
first hash the message and
then encrypt the message
using our public-key.
The encrypted hash value becomes
the digital signature of this message.
Third, cryptanalysis attacks try every
possible key on a piece of ciphertext
until an intelligible translation
into plaintext is obtained.
This is false, because what's described
here is actually the brute force attack,
or the spy research all
possible keys until
the ciphertext is translated
into a plain text.
Well as cryptanalytic attacks would
use knowledge of the algorithm or
the plain text such as the frequency
of letters in order to break a scheme.
In other words a cryptanalytic
attack typically
does not need to try every possible key.
Fourth, the secret key is input
to the encryption algorithm.
This is true.
An encryption algorithm takes as its
input, the plain text and a key.