From the if statement here,
we can see that the puppies route should
respond to get and post requests.
So we can add the methods here.
A get request to the slash puppies
route represents a request to view
all of the puppies
already in the database.
So get all puppies is
the appropriate method to call.
The post request represents making a new
puppy entry in our web application.
So let's return the make a new
puppy method accordingly.
When the puppy's route is accessed with
an integer variable, this represents
an operation on a specific puppy
that has already been created and
assigned an ID number.
So then get, put, and delete operations
can be used to read, update, and
delete a specific puppy entry.
So let's call the get puppy ID,
Update Puppy ID, and
delete Puppy ID for
this exercise .Solution code for
this activity is available
in the instructor notes.