Now, why doesn't
the general tree search or
graph search algorithm stop when it
adds a goal node to the Frontier?
The reason is because it might
not be the best path to the goal.
Now here we found a path of length 2.
And we added a path of length
3 that reached the goal.
The general graph search or tree search
doesn't know that there might be some
other path that we could expand that
would have a distance of say two and
a half.
But there's an optimization
that could be made.
If we know we're doing breadth-first
search and we know there's no
possibility of a path of length two and
a half, then we can change the algorithm
so that it checks states as soon
as they're added to the frontier.
Rather than waiting
until they're expanded.
And in that case, we can write
a specific breadth-first search team
routine that terminates early.
And gives us the result as soon as
we add a goal state to the Frontier.
Breadth-first search will find this
path that ends up in Bucharest.
And if we're looking for the shortest
path in terms of number of steps,
breadth-first search is
guaranteed to find it.
But if we're looking for
the shortest path in terms of total
cost by adding up the step costs,
then it turns out that this
path is shorter than the path
found by breadth-first search.
So let's look at how we
could find that path