We're going to be implementing the
methods of a pet provider shortly but
let's recap what we've
learned about URIs so far.
So we've decided that there are two
types of content URIs in our pets app.
So there will be one that
operates on the whole pets table.
And another one that operates just
on a single row of the pets table.
And we do so
by appending the row id to the URI.
And most recently you've
modified that to add contents for
these URIs in the pet content file.
Now to start figuring out how
to implement the provider,
we're going to zoom
into the details here.
Of exactly how the provider
interacts with the data source.
In our case our data
source is the data base.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
All we know that the URI code, so
in this case the catalog activity will
perform an action such as try the query
the content resolver for a pet URI
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The content resolver will realized
that the pet URI has the pet content
authority and then send the request over
to the correct pet provider in order to
handle this.
Now at this point it's up to our
provider to determine how to handle
request by either fetching or
modifying the data source as needed.
So for
to figure out how to handle request,
the pet provider utilizes
the URI matcher.
So the URI matcher determines what
kind of URI was passed to it.
And so that we can use that to figure
out which path we need to follow.
For example, if the URI is of this
first format then we go down path one,
meaning that we perform an action
on the whole pets table.
Whereas if the URI is of another format,
then we go down this path
where we perform an action on just
a single pet from the pets table.
Now here's another way
to think about all this.
So the URI is use by the activity,
the content resolver as
well as the pet provider.
And it's use as a signal for what part
of the data that we're interested in.
Now once we hit the URI matcher,
we use the URI to determine
which path we need to go down.
And once we make this decision,
the URI has served its purpose and
we don't need it anymore.
So from then we know exactly what
database table we're interested in and
we can interact with
SQLite database object
directly to help us interact with it.
Now in order to separate the behavior
for the different pads in the provider
we should list out all
the possible URI patterns.
So here we have the general content URI
for the pets table which ends in /pets.
And we also have have
the specific content URI just for
a single pet which ends in
/pets/ some row number.
So we were able to turn
this into a general pattern
by adding this # symbol here.
And this # symbol replaces
the number that should be expected.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So this # symbol is known as wild
card character where any length
integer can be replaced
into this spot here and
the URI will still be able
to match this pattern.
So now all the pet URIs will fall into
either one of these two patterns.
Anything else would not be recognized
by our pet provider as a valid URI.
So if the URI ends in something
like /petowner instead of /pet
then the URI won't be recognized.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So just to make it easy to refer to
these two patterns I went ahead and
picked out a unique integer code for
each one of them.
So here I have 100 associated
with this pattern and
101 associated with this pattern.
But I just randomly decided
to choose 100 and 101.
You could've easily started off
with one and labeled this one two.
So the only caveat is to make
sure these values are unique.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now instead of having to
remember the integer number.
Let's also assign an easily recognizable
name to each of these patterns and
that means you can call
it anything you want.
So I decided to call it PETS and PET_ID.
Now in our code, this means that
we've created a constant integer
variable called PETS,
which has the value 100.
And there's also a constant
integer value called PET_ID and
it's associated with the value 101.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So now that we have the names for
each of the paths we fork off into.
So in this case, the PETS case and
the PET_ID case,
we can go in either direction
based on the URI that we received.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So let's walk through
exactly how that works and
here's an end to end flow
using an example URI.
So say that the activity calls
the resolver query method,
with the general pet URI,
so ending in /pets.
So this request is passed
off into the provider, and
is passing the same URI here,
the one that ends in /pets
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now within the provider query method we
send the URI into the URI matcher and
it successfully finds a match with
one of the valid patterns our pet
provider knows about.
So thus the output of the match will be
the code 100 which equals
the constant PETS.
Knowing this we can query
the entire pets table.
So you see here how we use the URI to
determine what part of the data
source we needed to act on.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
All right, here's the second example.
So what if the activity
passed in a different URI?
For example,
this pet URI that ends with the id 3.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now, within the query method of
the provider we send the same URI,
the one ends with /3 and
send this URI to URI matcher.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So URI matcher recognizes that
this URI follows this valid
pattern that we do accept.
And it returns back to us,
the integer 101.
And this integer number maps
to our PET_ID constant.
Now having this information we know that
we should be querying a specific row of
the pets table.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So to help solidify what we just
learned, let's take a look at another
example of how the URI matcher works
within the contacts app example.
So as a heads up,
the contacts app example will
have a more complex database.
But no worries, we'll be walking
you through exactly how that works.
So say in the contacts provider
there's a lot of data about
all the viewpoint on contacts list.
And as a result, the provider offers
many different content URIs to access
specific parts of the data.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So observe the formats
of these patterns and
note how they are similar to
the pet URIs that we saw earlier.
So this first URI here ends in
/contacts meaning the contacts table.
The second one here ends with
the exact same /contacts but
it has the /# sign at the end.
I remember earlier I said that the pound
symbol is a wild card character
that can be placed with
an integer of any length and
the URI will still be able
to match this pattern.
So this integer will represent
a specific row in our contacts table.
Now this next line here
we see an asterisks.
So as an aside,
this new wildcard character is
something we haven't seen before.
But all it means is that we can replace
it with a string character of any length
as opposed to an integer,
which is what the pound sign was for.
Now some example URIs that would match
this pattern in the context URI would
end up being, /lookup/Adam,
so the name Adam.
Or perhaps /lookup/Diana if
the name Diana will inserted here.
However, for out pets case, we won't
need to worry about this symbol.
So I'll leave it up to you to finish
reviewing of these patterns here, but
they're just essentially combinations
of patterns that we've seen earlier.
All right, so moving on, let's assign
each of these URIs an integer code
as well as a constant value so
it's going to be easier for
us to refer to these code values.
So when we refer to the contacts case,
we know that the URI pattern
will be of this format.
And we'll be querying
specifically the CONTACTS table.
And if say we were to
refer to the DATA case,
we know that the URI is of this format.
And we'll be creating the data table,
which will contain details such as
the phone number, email addresses and
so on of our different contacts.
So given that information
that table when each type of
content URI is passed to
our content provider,
the URI matcher can help us determine
which database table we need to talk to.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So save the contact the editor activity,
calls the resolve query method
with the general contacts URI.
So here ending in /contacts.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Well, this URI gets passed to
the contacts provider within
the query method.
And we use the URI matcher to
determine what kind of URI it is.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So the URI has a contacts authority
which ends in slash contacts.
So the URI matcher returns the code
1,000, which is the contacts case.
And this means that will return
a query on the whole context table.
So say we have another example, where
the content URI ends in /contacts/5.
So this URI pattern ends with a row ID.
Thus the URI matcher will
return the code to us 1000,
which is the CONTACTS_ID case.
And from this,
we know that we'll be creating
a single row in the contacts table.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now for the content URI that
ends with /data while the URI
matcher returns to us the code
3000 which is the DATAcase and
this means we end up querying
the database table called data.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now for this last example,
where the content URI ends with /data/4,
we're going to substitute 4
with any other id number.
Well, given this the URI matcher
actually returns to us 3001
which is the DATA_ID case.
And we know that we were creating
a single row of the data table.
[BLANK_AUDIO]