Waiting for a computer game
player to make a turn is no fun.
After two seconds of waiting,
a human player is likely to
start thinking of other things.
We really need a way to
choose a move quickly.
>> Well, we can't search to end game,
but how deep can we search?
>> Let's assume, again, that we can
search 10 to the 9th nodes per second.
So in two seconds, we can actually
search 2 times 10 to the 9th nodes.
So I need to solve the equation,
8 to the x is less than
2 times 10 to the 9th.
We can do this by taking
log base 8 on both sides.
>> That log base 8 is pretty annoying.
>> Yep,
time to bring out some old math skills.
We know that log a of x is equal to
the log b of x over the log b of a.
So we can use that formula
to solve our problem.
We'll use log base 10 here for
convenience.
So we end up with x is
less than log base 10 of 2
times 10 to the 9th
over log base 10 of 8.
And we end up with x
being less than 10.3.
>> So we should be okay if we
only search 10 levels deep?
>> Provided that our estimate
of a branching factor of 8,
on average, is good.
To be on the safe side,
let's only go to depth 9.
This idea of only going as far as we
think we can to safely meet our deadline
is called a depth-limited search.