We have the same database that
we were talking about, but
we're going to do a different
kind of attack here.
We're going to de-identify it
by removing student ID, so
de-identification, you take
the database, drop the attribute that
is student ID, and, if there are names,
maybe we remove those, too.
Furthermore, the field that has the
state of the student because we just now
saw in the previous question that,
if there are too few students from
a given state that could be a problem.
So we're going to do generalization
by replacing state with sort of
the US region.
East Coast, Midwest, West Coast,
whatever way you want to do it.
We're not asking for a specific state.
That is too small and has only one or
a small number of students.
So this generalization is essentially
replacing state by a larger geography,
hoping that there'll be more students
who would come from the geography.
The generalization ensures that
there are at least two students from
each region.
The problem where we only had
one from Wyoming is going away.
Are inference attacks still possible?
Again, yes-no possibility,
so think about it.