You just finished your first lesson,
and you may be feeling excited,
or confused, or
intrigued, or frustrated.
But, before we continue,
I want to take a little time to
explain how learning to code works.
But actually, what I want to talk to you
about isn't just about how learning to
code works, it's actually about
how learning anything works.
But it's especially relevant to coding.
And if you really internalize what
we'll discuss in this lesson,
you'll be in a much better
position to learn programming.
Anything you learn, whether it's
a language like Spanish, riding a bike,
or programming a computer,
you always begin at the exact
same place as a complete novice.
And if you choose to put in the effort,
you can become an expert.
The problem is that there is a big
gap between these two extremes.
So, instead of treating learning as
an attempt to bridge this massive gap
all at once, it's better to think
of it as a continuum of expertise
that begins somewhere over here, where
you don't even know where to begin and
goes all the way over here, to where
you forget how it was ever even hard.
Right now, you're somewhere over here.
You're actually not a complete novice.
You've learned a bit, and
since you're in this nano degree,
you do have an idea of where to begin.
And learning happens whenever
you make progress this way.
Now, this is fine; you may not
understand why this is worth
talking about, and I'll explain
exactly why this way of thinking
about learning is incredibly
helpful in just a minute.
But, the explanation
will be much more clear
if you take a minute
to think of something.
In which you are an expert,
or at least a near-expert.
And you are an expert in something.
If you're having trouble,
your native language is something
you're probably an expert in.
But ideally, try to think of something
in which you've acquired your expertise
somewhat more recently.