[Narrator] So to start with some lingo about unsupervised learning.
If you look at this as a probabilist, you're given data, and
we interpretively assume the data is IID,
which means identically distributed and independently drawn
from the same distribution.
So a good chunk of unsupervised learning
seeks to recover the underlying--the density of
probability distribution that generated the data.
It's called density estimation.
As we find out our methods for clustering,
our versions of density estimation
using what's called mixture models.
Dimensionality reduction is also a method
for doing density estimation,
and there are many others.
Unsupervised learning can be applied to find
structure and data.
One of the fascinating ones that
I believe exists is called
blind signals separation.
Suppose you are given a microphone, and
two people simultaneously talk, and you're
record the joint of both of those speakers.
Blind source separation or blind signal separation
addresses the question of can you recover
those two speakers and filter
the data into two separate streams.
One for each speaker.
Now this is a really complicated unsupervised
learning task, but is one of the many things
that don't require target signals as
unsupervised learning yet make for
really interesting learning problems.
This can be construed as an example
of what's called factor analysis where each
speaker is a factor in the drawing signal that your microphone records.
There are many other examples of unsupervised learning.
I will show you a few in a second.