It is not actually necessary to go
through the kernel to get to a device.
For some devices,
it is possible to configure them to
be directly accessed from user level.
This method is called
operating system bypass.
We're bypassing the operating system and
from user level,
directly accessing the device.
That means that the device registers or
any memory that is assigned for
use for this device is directly
accessible to the user process.
The operating system is
involved in configuring this.
So, making sure that any memory for
register share data corresponding to the
device are mapped to the user process.
But then after that's performed,
the operating system is out of the way.
It's not involved in it, and
we go from the user process all
the way down to the device.
Since we don't want the user process
to go into the operating system,
this driver has to be
some user level driver.
It's like a library that the user
process has to be linked with
in order to perform the device
specific operations
regarding the access to registers or
device configurations that are typically
performed by the kernel level drivers.
Like the kernel level drivers,
this code, this user level drivers,
will typically be provided by the actual
manufacturers of the devices.
When bypassing the operating system, the
operating system has to make sure that
it still has some kind
of coarse-grain control.
Like for instance, enabling or
disabling a device,
adding permissions to add more
processes to use the device, etc.
This means that the operating system
relies on some type of device features,
like for instance, the device has
to have sufficient registers so
that the operating system can map
some registers to the user process.
So the user process can perform
the default device functionality like
send/receive if it's a network device or
read/write if it's a disk device.
But still retain access to
whatever registers are used for
configuring and controlling
the device that are needed for
these coarse-grain control operations.
If the device has too few registers and
it's reusing the same registers for
both the core data movement or
the core functionality,
as well as these control operations
that are needed to be performed by
the operating system, we can't do this.
We need to be able to share the same
device across potentially multiple user
processes.
So assign some subset of
the registers to different user level
processes to be controlled by different
user level drivers and libraries.
And still make sure that the operating
system has some coarse-grain control
over exactly how the device is used.
And whether something
needs to be changed.
Another thing that happens when multiple
processes use the device at the same
time is that when the device needs to
pass some data to one of the processes.
It is now the device that needs to
be able to figure out how exactly
to pass data to the address space
of process one versus process two.
For instance,
when receiving network packets,
the device itself has to determine which
process is the target of the packet.
If you think about what that means with
respect to the networking protocols,
that means the device has to
peek inside of the packet
in order to see what is the port number
that this packet is intended to do.
And then also it has to know which
are the socket port numbers that
these processes are using
in their communication.
So what that means is that
the device has to perform some
protocol functionality in order
to be able to demultiplex
the different packets that belong
to these different processes.
In general, it needs to have
demultiplexing capabilities so
that data that's arriving in this device
can be correctly passed through
the appropriate process.
In the regular device stack, where
the operating system kernel is involved,
it is the kernel that
performs these operations.
The kernel is aware of the resources
that are allocated to each process.
And the mappings that
each process has with
respect to the physical
resources in the system.
When the operating system is bypassed,
those types of checks have to be
performed by the device itself.