[Thrun] The answer is approximately 0.0142,
and it is an exercise in expanding this term using Bayes' rule,
using total probability, which I'll just do for you.
Using Bayes' rule, you can transform this into P of H given R comma S
times P of R given S over P of H given S.
We observe the conditional independence of R and S
to simplify this to just P of R,
and the denominator is expanded by folding in R and not R,
P of H given R comma S
times P of R plus P of H given not R and S
times P of not R, which is total probability.
We can now read off the numbers from the tables over here,
which gives us 1 times 0.01 divided by this expression
that is the same as the expression over here, so 0.01 plus this thing over here,
which you can find over here to be 0.7, times this guy over here,
which is 1 minus the value over here, 0.99,
which gives us approximately 0.0142.