So some assumptions I'm going to tell you now are,
the ones that we're going to use to drive a particular computational theory.
It's not clear exactly what assumptions your brain makes,
because your brain does some very complicated things.
But, here's some simple assumptions that we can make use of computationally.
So this first assumption is that, this light is slowly varying, okay?
So for sort of a kind of a plainer or, or smooth world.
That's not unreasonable.
The light falls off.
So we've got these beautiful lights here,
that Megan has set up to make me look gorgeous.
I look gorgeous, right?
Right Megan?
>> yes.
>> Thank you very much.
anyway, and as I move the light, change it a little bit.
Now we have some other light sources, but
the idea is that the light changes slowly as I move around.
In fact, even on a cast shadow, when you see these shadows here.
Right first of all they're not harsh because Megan's such a good videographer,
she set up these lights.
But also, because of the size of the light source,
there's still relatively slowly varying compared to say
the line between my skin and the shirt, all right.
So the light is slowly varying.
The next thing and this is somewhat more problematic,
is we're going to assume within an object or within a patch.
The reflectance is constant.
That's a little bit of a stretch,
because there's a question of how big a patch, et cetera.
So we have these things here, you see this texture, and
maybe you can say we're going to assume that this texture is constant.
But the idea is that whatever reflectance function we're going to use,
we're going to assume it's constant over a patch.
And that between objects, the reflectance changes quickly.
Okay, so that any smooth variation we see is due to lighting.
Any sharp variation that we see, is due to the texture, all right?
And that should give you a hint of how we're going to solve this, right?
We're going to look for changes.
And we're going to try to eliminate the smooth changes and
keep only the sharp ones.
Now this assumption is sometimes called the Mondrian world.
And if, if, I, I, I don't really know whether he's French, or must be Piet.
Must be so, that would be Mondrian.
My French is awful, so somebody, write in a complaint to Megan.
Anyway Piet Mondrian, a very famous artist started a bunch in contemporary art.
And you've probably seen his work.
He made these pictures that were just these constant intensity patches.
Now, his patches happened to be square, or rectangular, I should say, and
that was part of the deal.
But the idea is that, this is the model that we're going to make use of, right?
That our world is made up of patches of
constant intensity separated by sharp boundaries.
Now, of course, we're not going to use anything so
beautiful, he's an artist, but we're boring, so
we're going to assume that we've got objects that look like this.
Okay, so we're just going to talk about intensity today.
I don't have these black stripes between them,
I just have patches that have constant intensity.