Now, let's define what
scan actually does.
What is the scan operation?
So, there's three inputs to scan.
The first, is an array of length n.
The second, is an operator
a binary associate of operator.
For the purposes of explaining this,
we're going to soon that
that operator is plus.
And finally, we have an identity
element that's associated with that
particular operator.
So in this case,
the identity element is zero.
Let's keep in mind that this
discussion will apply to
any binary area associative operator.
So, our input is an array of length and
we start off by designating the first
element of the input as A zero.
Second element is A one,
the third is A two and so on.
And so, the scan operation will
produce an output, given these inputs.
What does that output
actually look like?
So the output at any given position,
is the sum of all the elements
that precede it in the input.
So, let's see how that actually works.
So the output at position zero is,
the sum of all the elements
that come before it.
Well there is no elements before it, so
the output is simply
the identity element.
The output at the first position here,
is the sum of all the elements
that come before it.
In this case,
there is one element that comes before
it, so that's copied over to the output.
The output in the third element here,
is the sum of all the elements
that come before it.
In this case the sum of A zero and
A one.
The output for the fourth element is,
simply the sum of all
the elements that come before it.
In this case the sum of A zero and
A one and A two and so on.
And so finally,
you reach the final element and
it is the sum of everything in the array
except for the very last value.
That's the definition of scan and
keep in mind again, that this will apply
to any binary associative operator.
Whether that be multiply, max, min,
logical operations like AND and
OR, and so on.
Let's do a simple example.
Let's take the sum scan of this
input array, [3 1 4 1 5 9].
So, how do we compute the output?
First we always start with
the identity element.
Then we start with the first element,
three and one make four.
Three and one and four make eight.
Three, one, four and one make nine.
Three, one, four, one, and five make 14.
So for our input here,
to scan to a sum scan is
314159 The output is zero,
three, four, eight, nine, 14.
Now, let's try doing example with
a different binary so sort of operator.
So as a little quiz,
let's make sure we understand.
Let's try a max scan on
an array of unsigned integers.
The same array of unsigned integers
three, one, four, one, five, nine.
Like to ask you two things first.
What is the identity element if we
do a max scan on unsigned ints?
And second, what's going to be
the output of this max scan operation?