The answer is none of these.
Start by writing down
the efficiency of the algorithm.
Remember that's speed up divided by P.
By the way, if you expand it,
you get this expression.
This denominator has a special name.
It's called the parallel cost.
So let's plug in these two times,
T star and T of n P.
And let's do a little algebra.
In this case,
I'm going to divide the numerator and
denominator by tao times n times P and
you should get something like this.
Notice that there is no setting of n
that will make E of n P a constant.
The problem is this first term which
goes to infinity as P increases.
In other words,
the efficiency will always tend to zero.
Here's a thought question for you.
Is a bucketing or
pipeline scheme possible?
And if so would it fix the problem?
Hmm.