So we're going to create two buttons.
One with the text load interstitial, and
one with the text
interstitial not ready.
Let's first look at the layout
file where these are defined.
So this is going to be in
the interstitial activity.
So we open the activity_interstitial
layout file here.
Here you can see a linear
layout that has two buttons.
The first button is our load button.
It has the text Load Interstitial.
And when we click on the button the
loadInterstitial method will be called.
The second button is the one
showing Interstitial Not Ready.
And when this button is called, the
showInterstitial method will be called.
And as you can see, I haven't
really hard coded the text here.
These are actually string
resources that we'll define in
our string resource file.
So if we look at the definition
of these constants,
we go into our Strings resource file.
The interstitial_load constant
is set to Load Interstitial.
The interstitial_not_ready constant
is set to Interstitial Not Ready.
I've also defined a constant called
interstitial_loading that I set to
Loading Interstitial.
We'll use that later in our code.
Here you can also see that we have
defined the interstitial_ad_unit_id.
This will be the ad unit id that
we use for our interstitial ad.
And as you can see,
I've hard coded it to this string here,
which is the string you can use
to display test interstitial ads.
Similar to this constant up here which
is the test ad unit id for banner ads.
All right, so
now when we have our layout file in
order, lets look at the actual code.
So we go into the interstitial
activity java file.
So first of all you can see that
we've added a member, mShowButton.
And in onCreate we call
our parent's onCreate.
Then, we set the content
view to the layout file
of the interstitial activity,
the one we just looked at.
We find the button using,
findViewById, providing the showButton
in the layout file as an argument.
And then we disable this button.
When the Load Interstitial
button is clicked, we,
again, disable the show button.
And then we change its text
to Loading Interstitial.
And, as you can see, this text is also
something we've defined in our resource
file, the interstitial_loading
resource we just looked at.
So we get this string resource
using getResources and getString.
And for now the show interstitial
callback will be empty.
We will add code to this callback later,
but as you can see, this callback
can't even be called right now because
this button is always disabled.