All right, so here we are in Android
Studio looking at our source code for
the main activity.
Let's go ahead and look at
the AsyncTask doinBackground method.
Now if you look closely at the code
here, you'll notice that we're
converting the string holding
the URL into an actual URL object.
Then in this try catch block,
we go ahead and
make an HTP request using the URL.
But what's a URL object?
What's this class?
Let's go ahead and look at
the Android reference documentation.
As introduced earlier,
URL is an acronym that stand for
Uniform Resource Locator and
it identifies the location
of an Internet resource which in our
case is a list of earthquake data.
Look at the Soonami app makeHttpRequest
method to see this in action.
Then answer this quiz question.
What's the data type of
the value returned by calling
url.openConnection method?
Write you answer here.