Peter is going to teach us about search.
While we already did a lot of
searching in the game playing section,
most search algorithms
are not adversarial.
Peter, why is search so important in AI?
>> Well to me,
AI is all about figuring out what to
do when you don't know what to do.
Regular programming is writing
instructions to make the computer
do what you want when
you do know what to do.
In AI, it's for when you don't know.
And search is one of the key areas
where we can figure out what to do
by planning a sequence of steps, even
when we have no idea what the first step
should be until we solve
the search problem.
>> When watching these lessons,
please pay careful attention
to the a-star algorithm.
It is one of the most famous AI
algorithms, and a lot of job
interviewers in the field will assume
you're familiar with its concepts.
Let's do a challenge question
to give you a preview
of what you'll be learning.