So welcome back to Computer Vision.
We're talking about doing tracking.
Now, last time we introduced this
idea of tracking as induction.
That is, if I know what's going on at
time t, or I have some belief about
the state of the universe of time t,
I make a prediction for time t plus 1.
Then based upon that prediction,
that might affect how I
go get my measurement.
I get my measurement, and it's noisy,
and I correct for t plus 1.
And that continual loop,
that's what we mean by tracking.
And we did a little bit of, sort of,
onerous mathematics where we talked
about, the prediction part
leveraged two things.
It leveraged our belief of where we
were the last time that makes sense and
all right, in terms of, we might believe
the position, we believe the velocity or
something.
And we had to have a dynamics model,
that is,
something that tells us how
things will change, all right.
So given some belief about how some
things were, and how some things change,
that gives me a new belief
about where things might be.
And then the correction, the,
the update, after we took a measurement,
remember we made use of Bays Rule.
And the idea is, we take the prediction,
we multiply that by a likelihood, and
we'll talk more about that,
not so much today, but next time.
And combining those and then normalizing
allows us to know the prediction,
our best guess now, of the state at
time t after the measurement at time t.
And that was referred to as
the posterior distribution.
So today, we're going to do a specific
case of what's called linear dynamics,
all right?
Where the predictions are based upon
a linear function of our current belief.
And we're going to assume that we've
got Gaussian noise both in terms of how
things might change, so we have
a distribution, we believe how things
might change plus there's some
noise added, Gaussian noise.
And furthermore we're
taking measurements and
our measurements are a function
of the state, plus noise, but
what kind of noise?
>> Gaussian noise!
>> Very good.
And we'll show a a simple
linear recursive filter called
the Kalman filter that's designed
to handle this nice clean case.