The answer to this is, yes.
They're different ways of
doing voice biometrics.
Either someone can record your voice and
play it, that's one way, or
they're also sort of voice synthesis
kind of attacks people can do
if they have some segment of voice
from you that can build a model for
you and so, similarly,
these could be repeated.
So just because it's something you are,
in the end we're extracting a set of
features from you that we
make available to the system.
If somebody else can grab
those set of values, well,
then they can fool the system into
believing that is really you, and
defeat the biometric indication method.
So, it's interesting read
how you defeat fingerprint,
the touch ID that users fingerprints but
similar tax people have explored on
voice space authentication and so on.
So yes we make hopefully we make
the task harder for the attacker but
there is never a full proof, completely
100% secure authentication solution.