Having defined a random variable,
it now makes sense to talk about
a random variable's average or
expected value.
Formally, we define the expectation
of a random variable X, like this.
We consider the set of
values that X could take on,
notating it as X of omega.
The image of the sample space under X,
and we sum over all these possible
values, giving each a weight according
to how probable the value is.
Thus the expectation
is a weighted average
of all the values that
a variable could take on.
For example,
let the random variable X be the number
of heads in three fair coin tosses.
Then, according to this definition,
this would be 0 times one-eighth for
getting no heads, plus 1 times
three-eighths for getting one head.
There are three possible tosses
that could've come up heads.
Also, 2 times three-eighths for
getting two heads.
Similarly there are three possible
tosses that could have come up tails so
as to give us two heads, and
lastly there's only a one-eighth
chance of getting all three heads.
Adding these up we get twelve-eighths or
3 over 2.
Now if I asked you casually how
many heads will there be in three
coin tosses on average.
You probably would have said
three over rather quickly
without doing all this calculation.
Each toss should get you half a head,
so with three,
you should get three halves,
you might have reasoned.
In terms of our notation,
we can express the argument like this.
We let Xi be 1 if the ith
fair coin toss is heads.
And we let it be 0 otherwise.
Then we say that the average
number of heads in three tosses
is the expectation of X1 + X2 + X3.
And this is the expectation of
X1 plus the expectation of X2
plus the expectation of X3 and
this totals to 3 over 2.
The key step in the proof
is this equality here,
which says that the expectation of
the sum is the sum of the expectations.
This is called the linearity
of expectation.
And as we will see, this turns
out to be a very powerful idea.
In general, for
any two random variables X and Y and
any constant a,
we have these two equalities.
The expectation of the sum is
the sum of the expectations, and
we can just factor out constant
factors from expectations.
Remember this theorem.