Here I've shown how to extend the language of classical planning to handle resources.
We've added a new type of statement saying that there are resources
and how many of each there are.
We can say there's five nuts and four bolts,
and we're also going to explicitly model inspectors, and we have one of them.
Then the actions have two new types of clauses.
The fasten action has a consume clause, saying it consumes resources
and once it uses them, they're gone forever.
Fastening is going to consume one nut and one bolt.
The inspect action has a used clause, and that says it's going to use one of the resources,
the inspector, while the action is going on.
But once the action is completed then the inspector has returned to the pool
and is available for use elsewhere.
Keeping track of resources this way gets rid of that computational or exponential explosion
of looking at different combinations by just treating all of the same resource identically.