All right.
So we can think about maximizing reward.
Or expected reward, or
expected discounted reward.
But over a finite horizon, instead
of this kind of infinite horizon,
like we talked about in number two.
And that's similar.
It's something that is
actually computable,
but can be very expensive to compute.
>> Sure.
So, how would you actually compute that?
>> That's a fair question.
Let's save that one,
because some of these problems
are actually going to end up being
reducible to each other so we won't
have to solve all of them independently.
We just have to relate them to
ones that are already solved.
>> Okay, well I will point out,
since I'm being meta,
that if the finite horizon is one
>> Then we know the answer.
>> Mh-hm, right.
So the finite horizon is one,
then chose the one that has
the maximum likelihood estimate.
>> Mh-hm.
>> That's fair.
And you sort of kind of generalize
that idea to do two Horizon of two,
horizon of three, horizon of four.
You could just kind of iterate it out.
It's a little bit like value iteration.
So now we're going to have
a slightly twistier definition.
So, what about a metric like this?
We're going to try to identify a near
optimal arm, and near optimal means,
well, we can be wrong by choosing an arm
that's epsilon close to the real arm.
Somebody's going to give us
an epsilon as a parameter, so
we don't have to get
the absolute best arm Mm-hm.
>> because that's actually
impossible to do in finite time,
because we could always be really
unlucky, and get just a strange sample
where the highest payoff arm just
happens to not have paid off for us.
So, we're going to soften it to
a near optimal arm, epsilon close to
the actual optimal arm, and this
doesn't even have to work all the time.
It just has to work
with high probability.
Probability 1 minus delta.
And the number of pulls before we can
identify or before we have identified
the near optimal arm needs to be
polynomial in the number of arms.
1 over delta.
1 over epsilon.
There's some polynomial.
We'll call it T.
Of K, epsilon, and
delta that bounds the number of
pulls before we can identify the near
optimal arm with high probability.
>> So
that T is not the transition function.
So you're not moving from state K to
state delta through action epsilon.
>> Oh, good point.
Yeah, that was probably
not the best use of T.
T here is supposed to be time.
Would you like tau better?
>> Sure, let's call it tau.
I like tau.
Cool, I like the tau.
All right, so I like four,
because it looks like PAC learning and
it looks like the kind of thing that
machine learning people come up with.
>> Yes!
Yes, it is a lot like PAC learning.
It is a very PACish sort of thing.
I had forgotten that we knew about that.
But that was in our other class, right?
Probably approximately correct.
>> Yeah probably approximately.
>> So there was one paper
that actually called this
>> PAO.
>> PAP.
>> Probably approximately optimal.
But that didn't end up sticking.
They call this PAC even though it's
not really a correctness thing,
it's not a classification.
But it, the rest of the flavor
of it is very much like PAC so
we just stick with that.
>> Well it's a classification if
the goal is to classify the best arm.
>> Yeah.
That's
a good way to think about it, sure.
So here's a metric that's
kind of like number four.
In that we're again going to have
some function of epsilon, delta, and
k, that is going to give us
a number of time steps, and
in this particular case,
instead of saying, at the end of that,
we're going to know what
the near optimal arm is,
instead we're going to say, we're
going to have nearly maximized reward.
Over that, that interval.
Basically, you give me an epsilon,
a delta, and a k,
number of arms, and I will make a
strategy and a polynomial tau prime, k,
epsilon, delta, such that,
if I run that long,
I will get at least this close,
I guess per step, to the maximum reward.
With high probability.
>> Okay, okay.
So, that's like there
was between one and two.
Where, instead of the goal being to
figure out what the best arm is,
the goal is to pick up as much
reward as possible on the way to
figuring that out.
>> Yeah, yeah,
that's a good way to think about it.
>> So, we're actually willing to take
longer to find the optimal answer so
long as we pick up more
reward along the way.
Could be, yeah,
could be that there's a trade off there.
It could be that these things
are relatable to each other.
>> At least, a little bit relatable
to one another because certainly,
if I can do five quickly,
I would probably do four.
>> Well, we'll work that through, but
I wanted to put these
up as separate things.
And then it turns out we can,
in fact, relate them to each other.
>> Cool.
But
if I had to choose between one of them,
I think I'd Prefer 5 to 4 just because
it does matter how I get there,
not just that I got there.
>> Yeah.
And certainly this
is going to deal more
directly with reward.
Look, it seems like for number 4,
we could actually potentially
do a lot of really terrible stuff for
tao, K,epsilon, delta steps.
As long as at the end of it we go,
And here's the right answer.
We could have sort of popped
up with our hand saying,
this is what I should have been
doing but haven't been doing.
[LAUGH] Whereas in number 5,
the money is where your arms are.
[SOUND] That's not right, but we're
actually getting nearly optimal payoff.
>> Okay, that makes sense, cool.
So I can't wait to see how you
relate all these things together.