So, why is the epipolar constraint useful?
Well, we've already said that basically, the epipolar constraint reduces
the correspondence problem to a one dimensional search along the epipolar line.
In this particular case, we have parallel epipolar lines,
we'll see that in just a minute, but the red dot on the left that's located in
the window of this beautiful chapel or whatever that is.
Is located somewhere, in this epipolar line on the right, so I search for
the middle of the window, I don't have to look all over the image,
I'm just looking along the corresponding epipolar line.
So what do epipolar lines look like, and we'll consider two cases.
There's the general case on the top, where we've got verged cameras, and
then there's this special case where we have parallel optical axes.