Here's my solution.
Yours might not be exactly the same,
but that's okay as long as it outputs
the same initial action based
on the parameters given.
I started by adding a new field,
the int numStates, to my FirstMDP class.
Then in the constructor,
I initialized this.numStates to 6.
Then, down in the bestFirstAction
method, I create a ValueIteration object
using the computeValue
method we defined earlier.
To extract the value of each state,
I start by using
the static getState method
from the GraphDefinedDomain class to
convert from integers to state objects.
Then I use the value
method of the object vi to
obtain the value of each
state object in our MDP.
These values are then stored in
the array V for easier access later.
Finally, I check to see whether V[1],
V[2], or V[3] is the largest.
If V[1] is the largest,
then I return the string action a.
If V[2] is the largest,
then I return the string action b, and
if V[3] is largest,
then I return the string action c.