Let's return to our polynomial
identity verification algorithm and
see if we can improve it.
So far we've seen how if
the two polynomials are equal,
then the algorithm will always say so.
But if the polynomials are different,
there's up to a 1 in 100 probability
that the algorithm will say
that they're the same anyway.
Maybe this isn't good enough.
We want to do better.
Well, one idea is to just change out
this number 100 for a larger number.
This works, but on a real computer we
might start running into range problems.
We don't want our algorithm to strain
the difference between the theoretical
models in practice.
Another solution is repeated trials.
Instead of just testing for
equality at one point,
we'll do it at several random ones.
Such an algorithm might look like this.
We start out by assuming that
the two polynomials are equal.
Then we try different values for x,
and if we ever find one where the two
polynomials are not equal,
then we know that they aren't.
Note that we could terminate as
soon as a difference is found, but
this version of the algorithm makes
the analysis a little more clear.
For simplicity,
we'll make this k equal to 2 so
that we can visualize the sample
space with a 2D grid like so.
The row corresponds to the value of
x chosen in the first iteration,
and the column to the value of x
chosen in the second iteration.
Now the size of the sample
space is 100d quantity squared.
And since there are at most
d squared pairs of roots for
the difference between A and B,
at most d squared of these possibilities
will make the algorithm fail.
We'll let F be the event that the
algorithm fails on unequal polynomials.
By symmetry we can argue
that all elements of
the sample space should
have equal probability.
So the probability of the algorithm
failing on two unequal polynomials
is just d squared divided
by 100d quantity squared.
Which is 1 over 100 squares.
That's 1/100th of the probability for
just one trial.
We can also make the argument by
following the actual process of
the algorithm more closely.
We'll let E1 be the event that the
polynomials are equal at the value for
x chosen in the first iteration.
In terms of our grid,
this subset is a subset of the rows.
As we argued before,
this probability is at most 1 over 100.
Similarly, we let E2 be the event
that the polynomials are equal
at the value x chosen in
the second iteration.
In the grid this corresponds to
a certain subset of the columns.
Again, these columns take up at most
1/100th of the whole probability mass.
We're interested in the probability
of both E1 and the E2 happening,
i.e., the intersection
of these two events
represented as the black
region in our grid.
What fraction of the probability
mass does it take up?
Notice that in order for
a sample to fall into the black region,
the first iteration must
restrict us to the blue region.
The probability of this happening
is just the probability of E1.
Then from within the blue region,
we ask what fraction of
the probability mass does E2 take up?
Well, that's just the probability of E1
and E2 divided by the probability of E1.
And we want to multiply this
quantity with the probability E1
to get the result.
This sort of ratio is common enough
that it gets its own name and notation.
We notate it like so, and we read this
as the probability of E2 given E1.
This is called
a conditional probability.
The interpretation is that it gives
the probability of E2 happening
given that E1 has already happened, or
that it's somehow destined to happen.
More specifically,
it is the probability that the second
iteration will pick a value
where the two polynomials are equal
given that the first iteration did.
Well, of course, this is the same
probability as E2 happening,
regardless of what happened
in the first iteration.
So this is just the probability of E2.
This condition is known as independence,
and it corresponds to our intuitive
notion that one event is
not dependent on another.
Substituting these values,
we find that this approach gives
the same result as the other one.