So what exactly is a StackView?
A StackView is a view that doesn't
display anything by itself.
Instead, it organizes
the views it contains.
Even though it uses
Auto Layout under the hood,
you don't have to directly
mess around with Auto Layout.
The StackView can organize
views in two ways,
horizontally as a row of views and
vertically as a column.
And that's all there is to it.
By combining stack views together, you
can create almost any UI that you need.
Such a simple concept.
Rows and columns and
all our problems are washed away.
Yet another brilliant example
of Apple's ingenuity at work.
Whoever came up with this,
it's obvious that the inspiring
spirit of Steve was with them.
>> [APPLAUSE]
>> Actually,
the whole idea was
borrowed from Android.
>> [LAUGH]