So we have clicked Andy provided us, and
we're not at the Google App Engine
download page.
Let's go ahead and
click on Google App Engine for
Python since that's the programming
language we will be using.
Look like it opens the window a little
bit, so we're going to scroll down.
And then we're going to choose
the operating system for our computer.
I'm using a Windows computer,
so I'm going to go ahead and
click on the Windows download link.
And we're going to want to keep that,
and
as you can see in the bottom left-hand
corner, the download has begun.
Let's actually scroll down and
click on installing on Windows.
So it looks like it gives us some
additional instructions, first we're
going to want to click on the link we
just downloaded once it's finished.
And two, we're going to need
Python installed on the computer
to use Google App Engine.
Since you already have Python installed,
we're good to go.
Let's go ahead and
click on that download file, and
then we're going to go ahead and run it.
Okay, we are at
the installation instructions.
We're just going to follow all
the instructions they have, click Next.
A short license that
we're going to read.
going to want to accept the returns
of the license agreement.
Continue forward.
Okay this page is going to tell
us where we're going to install
Google App Engine.
It's going to create Start Menu
shortcuts, a Desktop shortcut, and
add your path to the user path.
That just lets Google App Engine
know where you're installed.
Now, let's stick with
the default settings.
Click Next, and
then we're ready to install.
We click on Install and we'll wait
while it completes the installation.
We're going to click on Yes,
we do want to allow the following
program to install.
So I allowed Google App Engine
to be installed on my computer.
Make sure to do that, too, if you
get a pop-up, asking for permission.
Okay, it looks like
the installation has finished.
Let's go ahead and
run the launcher just to double
check that everything worked out.
So great, it looks like we've downloaded
and installed Google App Engine and
ran it successfully.
Let's move on.