Before this quiz starts,
I want to talk testing strategy.
First off, you want to make sure
that you're collecting clean data.
So, you should first quit any
other apps that you have running
besides the browser.
Along the same lines,
extensions can skew your results.
So, make sure you're running your
tests in an incognito window.
You should also recognize that
sometimes you may have several
bottlenecks in your code, and
they may be triggered in different ways
from different parts of the pipeline.
So, it's important that you focus on
the causes of bottlenecks more than you
focus on their symptoms.
And lastly, with any performance issue,
make sure you always measure first,
before you start to apply fixes.
There's no point in fixing
an issue you don't actually have.
And you won't be able to know how
well your fixes actually work
unless you've measured first, so
that you can compare the difference.
All right.
Well, now it's time for
you to practice your def tool skills and
take a timeline recording of the website
linked in the instructor notes.
Limit the timeline to just scripting.
And then start recording.
Click on the Switch Layout button and
then,
see if you can figure out where
the jank was caused inside the code.
Type your answer into this box.