>> David's example of a robot that knows how to assemble cameras, but
then is given the goal of disassembling a camera is a good example of
goal based autonomy. Earlier we had looked at, how an agent can go about
repairing his knowledge or reasoning or learning when it makes some mistake or
reaches a failure. But sometimes it is not so much that the agent
reaches a failure, as much as it is that the agent is given a new goal.
When the agent is given a new goal, we do not want the agent to just fall apart.
We do not want brittle agents. We want agents that can then adapt their
reasoning methods and their learning methods to try to achieve the new goal.
Even if they were not necessarily programmed to achieve that goal.
We know that human cognition is very robust and flexible. You and
I address a very large number of tasks, a very large number of problems and
achieve a very large number of goals. If we are to design human level,
human like AI agents, then those AI agents will have to be equally robust and
flexible. Metacognition provides a powerful way of achieving that robustness and
flexibility. It does so by flexibly, dynamically,
selecting among competing strategies. It does so, reflexively and
dynamically, integrating multiple strategies as the problem solving evolves.
It does so, by using reasoning strategies and
knowledge that were programmed into it to achieve new goals.