Did you know each Boeing 747 has
more than 170 miles of wiring?
These are extremely complex machines
with a variety of redundant systems.
Navigation, pressurization,
air quality, and so much more.
All of these systems go
through a number of tests.
But did you know, that there are some
test that no airplane has ever passed?
When airplane manufacturers
design a plane,
they design the structure
of the wings to flex.
The manufacturer expects that
a particular design will flex enough to
withstand any turbulence
the plane may experience.
But when they test this design,
do you think they only flex
the wings enough to pass the test?
Nope, they continue to put
pressure on the wings,
flexing them until
the wing break right off.
It's a test that cannot be passed,
failure is the only option.
The important part is they defined
an expectation and they validated it.
That's all a test is, validating
an expectation about something.
During this course, I want you to
think about testing in this way.
Failing a test is not bad,
test failure tells you something, and
will help you build bug
free apps with confidence.