Now that we have talked about
number of defenses against
buffer overflow attacks,
let's look at some questions that
help us understand what these defenses
can do for us and what they cannot.
So the defenses that we talked
about included stack canaries,
address based loud randomization.
So, the first two questions about that,
and the third question is whether
a certain buffer overflow vulnerability,
read only kind in this case,
would be avoided, or would go away, when
we can't execute code off the stack.
So look at the defenses and
what they can do for
the kind of exploits we
talked about before, and
once you have a chance to do that we'll
come back and talk with the answers.