All righty, remember I'm not going to
go over everything that could be fixed,
because A,
that'd be like a 30 minute video.
And B, there are so many different
solutions to this problem that
it's really unlikely that your code
in the end looks anything like mine.
So here are a few of the high
level problems that I fixed.
Check out the links in the instructor
notes to see my full fixed,
along with the description
of all the known bugs.
Okay, so here we go.
Even without opening DevTools, it's
pretty obvious that this slide in and
slide out motion is a little janky.
You'll also notice that
scrolling is janky.
As these are the two major interactions
that users will have with this app,
I'll show you how I fix them.
First off,
I'm going to tackle the janky scrolling.
So what's going on here?
As I scroll down and
then back up, you can see that the
little indicators indicating how many
points each story has not only
changed size, but also changed color.
I want to see what that
looks like in DevTools.
I will start a recording, scroll
a little bit, and then stop recording.
In the timeline, it's pretty obvious
that I'm not hitting 60 frames per
second because here's the 30
frames per second line.
I'll zoom into one of these frames.
Oh boy!
This is a very bad sign.
Let me zoom in further.
You can see that after the scroll
event a function was called.
And then you've got a lot of layouts
with a lot of red triangles.
That is an excellent sign that a forced
synchronous layout is happening.
Sure enough, there is the warning that
forced synchronous layout is happening,
and it looks like it is
happening inside the function
called colorizedAndScaleStories.
I am going to jump into the source code
and see what this function's doing.
In the source code, I'm now looking
at colorizedAndScaleStories.
And from the comments, it seems like
this is probably a source of jank.
So, thank you Paul for
leaving these behind.
Take a look at this part of
the function, notice that a lot of
properties that cause the browser
to run layout are being accessed.
Then at the bottom of the function,
recalculate styles has to happen
because there's a new style applied.
These two combined are causing
the force synchronous layout.
And it's a huge problem for performance.
Now this begs the very interesting
question is this code even worth fixing?
The effect is, well,
pretty much negligible.
Having story points that
are different sizes and
different colors doesn't really add
anything to the app as a whole.
For instance,
are the one's higher up more
important than the one's lower down?
I don't really think so.
Ideally, this is the kind of effect
you couldn't possibly achieve with CSS
properties like scale and
transform instead of using JavaScript.
But I, to be perfectly honest,
think it is totally unnecessary.
So, I'm just going to
drop it all together.
Here's the result.
I got rid of all the calls to
colorize and scale stories, and
you'll notice that now all of
the points here look the same.
But more importantly, what effect
does this have on performance?
Let me show you.
I'll hit record and
then start scrolling.
Now look at that!
This is much nicer.
I see the scroll event and there is
only one recalculated style afterwards.
No big deal,
this is much more performant.
And that should be pretty
obvious from the timeline.
Next up,
there are a few other scrolling bugs.
I'm looking at loadStoryBatch.
It does visible work to the page
where it appends a new story to
the page as it's loaded.
But it's not inside
a request animation frame.
Ideally, anything that is making
a visible change to the page,
should be happening inside
a request animation frame.
So, I've gone ahead and added
requestAnimationFrame to the call for
loadStoryBatch, and that'll be
a nice little performance boost.
Now, I will take on the stories
that slide in, and then slide out.
You'll notice that the frame rate
actually doesn't look
awful on this computer.
But on my phone,
it's pretty much unusable.
And actually, on my laptop,
these bars looked a lot worse.
So, it's worth tackling.
It looks like the slide in,
slide out motion is firing a timer,
which doesn't quite look right.
And you'll also notice that there's
a force synchronous layout down here.
All in all, it's worth
investigating what's going on here.
Looks like line 180 in
app.js is being called.
So, I'll click on that.
And I can see that a function
called animate is happening.
I'll take a deeper look
inside the source code.
I'm inside animate now and first thing
I notice is that there's a set timeout.
Just like before,
this is visible work that's happening
outside a request animation frame.
So that's an obvious fix.
But then the real question is,
should this work even be
happening with JavaScript?
It's a simple transition that could
just as easily be handled with CSS.
Using some nice transforms and
will-changes,
it shouldn't be too difficult for
the browser.
And take a look at this.
Inside onStoryClick, a new storyDetails,
which is a thing that slides in
gets appended to the body every
time somebody clicks on a story.
Given the fact that only one story
will ever be shown at a time,
this is incredibly wasteful.
After a few clicks, the DOM is going to
be filled with a bunch of abandoned
nodes that are doing nothing but
taking up memory.
So, I wound up refactoring onStoryClick
to simply change the inner
HTML of the story details page instead
of creating a brand new one for
every story.
That'll prevent performance from
dropping in the long run, but
it doesn't speed up the slide in,
slide out motion.
So, I want to take a closer
look at what's happening there.
I'll start with DevTools.
I'll turn on the JavaScript profiler.
Start recording.
And then slide in.
And then slide back out.
Just like I saw before, onStoryClick
is causing a forced synchronous layout.
So I want to figure out a different
way to create the slide in and
slide out effect.
I'm inside the function
called showStory.
It looks like it's causing the forced
synchronous layout with the call to
left, which causes
the browser to run layout.
And then the call to style.left,
which causes the browser
to run recalculate styles.
If this happens more
than once in a frame,
you've got a forced synchronous layout.
I could refactor this in some way,
but honestly,
I just don't want to deal with it.
So, I'm going to go ahead and
do this with CSS instead.
So, what I decided to do is refactor
showStory and hideStory which work
the same way, with a couple changes
to the classes of storyDetails.
I'm simply adding and removing
classes called visible and hidden.
I'll show what this looks like in CSS.
I'm looking at story
details inside app.css.
I've deleted a few things here,
just to make it easier to show
you everything that I want to.
Notice this property left at 100%,
this pushes the story
details page off the screen.
So what I wind up doing with visible and
hidden is transforms to translate the x
position, either all the way to the left
or back to it's original starting point.
I've also gone ahead and given
story-details the will-change transform.
Just to let the browser know that
the story details will be sliding
back and forth.
To achieve the animation I've added
transition transform with 0.3 seconds.
So, it'll take 0.3 seconds for story
details to come in or slide back out.
Looking at these properties, you'll
probably see a few differences from
where you started and that's because
I got rid of the opacity changes,
because I didn't think they
were really doing anything.
I think I've done a lot, but of course,
the only way to really know for
sure is to record a timeline trace.
That looked a lot better and
the timeline is showing
that that was a lot better.
All the bars are well
below the 60 fps line.
I no longer need any JavaScript to
animate the slide in and sliding out.
And all the force synchronous
layout warnings are gone.
That is awesome news.
Everything's looking a lot better, but
there's still a lot
more that can be done.
For instance,
the CSS in the app could be improved and
some of the story loading could
be off-loaded to web workers.
Once again, see the instructor notes for
my full solution as well as some other
fixes that you might want to try.
So then, does your app outperform mine?
Did you do yours totally differently?
Post your optimized apps in
the forums because I can not wait
to check them out.