It's great that Firebase
authentication gives us a way to keep
all of our user
authentication in one place.
It provides multiple ways for
users to sign in such as with password
authentication, Google Sign-In,
Facebook Login, Twitter, and GitHub.
Adding sign-in to your app
sounds pretty basic, but
it actually takes a lot of work to not
only get the user experience right, but
also to keep your user
credentials safe and secure.
Firebase authentication saves you from
all the headache, as we shall see.
Firebase gives you the flexibility to
choose your own authentication scheme,
whether that's with email and
passwords, Google, Facebook, or others.
But you would still have to implement
that authentication scheme for
each provider as well as create
user facing screens for signing in.
There's a better way though that
saves you development time,
which is just what we need this weekend.
It's called FirebaseUI.
FirebaseUI is an opensource library
created by the Firebase team.
It handles the UI flow for
authenticating with Firebase.
Implementing the best practices for
sign-in and
following the brand guidelines for
each of the providers.
It also allows us to easily enable and
disable providers literally
by changing one line of code.
At the time of this recording,
FirebaseUI supports passport
authentication, Google sign in and
Facebook log in,
which is just fine for friendly chat.
Using FirebaseUI allows you
to focus more in the features
that make our apps special.