You remember how problem solving works.
We have a state space like this and
we're given a start space and
a goal to reach and
then we search for a path to find that
goal and maybe we find this path.
Now the way a problem
solving agent would work
is first it does all the work to
figure out the path to the goal.
Just doing by thinking.
And then starts to execute that path.
To drive or walk, or
however you want to get there from
the start state to the end state.
But think about what would happen
if you did that in real life.
If you did all your planning ahead of
time, you had the complete goal and
then, without interacting
with the world.
Without sensing it at all you
started to execute that path.
Well this has in fact been studied.
People have gone out and
blindfolded walkers.
Put them in the field and
told them to walk in a straight line.
The results are not pretty.
Here are the GPS tracks to prove it.
So we take a hiker, we put him at
a start location, say here and
we blindfold him so that he can't
see anything in the horizon but
just has enough to see his or
her feet so that they
won't stumble over something and tell
them execute the plan of going forward.
Put one step in front of each other and
walk forward in a straight line and
these are the typical paths we see.
Start out going straight for a while.
But then go in loop de loops.
And end up in not at
a straight path at all.
These ones over here, starting in this
location, are even more convoluted.
Yet, going straight for a little bit,
and then go in very tight loops.
So, people are incapable
of walking a straight line,
without any feedback
from the environment.
Now here, this yellow path,
this one did much better.
And why was that?
Well, it's because these paths
were on overcast days and so
there was no input to make sense of.
Whereas in this path,
was on a very sunny day.
And so even though the hiker
couldn't see farther than a few feet
in front of him, he could see shadows.
And say as long as I keep the shadows
pointing in the right direction
then I can go in
a relatively straight line.
So the moral is we need some
feedback from the environment,
we can't just plan ahead and
come up with a whole plan we've got
to interleave planning and executing.