It's often convenient to build
different Variants of your app.
A free version, and a pay version
is the most obvious example, but
you also want a de-bug version of your
app for development purposes, and
a release version for when your
app is ready for the play store.
Instead of constantly needing to
maintain separate code-bases for
every Variant, we can simply write the
code that is unique to each Variant and
Gradle will take care of the rest.
A Build Variant is a cross product
of two components, a Build Type and
a Product Flavor.
The two are mechanically similar,
but conceptually orthogonal.
Build Types are typically
transparent to users and
are only important to
you as a developer,
whereas Product Flavors control
features that are visible to end users.
Build Types are used to control
how our app is built and packaged.
By default, every Android app has
two Build Types, debug and release.
As the name implies, Debug Build Type is
primarily used during development, and
the Release Build Type is for
production.
Also, by default, the Debug Build Type
is compiled with debug symbols and
signed with a debug key, which allows
us to install on a development device.
You can also define additional
Build Types, for example, for
quality assurance testing.
Product Flavors are used to create
Variants that will be user facing.
Product Flavors will typically map one
to one with a place door download.
A very common case is an app
with free and paid versions.
Together, Build Types and Product
Flavors create a matrix of Variants.
With Debug and Release Build Types, and
free and paid flavors,
you get a two by two matrix of Variants.
In this case, we have Variants.
Free Release and free Debug, and
paid Release and paid Debug.
Let's check out how to declare and
configure Build Types and
Product Flavors in our Gradle build.