With your editor and
your browser output side by side, you'll
need to do a lot less context switching.
Usually you'll need to reload the page
manually and trigger the build process
again after you've made some
changes to the source code.
If your build system is doing this for
you, you can save a lot of time.
While the actual time of the rebuild or
reload of your page doesn't change,
the reload is done automatically.
So, by the time you focus on the output,
you've saved a couple of
seconds of contact switching.
Even though it might feel faster
due to the automatic reloads,
the build process
actually isn't sped up.
It's your brain.