Second, will need to add a few
things to the Android Manifest.
GCM requires several permissions.
Sunshine is actually already requesting
one of these which is Internet, which we
obviously will use to communicate
with Google and with our fake server.
So, we can go and
check this one off the list.
The next permission is Wakelock,
which is technically optional
depending on whether you want to keep
the processor from sleeping
when you receive a message.
We are going to include it however,
because the receiver that we will use to
get the downstream messages
is the provided GCM receiver,
which extends from
WakefulBroadcastReceiver.
Unless you intend to write
your own receiver and
to not use a WakefullBroadcastReceiver,
this permission is not optional for you.
The Receive permission is what allows
our app to register to receive messages.
So you obviously need this one.
And finally, the message permission
is a custom permission made
using our package name so that no other
Android app can register to receive
messages intended for our app.
Those sneaky little eavesdroppers.
So first you'll need to actually
declare the permission.
And then you can register to use it.
Beyond the permissions,
we'll need to inform the app of four
new classes that we will be using.
The first is a declaration
of GCM receiver
which handles downstream messages
sent via GCM to your app.
Because the service wants to receive
messages only from the GCM framework,
add the send permission for
Google Cloud Messaging to the receiver.
Note that we aren't requesting
a permission here but
requiring one instead.
Requiring this permission means that
anything trying to send a message to
this receiver must provide
the send permission which
ultimately protects our receiver
from bugging and senders.
If you want to support
pre 4.4 KitKat devices,
you'll need to add an additional action
not just for receiving but now also for
registration to the intent filter
declaration for this receiver.
But once you have all of this,
you're good to go on this declaration.
Then we have a declaration of
a GcmListenerService which enable
various aspects of handling messages
such as detecting different downstream
message types,
determining upstream send status, and
automatically displaying simple
notifications on the app's behalf.
And that is our second class down.
Finally, we have to create a service
that extends InstanceIDListenerService
to handle the creation, rotation and
updating of registration tokens.
So this is a big one.
These are all of the required
classes that we need.
However, I am also going to have
you add one more declaration for
a helper service,
which we will discuss later.