In the comparison table we showed you,
we said that ArrayList is a class and
you need to call methods to access and
modify elements of the list.
So now let's discuss the ArrayList
class in more detail and
how you interact with it in code.
So we start by opening up the
documentation page for the ArrayList,
and at the top it says public class
ArrayList extends AbstractList.
This extends keywords means that we
inherit a bunch of behavior from
the AbstractList class for free.
So let's click open
the AbstractList class.
This page says that the AbstractList
class is an abstract class.
And remember that an abstract class is
partially implemented, meaning that it
has some methods implemented and
some methods that are left blank.
Looking at the class definition further
we see that it extends another class.
Here it says,
extends AbstractCollection.
But we won't go into those details now.
What I do want to point out is
that AbstractList implements
the list interface.
I'm going to click that link
to open up the list interface.
So through these long chain of
inheritances I want you to know
that the initial ArrayList actually
implements the list interface.
The list interface was defined in Java
as some general behavior about lists.
Reading through the description, it says
that a List is a collection of elements
that maintains an ordering amongst them.
Each element has an index, so
you can access the element
based on the index position.
In the last class, we talked about
interfaces, and how they can be used to
find a contract with expected methods,
inputs, return values and method names.
But the interface doesn't specify how
each method should be implemented.
So the List interface
has abstract methods,
like the add method, the get method for
accessing elements at specific indexes.
It also has the remove method and
many others that you see here.
Well since the realist class implements
Implements this list interface
it has to provide an implementation for
each of these methods.
And as you'll see shortly,
you can call all these methods
on an ArrayList object.
Now the reason it's useful for
a list to be an interface
is because there are many
other types of lists in Java.
Now we won't cover all of
them in this course, but
to name a few there's linked lists,
stacks, vectors and others.
So hence there is a purpose for
having a predefined contract
in the list interface.
So to map out what we just talked about,
here's an updated version of that
diagram with the ArrayList class,
abstract class and List interface.
So List here is an interface and
there's no implementation
of any of it's methods.
AbstractList is an abstract class and it
has some methods partially implemented.
ArrayList is a concrete class and
it has state and implementation for
all of its methods.
So we can create an object instance of
the ArrayList and use it in our app.
However we can't create instances
of the abstract class or
the interface because those
are proper complete classes.
When using anything that implements
the list interface such as
the ArrayList class you'll notice
something about the method signatures.
So let's scroll down and
take a look at one.
For example in the add method, you'll
see a call for something called E,
for the ArrayList add method it says
the input should be an object of type E.
And if you take a look at
the get method we see that
it accesses an element of the list
at a given index position, and
it returns the value
of an object type E.
So, what is this E that is referring to?
Well, this brings us to a topic of
generics and generic types in Java.
The E is just a placeholder.
Officially E is called a type parameter.
Which means that when we actually create
an instance of the ArrayList, and
call these methods say add or
get on that object.
We can replace the E with
a particular data type.
So this would give
developers more information,
than if we just used a question
mark in place of the E.
So in this case,
E is short for element, and
where does the word element come from?
Well individual parts of
the collection are called elements.
Since these methods such as get and
add deal with elements
in a collection of data.
This is an appropriate substitution.
This E can be replaced by any
non-primitive data type that you'd like.
So instead of creating an ArrayList you
can create an ArrayList angle bracket,
E angle bracket of a certain type.
For example, you couldn't
create an ArrayList, of string.
Which means that everywhere you
see the E in the documentation.
In your case it will be replaced
with the String object data type.
So if you call the add
method on a string ArrayList
it expects a string as an input.
If you call the get method
on a string ArrayList it
will return a string data type.
So as a result the ArrayList
class is a generic class,
where the places that have a E specified
can be swapped out for a specific
object data type, when you actually
create an instance of the ArrayList.
There are other common type
parameter such as T, N and V.
And to see more check
out the text below.
All right, so I know we've covered
a lot of theory about how and
why the ArrayList came to be.
So now comes the relevant
practical information.
We've put together a condensed
list of commonly used
ArrayList method calls you can use, and
we're showing an example where we
use string as a parameterized type.
So everywhere you see
a string in this example,
you could potentially replace
with a different object type.
Notice the one difference compared to
creating an array is that when you
create a new ArrayList you don't need
to specify the link to the list.
To add and remove elements of
the ArrayList, we use the add and
remove methods respectively.
Now notice the difference of how to
retrieve information from an ArrayList.
The ArrayList doesn't use the bracket
notation that we used in arrays,
instead it uses the get method and
the index that we're interested in.
Remember for arrays we used array.length
to retrieve information about
the array's length attribute.
However, for ArrayList objects
we need to use the size method.
Note that there's no input parameters,
so it just uses empty parentheses, and
the return value of this will be
the number of elements in the list.
Now in the next exercise, I want you to
read through each line of comment and
write the code that would be used
to either create the ArrayList or
modify the ArrayList
according to the comment.
So here's an exercise to help you
understand how to better work with
an ArrayList.
Assume that these lines of code
live within a Restaurant App where
each user can maintain a list
of restaurants they want to try.
So write out the correct code
statements underneath each comment.
The first comment asked to create
a new ArrayList object called
restaurantsToTry.
And it will contain a list of Strings.
The next comment is to add
a restaurant called Morning Cafe
to the ArrayList that you created above.
The third comment is to add
another restaurant called
Barbecue Time to the ArrayList.
Fourth comment, is that the user has
just tried the Morning Cafe restaurant,
but we'd like you to remove that
restaurant from the ArrayList.
And the fifth comment says,
get the length of the ArrayList, and
then store as an integer variable
called numbersOfRestaurants.
All right, now go ahead and
give these a try.
And I'll see you back in the classroom.