So, here's the same idea
the Bellman Equations and
the learning update rule but
his time with actions.
>> Actions.
>> So, in the action form of it,
we have this Bellman equation,
the Q form of the Bellman equation
Q(s,a) equals the immediate reward plus
the discounted, expected value of the
maximum action in the resulting state.
Okay, so, when we actually land
in that new state S prime,
we choose the action that is best for
that state.
>> Right.
>> But otherwise, this is really
the same kind of update as before.
And so, we can translate this into
a TD0-like rule using the same sorts
of idea so that we're going to have
a new estimate of the value function,
and the way that we're going to change
it as we go from one time step to
the next time step as it's the same
everywhere except for the state and
action that we just left.
We just took action At-l and state St-1.
And so that one we are going to update.
We are going to move a little bit in the
direction of the immediate reward plus
the discounted value of the state
that we landed in St where the value
is taken- Is that better?
>> [LAUGH]
>> [LAUGH] It's taken with respect
to the best action that we
get from that state, okay?
So, this is, again,
the same update rule.
The only difference is we got this
extra little max in here to simulate
the idea of choosing the best
action from each state.
All right, so, what I'd like to argue
here is that this Q learning update rule
is actually taking care of two different
kinds of approximations all at one time.
So, let me step you through what those
are and then what we're going to do is
understand how each of them
works independently, and
then use a result that says if these
two things work independently,
they're going to work together.
So, all right, here's the first idea.
Notice that if we knew the model,
if we knew the transitions and rewards,
then when we go from some state,
take an action, get a reward,
go to a next state, we could actually
use that to update the Q values
simply by applying the Bellman equation
>> Right
>> All that's really happening there is
we take the old Q value estimate and
we update it in the way that the Bellman
equation says we should update it at
that particular state connection pair.
And so
we haven't quite argued that this works.
We said that it works but I want to dive
into a little more detail about why this
works, but I want to show that there's
a second kind of approximation that's
actually being used at the same time.
So, here's the second kind of
approximation that's going on with the Q
learning update.
It says that if we knew Q star already,
we could use that to learn Q star,
which now that I say it out loud,
seems kind of tautological.
>> I think, it, currently, is.
>> But don't mean it quite so directly.
What I'm saying is, let's say that we
run the Q learning update like this.
We say, we're in some state.
We took some action.
We got some reward.
We ended up in some next state.
We're going to update the Q value for
the state action pair that we just left,
moving it a little bit in the direction
of the reward that we just got,
plus the discounted value of the next
state, St, which for the purposes for
this little update rule,
we're going to use the actual
Q values to get that estimate.
So, we're kind of cheating here.
We're saying, we already know the Q
value at least for the next state, and
we're going to use that
to update the Q value for
this J action pair that we just left.
>> Right, and that would work because
since we keep applying truth to it,
Q star being true, eventually, you have
to kind of get closer and closer and
closer to it.
>> Yeah, and do you remember there's an
important property though that we have
to have in terms of this learning rate.
>> Proper subscripts?
>> No, you can get subscripts wrong and
you can always fix it in post.
>> Well, what's that property, Michael?
>> Yes, so what is the property?
This is just like in the TD row where
we looked at, where we said that,
if we have the learning rate
sequence sum to infinity but
the square to that sequence be finite,
then you know good things happen we
actually convert it to the right answer.
>> Right.
>> So, in this particular case if we
have, if we know what the target is,
if we know where Q star is
supposed to be for the next state,
we can use that to actually,
what we're really doing here is dealing
with the expectation over next states.
And we handle that by using next states
sampled from the distribution, because
we're actually acting in the world, and
instead of actually computing this sum,
we just do this successive averaging
thing and that's going to work out.
>> Right and so it's insanely
high probability you will move
towards the expectation.
>> Yeah, like, probability is seven.
>> Yeah, that's pretty insanely high.
>> That's pretty insanely high.
>> Yes, so
the piece that we really don't have yet
to build on is this first piece.
What is it that's making
the Bellman equation update
actually converge on the solution to
the Bellman Equations or Q star, and, so
we're going to prove that next, and
then we're going to show, or actually,
assert, that these two things can be
tethered together in such a way that
they're both going to end
up converging in tandem.
>> Nice.