Now that we have a general
overview of the lighting tab,
let's dive deep into the scene tab.
Starting from the top,
we have the environment lighting tab.
Remember the skybox from
the cameras lesson.
In that lesson we added a skybox
component to our camera, but
that resulted in us not
seeing it in the scene view.
If we want to see our skybox in the
scene view and be the default sky for
our cameras.
You can actually set the skybox here.
Now let's set the skybox to
the one we created last lesson.
Drag and
drop it into the skybox property.
Now if we zoom out,
it most likely doesn't look like
the red tint that we set up.
That's because Unity's procedural skybox
is controlled by having a directional
light that emulates the sun.
We can set it in the environment
lighting tab with the sun property, and
if nothing is set there Unity
defaults to the strongest intensity
directional light within our scene.
Let's open up the directional
light we created and enable it.
Now let's change it from
point to directional.
If your scene doesn't
look red like ours,
that's because we actually
need to rotate our light, so
that it's in a direction that's coming
from the top and facing our apartment.
Let's do that by rotating our sun
by 45 degrees in the x direction.
Awesome we now have our
skybox properly set up.
Now going back to lighting panel let's
look at the next property which is
ambient lighting.
Unlike any light we've discussed before,
ambient light is a light source that
affects all objects in the scene at
affix intensity and from all directions.
Basically think of it like
a 360 degree directional light.
We can send to be sampled from a skybox.
Gradient, or just a simple color.
And for our purposes with the apartment,
we'll just want a simple color.
Once we set the color, we can then
change the ambient color property.
This allows us to change the color
as well as the current brightness.
To not overwhelm our area lights, let's
make sure we have a nice low gray set,
and then have the current
brightness at about point six.
The last core component of
environment lighting is reflexions.
In the real world light bounces
off a bunch of objects, but
calculating that in Real-Time
is an expensive process.
Unity has a system in place for
calculating reflections for
use with shiny objects.
And then the environment
tab allows us to specify
how reflections
are calculated from the sky.
Since our apartment is indoor, we don't
want it to be affected by the sky.
And that's want to turn off reflections.
To do that, simply make sure that the
reflections for us is set to custom and
the queue map is set to none.
If you do make a scene that
you want reflections for,
make sure to read the further
reading to learn more about them.
And that covers environment lighting.
I know a lot of this wasn't
part into our apartment but
still definitely useful to know in
case you are building scenes that
are affected by your environment.