Before we go further,
let me actually just talk about
the concept of depth in a scene.
Remember we started talking modern
computation photography that we're
interest in.
Capturing the 3D scene that is lit by
some sort of illumination sources.
We want to use the optics,
the sensor to capture the information
that actually can be processed
displayed for user to interact with.
So essentially we're interested in
capturing a photograph in computational
photography that basically captures a 3D
scene, and all of the related geometry.
Look around yourself.
You have a 3D environment, and but in
essence that's what we want to capture
in a photograph that shows the shape and
size of things around it, and also
relative information of, how they're
related to each other in shape and size?
So an image like this,
in the real world actually has depth.
That is parts of the image are in front,
parts of them are in the back.
Here of course there is
some missing detail, but
you can see the 3D environment or
the 3D information of this scene.
In this case,
just shown from this image.
Now missing information,
we'll talk about that in a bit.
But in essence,
what we want to do is capture images
that also can show the depth.
Here is one example of subtypes
of images, depth image or
sometimes also referred
to as a range image.
All the black pixels here,
basically show the fact that,
these are all values of zero
considering that's the background.
And everything in front, and
different intensity values show how
close they are,
to my viewpoint in this camera.
The brightest points are of
course the closest, and
the farthest points are black.
Missing information here is of
course represented by black also.
So of course, you really want to
start capturing a 3D environment,
we need depth, geometry,
and 3D information.
In this lecture we're going to
talk about, how to capture that?