The first statement,
new threats can be detected immediately,
this is false because a misuse detection
of signature-based detection system
can only detect attacks that match
patterns or rules of known intrusions.
Second, when a new virus is identified,
it must be added to
the signature database.
This is true.
Because a misused detection system
detects attacks based on signatures
of known intrusions, therefore
when a new attack is discovered,
its signature needs to be added
to the signature database.
Third, can only detect
an intrusion attempt
if it matches a pattern that is
in the database, this is true.
This is essentially the definition of
a signature-based detection system.