The answers are, in this case only the
second is a correct representation. Any combination is
possible to be dialed. It's not the case
that we can, it's only possible to dial the
correct combination. Now here, we said that the
lock button works at any point. Whether it's open
or not, the lock button will always lock
it. And so that's represented by the third option.
True implies it's possible to lock.
In this case, the first one is a correct representation of the successor state
axiom for open, and the second one is not. Because note what it says. If we
already have the lock open, and then
we execute some dialing action that's not dialing
the correct combination X, we want it
to remain open. But this second axiom would
make it be closed, which is not what we want.