So what I just told you is referred to as the direct linear calibration or
transform or transformation method.
It has a couple of advantages.
One is, it's pretty simple to formulate and to solve.
Like I said, it's literally, you just take your points, and
you make that a matrix.
You then do some SVD.
You pull out the column.
Bang, there's your m.
Now these methods are referred to as minimizing an algebraic error
because essentially what we did was we set a m.
We fixed m to be a unit vector and then algebraically forced found the m
that gave us the smallest algebraic magnitude of a m.
There are some disadvantages to this method.
First is that it doesn't directly tell you about the camera parameters.
But we'll get, we'll fix some of that in just a minute.
It's also approximate because that m was based
upon a particular matrix based upon pure extrinsic and intrinsic projection.
What if we had something like radial distortion that we could actually model,
but we couldn't model within our projective transform equation.
How would we do that?
Suppose I actually knew the focal length, right?
I went out and bought a really expensive lens with focal length 3.746586,
really precise millimeters.
I don't want my m screwing with that.
It needs to stay that value.
I want to come up with the minimum solution using that precise value.
And then finally, another problem,
I put down mostly, I think it's just another one of those problems.
It's not actually minimizing the thing that I really want minimized.
It's minimized this kind of cute algebraic trick that I had.
So, what is it that I actually want to minimize?
Clearly, the amount of weight I put on every holiday.
But besides that, what?
Okay, that was not even a funny joke, but
it, it was going too long without any jokes.