Now, the probability of sampling a particular variable,
choosing a +w or a -w, depends on the values of the parents.
But those are chosen according to the conditional probability tables,
so in the limit, the count of each sampled variable
will approach the true probability.
That is, with an infinite number of samples, this procedure computes the true
joint probability distribution.
We say that the sampling method is consistent.
We can use this kind of sampling to compute the complete joint probability distribution,
or we can use it to compute a value for an individual variable.
But what if we wanted to compute a conditional probability?
Say we wanted to compute the probability of wet grass
given that it's not cloudy.
To do that, the sample that we generated here wouldn't be helpful at all
because it has to do with being cloudy, not with being not cloudy.
So, we would cross this sample off the list.
We would say that we reject the sample, and this technique is called rejection sampling.
We go through ignoring any samples that don't match
the conditional probabilities that we're interested in
and keeping samples that do, say the sample -c, +s, +r, -w.
We would just continue going through generating samples,
crossing off the ones that don't match, keeping the ones that do.
And this procedure would also be consistent.
We call this procedure rejection sampling.