Here is a screen capture from a tool called Lattix, that can construct these
dependency matrices from code and point out violations of various principles.
The Lattix tool provides several interesting features.
On the left hand side of the image,
actually is conveying the hierarchical structure of the system's components.
This hierarchical structuring can be dynamically specified by the user.
So within the left hand column there are some sub columns.
The ones on the extreme left, contains the ones that are just to the right of
that, which contains the ones just to the right of that and so on.
In the Lattix version of the DSM, here shown,
the numbers in the cells are not just zero and
ones, they are integer values which indicate the number of dependencies.
More over, the user of the tool can specify the kinds of dependencies and
get numbers for each of the different kinds.
The red triangles on some of the cells indicate violations of
user specified design principles.
And, the internal brown squares that subdivide the overall
DSM indicate candidate modules having no violations.
The user can construct such modules, by suitable column and row permutations.
And once you've done that and you can then focus on the remaining cells that
have violations and try to get the whole matrix to be violation free.