So here's a diagram for
question number 1.
This is what the word class will look
like after we make the modifications for
it to be able to hold the audio
resource id for each word.
And with that, we can create an array
list of what objects for each category.
Now into the second question,
when an item in the list is clicked on
then the onItemClick
listener gets triggered and
the onItemClick() method gets executed.
So this method has
four different inputs.
So your code within the onItemClick()
method can take advantage of
one of these variables.
Now if we look at the official Android
documentation that we showed you earlier
of the onItemClick() method,
there's a description of
what each parameter means.
So let's walk through each of
these four answer choices.
For the first answer, adapterView,
that's simply a reference to
the listView and
that's not what we're looking for here.
So the second choice view is the list
item view that we clicked on.
So this is almost what we want.
Now we can find the textView
inside the list item lay out,
and then call the getText method to
get the desired word as a string.
But simply having a string wouldn't
help us find the audio file associated
with each word.
So this parameter is not what we need.
Next we have position which
is the position of the item
within the adapter's data source.
So if the second list
item was clicked on,
it would correspond to position 2 within
the adaptors internal list of data.
Well, this choice position
is pretty promising because
it leads us to the word object
within the array list, and
from that word object we can
retrieve the audio resource ID.
So just to be thorough,
let's look at the last option
its last choice here ID is the row
idea of the item that we clicked on.
Now within the adapter you can specify
the numeric ID to identify each row.
You can also use random numbers for
each row if you want but for
the most part,
we don't need to rely on ID.
So, after looking through
all these answer choices,
the best one to use here is the position
parameter because from that
we can get the corresponding word
object from the ArrayList of words.
And that means we can find
the correct audio resource ID and
then configure the Media Player
object to play that audio file.