the 2015 imagenet winner was a network
from Microsoft Research called resnet
residents claim to fame is that it has a
massive 152 layers for contrast Alex it
has eight layers VG has 19 layers and
Google annette has 22 layers resnet is
kinda like VG and that the same
structure is repeated again and again
for layer after layer the main idea was
to add connections to the neural network
that skip layers so that very deep
neural networks could practically be
trained resident achieves a loss of only
three percent on imagenet which is
actually better than normal human
accuracy
now that you've learned about VG google
annette and resnet we'd like you to get
your hands dirty in the next assignment
you load each of these networks and
benchmark their performance