So we already said you could just do nearest neighbor, right?
I got a point here.
I key point here.
I search every key point over there to find out which one is best.
And by the way as I mentioned before,
those of you doing the problem set will probably end up doing just this.
But as we pointed out that could be really expensive.
You might have thousands of points here,
and thousands there, and that's awfully lot of combinations.
So we're going to do something a little bit smarter, okay?
We're going to use a approximation to a nearest neighbor search.
And the idea is that we generate hypotheses from
an approximate nearest neighbor, matching for each of the vectors.
And it's essentially in, SIFT uses this algorithm by Beis and
Lowe called best-bin, and it's a modification to the k-d tree algorithm.
And I'm going to assume those of you who are in computer science,
that you have some familiarity with what k-d trees are.
It's, it's essentially you can think of it as in a binary world,
just binary splitting things, k stands for k-dimensional.
Tree where you, you split them along.
It allows you to access points in essentially a a log n
instead of a something proportional to n.
And they did a little modification of that.
That allowed you to sort of sort your bins that you're searching for quickly.
And two points are important about this.
One is that it is.
A pretty good algorithm for the SIFT search.
And it's reported anywhere from two to three orders of magnitude speed-up.
And anytime you can buy two or
three orders of magnitude speed-up, you should do that.
Now of course, you can't cheat the piper.
You know, nearest neighbor is certain algorithm in complexity.
By doing it this way,
you find the nearest neighbor, the one that actually matter.
On approximately, again currently they'll tell you 95% of the time.
So, you have to wonder, you know, exactly what it is.
It can't be guaranteed but the idea is that for sort of well behaved
systems you're getting in the 90 plus percentile, which is good because if
you remember before, we said the descriptors aren't perfect anyway.
So some of our matches are going to just be wrong.
So we're finding 95% of the right matches, that's going to be pretty good.
This figure here sort of shows you a little bit of what's going on.
Again, this comes from, from their paper.
The algorithm is called Best Bin First.
The idea is, if this was your probe point, and
you found this point D when you do normal k-D trees.
You essentially recourse up the trees and, and, and branch out looking for
nearest points, and
all that they did is they had a way of sorting through the bins.
So they would order the bins themselves, so
they didn't just recourse through the tree.
And it gave them this speed-up.
And this listed here is the, the reference to the paper, and
it just makes it easier to find the nearest neighbors.
To, usually find the nearest neighbors.