To create a scale, we'll need a variable
to store the scale, and we'll call it r.
I'll need to use D3's scale function,
and then we're going to
use a square root scale because
we're working with circles.
We know that the square root
of a country's population
corresponds to the radius of the circle.
The population ranges from
52,070 to 1.3 billion, so
those numbers will be the minimum and
the maximum for the domain.
And finally, we map our domain to
a range of output pixel values
between 10 pixels and 50 pixels.
Finally, we can do some sanity
checks to make sure that our scale
works as intended.
Our smallest country population
produces the smallest pixel value, and
our largest country population
produces our largest pixel value.