Services hang out in the background,
processing, downloading, or
uploading data while the phone is locked
or the user is using unrelated apps.
This is nice, but
you might be wondering how services
are started in the first place.
There are three ways to start a service.
You can manually start a service,
you can schedule a service, or
you can bind to a service.
The most straightforward way
to start a service is to call
the startService method from a context,
such as an activity.
The service will execute, but
will not usually communicate back
to the component which started it.
If you want to have a service execute
at some point in the future, or
when some conditions are met,
you can create a special type
of service called a JobService.
You create your JobService, and
then you define when the job should
run using a scheduler, like
JobScheduler or Firebase JobDispatcher.
They allow you to define complex
run schedules for your service,
like have a service run
every 24 hours when on WiFi.
Then the scheduler schedules the job for
you.
We'll be talking about scheduling
services like this in greater detail
later.
Finally, a bindService offers
a client server-like interface.
With your service being the server and
the various components binding to
the service being the clients.
Components bind to the service
using the bindService method.
Unlike started services, which you
tend to start and then forget about.
Bound services can easily communicate
back to the components that are bound to
them.
An example of when you might use a bound
service is a media player application.
You might have a bound
service which plays audio and
an activity which controls the UI.
It's important to use a bound service as
oppose to a started service because you
probably want to update the UI to
represent where in the audio you are.
If you press the Pause button in the
activity, you might also want to send
additional commands to
the service from the activity.
Note that a service being bound or
started is not mutually exclusive.
A service can be both.
We'll be using services
in Sunshine in two ways.
First, when the user
changes their location,
new weather data needs to be immediately
downloaded in the background.
Secondly, weather data should
be downloaded on a regular
schedule in the background.
Because of this, I won't say
much more about bound services.
But if you're curious about them,
I've provided some links below.
I'll be focusing on started services and
scheduled job services.
Let's talk about started services first.