I mentioned failures in
the previous Morris cell, so
let me try to illustrate why our failure
is more of a problem in a large scale
system like a cloud platform, than if
we're not really concerned with scale.
Think about the following question.
A hypothetical cloud
has N=10 components, or
10 CPUs, where each CPU has
a failure probability of 0.03.
My question is, what is
the probability that there will be
a failure somewhere in this system,
in case there are ten components.
Then think about also what will
happen if there are more components.
So they're 100 components, what in that
case is the probability of a failure?
You should provide the answer in terms
of what is the percentage chance.