Query method returns a cursor
which is exactly the same
object returned by
Android SQLite database class.
So, in the on post execute method you
know have access to a cursor object.
Cursors are iterators that provide
read/write access to the data of
a content provider.
The data is in a tabular
format as shown here.
If you haven't worked
with cursors before,
you can head over to the SQL databases
lesson which is linked below.
For the data in this database,
there are only three columns,
Word, Definition and _ID.
I've also only drawn out a few rows so
this data looks manageable.
But what if your database
had hundreds of rows and
what if each term had 20 columns
of data associated with it?
It can be costly to get all of this
information if the database is hundreds
of rows long and has 20 columns.
And that's where these
parameters come in.
These null parameters
when they are not null,
relate to what is known as
the projection selection,
selection arguments, and sort order of
the data returned by the query function.
These arguments mirror the different
parts of a query statement in SQL.
A projection in SQL is used
to narrow down the number
of columns returned such
as only getting the Word.
A selection along with
the selection arguments are used
to narrow down the number of rows
returned based on some criteria.
For example, only selecting terms
that start with the letter a, and
the sort order determines the order
you get the data back in.
For example, sorting alphabetically.
In general, when you pass in null, it
means no sorting, and grab everything.
If you want to see code examples
of how to use these constraints,
check the notes below.
But for your toy app,
you won't need these,
because you'll be working with all of
the information in the content provider.