At its core, Auto Layout is a system for
finding the best possible outcome
given a set of constraints.
This is called dynamic programming,
and it's a very useful technique.
Sounds like Greek to you, no problem.
Let's see an example you're familiar
with, a travel planning website.
When you book a flight,
you usually provide the system with
several restrictions or constraints.
You want to fly from
San Francisco to Fort Lauderdale.
You prefer a non-stop flight.
You wish to leave Friday afternoon and
return Sunday night.
And you wish to pay as
little as possible.
Given these constraints,
the system will do its magic to
provide with the best possible flight.
Some of the constraints
are more important than others.
For example, a flight that
matches all the conditions but
instead takes you to Bangkok,
it's not going to cut the mustard.
On the other hand,
others are more flexible.
You might accept stopping at Phoenix for
a short period of time,
if no direct flight is available.
Therefore, constraints
have different priorities.
Some are a must,
while others are a plus.
Auto Layout is exactly the same but
for UIs.
We provide the system with a series
of constraints that specify
desired size and position of views.
And Auto Layout comes with
the best possible answer.
The major restriction in flight
planning is usually your budget.
In Auto Layout, it's the amount
of screen real estate available.
But the idea is the same.
Now that you understand what Auto Layout
is, let's find out how we can use it.