Now let's look at, in what ways computational photography enables imaging
perhaps to generate newer or better types of imaging.
One, you know, computational photography may allow you to
get unbounded dynamic range, this might be hard for you to see.
But in these types of images being able to get a very good viewpoint of
the outside, with a little bit of information about the inside,
something our eyes can do very well.
Cameras have a tough time doing.
But at the same time, we can vary a lot of different types of
things on a camera, if we bring computation close to it.
For example, we can vary things like focus, depth of field.
Here basically shown by these two examples.
We can of course play around with resolution, control it
as we need to while the picture is taken, at that time of taking the picture.
We can control lighting.
But basically, we can control a lot of things.
Also color, reflectances of the environment, and all of that wonderful stuff.
Again, understanding how to do this is valuable, and
something we will look it from a technology perspective.
But after you master the technology prospective,
how you leverage it to do better photography, well I'll leave that up to you.
So in essence this supports a creation of a newer medium of photography,
which could be enhanced by these technologies.
And of course, worse comes to worse, you can always just revert back to
the traditional form of digital photography and take pictures as you've done.
Question now is, if we bring in more computation, can we do more?
I'm being very careful and
I'm not using the word better, because I don't want to get into that argument.
But the bottom line is computation and photography combined together,
will let you do different, and perhaps more types of things with cameras.