One cool thing about a higher
dimensional network is figuring out how
to exploit it both for fun and profit.
Let's start with a low
dimensional example.
Suppose we're doing an all-gather
on a linear network.
Here's the before and the after picture.
This is a lower bound
on the execution time.
N, in this case,
is the length of each output vector.
Now, if you did the all-gather using
a bucketing scheme, then you would find
its execution time to be
approximately alpha times P + beta n.
So this matches the lower bound beta,
but not in alpha.
Here's a question.
If I gave you a higher dimensional mesh,
could you do better?
Let's take a 2D mesh as an example.
Initially, suppose there
are m words per node.
So, since this is
an all-gather on every node,
we have the capacity to store all of the
words from all of the processes, but,
initially, we only
have one little piece.
Now, if you do an all-gather,
here's the output.
That is, when it completes,
all nodes have a copy of all the data.
So how do you implement this operation?
You could certainly run
the 1D linear algorithm.
The question is,
can you exploit the extra capacity
that comes from extra links?
Here's an idea.
Why don't you start by doing a 1D
all-gather within each process row?
When that completes, each node
will have a complete row of data.
Now do an all-gather, but
this time within each column.
When it completes,
you will have the final output.
So how much time does this take?
The row and
the column gathers are one dimensional.
Let's suppose we use the one
dimensional bucketing algorithm.
Remember the cost of that algorithm.
Let's consider the row
all-gathers first.
Within each row, there are square
root of P processes participating.
The total output size is m
times the square root of P.
Therefore, this is
the cost of the row part.
Notice that relative to
the one D algorithm alone,
we've already improved the latency.
It scales like square root of P,
rather than P.
What about the column communication?
The data volume is now N, but
you still only have square root
of P processes participating.
Therefore, the execution time to run
the column part of the algorithm is
the 1D algorithm on an input of size,
n, over square root of P processes.
Let's sum up the row and
the column times.
Asymptotically, the total time is now
proportional to just square root of P
in the alpha term.
With respect to the beta term,
it's basically optimal.
In other words,
taking advantage of a higher dimensional
network gets us a little bit closer to
the ultimate lower bound,
at least on the number of messages.