The best place to start learning Cast
is our collection of sample apps.
We have everything from a hello Cast
example to a complete video player.
Hello Cast is a great learning tool.
It includes a one-file sender app,
it's easy to understand.
And once installed, it lets you do this.
Hello world.
Next step is our reference application,
Cast videos.
This complies with the design checklist,
and
it's by far your best bet to use as
a starting point for your integration.
Source code is available for
Android, iOS, and Chrome.
It includes a reference
receiver app as well, and
we also have samples to help you
with specific tasks like DRM.
Now before we get into
the details there's a couple
of topics we should discuss first.
A receiver app is launched when a sender
tells a cast device, like a Chrome Cast,
that it wants to launch
a particular receiver.
It does this by specifying
an application ID.
All receiver apps have
a unique application ID,
and the sender must provide this
during its request to the cast device.
The cast device then looks up that
application ID using Google service, and
then downloads the URL that
corresponds to the receiver app.
It then loads it onto the cast device.
When you start adding cast
functionality into your application,
the first thing you'll need to
do is get an application ID, and
you'll do this by visiting
the Cast Developer Console.
This is a self service online console
where you can publish your own receiver
apps so they can be downloaded
by any cast device.
This is actually pretty important and
great for developers,
because it means you can self-manage
your Google Cast receiver releases.
To do so, you'll first need to
register as a Cast developer, and
pay a small $5 registration
fee to verify your account.
This is just a one-time thing.
Once you've registered, you'll be
greeted by the developer console where
you can register your
receiver applications,
as well as register your Cast devices.
It's important to register
your cast devices, so
they can be used for debugging.
And the main reason is so they can
download a non-published receiver app.
Once you've registered your cast device,
it can take about 15 minutes for
those changes to propagate out,
and you'll need to reboot your
cast device at that time.
I'd recommend going ahead and
registering your cast device for
development now.
This is important to do, because cast
functionality is unfortunately not
supported by the emulators.
So we need to use a real Android
device like a phone or a tablet.
.And a real cast device like a
Chromecast for development anti-bugging.
These are some of the recently published
receiver apps at chromecast.com/apps.
When you publish your receiver,
it can take about six hours for
those changes to propagate
to all cast devices.
And, although the user experience
guidelines we mentioned earlier
are optional, they are required if you'd
like to be featured on this web site.
Developing is optional for
this class, and if you'd like,
you can follow along without
doing any on your own.
But if you do intend to
write cast applications,
then I'd recommend going ahead now and
creating an account at Cast Developer
Console and registering your device.