To start solving this problem,
I'm going to write some methods first.
Methods are little blocks of
code between curly braces and
I can get my buttons
to trigger my methods.
So I'm going to have a method for
each of the buttons.
I'll start with the plus three points
button, I'm going to type public void,
now this is when you would
type the method name.
And you should feel free to name
the methods whatever you'd like.
And I say that as long
as it makes sense.
So I'm going to try to name this method
very explicitly what's going to happen
when you click the plus
three points button.
This method name is going
to be addThreeForTeamA.
And again, you could name it
something a little bit different,
like addThreePointsForTeamA.
Okay.
Now after that,
I'm going to type the method parameters.
And you don't know too much about this,
but
you'll learn about it
more in the next lesson.
It's going to be view with a capital V,
and then the letter V.
And then, I'm going to make an open
curly brace and Android Studio is smart
enough to give me a closed
curly brace to close my method.
And now any statements that I put in
here are going to be what happens when
this method gets called.
So what I want to happen is for
it to display for
team A, and then I'm going to give it
the number that I want it to display,
and I want it to display 3.
Now this hasn't been associated
to my buttons yet, so
I have to go back to my XML, and I'm
going to go to the button that's plus
three points, this one right here.
And I'm going to add
an onClick attribute.
And in this onClick attribute,
I'm going to give it the exact same name
that I gave the method
in my main activity.
And actually Android Studio's
jumping the gun a little bit.
It's even trying to suggest that I
should put in here, addThreeForTeamA.
Because it kind of sees all the methods
that are available in main activity and
this one seems to fit the bill.
So sure I am going to click on this.
Okay, now I have
the onClick attribute here.
With this button that says +3 Points,
and it's going to trigger
addThreeForTeamA, and
I could go back to my main activity and
see that inside of addThreeForTeamA,
it says displayForTeamA(3),
which will make 3 appear on
the screen for the score.
Let's make sure all of
that logic is Okay,
here's my app, and
I'm going to press the +3 points.
Yay, and it says 3.
It might be kind of small on your
screen, but believe me, it says 3.
These other buttons don't work,
though, so that's as expected,
because we didn't change
any of the code for them.
All right, let's keep working.
So, now that I know that that worked,
I'm going to go ahead and
do the same thing for
the other two buttons.
In fact, I'm going to do such the same
thing that I'm going to copy this and
I'm going to paste it twice.
And I'm just going to say,
addTwoForTeam A, and addOneForTeamA.
And here, I'm going to change this to
displaying 2 and this to displaying 1.
Okay.
So that's pretty much the same thing for
2 and 1 that I did for adding 3 points,
but I also have to remember to go over
to the XML, so I click to go over here.
Okay.
And I'm going to add two more onClicks.
So for my +2 Points button,
I'm going to do a onClick,
and oh, how nice of it.
It's giving me three
different options now and
I want to make sure to
select the right one.
So, this is +2 Points, so
I'm going to select addTwoForTeamA.
And now I'm going to come down here.
Type onClick.
And select the addOneForTeamA.
Okay, so, I'm feeling pretty
confident that that's going to work.
I'd bet some money on it, but
I should still run it to test it out.
Okay, so, I press +3.
Still works.
I press +2.
Oh, cool.
It says 2.
And now I press free throw,
and it shows 1.
So, awesome.
I've completed the task.
And because I've completed the task, I
get the honor of checking this box off.