At the end of the previous video, we ended at the following iteration.
We arrived at a precisely formulated statistical inference problem.
Specifically, to estimate the number of steps since candy C was chosen.
We will do so using the regression estimator, which uses as features,
the interselection time of Airheads, Hershey's, Reese's, Kit Kat and Rollo's.
And we choose a linear model to implement that regression estimator.
Let's now build that model using IPython Notebook.
Then in the validation phase, we'll examine how well that model works out.
I've added a link to the IPython Notebook for you to download and follow along.
To use our linear regression model, we first need to prepare our input data.
Recall that our feature set is the interselection time of each candy type.
Thus, each record will have a column for each brand of candy and the value in
each column will be the number of turns since someone selected that type.
First, we create a variable called shared state events containing these values.
Then we convert the data to a data frame.
There are six types of candy and so we have six columns.
We can see that by examining the data frame.
Now, I'm going to use the linear regression implementation for module sklearn.
Feel free to use any module that you'd like.
We split our data into features and labels.
And we also split into a training and test set.
We then trained our model and
we can see it resulted in the following coefficients.
This means that the model that we've learned for our aggression estimator, is
the following, just to read it aloud, 0.31 times the interest election time for
airheads, plus 0.07, times Hersey's, plus .15 times kitkat,
plus 0.06 times reese's, plus 0.14 times rollo's, plus a constant.
In our next video, we'll start validating this model.