The answer is log n again.
Starting to see a pattern?
So the easiest way to see this,
is to remember the duality between
bag operations and binary arithmetic.
Well let's say I'm adding
these two binary integers.
I'll go bit by bit.
Each bit I'll do some operation.
And then I may or may not do a carry.
And all those operations are basically
constant time pennant combine
operations.
And of course, again I might have
to scan the entire length of
the bit string.
Therefore, the cause should be
logarithmic in the size of the bag.
I want you to think about that for
a second.
That's a super cool result.
Why?
Because it basically says that it takes
the same amount of asymptotic running
time to insert n elements into
a bag as it does to insert one.
In fact, that means the amortize
time to insert elements into a bag,
is basically a constant.