Now, I've told you what a successful plan looks like,
but I haven't told you how to find one.
The process of finding it can be done through search
just as we did in problem solving.
So, remember in problem solving,
we start off in a state, and it's a single state, not a belief state.
And then we start searching a tree,
and we have a big triangle of possible states
that we search through, and then we find
one path that gets us all the way to a goal state.
And we pick from this big tree a single path.
So, with belief states and with branching
plan structures, we do the same sort of process,
only the tree is just a little bit more complicated.
Here we show one of these trees,
and it has different possibilities.
For example, we start off here, and we have one possibility
that the first action will be going right,
or another possibility that the first action
will be performing a suck.
But then it also has branches that are part of the plan itself.
This branch here is actually part of the plan
as we saw before.
It's not a branch in the search space.
It's a branch in the plan, so what we do
is we search through this tree.
We try right as a first action.
We try suck as a first action.
We keep expanding nodes
until we find a portion of the tree
like this path is a portion of this search tree.
We find that portion which is a successful plan
according to the criteria of reaching the goal.