Now that we've covered provisioning Vagrant files and
the provision.sh file to add in our Python package, we next talk about Flask.
Flask is called a microframework because it keeps the core
simple but extendable.
Flash has no database extraction layer, form validation, or any other
component where preexisting third-party libraries provide common functions.
As you can see from the home page, Flask is fun and easy to setup.
In this quick video, I'll demonstrate how easy it is to modify Flask.
Make sure your visualization is running or launch your server again by
navigating to the viz in your terminal directory and entering python app.py.
And in your local browser, navigate to http://127.0.0.1:5000.
And next in Atom, navigate to your viz folder and open app.py.
I used the tutorial to create a Flask application named app and a decorator
function syntax to create an app.route with the forward slash location.
To change this location, we can simply copy and
paste, and I've renamed the new route /hack.
And after defining our route, we define the function show_hack.
We then navigate back to our browser and enter in our new location, /hack.
And we see that our code updates immediately and
the same Twitter storm word cloud template is accessed using our new location.
Now that we've seen how easy it is to modify paths in Flask,
our next job is to explore the key-value paired database Redis.