For Sunshine,
building a content provider is just
one part of managing weather data.
And unlike the to-do list app,
you won't be attaching your
provider methods to the UI.
Instead, you'll only code those
methods in the Weather Provider class.
And to make sure they're
working correctly,
you'll be testing them
with Android test classes.
Test classes that you see if a method or
object is working like you expected to.
Without the need for UI code and
without any risk of crashing your app.
These tests exist in a package that's
separate from the main app package.
And in the Sunshine exercises,
you'll find test classes called test
URI Matcher and Test Weather Provider,
that you can run to make sure
your code is working as expected.
If your code is complete and
you run these tests, Android Studio will
give you a message saying you passed.
But if something is wrong, like if you
forgot to set a notification or return
an incorrect value, you'll get a message
saying that a test has failed and why.
And the feedback you get
should help you go back and
correct any minor coding errors.
Professional programmers often rely
on tests to make sure that their code
is working every step of the way.
So this is also
an important skill to have.
In the following text,
you'll be given some short instructions
on how to use the test
classes provided in Sunshine.
Then you can start building
the Weather Provider.