All right, for this exercise we
want to do the same thing, but for
the latitude and longitude search.
One caveat to the search,
is that we need to convert
the values from the latitude and
longitude text fields, into the bbox
parameter that Flickr expects.
Remember from our demonstration
using the Eiffel Tower's coordinates
that the bounding box string
needs to be a list of
four values in the order from minimum
longitude to minimum latitude,
maximum longitude and
then finally maximum latitude.
So I'm going to help you get started.
First, I'm going to copy over the
parameters from the text search while
making sure to remove
the text parameter.
Then, we'll add a B box parameter and
I'm going to recommend that we populate
this value using a method
called bboxString.
So that method doesn't exist yet,
so we should be getting an error.
And then, we can just put this anywhere.
We'll say private func
Now it's going to be your job
to implement this method.
Before you get started, I want to
point our four useful constants in
the constants.swiftall
that can help you.
The first two are called
SearchBBoxHalfWidth and
SearchBBoxHalfHeight.
What these constants represent
is the amount that you want to
vary the latitude up and down and
the longitude left to right.
Now feel free to adjust these constants
if you want to vary the overall size of
your bounding box, but
the one default value should be fine.
The other two constants
are the SearchLatRange and
SearchLonRange tuples,
notice these are tuples.
And you should try to use these two
constants to ensure the bounding box you
create, does not use latitude or
longitude values that fall
outside of the accepted range.
For example, if a user enters
the latitude of negative 89.5,
and then you use this half,
I guess that would be half Height,
to vary it by one up and one down,
it would result in negative 90.5 and
negative 88.5.
Now the negative 88.5 value is fine.
It falls within this range.
However, the negative 90.5 value falls
outside of the accepted range because
it is lower than negative 90.
So you can use these constants and
perhaps combine them with Swift's max or
min functions to ensure that this
kind of error doesn't happen.
If you never used Swift's max or
min functions before, I've posted a link
to a stack overflow post that describes
them in the instructor notes.
Now I'll leave the implementation
of the bbox method up to you.
If you correctly implement the method
you should see a URL like this one
assuming the half width and
half height constants are set to their
default values of one, and the user does
a Lat/Lon search with a latitude
of 48.85 and a longitude of 2.29.
Check this box when you're done.
Good luck.