I'll start at the top.
And no, complicated password
requirements are not likely to drive
users away unless there's something
totally insane like 1,000 characters.
But in that case, you should still
just use a password manager and
then not worry about it, so no.
Registration gates will though.
More on this one in a moment.
Suggesting products is fine,
no harm in subtlety helping people
find products that they might like.
Just don't overdo it.
And a shipping address should have a
name, so this one also isn't a problem.
Okay, so
it looks like the only problem from this
list is registration gates on checkout.
Remember how you should avoid
putting your products
behind a registration wall?
The same applies to purchases.
When someone wants to buy something,
they just want to buy it.
Don't slow them down, and
that's all registration gates really do.
If you minimize the time to conversion,
you'll watch your conversions increase.