Let's make use of that matrix, all right?
What does the essential matrix constraints say?
Essential matrix constraints says, that p prime times z times p equals 0.
Where p prime and p are the locations of the points, one in the prime frame and
one in the regular frame.
All right.
So, where are our points P?
Well, it's in some location, cap X, cap Y, cap Z.
Okay.
Which is also, in the other frame, cap X prime, cap Y prime.
Also Z, because the Zs are the same because our planes are parallel, right?
Right.
So here are our points written.
And the first time I wrote them as we said before,
p is XYZ, P prime is X prime, Y prime, and the same Z.
But, kind of written kind of cool over here, right?
We assume that under normal projection, little x is f times big X over big Z.
So I'm just writing big X as Z times little x divided by f.
Okay?
And that's how I entered in these things here.
Same thing with the primes over there.
Okay?
Let's put those points in our, essential matrix equation.
All right.
So, I've just inserted them here using our e.
And now I've done something a little bit sneaky again.
So here I have p prime e p, but you'll notice I've now divided
my points all the way through by the, the amount z over f.
A constant, right?
Z is whatever, s,
something, I don't know what the value is, but it's some constant value, and f,
I don't, might not know what that is, or I might, some value.
And I just divided all the points through by that.
Now, why am I allowed to do that?
See, in class, everybody yell out the answer.
But over the ether.
You guys can't say, because it equals 0, dummy.
All right? So I can multiply anything I want by a constant and
it stays equal to 0, and I just wrote it this way to make it
easier to see the equations that are about to happen.
So I just divided by z over f.
Copy that equation over again, multiply out the first one, so now we have x
prime, y prime, f dotted with, or transposed, of 0 bf, minus By equals 0.
Multiply it more again, we get Bfy prime equals Bfy.
B is a constant, f is a constant of divide through, and
it just says y equals y prime.
y equals y prime?
What does that mean?
Oh.
That means if I have some point in the image location x y in the regular frame,
the line y prime equals y is the line, that this point has to be on.
And think about what this is, so a,
a points at x y so it's the sum x location and it's y, let's suppose y is 17.
The equation y prime equals 17 is what.
That's a horizontal line at height 17.
So what this says is, our epipolar constraint for
parallel cameras, right, is that given a point in the image,
the corresponding point is on the same horizontal line.
Except last time, I just had to make you believe me.
In fact, you didn't even ask the question, because it's very quiet in here,
but, it made common sense that if these cameras were lined up it
should be at the same line.
Well, common sense doesn't get you very far in mathematics.
Here is the derivation, if you will, that from parallel planes you can
lined up this way, that your epipolar lines are horizontal.
'Kay? So the answer to that previous quiz of, does this work for
parallel planes?
It works beautifully, actually.
The rotation matrix is just the identity and
it derives out that your epipolar lines are in this cast the horizon,
the parallel horizontal lines at the same height.
Cool huh?