Coming up soon we'll be adding multiple cats, so
we're going to get ready by moving the model to a separate area.
Because if we left the model where it is in the ViewModel, we'd be putting all
of this into a for loop, and making it again, and again, and again.
There's gotta be a more separated and readable way to do this.
All of this code that I'm selecting here should move
into a special function which will make us new Cats.
I'm going to cut all of it.
And wow look at how simple our ViewModel is.
We'll call this function Cat with a capital C.
As you can see, all of the cat logic is here inside of our Cat function.
And our ViewModel down here is super, super simple.
Now, we do still need to actually make this cat.
I'm going to store our cat in a currentCat variable,
specifically, a Knockout observable.
And instead of passing in an object literal, like this,.
I'm going to pass in a new cat and that should work.
Well, almost.
We actually just changed where our cat lives.
Now instead of finding our cat's properties right on the ViewModel,
we need to look inside of the currentCat variable.
So over in our html, we need to make a couple changes.
So here in our html, we need to change all the data-bind properties that
are looking for cat-related properties.
They all need to be currentCat.name, currentCat.title, et cetera.
That's because, once again, our cat is not living on the ViewModel anymore,
our cat is living in the currentCat observable.
And remember, we put the parentheses here because currentCat is actually
a knockout observable, which is a function.
In order to get the currentCat value, we need to run that function and
it will return the value to us.
Let's hop over to our browser and hit refresh.
Sure enough, everything seems to work just fine.
We have our nicknames, our cat image, and all of this.
If we try to click, however,
we get an uncaught TypeError, undefined is not a function, line 34.
In our code, app.js, for me line 34 is this right here.
Now what's the problem with this?
What is this.clickCount?
Well, this represents the ViewModel and there is no clickCount on the ViewModel.
Remember, clickCount is now living inside of our currentCat.
In this case, I need to save this.currentCat.clickcount is
going to be this.currentCat.clickcount plus one.
And now if I hop back into the browser and
I hit refresh, sure enough my clicking works just fine.
Go ahead and make those main changes.
First of all, moving your cat into a separate cat function.
Secondly, updating the bindings in your index.html file.
And finally, updating our increment counter so
that way it can get the click count properly from the model.
Go ahead and make those changes.