So let's look at three different cross-faded results we looked at, and
let's compare them.
Here, the whole blend from the entire size of the window, so
the window size here was, the entire image.
In this case, the window is this region, and in this case, this region.
Each one of them has a different effect, here,
you can still see a little bit of a sharpness, a drop-off.
Here you see, less sharpness much smoothness but
you dil, do see a little bit of ghostly artifacts.
And here of course everywhere you see transparency and ghost artifacts.
Now you can see all these images clearly,
again, more ghosting, transparency artifacts all over the image,
just restricted to this region, and this one is much nicer but does seem to
have a little bit of a crisp sharp line that does show up in between.