Given the non-optimality
of depth-first search,
why would anybody choose to use it?
Well, the answer has to do
with the storage requirements.
Here I've illustrated a state
space consisting of a very large,
or even infinite, binary tree.
As we go to level one, two,
three down to level n,
the tree gets larger and larger.
Now, let's consider the frontier for
each of these search algorithms.
For breadth-first search we know
the frontier looks like that.
And so when we get down to level n,
we'll require storage
space of two to the n paths
in a breadth-first search.
For cheapest-first, the frontier
is going to be more complicated.
It's going to sort of work
out this contour of cost, but
it's going to have a similar
total number of notes.
But for depth-first search,
as we go down the tree,
we start going down this branch,
and then we back up.
But at any point, our frontier
is only going to have n notes,
rather than two to the n notes.
So that's a substantial savings for
depth-first search.
Now of course, if we're also
keeping track of the explored set,
then we don't get that much savings.
But without the explored set,
depth-first search has a huge
advantage in terms of space saved.
One more property of the algorithms
to consider is the property of
completeness.
Meaning, if there is a goal somewhere,
will the algorithm find it?
So let's move from very large
trees to infinite trees and
let's say that there's some goal hidden
somewhere deep down in that tree.
And the question is,
are each of these algorithms complete?
That is, are they guaranteed
to find a path to the goal?
Mark off the check boxes for
the algorithms that you believe
are complete in this sense.