And I hope you guessed function A.
Even though both perfectly describe the data
B is much more complex than A.
In fact, outside the data
B seems to go to a minus infinity much faster
than these data points
and to plus infinity much faster
with these data points over here.
And in between
we have wide oscillations
that don't correspond to any data.
So I would argue
A is preferable.
The reason why I asked this question
is because of something called Occam's Razor.
Occam can be spelled in many different ways.
And what Occam says is that
everything else being equal
chose the less complex hypothesis.
Now in practice
there's actually a trade-off
between a really good data fit
and low complexity.
Let me illustrate this to you
by a hypothetical example.
Consider the following graph
where the horizontal axis graphs
complexity of the solution.
For example, if you use polynomials
this might be a high-degree polynomial over here
and maybe a linear function over here
which is a low-degree polynomial
your training data error
tends to go like this.
The more complex the hypothesis you allow
the more you can just fit your data.
However, in reality
your generalization error on unknown data
tends to go like this.
It is the sum of the training data error
and another function
which is called the overfitting error.
Not surprisingly
the best complexity is obtained
where the generalization error is minimum.
There are methods
to calculate the overfitting error.
They go into a statistical field
under the name Bayes variance methods.
However, in practice
you're often just given the training data error.
You find if you don't find the model
that minimizes the training data error
but instead pushes back the complexity
your algorithm tends to perform better
and that is something we will study a little bit
in this class.
However, this slide is really important
for anybody doing machine learning in practice.
If you deal with data
and you have ways to fit your data
be aware that overfitting
is a major source of poor performance
of a machine learning algorithm.
And I give you examples in just one second.