Let's go through how to create
a minimal Android Auto compatible app
that implements all of
this functionality.
We will be able to put all of
the code into a single file
to give you a nice concise walk-through.
Let's create a new project from scratch.
So go to File, New Project and
give it a name of something like this,
MinimalAutoMedia, and
create it in an appropriate location.
Next.
Make sure just the Phone and
Tablet option is checked and
everything else should be off.
And for the API level,
select API 21 or later.
This is when the media
API was introduced.
Click Next.
Select a default blank activity.
Next again.
You can leave the activity and
layout names at the defaults.
Click Finish and
Android Studio will create the project.
We need to declare an XML file that
will contain Android auto information.
So let's open up the Android manifesto
XML and lets add something inside
the application tag but
not inside the activity.
You can see here we're
defining something for
com.google.android.gms.car.application
and
we're specifying an external
place to find it.
Now we need to create
the referenced file.
So we go to RES, and
you won't have an XML directory.
So create that by right-clicking, new,
directory, type the word XLM,
and then hit OK.
You'll notice that I had to collapse and
then expand the RES directory
to make the XML folder visible.
Right click on that directory and
select new, file, and
type in this name,
automotive_app_desk.xml.
And hit okay.
Inside this file you need
to declare support for
media with some XML like this.
And if we go back to
our Android manifest,
you can see that this is now green.