Welcome back. We're down to our final main unit.
This one is on natural language processing--
that is, understand natural languages like English or German or French
and figuring out what to do with them.
Now, this is a very interesting topic for three reasons.
One is a philosophical one--we as humans have defined ourselves much in terms
of our ability to speak with each other and understand each other.
This ability to use language is something that we feel sets us apart
from all the other animals and from the other machines.
Second is in terms of applications.
We really would like to be able to talk to our computers and use them for various things.
Sure there are occasions where clicking with a mouse is the right thing to do,
but talking is natural, and we want to be able to communicate with our machines.
Then third is in terms of learning.
We want out computers to be smarter,
and much of human knowledge is written down in terms of paragraphs and sentences of text,
and not in terms of formal databases or formal procedures written in code.
It's all in text, and if we want our computers to be smart,
they'd better be able to read that text and make sense of it.
That's what this lesson is all about.