So here I'm going to actually look at a specific example.
Here the goal is, I want to take a small image,
let's say this is a 120 by 240 image of a strawberry, but
I want to generate from this is something twice as big, so 480 by 240 image.
What I'm going to do is now take this original image of strawberries and
basically replicate this across the whole region.
Except the intention is now to do this.
And as soon as I replicate one to the other, I also keep on finding
the seams between them that would allow me to generate a newer, larger image.
So here, basically, I copy the overall image over.
And when I copy it on top, I also find a seam.
Our copies would be overlapping.
But then, of course, basically I do this by randomly putting them in
different regions in this manner, and
now the yellow lines basically show that we have found the best possible seams.
And now this allows us to generate a much bigger, and
a larger image which basically has more strawberries.
This example can be applied to many different ways.
I can use this to generate a larger version of this.
I can generate a larger version of this.
Or even a larger version of this flower image.
I'll talk about this next, in a bit.
But more importantly, notice what happened here.
I extended the Machu Picchu image, except that when I extended it,
because of a variety of reasons, it actually added a hill, image is smooth.
Of course this is now no longer the real image,
because the real Machu Picchu scene would not have these three different hills.
But now we actually generate images like this.
So in essence, this method that I just talked about, finding seams,
can be used to generate much larger novel images, fake images this way, too.