The next step is to configure
the system to use the sign in API.
When you've signed into your project,
as you can see here, select the APIs and
off link on the left.
Once you've done that, select APIs.
Under the APIs, you'll then need to
find the Google+ API and enable it.
Once its enabled, you can then go to
the consent screen link on the left.
You might be familiar with the consent
screen from signing into apps, and
you can see an example
here on the right.
To build one of these, the least that
you have to configure is an email
address, so I'm just going to
put mine in, and a product name.
I'm just going to call mine Signin1_1.
Once you've done that,
scroll down and click Save.
Finally, under the Credential's link,
I'm going to create a new client ID, and
I'm going to select this to be
an installed application for Android.
I need to give it a package name and
you have to remember this package name.
You'll need it in the next step as
you're building your application.
I'm going to call it
com.udacity.firstsignin.
And then you need your certificate
fingerprint, your SHA1.
Now this is what you got
in the terminal earlier on.
So, if I go back to my terminal,
I've highlighted my SHA1.
I'm going to copy it and then I'm
going to go back to the console.
And in the console I'm
going to paste that.
Then finally, I'm going to
leave Deep linking disabled and
create a new client ID.
So, we'll take a moment to
create the client ID And
you can see it's up here now.
So now, any application trying
to sign into the infrastructure,
the package name will be
checked against what's allowed.
And if I build an application called
com.udacity.firstsignin on the machine
with this fingerprint, then that
application will be able to sign in.
If I run that code on a different
machine, it won't sign in.
I would have to create a new client
ID for that Android application
with a certificate fingerprint
from the other machine.
This is one of the limitations that
you'll get when your debugging.
So sometimes you'll have
problems when you sign in and
it doesn't appear to work, and that's
usually the case of what's happened.
So next up,
your going to create a project and
your going to configure it to use this.