So far, we have described how the
operating system controls the processes'
access to physical memory.
But what we didn't explain was how
the operating system decides how to
allocate a particular portion of the
memory to a process in the first place.
This is the job of the memory
allocation mechanisms that are part of
the memory management subsystem
of an operating system.
Memory allocation incorporates
mechanisms that decide
what are the physical pages that will be
allocated to particular
virtual memory regions.
So what are the physical addresses
that will correspond to a specific
virtual address.
Once the memory allocator
establishes a mapping,
the mechanisms that we discussed so
far, like the address translation,
use of page tables, et cetera.
They're simply used to determine
a physical address from a virtual
address that the process
presents to the CPU.
And also to perform all necessary checks
regarding the validity of the access or
the access permissions.
Memory allocators can exist at the
kernel level, as well as the user level.
Kernel-level allocators are responsible
for allocating memory regions,
such as pages for the kernel, so for
various components of the kernel state.
And also these are used for certain
static states, for the processes when
they're created, like for their codes,
stack, or initialized datum.
In addition, the kernel-level
allocators are responsible for
keeping track of the free memory
that's available in the system.
The user-level allocators are used for
dynamic process state, for
instance, for the heap.
So this is state that's dynamically
allocated during the process execution.
The basic interface for these
allocators includes malloc and free.
What these calls do is that they request
from the kernel some amount of memory
from its free pages, and then ultimately
release it when they're done.
Once the kernel allocates
some memory to a malloc call,
the kernel is no longer involved
in the management of that space.
That memory will at that point be used
by whatever user-level allocator is
being used, and there are a number
of options out there right now.
That have certain different trade-offs
in terms of their cache efficiency or
friendliness with respect to how they
behaved in a multithreaded environment
or other aspects.
We will not discuss the internals
of these user-level
allocators in this course.
Instead, we will briefly describe some
of the basic mechanisms that are used in
the kernel-level allocators.
And the same kinds of design principles
are used in the design of some of
the user-level allocators
that are out there today.