As we said at the beginning when we first introduced the chi-square test for
independence, we evaluate the relationship between two variables. In this case,
the type of verb used smashed, hit or control. And the response, yes or no. In
this case, we have a two by three contingency table. Two rows and three
columns. You've seen on our other lessons that testing for significance is only
part of the story. We should also measure the strength of the relationship
between these two variables. This is our measure of effect size. When we have a
contingency table that's greater than just a two by two matrix, we use Cramer's
V. This is also symbolized like this, and might be called Cramers phi
coefficient. This is equal to the square root of our chi square value divided
by the total number of subjects in our study, times k minus 1. K is the smaller
of the number of rows or columns. What would k be in this case?