In the following quiz,
you'll be asked to write your own
function that returns random nouns.
We'll use this in our mad libs generator
to simulate a person playing our game.
Which will make things
a bit more interesting.
Now don't worry,
this isn't as hard as it sounds.
Particularly because we'll be using
a new function called randint
to help us out.
Just remember the function
string.replace
from a couple of lessons ago.
We'll see that randint
looks pretty similar.
Now before we can use randint,
we're going to have to put this line
of code at the top of our file.
This might look a bit strange
with words like from an import.
Essentially, this allows
us to use randint
since the function isn't
built into Python.
However, it's not necessary to fully
understand what this line of code means.
To use the randint function itself.
You'll learn a lot more about what are
called import statements in stage three.
But for now, let's focus on how
to use the function, randint, so
we can generate random nouns.
This is the basic structure of randint.
As you can see, randint takes
in two arguments, low and high.
And will return a number from
the first to the second argument.
With both arguments
included in that range.
So, if I ran this line of code num
could be the number 1, 2, or 3.
You'll use the randint
function in the following quiz
to generate a random number
between zero and one.
And depending on the output of that
number you'll return one of two nouns.
Good luck.