So we've spent all this time learning
some new concepts and writing some code.
But we haven't been able to verify if
our provider code is correct or not.
Now in this code check point,
let's modify the Catalog Activity
to call the Resolver query method.
Now let's start off by opening
the CatalogActivity in Android Studio.
And then scroll down to
the displayDatabaseInfo method.
So currently in this method,
we're interacting with
the SQLite database directly.
And we've discussed before
that this is bad practise.
Instead, we should be contacting the
database through the ContentResolver and
a PetProvider instead.
So to correct this,
let me comment out a side of code, so
that we can compare it to
the correct code later on.
So now I'll add a new code where we'll
use the ContentProvider instead.
And that means that we no longer
need this database call up here, so
let's go ahead and delete that.
So now instead of directly querying
the database, like we do here,
I'm going to call to getContentResolver
and then query that instead.
Now from this,
we also get back a Cursor.
So let's set that up and
then end it with a semicolon.
Now all that's left to do, is to fill
out the parameters of the query method.
So the first parameter if you remember,
will be the the URI, but
I'm going to actually leave that
blank for you to fill out later on.
So I'll just leave it blank there.
The next parameter will
be the projection, and
all the other parameters
I'll set as null.
So remember that the URI is what
defines the ContentProvider and
the data that you're interesting
in getting a Cursor for.
So it's really important
to get this value correct.
Well, with those changes made,
I'm actually going to stop here and
let you finish out the rest.
So can you help me figure out what
URI I should be putting in here.
So for this code check point,
I'd like you to complete these steps.
In the CatalogActivity's
displayDatabaseInfo method, first,
remove code that directly interacts with
the PetDbHelper and the SQLiteDatabase.
Instead, we're going to call
the ContentResolver's query method.
And that in turn will call
the PetProvider query method.
And from that,
we'll receive a Cursor as a result,
in order to use the same
production as before.
Third, to ensure that the app
is running, compile it and
double check that there
are no visible changes.
Now when you're done with these steps,
fill in this blank here
as to which URI you passed in
to the resolver's query method.