Now, the introduction of mixed strategy
brings us some curious philosophical problems
related to the idea of randomness, secrecy, and rationality.
We said that sometimes the rational strategy
can be a mixed strategy.
That is, ones with probability in it.
Probability P, I do action A,
and with probability 1 - P I do action B.
And that suggests that we need some secrecy
so that our opponent doesn't know which of these random choices we're making.
The curious thing is that that's only true
at the extent of an individual play,
not to the extent of the strategy itself.
So, if this is the optimal strategy,
a mixed strategy, it's okay for us to reveal
that strategy to our opponent because our opponent
can also compute that that's our rational strategy,
and so we won't do any worse by revealing to the opponent
exactly what our strategy is.
However, the actual implementation of that strategy,
that is, this is the grand strategy, that in this situation,
whenever we're faced with playing this game, this is what we'll do,
that part can be revealed, but the actual choice
that this time we're going to choose A or we're going to choose B,
of course, that has be to kept secret.
If we reveal that, if our opponent can somehow discover
which choice we're going to make based on this random choice,
then our opponent can get an advantage over us.
Now, with respect to rationality,
we said that a rational agent is one that does the right thing,
and that's still true.
However, it turns out that there are games
in which you can do better if your opponent believes
you are not rational, and that has been said about various politicians
throughout history, and I won't pick on one or another.
But sometimes it has been said that they are intentionally
cultivating an image of being crazy
so that they can gain an advantage
when faced with certain games with opponents.
For example, suppose 1 action available to a leader is to go to war,
but both sides realize that the strategy of going to war
is dominated by other strategies and thus would be irrational.
So, a leader who is perceived to be rational and makes a threat
of "Give me this concession, or I'll go to war against you,"
that's not a credible threat.
The leader's threat would be dismissed, and it would have no effect.
However, if the leader can convince the opponent
that he is irrational or crazy, then the threat suddenly becomes credible.
And so note that being irrational doesn't help,
but appearing irrational can gain you an advantage.