For a key for the user,
we want something completely unique.
For the same reason that we wanted
a completely unique key for
shopping lists, and shopping list items.
We also wanted to be something that's
easily accessible from AuthData.
We also want a piece of data that we
can have on hand when the user is
first created.
In relation to the keys uniqueness,
two users could have the same full name,
especially if they have a common
name and we get tons and
tons of users using ShoppingList++.
So, this probably not a good option.
Now, we've been using push IDs in this
situation, but given that we have
a unique UID and an email, do we really
need to generate a new unique ID?
Not really.
If we wanted something like that we
could use the already generated UID.
So push ID is a no.
That leaves us with either using
the user's email or the user's UID.
Now, UIDs are usually the go-to choice.
They're uniquely generated for
each user of Firebase.
Now, because it's going to generate
a different UID if a user signs in and
makes a user with Password/Email
versus with Google,
the UID is actually not a really
great option for our scenario.
But because the two things that these
accounts share is an email, and
usually an email is only
associated with one person,
email is actually a pretty
good choice for us.
But there is one issue with
using emails as a key.
By nature, emails contain periods.
And periods are actually not
allowed as part of a Firebase key.
So I'll give you some advice about
how to deal with that in the spec
that I'm about to send you.