Now I want to talk about
one more representation for
planning, called situation calculus.
To motivate this, suppose we wanted to
have a goal of moving all the cargo from
airport A to airport B, regardless of
how many pieces of cargo there are.
You can't express the notion of all
in propositional languages like
classical planning, but
you can in first order logic.
There are several ways to use
first order logic for planning.
The best known is situation calculus.
It's not a new kind of logic.
Rather, it's regular, first order logic,
with a set of conventions for
how to represent states and actions.
I'll show you what the conventions are.
First, actions
are represented as objects,
in first order logic,
normally by functions.
So we would have a function,
like the function fly,
of a plane and a from airport,
and a to airport.
Which represents an object
which is the action.
Then we have situations, and situations
are also objects in the logic.
And they correspond not to states but
rather to paths.
The paths of actions that we
have in state space search.
So if you arrive at what
would be the same world state
by two different sets of actions,
those would be considered two different
situations in situation calculus.
We describe situations by objects.
So we usually have a initial situation,
often called s0.
And then we have a function
on situations called result.
So the result of a situation object and
an action object is equal
to another situation.
And now instead of describing
the actions that are applicable in
the situation with
the predicate actions of s.
Situation calculus, for some reason,
decided not to do that.
And instead we're going to
talk about the actions that
are possible in the state, and
we're going to do that with a predicate.
If the predicate possible of a and s,
is an action, a, possible in a state.
Now, there's a specific form for
describing there predicates.
And in general, it has a form
of some precondition of state s
implies, that is possible
to do action a in state s
I'll show you the possibility axiom for
the fly action.
We would say if there's some p,
which is a plane in state s.
And there's some x,
which is an airport in state x.
And there's some y which
is also an airport
is an state s and
p is at location x in state s,
then that implies that it's possible
to apply p from x to y in state s.
And that's known as a possibility
axiom for the action fly.