Since we're talking about
the trickiness of RPC calls,
let's also talk about errors in
fault handling and reporting.
When the client hangs while waiting
on a remote procedure call,
it is often hard to take
what exactly is the problem?
The server can be overloaded, the client
request may be lost, the response may be
lost, the server machine may have
crashed, or the server process may have
crashed, or some element in the network,
some switch or router may be down.
Even if the RPC runtime incorporates
some mechanisms that time out
whenever a client RPC call hangs,
and then retries them automatically.
They're really no guarantees that the
problem will be resolved or that the RPC
runtime will be able to provide some
better understanding of what's going on.
And potentially, for some cases, it is
possible to really understand what is
the cause of the error, but
in principle that is too complex.
It would have involve a lot of overhead,
and ultimately,
it's still unlikely that it will
provide a definitive answer.
For this reason IPC systems typically
try to introduce a new type of error
notification or a new type of signal or
exception that tries to capture what
went wrong with an RPC request without
claiming to provide the exact detail.
This serves as a catch all for
all types of errors,
all types of failures that can
potentially happen during an RPC call.
And it also can potentially
indicate a partial failure,
so maybe the call really
didn't quite fail,
it's just that the client doesn't
know what succeeded and what failed.