Now that we understand these lines of
code and have practiced typing them,
go ahead and add them to the increment
method within the main activity.
Remember that a common beginner mistake
is to specify the data type again.
You only need to specify the data type
once when you declare the variable.
After that,
you can just use the variable name.
If we add a breakpoint on Line 25 and
then run the debugger,
we can check what the quantity
variable value is at each step.
If I click on the plus button, then
the breakpoint on Line 25 is triggered.
I'll click step over to go
to the next line of code.
Now we see that the quantity variable
has been created with the value of two.
If I click step over again,
then we see that quantity variable
has been updated to three.
This is because of the quantity
equals quantity plus one line.
Then we can hit play
to resume the app and
we can see the latest quantity value
being shown on this screen here.
Do the same thing in
your version of the app.
Modify the increment method to
update the quantity variable
using quantity equals quantity plus one.
Then use a debugger to step through and
verify the quantity variable
value at each step.
After that, feel free to experiment
with different expressions for
updating the quantity variable.
You could do quantity plus one,
or one plus quantity.
Or you could use the variable name
twice, or as many times as you want, or
you can do other arithmetic operations.
You can run this on your
device to see what happens.
When you're done experimenting, go ahead
and revert back to what you had before,
so that we can continue with the lesson.
Check these boxes when you're done.