So, what is an operating system and
what is the operating system's role in computing systems?
Let's start taking a look at what a computing system looks like and
how it's used.
Computing systems consist of a number of hardware components.
This includes one or more processing element.
So, processors or CPUs.
Today, the CPUs further consist of multiple cores.
So, a single CPU will have more than one processing element.
And there's also memory, and there are also devices like network interconnects
for connecting to the Internet, like your Ethernet port or your Wifi card.
Other components include graphics processing cards, like GPUs for instance.
And also storage devices like hard disks, SSDs, flash devices like USB drives.
Except for in some very specific environments like certain embedded platforms or
sensors, all of these hardware components will be used by multiple applications.
For instance, on your laptops or
desktops, you may currently be running a browser, a text editor, perhaps Skype.
You may have a number of other applications.
In data centers, server machines also run also multiple applications,
maybe a web server,
a database, or some computation intensive simulation, many other options.
An operating system is the layer of systems software that
sits between the complex hardware and all of these applications.
There isn't one formal definition of what an operating system is.
So instead, we will look at the role that the operating system serves and
the functionality that it must provide.
And in that way,
we will try to build our understanding of what an operating system is.
First, the operating system hides the complexities of the underlying
hardware from both the applications, as well as the application developers.
You don't want to worry about disk sectors or
blocks when you're saving the output of a computation in your program.
For instance, the operating system hides the complexities of
the various types of storage devices, so hard disks, SSDs, USB flash.
And it manages a higher level abstraction of file, and it provides some
number of operations, like reads and writes, that you can perform on that file.
Similarly, for a web server application, when you're accepting and
responding to end user requests, you don't want to think about the bits and
the packets that you need to compose when performing that communication.
Instead, the operating system abstracts the networking resource.
It provides a higher level abstraction that is typically called a socket.
And then it provides some services to send and
receive packets or data from that socket.
Furthermore, the operating system not only hides the hardware complexity, but
it actually also manages the underlying hardware on behalf of
the executing applications.
For instance, the operating system decides how many and
which one of these resources will the application use.
For instance, the operating system allocates memory for
these applications, and also is the one that
schedules these applications on to the CPU that can execute them.
It also controls access of these applications to
the various devices in the system.
So overall, it's responsible for all types of resource allocations and
resource management tasks on behalf of these applications.
Finally, when multiple applications are co-running on the same hardware,
the operating system must ensure that each of
them can make adequate progress and that they don't hurt each other.
So, it will provide isolation and protection.
For instance, the operating system will allocate to
different applications different parts of the underlying physical memory.
And it will also make sure that unless explicitly intended,
applications don't access each other's memory.
This is important both from a protection perspective so they don't read each
other data, and it's also important from an isolation perspective so
that they don't end up overwriting each other's memory.
Note that these types of mechanisms are important even in environments that
were traditionally considered embedded platforms like mobile phones,
where hardware was typically running just one application.
Think about it.
How many applications do you currently have running on your smartphone?
On my phone, I have a browser, I have Skype, I have Facebook.
And I still have that one key application, and
that is the actual phone, making phone calls and receiving phone calls.