This kind of, of approximation or obstruction is typical,
particularly at the analysis stage, and you should feel comfortable with,
with making these decisions so you can focus on the, the important details and
avoid getting bogged down in some of the nuances of things.
The third part of the class model is the attributes and what we'll do here is,
as far as an analysis model is concerned is we are going to try to capture
in attributes, those parts of the application which the user can actually see.
And those are called percepts, and so we're going to try to understand what
all the percepts are, and model each one of those as an attribute. And so in
this case, can you think of, for the viewport, what is, what it's percepts are?