First, we'll bring in the last dataset
that we built with the principal
components for the four weather metrics,
and the few other measures we included.
The file is named
PCA Complete Process Results.yxdb.
A link to my dataset is available for
download in the instructor notes.
Next, we will connect in
the K-Centroids Diagnostics tool.
It's purpose is to help assess the
appropriate number of clusters to use
for a clustering solution.
Let's take a look at how we
might configure this tool.
First, I'm going to select
the variables, I think I want to use for
my cluster model.
Now, I included some extra,
principle components when we ran
the principal component's process.
But that doesn't mean that
I need to keep them all.
In this case,
I included in the PC process PC3 for
temp, PC4 for rain, and
PC4 for precipitation.
I've decided that I don't
want to use those for
this initial cluster diagnostics.
So just because I have
certain variables in my data,
it doesn't mean that I
have to use them all.
Since clustering is really
an iterative process.
You may find that you want to try out
various combination of variables to see
which might give you better results.
However, when using PCA,
one thing to note is that you should
never skip the first components and
use later ones.
That's because if you
recall how PCA works,
it tries to get as much variance
in the first component with
each subsequent component
having less variance.
If you want to leave out any components,
leave out the last ones,
like I've shown here.
Next, I'll check to
standardize the fields.
As we discussed earlier, clustering
algorithms are very sensitive to
outliers, and standardizing
the fields helps eliminate that.
I'll just keep the z score selected
as the default way to standardize.
Next, within Alteryx,
we have three different methods
that we can use to create clusters.
K.Mean, K.Medians, and Neural Gas.
I won't go in to the map
detail on these.
At a high level, each method differs
in the placement of the centroid and
the way distances are measured.
For more details on each method,
take a look at the reading node.
Since it's easy to do, my typical
approach is to test with all three
methods to see if I get some
distinct results from each one.
And then choose the method that
seems to provide the better results.
For our example,
I'll keep it on K.Means.
And finally, we have some options that
are related directly to testing for
the number of clusters.
The first two choices are for the
minimum and maximum number of clusters.
As I mentioned earlier, you might have
operational constraints that won't
allow for more than a certain number
of segments that can be used.
Or you may want to limit the number
of clusters to make sure that
you can make sense and act on each one.
And of course, the minimum needs
to be set to at least two.
Since having only one cluster eliminates
the need for this process to begin with.
For the purpose of the exercise,
let's set the minimum at 6 and
the maximum at 12.
For the last two options related
to Bootstrap replication and
starting seeds,
we will just leave at the default.
If you'd like to understand
the details behind these,
please take a look at the reading note.