We first add the user class to
the models.py file, like shown here.
Functions to hash and
verify a password are also provided.
Now, in the views.py file,
we will add the logic to create users.
I will add the user route so
that it will either create a new user or
identify an existing one.
Now I will add
the auth.verify_password decorator.
So Flask http off knows how
I want to validate my users.
Once that is done, I can protect
a route like /Bagels with the off.login
required variable, just like I did here.
With all of the code
modifications in place,
we should now be able to pass all
the tests in our Bagel tester.pie file.
Check out the instructor
notes to view this code.