Let's look into the project and
give it a try.
If we look over here in our outline,
we can see our three text fields and
our label.
And if we select a text field and
look in the identity inspector, you can
see that its class is UI Text field.
None of these views have custom classes.
Now, let's close these windows.
And switch back to
the project navigator.
Here, you can see the emoji
text field delegate and
the colorizer text field delegate.
They each have a class to themselves but
you're probably wondering
where the third delegate is.
Here in the view controller.swift file,
you can see that our
main view controller is also
a UI text field delegate.
It's going to be the delegate for
the character counter.
If we look a little closer at
our view controller.swift file,
you can see here are the outlets for
our four views.
And here are the two delegates and
if we scroll down here, to viewDidLoad.
We can see that each of the delegates
gets assigned to a text field.
And that the delegate for the character
counter, gets assigned to self.
If we swap the delegates, the behavior
of the text field swaps as well.
You can see here that I have switched
the colorizer and the emoji delegates.
So, let's see how that affected
our text field behavior.
And here, you can see that
the behaviors have swapped.
The first text field is
acting as the colorizer and
the second text field is
acting as the emoji fire.
We can do this because the three
text fields are identical.
The only difference is
supplied by the delegates.
In a little while,
we're going to trace the flow of control
through the objects in this app.
That way, we can see exactly how these
text fields interact with delegates,
using the UI text field
delegate protocol.