It's time for us to step through
some code using breakpoints.
Currently we're in the breakpoint
bug view controller and
we have a single breakpoint set
in the addBugToView method.
As we've seen before we can
set breakpoints like this on
individual lines of code.
And if the breakpoint's reached then
our app will go into a paused state.
And from here the application's
technically running, but
we have the power to execute
our app line by line.
And this is what is known
as stepping through code.
You can think of stepping through code
like having fine grain control over
the execution of your program.
So lets go ahead and run the application
and trigger this breakpoint.
So go to the breakpoint and
debugging scene and tap the screen.
There we go.
And now our breakpoint's reached.
The debug area appears, and we can
focus our attention to the horizontal
debug bar, here, that runs across
the top of the debug area.
On the far left there's a button for
hiding and revealing the debug area.
The next button,
called the Breakpoint Activation button,
looks like a smaller version of the
breakpoint arrow that we seen before.
And if we click it,
then it will toggle all the currently
enabled breakpoints as either on or off.
So it's kind of like a global state for
active break points.
Note that any breakpoints that are
currently disabled when you click this
button are not going to be effected.
So it only works with active
breakpoints, and we can demonstrate
this if I set a break point here
on the moveBugsAnimation line.
I'll keep it inactive, and
then we'll toggle this button.
Now they both go grey but when I go
back and the global state is active,
only our previously active breakpoints
are actually enabled by this.
This inactive breakpoint
is not affected.
We can drag this off,
we don't need it for now.
The next button on the bar is for
continuing the programs execution.
The hotkey for
this button is control command y,
you may be using this one pretty often.
And if we click it then our
app will resume like so.
So let's tap the screen again and
we'll reach the breakpoint again.
The next three buttons are also
related to execution control, and
they're called Step Over,
Step Into and Step Out.
You will really want to become
comfortable with these buttons because
they are most frequently
used when you are debugging.
And we'll get back to
them in just a moment.
Continuing right, we have a button for
the debug view hierarchy which allows
us to debug our apps visually.
And we're going to talk more
about it in the next lesson.
And then next, we have this arrow which
will allow us to simulate a location.
And we're not going to use this
button for this particular course.
The last three pieces of the tool
bar are called the jump bar and
they're similar to what we saw
earlier in the debug navigator.
So let's give our self some
more space first, there we go.
So the first element of the jump
bar is the current process.
And if we select so many bugs,
the current process.
Then we could see all the different
threads in this process.
And then from there we can jump to
the different stack frames within
a particular thread.
Now at the top level this might be
really useful if you're debugging two
processes at the same time,
like a client and a server.
If you want to investigate multiple
processes simultaneously it's a little
bit advanced, but Apple has
a great example in their 2012 WWDC
video called Debugging in XCode.
And I posted a link to this
particular session that they recorded
in the instructor notes
if you're interested.
The second element in the jump bar
is the currently selected thread.
If you click this element,
just like we saw a second ago,
we can jump between threads and
the thread stack frames.
And then the final element
is the current stack frame.