For Jesse Owens, that was an important state in his life.
It was a state as far as the Olympics are concerned.
And it turned out,
it was an important state as far as world events were concerned.
The color magenta, however, is neither.
It's not an event or it's not a state.
It's just the value of an attribute.
The building's sprinkler system turning on due to a fire.
That's an event, an instantaneous change of state.
Telephone ringing is also an event.
Rainy day is a state.
Big Ben chiming, now I know it takes a long time for it to chime, but
let's just think of it as being the start of chiming, that's an event.
Once again, an abstraction over that whole sequence of chimes.
The Inter, International Space Station is neither.
You can think of it as a very, very, very complex object itself.
And the screen saver on your laptop turning on, event.