So now our ViewController
should be all set.
But our buttons still need some work.
This button is an instantiation
of the UIButton class.
It belongs to a category of view
objects called control objects.
Control objects turn user actions
like finger taps into events.
Now we need to create
an object inside this button
that will tell it to contact our
ViewController when it's clicked.
We call this a target action, and
this is the word that IB action
is derived from in story word.
This little target action holds
three key pieces of information.
An object to notify, the target,
the method to use, the action,
and the event that will
trigger the target action.
So now let's go back to Xcode and
implement our target action.
We do this by invoking
a method on the button object.