As we look through
AddressBookSpec.js file,
we can start identifying
some redundant code.
We're having to set up our addressBook
and Contact in each of our specs.
On the one hand, this is a good thing
because we're getting a nice clean slate
for each and every test.
On the other hand,
we're doing this manually.
Thankfully, Jasmine offers a way for
us to define a function
that should be run before each and
every one of our tests.
It's called the beforeEach function.
Let's refactor our spec real quick, so
we don't have to keep
repeating ourselves.
I've moved the addressBook and
thisContact, variable declarations,
up to the suite itself.
Remember, in JavaScript,
inner scopes have access to
variables declared in outer scopes.
So I know all of my specs will
have access to these variables.
Now all I need to do is
place my instantiation
within this beforeEach function.
Now, these two lines we'll
run before each of my test,
contained within this test suite.
You may ask yourself,
why didn't I move the addContact
line into beforeEach as well.
With just these two specs,
I could have done that.
It would have been fine, but I'm not
completely sure that adding a contact
is required functionality for any future
specs I may write within this suite.
For now I'm just going to keep those
lines right where they are, and
if I decide otherwise in
the future I can always move it up