The code for this course lives in
a git repository hosted on GitHub.com,
at GitHub.com/udacity/ud406.
Let's check it out.
Here we are.
If we scroll down to the bottom,
here we'll find a read me that actually
explains everything you'll
need to do to download and
start loading up the course demos and
exercises.
If you're familiar with git and
GitHub, just go ahead and fork and
clone this repository.
Or, easier,
if you scroll back up to the top,
you can hit this Download Zip
button to grab the code.
If you can't access GitHub at all, you
can also download the code directly from
the downloadable section
in the classroom.
Now that our zip has
finished downloading and
we moved it to the desktop,
we can go ahead and extract it.
And here we are inside the course code.
You can see all the demos, exercises,
and exercise solutions for the course.
Go ahead and
grab the course code for yourself.
Check off these boxes as
you complete each task.