Another way you'll get support in
the Nanodegree is at office hours.
These sessions happen
multiple times each week.
Another perfect place to
deepen your learning and
ask your questions to
ask the coach team.
The schedule is listed in
your Nanodegree portal.
Sessions often start out with
coaches talking about common
issues students encounter or elaborating
on a particular tricky concept.
Then we move into an open question and
answer time.
Decisions happen over Google Hangouts on
Air, so you'll need to request to join
our Google+ community
to participate in them.
You'll also need a Google+
account to join the community, so
if you don't have that, make one first.
If you can't attend sessions live,
don't worry.
They record it.
You can post your
questions in advance and
then watch the session afterward if
you can't make it to hear our answers.
To learn how to participate
in Hangouts on Air,
read the doc that's linked
in the instructor notes.