In database terminology, a column
with a references constraint on it,
is also called a foreign key.
Now this has always sounded like
a bit of a weird term to me,
like it was the key to a lock
from far across the sea, but
a foreign key is just a column or
a set of columns in one table,
that uniquely identifies
a row in another table.
It's possible for
a table to have two or more foreign
keys, actually that's really common.
For instance, consider a database of
students grades in various courses.
Here we've got a table of students
names and their ID numbers.
And the ID is a primary key
because names aren't unique.
And we have a table of courses, with
course names and course IDs as well.
And then we have the grades table,
which has foreign keys
into both of those tables.
Here are the same tables,
but this time drawn out.
Usually a foreign key will point to
the primary key of the referenced table.
That's because the whole point of
a foreign key is to uniquely identify
a row in the referenced table, and
the table's primary key does that.
Now here's a quiz.
These tables are for
a more complex forum app than
the one you worked on last lesson.
This app allows users to log in and
post comments, and
also vote on other people's posts.
Take a look at these tables, and see if
you can figure out which columns should
be primary keys, and which columns
should be foreign keys referencing them.
In the users table,
we have a username or handle or
alias, and the user's full name.
In this posts table,
we have the post content, the author's
username, and an ID number for the post.
And in the votes table,
we have the id number of a post,
the username of somebody who
voted on that post, and a 1 or
minus 1 for whether they liked it or
disliked it.
So for each one of these columns, if it
should be a primary key of that table,
put a P in that box.
If it should be a foreign key, put an F.
If it shouldn't be either one,
leave the box empty.
Also, although there's no check boxes
for them, think about if any of
these tables should have primary
keys with more than one column.