Recall that we have actually
talked a lot about Panoramas.
We basically said, if we took a bunch
of pictures, and again, this is
the picture that you've seen many of
times, of Lesko's Sports Stadium.
Each individual picture does
not carry enough detail
to kind of showcase the space very well.
By combining all of them, we can
actually, now generate a newer image.
In this instance, a Panorama that
actually captures the space very well
because primarily, it goes beyond
the limitations of a limited
field of view of each and every image,
and generates a larger field of view.
So, in this case, 7 pictures,
which are each about 3 by 2,000
pixels about 7.1 megapixel.
Was used to generate a 31 megapixel
image with a field of view of 151
degrees wide, and of course,
it took a lot more disk space,
and everything else, but of course,
it shows a lot more detail.
Recall also,
that while we were looking at Panoramas,
we learned about how to generate Planar,
Spherical, and Cylindrical Panoramas.
Again, took a lot of pictures, stitched
them together to generate a Panorama,
and by now, you know, of course,
how we can do this kind of stuff.
Now, we're going to start
taking one step forward, and
try to think about what else can we
do with a bunch of pictures of space?