To start off with here's the native
version of my check out form.
See how it looks kind
of material designee?
The reason why is because I want to
building the polymer version first
because to be honest my design
skills aren't really that great.
I wanted to apply some material
design best practices and
then I just copied the results
over using native HTML.
With this version I actually kept
a few of the original inputs, but
I did do as much as I could to
get rid of as many as possible.
I also made the language
a little bit friendlier.
And I did my best to make sure
that the form was pared down
to just the bare minimum.
I also make the assumption that
somebody wants to use the same
billing address as they used for
shipping.
That allows me to add this
check box which i like.
If somebody wants to use a different
billing address they simply click it and
then enter it.
You can see that I'm using
placeholders in lieu of labels.
But if you look in the source code,
you can see that the labels
are actually still there.
Screen readers need labels so
I wound up just simply hiding
them using a special CSS class.
This keeps them in the dom,
but they don't show up.
There's also a bit of
validation happening.
Among other things,
credit card numbers are being parsed
to find the type of credit card.
That's pretty helpful.
Of course,
this version doesn't quite follow all of
the best practices that you've learned.
I wound up ditching
the progress bar at the top and
I'm doing nothing to
help out with location.
And so here is the polymer
version that uses gold elements.
The similarities are obvious but
there are two big differences
that I want to point out.
First off, there's a nice progress
bar at the top that expands
as the user fills in
validated information.
And two, this version takes
advantage of a user's location.
Watch as I click in the address bar.
The site wants to know if
it can use my location.
I wound up hooking up this
input to the Google Maps API.
Which allows me to auto complete
addresses as a user's typing.
And now that I have the address,
I'm also helping the user out
by giving them the zip code already
in the credit card information area.
And of course if the billing
address is different for
the credit card,
you simply click right here.
And the browser scrolls down to
show you a new address input, nice.
There are a few other changes that I
made so I encourage you to check out
the source code which you can find
a link to in the instructor notes.
So how did your checkout
forms compared to mine?
Think you did better?
If you haven't already,
share yours in the forum.
In the next lesson you'll be
practicing with mobile form techniques.
Before then, here's the next part
of the interview series with Luke
where he'll discuss mobile first.