So that was how well humans could do.
If you take a look at
how well machines do.
Okay?
The SVMs performs better
than any single sub, or
I should say than every single subject.
In other words, the machine was
better than the best person.
Okay, and the overall performance,
you can see the SVM didn't care at all,
really, about the low-res
versus the hi-res.
In fact, it had slightly higher error
rates on the high resolution than low.
Which and,
you know, could be that difference
is not statistically significant.
Unsurprisingly, the humans did
much better at the high resolution
remember we saw was 6% and the low
resolution, you know, they did awful.
So the machine did
better than the humans.
This is something we see a lot,
if you have lots of data to train.
The machine learning methods can
be quite sensitive to learning
the distinctions, sometimes
better than what, humans can do.
The one you have to be a little careful
of in this particular thing is,
remember that low resolution
image I showed you?
I don't, I, I, I went back and
I read the paper.
On the left is the original
48 by 84 image.
Okay?
In the middle is a, 12 by,
is the 12 by 21 image that they showed.
But of course,
it's blown up to be the same size,
and when you blow it up to be the same
size, you put these edges in here.
Now we talked about this.
Right?
What happens if you just replicate
the pixels?
Remember aliasing?
What you've done is you've,
you've put in these high frequency
things that really don't belong there.
If you were to smooth that image,
you would remove that aliased stuff, or
you could reconstruct it better, you'd
get a picture that looks like this.
And I'm going to guess that this
picture would have been easier for
humans to deal with than this picture
even though they have exactly the same
amount of information, right?
This picture is just the blurred
version of that one.
Okay?
So that, that's something to,
to remember.
In fact, let's do a quick
psychophysics experiment.
You ready?
All right,
can you recognize that picture?
Say no.
>> No!
>> Okay.
I'm going to take that same picture and
now I'm just going to blur it.
Can you recognize it now?
Do you remember the picture?
Come here, come here,
come here, come here.
I'm going to make you get on camera.
On camera.
On camera, there you go.
So, so who is that?
>> That's you.
>> That's my, that's your hero,
you're supposed to say.
>> That's my hero.
>> There you go, yes.
That's just, that ugly puss is me.
Now you know when you were
looking at just this picture,
that was probably hard to tell.
So you have to be a little careful on
how you do things and you know, for
your psychophysics.
So that, that ends that digression.
By the way here were the hardest
examples for humans to classify, okay?
So you might take a look at them and,
and
try to decide what you think they are.
I'm not going to do that because
I don't know who they are and
I don't want to insult anybody.
These were the actual true examples.
I mean, sorry, the true labels.
So did you get them right?
I got one wrong.
I'm not going to tell you which.