So, the first is, we're going to
play either the beeping noise, or
we're going to play the radio depending
on, I think that we had that setting
from earlier, from the other
system of which mode we're in.
>> So we have a state machine
indicating whether we're in a mode
that we expect to hear beeps or
we expect to hear radio.
And depending upon which of
those two states we're in,
we would expect to hear different
things coming out of the speaker.
>> Right.
>> Okay.
What else?
>> And then we are going to be working
with our two other internal state
machines.
The one for starting the snooze
timer that'll run up to ten minutes.
>> But that's only if the user
has hit the snooze button.
>> That's right.
Okay.
>> So we don't expect,
as a response to the times matching-
>> Right, right.
>> That that one happens.
>> Okay, well then, just that one
system then, of the internal system for
our alarm in which,
after an hour, it'll go off.
>> So we have to start
counting that hour up in order
to know when to turn it off.
So to deal with this,
we've invented a new event,
event twenty, when the clock
time reaches the alarm time.
And we need to list as the responses for
that event what Jared
was just talking about.
>> So while we're on the topic
of setting the internal timers,
we said the snooze one, this won't be
effected unless we're talking about
the specific event where
we press the snooze button.
If you were to press the snooze button,
will that reset the alarm,
the internal alarm timer, back to zero?
>> So, recall that we have this timer
which is timing up to an hour, for
how long the radio's going to play or
the beeper's going to beep.
And Jerod's question is if during that
time the user hits the snooze button to
shut them off,
whether that timer resets.
I don't personally know, but
that's an excellent question that
the developer would
actually have an answer to.
My intuitive reaction is that no,
it doesn't reset the timer,
it just allows you to snooze
a little while longer.
>> Okay.