Let's look at an example.
And, for instance, we said one of the responsibilities of
the operating system is to manage resources like memory.
So, we'll look at a memory management based example.
To do that, the operating system uses a memory page as an abstraction.
And this abstraction corresponds to some addressable region of memory of
some fixed size, for instance, four k.
The operating system also integrates a number of mechanisms to
operate on that page.
It can allocate that page in DRAM, and
it can map that page into the address piece of the process.
By doing that it, allows the process to access the actual physical memory that
corresponds to the contents of that page.
In fact, over time,
this page may be moved across different locations in physical memory.
Or, it sometimes may even be stored on disk, if we need to make room for
some other content in physical memory.
This last one brings us to the third element, policies.
Since it is faster to access data from memory then on disk,
the operating system must have some policies to decide whether the contents of
this page will be stored in physical memory or copied on disk.
And, a common policy that operating systems incorporate is one that decides that
the pages that have been least recently used over a period of time are the ones
that will no longer be in physical memory, and instead will be copied on this.
We refer to this also as swappings.
So, we swap the pages.
It's no longer in physical memory, it's in disk.
The rational for that is that pages that have not been accessed in a while, so
the least recently used ones, are likely not to be as important, or
likely will not even be used any time in the near future.
And, that's why we can afford to copy them on disk.
The ones that have been accessed more frequently are likely more important, or
likely recurrently working on that particular part of the content, so
we will continue accessing them, and that's why we maintain them in memory.