So let's look at the whole
concept of parallax.
So from these two eyes, if I was looking
at a scene, and here I'm just going to
create a synthetic scene here, and
I'm going to put a object like a star.
If the left eye was looking at the
object, that basically would mean that
a ray of light is coming out
from here and going there.
And of course,
coming from this one would go here.
So the ray of light actually going in to
capture the scene from the right eye,
of course sees the star and
of course has got the red background.
Which actually, would then actually
show an image like this, right?
Because there's a red background,
there's a star in front of it,
this is what you'd see
from the right eye.
The left eye on the other hand,
would see, this.
So one of the observations
that are important for
understanding the concept of parallaxes.
That points at different depths,
will displace differently.
We'll get to that in a second, but
you basically see that now both these
eyes are seeing something different.
And that's the kind of point that
we want to make here to kind of
understand what's going on.
Parallax, which we'll talk about in
a bit, basically kind of says is,
because of this feature, that if
this thing was further back here,
it would display differently,
or look differently as
I would actually look at this
object in relationship to it.
And similarly, on the other hand,
if objects were closer,
they would look different to.
So here, basically you see the
relationship that because it's in front
of it, it looks different because of
the fact the background is different.
In case of course both of them
are the same distance, but
if they were different you can
actually see the difference
that it'll have in our
perception of depth.