So for the stack question.
You'll often see where I think Sam was
very good about having an answer and
kind of having a solution to begin with,
but,
I would have liked if you asked a few
more of kind of follow up questions I
think we've described a very naive
solution well I needed a good job there.
You'll see a lot of times where people
expect to have to write
an entire class from scratch.
So I think Sam initially thought okay,
well I'm going to have to write entire
stack class and then go on from there.
You should ask your interviewer
what level of detail they want.
And also when you're writing the code,
you should also ask what
they're looking for.
If they want syntax perfect code,
then write syntax perfect code.
But in this case I didn't really care.
I cared more about the implementation
and the structure.
And so I think Sam could probably go
through and ask me a few more questions
about the level of detail I wanted,
because I was perfectly fine with him
using the Java util stack, but he felt
he would need red zone in the beginning.
So that's a part where
maybe he could follow up.