Welcome to Computer Vision.
Robotics can essentially be broken
down into a three step cycle.
The first step is to sense or
perceive the world.
The second step is to decide what
to do based on that perception.
And the third step is to perform
an action to carry out that decision.
Computer vision is a major part of
the perception step in that cycle.
If you ask Sebastian, he'll tell
you that 80% of the challenge of
building a self-driving
car is perception.
>> And
this module is all about perception.
Computer vision is the art and
science of perceiving and
understanding the world
around you through images.
In the case of self-driving cars,
computer vision helps us detect
lane markings, vehicles,
pedestrians, and other elements in the
environment in order to navigate safely.
Later in this nano degree program,
you'll be using laser and
radar data for the task of perception.
So you might ask,
why bother doing this at all with camera
images when we have more sophisticated
instruments at our disposal?
So why are we doing this, David?
>> Good question.
Self-driven cars employ a suite
of sophisticated sensors, but
humans do the job of driving with
just two eyes and one good brain.
In fact,
we can even do it with one eye closed.
>> Indeed we can.
So let's take a closer look at
why using cameras instead of
other sensors might be an advantage
in developing self-driving cars.
Radar and lidar see the world in 3D,
which can be a big advantage for
knowing where you are relative
to your environment.
A camera sees in 2D but at much higher
spatial resolution than radar and
lidar, such that it's actually
possible to infer depth information
from camera images.
The big difference,
however, comes down to cost where
cameras are significantly cheaper.
>> That's right.
It is altogether possible
that self-driving cars will
eventually be outfitted with
just a handful of cameras, and
a really smart algorithm
to do the driving.
That's why we're really excited
to dive into computer vision with
you in this module.