All right, let's start by creating
a new class and call it reminder tasks.
Inside, let's create a public
constant string called
action increment order count.
This is the first intent to action that
the reminder tasks knows how to handle.
Then we'll create a method that
increments the water count
using the preference utilities
that we've created for
you which simply updates an integer
value stored in shared preferences.
Finally, we are going to create a method
called execute task that increments
the water count if the action matches
action, increment water count,
which is the only action that
reminder tasks knows about so far.
Now, let's go to the actual intent
service, go to water reminder intent
service and create the water
reminder intent service class.
Make sure you extend from
the intent service then,
we'll fill in the default constructor
with the name of the service,
which in this case would use the name
of water reminder intent service.
The next thing to do in this file
is to over ride the on handled and
tenth method which is the method
that the intense service calls
on the background thread.
Very similar to the eluded and
background method that we used for
a same task loader.
We are going to set the action for
the service to perform
using intent.setAction.
So let's get the intent.getAction
here to retrieve it.
Then we'll call
ReminderTask.executeTask with that
action as well as the necessary context.
We're almost done, services like
every other android component
needs to be registered in
the android manifest file.
So let's go there and
create a new service tag.
We'll do that within our
application's tag itself.
We'll set the Android name pointing
to our intent service class and
we'll set the server to false.
This works the same way as an exported
tag for content providers.
It controls whether other
applications can access your service.
This is important because we only want
our app to be able to call our service.
Finally, let's test to make
sure that all of that works.
We'll go to our MainActivity and
inside the method called incrementWater,
let's create a new explicit intent
called IncrementWaterCount
that refers to our service.
Then we'll set the action of the intent
to ACTION_INCREMENT_WATER_COUNT from out
WaterReminderIntentService.class.
And now all we have to do to
start our service is to call
start service with our
increment water count intent.
Remember that this increment water
method is already set up to be called
every time the user
clicks on the cup icon.
So now every time this image is clicked
the background service will increment
the count.
And because we've already set
the activity to listen to
the preference changes the UI will
display the updated count immediately.
Perfect, let's give it a go.
Now when we run our app and
start clicking on the cut icon
you can see that the counter is
incrementing as expected, perfect.