Most views in Android will stick
to a few simple text styles and
colors that will repeat
throughout the code.
Like for each of the listed activities
on the main screen of our app.
Each view is the same color with
the same text size and color.
And it will be tedious
to go into our xml and
type in the same property values for
each of these.
So instead, Android gives us a way to
group properties like the color and
size of a view, as a style or theme.
A style is an xml resource file,
found in the values folder,
where you can set all of these
properties in one place.
Then later we can apply that
one style to any view we want.
And the theme is created
in the same way.
A theme is just a style that's applied
to an entire activity or application and
not just one view.
For our next task, we'll go through how
to create and apply styles to our app.