Android throws an exception when you
try to access the network on the main
thread, but what does that mean?
Like any modern operating system,
Android supports doing
multiple things at once.
You see that when you hit the Recents
key to swap to other running apps or
when you do things like play
music in the background.
But Android multitasking
goes much deeper than that.
Each Android app can be divided
into multiple threads of execution,
that can all run concurrently.
On modern Android devices, these threads
of execution can be scheduled by the OS
to run on different CPU cores.
But the system might choose to time
slice the amount of single CPU
which means running each for
a period of time.
Either way,
to your application it appears as if
the threads are running concurrently.
To make things easier on the developer,
Android apps have a single
user interface thread.
This thread is responsible for getting
events from the various sensors and
setting up the next frame to draw.
To run at an ideal 60 frames per
second We need to make sure that all
the computation between draws
takes less than 17 milliseconds,
which is pretty fast.
In other words, we want to do as little
as possible on this main thread, but
networking can take seconds, which
means you're app would be frozen for
all that time if the networking
call is on the main thread.
The user couldn't interact with it.
After five seconds of
ignoring user input,
Android would actually prompt
the user to close your app.
So to use network,
we need to run the network task
on a secondary execution thread.
But we need to make changes
to the user interface,
like setting the text view to
show the result in the UI thread.
Fortunately, Android provides a helpful
framework pattern to do this.
Enter Async task,