Something that might have made you
a little uneasy is that I made
an assumption about the class name
navbar being unique to the page.
Class names are not guaranteed
to be unique on a web page and
many times a class name is used on
multiple elements on a web page, so
that way we can repeat
particular styles.
IDs however are typically reserved
as unique identifiers for HTML tags.
We can determine if a particular
class name is unique or
not by using d3selectAll function.
Instead of returning only one element,
the function will return any
elements which match the criteria of
the CSS selector that you
pass in to the function.
For example, if I pass in navbar class,
I'll get back a d3 selection.
In this case it was unique.
Another example is I could select
all the images on the page
by passing in the HTML
tag name of image.
Here I didn't use a class name but
usually you often use class names or
D selectors to select
elements on the page.
And now, the elements are not unique
since there's four different images.
There's a logo, and there's some social
icons at the bottom of the page.