So this general area of work, is actually started by, I guess,
probably Horn and maybe some others, but I certainly learned about it from back,
way back in the 70s and continued in the 80s and
90s quite a bit, it's referred to as shape from shading.
And the idea is, over here you see a picture of a real sphere this time, right,
and you can tell this is a sphere, right with the light source over here.
Likewise, you can tell that from this person that,
that probably this is the front part facing you and that the shape tapers off.
Likewise, you can tell from the shading here something about the texture and
the shape of the face.
And the, the question is,
is how do you use shading as sort of a cue for recovering the shape information?
So in order to talk about shape from shading or,
I'll call it shape from lighting.
Because one of the things that we're going to do in
a little bit called photometric stereo, it's not so
much a shading variation as it is from having multiple light sources.
What we have to do is we have to look at the relationship between the intensity
that's seen by the camera and the actual shape of the object.
Now, that means we have to look at that reflectance function.
Remember what we defined I guess two lessons ago about this interaction between
the surface normals and the light direction and the surface itself.
In particular we're going to introduce a mathematical construct.
Refered to as the reflectance map,
and the reflectance map will be the basis of a lot of what we'll be doing today