Let's talk about permissions.
When each APK is installed,
it's given its own unique Linux user ID.
And each app runs within its own
instance of an Android runtime.
As a result,
each app is completely sandboxed.
Its files, processes, and
other resources
are inaccessible to other apps.
This sandboxing approach
is used to ensure that,
by default,
no app can access sensitive data or
perform actions that could adversely
affect other apps, the OS or users.
Things like accessing the Internet,
getting the user's location or
reading or
modifying the contacts database.
Rather than asking the user each time an
app tries to access something sensitive,
you declare the permissions you
require in your app's manifest.
You can get a list of all the
permissions your app may require here.
So why not just ask for
all the permissions and
never worry about it again?
Well when users install your app
on older versions of Android,
they are greeted with a dialogue listing
the permissions you've requested,
along with more user
friendly descriptions.
Nothing says this app was built by
hackers who want to steal my data,
rob my house, clear out my bank account,
and take and share nude pictures of me,
like a weather app that wants access
to every permission on my device.
Since that can be overwhelming to users,
starting with Android 6.0 Marshmallow,
many permissions are granted without
the need for the permissions dialog.
Certain sensitive informations
must be acknowledged by the user
when your application is running.
The best practice is to request the
absolute minimum number of permissions.
Every time you need to request a new
permission, take as a flag to stop and
consider if there are other alternatives
that might achieve the same goal.
For example, in Android you can launch
the camera app and ask it to take
a picture on your behalf rather than
having to access the camera directly.