Okay great.
Now let's put it all together and
do some shell commands.
Each of the answers in this quiz will
involve globbing, but it'll also involve
remembering some of the other commands
you've learned in this course.
For the first task, you'd like to back
up some files from the www directory
to the backup directory.
Our second goal is to list all the files
in the current directory that end in jpg
or png.
And our final goal is to print
the string Short names: followed by all
the one-character filenames
in the current directory.
These questions are pretty tricky.
If you're having trouble,
head over to your terminal and
create a temporary directory
full of test files,
that way you can experiment and
try out your commands.