An additional example of doing this
kind of projector calibration,
in this instance with
a smaller object in the scene,
where you want to actually display
the information from a projector,
is showcased in this video here.
>> Hello, I'm here to talk to you
a little bit about our system for
automatic projector calibration.
The basic problem we're trying to
solve is the task where trying to fit
a projected image perfectly onto
a target surface such as this.
Typically that requires a screen to be
directly in front of the projector, and
at a very specific orientation,
to get an undistorted image.
But what we would like to do is be able
to place the screen in any location
that's convenient, and then calibrate
the projector onto the target surface.
To demonstrate our system I
have an unmodified projector,
a computer beneath the table,
and this target surface.
If I turn this surface over,
you can see that we've implemented
it with some electronics.
What we have here are optical fibers
that channel light energy from each
corner of the screen, to an electronics
package containing four optical sensors
and a USB connection to the PC.
When I turn the screen back over you can
see that there is no visual evidence
of the fibers.
The white surface acts
to hide the fibers and
also provides a light diffuser which
improves calibration reliability.
To calibrate onto the target, I can
simply place it in the projection area,
and then project a series of
great coded binary patterns.
These patterns uniquely identify
every pixel in the projection screen,
allowing us to discover
the location of each fiber.
We can then use this information
to project a corrected image.
Here in this close-up, you can see that
the quality of calibration is very high.
The discovered location of each fiber is
actually closest to the nearest pixel.
The prototype shown here
is capable of performing
the calibration in just over one second.
We're currently working on techniques
that will hopefully allow us to achieve
interactive rates.
Here's what the calibration process
looks like from the perspective of
the target.
You can see the irregular
flashing from the projector.
This pattern of flashes indicates
the location of the camera in
the projector's screen space.
To illustrate the robustness
of this technique,
we will gradually decrease
the projection angle of the calibration.
We have found that the calibration
continues to work reliably,
even though the projection
angle is less than two degrees.
In this last calibration,
the screen is actually facing
slightly away from the projector.
The expansion of the projection frustum
sufficient for this technique to work.
We can also fold the optical
path using a mirror,
with no effect on
the calibration process.
The image will be automatical reversed,
since the orientation of
the image is determined by
the screen and not the projector.
This wire frame test pattern
that I've been using
is mainly to make it easy to
see the quality of calibration.
By using open Gl or
Direct X, we can warp real time video
on low cost commodity hardware.
We also have an implementation that
allows us to work the active Windows
desktop creating a fully usable,
calibrated display.
IN this board, we've added a total of
six sensors, one in each corner, and
two across the middle.
This allows us to calibrate two
projectors that are placed side by side,
creating a method for automatically
stitching multiple projectors.
We calibrate each
projector individually, and
then blend the two images together.
>> So the previous method showed
us how to do the same thing here.
The big difference here is in the
previous system we had a camera looking
at the scene.
In this case they've
actually improvised and
put a small fiber sensors at,
in this instance six locations,
of course in the previous one
they just put four of them.
So in essence they basically
have is a one pixel sensor.
Just that single pixel and
then the grid pattern that actually is
shown on the surface allows us to kind
of uniquely identify exactly what
each one of those sensors is seeing.
And that allows him to calibrate for
this kind of information.
A really, nice, unique, simple example,
where I can, still using a projector and
a camera, but in a much simpler manner.
And again, the camera is basically
a simple slow lens one pixel camera.
And of course they use multiple ones