This quiz is about computational
speed limits like this one, or
if you prefer metric distances,
this one.
Start by considering a 2-D
mesh of physical processors.
You can, if you wish, imagine that this
mesh is actually a many core processor
that fits on a physical
die of a certain size.
Let's say that size is L by L.
In this mesh every interior
point is connected to its
eight nearest neighbors.
This means each processing unit can
communicate along diagonal routes.
Now consider a single
operation defined as follows,
it starts at the processing
unit at the center.
The operation then travels as a signal
to a unit at one of the corners.
It then turns around,
making a round trip back to the center.
Let's say you want to be able to do say,
3 trillion of these operations
per second sequentially.
So you want to do this
round trip operation,
center to corner to center,
center to corner to center.
And then do that 3
trillion times per second.
And by way of reminder,
a trillion is 10 to the 12th.
Here is my question.
If a signal travels at
the speed of light,
what is the maximum physical
dimension of this mesh?
In other words,
what's the largest l can be?
I want you to give your answer in
micrometers, or a micron, for short.
And since we're doing a back
of the envelope exercise,
you can round your answer
to one significant figure.
A handy fact is that the speed of light
is about 300 million meters per second.