In the evolution of camera, couple of other things have happened.
One, I believe, is our relationship on how we use a camera.
In the old days, this is the kind of, a very formal, you set up a camera and
you basically use it for a few pictures.
This kind of resulted in more of this stand up kind of relationship where
you began.
Spent a lot of time focusing and doing other types of things.
Too much more now, a standoffish, casual photography.
So again, formal to casual has been one of
the trends that's happened with photography.
Of course, we have lots of mobile cellphone cameras in everybody's hands.
Wearable cameras are now showing us, of course,
these are types of extreme sports cameras, people doing skiing, diving, and
even under water snorkeling and scuba diving with cameras like this and
giving you a very interesting experential sense of what's going on.
Of course I can't not mention my friend and colleague Thad Starner,
who worked with Google to kind of help create this Google Glass,
which is again a wearable camera widely being used for capturing experiences.
But, just to kind of showcase this could go completely in the, you know,
interesting directions, I'll let you think good or bad, but more and more
cameras are going to be worn by us on our bodies, for capturing experiences.
But this is where cameras are getting cheaper,
smaller, and getting much more wider use.
I love to share this example.
This is from the movie, Her and in fact, in this movie the character played
by Joaquin Phoenix always took a camera with him.
And in fact here you see the camera in his pocket and
it basically could see everything around him.
And of course they communicated and
shared experiences through the camera and of course what he saw.
This is an interesting future.
Again as I said we'll see if we get there or
not but, again, cameras are playing a role in these types of things.
And at least there's at least been signs given as to what could happen.