So now, let me introduce you to
the computer vision paper that
sort of motivated us
all to pay attention.
And, that was this paper by
Paul Viola and Mike Jones.
It was called Rapid Object Detection
using a Boosted Cascade
of Simple Features,
that objects were faces.
And, that's part of what
caught everybody's attention,
because everybody's been looking for
faces for a long time.
This was in CVPR 2001.
I will tell you that I was at
a presentation that Paul gave.
I think it's actually even
before this was published,
where he pulls out a camera,
connected to his laptop, sweep,
sweeps it around the, the, audience,
and it finds all the faces.
And, this is on a generic laptop,
wasn't very complicated.
And, it was it wasn't doing training,
he'd have trained it before.
Training is expensive,
but we all said oh, and
from then on we paid attention to Paul.
Not that we didn't pay
attention to him before, but
this was, this was a really big deal.
All right, so
there were several good ideas,
in fact,
better than good ideas in this paper.
First one,
which didn't seem like such a great
idea until we saw how easy it was to
do it was to use rectangular brightness
patterns as the features that
you're going to compute.
And, let me show you what,
what we're talking about here.
All right, so
here's some rectangular filters.
And, a rectangular filter, for
example, this one here, right,
just means that you take, see that's
pli, its white here and black there.
So, you just sum up all
the pixels in that area, and
you subtract off all the sum
of the pixels of that area.
So, you can think of it as a large
size kind of a gradient, right?
So, there are ones that would
compare horizontal, you know,
the pluses over here, and
the minuses over there.
There were ones that were vertical,
minus here, plus there.
They were of different shapes.
They also had some three way ones
where you'd have plus, minus, and
plus like that.
And then there were these cross ones
where you have plus like that, and
minus like that.
Just a whole bunch of them, and then
those would be applied to the image.
And here, we're showing you
two different features, again,
comes from the paper, right here.
And, the idea is that you might put
it down here in the picture, and
put it down here on the picture.
It just looks at the difference in
average intensity of adjacent regions,
or three of them, two, you know,
three regions in the face.
Now, the reason this turned
out to be such a great idea,
is that you can compute this thing very,
these things very,
very quickly if you're going to
compute a lot of them.
And, the idea was to use something
called the integral image.
And, this image here,
this is the integral image,
and I'll explain what it is.
The integral image works the following.
The value at some integral image,
x, y, would be the sum of
all the pixels in the top left-hand
corner behind it in the image.
Okay?
So,you go over to the, so
if you have my original image here,
the integral image
is the sum of all of these pixels, and
you just put its value right there.
Okay?
That's the integral image.
Now, you might ask,
why is that so important?
>> Why is that so important?
>> Very good.
So, I'll show you.