In the first exercise,
you saw string interpolation.
In other words,
inserting the values of variables and
expressions directly
into string literals.
Let's see it again now
with another example.
Say we have a statement about
how much food my roommates dog,
Mia eats per month.
If we were to use a variable for
the dog's name instead of just Mia, our
statement becomes much more versatile.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So here I declare, dogName and
lbsPerMonth, as variables and
we can insert them into
our original string.
And here you can see, this is
the same string as we had earlier.
But now, because we're using
variables and string interpolation.
If I want to know how much Zebedee,
the smiling Samoyed, eats per month,
we can just switch out the values
of our two variables, and voila.
Now we have Zebedee eats 25
pounds of dog food per month.
We can add expressions as well.
Zebedee is a pretty worldly pooch, so
lets say we want to know how much
Zebedee eats in kilos instead of pounds.
This expression for
kilos which includes the conversion rate
can be evaluated as the string is built.
And we'll print it out here
as our metricDoggyDiet.
And if we wanted to change this up so
we know how much Mia eats in kilos,
we can just plug in her consumption
rate in pounds and we're good to go.