Now we said we have three ways to reduce this exponential b to the m--
reducing the branching factor b, reducing the depth of the tree m,
and converting the tree to a graph
Let's see how each of those fare.
First, for reducing b we came up with this alpha-beta pruning technique.
In fact, that is very effective.
That takes us from a regime where we're in order b to the m to one where,
if we do a good jog, we can get to order b to the m/2.
Now what do I mean by doing a good job?
Well, we get different amounts of pruning depending on the order
in which we expand each branch from a node.
If we expand the good nodes first, then we get a lot of pruning,
because we do a good job of getting to the cutoff points.
If we expand the poor nodes first, then we don't do any pruning,
because we don't get to that cutoff point until later.
But if we can do well, then we get to the square root of the number of nodes.
In other words, we get to search twice as deep into the search tree.
That's all 100% perfect in terms of not changing the result.
We'd still get the exact evaluation.
We just stop doing work that we didn't have to do.
Now for the tree to the graph, we haven't talked that yet.
In fact, it depends on the particular game, but in many games it can be very useful.
In games like chess, we have opening books.
That is, we look at the past openings
and we just memorize those positions and what are the good moves.
It doesn't matter how we get to those positions.
We can get to them in multiple paths through a tree,
and we can just consider it a single graph.
We also have closing books, where we can memorize all the positions
with five or fewer pieces and know exactly what to do.
In the midgame when there are too many positions to memorize all of them,
we can still search through a graph if we want to or if we want we can just do part of that.
One thing that has proven effective in games like chess is called the killer-move heuristic.
What that says is if there's one really good move in part of a search tree,
then try the other move in the sister branches for that tree.
In other words, if I try making one move and I find that the opponent takes my queen,
then when I try making another move from that same position,
I should also check if the opponent has that response of taking my queen.
Converting from a tree to graph, also doesn't lose information.
It can just help us make the search go faster.
The third possibility was reducing m, the depth of the tree,
by just cutting off search and going to an evaluation function.
That is imperfect in that it is an estimate of the true value of the tree
but won't give you the exact value.
We can get into trouble. Let me show you an example of that.