So in terms that are a streaming pipeline,.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Do you guys leverage Trident at all?
>> So, Trident we were using originally.
>> Okay. >> But then there, due to some production issues and
and we decided to kind of phase it out.
>> Right.
>> The main reason is like he targeted some kind of issues in terms of
how often we can sustain the right,
especially because is a [INAUDIBLE] system, not a tuple-oriented system.
>> Yeah-
>> So on that writing of those tuples inside,
any of those batches are leading had some constraint.
And then we also found out, like more than 98 [INAUDIBLE] jobs
are using regular Storm as compared to Trident.
>> Right. >> Then when we look at use cases for Trident when we went deeper and
they, they no need to do exactly once.
>> Right. >> So it so but thing of merging these [INAUDIBLE] doing multiple,
maintaining those systems means, that we decide to do only one system.
So that kind of converged everything went to strong [INAUDIBLE]