So here you can see that constants
have been set up, state_signed_in,
state_signing_in, state_in_progress,
are zero, one, and two respectively.
We also have this integer called
signInProgress that's going to be
used to track them.
Now let's take a look at what's
in the onConnected method.
So, onConnected is called
when we successfully connect
to the Google infrastructure,
ie we've actually logged in.
So I'm just going to log
that we're onConnected, and
because we're logged in, we want to
set the sign in button to be disabled.
So setEnabled false, and
we want the sign out and
revoke buttons to be true so
that the user can click them.
Next we just want to set that the sign
in progress is STATE_SIGNED_IN, so
we're indicating
the the process is complete.
Finally, we're signed in, so
let's do something interesting.
We're just going to get a person
object of the current user using
the Plus.PeopleApi.getCurrentPerson and
passing it to client.
Once we have this person object we
can then access properties on it,
such as their display name.
So when I sign in to the infrastructure,
my actual real name and
not just my email address
is available to the app.
And as you saw when I demoed the app
earlier on it would say something like
welcome with my full name, or
Signed In to G+ as with my full name.
And that's how it was able to do it.
So now we have onConnected
implemented and it's looking good.
We will next need to take a look
at onConnectionFailed and
at what we manage in that.