Given two prime numbers, p and q,
we need to compute n, total n, and then
we need to select a public key, and from
there, we need to compute a private key.
We know that n = p x q.
Therefore, n is 33, and since p and
q are prime numbers,
total n is (p-1) x (q-1).
Therefore, total n is 2 x 10 = 20.
We selected e public key 7,
which is a prime number.
Obviously, because it is a prime number,
it's relatively prime to total n.
It will have a multiplicative inverse.
What is the value of t such that e
times t mark total n is equal to 1?
Given that e is 7,
it's obvious that t is
3 because 3 x 7 is 21 and
21 minus 20 is 1.
So what's the public key?
The public key is the pair e,n.
Therefore, it is 7, 33.
The private key is d,n.
Therefore it is 3, 33.