You're now ready to upload
the file to Firebase storage.
And you'll do that using putFile,
so let's add that here.
So this code here will take
our storage reference and
will save the selected image there.
And with that,
we're done sending the photo to storage.
One line of code and it doesn't
even look like networking code.
That's the magic of Firebase.
Now the putFile method
returns a upload task and
what we'll do is we'll add
a completion listener to it
which takes an activity as its first
argument and a OnSuccessListener.
The OnSuccessListener has one method you
should override, aptly named onSuccess.
The onSuccess method has a taskSnapshot
parameter, which will be our key to
getting the URL of the file
that was just sent to storage.
Here I'll use taskSnapshot
.getDownloadUrl and I'll save that URL.
Now that I have the URL,
I can save it to the database,
just like sending a text message will
create a FriendlyMessage object.
And in that object, I'll pass null,
the username, and the downloadUrl.
And then I'll take this FriendlyMessage
object and store it in the database and
now, let's run it.
I've got the app up and running so
let's if we can add a photo.
And Friendly Chat is able to upload a
photo and show it in the messages list.
Awesome work.
Just to be clear how we're able to both
show text messages and photo messages.
Let's take a quick look at the adaptor.
In the message adaptor class I'm
going to look at the Get View Method.
The way I set up friendly message
is that it's either text message or
a photo message, but it's never both.
So what we could do is we could check
if the message has a photo URL and
if it does then it's a photo.
Scrolling down,
I can use a statement here to say,
if it's a a photo,
then show the photoImageView, but
don't show the messageTextView, and
use Glide to load in that photo.
On the other hand,
if it's a text message,
then I do not show the photoImageView,
I do show the photoTextView,
and I set that text view
to the message text.
Either way, the author text view will be
visible with the correct author name,
and that's it.
You've successfully implemented storage.
Storing files with firebase requires
no server setup, no networking code,
has caching out of the box,
and provides a secure and
scalable bucket to
store your apps files.