All right, so first, some notation.
As before, we've got our world times our m is our projective equation.
And notice we've got two versions here.
And again, what we're saying here is that uv1 is projectively similar to wu,
wv and w.
And in fact, in order to get back uv1,
I could take wu, divide by w in order to get that.
And that's actually what's written on the bottom.
All I've shown is that ui, that's for point i, I have to
take the product that's the first row divided by what becomes the third row.
Same thing for vi.
So the point here is that I get a pair of equations for every point.
For every point i here, I have an equation that's, that goes from x, y,
z to ui, and x, y, z, to vi.
So what we're going to do is we're going to have to solve for
this m matrix using a, a whole bunch of points.
Just continuing, I just slid those equations up, and
now I've just carried through, just expanded it through.
And one thing you'll notice is that every term has an m in it.
And for those of you who know anything about linear algebra,
that should start to worry you just a little bit because typically when I
want to solve a linear set of equations,
I hope that there's some term that doesn't have a variable in it.
And we'll see that in just a sec.
So, I have this pair of equations for
each point, all right, writing it again like that.
So now the question is how best to solve this, all right.
I'm going to write this a little bit different way.
So here I have all my variables, and here for
just one point, I have my coefficients.
So notice my coefficients involve capital Xs and Ys and Zs.
Those are the values out in the world, along with the v's and
the u's, which are the points in the image.
Now, stretch way back into your memory from linear algebra, and you right,
might remember that usually you were solving equations of ax equals b.
And you could have more equations than unknowns, and
you'd solve to a least square solution.
But there was a particular kind of sol,
of set of equations where the right-hand side was
referred to as a homogeneous set of equations when they were all equal to zero.
And that's why this is a homogeneous set of equations,
not just homogeneous coordinates.
These things are all sort of related.
And when you get really, really old, you'll figure that out.
But for now, you can just remember that these are homogeneous equations.
So the question is, how do we solve that?
Because obviously, there's a trivial solution.
What's the trivial solution?
Well, if a times x equals 0, and I'm looking for
an x, well no matter what a is, x equals 0 would be a solution.
So I could just say all the m's are equal to 0.
And that would not be a very satisfying solution.
So the question is, what's the best way to solve this?