Can we actually predict stock
prices with machine learning?
Investors make educated
guesses by analyzing data.
They'll read the news,
study the company history,
industry trends, there are lots of data
points that go into making a prediction.
The prevailing theory is that stock
prices are totally random and
unpredictable.
A blindfolded monkey throwing dart at a
newspaper's financial pages could select
a portfolio that would do just as well
as one carefully selected by experts.
But that raises the question, why didn't
top firms like Morgan Stanley and
Citi Group hire a quantitative
analyst to build predictive models?
We have this idea of a trading floor
being filled with adrenaline-infused
men with loose ties running around
yelling something into a phone.
But these days you're more likely to
see rows of machine learning experts
quietly sitting in front
of computer screens.
In fact, about 70% of all orders on
Wall Street are now placed by software.
We're now living in
The Age of the Algorithm.
Hello world, it's Raj.
And today, we're going to build a deep
learning model to predict stock prices.
Records of prices for traded
commodities go back thousands of years.
Merchants along popular silk routes
would keep records of traded goods
to try and predict price trends, so
that they could benefit from them.
In finance, the field of quantitative
analysis is about 25 years old and
even now, it's still not fully accepted,
understood or widely used.
Just like Google plus.
It's the study of how certain variable
correlate with stock price behavior.
One of the first attempts at
this was made in the 70s by
two British Statisticians named Box and
Jenkins using mainframe computers.
The only historical data they had
access to were prices and volume.
They call the model Arima and
at the time it was slow and
expensive to run, but by the 80s
things started to get interesting.
Spreadsheets were invented so that
firms could model company's financial
performance and automated data
collection became a reality.
And with improvements
in computing power,
models could analyze data much faster,
it was a renaissance on Wall Street,
people were excited
about the possibilities.
They started showing up at seminars and
discussing their techniques.
>> You should see what's
going on at the bigger firms,
I mean I know all the information.
>> But all this quickly died
down once people realized that
what works is actually
a very valuable secret.
>> All right, get the fuck off my boat.
>> Since then the most successful
quants have gone underground.
In the past few years we've seen lots
of academic papers published using
neural nets to predict stock prices
with varying degrees of success.
But until recently, the ability to build
these models has been restricted to
academics who spend their days
writing very complex code.
Now, with libraries like Tensorflow,
anyone can build powerful predictive
models trained on massive data sets.
So let's build our own model using
Keras with a Tensorflow backend.
For our training data we'll be using
the daily closing price of the S&P
500 from January 2000 to August 2016.
This is a series of data points indexed
in time order or a time series.
Our goal will be to predict the closing
price for any given date after training.
We can load our data using
a custom load data function.
It essentially just reads our CSV
file into an array of values and
normalizes them, rather than feeding
those values directly into our model,
normalizing them improves convergence.
We'll use this equation to normalize
each value to reflect percentage
changes from the starting point.
So we'll divide each price by
the initial price and subtract 1.
When our model later makes a prediction,
we'll denormalize the data
using this formula to get
a real world number out of it.
To build our model,
we'll first initialize it as sequential
since it will be a linear
stack of layers.
Then we'll add our first
layer which is an LSTM layer.
So what is this?
Let's back up for a bit.
Recognize this beat?
Sing the lyrics with me.
You don't have to say what you did.
I already know.
I found out from him.
It's easy to recall the words forward,
but could we sing them backwards?
[MUSIC]
No, the reason for this is because
we learn these words in a sequence.
It's conditional memory.
We can access a word,
if we access the words before it.
Memory matters when we have sequences,
our thoughts have persistence but
feed forward neural nets don't.
They accept a fixed size
vector as input like an image.
So we couldn't use it to say predict
the next frame in a movie because
that would require a sequence
of image vectors as inputs.
Not just one since the probability
of a certain event happening would
depend on what happened
every frame before it.
We need a way to allow
information to persist and
that's why we'll use
a recurrent neural net.
Recurrent nets can accept
sequences of vectors as inputs.
So recall that for
feed forward neural nets,
the hidden layer's weights
are based only on the input data.
But in a recurrent net, the hidden layer
is a combination of the input data at
the current time step and the hidden
layer at a previous time step.
The hidden layer is constantly changing
as it gets more inputs and the only
way to reach these hidden states is
with the correct sequence of inputs.
This is how memory is
incorporated in and
we can model this
process mathematically.
So this hidden state at a given time
step is a function of the input
at that same time step
modified by a weight matrix,
like the ones used in feed forward nets.
Added to the hidden state of the
previous time step, multiplied by its
own hidden state to hidden state matrix,
otherwise known as a transition matrix.
And because this feedback loop is
occurring at every time step in
the series,
each hidden state has traces of
not only the previous hidden state but
also of all of those that preceded it.
That's why we call it recurrent.
In a way, we can think of it
as copies of the same network
each passing a message to the next.
So that's the great thing
about recurrent nets.
They're able to connect previous
data with the present task.
But, we still have a problem.
Take a look at this paragraph.
It starts off with,
I hope Senpai will notice me, and
ends with, She is my friend,
He is my Senpai.
Let's say we wanted to train a model
to predict this last work given
all the other works.
We need the context from the very
beginning of the sequence to know
that this word is probably Senpai,
not something like buddy, or mate.
In a regular recurrent net,
memories become more subtle
as they fade into the past
since the error signal from later time
steps doesn't make it far enough back in
time to influence the network at early
time steps during back propagation.
Joshua Bengio called this the vanishing
gradient problem in one of his
most frequently cited papers titled,
Learning Long-term Dependencies
with Gradient Descent Is Difficult.
Love the bluntness.
A popular solution to this is
a modification to recurrent nets called
long short term memory.
Normally, neurons are units that
apply an activation function,
like a sigmoid,
to a linear combination of their inputs.
In an LSTM recurrent net,
we instead replace these neurons
with what are called memory cells.
Each cell has an input gate, an output
gate and an internal state that
feeds into itself across time
steps with a constant weight of 1.
This eliminates the banishing gradient
problem since any gradient that flows
into this self-recurring unit during
back prop is preserved indefinitely,
since errors multiplied by 1
still have the same value.
Each gate is an activation
function like Sigmoid.
During the forward pass, the input gate
learns when to let activation pass into
the cell, and the output gate learns
when to let activation pass out of it.
During the backward pass,
the output gate learns when to let error
flow into the cell and the input gate
learns when to let it flow out of the
cell through the rest of the network.
So despite everything else in
a recurrent net staying the same,
doing this more powerful update
equation for our hidden state
results in our network being able
to remember long term dependencies.
So for our LSTM layer,
we'll set our input dimension to 1 and
say we want 50 units in this layer.
Setting return sequences to true
means this layer's output is
always fed into the next layer.
All its activations can be seen
as a sequence of predictions
this first layer has made
from the input sequence.
We'll add 20% drop out to this layer,
then initialize our second layer as
another outlet LSTM with 100 units, and
set return sequence to False on it since
its output is only fed to the next
layer at the end of the sequence.
It doesn't output a prediction for
the sequence, instead a prediction
vector for the whole input sequence.
We'll use the linear dense layer to
aggregate the data from this prediction
vector into one single value.
Then we can compile our model using
a popular loss function, called mean
squared error, and use gradient descent
as our optimizer, labeled RMS prop.
We'll train our model
with the fit function,
then we can test it to see what it
predicts for the next 50 steps,
at several points in our graph and
visualize it using MapPlot Live.
It seemed that for a lot of the price
movements, especially the big ones,
there is quite the correlation
between our model's prediction and
the actual data.
So, time to make some money and
play some T.I..
But will our model be able to correctly
predict the closing price 100%
of the time?
Hell to the no.
It's an analytical tool to help us make
educated guesses about the direction of
the market that it slightly
better than random.
So to break it down, Recurrent nets can
model sequential data since at each time
step the hidden state is affected by
the input and the previous hidden state.
A solution to the vanishing
gradient problem for recurrent nets
is to use long short term memory cells
to remember long term dependencies.
And we can use LSTM networks
to make predictions for
time series data easily using Keras and
Tensorflow.
The winner of the coding challenge
from the last video is Vishal Batchu.
Vishal used transfer learning to
create a classifier for cats and dogs.
He chose a layer from a pretrained
Tensorflow model and built his
own custom convolutional net on top
of it to make training much faster.
Wizard of the week.
And the runner up is Jie Xun See.
I loved how he added
a command line interface for
users to input their images.
The coding challenge for this video is
to use three different inputs instead of
just one to train your LSTM network to
predict the price of Google's stock.
Details are in the read me, post
your GitHub link in the comments and
I'll announce the winner in a week.
Please subscribe for
more videos like these and
for now I gotta count my stacks
of layers so thanks for watching.