The best place to start learning is
with the sample app that comes with
Android Studio.
We'll use this to understand
the principles and
then apply them to
uamp in a later lesson.
Fire up Android Studio and
start a new project.
Give your application a name,
and hit Next.
Choose TV as the form factor and
make sure the minimum API
version is at least 21.
Now of course in the real application,
we wouldn't just target Android TV.
We'd build our mobile and
TV UI into the same APK.
Just for right now, I want to keep
the code to an absolute minimum, so
I'm just targeting TV.
Make sure you add an Android TV
activity to your project and hit next.
These will be the names of our first
couple of lean back fragments, but
the defaults are fine.
So hit finish.
Let's take a fair amount of code here,
but no worries.
A good learning strategy is to
learn what the big pieces are and
how they fit together, and
that's exactly what we'll do today.
Let's start by looking at the manifest.
The most important part is how we
specify a main activity for Android TV.
As we discussed earlier, this is
accomplished by using the Leanback
launcher and
intent filter which you can see here.
If we were also writing an app for other
devices, we'd have their main activities
and corresponding intent filters
above or below this section.
Scrolling up a bit did you notice
these two users' feature tags?
The first indicates that a touch screen
is not required as we discussed.
The second is necessary for
app to be listed as an Android TV
application on the Google Play Store.
And by the way, the sample set this
required attribute to true, but
I've changed it to false, and
this is how it would look if we also had
a mobile version inside the same APK.
I mentioned earlier that Android TV
comes with a nice theme called
Theme.Leanback.
Here's where we apply it.
Because we're using the Leanback
support library fragments,
it's necessary that we use this theme or
one that extends from it.
And by the way, you can notice that
this theme is actually applied at
the application level.
If we were writing an app that had
a mobile version as well,we'd apply it
only to the TV activity.
Now let's open up MainActivity.
The entry point for our application.
What's this?
There's nothing here.
Correct.
That's the end of the sample app and
we're all done in this lesson.
To recap, we learned how to
open up the Android manifest.
Just kidding.
The reason why there's nothing here is
we're going to start by using the browse
fragment from the lean back library.
All fragments have to be contained
within an activity in order to
be displayed.
Our strategy here is just to use this
activity to specify a layout that
contains the browse fragment.
Here is the layout file, it doesn't do
much except reference that fragment, so
lets head there next.
Finally, code.
Our main fragment extends the browse
fragment which is provided by the lean
back library.
Scrolling down a bit, we see there's
way too much code to dive right in.
Really to learn a concept, you need to
fit all the code on about one page.
Let's start by looking
at onActivityCreated.
I want you to trust me here and
comment out these lines.
In this lesson we're going to take
out all the functionality and
put it back in piece by piece.
Now it's time to set up
an Android TV emulator runner app.
Using a real Android TV device,
as covered in the notes,
is strongly preferred.
It's much faster and less buggy.
That said though, in this lesson
I'm going to use the emulator,
so everyone can participate.
To start an emulator,
bring up the Virtual Device manager.
Select Create a Device.
In the Category tab, select TV.
Here, I'm going to choose an android TV
running at 720p for performance reasons.
On the next tab, we have a couple
of choices between API level and
architecture.
Here I'm going to select
an emulator with api level 21 and
architecture x86 for
performance reasons.
Recall that api level 21 is the minimum
version supported by android tv.
Also, for notes on why I picked version
21 and not 22 see the instructor notes.
On the next screen give your TV a name
and make sure use host GPU is selected.
This will improve performance.
For more tips on improving performance
via hardware acceleration,
see the instructor notes.
Now click finish.
Start your emulator by selecting it and
pressing play.
It may take some time to
start your emulator, so
don't close it when it finishes.
Also, you'll notice that recommendations
aren't available right now.
The reason is we don't have any apps
installed to provide those recs.
Now lets run our app on the emulator.
Here's our emulator.
Often, when you're developing for
multiple form factors you'll have
a variety of emulators running.
And you can check whether or
not your app is compatible
with one via this column.
When our app starts up,
you'll see an almost blank screen.
This is the empty browse
fragment with no content, but
there's actually more going
on here than it seems.
On the emulator, the arrow keys
function as the d pad remote controls.
Press right and watch what happens.
The header section of
the browse fragment collapsed.
Pretty cool, right?
Hit left to bring it back.
The escape key functions as
the back button on the emulator.
Press that once to return
to the home screen.
And here's where our app was installed.
That might not seem like much so
far, but trust me, things are going
to get awesome very soon.
Slow and steady wins the race.
If you'd like to follow along in code,
create a project in Android Studio, and
do the steps as
discussed in this lesson.
Alternatively, you can wait
to do your own coding live,
when we get to the exercises in you-amp