We covered the first two
items in the last video.
Feel free to re-watch those if needed.
The task to experiment with the code
was a little open ended, so
these are a couple of
things that we tried.
There's no single correct answer for
this one, though.
If I set the quantity to equal two times
the quantity, then if I hit the plus
button, then it will double
the number of coffee cups we have.
When I tried it on a device,
indeed it does double the number
of coffees from two to four.
I can also use the variable name
twice or as many times as I want
in the expression that will be evaluated
to store as a value for quantity.
Let's run this to see what happens.
This is essentially three times
quantity, so if the orignal quantity is
two, then when we hit the plus button,
it should bump up to six cups of coffee.
Even though it doesn't make
sense to update quantity so
many times within the method,
I just added more lines of code so
that you could see what would happen.
First I run the app in debug mode,
then I click on the Debug tab, and
I can trigger the breakpoint by
clicking on the plus button.
First I see that the quantity
variable has been initialized to two.
And then we take that quantity variable
and double it and then add another two.
That makes six cups of coffee, which is
the value down here for the variable.
If I click step over again,
we're going to take the current
quantity value and add two.
Since the value was six before,
six plus two equals eight.
Then I'm going to take
the existing quantity,
which is eight, multiply it by three
to get 24, and display that on screen.
If I click resume,
then the screen updates to 24.
Now let's revert back to
what we had before, so
it matches the rest of our code.