So, how much more complex
has this system become?
100 times?
500 times?
10,000 times?
I think if I remember right,
the first version of DOS was
about 5,000 lines of code.
I said assembly code, but about 5,000.
Windows currently is running
in the tens of millions range.
If you look at more recent Windows-based
operating systems, 50 million or
whatever it is,
we're talking rough estimates here, so
it's tens of millions.
So if you go from 5000
to tens of millions,
the complexity has grown
by a factor of 10,000.
So one of the things people say,
why do we have these vulnerabilities?
Well, it's complexity, and
it's complexity because we have
all these fancy features, and
richer interfaces, and APIs that
are more general, and things like that.
And that adds to the complexity.
So it relates to correctness.
Getting operating systems correct is
a challenge because they're complex.
And here is an example of how
the complexity has grown over time.