So at this point,
you know what you can afford to do and
when you can do it,
which is pretty handy.
>> Yeah.
Now one thing to bear in mind
is just because you can,
say, paint or do layouts or
even run JavaScript doesn't mean
you have an unlimited budget.
Layouts and style calculation times for
example, both depend on the number
of elements that are affected.
As you'll see soon, one of the ways
you can keep that time down
is to reduce the number of elements
on which they have to work.
>> Mm.
Check out the instructor notes below,
where you'll find a table with time
allowances for different tasks.
It'll help you set a budget for
each of those tasks.
So that you and
any other developers you're working
with are all on the same page.
>> Hm.
Now that you have a better idea of how
to think about your app as a whole.
It's time to drill into the specifics
of resolving performance issues.
>> In the next lesson you'll be taking a
look at the tools that you have at your
disposal for
identifying jenk in your apps.
The first step in reducing
jank is identifying its cause
which is exactly what you'll do.