If you want to get better
at building forms,
you need to start critiquing forms.
Many forms that look pretty reasonable
are, in reality, not that great.
With that in mind,
I want you to try critiquing this form.
You could find a link to it
in the instruction notes.
This form is actually part
of the final project for
this course which is
an event planner app.
You'll eventually have a chance to
apply everything you've learned in this
course, to turn this clunky app
into a high conversion machine.
And by the way, the version that you'll
see in a few moments might look slightly
different than this one.
And that's simply because we might
tweak it a bit between now and
when you're actually taking the course.
Overall though,
it should look pretty much the same.
Anyway, play with his form for
a moment and
when you're done,
I have a question for you.
How would you improve this form?
Would you change the title?
Would you consolidate inputs?
And this means simply taking multiple
inputs and turning them into one.
Would you write better
validation messages?
Or would you add more questions?
Check all that apply.