Let's go ahead and
create a new Android project and
then have a look at
the default build scripts.
We'll give our app a domain,
and a location.
We'll set a min SDK and
we'll add a blank add
a Blank Activity with a Fragment.
We'll leave the defaults for
the fragment.
So, here we are in our
newly created Android app.
If we go ahead and
haul out the ancient test device and
then run our application,
let's see what happens.
All right, sweet,
it looks like we're up and running.
So let's dive into what Gradle
configuration is present by default.
Again, the project pane has defaulted to
this Android-centric setup, but I find
this kind of confusing, so I'm going
to switch back to the project view,
to just show the straight
up project layout.
So here's our project, and
here's our build.gradle file.
There's a whole lot going on in
the default Android buildscript.
For starters, this is actually
a multi-project build and
the Android app itself is a sub project.
We'll talk all about
multi-project builds in Lesson 4.
But it's set up this way, so it's easy
to add other sub projects that we want
to build together with the app
like libraries or even a backend.
There are two things to notice
in this root buildscript.
First, we declare
a buildscript dependency
on come.android.tools.build:gradle:1.2.2.
There are two things to
note in this buildscript.
First, we declare a buildscript
dependency on this artifact coordinate.
This is where the Android plugin for
Gradle lives.
Second, and we'll talk about this
part of the Gradle API soon.
This block adds the jcenter repository
to every subproject of this build.
That means every subproject can
just declare dependencies and
they'll automatically be
retrieved from jcenter.
Now let's take a look at
the build script specifically for
the Android build,
which is in the app directory.
So here's the build script for
the Android app.
Note that it first applies the Android
plug in which it fetched from jCenter.
All configuration happens in
the Android configuration block.
All that's absolutely required
are the first two lines defining
the SDK version and
the build tools version.
The default config block configures
the attributes of the Android manifest.
We'll talk about the build
types block momentarily.
Finally, the dependencies block
works just like Java dependencies.
This declares the compile time
dependencies on every jar in the libs
directory and
on the Android Support Library.
Finally, this dependencies block
works just like Java dependencies.
Here we're declaring a dependency on
every jar in the libs directory as well
as on the Android Support Library.