All right. Welcome back to com, Introduction to Computer Vision.
Today finally, we're going to get to talk about calibrating cameras.
Where we're going to be calibrating with spectra 3D world.
So finally, we can get to the parameters of cells.
If you remember last time, we solved for the full projection equation.
That was made up of really a composition of the translation, rotation,
projection and intrinsics.
For the rest of today, we're not going to worry about the fact that M
has this internal structure, till maybe the very end.
We're going to think of M just this way.
That is M is going to be this matrix that's going to take your world points and
homogeneous coordinates.
And eventually, get you out your image points also in homogeneous coordinates.
So what we're going to try to do is find that M.