We've gotten our first taste of
web services with Flickr, and
what I want to do is expose you to some
of the other data that's out there,
because there's a ton.
So I'm going to give
you a description for
some data that a developer
might want to use and
I want you to match that with a web
service that best fits the description.
So for developer A, let's say I want
to access information about American
legislators, districts,
committees, bills, and votes.
For developer B, I want to build
an app that displays player stats and
game results from the game
League of Legends.
And that's a good one.
I play that one, actually, a lot.
For Developer C,
I want to display the locations
of restaurants in a city or town.
For Developer D, I want to access
information about the economies of
countries from around the world.
And Developer E, I want to display
information about sales and
products at top designer labels.
For options, we have the OpenMenu API,
the World Bank API,
Sunlight APIs, the Gilt API,
and Riot Games API.
So to answer these questions, I want you
to put the number of the web service
in the text box for the developer it
best helps over here on the left.