Here's the result of running the Greedy agent over 500 trials.
And I've graphed 2 things here:
One is the error; and you see, over the top--
over the first 40 or so trials--
the error was very high--way up here.
But then, suddenly, it jumped down
to a lower level, and stayed along that level all the way through to 500.
I've also graphed, with a dotted line, the policy loss.
What does that mean?--so that's the difference
between the policy that the agent has learned and the optimal policy.
So if it had learned the optimal policy, the policy loss would be zero, down here.
It doesn't quite get to zero.
It was high, up here,
and then at around step 40, it learned something important.
What did it learn?--well, here's the final policy that it came up with.
Maybe it started originally going in this direction in hitting the minus 1;
and then it flipped and learned a new policy that went in a better direction.
But it still hasn't learned the optimal policy.
And we can see--for example, this looks like a mistake here.
In state 1-2, it's policy is moving down
and then following this path, which it learned, towards the goal.
But really, a better route would be to take the northern route, and go through this path.
But it hasn't learned that.
Because it was Greedy, it found something
that seemed to be doing good for it, and then it never deviated from that.