All right, so now back to the Pets app.
So, so far,
we've covered the merits of why you
want to use a content provider and
then heard about future possibilities
of using it to share pet data.
So now let's work on diving into the
details of how specifically the content
provider works.
Now, as a word of caution here,
learning about content providers
will involve learning a lot of
new Android framework classes,
as well as adding additional
code across multiple files.
But don't be scared off,
we'll be breaking it all down slowly and
walking you through the process.
So let's start of with a high-level
picture of all the components.
And then we'll zoom in to each component
as we move through the lesson and
implement each part of
the content provider.
So let's begin this discussion
with a Contacts app example.
And later in the quiz,
you'll apply the information that you
learned into your Pets app specifically.
So in this case,
the Contacts app does need to share its
data with other apps on the device.
So this will be an ideal use case
to take advantage of everything for
the content provider has to offer.
Now let's assume there are bunch of
social networking apps installed
on your device,
including your Contacts app.
So the Contacts app contains
a Contacts DatabaseHelper, and
this manages the creation and
versioning of the database.
So this database will contain all the
details of the contacts in your phone.
So whether it's your mom, your dad,
your grandma, whomever you contact with,
this database will store it.
So if other apps want access to the
information in our contacts database,
we can create and expose a content
provider to the Android system.
And then the other apps can
interact with the content provider.
So here, more specifically called
Contacts Provider, request data from it.
And then the content
provider will interact with
the Contacts DatabaseHelper, and then
the database to fetch the appropriate
data and return it to the caller.
So, how do other apps communicate
with the contacts provider?
Well, for one thing,
they'll use the contract,
which contains details on what tables
and columns are available here.
Now, all parties must adhere to the
contract because as the name applies,
it's a binding contract.
So the Google+ app wants to
request data on a specific person.
It refers the contacts contract,
and creates a request for
a specific content URI.
So a content URI uniquely
identifies a set of data.
So this is similar to how a web URI
address uniquely identifies a unique
website on the Internet.
So how does the Android system
know that the Google+ app
wants to talk to our Contacts app?
Well, this is based on
the information that we've passed in
thru the content URI.
Given this information, this is going to
determine which content provider and
which app can handle our request.
Now this is important because you
can imagine that there are numerous
other apps on the device that all
have their own content providers.
And these content providers are used
to shared data to outside apps.
For example, the Calendar app has
a calendar provider to provide access to
the user's schedule of events.
Additionally, the Android framework
also exposes a provider for
the user's dictionary.
And this dictionary is all the words
that you add when you're say,
typing text, these are added
into your dictionary here.
Now there's something on Android
called a content resolver.
And it takes the URI and
resolves which content provider
should handle our request.
Now the magic behind how the content
resolver knows which provider to go to
is that it uses the content authority.
And the content authority is
this specific part of the URI,
which let's the content resolver know
which provider should handle a request.
This content authority is similar
to parts of a website URL.
So just like all Google.com URLs
contain the words Google.com,
all Contacts app URIs
contain com.android.contacts.
And we'll be getting into more
the details of how the content URI as
a whole is structured in later videos.
So for now, just focus on the content
authority part of the content URI.
So all the other apps, as we see here,
actually talk to the content resolver
and not directly to the provider.
So the content resolver will expose
the same methods, our query(),
insert(), update() and delete().
And it calls the appropriate
methods on a provider for us,
which in turn calls the appropriate
provider methods to act on the database.
So, so far, we've seen
the example of how outside apps
call on the content provider
of another existing app.
For example,
our Google+ app calling into the content
provider of the Contacts app.
But there's also situations where
the code, within the Contacts app,
can actually use the provider itself
to load data into its own UI.
So let's zoom in on a specific case and
focus on our Contacts app.
So in this case, the ContactEditor
Activity of the Contacts app will use
the provider and loader in order to load
data from the database into the UI for
editing our contacts.
So the ContactEditor Activity
can call methods on
the Content Resolver with
the contact's Content URI.
And the resolver will then route the
message to its own Contacts Provider.
So the provider will send
a request to the database, and
we'll get some result back.
And this result will get sent
back to the Content Resolver,
which will then ultimately return it
back to our ContactEditor Activity to be
seen in our UI.
All right, so I know that was
a lot of information to cover.
So let's pause here and answer the
following quiz question in order to test
your knowledge of how all these
components interact with each other.
So this quiz will involve applying
what you just learned to the Pets app
specifically, in this end-to-end
flow using a content provider.
And as a reminder,
in this use-case we're not sharing
our pet data with any other apps for
now, so this quiz is focused
specifically on just the Pets app.
So we're focusing on the UI and
how it use the content provider to
access data in the data source.
And so far, I've helped you out by
filling in the content provider and
SQLiteDatabase of this diagram.
I'd like you to go ahead and
use these answer choices and
fill out this remaining
blanks in this diagram.