Okay, so hopefully that wasn't too difficult.
I'm looking here at our MainActivity.java and I'm in the onCreate method.
So we've discussed most of the stuff here and we talked a lot in
particular about these two lines where we get the ContentResolver.
And we do the actual query.
Also note that I have a text view up here that I've retrieved.
So down here is where we start the try, and
we start sort of doing things with the cursor that we got here.
So I'm going to scroll down.
Okay, so here's the first full part of the try statement.
And the first thing we do is just print out a couple of informational lines at
the top of the app.
To get the number of words we just use cursor.getCount.
This gets us how many rows are in the table.
And because we got all rows in
the table this is going to give us the complete number of words.
Next, we go ahead and we print out the column names.
UserDictionary.words.id is the of the id column.
UserDictionary.words.frequency is the name of the frequency column.
UserDictionary.words.word is the name of the word column.
I imported user dictionary so that's why I'm not using it up here, but
you can see me using it down here.
Speaking of these lines of code, this is where we go ahead and
grab the indices of each of the columns.
We use the cursor.getColumnindex method and we pass in the name of the column.
So I'm passing in the name for ID, getting the index for
the ID column, and so on.
This was another method that we looked at.
The cursor.moveToNext, which works really well in a while loop.
So we're using this to iterate through every single row that's stored
inside the cursor.
And for each of these rows we're using the indices that we grabbed up
here to grab the actual values using the getInt and the getString method.
So again, we have the wordColumn index that we got from up here.
Then we use getString and that gives us the actual word.
And our final step right here is just to append all those values that
we just grabbed for the row to the TextView.
Now I'm going to scroll down a little bit more to look at
this finally statement.
Okay. So this is the last thing that we do and it's just closing the cursor.
Remember, I had that whole rant about how it's important to close
cursors because we might leave memory lying around.
In this scenario, if we only run the app once, it's probably not going to crash.
But it's a really good habit to get into having the try statement up here,
followed by the finally statement down here,
where you make absolutely sure that you close your cursor.
And once you're done, your app's going to look a lot like this.
Now, it's going to have your own words here, but
it is going to just be plain text in a text box on the screen.
So, that's pretty much it for this exercise.
I hope it wasn't too difficult.
There's a link to the GitHub repo below, if you want to pull down
the actual code, and play around with it, and take a look at it,.
Otherwise, feel free to go ahead and move on.