Let's see problem five now is back
looking a little bit more deeply at the
data.
So this data set of that has been, you know,
it's a real data set.
It's got a lot of noise and random
things in it. In particular, we
haven't taken really good care about
removing duplicates from the data sets.
And it's possible that some of the data
that's in the test set also exists in
the training sets. It would be a problem
if you really read about overfitting, but
it also might be just the reality of
things. It's very often that you train on
some data and at this time,
you know, when you're actually using your
classifier the same data shows up.
It can happen. So depending on the use
case, you might want to sanitize your
data or not.
In this case, we're not going to sanitize
it, but we want to know how much overlap
there is because it might actually if
you know the entire test that is
contained in the training set then we we
are in trouble and we are really at risk
of misleading ourselves in thinking that
we've created the perfect classifier.