One way to solve this is to use so
called indirect pointers.
Here is an inode structure that
uses these indirect pointers.
Just like before, the inode contains
metadata and pointers to blocks of data.
The inode is organized
in a way that first,
it has all of the metadata, owner,
when is the file last accessed?
Then it starts with
the pointers to blocks.
The first part is a list
of pointers that directly
point to a block on disk
that stores the file data.
Using the same example like before,
where we had blocks that are 1 kilobyte
large, and we used 4 bytes to
address an individual block,
these direct pointers will
point to 1KB of data per entry.
To extend the number of disk blocks
that can be addressed via single inode
element, while keeping
the size of the inode small,
we use so-called indirect pointers.
And indirect pointer, as opposed to
pointing to an actual data block
will point to a block
that's full of pointers.
Given that our blocks
are 1 kilobyte large and
our pointers are 4 byte large, that
means that a single indirect pointer
can point to 256 kilobytes
of file content.
So just using a single element
of the inode data structure
as this indirect pointer can
significantly increase the overall size
of the files that can be
supported in this file system.
Now, if we need even larger files,
we can use double indirect pointers.
A double indirect pointer,
points to a block which contains
pointers to blocks of data.
If every block has 256 pointers,
then this double
indirect pointer can help
us address 256 times 256
times 1 kilobyte blocks for
a total of 64 megabytes of data.
We can apply the same idea to triple
indirect addressing and so forth.
The benefits of using indirect pointers
is that it allows us to continue using
relatively small inodes, while at the
same time addressing really large files.
The downside is that this
has an implication on
slowing down the file access
with direct pointer when we need
to perform an access to
a portion of the file.
We need to first access
the inode itself and
that may be stored somewhere on disk,
and then we will find out what is
the pointer to a particular data block,
and we will access the data block.
So we mean the performing 2 disk
accesses per file access and
that's at most.
With the double indirect pointers,
the situation is very different.
We need one disk access to get to
the block that contains the inode.
Then we may need another disk access
to get to the first addressing block.
Then, from there, a second disk
access to get to the second level
addressing block, and then finally we
get to the block that contains the data.
So for a single file operation, we may
end up performing up to 4 disk accesses.
That's a 2x performance degradation.