Assume that this is a code snippet
from an InboxActivity.java file
within an email app.
Now there's a lot of code here with
concepts you haven't learned before.
So it's okay if you didn't
get this one correct.
Let's walk through it together.
First, we create an integer variable
called numberOfEmailsInInbox.
We initialize the variable
to have a value of 0.
Then we create another integer
variable called numberOfDraftEmails.
And we initialize that
to have a value of 2.
Next we create a string
variable called emailMessage.
And the value is you have blank emails,
where blank is actually a variable
referring to numberOfEmailsInInbox.
So this evaluates to you have 0 emails,
because this variable has a value of 0.
Next we have another string
variable called draftMessage.
The value is You have
blank email drafts.
Blank actually refers to
numberofDraftEmails and
this has a value of 2.
So this right hand side maps
to You have 2 email drafts.
So far we have four variables and
nothing has been printed
to the logs yet.
Now we have an if statement.
There's no else block of code down here,
and that's perfectly fine.
This statement reads if
the numberOfEmailsInInbox = 0,
then perform the code within
these opening and closing braces.
We remember that
numberOfEmailsInInbox is equal to 0,
so this code in the opening and
closing braces would get executed.
It simply updates
the email message variable
to say You have no new messages.
Okay, so we know that the latest value
of email message is You have no new
messages and the latest value
of draft message is up here.
You have 2 email drafts.
Let's continue reading.
There's another if statement down here.
If the numberOfDraftEmails equals 0,
then perform the code within
the opening and closing braces.
However, numberOfDraftEmails
has a value of 2.
That means this condition here is false
and we can skip this block of code.
Therefore, the draftMessage
variable stays at the value of You
have 2 email drafts.
It does not update to this new message.
Finally, we're back in a regular
execution flow of the method.
There's no more if statements, and
we can run this line of code
which prints to the logs.
It prints the emailMessage
to the logs and
then next it prints
the draftMessage to the logs.
At this point in time emailMessage says,
You have no new messages,
and draftMessage says,
You have 2 email drafts.
Looking at our choices,
option C is what we want.
Option A is incorrect
because we don't print out
the message at every point in time.
We only have two lines of
code that print to the logs.
Option B is incorrect because
the emailMessage string gets updated
within the if statement.
And there's actually 2 email drafts,
not 0 email drafts, so
the second log statement
is also incorrect.
That leaves the remaining
correct choice, option C.