That's still pretty ugly.
We can make that look even nicer.
All right?
Here is a very simple, beautiful way of writing this.
That this quadratic approximation, so
quadratic, remember we're just looking at the square terms of the u v.
Right? It can be written matrix form as u v times this matrix M times u v.
This, you know, you could think of this as u v, transpose.
All right, where M is the second moment matrix written down here, okay?
Again, what is has is it's the weighted sum of the squares and
of the product of the two different derivatives.
It pays to think a little bit more about this M matrix,
because we're going to do it even more in a minute, all right?
So, here I've just copied it over, and for a moment, it's kind of a joke.
For you guys that're physics geeks, if I say for the moment and
we're talking about the second order matrix,
you realize it has something to do with moments of inertia.
Nevermind.
Okay, I'm going to write that M matrix in, without the weights at the bottom.
Okay.
And when I write it that way,
you can see that this is just the sum of ixx, sum of iyy, and the cross sum.
That can just be written as the sum,
this is referred to as an outer product, right?
So it's the outer product of the single gradient, okay.
That's what this says.
One of these is just the outer product of one vector.
It's a two by two matrix but it's an outer product of one vector.
In linear algebra you realize that's only a rank one matrix, right.
Because let's just take the columns, the columns are just a multiple of Ix Iy.
And each column is, is a, is a, is a multiple, multiplied by a different scaler.
So when the two columns are scaler multiples of each other,
it's not a full rank matrix.
So its two by two is actually rank one.
Okay, that's what it says here, each is a product of rank one.
And then of course,
this thing is going to be summed over all of the points within the window.
So what's it going to take for this matrix to be full rank, for
this to be sort of a well-behaved ellipse?
We would actually have to have gradients in different directions over
the window to be summing up a bunch of different rank one matrices and
that would get us to a full rank.