So here's the main idea of this algorithm called RANSAC.
Fitting a line,
a model, is easy if we know which points belong to that model and which do not.
At which point I wrote, duh.
Yeah. A little more interesting.
Now if I had proposed a particular model, a particular line, we could probably
guess, in a whole bunch of points, which of those points come from that line, or
come from that model, and those are called inliers.
That is, they come from the model.
The algorithm Random Sample Consensus works as follows, and
we're going to go through this.
Randomly picks some points to define your mo-,
Line or your model.
Okay?
Then, repeat this enough times till you find a good one.
And what does it mean by a good one?
A good one is one that has many inliers.
That is, a lot of points are from that line.
And you might think that this is a.
Hopeless idea.
Just randomly picking things and, and computing them and hoping that you get.
Well it turns out that actually as was shown by Fischer and
Bolles way back in the dark ages of the universe 1981.
That actually this copes with a very large proportion of outliers very well.
I'll also tell you that Marty Fischer was my first boss after my PhD,
and Bob Bolles sort of taught me the ways of the force, or
of computer vision after 1981.
But not that many years after.