As we've talked about before
users can either be signed in or
signed out in friendly chat.
Moments a go, we just set up what
happens when they're signed out.
FirebaseUI will display
a sign in flow for them.
Now when they're signed in,
we need to do a few things.
We need to set up
a display message list,
and we also need to make it possible so
that when they type in
a nice friendly message, their user
name will appear right next to it.
In this way it'll actually
be clear who's talking.
When signed out,
we need to do the opposite, and
tear down the message screen.
Once the message screen
has been torn down,
we'll send them back to the sign in
screen, like we're already doing.
Let's add a little bit more
code to our Auth State listener
to deal with these UI changes.
Okay, so here's my handy
dandy AuthStateListener and
I'm actually going to
add two helper methods.
The first one will be in
place of the toast and
it's going to be called
onSignedInInitialize.
And the second, I'll call here, and
I'm going to call it onSignedOutCleanup.
Now, for onSignedInInitialize,
I'm going to pass in the user name, and
I can get the user name by taking
the Firebase user object that I have and
calling getDisplayName.
I'm going to now scroll down
to the bottom of our class and
actually create those two methods.
On signed in initialize, I'm going to
go ahead and set the user name, and
I can do that by taking my
user name member variable and
sending it to user name
that I just passed in.
Now what does setting this
user name variable do?
Well if I scroll up to here to where
I am performing the database rights.
You'll see that when I make
the friendly message object for
my new message that I am
including a username, mUsername.
So once mUsername is set, any message
that is sent will have that username.
Okay, let's scroll back
down to the bottom.
Now, beyond setting the username here.
This is a great place to
attach a read listener.
You might have noticed that
reading isn't quite working, and
that's due to where I
attached the read listener.
So let's scroll up and
see where that is now.
Here we go, here in onCreate is where
I'm attaching that read listener.
The problem is,
the user isn't logged in yet here.
Because this is an onCreate.
Before the AuthStateListener
is even made or attached,
our database rules say that you have
to be authenticated to be able to read.
So what's happening is it doesn't
have the permission to successfully
pull the messages from the database.
So it'll actually only be effectual to
attach this read listener when the user
is actually signed in.
So I'm going to go ahead and copy all
of this code that creates and attaches
the read listener, cut it, scroll down
to the bottom and move it down here.
Now, you're only setting
the username and
pulling the messages list when
the user's actually logged in.
Now onSignedOutCleanup is going to
actually do the opposite to
tear down the UI.
It's going to unset the user name,
clear the messages list, and
detach the listener.
I'm actually going to
go one step further and
take this attaching read listener
code and put it in a separate method.
So here I've created a method,
attachDatabaseReadListener.
And I'll go ahead and call that instead.
This allows me to have a single
place to attach listeners,
which can help keep
things more organized.
Now, onSignedOutCleanup will do
the opposite teardown to the UI.
So, instead of setting the username,
it will unset the username,
then clear the messages, and
finally, detach the listener.
So the first of those three things
is to take the Username, and
to un-set it by changing
it back to ANONYMOUS.
Next I can take my Adapter and
clear the messages from it.
And we're doing this because
a user who is no longer signed in
shouldn't be able to see those messages.
Also, if you didn't clear the messages,
you get a bug where you'd find
duplicate messages when you're logging
in and logging out multiple times.
Similarly, I'm going to want to
detach the read listeners here.
And just like I created
a attachDatabaseReadListener method,
I'm going to create
a detachDatabaseReadListener method.
And I will define that method down here.
And to remove the listener,
I'm going to call removeEventListener,
passing in mChildEventListener.
Now you can make this code more robust
by enforcing that you only ever attach
or detach a listener at one time.
So in detatchDatabaseListener,
I'll write an if statement, making sure
that childEventListener is not null.
And then after it's detached,
I will set childEventListener to null.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I'll do a similar thing
with the attach method.
I'll add a check up here to see
if child event listener is null.
And only if it is null,
meaning that is has been detached,
will I create and attach the listener.
Okay, and now one final step.
The ReadListener is attached up here
in the onSignedInitialize method.
OnSignedInitialized is called when
authentication state changed is called.
AuthStateChanged is called when it is
added to our FirebaseAuth object which
is a long way of saying,
if you resume the code and
the user's logged in a database
listener will be attached.
So we should also make sure
to detach it on pause.
Okay, one more thing.
Because we attach
the AuthStateListener in on resume,
which if the users logged in,
will then trigger on site and
initialize which will
then add a read listener.
We should also be sure to
detach the read listener here.
As well as clear the adapter.
These two lines of code also make sure
that when the activity is destroyed in
a way that has noting to do with signing
out such as a that the listener is
effectively cleaned up.
Okay, you're done.