To improve our networking code,
we need to find a way to reduce the
redundancy between each network request.
Right now, we're looking at
the login view controller and
we have this split view.
On the left we have the get
Session ID method, and
on the right we have the get User ID
method, and there's a lot of
code duplication between these requests,
as well as our other requests.
Now these methods have
been modified ever so
slightly since the MyFavoriteMovies app,
but nothing drastic,
you should be able to follow this.
Now what we want to do is
identify what's common between
both of these requests.
This is what's going to allow us to
create a reusable piece of code to get
rid of all the stuplication.
For example, in each of these requests,
we don't need to duplicate
adding the ApiKey.
Both of these methods take the API key.
So maybe we can pull that out.
And if we keep looking we'll find
plenty more examples of this.
So for this exercise called
Abstracting Away Redundant Code I'm
going to provide you with a code
snippet of the getSessionID method.
And this code snippet,
you can find in the instructor notes.
And you're going to look at this snippet
and determine which sections of the code
are redundant by comparing it
to the other network request.
And finding these redundancies is
going to be such a valuable skill for
you to practice and
it's going to give us a basis for
how to build our API client.
Now when you're done
looking at the code and
you found the sections you think
are redundant, I want you to enter for
the section numbers as a comma
separated list in this box.
For example, if the redundant
sections are 2, 4 and 8,
then your answer should look like this.
And the sections are numbered within
the code snippet that you'll download.