We get the answer by reading numbers off the conditional probability tables,
so probability of B being positive is 0.001.
Of E being positive, because we're dealing with the positive case now
for the variable E, is 0.002.
The probability of A being positive, because we're dealing with that case,
given that B is positive and the case for an E is positive,
that we can read off here as 0.95.
The probability that J is positive given that A is positive is 0.9.
And finally, the probability that M is positive given that A is positive
we read off here as 0.7.
We multiple all those together, it's going to be a small number
because we've got the .001 and the .002 here.
Can't quite fit it in the box, but it works out to .000001197.
That seems like a really small number, but remember,
we have to normalize by the P(+j,+m) term,
and this is only 1 of the 4 possibilities.
We have to enumerate over all 4 possibilities for E and A,
and in the end, it works out that the probability of the burglar alarm being true
given that John and Mary calls, is 0.284.
And we get that number because intuitively,
it seems that the alarm is fairly reliable.
John and Mary calling are very reliable,
but the prior probability of burglary is low.
And those 2 terms combine together to give us the 0.284 value
when we sum up each of the 4 terms of these products.