Let's summarize quickly on our question:
how long should a timeslice be?
CPU bound tasks prefer
longer timeslices.
The longer the timeslice,
the fewer context switches we'll have
to perform, so that basically limits
the context switching overheads
that the scheduling will introduce.
To perform useful work,
the useful application processing
to as slow as possible.
And as a result,
both the CPU utilization,
as well as the system throughput as
metrics will be as high as possible.
On the other hand, I/O bound
tasks prefer shorter timeslices.
This allows I/O bound tasks to issue
I/O operations as soon as possible.
And as a result, we achieve both
higher CPU and device utilization,
as well as the performance that the user
perceives that the use, the system is
responsive and that it responds to
its commands and displace output.