Okay, so here we are in Android Studio.
And we have the project pane open.
Let's become familiar with the code
base for the Quake Report app.
So the first thing I'm going to
do is go to the app directory and
look in the java folder.
This is where all the logic for
the app is.
Then I'm going to move down here to
the resources folder, expand it.
This is the folder that contains
everything related to the appearance
of the app.
These files control how the app
appears on different devices.
Resources can include XML files,
images, and other media files.
We can start by expanding
out the layout folder.
Here we have
the earthquake_activity.xml file.
This file defines the layout for
the main screen in our app,
which is just a list view.
Then we have the mipmap folder, which is
a special folder just for the app icon.
Other images in your app should
go in the drawable folders.
Then we have the values folder.
This contains the colors.xml file,
which defines the colors for our app.
And we also have some additional
resource files for the styles and
themes as well as text strings.
So let's go back to the java folder.
We have one Java file called
the EarthquakeActivity.
And it turns out that the
EarthquakeActivity is the main screen
for our app.
When the activity is created,
we set the content view to
the earthquake_activity XML layout.
Then we create a fake list of
earthquakes because this is placeholder
data until we get real
data from the server.
We represent the list of earthquakes
as an ArrayList of strings,
which then contains the names
of different cities.
Then we create an ArrayAdapter which
knows how to create list item views,
one for
each earthquake in the ArrayList.
And then the list items will
be added into the ListView
that we defined in our
earthquake_activity XML layout.
Last but not least,
we have the AndroidManifest file.
This file contains important information
about our app that the Android system
needs to know, for example, the package
name, the app name and the activities.
Now going back to our quiz,
here are the answers to the questions.
Our main activity is defined in
the EarthquakeActivity.java file.
And the layout for
the activity is defined in
the earthquake_activity.xml file.
And lastly,
within our EarthquakeActivity class,
we have an array list
variable called earthquakes,
which holds the list of
earthquake locations as strings.