Jay did you get this working?
>> No, but
I can do it right now to begin,
I'm going to respond
with a match in the cash.
For this request,
I can just pass event dot request
straight into cash's dot match.
Of course there may not be a match in
the cache for this particular request.
In that case the promise
will resolve with undefined.
So if the request is truthy, meaning I
got a match in the cache I'll return it.
Otherwise I'll return a fetch to
the network for the original request.
I can actually make this a little bit
neater by just writing as a response
or fetch.
With force update enabled
I can refresh the page.
And while it doesn't really
look like much has changed.
But if we go offline and refresh,
we get a whole lot of content still.
We shouldn't underestimate what
we've done here, it's pretty huge.
Here's what we've achieved.
Things haven't really changed
with a perfect connection,
but perfect doesn't exist.
On a slow connection, we're getting
stuff on screen a whole lot faster.
On WiFi, we're delivering stuff rather
than a blank screen which is great.
And offline gets content,
rather than a complete failure.
There are things we need to fix though.
The photos and
avatars aren't working offline.
But also if we disable force updates.
And go online.
We can see this post from Sam
with the picture of the car.
And these newer posts above it.
But if we now go offline.
And refresh Sam's post is
showing us the latest.
We're not updating
the posts in the cache.
This is because we cached
the HTML once and install time.
So we're stuck with that set
of messages in the cache.
Here's a to do list that gets
us from where we are now to full
offline first success.
We need to come out of a system for
an intrusive app updates.
We want to get the user using the latest
version as quickly as possible.
We should continually update
the cache of posts so
we're not left with the same content
we originally installed with.
Then we need to cache the photos and
cache the avatars.
The rest of the course
is about doing this.
Starting with unobtrusive app updates.