So let's now compute this homography for the, the Great Wall of China.
Actually Steve did this a really long time ago,
but I'm going to pretend that we're doing it right now.
So in order to compute homography, the first thing we need,
is we need sets of corresponding points all right?
So on the left, we have the original points, x1, y1, x2, y2,
all the way up to xN yN.
We have a bunch of points, and
on the right, we have the corresponding points in the second image.
X1 prime, Y1 prime, X2, and for
now, we're going to assume that these points have been found by that tried and
true method of paying somebody else to click on them.
That's called Amazon Mechanical Turk or something where, or
maybe you're an undergraduate, and your advisor's beating you up, and
so you have to do all the clicking, or maybe you're doing this for
a problem set for a computer vision class and you have to do the clicking.
But basically is somehow you've identified corresponding points between
the two images.
So, what we have to do now, is we have to solve for this equation, right?
We know that the relationship between p and p prime is going to
be this homogeneous coordinate, transform, or homogenous, homography H.
So how do we solve for H given some number of points?
Well, there are two ways.
The first way is the non-homogeneous.
Boo, hiss, all right.
Going back here, even though there are nine variables in the,
in the, matrix, we know there are only eight degrees of
freedom because it's only known up to a scale value.
So we can set, for example, the last entry to one, all right?
Well then, we can set up a linear set of equations, Equals b, where,
the vector now is of h where it's going to be a, b, c, d, e, f, g, h.
But this h isn't the same as that h.
This is the h that's all the elements of the big matrix h,
and this is dumb little h.
Okay, so we got a through f, pretty smart, and dumb little h,
and then g is in there somewhere.
You, you get it.
There's eight unknowns.
Okay, if I knew the first eight letters of the Greek alphabet I
would have made them that way.
But basically, I've got eight unknowns.
As long as I have four points, I would have eight equations, why?
Because I get an equation for
the X, an equation for the Y for each point, corresponding point.
But I really because my location, locating of the points won't be precise.
I would be better if I had a whole bunch more points then I would do a least
square solution.
And you would solve for the minimum of the magnitude of Minus b squared,
the minimum of that square using least-squares, and
you've known how to do that since eighth grade, I hope, ninth grade,
twelfth grade, I don't, somewhere along the way.
If you don't know what I'm talking about [LAUGH],
go learn a lot of linear algebra before we take the rest of this class.
All right, but this is the non-homogeneous way.
Thinking about this set of equations we've already seen this, right?
Remember when we were doing the extrinsics and we had a whole bunch of
equations, two N of them, and we had am equals 0, because we didn't change it.
So we can do just like we did before.
You multiply this through.
You divide out by the,
by w, and you'll get two homogeneous equations for each point, right?
Now instead of m, we're solving for h,
and we have a whole bunch of terms all linear in terms of h, and it equals 0.
And we have 2n of those equations where n is the number of points.
And how do we solve this?
Well you use that singular value decomposition just like we did last time.
Or you could take that a transpose a matrix, solve for the eigenvectors.
Pull out the eigenvector with the smallest eigenvalue and that was our solution.
Remember we showed that it was the same thing.
That's the way for solving for the homography coefficients.
And by the way, that's the cool way, because you can impress people.
because you can tell them to use singular value decomposition, which has so
many syllables in it, they're sure you're really smart.