In the previous lesson, we finally got
to play around with our apartment and
bring it to life with animation.
Now how do we take that beautiful
scene and actually view it in VR?
Well, we use a game object
component called a camera.
Just like in the real world, a camera is
a tool we use to capture our world and
show it to users.
With Unity,
instead of capturing the real world,
we capture virtual ones
like our lovely apartment.
Like any game object, we can
translate and rotate our camera and
this allows us to control
what the user sees.
And just like the real world,
positioning our virtual camera
is important in order to show users
exactly what we want them to see.
Otherwise, we might show them
something we didn't intend.
Camera's are super important and
without them, we literally would not
be able to see any of our masterpiece.
Let's check out how we can use them