On the new site we
were looking at before,
when we made the screen size smaller,
we couldn't see all of the elements.
So responsive design would
really help this website.
The content would then
adapt to fit any device.
The front end developers
that made this website,
can also work with designers to
create multiple mock ups for
the website to show all of the content,
even with different screen sizes.
While front end developers do focus
on optimizing website loading speeds,
this wouldn't exactly help
the problem of a responsive website.
Finally, front end developers don't
actually handle storing client
data in a database.
That's something that
backend programmers work on,
which we'll learn about more later.