If you take a look at Rick Szeliski's book which we mentioned earlier,
you can see a whole bunch of Fourier Transform pairs.
For example the impulse, which is drawn like that has a Fourier Transform of 1.
As we said that makes sense, because the impulse when you convolve it,
just gives you back the original function, so
you'd better keep all of the frequencies.
Likewise, we said here that the Fourier Transform of a Gaussian is
another Gaussian.
But again, G of sigma goes to 1 over sigma.
So fat Gaussian in space, skinny Gaussian in frequency.
But look at this one.
If I have a box filter, which is just a filter that's shaped like a box,
it produces what's called the sinc function.
Okay. And that's drawn here.
And let's look at that a little more closely, okay?
So here in this spatial domain, we have our box filter and
this is our sinc function.
All right? Now sinc of x is sine x over x, all right?
And we can think about that, if you take the limit as x goes to zero of the,
you remember L'Hopital's rule take the derivative of the top that's the cosine.
Derivative of the bottom is just one plug in a zero it's one.
So the, the limit as x goes to zero is in fact, one right there.
And then as x gets bigger, the sine gets attenuated and
that's what you're seeing here.
So in other words, if I were to convolve something with a box filter.
My frequencies are going to behave kind of in a weird way.
You know, I have this nice kind of low pass stuff, but then I'm going to have
these various other frequencies that are going to get accentuated.
And if you remember, we did that very early on when we introduced filtering.
Remember, we convolved something with a box, with a square?
And we said, man is that ugly?
This is why it's ugly.
So you see this picture here?
You see how it's got all these little striations.
And I said, when we first did this, that that's because boxes aren't smooth and
that we would make this more formal when we did Fourier analysis.
Well, I made good in my promise.
Okay? The reason that when you convolve an image with that
little square box that you see all this junk is because of
this ringing here in the frequency domain.
That's why we said, what you should do is do what?
Is you should apply a Gaussian not a box,
it makes a nice, pretty picture, you know, a nice, smooth picture.
Because in the frequency domain, you get this nice, smooth Gaussian.
One more thing about these sinc functions, okay?
So we showed that the Fourier Transform of a box is the sinc.
Well, because of the symmetry, if I had a box in frequency space,
that would be a sinc in the spatial domain.
So what if I were to take some function, take its Fourier spectrum and
multiply it by that box, what would that look like?
Well, I already just showed you that.
Right? This is essentially, it's sometimes called a pillbox, because it's a box.
But in 2D, that is instead of being just a particular width, it's a radius.
Right?
So everything outside that diameter is set to zero and
everything inside is kept exactly.
If you remember the picture we got was this ugly picture with all
this ringing in it.
Well, now we know why.
When you multiple the frequency by a box, it's as if you convolve
the image with its Fourier pair over here with the sinc function.
So if you take this pretty picture and
you convolve it with this ugly beast, you get something that looks like that.
And that's where the ringing comes from.
That's why you never want to just cut out the high frequencies, because
what you're essentially doing is convolving your image with a sinc function.