There is a danger in the previous example that the parent and
the child thread will try to update the shared list at the same time,
potentially overriding the list elements.
This illustrates a key challenge with multi-threading that there is a need for
a mechanism to enable mutual exclusion among the execution of
concurrent threads.
To do this, operating systems and
threading libraries in general support a construct called mutex.
A mutex is like a lock that should be used whenever accessing data or
stayed that's shared among threads.
When a thread locks a mutex, it has exclusive access to the shared resource.
Other threads attempting to lock the same mutex are not going to be successful.
We also use the term, acquire the lock or
acquire the mutex, to refer to this operation.
So these unsuccessful threads, they will be what we call blocked on
the lock operation, meaning they'll be suspended here, they will not be able to
proceed until the mutex owner, the lock holder, releases it.
This means that as a data structure the mutex should at
least contain information about its status.
Is it locked or free?
And it will have to have some type of list that doesn't necessarily have to
be guaranteed to be ordered, but
it has to be a some sort of list of all the threads that are blocked on
the mutex and that are waiting for it to be free.
Another common element that's part of this mutex data structure is to maintain
some information about the owner of the mutex, who currently has the lock.
A thread that has successfully locked the mutex, has exclusive rights to it,
and can proceed with its execution.
In this example, T1 gets access to the mutex and thus continues executing.
Two other threads, T2 and T3, that are also trying to
log the mutex will not be successful with that operation.
They will be blocked on the mutex, and
they will have to wait until thread one releases the mutex.
The portion of the code protected by the mutex, is called critical section.
In paper, this is any code within the curly brackets of
the lock operating that he proposes to be used with mutexes.
The critical section code should correspond with any kind of
operation that requires that only one thread at a time performs this operation.
For instance, it can be updated to shared variable like the list or
increment a counter.
Or performing any type of operation that requires mutual execution between
the threads.
Other than the critical section code,
the rest of the code in the program, the threads execution concurrently.
So using the same example, imagine that the three threads need to
execute a sequence of code among block A fold by the critical section.
And then some other portions of code, blocks B, C, and D.
All the code blocks with a letter can be executed concurrently.
The critical sections, however, can be executed only by one thread at a time.
So thread two cannot start the critical section until after thread
one finishes them.
Thread three cannot start its critical section until any prior thread
exits the critical section, or releases the lock.
All of the remaining portions of the code can be executed concurrently.
So in summary, the threads are mutually exclusive with one another,
with respect to their execution of the critical section code.
In the lock construct proposed by Burrell, again,
the critical section is the code between the curly brackets.
And the semantics are such that upon acquiring a mutex,
a thread enters the locked block.
And then when exiting the block with the closing of the curly bracket the owner
of the thread releases this mutex, frees the lock.
So the critical section code in this example, that's the code between the curly
brackets and the closing of the curly bracket implicitly frees the lock.
When a lock is freed, at this point any one of the threads that are waiting on
the log, or even a brand new thread that's just reaching the lock construct,
can start executing the lock operation.
For instance, if T3's lock statement coincides with the release of the lock,
of thread one.
T3 may be the one, to be the first one to execute, to acquire the lock and
execute the critical section although T2 was already waiting on in it.
Who will use Burrell's lock construct throughout this lecture.
However, you should know that most common APIs have two separate calls,
lock and unlock.
So, in contrast to Burrell's lock API,
in this other interface, the lock/unlock interface, both the lock and
the unlock operations must be used both explicitly and
carefully when requesting a mutex, and when accessing a critical section.
What that means is that we must explicitly lock a mutex before
entering a critical section.
And then we also must explicitly unlock the mutex when we
finish the critical session.
Otherwise nobody else will be able to proceed.