Now you have probably
used web browsers a lot.
And if you're taking this course as
part of a Udacity Nanodegree program,
you've set up your own web server for
a previous project.
But what is a server?
What does a program do
in order to be a server?
We can investigate
this a bit with Netcat.
On your Linux box, bring up the nc
manual page with man nc, and
skim it for a general idea.
Then read the section
client/server model closely.
And using that, how would you
get nc to listen on port 3456?
Put the command you'd use here.
Don't worry about the details of
what listening on a port is yet,
just take a look at the manual and
see if you can find out how to do it.