So now we can see the code for
resolve sign in error and
we can see how it works.
First of all, if we don't
already have a sign in intent,
we want to execute this code.
If we have one already we'll just wait
for it do it's activity callback.
So what we're going to do is we're
going to first of all set the sign in
progress to say,
the state is in progress.
And then we're going to call
the startIntentSenderForResult.
Check the documentation for this one.
What it does basically is it takes your
sign in intent's intent sender, and
then you tell it the RC_SIGN_IN code so
it's actually sign in intent
that we're working on.
This needs to be put
in a try catch clause.
So the catch would be
IntentSender.SendIntentException,
in which case we're
just going to log it.
And we're going to change
our sign-in progress.
If it errors of course,
we'll also try to reconnect the client.
So now this is what we did if
we didn't have a sign-in intent.
And of course, if we did have one
already we'll just show a dialog saying
there was an error.
Though sometimes it can happen where
it's unable to provide an intent.
We don't get the accounts intent.
And we don't get the confirmation
screen or anything like that.
And in that case we'll
just log an error.
Now this intent will also generate an on
activity result, so we just need to
implement an on activity result code for
the results coming back from the intent.