So let me, you know, again, just look at the whole concept of feathering.
Here are my two images.
What I can do is, I can take, and of course, we would be doing this at
the frequency spectra for each and every one of the octaves, F1 and F2.
Here I'm showing it in the spatial one.
Imagine if I was to take this signal like this and do a,
you know, computation as we've done here.
Before, again, remember these are just step functions of different types.
Of course, you'd see a sharp boundary.
So, one way to do this would be, is, I can blur this sharp boundary.
So I can run some sort of a blur kernel on these two band images here.
So this would actually make this area be not just a sharp step but
a ramp between the two.
So that would be the output here.
And if you actually use this just for
feathering between these two images, that's what the output you would get.
So now you actually see, there is blending going on, but it's much smoothed out
because of the fact that this is no longer a sharp function.
Of course, the important part to remember is, we want to do this at each and
every different octave.
So bottom line is, in doing this process, we basically can
smooth out the images, because in essence doing this blurring and
all the entire process of feathering makes the blend smoother.
So recall again, what I'm really interested is saying is,
we want to do this feathering, but we want to do this for the corresponding
octave in the Fourier domain, we want to compute the inverse Fourier transform.
And this basically allows us to do this by summing the different types of
octave images in frequency domain, and allow us to generate a smooth image.