So in this lesson, I just want to add a simple concept to, what we've already
discussed when we actually covered the whole concept of point processes and
simple arithmetic operations in the pixel values between multiple images.
I'm also going to showcase a real example of something that you'll witness and
perhaps are bothered by, as, and something that you know,
hopefully I can explain.
So another title for this lesson could easily be,
What is with all those weird artifacts in the lecture videos?
So we are going to cover, and understand those.
First let me show you the videos that you have been seeing.
Right, when you see these videos you are seeing,
various kinds of artifacts showing up in my hand, goes over it and
I am writing things down, on diffrent types of things and
you can see all of the effects but, you know, this is because.
These images of these videos that you've seen are actually a result of
combining things from multiple different types of images, and compositing or
blending them together to showcase things.
So again, I would like to explain to you why you are seeing some of
those artifacts that you are seeing in these videos.
Again, they relate exactly to topic at hand,
of doing pixel arithmetic operations.