The second one would be a good choice, and I'll explain why.
The total amount of computation to be done is proportional to l²,
the number of cells in the domain.
So if we have n² course or processors,
the amount of work for each of these is proportional to l² over n².
Which means that the first term describes the time taken by the computation alone.
But then the processors, or the course,
have to exchange data at the boundaries.
Add that, and the amount of that data is proportional to n minus 1.
We have n minus 1 vertical boundary lines
and n minus 1 horizontal boundary lines,
and it is proportional to l, because we have l cells along each boundary line.
So of these expressions, the second one makes the most sense.
Footnote: When we use this expression,
we'll find that the optimum number of processors
is proportional to the cubed root of the number of cells, l².
This is a little surprising on first sight.
You may expect that the optimum number is proportional
to the number of cells, not proportional to its cubed root.
This relationship is easy to verify by looking at the minimum of this expression.