So far you've added Record button that's
perfectly centered on screen for both
the iPhone and iPad. Now we need a way to
connect the Record button here in the
View to the code in the ViewController.swift file.
we need a way to work
with both the view that we see here in
Interface Builder and the code for the
View Controller at the same time.
There's a great way to do this in Xcode, and it's
called the assistant editor.
Before I show it to you, I’m going to reveal the
Navigator panel again. We can do that by
clicking this button here. So to use the
assistant editor, first we want to make
sure that we have our
Main.storyboard file selected, then in the
upper right-hand corner of the editor,
we want to click on the button that looks
like two circles intertwined.
This will show the assistant editor.
Great. Ok this looks like a lot of madness on
the screen, so let's hide away a couple
things so that we know what we're
looking at. I’m going to get rid of the
inspector panel or the utilities.
I’m also going to hide the debug area on the
bottom.
Great this is what we want to see.
The assistant editor splits Xcode in half.
And on the right side right now, we have
our code for the View Controller.
And on the left side we have our interface.
I’m also going to reduce the size of the
Document Outline. And scroll around to
center our interface in the interface
editor here.
Ok now we're going to use something
called an IBAction to connect the
button to our View Controller.
It's going to link the pressing of the button to a
function that's actually inside
our View Controller in code.
This is known as a Target-action.
The target is the View Controller and
the action is the function we're about to create.
Select the Record button in
the Storyboard and then we want to
control drag it over to the View
Controller’s code until it's right above
the last curly brace. So I’ll hold control
and then I’ll click drag and let's hover
it right here right above this last
curly brace and then let go.
In the dialog that appears, we want to
select Action and not Outlet.
Then for the name, let's type recordAudio.
This will be the name of the function that's
going to be created. And click Connect.
Now we see that Xcode created a
function for us called recordAudio and
it's connected the button to this
function in the ViewController.swift file.
We can see that the function
is connected back to our interface
because of this filled in circle next to
the function. When I hover over it, we can
see that the button is highlighted in
the Interface Builder. So now every time
a user presses the Record button, this
function will be called. A good practice
for software development is to test your
code often and PitchPerfect is no
exception.
Let's add a line of what I call caveman
debugging to this function to print out
to the console that the button was pressed.
So we'll type
print(“record button was pressed”).
And this should be printed each time
the user taps the button.
Ok let's press Run and run PitchPerfect
in the iOS simulator. First I need to go
back to iPhone 7, that's what I
want to use. And run. All right before I
click the Record button to test this,
if you're not seeing the debug area,
make sure that it's revealed in Xcode.
You can toggle it on and off by clicking this
button in the top right hand corner.
And I’ll drag it up to give it a little bit
more screen real estate. And we'll go
back to our simulator. Now when I press
the Record button, I can see the message
is appearing in the console. If I press the
button again, it prints out again
So we can tell that it's calling our
recordAudio function. You may be wondering why
do I call this print statement caveman debugging?
Well it's the oldest and
simplest form of debuging your code
just by logging something to the screen.
As you progress with content you'll
learn some really powerful ways to watch,
debug and step into the execution of
your code. For now we're fine to use
caveman debugging to ensure the recordAudio
function is getting called.