Now let's think about a light source,
an illumination source that can be aware
of what things are in front of it so it
can actually react appropriately to the
obstructions or objects in front of it.
Here you see a subject walking,
and of course,
you saw a little bit of a shadow, but
if you notice, the shadow is not there.
Imagine in this instance if there was
light being shone on this person,
there should have been a shadow.
And he's moving around, you kind of see
a little bit of the hands pop up but
they vanish.
Also most projector systems like this,
if you notice, there must have been,
if the person was there,
a much more thorougher light
source on the person themselves.
So this actually is done by
actually a scenario like this,
where basically using a camera
looking down this way,
you can actually track
where the person is.
So once you know where
the tracking of the person is,
you can actually turn off the signal
that actually is on top of them.
Of course,
that's the reason there was a shadow.
If you turn it off there
won't be a shadow.
And, of course,
there's another projector.
So having a, you know,
two project, projectors here,
this one fills in the hole, so now we
get a full image from this one, and
this one of course is no
longer shining lights on it.
So by having two projectors and a camera
tracking a person, in this instance, you
can now design a system that will allow
you to get images that are full all
the time and also of course not having
a lot of bright light on the subject.
This just demonstrates that you can
do this in pretty quite, you know,
pretty efficient computations, and
it works for videos of this type.
And of course, by having these
projectors, and remember what we learned
about how we can do alignments and stuff
like that, we can align both the images
to be perfect, like we've done for
all forms of image alignment or
camera projection alignment camera
calibration stuff that we looked at.