Now, I'll analyze the average case
performance of Quicksort, and
show that it is order n log n,
just like the best case.
Suppose that randomized Quicksort is
used to sort a list consisting of
elements a1 through an, all distinct.
We'll let Eijk be the event
that the element ai
is separated from the element
aj by the kth choice of a pivot.
And we'll let xij be a variable
that's 1 if the algorithm actually
compares ai with aj, and
we'll let this variable be 0 otherwise.
And we'll let xij be a variable
that's 1 if the algorithm
actually compares ai with aj,
and we'll let xij = 0 otherwise.
The sum of these xij will count the
number of comparisons that the algorithm
actually uses.
Now, I claim that the expected value for
xij is 2 divided by j- i + 1.
We'll look at this argument in some
detail, so we'll need a new canvas.
By the definition of expectation,
the expected value of xij
is this expression here.
So it's really just the probability
of xij being equal to 1.
In fact, this is true of all 0,
1 variables.
Now, ai has to be separated from
aj by some pivot in the algorithm,
and it won't be separated by 2.
Therefore, these Eijk
events are disjoint.
And this sum must be
the probability that xij is 1.
This argument is known as the Law
of Total Probability, by the way.
Each term here can be written in
terms of a conditional probability.
And it turns out that this quantity here
is the one that we're going to want to
reason about.
Given that ai is going
to be separated from aj,
it must be that they
haven't been separated yet.
So whatever the current list is,
it must include ai, aj,
every element in between, and possibly
some more elements to the outside.
Given that the separation does occur,
however,
the pivot must be chosen in this range
here, including the ai and the aj.
ai will actually only be compared to aj,
however,
if one of the two is chosen as a pivot.
Therefore, given that the separation is
going to occur, the probability that it
will actually require a comparison of
these two particular elements is only 2,
the chances of choosing
one of them as a pivot.
Divided by j- i + 1, the possible
number of choices of pivot, here.
Substituting this value into here,
will then give us the answer.
Our sum then, just becomes this ratio
times the probability of the Eijks.
We can factor out the constant
term here however.
And since i must be separated from j by
some pivot, the remaining sum is just 1.
So we obtain the desired result.
With this claim established now,
we argue that by the linearity of
expectations, the expected number of
total comparisons is just the sum
of the expectations for these xijs.
Going for
simplicity rather than tightness,
we can bound this expression
by this one here and
see that summing up the 1 over js is
rather like integrating 1 over x.
So this inner sum here becomes a log.
And then with the outer sum we
end up with n log n, overall.
To sum things up then,
we can state our result as follows.
For any input of distinct elements
Quicksort, with pivots chosen
uniformly at random, compares order
n log n elements in expectation.
The average case is on the same
order as the best case.
This is comforting, but
by itself is not necessarily
a good guarantee of performance.
It's conceivable that the distribution
of running times could
be very spread out, so that it would
be possible for the running time to be
a little better than the guarantee or
potentially much worse.
It turns out that this is not the case.
The running times are actually quite
concentrated around the expectation,
meaning one is unlikely to get much
more or much less than the average.
This sort of argument is
called a concentration bound.
And if you ever take a full
course on randomized algorithms,
a good portion will be devoted
to these types of arguments.