Hint portion.
In the first portion of this video,
I'll write some pseudocode describing
how I structure the algorithm.
Then in the second portion of the video,
I'll fill in some of the details.
If you just want to see
the pseudocode as a hint,
watch up until the timestamp listed
in the instructor notes on this page.
In general, to compute triangular form,
we will need to proceed downward
through the equations in
our system one at a time.
Let's start with a for loop to do this.
Let m equal the number of equations and
then start the for
loop with for each row i = 0 to m -1.
I'm specifying the start
index here as 0.
Since many languages use 0 as a start
index for a list or an array.
Next, we need to check the coefficient
of the appropriate variable
in the current row.
How do we know which
variable is appropriate?
Of course,
we'll want to start at the left most
variable on the first equation.
But sometimes, we won't want to examine
the ith variable, in the ith row.
We'll want to skip
down to further terms.
Let's say that j will represent
the current variable.
So, for this example, j = 0,
would mean the x term,
j = 1 would mean the y term, and
j = 2 would mean the z term.
Let n equal the number of variables and
let j = 0 and we'll put both of these
initializations outside the for loop.
Now at the top of the for loop,
let's call c the coefficient of
the jth variable in the ith row.
In most cases, we'll just want to
clear all the terms below this term.
So let's add that instruction
near the bottom of our for loop.
Clear all terms with
variable j below row i and
then we'll increment j to
move on to the next variable.
However, if c, the current coefficient,
equals 0, then we will need to
swap with an appropriate row.
So let's add, if c is equal to
0 after our assignment of c.
If we find a row under row i
with a non zero coefficient for
variable j, then let's go ahead and
swap that row with row i.
Of course, it could be possible that
there's no row underneath row i
that has a non zero coefficient for
the jth variable.
If this is the case, then we are done
clearing the jth variable and
we need to move on to the next one.
So we will increment j.
We also need to make sure
that j isn't getting too big.
However, we don't want to
increment the row counter i,
until we've performed
a successful variable clearing.
How I solve this problem is I put
a while loop inside the for loop.
While j is less than n.
Then, we need to make sure we perform
this check, is j less than n,
after we increment j after failing
a row swap or after a clearing.
So, if a swap fails and
we have to increment j, we'll run
another iteration of the while loop.
And then when we clear
a variable underneath the row,
we'll break out of the while loop to
allow an increment of the for loop.
So this is the basic structure
of my solution to the problem.
What's left is to rewrite all
this in proper syntax and
then to fill in what is meant
by these two statements.
If there's a row under row I
with non zero coefficient for
variable j, and clear all terms
with variable j below row i.
In the solution portion of this video,
we will define these
functions more precisely.
This is the end of
the Hint Portion of the video.
The full solution will now follow.
Okay, here's the function
compute_triangular_form,
now in proper Python syntax.
Instead of the non descriptive letters
m and n, I've used num_equations and
num_variables to represent the number
of equations, that is the length of
the system and the number of variables
given by the system's dimension.
Some technical changes I've made
from the pseudocode include wrapping
the value of c in a MyDecimal
object because I want to allow for
some tolerance in what is considered 0.
So instead of asking if c
equals equals zero, I use c.
is_near zero instead.
If c.is_near_zero, then I call
system.swap with row below for
non zero coefficient, if able.
This is somewhat of an unwieldy name but
it's fairly descriptive of
what's supposed to happen.
It will return either true or false
depending on whether the swap succeeded.
I also call the function
system.clear_coefficients_below
which clears all coefficients
of variable j below row i.
Looking at the swap with row
below etcetera function,
we can see that it's
fairly straightforward.
It looks at all rows beneath
the given row looking for a non zero
coefficient for the given variable,
specified as COL short for column.
If it finds such a coefficient
that isn't near zero
then it makes the swap and returns true.
Otherwise, it returns false.
The clear_coefficients below function
is also fairly straightforward.
It computes the ratio alpha it
needs to multiply the given row by,
in order to clear each row
k underneath the given row.
And then it adds alpha times
the given row to row k.
To compute alpha, it multiplies
the reciprocal of the coefficient
of the given row times the negative of
the corresponding coefficient in row k.
Now, let's run our test code and
make sure it works.
Hooray, no fill your messages
were printed, let's move on.