We're going to start by setting
up an AuthStateListener.
Why?
Well, our app has two states,
signed in and signed out.
And we need a way to determine which
of these states the app is in.
An AuthStateListener is a listener which
we attach to the fire base off object.
It executes whenever
the authentication state changes.
This includes when the listener
is first attached and
FirebaseAuth is first initialized.
In that way as soon as the user opens
the app you can know what state
they're in.
Our listener will have the code for
both setting up after you sign in and
tearing the UI down after they sign out.
So the code in the AuthStateListener
will determine what to show the user.
Following best practices,
we'll test the listener in onResume
when the app is started and visible.
And we'll also clean up the listener by
detaching in onPause when the app is no
longer visible.
It's important to remember to attach and
detach the listener,
especially since because now we're
showing multiple activities in the app.
The first is the activity when you're
signed in, which is our main activity.
And the other activity is the login
flow that show when you're signed out.
Note that the activities with the log
in flow are generated by AuthUI.
You want to make sure to be careful not
to attach the same listener more than
once as you navigate back and
forth between the two states.
But for now, we'll just worry about
setting up the AuthStateListener and
having it launch our sign in screen
if the user's not logged in.
If the user is logged in, for
now, we'll just show a toast.
Okay, enough talk, time to create.
I'm here in MainActivity, and
as with any fire based service,
the first thing you're going to need to
do is get an instance of the class, and
in this case the class
is called FireBaseAuth.
I'll make an instance variable for
it right here.
I will also need a variable for
my Authentication State Listener.
So I'll make that right here.
Okay and
now let's initialize FireBaseAuth.
So I'm going to scroll down to onCreate,
and
right after I initialize the database
I will initialize my Auth object.
And I do it in a similar way to how I
initialized my FirebaseDatabase object.
I call the static method
getInstance on FirebaseAuth.
And I also need to initialize my
authentication state listener and
I'm going to do that at the bottom
of onCreate so let me scroll down.
And here at the bottom I'm going
to say mAuthStateListener =
new AuthenticationStateListener.
Right now you've created your
AuthenticationStateListener, but
you haven't attached it yet.
If you remember what I said before
you're going to do that in on resume.
So let's scroll down and we're going to
add both onResume and onPause.
So here in onResume I'm going to add
the AuthenticationStateListener.
And I'll do that by calling
on my FirebaseAuth object.
Add AuthenticationStateListener and
I'll pass in the listener.
And then up here onPause I'm going to
do the corresponding removal of
the listener.
And that's just using
the removeAuthStateListener method.
Okay, so I'm adding it and
I'm removing it as the activity is
in the foreground and
then no longer in the foreground.
So at this point, we have a listener.
It's getting added and it's good to go.
But if we scroll up to our
actual definition of it,
it is not actually doing anything.
So, what you want to do, is to actually
check to see if the user is logged in or
not.
And then if they're not logged in,
you're going to show
them that log in screen.
Now, in this on off changed method,
you're given this parameter here,
this FirebaseAuth parameter.
And the difference between this
FirebaseAuth parameter and
the one that you initialized up here, is
that this one is guaranteed to contain
whether at that moment,
the user is authenticated or not.
And this variable has two states, it's
either signed in or it's signed out.
Okay, so I'm going to use this variable
to get something called a FirebaseUser,
and then I can check if
the user's actually logged in,
by seeing if this Firebase
user is null or not.
So here are our two cases.
The user is signed in if
the user is not null, or
they're signed out if they are null.
And here,
where the user is signed out, is where
you want to launch the sign in flow.
And that's where FirebaseUI comes in.
FirebaseUI is spectacular,
because with just one call, it'll
start this whole sign in flow for us.
Over in FireBaseUI's auth read me,
they have a couple of sign in examples.
And this one here is actually
the closest to what we want.
It enables sign in with some providers.
So, I'm going to go ahead and
copy this, and then over here,
if the user is signed out,
I'm going to go ahead and
call that method to start the sign
in flow, with a few small changes.
I'm going to get rid of
this Facebook Provider,
because we're not using Facebook.
Authentication for a.
And here I'm going to do something
called disabling SmartLock by setting is
SmartLockEnabled to false.
SmartLock allows the phone to sort
of automatically save the user's
credentials and try to log them in.
But for our simple learning purposes,
we're not going to be using it.
You might also notice that you're
passing in this RC_SIGN_IN constant.
If I scroll up, I'll see that
I'm doing this static import and
I actually don't want to do that.
Android Studio just kind of
automatically added it for me.
I want to define this constant myself.
So up here I'm going to add
a public static final integer and
I'm going to call it RC_SIGN_IN,
and we'll set it = 1.
The RC here stands for request code, and
if we scroll back down to where we use
it, so RC_SIGN_IN is passed in down
here to startActivityForResult.
And it's a flag for when we return from
starting the activity for the result.
And I promise we'll be using this
shortly so hold tight on this one.
Finally, when these are signed in, I'm
just going to add a quick little toast.
Okay and here's the Toast.
We want to be able to know when
the user actually successfully signs in
with the log in flow which
is why I'm adding this.
Okay so let's try running the code now.
So you'll see that instead of going
straight to the chat messages,
you now see this sign in flow.
This sign in flow was brought to you
by Firebase UI, which is pretty nifty
considering that you only had to
write this one line of code here.
Okay, so I'm going to say,
sign in with email.
And Firebase UI actually deals with
the entire login flow for that.
So I'll enter my email here.
And then it's smart enough to know
that I don't have an account yet.
So I could give it my name and
a password.
Okay, and then I'll save it.
Now that I'm successfully
logged in I see my toast.
There are a couple bugs on this screen
though and they mostly have to do with
our read listener and permissions and
you'll be fixing that up next.
But for now, revel in the fact that
you've logged in your first user.
Also, if you go to your off tab,
you'll be able to see them created here.
Awesome work.