So I'd like you to apply what you just
learned about Arraylist to modify
the NumbersActivity to represent
the list of vocabulary words as an array
list of strings,
rather than array of strings.
Now if I were creating this app
in a professional environment
either an array list or
array would be valid.
On the other hand, if our app connected
to the Internet and would continue to
grow with new words over time, then a
list would probably be more appropriate.
So even though our app won't get
new words from the internet,
within the context of this course I'd
still prefer to use an array list
because it's easier to add additional
words without worrying about needing
to change the size of the array.
So for the first part of this exercise,
I'd like you to modify the app so
we store the words in an array
list instead of an array.
Now the words should stay the same.
It should be the numbers one
through ten spelled out.
And be sure to update
the log messages so
we print out each element of the array
list instead of from the array.
And remember you can always reference
this table that summarizes how the code
is different between an array and
array list.
And when you run the latest
version of the code on your device
there should be any changes
in the appearance of the app.
And remember you can check the logs
to verify that the list was
created properly.
And go ahead and
check these boxes when you're done.