We need to modify our Quake Report app
to parse a JSON response from the USGS
server and convert it into
an array list of earthquakes.
So first I ask you to copy over
the QueryUtils class that I provided for
you in this link.
Select all this text and copy it.
Then in Android Studio, go ahead and
create a new Java class
file called QueryUtils.
You can remove the initial boilerplate
code, and then paste in these contents.
Let's collapse this pane so
it's easier to read this file.
Now you can scan this file to
become familiar with it, but
let's review it right now.
In this class we have a string
constant in all capital letters,
called SAMPLE_JSON_RESPONSE.
Since it's a static
final constant value,
this means the value will never change.
So remember that when we set this
constant to equal the response from
the USGS query.
The special characters like
the quotation marks are properly escaped
with a backslash character.
Then we have a private constructor,
which means no one should create
an instance of this class.
This is a utility class, so
it'll contain static variables and
static methods,
where you can call the method directly,
without having to have
an object instance of class.
Now, the most important method
is this public static method
called extractEarthquakes
that takes in no inputs and
returns an array list of earthquakes.
Within the method, we create an empty
array list of earthquakes and
return it at the end of the method.
We also have a try-catch block,
which will handle intercepting
any exceptions that get thrown
from the JSON parsing code.
We'll talk more in detail about
the try-catch blocks in Java
in the next lesson.
But for now, there's a single TODO
mark in this method that we left for
you to finish.
So let's write that together now.
Now, you could have used the pseudo
code we provided you to guide you in
writing this code.
First, we create the root JSON object
by calling the constructor, and
passing in the sample
JSON response string.
This class will parse the whole GL JSON
string we got back from the USGS API.
We'll then store this object in
a variable called baseJsonResponse.
Now, we're looking for the magnitude,
place, and time of the earthquake.
So to drill down for that info,
we first need the features array.
Within the root JSONObject,
we want to get the values
associated with the features key.
It should map to a JSONArray that
contains a list of earthquakes.
So let's call the getJSONArray method
on the baseJsonResponse object,
passing in the features key as a string.
We can then store the result in
the earthquake array variable,
which is of data type JSONArray.
At this point, we want to loop through
each earthquake in the earthquake array.
So, let's start with the for loop.
If you want to review loops and for
loops, you can check out the notes
below for a video from the last course.
Now we begin creating a loop by
initializing the counter variable
i to be 0.
Before each iteration of the loop
we test that the condition
i is less than the length of
the earthquakeArray is still true.
If it is true, we can execute all
the lines of code within the loop.
At the end of one iteration,
we increase the value of i by 1,
indicated here by the i++ syntax.
And then we can go ahead and
loop around again.
Next we can pull out the JSON
object at the specified position of
the earthquakeArray.
We start with position 0, which is the
initial value of the counter i variable.
Once we have the current
earthquake JSON object,
we can extract out the JSON object
associated with the properties key.
Remember that this lists out many
of the earthquakes' attributes.
As you can see,
these JSON objects are deeply
nested within the overall response.
But finally, we're at the level where
we can access the individual values
of the properties JSONObject by
referring to the key mag for
magnitude, place for
location, and time for
the time in milliseconds that
the earthquake happened.
For now, we can extract all
these values as strings,
because we're just displaying
them straight to the screen, and
not doing any additional calculation or
formatting on them.
Then we can create a new earthquake
object from these three strings.
And lastly, we need to add the new
earthquake to the list of earthquakes.
After the loop finishes executing
once per each earthquake in
the features array, we will then build
up a whole array list of earthquakes.
Then we can return this list as
the return value of the method.
Great work.
That was a very challenging problem
with a lot of tricky job syntax, so
you should be proud of yourself for
solving it.
I'm going to go back now and
add some more comments to my code.
All right, this looks good.
Now let's test this code
by calling this method.
For step number three of the quiz,
I asked you to modify the earthquake
activity to call the query utils
extractEarthquakes method.
So in this file, let's delete
the fake array list of earthquakes
that we created earlier, and
let's call the QueryUtils method now.
There are no errors in our code,
so let's run it on a device and
see what happens.
Awesome, our app now shows
the list of earthquakes.
This should look similar to
the sketch you drew earlier
when you parsed the JSON
response manually in your head.
If you want to reference any
of the code we showed you,
check out the notes below for
the code diff.