And the answers are 10, 19 and 23. Let's look at A. We have to move nine steps.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight nine, and over here, we have
to turn right, which costs us one so the total is going to be ten. For B,
there's two ways to get there. We can
go straight and left, which will be 6 steps,
but we've got to pay a cost of 14, for
a total of 20. It turns out it'lll be cheaper
to take the loop over here and do three right
turns, which is a total of 16 steps, and we have
three right turns, which gives us 19. For C, it
turns, there are multiple of ways to get there. You can
go straight, turn left over here. Straight, turn left over
here and go around here, which looks inferior. Or, do the
right turn trick again, but now this time do five right turns to
get to C. When you work it out, you find that going straight
and turning left is the cheapest. These are nine steps, and we pay the cost of a
left turn, which is 14, adds up to 23.