So, a couple conclusions about RANSAC.
The good, it is simple and general, it is used often.
It's applicable to many different problems.
It is robust, even with respect to a very large number of outliers,
that's really the key element.
And, it is not sensitive to the number of points that are in the, in,
in the system.
We had you do the Hough transform, and those of you doing the OMS,
you're going to do the RANSAC as well.
I will tell you that in general it's easier to get RANSAC to
work than Hough transforms.
The parameters are little more finicky than in a Hough.
And for large numbers of parameters RANSAC just means to take lots more samples.
And it goes up kind of painfully, but not awfully.
If you remember Hough transform the space complexity goes up
cominetorically in number of parameters.
And these days it's easier to deal with things that require you to be fast, but
not big.
And so, RANSAC you have to be fast as the numbers go up.
In, in Hough the, the memory size gets larger.
So, in general, making RANSAC work is easier.
The not-so-good, I don't want to say the bad, because Barney and
Bob are good friends of mine.
But actually, there's a huge body of work on RANSAC and
all its derivatives from that.
It's, it's just one of the most fundamental algorithms in computer vision.
The computational time grows quickly, with the number of parameters.
That was the s, the size of the minimal set.
Not, not awfully, awfully but you know, when you start to
get more than ten you're going to be wishing you were less than ten.
It's a little bit challenging if you've got like multiple plains, and
you wanted to full, find out each of them.
You have to be a lot,
then you have to be a lot more careful with your thresholds.
So it's not as good at multiple fits.
It's really not so great for approximate models, right?
So it, suppose it's kind of a plane, but not really a plane.
That's a problem, because now you pulled out some points.
And where it's not quite, it, it, you know,
fit a plane, it's not quite the right plane anymore.
So it can be kind of sensitive to when your model doesn't really match,
the underlying structure of what's out there.
I will tell you that it's used all the time for
doing things like, it says homogra, any sorts of image transforms.
It's also used often for
doing understanding relative views such as fundamental matrices.
And generally it's used for pretty much every problem in robot vision.
It's amazing to me.
affect, I see bubbles, on some occasion, and you know, I keep
reminding him that you know, I wish I had an algorithm that I see used just, so
often these days, because it, it is a fundamental algorithm for robot vision.