So for the Move ScrollBar action,
we will see, or the other things
that'll be involved is that the handle
itself will move, but at the same time,
we're going to need to get a new
sequence of lines from our file manager.
>> So let's imagine we're scrolling up,
and we would expect to
see some subsequent lines in the file
appear at the bottom of the screen.
How about the width of the scroll bar
handle, or do we expect that to change?
>> The width of the scroll-
>> The height.
>> No, I don't think so
unless we're resizing the window.
>> Okay,
then how about going on to the resize.
>> Right, and I guess that would be one
of the first things that would have to
happen, is when you resize the window,
the size of your handle can change.
It may also move
the position of the handle.
So like if you had the handle
at the bottom of Viewport and
you start bringing the Viewport up,
then it's going to kind of gradually,
I guess that's part of moving the view,
or changing the Viewport size as well so
these kinds of things
are all working together.
>> Right, okay.
And we might need to see some
additional lines of the file.
>> Right, right.
>> Ultimately, each of those responses
represents a relationship between
the corresponding components.