This is actually a really hard question,
and probably way too unfair for a quiz.
Yeah, I'm a jerk like that.
So I would say that your best
bets are the hypercube and
fully connected networks.
Here's my thought process.
An all to all is intrinsically
bi-section, limited.
So, of these choices,
only hypercubes and
fully connected networks have
linear bi-section widths or better.
That's what you would need to knock down
this bandwidth term from being linear in
P, to something that is logarithmic
in P, or maybe even constant.
Okay, so that's not a rigorous proof
that these are the right answers,
it's just an intuitive idea.
So, what I'll do is I'll put some
pointers in the instructor's notes where
you can do a little bit more
reading if you're interested.
I know you'll be interested,
because if you do the reading,
Mr Tofu will give you a cupcake.
This cupcake is for you,
Mr Tofu wants to give you a cupcake.