When thinking about graph algorithms
in the distributed setting,
it will often be very helpful to look
at a graph as an adjacency matrix.
Now, if you haven't seen that before or
you just need a refresher,
here's a crash course on how it works.
Start by giving each
vertex an integer label.
Next, create a matrix to
represent this graph.
Let's call it A, with row and
one column for every vertex.
Now for any edge that goes
from a source vertex i,
to a destination vertex j,
we'll put a one in the ij entry of a.
Otherwise, if an entry is empty,
assume that it has a value of zero,
which means no edge.
For instance,
let's start with vertex zero.
It's adjacent to vertices one and five.
So, let's go to row zero and
place ones at entry one and entry five.
Now, this graph is undirected,
so both rows one and
row five will also have
a one in column zero.
Put another way, the matrix for
an undirected graph is symmetric.
In linear algebraic terms,
we say A is equal to A transpose.
Now, let's do the same thing for
vertex one.
It's adjacent to vertices one,
two, and six.
So let's mark those entries of A.
And of course we'll update
the symmetric image.
When you're all done you
should get this matrix.
In general consider any
undirected graph, call it G.
Let's suppose that it has n as in Nancy
vertices and m as in Michael edges.
It's adjacency matrix will be n by n.
And since it's undirected, it will
be symmetric with two m non-zeroes.