Let's do a little quiz where you
calculate the communication time of
the summa algorithm.
You argued previously that
the running time to do all the flops
is 2n cubed over P.
But what about communication?
Here's my question.
Which of the following estimates
are plausible estimates of the overall
communication running time?
For the alpha term,
I want you to choose one of these.
For the beta term, I want you to
choose the matching one of these.
Now, I put a big O in front of this so
that you can ignore constants and
just focus on asymptotics.
Now, there may be more than one correct
pairing, so the key is, based on your
choice for one of them choose something
that's plausible for the other one.