Even though nc -l can only
handle a single connection,
you can still do some pretty
entertaining things with it.
Earlier in the lesson, we used it to
send HTTP requests to a web server and
got HTTP responses back.
But how about the other way around?
Let's take a look at what happens
if we use nc to listen for
a connection from a web browser.
Here I'm having nc listen on port 2345.
And then I'll tell my browser to
access that port on my machine.
The browser isn't getting
anything interesting.
But look at what nc is getting.
It's got the HTTP requests and
all the headers that the browser sent.
Okay, cool.
But how about if we send some HTTP back?
What do you think will happen if you run
a printf statement outputting an HTTP
response with HTTP/1.1 302
Moved\r\nLocation: https://www.eff.org.
All of that in single quotes,
piped to nc -l 2345.
And then point your web browser
at your IP address, port 2345.
You can copy this string from below.
Do you think that your browser will
display the eff.org home page?
Do you think that nc will print your
browser's request on the terminal?
Do you think that nc will exit?
Or maybe some combination of these.
Mark all of them that
you think will happen.