Okay, so now that we have our
YAML file set up, let's try and
deploy our website.
So, we'll select our project and
we'll hit Deploy.
And you'll see that we have to
sign in our Google account.
So let's do that now.
So you'll see this window
pop up after you sign in.
And let's take a look at what it says.
It says error 401, begin server output,
must authenticate first.
So, if you're wondering what
this error means, it just means
that you have to change the security
settings on your Gmail account.
So let's switch over to Gmail,
and let's refresh our inbox.
Okay, so we refreshed our inbox and
we received an email from Google.
Let's take a look at what it says.
So, it says we recently blocked a
sign-in attempt to your Google account.
So what you need to do here is click
on this link under if this was you.
And I'll take you to this tab.
We'll click on turn on access for
less secure apps.
So once it's updated, we'll switch
back to Google App Engine and
let's try to deploy again.
Okay, great.
So you'll see this pop-up window.
And it has a bunch of status
updates from Google App Engine.
And you can see at the very bottom it
says, you can close this window now.
So let's close it and
we'll switch back to our web browser.
So let's open a new tab and
lets check out our website.
So our url is,
ouruniqueprojectid.appspot.com.
And look at that, we have our website.
Hello Udacity.