Here's one possible solution.
Remember that a bitonic
split pares elements from
each half of the bitonic sequence.
For each pair it then pulls out
the smaller and the larger.
That is of course the perfect task for
a plus comparator.
So here notice how the plus comparators
pair elements of the input sequence.
The mins of each pair will
show up on these wires and
the maxes will show up on these wires.
Let's check the output.
Both halves of the output
are bitonic up to a circular shift.
Awesome.
Now I happen to place
the comparators this way.
But of course, any permutation
of the comparators would work.
So, a valid final bitonic split
circuit would look like this.
By the way, what's the work and
span of this circuit?
I'll let you ponder that while
I get ready for the next topic.