>> Since your first midterm exam is coming up, let's talk about how to review
the topics we've covered this far. >> Our journey with Grant began way back with
talking about variables and expressions which we then combined into equations to
help him start figuring out a plan for this glasses wiper business. First, he
dealt with linear equations and inequalities, how to graph them and how to solve
them. Once we encountered situations where Grant needed parabolas and their
corresponding quadratic equations, we figured out how to handle those as well.
Along the way, we've worked with every category of real number that we talked
about at the very start of the course, as well as a new classification of
number, complex numbers, which have both real and imaginary components. You've
learned a ton about algebra in the course so far, and you may be wondering, how
do I study for all of this material? And how do I take a test on the Udacity
site? Well, we've come up with a few tips to help you out. >> Go back and look
at practice questions and problem sets for Lessons 1 through 16. I also
recommend watching my review sessions and redoing the problems that come after
them. >> Make sure that you're comfortable using MathQuill, since you'll have to
input some answers in the test using it. You can look at the MathQuill overview
page on the wiki and you can go back to quizzes in the units that use MathQuill
and practice typing things in there. >> Also, make sure you're comfortable
working things out on paper, as well as typing them. Best of luck, we know
you're going to do great. >> After this first midterm, we'll be moving on to a
second case study, a new context for learning about Algebra. We're sad that our
time with Grant is over, but he's going to be just fine handling his glasses
wiper business now that we've taught him so much about math. And now, we get to
study something new and exciting, architecture. This is going to help us learn
about functions, specifically higher order polynomial functions and rational
functions and give us a lot of pretty things to look at and understand
mathematically.