You've seen two of these already.
The one with two black corners shutting in,
turned out to have a very strong match.
And we saw that this area on the wall was essentially featureless.
Similarly, any region that is too bright, or too dark,
has too little information to be useful.
Also, regions that only have horizontal edges going through them, like this, or
this one, are not useful in our stereo set up.
This is because they could result in multiple matches along the epipolar line.
Okay then, which ones are good?
Anything with a fairly distinct corner works.
So do regions with distinct vertical boundaries.
If you consider the epipolar lines going through them, you'll see that
there's no other region in the image along that line which matches the region.