I'd like to talk a little bit more about correspondence.
Specifically, we've learned that searching for correspondence means
we search along a single scan line,
but I'd like to ask the question whether it's optimal to correspond individual patches
which are independent of each other.
Would it make sense to look at the context of an entire scan line?
Let's look at the following situation.
We have a background that's black.
We have a foreground that's red,
and we have sides of the object that are both blue.
In a left image, we might see black, black,
and then there is this blue element that is only visible from the left camera,
a couple of reds--3 of them--and then we see more blacks.
From the right imager we might see black, black.
We won't see the blue over here, because it's occluded,
but we'll see a couple of reds followed by the blue over here,
which is only visible from the right camera, followed by more blacks.
When we look at the entire situation,
the question is whether we can correspond red pixels to each other
irrespective of context or whether it makes sense to look at context.
Specifically, take the mid red pixel over here--this guy over here--
and let me ask you does it correspond to the left red, the center red, or the right red?
Please check the corresponding box.