Hi, I'm a course manager.
>> And I'm Leila,
a course developer here at Udacity.
You're going to be working
with us to learn about and
implement this portion of
the software development life cycle.
This is basically the part of
the pipeline where you need to make
decisions about when and
how your software product and
updates to your software product
get delivered to customers.
>> In this course, Leila and I are going
to be talking about continuous
integration and delivery which
are core principles in DevOps.
Continuous integration is the process
of building combining and
testing developer code.
>> And continous delivery is when you
also have automated deployment processes
An additional tests that assure
the constant production readiness of
every build.
>> Together these two parts of
the software publishing process cover
a significant part of
the software life cycle.
They're critically important to think
about as they ensure that features can
move from the implementation phase
into customer hands in a reliable and
smooth way.
>> Now ultimately your team could be
working towards continuous deployment
Which is when builds are automatically
deployed and made available to users
after being automatically integrated,
built, and tested.
>> We'll talk about these key concepts,
discuss different technical and
cultural approaches to
automating the process, and
work to implement
a simple deployment flow.
>> That sounds fun.
want to dive in?
>> Sure.