So, course is a string field,
and it has field number 1.
This could also be a bytes field,
since this string does not have
any high Unicode characters in it.
But it's a good idea to
support Unicode though,
since things like people's names aren't
guaranteed to be in plain ASCII.
Like student, for instance.
So that's definitely going
to be a StringField.
And we'll give it the number 2.
They started variable is true,
so that's a Boolean.
We'll call that messages.BooleanField
with field number 3.
Current_lesson is an int, so
that goes in an IntegerField, number 4.
And finally, fraction_completed is
a float, so that goes in a FloatField.
And that'll be a number 5.