Let's check out to what it takes
to create a walking animation.
The animation constructor expects
an array of texture regions.
Now what is a texture region
as opposed to a texture?
We'll actually talk about that in
the next node, so hold on a second.
We have three frames in our walkLoop.
So we load up the texture,
convert it into a TextureRegion, and
add it into our array, then we pass
them to the constructor how long we want
each frame to last, the textures
to display, and then the PlayMode.
Also note that when we create
our application listener
we save off the time
at which it's created
that way we can get the appropriate
frame from the animation later.
Then down in the render callback we
figure out how many seconds have elapsed
since we started displaying the
animation using this bit of math here,
and then we ask the walkLoop for
the key frame that we should
be displaying right now.
That's the texture we want to display
given the elapsedTime since we started
displaying the animation.
There's also a whole lot more detail in
here about how to draw the cool
explosions we're about to see.
I'll let you look into that on your own.
So here's the result.
The animation has three frames, one
where GigaGal's left foot is forward,
one where her right foot is forward,
and one where her feet are about even.
Since we put this in ping pong mode that
means we go left foot forward, even,
right foot forward, even, and so on.
Also GigaGal appears to
be in a bit of trouble.
Hope she runs through
all the explosions okay.
Dig into the to do's in the course
code to set up GigaGal's walk loop and
the explosion animation.