At the end of this unit, you'll do
a project on unsupervised learning.
We'll give you a data set, but unlike
the data set from the previous project,
this data set has no labels to it.
And, we'll ask you to construct
a model just of the data that's there.
Now, the exciting thing about this
is because there are no labels to
this data, your model may actually
differ from somebody else's model.
You may choose to focus on different
factors or different variables and
that's not a bad thing.
The quality of your model is determined
by your goals, the predictions you're
trying to make, or
the questions you're trying to answer.
So, focus on the kinds of questions
you're trying to answer when
constructing your model of the data.