Recall the metrics of
interest in the work span or
the multi-threaded DAG model.
There's a total number of operations for
work, there's a critical path length, or
span, there's the ratio of those two,
or the average of available parallelism.
There's execution time
bounded from below and
above according to Brent's theorem,
and finally there's self speedup.
Self speedup is relative to the same
algorithm run on just one processor
rather than relative to
the best sequential algorithm.
Lucky you, I have a question for you.
Of these five measures,
which one best expresses dynamic power?
For the purpose of this exercise,
you can ignore constant power, and
you can assume a constant
energy per operation.
The case of variable energy per
operation is also a lot of fun, but
let's not consider that for the moment.
Dun, dun, dun.