Let's talk a bit more about the flow
of who calls what with Android Auto
media playback.
You can see that Android Auto
initiates the process by calling
onGetRoot of your application.
This returns back a route note ID,
and also a session token.
Next, Android Auto calls onLoadChildren
to get the complete hierarchy of the
media available from your application.
This allows browsing, but
also voice search overall with songs.
When the user is ready,
they get to pick a song,
which is then cast as an argument
to the media session dot call back.
Your app then takes action,
such as selecting a song, play, pause,
next track, et cetera.
After taking action,
your app communicates changes in the UI
by changing the metadata or
the playback state