Let me show you a few
examples again from YouTube.
This is an original video
again somebody on a bicycle.
There was an explosion, and
they're taking videos, and
you can see a lot of
non-rigid warp going on, and
of course notice things like you know
smoke here are actually not known for
being able to have very good corners,
and features that we can actually track.
This is the output, still has a little
bit of non-rigid warp, but not as much.
You would agree that it
is actually much better.
Let's put them next to each other.
Original.
Stabilized, removed
the rollling shutter.
So now as I said,
when you upload videos to YouTube
thanks to working with the YouTube
engineers, and again, you know,
Mattias and Vivek were full time
members of research staff at Google,
were able to now get this
running on the YouTube site.
When you upload a video
it pops up saying hey,
we think your video is shaky.
What would you like to do?
If you hit this button preview one,
two, three seconds later you
get a real time preview.
You can interact with it,
you can see the original, and
the stabilized version
next to each other.
And now I guess, you get the message
that basically using the approach we
just did, we can actually stabilize
video, and of course, the person can of
course, at the end save their video,
and use it for other purposes.