So one of the most crucial things that you have to do in this class is you
have to get hands-on experience with playing around with images.
And for that purpose, I would like to now introduce to you several tools we
will be using in this class.
Again, it's essential that you learn how to interact with images,
because we are going to be doing a lot of processing and
computation on images to take us towards path of doing competition photography.
To facilitate this,
first thing we will pair on with is something referred to as OpenCV.
An an interface to OpenCV that's available through Python.
Now, [INAUDIBLE] or
Daniel, the head TA, is the instructional designer for this class.
We'll provide you the various suggestions on how to get setup on this kind of
stuff either on and stuff like that.
But the goal of this just brief introduction here is to
introduce to you these tools.
OpenCV has become a predominant standard of doing any kind of computer vision or
computational photography.
It's a toolkit that actually started off from Intel many, many years ago,
but it's become an open standard.
And basically its available to anybody who can download it and
basically write code in C++.
And now with availability for Python wrap around it, even in Python.
Again, please look at these sites and
look at how we can actually interact with this.
What we are going to provide in this class is both an interactive browser, and
I'll show you that in a bit, and also ability for you to download and
actually set this up to do various types of processing of images for
computational photography.
Several of the assignments are going to rely on you to do this kind of coding in
this environment.
And share with us as part of different metrics of success of how
we can actually accomplish these goals in this class.
The next toolkit and again is a much more widely available as matlab.
This is a predominant tool for doing processing of matrices, but and
of course you know images can be represented as matrices and
it becomes actually a very widely used tool for image processing.
So if you get matlab you can actually also get the image processing toolkit, and
allows you to do a lot of different types of things.
I'll showcase that in a bit.
For educational purposes it's available at a student discount.
again, you can get that from the MathWorks website.
Again, I am not getting any financial rewards for recommending this.
It's up to you to do so.
Of course there is a public version that is
somewhat similar to Matlab also available called Octave.
Of course my hope is that you will interact and
play around with these tools to kind of help you create the building blocks that
create the machinery for doing computational photography.
Another toolkit that's become widely used these days is called Processing.
We will not be using much of this in this class, but
I just wanted to introduce this to you a little bit.
And so again a Java based setup that lets you actually play
around with images and manipulate images and videos and stuff like that.
Let's look at all three of these very briefly first.
So this just showcases an example of what we can do in a browser using OpenCV.
But of course you can use this extensively on your own workstations after you've
downloaded both OpenCV and Python on your workstations and
got them installed correctly.
Again just by doing simple coding like this we were able to run and
do processing on images.
I've just showed you, you know, smoothing an image, grayscale, edges, and
cropping an image.
And all that kind of stuff after I did the test run.
Showed all of the examples on the browser.
When you run this the first time it will be a little slow, and you'll get,
get better as you use it, but
of course really doing more complicated things that we do in this class will be
much better if you do it on your own computer, not on this browser-based stuff.
And you'll be able to actually, you know, save your work and
all that kind of stuff, and in track with the code that you develop.
So this will become a,
you know, tool that I'd like for all of us to use in this class.
And this the primary tool that you'll be doing your assignments and stuff.
I'm here now showing you just a screenshot from MathWorks Matlab.
Again this is a tool that you can also use for
doing a variety of things and it becomes a very interactive tool for
being able to kind of just load images and manipulate images.
For example.
So here I'm basically typing in that I want to assign to the variable buzz
image content from the file buzz3.jpg.
Once it's there I can actually show this image.
Which is basically right here.
So just by interactively doing these types of things I can now generate or see
images and of course then I can run various types of processing on these images.
One of the beautiful things about having it in Matlab is that you also can do
variety of things by just you know, using the mouse on it and stuff like that.
Very handy tool.
Again, Octave provides very similar facilities and
I encourage you to look at both the MathWorks site and the Octave sites.
Again, I do want you to make sure that you're picking up on
these concepts on your own.
We will not be getting into a lot of these details in the class.
again, these are introductory materials which, and there's lots of
material out there on the web for you to get familiar with these things.
Finally, this is processing.
I, I'm just showing you again the main console window for this one.
I've just inputted in a simple code.
Most of the time you'll have two different types of things.
One, do us a little bit of a setup.
Here are basically says the size of the file.
I'm actually loading in this file, and then basically displaying this image.
And of course we can just run this and it displays the image.
Again, we can now do a variety of regular processes on this image because what,
in essence, we know is how to display an image which also mean now we
have the entire image in our code to do a variety of things with.
And once we have code we can interact with this code to do a variety of things.
For example, here I am just going to now change this code, run it again.
And if you notice what I basically have done,
put half of the image of buzz here at this point here, so.
Simple processing like this can be done, and again,
in this one we'd be actually leveraging Java style code.
Three simple tools for you to play around with images.
Again, I want to emphasize that we will be using one of them more extensively.
So I just briefly showcased three different tools.
again, I want to emphasize, this is a tool that you can use in the browser, and
also interact with on your own computer by installing the tools.
Please look at the OpenCV and
the Python sites and get familiar with these things.
We will provide with various types of recommendations how you
can get set up on this.
Welcome to use and get access to MatLab and Octave if as, as much as you want.
Those of you interested in doing these kind of things with processing,
you can feel free to do this.
I do want to remind everybody that most of the assignments and
stuff that we will be providing would be actually in this domain and
we'll also be providing some sample code to get you started.