Every time an app starts up, it creates
a singleton application object,
even before it creates
the main activity.
Activities can get hold of
the application object,
by calling the method getApplication.
We're going to save our tracker
in the application object.
If you want to add things
to the application object,
you need to create a subclass of
application, but it's pretty simple.
I'll show you how.
If you already know how to do it,
bear with me.
It really won't take long.
You need to extend the application and
save it.
And for now,
that's really all you need to do.
Next, you need to make sure that
when the application starts,
it creates an instance
of your new subclass,
instead of the default
application class.
To do that,
go to Androidmanifest.xml and
add a name attribute and
specify the name of your new subclass.
You'll need to enclose it in strings and
put a dot in front of the name.
That's all there is to it.
Now when your application starts,
it creates an instance of
your new application class.
Go ahead and
define the new application subclass now.
You're going to need to create a Java
class that extends Application, then
specify your new class as the name of
the application in AndroidManifest.xml.
All you need is the name, but
remember to put a dot in front of it.
And when you're done, enter the name
of your application subclass here.