To figure this out,
let's think about what this first
set of comparators is really doing.
What it's really doing is
creating up and down pairs.
If that's the case,
then what must be true?
Well, the first four elements
are bitonic, as are the second.
Does that mean it's time for
a celebratory cocktail?
Not yet.
Patience, my child.
Now, you have two bitonic subsequences,
but your goal is to get just one.
So, what you need to do is to turn one
of these into an increasing subsequence,
and the other into
a decreasing subsequence.
Let's take the top half.
Given a bitonic sequence,
how do you get an increasing sequence?
Well, the increasing sequence is sorted.
So, you'd use a bitonic merge,
of course.
Let me fill in the circuit.
This top sub circuit is just a bitonic
merge network for an input of size four.
The bottom one is the same,
but with minus comparators, so
that you get a decreasing sequence.
In fact, you can view this first
layer that I filled in for
you as little bitonic
merges of size two.
And so you can verify what's happening,
here's a trace.
Okay, let me summarize all of this.
You start with an arbitrary input.
Then, you run little plus minus
bitonic merges of size two.
After that, you run plus minus
bitonic merges of size four.
And if you add larger input sequences,
you would just keep going.
In other words, to go from an arbitrary
input to a bitonic sequence,
you just run a bunch of bitonic
merges of increasing size.
Neat, but not on the rocks.