Hey, what's going on?
And thanks Colt.
Now, I'm really excited
to join heads and
perf out a developer
situation involving overdraw.
Now, if you want to follow along,
you'll want to clone the code sample
at the URL in the instructor notes.
All right, so here we are in
our sample code application.
Now, let's imagine,
you just created a chat application, and
you want to find out how well you did
in respect to overdraw performance.
The first thing you'll want to do is
gather information about how your
app is performing.
To do this you're going to
turn on the GPU overdraw debug
setting on your device.
You will find it within the Developer
Options section of your systems
settings, like so.
Okay, it's on now.
Now, back to our chat application.
Uh-oh, look at all this excessive
overdraw happening here.
You want to reduce this,
particularly the red areas.
So here's a little reminder
about what the colors mean.
Cool, ready to dig in?
Let's dive into how the UI
is currently built, and
see if we can clean it up
a bit to reduce some overdraw.
Now, as Colt mentioned,
one way to do this is to remove
unnecessary backgrounds and drawables.
So let's take a stab at doing that.
How about we spiff up
Chatum to be like this?
But let's chip at the problem
one step at a time.
For example,
notice that we have a green or
two x overdraw occurring in
Chatum's background right here?
Now why could this be?
Well it turns out that Chatum's
base activity uses a frame layout
with an opaque white background
that fills the entire screen.
We like this, but it collides with
Android's material theme defaults,
particularly the window
background drawable.
This causes unnecessary overdraw.
Now as a developer,
we have a design decision to make.
Let's say we want to keep
our white background,
which means there's no real purpose for
the material's theme.
So one optimization we can make
here is to set our activity's
background drawable to null.
Now, let me show you how
you can do this in code.
In Chatum's base activity,
let's look at the onCreate method.
Use the following statement
to nullify the background.
All right, sweet.
By nullifying the background we've
reduced this overdraw from a green to
a blue, effectively making
the overdraw now one x.
Nice.
Now this was a programmatic change.
But lets take a look at our XML markup
to see if we can tweak anything else.
Now, you probably already noticed that
there are three XML files that specify
Chatum's user interface.
There's the base activity
Chatum Latinum, the XML for
our chat fragment, and then lastly,
the individual XML for our chat items.
As mentioned before,
we intentionally want to keep
this white background right here.
So, let's not remove anything.
But maybe there's some opportunity for
tweaks in the remaining two XML files.
This is where I could use your help.
Do me a favor and
comb the remaining XML files, and
see if you can remove any
unnecessary backgrounds declared.
When you're finished,
enter the number of backgrounds
you've removed in this box here.
If you're having trouble,
no need to worry.
Just move on to the solution.