What we're going to do is,
now we're going to look at some properties of the Harris detector.
And actually of, of one or two other ways of detecting some interest points.
Remember, the reason we're doing this is to find points that
are going to be our feature points.
So, let's start with rotation, okay?
If I've got an image.
So we have here a little.
Notional corner.
And I would rotate it, how would the Harris operator change?
Well, remember that whole thing about the ellipse rotating?
Well the ellipse would rotate, right?
But it would be the same ellipse, right?
Because the variations in the gradients would be the same over the window.
They just, the whole thing would have rotated.
So basically, the Harris corner detector is invariant to rotation.
That's cool. You don't have to take my word for it, you can take somebody elses
word for it, no, you can actually study these things empirically, alright.
So the idea is you take some picture, you find some corners, and
then you change the picture somehow, right.
So, maybe you rotate it a little bit, and then you find some corners again, and
you measure sort of this repeatability.
Right? So the number of correspondences that were found versus
the possible ones that you should have found.
That is, how repeatable was the ability to find the same corners?
And as you can see here, as they varied the rotation of the picture all the way
up to 180 degrees, you've got pretty good reviews.
By the way, ImpHarrises improved Harris.
But you can see that both Harris and the improved Harris are.
Pretty invariant with respect to rotation.
By the way, these plots come from this very nice paper from Cordelia Schmid and,
and folks there.
And in fact, here it is, showing you,
it's from the International Journal of Computer Vision.
I put this, these sort of basic res, sources in here just so
you can see where some of this stuff comes from.
And if you're interested in computer vision,
I encourage you to take a look at what these.
Papers actually do, to get a sense of how this stuff got derived.