Now, everything is set for
the execution of the experiment.
The new candy product is shipped
to the treatment stores, and
the experiment is run for one month.
At the end of the month,
the results are in,
and it's now time to
dig into the results.
If you remember lesson two,
when analyzing a completely randomized
design, we used a T-test to test
the difference between the two groups.
We're going to do something similar for
a matched pair design, but
since we're comparing each treatment
to one or more control units,
on a unit by unit basis,
we'll use a slightly different T-test.
In the randomized experiment,
the T-test compared the mean and
variance of the treatment observations,
to the mean and
variance of the control observations.
In matched pair design,
the T-test looks at the mean and
variance of the difference
between each matched pair,
to see if it's significantly
different than zero.
This methodology is used inside of
the A/B analysis tool in Alteryx.
We'll walk through an example next, and
discuss how to interpret the results.