Finally, let's look at some aspects of the threading support in Linux as well.
Note that the current threading support in Linux has a lot of
lessons learned based in large part on earlier experiences with threads.
Such as,
the experiences that are presented in the two Solaris papers were described.
Like all operating systems, Linux has an abstraction to represent processes.
However, the main abstraction that it uses to represent an execution context is
called a task.
And it's represented via corresponding task structure.
A task is essentially the execution context of a kernel level thread.
A single-threaded process will have one task, and
a multi-threaded process will have many tasks.
One per thread.
Some of the key elements in a task structure are shown here.
Each task is identified by a task identifier, however for
historic reasons we call this a pid like a process ID.
It's a little bit misleading.
What this means is that, if we have a single thread of process that
has one task, then basically the task ID and the process ID are the same.
If we have a multi-threaded process, then we will have multiple tasks.
Each will be identified by its own identifier for
the task, and that will be held in the process ID.
Now the process as a whole, basically the entire group of tasks.
Will be identified by the process ID of
the very first task that was created when the process was first created.
This information is also stored in the task group ID field.
In addition a task structure maintains a list of tasks.
So this basically links all of the tasks that are part of
a single process it's all of threads of the process.
And so one can figure out what the process ID for
a group of tasks is also by walking through this list.
Having learned from implementation efforts like the Solaris threads
implementation Linux never had one contiguous process control block like what we
described at the start of this course.
Instead the process state was always represented through a collection
of references to data structures, like the memory management, file management.
These are all referenced via pointers.
So this makes it easy for tasks in a single process to share some portions of
the address space, like the virtual address mappings or files.
And in that case these pointers would simply point to the same
memory-management structure or file-structure.
There are a number of other fields in the task structure.
It's a data structure that's approximately 1.7 kilobytes large so
there's quite a lot of information in it.
To create a new task,
Linux supports an operation clone, and this is similar to this.
It takes a function pointer and
arguments similar to like what we saw when we were creating a new thread.
But it also has this one argument that's called sharing flags.
The flags parameter is a bit map that specifies which portion of the state
of a task will be shared between the parent and the child task.
As you can see the values of these flags can have different effects when
they're set versus when they're cleared.
For instance, when all of the flag bits are set,
then we're really creating a new thread that shares everything,
the entire address space and everything else with the parent thread.
They're part of the same address space.
If all of the sharing flags are clear,
then we're really not sharing anything between the child and the parent.
And this is more similar to what we saw happens when
we're forking a new process.
And in some cases various combinations make sense.
For instance you may want to share the files or
something else between the parent task and the child task.
Speaking of fork you should know a couple of things.
First of all fork in Linux is internally implemented via clone
by basically having these flags cleared.
And also fork has a very different semantics in Linux and compliant OS's
in general for multithreaded processes versus single threaded processes.
So for a single threaded process when we're forking we're really
expecting that the created,
that the child process will be a full replica of the parent process.
Where as with mult-threaded processes the child will
be a single threaded process.
So we're really going to create a replica of the portion of
the address space that's visible from the parent thread.
From the parent task in the process that called the fork.
This has a lot of implications on some issues related to synchronization,
to what happens with mutexs.
It's beyond the scope o f the class, but
I should just make sure that, that you're aware of this.
So that's why I'm bringing it up at this point.
The current implementation of Linux Threads is called
Native POSIX Threads Library, NPTL.
And this is a one to one model where there is a kernel level task for
each user-level thread.
This implementation replaced an earlier implementation, Linux threads, which was
very similar to the many to many model that was described in the Solaris papers.
And it suffered from the same kind of complexity regarding signal
management, etc.
In NPTL because of the one to one model the kernel sees every user level thread.
Sees all of its information,
whether it's block synchronization, what is its signal mask, everything.
This is made possible for two reasons.
First, the kernel traps have become much cheaper.
So the user to kernel level crossing that we've been trying to avoid in
part with this mini to mini model has become much faster and
we can afford to go through the kernel and update the kernel level signal map.
Also modern platforms have more memory so there really isn't some constraint to
keep the number of kernel level threads as small as possible.
So we can create as many kernel level threads and, as the process needs.
There aren't restrictions on the range of IDs that are too stressing for
most of the common processes.
So these sorts of things eliminate some of the main reasons for
going to the many to many model.
Still, however, when we start thinking about extremely large number of threads,
and as a community this is something that comes up in
the context of exascale computing.
Or when we are thinking about thread management in
platforms that are really complex,
that maybe have different kinds of processors, heterogeneity, et cetera.
Then it makes sense to start thinking again about user-level library support,
about providing more custom policies for how threads are managed, how threads,
how many threads are there going to be in the system, or similar issues.
But for most practical purposes, the one to one model that's supported by
the current Linux threading model is completely sufficient.