All right.
Here's how we're going to define
our modification of the reward function.
In this case of what we're going
to call potential base shaping.
The potential is going to be
defined by this function, Si is it?
>> Let's go with Si.
>> All right.
Here's the idea.
Once again, here's our Q function
defined in terms of a reward function.
And I did mess with this a little bit
because I now made rewards dependent on
the state that we end up in as well.
because that's going to be helpful for
keeping track of how
rewards are changing.
>> Wait, does that change anything?
That doesn't change anything, right?
Does it?
>> It doesn't change anything
in this Q function, no.
So it's the reward plus the discounted
value of the next state.
And we average that over
all possible next states
weighted by the transition probability
of ending up in that next state.
So that's all the same.
If we actually have a reward function
that's not defined in terms of S prime,
that's fine.
This is just helpful for the notation.
It doesn't actually change
anything if we ignore S prime,
the definition of R(s,a)
>> Oh, and in fact, if R(s,a) Ddoesn't
depend of S' then you're just
doing a convex sum over R(s,a) so
you want to put the R(s,a) so you'll
get back to where you were before.
>> Exactly right.
So that's right the reward
function pops back out which is
sort of the opposite of what we
just did we shoved it in there.
>> Okay.
>> Good all right and so now.
Our new reward function, R prime,
that we're going to use is going
to be the old reward function,
first state-action pair, minus
the potential of the state that we're
leaving, plus the discounted potential
of the state that we're entering.
So this difference here between the
potential of the state that we end up in
and the potential of the state that
we left is the bonus that we get,
the amount that we're getting warmer,
we're getting closer to good.
>> Okay, so looking at it.
I see, I see, let me make sure
I have the intuition here.
Let's ignore the minus side of S and
just think about the plus
gamma syathus prime.
You're saying that every time we enter
into some state, s prime, we're going to
get that little bonus, which is what
we've been talking about before.
But, now I gotta account for
the minus side of this.
Well, the minus side of this is
just a way of saying yeah, but
whenever I leave a state I
have to lose that bonus, and
that's your way of avoiding those
kind of sub-optimal positive loops.
>> Yeah, exactly right.
It's sort of like, I don't know,
good bookkeeping or accounting.
We have to make sure that, sure we made
a transition from state s to s prime.
We get this advantage of being in
s prime but we have to have lost
the advantage of having been in
s cause we're not there anymore.
>> Okay, so this makes sense.
>> Great, okay.
So what we need to do now is figure out
what does the new Q function
look like when we've made
these revisions to the rewards as
a function of the old Q function?
>> Okay.
Oh, I think I know the answer.
>> All right, so
do you think you're ready for a quiz or
do you need any additional
explanation of what I'm asking?
>> No, I think I know.
We know either Q of SA is we're going
to change the way the reward function
works to have these potentials, and so
that's going to change what Q of SA is.
It's going to be now called Q prime of
SA, and you want to know if there's some
nice way to describe Q prime of SA I
guess in terms of the old q of s of a.
>> That's right, that's right and
in fact there is a nice
way of explaining it.
Or it's not of explaining it but
of defining Q prime in terms of Q.
>> Okay I think I know the answer,
we'll see.