Welcome to the Core Sandbox a place
where you'll be testing out Swift code.
Here you'll mainly be doing two things,
running example code
to see its output and writing your own
code to complete programming challenges.
Let's say I wanted to know what
a particular line of code does,
what about the print function?
Here I'll try out some math, I'll put
some math here in between parenthesis.
And then I come down here and press
test run and it prints out the results.
Let's try out a string.
Again, I press test run and
here I can see my string is printed out.
Hello from the iOS team!
And I can see that this function prints
out whatever I put between parentheses.
So if you want to know what a line
of code does, you can always return
to this page, type in some code,
print the output, and press Test Run.
[BLANK_AUDIO]