Since we now know that in order to bake
lights for an object, it must be static
in the scene, we should figure out how
to tell Unity an object doesn't move.
So to do that, we first click
on the object in the hierarchy.
In this case I'm going to be
clicking on the GL game object.
Now if you look at the top right of the
inspector, you'll see a static checkbox.
This is the property that Unity uses to
tell whether an object is static or not.
You'll see that it's currently
unchecked, so let's enable it.
Once we do that,
Unity prompts us if we want to
apply this setting to all children.
Since that would be our whole room, and
we know that it's all static,
let's click Yes.
Now we've defined our whole
apartment to be static, and
we've actually enabled it that to be
static not only for lighting, but
also for
a bunch of different properties.
If we click the down arrow next to
the Static button, we'll see that
we can choose for which properties
we want this object to be static.
There can be cases when we want
an object to be static for,
say, lighting, but not for navigation.
You'll usually tackle these
on a case by case basis.
But in general, if you know an object is
never going to move, like our apartment,
then we should mark it static for
everything.
Now let's move on to
the lighting aspect.
In case you didn't notice,
we've actually already added in
several area lights to the scene.
So we just need to bake them now.
To do that, we go to Window &gt; Lighting.
Let's dock that next to the inspector
and then click Build to bake our lights.
Give it some time since this is bit
more complicated of a calculation.
To remove this red tint,
let's disable our point light, and
there we go,
we have a super nicely lit room.
Now, you may be wondering what
the sliding window is, and
we'll be exploring that next.