To make things concrete, let's
consider two multi threaded processes
in which the threads need to
communicate via shared memory.
First consider how many segments will
your processes need to communicate.
Will they use one large segment?
In that case you will have to
implement some type of management of
this shared memory.
You'll have to have some memory
manager that will allocate and
free this memory for the threads
from the different processes.
Or you can use multiple segments,
smaller ones, one for
each pair-wise communication.
If you choose to do this, it's
probably a good idea to prealloacate,
ahead of time, a pool of segments.
So you don't have to slow down,
that way, every individual communication
with the segment creation overhead.
So, in that case, you will have to
create how will threads pick up
which of the available segments
they will end up using for
their inter process communication?
So, using some type of queue of
segment identifiers will be, probably,
a good idea for that.
The tricky part here, if you are using
a queue of segment identifiers,
that means that a thread doesn't know
up front which particular segment
it's going to use for a communication
with a peer thread in the other process.
If that's important for the type of
application that you're developing, you
can consider communicating the segment
identifier from one process to another
via some other type of communication
mechanism, like via message queue.