This is very similar
to our first project.
It has a few twists though.
The view must always keep
the same aspect ratio.
We'll use a square but
it could be anything else.
The view must always be centered and it
should take as much space as possible.
For this case study we won't
be needing a stac view.
Although, it wouldn't hurt.
But we will learn a lot
about constraints.
Let's go for it.
Let's start by laying out the view.
This view could be inside
of a stack view, but for
this case we don't really need it,
although it wouldn't hurt.
So for the aspect ratio we
need a constraint that relates
the height to the width
of the same view.
That last part is new and
there's a constraint for that.
So control, drag,
and aspect ratio.
If you select it it's 48 x 43.
That's because it wasn't
a perfect square.
We can fix that by make it one to one.
And it's complaining about
it needs constraints for
the x position, and the y position.
I have to worry about that,
we'll do it later.
So auto layout knows that
the view has to be a square.
But it doesn't know the size or
the position.
Those are still ambiguous.
Well, have some patience.
Let's tackle the next requirement,
it must be centered.
We can fix that with two constraints
that center the view vertically and
horizontally.
Center horizontally and
center vertically.
Well, auto layout is hard to please,
now it's unhappy because
the size is ambiguous.
Think about it,
if I put ginormous image in there
the intrinsic size of
the view would change.
Image view would still be square and
centered, but
it would be way beyond the edges.
So we need to find a way to tell outer
layout to keep the image view contained.
Within the edges of it's super view.
What this means is that the height and
the width of the image view
must always be smaller or equal to
the height and width of the super view.
This is a new type of constraint.
Let's create them.
One for the height and
one for the width.
I'll select equal width.
We have created a constraint
that relates the width
of the image view to
the width of the view itself.
And here are the properties and
this is what we need to change.
So far,
every constraint that we have used,
the relationship has always been equal.
Something must be equal
to something else.
But, there are other options.
Less than or equal,
greater than or equal.
We want the width of
the image to be less than or
equal to the super view.
And now let's do the same thing for
the height.
Instead of equal, less than or equal.
And believe it or
not after all our troubles,
auto layout is still complaining
about the exact size of the view.
It knows the maximum size but
not the exact one.
At this point we can ignore the warning
as the exact size of the image view
will be provided by it's content as
soon as we assign an image to it.
So let's get it done so
we can get rid of the warning.
There's a misplacement.
Fix it, and there it is.
If you change the orientation,
it's still the maximum
possible square and center.
You could add some margins here, and I
recommend you try on other devices too.
So, in this case study, you've learned
that constraints can relate properties
of the same view, and that not
all constraints have to be equal.
They can also be less than or
equal than, not bad.