My name is Azad Balabanian.
&gt;&gt; Dioselin Gonzalez
&gt;&gt; Andrey Doronichev and
I'm a group project manager at Google.
&gt;&gt; I'm the creative lead at Upload.
&gt;&gt; Virtual reality principal
engineer at Unity Labs.
&gt;&gt; I changed my career to virtual
reality because I firmly believe that
VR is the future of computing and media
&gt;&gt; I was doing computer engineering.
We had a class on virtual reality, and
they were telling us about this brand
new virtual reality technology
that was invented by a Venezuelan.
Hearing about her story really inspired
me to get into virtual reality.
&gt;&gt; I changed my career to
virtual reality because
this is the playing grounds for
what's coming.
And to get your feet wet this
early is really important from
a design perspective.
&gt;&gt; In the past,
elements of digital world were always
constrained by a screen, big or small.
And then for the first time,
we got this rare,
amazing opportunity to
step into the video.
To step into the world of computing and
be surrounded by digital elements.
Move around,
interact with them naturally.
&gt;&gt; Virtual reality is
the mix of different senses.
So create a truly multi sensory system
is one thing that is
a huge opportunity today.
&gt;&gt; And that changes the way
you design software.
It changes the way you build it and
optimize it.
&gt;&gt; Virtual reality is honestly just
the step in the next direction of where
computing is going.
It's a very open field for
anyone to jump into and
actually make a name for themselves.
&gt;&gt; So for me it was a way to help
defining the future of computing.
And learn critical skills that will
make me relevant to this industry for
the next decade.
&gt;&gt; I'm Christian Plageman, co-founder of
Google's VR team and curriculum lead for
VR here at Udacity.
In this nanodegree program,
we bring you an amazing curriculum
to jump start your career
as a VR developer.
Here you will build a portfolio of
projects to showcase your new skills.
Each of these projects will
be reviewed for you and
you'll receive personal
detailed feedback.
You will learn the foundations
of VR as we cover 3D scenes,
script programming, a little bit
of science, a little math and
a whole lot about how to create
great reality from scratch.
By paying extra attention to VR design,
we'll explore what makes a VR
experience compelling, comfortable,
easy to use and immersive.
Now is the time to learn the skills
needed to make high quality
VR experiences yourself.