Here you can see where I've created my
PendingIntent called mSignInIntent.
It's just an activity level variable.
And ditto for the int mSignInError.
We'll be accessing these
in the onConnectionFailed.
And here you can see
my onConnectionFailed.
I have a connection result
called result coming in with it.
I'm just going to log
what's been going on.
And then I'm going to
check the mSignInProgress.
If it is not state in progress,
then we want to
get the resolution from the result and
load that into the SignInIntent.
And the error code from the result
will be loaded into the sign in error.
We can use these to log and
track what's going on.
If the sign in progress is
actually state sign in,
it shows that the user already
clicked on the button.
And we should continue
processing errors.
There can be a number of errors that get
fired when it's trying to sign in, so
we should just call resolveSignInError.
Finally, if we fall out of this
If clause and we're down to here,
then we're actually signed out, so
we should just call onSignedOut.
We'll implement that shortly.