Now let me so you what this
system looks like on YouTube.
This is one rendition of it.
When you go to YouTube,
you can upload a video.
And after you upload a video,
it's now part of the enhancement suite.
You can actually see the videos and
you can actually apply a variety of
different fixes to the videos
including change the colors.
But the one that I want actually
mostly emphasize is the one stabilize.
Click that button.
And a few seconds later,
you actually got a result.
This is the original video.
Shaky.
This is the final one
much more stabilized.
And of course,
since it's running on YouTube.
Thanks for the amazing efforts of all
of the YouTube engineers who have done
an amazing job of
building this whole UI.
In real time,
you can actually now see the impact
of what your algorithm just did.
I'll show you what active different
examples of this in a bit.
But what you can do is after
you've uploaded your video,
you can actually stabilize it and
actually save the MP4 file.
And after it, actually does the whole
full in the scales, HD resolution
stabilization on your video,
you can download it when its done.
Additional feature in this thing
is that when you upload a video,
it pops up and says, oh,
we think your video is shaky,
do you want to improve
the quality of it?
Completely automatic, as I said,
this is for purely casual users.
And once you press this button, again
it pops up, the improve quality next to
your self, next to the original one and
then you can visualize it.
And then of course, after if you
like it, you can save the changes.
Encourage anybody who wants to play
around with this to upload your own
videos on YouTube and try it out.
The interface has evolved
a little bit from this version.
But basically, it has the same
software that I'm talking about.