Now let's look at a couple of other important things about light itself.
One thing about light is it diffracts.
Basically because it's the, you know, it's light is best represented as
waveforms, and the wave nature of light basically suggests that when it hits,
and it's coming up this way, and it hits.
Hits a surface like this, and if there's a point, once it
hits this point it basically is going to start creating diffraction patterns.
So smaller the aperture,
would actually result in more diffraction from this point on.
So in essence what this shows is that once the light hits this point it actually
starts creating these diffraction patterns rather than going through straight.
If this was no surface here, it would of course continue going straight.
But once you put an obstruction and a small hole, depending on the size of hole,
you'd actually get diffraction patterns.
This is best also shown here,
through the light frames of This is also best shown here.
Light is coming in, once it hits this.
Because of the opening, a diffraction pattern is created and
you can see these diffraction patterns as rotations.
And, again, there's a little bit more intensity here that dissipates
as you go there.