Here's a diagram of the state space for
the vacuum world.
Note that there are eight states and we
have the actions connecting the states.
Just as we did in the Romania problem.
Now, let's look at a path
through this state.
Let's say we start out in this
position and then we apply the action
of moving right, then we end up in
a position where the state of the world
looks the same, except the robot has
moved from position A to position B.
Now, if we apply the action,
turn on the sucking action,
then we end up in a state where
the robot is in the same position,
but that position is no longer dirty.
Let's take this very
simple vacuum world, and
make a slightly more complicated one.
First, we'll say that
the robot has a power switch.
Which can be in one of three conditions,
on, off, or sleep.
Next, we'll say that the robot
has a dirt sensing camera, and
that camera can either be on or off.
Third, this is the deluxe model of
robot, in which the brushes that clean
up the dust can be set at one of five
different heights to be appropriate for
whatever level of carpeting you have.
And finally,
rather then just having the 2 positions,
we'll extend that out and
have 10 positions.
And now the question is,
how many states in this state space?
[BLANK_AUDIO]