Now, it's important for performance
that each individual function
runs as efficiently as possible,
but equally important for
performance is when and where in
your code that function executes.
See, whenever you first start an Android
application, the main thread of
execution is created, this main thread
is very important because it's in charge
of running your code, dispatching
events at the appropriate views, and
executing your drawing functions, which
we've kind of already talked about.
Basically, this main thread is
where your application was.
Now the main thread is also
sometimes called the UI thread,
because this is also the thread
your users interact with.
For instance,
if you touch a button on the screen,
then the UI thread dispatches a touch
event to the view, the view sets
the button state to pressed, and posts
a validate request to the event queue,
then, the UI thread
processes the request and
notifies the button to draw
itself in a pressed state.
Whew!
Now if you have any on touch event
handlers, those will be executed
in the middle of that huge flow,
and the longer it takes your
on touch functions to process,
the longer it will take, before your
draw function is ticked off, and
the view is updated visually for
your users to see.
The takeaway here is that your input
handling code is sharing cycles with
your rendering and
update code on this same thread.
This means the UI can't draw while
you're updating in the middle
of a computation that may be dealing
with touch events, network access, or
database queries.
In simple situations, this can cause
you to miss the 16 millisecond window
dropping a rendering frame and letting
your user experience annoying lag.
However if you end up pausing
the rendering of your UI thread for
more than five seconds,
the users presented with the infamous
application not responding dialogue.
Which basically asks the user if
they'd like to close your application,
which I'm not sure is ideal
in terms of user attention.
Right?
So how do you fix this?
Well, you identify any pieces of work
that do not need to be done on the main
thread that is the work doesn't
need to be completed in order for
the draw to occur.
And then you move that work onto
a separate independent thread of
execution, where it doesn't
block the UI thread.
For example, if pressing the submit
button completes an order, then
composing and sending the confirmation
e-mail can be done on a separate thread.
Now that may sound daunting but
don't worry, Android has a cool set of
APIs to make this easy for you to do.