How about you write
the function to do this?
That is compute an integral image.
At every location (y, x) and
the resulting image I,
you should store the, the sum of
the pixels from (1, 1) through y, x.
That is from the top left corner 'til
that pixel including y x coordinate.
Here's some test code.
We're using a magnified
image of blood cells, for
no apparent reason, and this is how we
should be able to call your function.
You should then be able to
display it scaled, like here.
Or just by passing an empty
vector in as the second argument.
Note that the maximum
value in an integral image
is in the bottom right pixel.
So this max expression can
be replaced by I end, end.
To check whether the function is working
correctly, let's define a window.
As a ground truth, we can select this
window within the original image, and
compute its sum.
Note that when reading the image,
we converted it to double type.
So we shouldn't face
any overflow errors.
The equivalent expression,
using the integral image I,
looks something like this.
I'll explain this later, but
it's basically A minus B minus C plus D.
These two values should be equal.
All right?
Give it a shot.