In some sense you might think that the visual system is making a mistake, right,
I mean after all these two squares have the same amount of
photons hitting your eye and
yet your brain says, no that one is made out of darker stuff than this one.
But of course what's actually happening is your brain is sort of decomposing
this problem into the amount of illumination and the underlying reflectants.
Let's use this example to frame the problem a bit.
First of all we're going to assume that we have a Lambertian surface.
And what we mean by a lambertian surface you remember is just the,
the lightness that will, will come back to the camera.
I'm just going to use the term lightness.
I'm not going to use radiance or irradiance, etc,
because I'm, I don't want to worry too much about that particular physics.
Basically I just want to talk about the lightness that the camera sees as,
is being a function of just three things.
The I is just the power of the illuminate, the strength of the light.
Rho is the albedo and then there's this theta angle and
the cosine of the theta determines the brightness of it.
And it's just the angle between the illuminate and the,
the normal, sometimes called the incident angle because it's the incident angle.
The problem is, we have this ambiguity, all right?
Let's combine both the angle and
the strength of the illuminate into a single term E.
Just think of that as energy or something like that, right?
It's the amount of energy incident on this,
we've already taken into account the cosine angle.
And then we also have some reflectance function maybe it's just the albedo R.
So the brightness at any point of time is equal to
this product of the reflectance times the energy, R times E.
So L is equal to R times E.
So, we can think of it this way, right?
E is the amount, is the sort of the appearance of a white piece of
paper with the given aluminant, right.
So if you were reflecting everything everywhere,
E would just be what it would look like if I had a white piece of paper.
Likewise, R, the reflectance, if I just had a constant white light,
all right, we're not worrying about color, but just constant light.
It's sort of the plainer patch, that's,
that's what the, the, the reflectance is.
And L is what we see.
All right.
And the problem is, if we measure L and we want to recover R,
the question is how is this possible because we might not know E, right.
So E can vary, right?
It can fall off, you know, because of the shadow, etc.
So the question is, how can we do this?
And the answer to do this is we have to make some additional assumptions.