In this demo, you'll use accelerometer
readings to create a bubble level,
like the kind you'd use in carpentry
to make sure that a board is flat.
This exercise is very similar to
the previous demo, where we drew lines
representing the magnitude of
the acceleration in the various axis.
In this case, however, we'll combine
those magnitudes in a single vector and
we'll draw a bubble there.
First, we'll draw a circle centered
in the middle of the world
with a radius equal to
a quarter of the world's size.
We want to scale the movement of
the bubble such that when the phone is
vertical, the bubble will
just be resting on this line.
So obviously you can't see it
when the phone is vertical,
but as I tilt the phone, the bubble
will be approaching that red line.
Then we'll just draw a little
green bubble right in the middle
that just barely holds the bubble
when the phone is level.
All right, give the bubble level a try.
This is another tough one.
So feel free to refer back to
the previous demo or the solution code.