First, let's look at the quantity covariance.
First we take the expectation value of x minus the mean of x and
y minus the mean of y multiplied together.
This quantity is the covariance between the variables x and the variable y.
The Pearson's correlation coefficient, is given as the ratio between
the covariance and the standard deviations of x and y multiplied together.
Scipy happens to have a built in library called pearsonr,
that calculates the Pearson correlation coefficient between two variables.
In our case, we want to calculate the relation coefficient between f1 and f2.
Let's run this code.
We get the values of 0.99.
This shows a direct
linear correlation between the variables f1 and the variable f2.
This sort of makes sense.
What that means, is that the average MediCare payment amount,
is directly proportional to the average MediCare allowed amounts.
You can also use the core plot method from c born to
quickly give you a correlation matrix of all your variables.
Let's run this code.
Upon running you will see a matrix like this.
It calculates the correlation between two variables that can be
calculated as they need to be numerical values.
In this case, we have a heat map that denotes all
the correlations between the different variables in our data set.
This is a nice little tool, to look at all the variables in their data set,
and see how they are correlated with each other.
If you want to learn more details on correlation coefficients,
please look in the referenced book in the instructor's notes.