So then I said that
Android isn't a horse.
>> [LAUGH] One sec.
Sorry my phone appears to be crashing.
>> That's not good.
>> No kidding.
I think it has something to
do with Shopping List ++.
Ever since I downloaded
the newest version and
started using it my phone's
been really sluggish.
And sometimes it feels like it gets
super warm, which is pleasant during
the cool nights I spend coding, but
probably isn't great for the phone.
>> Hmm, any ideas what could
be causing the slow down?
>> Hm, well I've been so wrapped up
with getting the features out the door,
I haven't even thought about
what might be going on.
It's probably some sort of memory leak,
and
it probably has something to do
with not cleaning up the listeners.
Right, I'm looking at the docs now,
there's a detach listener
that looks useful.
>> Hm, well I'm surprised that or
Walter or one of the other users
hasn't complained-
>> No!
My phone!
It died!
Why?
>> Shoot, I should probably
see what that was all about.
>> Wait!
Well, I got the docs here.
At least you and
I can go over removing listeners, and
maybe you can fix the app.
The code you're looking for
is removeEventListner.
To use this method,
you'll pass in the event listener.
However, the single location
has multiple listeners,
you need to make sure to go through and
remove each listener.
Keep in mind this doesn't
remove child listeners.
You'll need to call
removeEventListner(childEventListener)
for any child listeners.
Lastly, Fire based list adapters
will also need to be cleaned up.
Generally, you should keep
a reference to every listener and
location you add, and
then remove them in an onDestroy method.
However, for Firebase list adapters you
can call the handy cleanup method to
have them self destruct and destroy
any references they're holding on to.
>> Okay, what did I miss?
>> Is everything okay?
>> Well, Kagure's okay.
Her phone, poor thing.
>> I told the developer about
removing event listeners.
>> Great.
Can you remove them and
then fix up the memory leak?