So how does an application,
like Gmail, which can literally have
a list of millions of messages, work?
It has to do with recycling and
RecyclerView.
Here's our final forecast view for
Sunshine.
As you can see it's scrolls beautifully.
What's actually happening
is something like this.
Rather than creating these
list items as we scroll,
which would potentially
cause glitches and
performance problems, we keep some in
a queue, or recycling bin, for reuse.
What's actually happening
is something like this.
Rather than creating these
list items as we scroll,
which would potentially
cause glitches and
performance problems, we keep some in
a queue, or recycling bin, for reuse.
When we're about to scroll,
the RecyclerView returns one of these
previously created list items to you.
Your code then binds the list
item view with new content
then it can be scrolled in.
Views that are scrolled out are then
placed back into the queue for reuse.
This is a simplistic version
of what actually happens.
RecyclerViews have to deal with
fast flings, animations and
lots of other conditions, but
this is what's going on at a high level.