So when it said somebody didn't respond
well to an adverse thing that happened.
Reasonable people of course can have
different answers and agree to disagree.
They did a number of things
that were kind of right.
They actually discovered it themselves.
It wasn't in the newspapers [INAUDIBLE].
They fairly quickly actually
reached out to law enforcement,
also customers and so on.
So a number of people feel that
they actually did a good job,
there were some things that they
didn't do as well according to others.
One was that since they
responded fairly quickly,
they didn't know all the details
of the response was kind of weird.
Others said, well, they didn't
inform other key stake holders,
or people that they had business with,
and things like that.
But overall, I think tone was positive,
so I'm going to pick a yes here.
If you read more about it and
you have a different opinion and
you have a good justification for
it, here it's okay to choose a no.