One of the fundamental things about robotics is called "perception."
The story here is that you get sensor measurements, and you're trying to estimate
an internal state such that the internal state is sufficient to determine what to do next.
It's usually a recursive method. It's called a "filter." We talked about this at length.
I'm going to ask you a few questions about the state itself. So here's a quiz.
Suppose we have a mobile robot that is round and lives on a plane,
and it can turn on the spot, but its location is given by a two-dimensional coordinate.
It might face in a certain direction.
We really care about what's called the kinematic state.
That is, we care about where it is but not how fast it is actually moving.
So what is the dimensionality of the state space for such a robot?
I do realize we haven't really talked about this much yet.
I'd like you to take a good guess, and I'll tell you the answer once you have made your guess.