The Simplex method as
it is described here,
was first published by
George Dantzig in 1947.
Fourier apparently had a similar
idea in the early 19th century, and
Leonid Kantorovichhad already used
the method to help the Soviet Army
in World War II.
In was Danzig's publication however,
that led to the widespread application
of the method to industry.
As the lessons of operation
research learned from the war,
began to be applied to the wider economy
and fuel the post-war economic boom.
It remains a popular algorithm today.
As practical as the algorithm was,
theoretical guarantees on
its performance remain poor.
And in fact in 1972, showed that the
worst case complexity is exponential.
It wasn't until 1979, that Khachiyan
published the ellipsoid algorithm, and
showed that linear programs can
be solved in polynomial time.
His results were improved upon in 1984
by Karmarkar, whose method turned
out to be practical enough to be
competitive with the Simplex method for
real world problems.
Both of these algorithms take shortcuts
through the middle of the polyhedron,
instead of always going
from vertex to vertex.
In the next lecture,
we'll talk about the duality paradigm,
which rises out of linear programming.
And has been the source of many insights
and the inspiration for new algorithms.
Even with a whole other lesson however,
we're only going to be able
to scratch the surface
of the huge body of knowledge
surrounding this fundamental problem.
That has shown itself to be of deep
importance in both theory and practice.