Let's review what the quiz asked us.
We're supposed to set noun replacement
and verb replacement to our own noun and
verb strings, and then concatenate
the variables, substrings one to three,
noun replacement and verb replacement
to the empty string new sentence so
that it's in the same order as the
variable sentence that we have up here.
Well, let's start by giving our noun and
verb replacement strings some values.
Pretty simple,
I'll pick apple as my noun.
And I'll pick fall as my verb.
Now that we have noun and
verb replacements,
we'll need to add our five variables to
the empty string new_sentence over here,
so that it keeps the original
sentence structure like we have here.
Since Substring1 was
everything before noun,
we'll add that to new_sentence, first.
Since substring2 was
everything after noun,
we'll need to add
noun_replacement second.
Now that we have noun in place,
substring2 was everything after noun and
before verb.
So let's add that third.
Now our sentence has
everything up until verb, so
we'll add our verb replacement now.
Finally, we'll add substring3,
which is everything after verb.
And there we have it,
our string new sentence maintains a
structure of the original sentence, but
replaces noun and verb with our
own unique verbs and nouns.
Now all we need to do to generate
a new Mad Libs style sentence,
is to change the values of this noun
replacement and verb replacement.
Pretty cool.