Android wear devices have
a variety of screen technologies,
each with their own advantages and
considerations.
When designing ambient mode for
your Watch Face, you should consider
how it affects battery life and
screen burn in on different screens.
You can configure your Watch Face to
display different ambient designs,
depending on the kind of screen
available on your device.
Consider the best design for
your watch faces on all screens.
Some displays use a reduced color
spacing ambient mode to save power.
One reduced color space parse saving
method is to use a low-bit mode.
In low-bit mode the available colors
are limited to black, white, blue,
red, magenta, green, cyan and yellow,
as shown in this diagram here.
So this means you cannot use anti-
aliasing, which is commonly used to blur
the edges of lines in text,
to make it look smooth.
You can see how the top ABC123,
looks much smoother than the bottom one.
You can't do this
smoothing in low-bit mode.
On displays like OLEDs,
eliminating pixels consumes power.
So the more pixels you can leave
as black, will be more efficient.
You should aim for
5% of pixels illuminated.
Other displays support
grayscale in ambient mode, so
you can support showing a background
image like you can see here.
Generally, you probably
want to keep things simple and
not show a background on any type of
device, but you can in this scenario.
As we said before, OLED displays
are capable of being always on and
have good power efficiency.
But it comes with the problem
of screen burning.
If pixels are illuminated constantly,
they'll eventually be burned
into the display permanently.
So you should always
disable the background, and
keep 95% of the pixels truly black and
also avoid solid regions.
To avoid solid regions, you could
replace solid shapes, like these hands,
with an outline and
hole out the center where the hands
meet, like in this image here.
The system actually giggles your
image by a few pixels every so
often to ensure that no pixels
are ever stuck being permanently on.
You might notice this as the watch
goes from interactive to ambient mode.
Here is a sped up view of a watch and
you can see the movement
of the screen over time.
Okay, let's due a quick quiz.
Let's match the appropriate watch face
with the watch hardware that we have.