So just reviewing in homogeneous coordinates, given two points, p1 and p2,
if I ask you to find the line, no problem.
Just take their cross product, l is p1 p2.
No algebra required while doing cross-product.
No thinking about lines, equations or something Mrs.
Murphy taught you in eighth grade about how to go from.
No, you just take the cross product.
Likewise, if I have two lines a1x, b1y, c1 equals zero.
A2x plus b2y plus c2 equals zero, and
I want to know the intersection of those two lines.
That actually took a little bit of work in Mrs. Murphy's class, right?
If I gave you the equation of two lines and
I told you to find their intersection, you had to think about, well,
I have to sort of make them equal and solve these two sum.
No, you just cross them.
You know why Mrs. Murphy didn't teach you that?
She didn't know.
It's a long story about algebra teachers.
Anyway, cool.