Once a model is selected based
upon the AIC and errors,
we can use the time series forecasting
tool in Alteryx to produce
our forecast and visualization piece.
Looking across all of our models,
ARIMA and ETS, the ARIMA with
two MA terms is our best fit.
It has the lowest AIC and the root
mean square error values are smallest.
A lower RSMC means that our forecast
has a narrow range of possible values.
The TS forecast tool provides
forecast for either an ARIMA or
ETS model for
user specified number of future periods.
In addition, upper and lower confidence
interval bounds are provided for
two different user-specified
percentage confidence intervals.
For each confidence level, the expected
probability the true value will fall
within the provided bounds corresponds
to the confidence level percentage.
The results from our O node in the TS
forecast tool provides a table that
we could output to a number
of different file types
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The R node will present a TS
plot of the forecasted values
in an image of the output table.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Lastly, the interactive node
shows us the forecasted and
actual values with the surrounding
confidence intervals.
We can zoom further by
left-clicking on the plot and
highlighting the area to zoom,
to better see the forecasted area.