So let's talk a little bit about stereovision.
How do humans do it?
And at the very,
very end of the course we'll talk about the physiology of the human system.
But today I just want to talk about the computation.
If you think about it,
you can imagine that stereo is done a couple of different ways.
One way might be that you sort of find some regions in one image and
then you find those regions in the other image and your brain compares them and
sees how they've shifted relative to each other and
then somehow find, figure out the depth.
Another possibility is that maybe you just process the very
low level images doing some sort of a comparison and get the depth.
So you do fusion first, and then you do recognition.
So if theres a question of whether you do monocular recognition and
then fuse, or you fuse the images and
then do binocular, that is given the fused images to the recognition.
So back in the 60s a psychophysicist named Bela Julesz wanted to
look at this question.
So to test this he made a pair of synthetic images which were
obtained by essentially spraying black dots on white objects.
All right?
So here's a notional description comes from the Forsyth and Ponce book.
Of sort of putting imagine that those are white and you sprinkled pepper or
you sprinkled black dots all over the whole thing.
And you took one picture from this side and another picture from that side.
What you'd get are these two images.
Okay?
Now, when you look at those two images you don't see anything in there.
But if I showed them to you in stereo, which is very difficult for
me to do here you would actually see that block raised.
All right.
So what we can do is we can animate those we can
animate random dot stereograms in the same way that we animated the swimmer.
I don't have animations of this one, but I do have animations here of this well,
if you look at this for a little while I hope you'll see a shark.
So everybody see the shark?
Okay. So this is the, the heads sort of sticking out.
Then it bends around and then the tail sticks out again.
So you'll notice, notice I just drew that tail.
Okay.
But of course the tail is not in any individual picture.
It's only in understanding the difference between them.
Now this was actually done from what's called an autostereogram website.
You can go take a look.
There are ways of making these so
that if you just, you can use the same picture, cross your eyes, or,
or stare at them differently that you'll get different images in the two eyes.
But I think you get the idea that from these two images, you can see the depth.
And what's interesting is if I present one to one eye and
one to the other, you see that depth.
So the answer to Ullage's question was whether you process the image first
finding these regions and then line them up to do the stereo.
Or you first line up the sort of little, local pixel area in order to do the,
the stereo, it's clear that you do that first.
You don't have, you, that you do the stereo first.
You don't have to have any specific objects or region.
Sort of a clean way of saying it is that human binocular fusion,
fusing the two together, is not based upon matching large-scale structures.
Or any individual process of the image is actually based on
a low-level process that directly fuses the two images.