As your mobile device is busy executing
tasks, calculating how to split a bar
tab and uploading photos of your cat,
the underlying hardware is
effectively pulling energy from your
battery to accomplish this work.
And, as we've all seen,
the more work your device does,
the more battery it pulls and sooner
rather than later, your users are left
holding onto an uncharged phone that
doubles as an expensive doorstop.
The key to writing applications
that are light on battery drain
has everything to do with understanding
how the process works under the hood.
In the electrical engineering world,
this action of a hardware pulling energy
from the battery to execute tasks is
called current draw over time and
anyone who has an undergraduate in
electrical engineering will tell you not
every action on your device draws the
same amount of battery in the same way,
over the same period of time.
To prove this, let's take a handy Nexus
5 device, turn it on airplane mode and
let it sit on our desk.
If we leave the phone like this,
doing nothing,
we'll roughly get a month of life before
the battery is completely exhausted.
Feel free to try this one at home, kids.
We can consider this the baseline
in terms of battery life but
that's not really how these
devices are typically used.
As soon as your active, you're
going to be eating up more battery.
Now active in this context includes
things like the CPU doing work,
cellular radio transmitting data,
and the screen itself being awake.
So the question is this,
what tasks are my application doing
that's eating up the most battery?
Sadly though, that's not easy to answer.
Monitoring battery drain at the hardware
level is a catch-22 because of course
the monitoring itself needs to drain
battery to execute the actions to record
how much battery is being drained and as
such, most mobile devices don't do this.
The only real way to gather these
types of statistics on battery draw
is to attach a third party piece of
hardware to your Android device,
which can record the operations without
using up the phone's power to do so.
Now when we do this, we actually get
some really interesting information.
For example,
when a Nexus 5 is in standby mode,
there's actually not much
power drain going on, right?
But when we wake the device up or
turn on the screen, we can see a huge
power spike in the battery monitor,
which I mean, you kind of expect, right?
Turning on LEDs, painting the screen and
then all that CPU, GPU work required to
draw to the screen isn't free from a
battery perspective, which by the way is
completely different from when
the application wakes up the device,
say if it's using wake clock,
alarm manager or the job scheduler API.
When the device is asleep and
it's woken up through one of these APIs,
you'll see an initial battery spike
as the processor first wakes up,
followed by a bit of
work as it's executed.
Now, it's important to note
that once the work is done,
the device will go back to sleep on
its own, which, is really important.
Keeping the device awake for
long periods when doing little or
no work will easily chew
up your battery life.
Now your cellular radio,
on the other hand,
is a completely different
beast in this regard.
When your device tries to send data over
the mobile network, you can see that
there is a quick wake up cost associated
with getting your mobile hardware ready,
followed by a large spike for
sending out a data packet and
then another large spike for
receiving one back.
And because getting the radio
started is so expensive,
after it's done executing work, it will
stay on in a wait state for a short
period of time in case there are more
packets ready to come in right away.
So all this is great data but
most developers don't have access
to this kind of equipment, right?
I mean but with the L release of
Android, you've got a whole new set of
tools to help you optimize
the battery draw of your application.
Let's take a deeper look
at Battery Historian.