This implicitly of hitting run and
having your app appear on an emulator
hides a lot of complexity.
Remember that Android is a full
software stack and its base is a Linux
kernel that handles low level tasks like
hardware, drivers and power management.
On top of that are some core
C/C++ libraries like LibsC and
SQLite and the Android run time along
with the core Android libraries.
Your app runs within its own instance
of the run time using the classes and
services provided here in
the application framework.
On top of that, it's the application
layer, including your app and
every other app that's installed.
So when you hit run in Android studio,
the first thing that happens is your
code gets compiled into byte code
that can be run in the run
time on the device.
In Android Studio this is done using
Gradel, a build tool kit that manages
dependencies and
allows you to define custom build logic.
For now, note that we start with your
project, which Gradel builds and
then packages the Byte Code along
with your applications resources,
externalized images, UI, XML, into
an Android Application Package file.
And APK which is especially
formatted ZIP file.
Once you got a APK ready to go,
Android Studio signs it and
then pushes it to the device using
the Android Debug Bridge or ADB.
IF we return to the terminal, you can
see that ADB let's you interact and
debug apps on any device,
physical or virtual.
Things like pushing and pulling files,
viewing log cat output or
even running a remote shell.
So once Android Studio has ADB
installed, the APK it uses ADB
again to launch the app by sending
a start command via the remote shell
by identifying the package and
class name of your main activity.