Even though two variables might appear to have a relationship if we look at the
sample data, this could just be due to chance. And you've learned this before,
when we take a sample and we get that the sample mean is really far from the
population mean, this could have just been due to chance. Similarly, just
because our sample data works like it has a relationship, the actual population
of people might not or vice versa. Our sample data might not have a
relationship but the population actually does. Things like this naturally
happen with sampling error as you've seen before. And we are more sure as the
sample size increases. The question is, how much variation due to sampling
error is allowable before we decide that our results are not due to chance?
Again, we do Hypothesis Testing. Now, r is the correlation we get from our
sample data. Rho, which looks like a p, is the true correlation for the
population. Given this what do you think the null and alternative hypothesis
are