So, now that you can log a user in and
out of your website, let's use the
logins to protect pages that we don't
want anyone on the internet
to be able to access.
We can verify that a user is logged in
by checking to see if the login session
has the username variable filled in.
Since we populate it with each login and
delete it upon each disconnect,
if a username is not detected for
a given request,
let's redirect to the login page.
Prompting a user to go ahead and
log in to continue.
Decide which pages should be
visible to the public and
which ones should be private for users.
Go ahead and add this functionality
where needed in your application.
There are different places in
the code where you can check
to see if a user is logged in.
But keep in mind how that
impacts the user experience.
For example, it would be kind of
annoying to fill out a form only to
find out that you can't submit
it because you're not logged in.