Now let's consider a second case.
Here, the kernel level mask is one, so
the kernel thinks that the process overall can handle the signal.
However, the user level thread that's currently running on top of
the kernel level thread has the signal disabled.
So its mask has the bit zero in the signal,
in the appropriate place for the signal.
But there is another user level thread that's currently in the run queue.
So it's not executing.
It's runnable but it's not executing at this particular point of time.
That one has the mask enabled.
The threading library,
that manages both of these user level threads, will know about this thread.
So now when a signal occurs at the kernel level, the kernel sees that
the process overall knows how to handle this particular signal.
So it has the bit set as one.
But, it should be appropriate for it to interrupt this user level thread,
because this particular user level thread,
the one that's currently active, has a signal disabled bed.
We should figure out a way how to get to the threading library because that's
the one that knows about this other runnable thread that would be capable of
handling a signal.
We said that the way signals are handled is that when they
interrupt the process or either a thread that's running in the process.
The handling routine that needs to be executed is
specified in the signal handler stable.
So then one easy thing that we can do is for
all the signals in the system, we can have a special library routine that
will basically wrap the signal handling routine.
So when a signal occurs, we start executing the library provided handler.
That library provided handler can see all of
the masks of the user level threads.
If we have a situation like here,
where the currently scheduled user level thread cannot handle the signal.
But there is another runnable user level thread that can,
the library handling routine can invoke the library scheduler and
can now make this user level thread running on the kernel level thread.
So then the signal can be handled.