[BLANK_AUDIO]
So one of the most powerful things about
Kaggle is that anyone can sign up and
participate in the majority of our
competitions and interesting use cases.
Previously, these use cases were only
exposed to a small number of people in
the world who are considered
the experts in that problem.
But whether the really interesting
things that we've noticed as we've
watched patterns over who participates
and who wins in the competitions,
is there's basically no correlation
whatsoever between expertise and
who wins competitions.
We have the occasional competition
that was targeting astronomy and
run by astronomer.
But for every one like that we
have ten where an English major
will run bioinformatics competition or
a physicists write
a brain signal processing competition or
components along those lines.
So we think it's really powerful
to expose certain to use case for
madness domain to a large
community around the world.
That includes hedge fund traders and
clients, to electrical engineers and
computer engineers, to mathematicians
and physicists, to history and
English majors that all share
common passion for data.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
One of the really fascinating
competitions that we've hosted is what
are molecular activity
production with Mark.
We're at a set of 15 problems
that took different features.
Describing the structure or molecule for
each of the problems range in between
a couple hundred and
a couple thousand molecules.
And to many thousands of numerical
descriptors on the molecule or
properties.
And then, targeted different
things in the via like whether or
not the molecular to respond.
This target would respond to
the molecule in the body whether or
not the molecule would be likely toxic.
And it foment or
things along those lines.
And that was our first
time that we had to
serve techniques called deep learning
when non-computer vision competition.
So it's really fascinating to see the
approach that the top team in that which
was one of Jeff Hinton's PhD students
used to when it was something called
a multi task deep technical network
where the same neural network was
trained across the 15 sub problems.
So it leveraged information
from one sub problem
to improve the results on
the other sub problem and
that enabled it to do better than all
the other solutions in the competition.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Yes, usually during a competition
itself that top people in our community
are incredibly competitive but after the
competition so over it swaps to a very
collaborative environment where in
most cases there's a winning interview
published with the top teams where
they describe the solution in depth.
In many cases,
we actually release code for
the winning solution as well, all
the competitions we host for research
require the top three participants
to open source their solutions.