Okay. So, say I truly have more than
five terabytes of data. Seems like MapReduce is the
best tool for the job. How exactly does MapReduce
work? MapReduce is actually just a parallel programming model
for processing large data sets across a cluster
of computers. The most important thing to understand about
MapReduce at a high level is that computation is
done via two functions. The mapper and the reducer.
So, in the most general sense, we start out
with a collection of documents or records. If we were
indexing all of the books in the history of the
world. As we discussed before maybe each book is a
separate document. We send these documents in a distributed way
to many mappers. Which each perform the same mapping on
their respective documents and produce a series of intermediate key
value pairs. We then shuffle these intermediate results and send
all key value pairs of the same key to the same reducer for processing. We
do this so that each reducer can produce one final key value pair for each key.
If we didn't send all values corresponding to
a given key to the same reducer, we
would end up with many final, key value
pairs for each key. Which is not desirable.