So now that I can computer
rectangles very quickly,
I might want to look at
a lot of rectangles.
And, in fact, for
training their boosted classifier,
these guys looked at over
180,000 possible rectangles that
could be applied at,
sort of, a 24 by 24 window.
Okay?
And here's
basically what they're going to do.
They're going to look for
face in 24 by 24 windows only.
And they're going to
take your new image, and
scale it to a couple different sizes,
and say,
okay can I find it in anywhere
in that 24 by 24 window?
Okay, so we said the first main
idea was to use these patterns.
Well, remember we just talked about
boosting where use, you look for
weak learners?
All right?
Well, basically they're going to choose
whichever features they can find that
tend to be the best weak learners.
So they're going to use,
in fact they use a thing called
AdaBoost in order to do that.
So you want to see which weak learners
reduced the weighted training error
the best?
Don't you?
>> Yeah.
>> Don't you, don't you?
Okay, well turned out these
are the first two features selected.
All right?
That is for a 24 by 24 window,
if you have a face in here somewhere.
Those are the features
that they're going to use.
And you might wonder why has
it become those features?
Well take a look at it this way, right?
It's basically looking for eyes,
sort of darkish patterns in there
compared to what's down here.
Okay?
And then, there's this patch here
that says the middle of the,
it tends to be brighter in
the middle than around the edges.
Just these two features,
these were your first two weak learners.