Okay, here's one possible assignment.
And notice what I've done.
After one completes, any one of these
three phases can begin executing.
So I've assigned them all to phase 2.
Now that's fine,
it's a valid assignment.
But my PRAM only has two processors, so
I'm going to have to break
that phase up into two steps.
That's essentially the slack
that the ceiling creates.
Okay, so hopefully you now
have some intuition for
what Brent's Theorem means and
why it's an upper bound.
The other point I want to make is
that choosing this assignment of
work to processes and essentially
breaking down the execution into
phases is exactly what makes
scheduling such a tricky subject.