Let's start by creating two new files,
spec/AddressBookSpec.js and
src/AddressBook.js.
We'll then need to update our
SpecRunner.html to run these two files.
I included my source file here,
src/AddressBook.js.
And my spec file here,
spec/AddressBookspec.
Notice I removed the player and
song entries that were already there.
Now, let's start to think of what
functionality would be useful for
an address book.
I think being able to add a contact is
a pretty useful feature, don't you?
So, lets start writing a test for this.
I'll describe a new suite
called Address Book, and
within it I'll have a spec called
it should be able to add a contact.
I think I'll take the object
ordinate approach to this problem.
So, let's instantiate a new
AddressBook object in our spec.
Now, to add a contact,
I'm going to need some sort of
addContact method in my address book.
What would I pass to addContact?
I'm going to need some sort of object.
So, we created a new contact object
here, and instantiated as this contact.
And I'm just passing it in here.
Now, I need to think of
what is a good way for
me to test that this contact was
actually added to my address book?
I should expect that if I were to get
the first contact in my address book,
that this would be
the same as this contact.
So, I wrote a test that does that.
In doing this, I can see that I'm also
going to need to add a getContact method
in my address book that
accepts an integer index.