Jay, how did you implement this?
>> Well, it went a little like this.
We can see the problem building up.
I already have over 60
photos cashed to solve this.
I'm going to start by creating a ray
of images that I want to keep,
then I'll create a transaction.
To look at the witches objects store.
Then I'll get the object store and
get all the messages.
Now we can take a peek
into the database.
For each message, I'll look to
see if it has a photo property.
This contains the photo URL, but
without the width bit at the end.
So I'll add those to the array
of images that I want to keep.
Then I'll open the images cache and
get all the requests that
are stored in it using cache.keys.
Now, the URLs on request
objects are absolute.
So they'll include the local
host port 8080 bit,
whereas the URLs was storing
an index Db, they don't have that.
So for
each request I'm going to pass as URL.
So now if the path name of the URL
isn't in our array of images needed,
I'll pass a request to cache.delete.
So now with force update enabled,
I'll refresh the page.
And I've only got seven images cached.
Job done!
We're caching photos now,
we're so very nearly there.
The last thing we need
to deal with is avatars.
One more chapter before we
achieve total offline first.