Can we get an another example of
an iterative improvement problem?
>> Sure, here's one we'll
use throughout this lesson.
It's called N Queens.
Basically, the puzzles
the place N queens, so
they cannot attack each other.
On an end by end chessboard.
>> In other words, no queen can
be on the same horizontal row.
Vertical column or diagonal.
>> Okay, so
here's an example board of four queens.
I just put down the queens randomly.
And there are five ways that
the queens can attack each other.
>> So, our goal is to get
the number of attacks down to zero?
>> Yep, and we have four
dimensions in which to move.
Specifically, we can move
each queen's in it's column.
To minimize the number of attacks.
>> Well, there are two queens
that have three attacks.
It seems like a good idea
to move one of those first.
If we move the second
queen to the top row.
You could eliminate three
of the five attacks.
>> And
that leaves only two attacks left.
>> It seems like we should always start
from the queen with the most attacks.
This reminds me of the most
constrained variable heuristic
in constraint satisfaction problems.
But we'll cover that
topic in the next lesson.
>> Yep, and
taking that approach, the next queen
we should work on is the third one.
Which is involved in two attacks.
If we move it to the bottom row.
Then we will have no more attacks,
and we have solved the problem.
>> That's surprisingly effective!
We've solved the problem
in just two moves.
Whereas, with simple search,
we would have had many more steps.
>> Exactly, it is an example of
trying the stupid thing first.
Then adding intelligence
until we solve the problem.
However, four queens seemed too easy.
Let's try five queens and
see if it gets harder.