So in our last video, we started talking about how uncaptured features,
might be having an impact on the variance of inter-tweet time.
Now in order to understand how this might be, let's look at a simple example.
Let's suppose, we know that the model that is
producing data is a known linear model, 2x plus 3.
In addition to this we are going to add some background noise.
Specifically, we're going to sample randomly from a normal distribution,
with a mean of 0 and standard deviation of 50.
We're going to sample many points of the input and
output, and create a graph of the 95% confidence interval.
So, here, we're just sampling points from x, our linear model and
then some random noise.
We've added our collected data points onto data points_1.
Now for each value x, we have a spread of values.
For that spread,
we're going to calculate the 95th quintile, and the fifth quintile.
And now we'll just plot.
So in this graph, the red line is a real line, the true model.
And the blue and
green lines, represent the top and bottom end of the confidence interval.
As you can see, as a result of introducing some of the noise,
there's a little bit of a spread here.
Now, let's suppose that instead of using the single variable model,
with some normal noise we're going to adda new feature.
So our model now depends on two features, x and y.
But we're still only going to collect x values and the response values.
We're not going to collect the y values.
That is lets pretend we don't know about y and
just let it influence the observed values of f.
As you can see, not capturing the additional feature y,
has resulted in dramatically increased uncertainty and
consequently variance in the response value.
In this way, we can see not capturing enough features is potentially a source of
inaccuracy and uncertainty in our estimator.
Thus let's try searching for features which we have not yet captured.
If we successfully find features which have an influencing force over
tweeting behavior, we just may be able to reduce the variance of our data.
In the next few videos, we'll talk about a tool from the field of
information theory for systematically doing so.