The next thing to do in our app is
to change the price of the coffee
in case someone orders a topping,
like whipped cream or chocolate.
That's a good idea.
If they order whipped cream,
then we'll just charge them $1.
If they order chocolate,
then we'll charge them $2.
>> Right.
Let's figure out how
to do this in the app.
Here are a couple of examples
in other Google apps,
where the behavior can change
based on certain conditions.
In the Inbox app from Gmail, here's
a screen shot of the list of emails.
For a single email,
if there is a reminder attached to it,
then the app knows to show this icon,
this label and the reminder text.
If an email has image attachments,
then the app knows to show
those images in line here.
If an email mentions a trip,
then a travel card shows up
with the flight information.
In the Google Now Launcher app,
we have more examples of how the app
behavior changes based
on certain conditions.
For example, if the stock price
is increasing, then the delta or
the increase in the price will be
shown here in green font color.
If the stock price is decreasing,
then the difference will be
shown here in a red font color.
For this weather card,
if the temperature is good and
the weather is sunny,
then we show a sun icon.
If the weather is windy or cloudy,
then we show different icons.
We'll be modifying our app shortly so
that the price changes based
on the toppings ordered but
first, I want you to become
familiar with control flow.
Normally, the code in our methods
gets executed from top to bottom,
line after line but
with control flow statements,
you can change that
instructions are executed in.
For example,
you can skip certain instructions
if certain conditions are met.
We're going to do this by
learning about if/else logic.
You haven't seen code for
if/else statements before but
I'm going to throw you in
the deep end and see how you do.
In the next couple of challenges, you're
going to read some code snippets on your
own, and these are linked
in the instructor notes.
Then you're going to try to
guess what this code does and
try to determine the output.
You'll have several
options to choose from so
you can choose the best one
that matches this code.
When I say output,
I'm referring to the log statements
that get printed to the log cat.
Remember that you can access log cat
from this Android tab right here,
and it shows all the messages from
the system, and from our apps.
The code snippets that we're providing
to you are going to be writing messages
to the log here.
Let's do a sample question together.
You can find this link
in the instructor notes.
Assume that this is a code snippet
from a WeatherActivity.java file
within a weather app.
The first line of code creates
a boolean variable called isRaining and
the initial value is true.
Then we have this if/else statement.
If is raining is true,
then we write this to the logs.
It says, It's raining,
better bring an umbrella.
If is raining is false, then we go
into this else case and we write,
this message, It's unlikely to rain.
Since is raining is true,
then we fall into this case and
we write, It's raining,
better bring an umbrella.
Because we fall into this case, we can
skip the else block, this line of code
lives outside the if else statement so
it always gets executed.
It says, Thank you for
using the Whetherweather App.
Let's look for an option in
the quiz that shows, It's raining,
better bring an umbrella.,
immediately followed by, Thank you for
using the WhetherWeather App.
That's exactly option B.
Now here's a different problem for
you to try.
Check the notes for the code snippet and
then make your selection.