To get started you'll need to
download the Unity installer.
If you want to get the latest
version of Unity you can do so
by going to their website at
store.unity.com/download.
For these courses we'll be showing
you the workflow in Unity 5.4.0 F3,
which you can get on their archives.
There'll also be a link
in the text note below.
Unity is a constantly evolving program.
So if you want to follow along with
these videos make sure to get that
version which will be linked below.
Once you download the installer
go ahead and run it.
This process is very similar
to installing any application.
So I'll just point out the settings
that you'll want to have installed.
By default, Unity, documentation, and
the standard assets will all be
selected and they're all needed.
Depending on what phone you have,
make sure to install the Android
build support or iOS build support.
if you have space on your computer and
want to test on both phones,
make sure to click both.
This will become important later on
when you're putting an application
on to your device.
Next set the location you
want the program to install.
Defaults are usually fine for this.
And now just let it go.
This process will take a while since it
needs to download a couple of gigabytes.
Once it's done, we can go ahead and
close that window and
open up the Unity editor.
[BLANK_AUDIO]