So, if we have these motion models,
we'd like to be able to use
them within all of that
motion math we did before on
the brightness constraint equation and
the optical flow and that kind of
stuff and we can do that directly.
All right.
So here we have our image showing you
the math of an affine transformation.
Now, you'll all remember your brightness
constancy constraint equation, yes?
Yes?
Looks like That.
Remember, what this says was,
that the dot product between the u and
v, that's the amount of motion and
the gradient,
has to essentially remain constant with
respect to the change in intensity.
So that was the brightness
constraint equation.
Right?
We had two unknowns, one equation.
So the way we fixed that before is,
we assumed that all
the points had the same uv.
Suppose instead of saying
it's the same u v,
we assume that it's
the same affine model.
That means that we substitute in for
u and v the equations from above.
Doesn't that work out nicely?
All right, so instead of just saying u,
we're going to say okay,
over this window, we have to
find the a1, a2, a3, a4, a5, a6.
So how many unknowns is that?
One, two, three, four, five, six.
We have six unknowns over the window.
So how many points are we,
how many equations do we need?
Well, we need at least six, but
now our assumption has been relaxed.
Before we required that everything
be moving constantly, so
you can't really let your windows get
too big if you're going to require that
they be constant motion because as
you let your windows get bigger,
they may not be moving constantly.
But if you can allow for
an affine deformation, so
they're not all moving the same,
they're all just the same flow,
like maybe they're rotating around,
now I can have bigger windows.
So what we do is we take this equation,
all right.
Each pixel provides one linear
equation with six unknown, so
we're going to do that same least
squares minimization we did for
Lukas-Kanade, but now, instead of having
a constant uv, those two unknowns over
window, we're going to use this
linear model with six unknowns.
And we do exactly the same
thing we did before.
It's going to be a mean, minimized
squared error, least squares, and
that allows you to solve for
that over that region and
because the pixels are moving
differently depending upon the xy,
I can have a whole area that's rotating.
It's one model, so
all of those pixels use the same a1,
2, 3, 4, 5,
6 because it's the same rotation.
All right.
It's not the same little vector,
it's the same model.
So it can be a much more
robust way of doing things.
So here is a version of
the Lukas-Kanade now,
and it's taken from the original paper.
It finds that, it's a paper that's cited
a lot and it's almost impossible to find
by Jim Bergen and Anandan and
Keith Hanna way back in 1992, and
the thing that's different about
this from Lucas-Kanade is,
instead of computing m for motion, which
was just the specific motion everywhere,
we're doing these little m,
which are the model parameters, right?
And so you have to compute
the model parameters.