Now as you may know, when you're
building a user interface for Android,
it's generally good practice to
keep your layouts as simple and
as flat as possible.
Fredo had some good advice.
Remember that inflating your
layouts is an expensive process.
Each additional nested layout and
included view directly impacts
the performance and
responsiveness of your application.
So remember, gain information and then
gain insight into your app's behavior.
All right, so here I am back
in Android Device Monitor and
I've got the hierarchy
view perspective open.
And as before,
let's go over to our windows pane here,
select our device, and choose
the activity we'd like to inspect.
In this case, we're going to look at the
mobile perf compare layouts activity.
So I'm going to go ahead and
double click that to load it up.
All right, so I want to zoom in on
the particular area of the layout here.
In particular this root node
here which is our linear layout.
This is the root view group that's
going to be displaying these two lines
that we're looking at right here.
Now I want you to notice the two
different childs that come off of this
parent linear layout.
One of them represents the first
line here of our chat interface, but
it's implemented using
a nested linear layout.
Now the second child here corresponds
to our second line in our layout.
And instead of using a nested design,
we've used a flat design using
the relative layout view group.
So, if we hop back into Android Studio,
this is what it corresponds to in XML.
We're back in Android Studio, looking
at our source, and we're down in our
layouts folder, and we're looking at
the activity compare layouts XML file.
Now, let me bring the phone back
on the screen so we can compare.
All right so we have a parent
container that's a linear layout
of vertically oriented items.
So the parent container here is a linear
layout and the orientation is for
vertical items, so items that are
going to be listed from top to bottom.
So what I want to draw your
attention to here is for
our first chat line right about here,
we have one type of implementation using
more of a structured or nested layout.
This is little bit more intuitive and
might be similar to a way when you build
an application in steps and
it's very logical.
So, for example, we start with a parent
linear layout that's horizontal
in nature and on the left,
we're going to set up a our ImageView.
And on the right,
we're going to create another nested
linear container to contain our text.
But in this case,
the orientation is going to be
vertical instead of horizontal.
So that represents the first slide.
Now as I mentioned in hierarchy viewer,
we also have the second line
of our chat template here.
And instead of using a nested structure,
we've decided to take the same
visual design and instead of
build it in terms of a hierarchy,
we've decided to look at all
the elements in terms of boxes and
see if we can describe them with their
relative positions to one another.
Now what this gives us
is a flattened layout.
So instead of two layers of depth,
we have one or
a flattened layout using
this relative design.
Now, what we've done here is a relative
layout and we've specified our text now
in relation to the image view or
the placeholder for our avatar here.
For example, this first line on the top
is going to be the right of the avatar,
and then similarly the second line of
text is also going to be the right of
the avatar.
Now, we can also delineate which order
we want the text items to follow.
In this case we use the attribute
layout below and this specifies that
this particular text view actual comes
below this particular one up here.
All right, so
what does that really mean?
What does that gain for
us in terms of performance?
So let's hop back the hierarchy viewer.
All right, so
here we are back in our layout.
Again, we've got the linear
layout design up top and
then the flattened relative
layout design on the bottom.
Now we can use the rendering/profiling
feature of hierarchy viewer.
We kind of get a sense of
how each design behaves.
So let's select the root node here.
And we're going to click on
the profile rendering button
represented by this Venn diagram here.
So let's go ahead and click it.
And as you can immediately see,
what I want you to notice is
via the yellow color here.
The linear layout design is slower than
the relative layout design in terms of
its rendering process measure layout and
draw.
So let's go ahead and
click that a few more times.
Again this linear layout design is
imposing a bit more overhead on
the rendering pipeline compared to the
relative layout which is all green here.
Let's sample it a few more times.
All right, they're about even here.
Let's try one more time.
All right now, so it should be clear
that when we profile this parent
node here, and we look and inspect
at the two distinct layout designs,
we notice that the linear layout, or the
nested version, is quite a bit slower,
or at least clearly slower than our
flat and relative layout version.
So again, when you can see these
opportunities to flatten in your layout
design or when you are re-factoring,
see if you can take steps to
flatten your design when possible.
So let's go ahead and apply this best
practice to our Chattinum Lattinum
design that we looked at earlier.
Let's see if we can find
some inefficiencies and
flatten that layout to see if
we can gain some performance.