In the instructor notes, you'll find a
link to this kind of terrifying website.
It may not look like much now but
click this animate button and
see what happens.
So this is a really
super janky animation.
Even on my new MacBook Pro,
this thing is barely chugging along.
What I want you to do is
record a timeline trace of
what happens when you
click the Animate button.
When you've got the timeline
try using both views.
Like the waterfall view and
the flame view.
Play with both of them and
see which works better for
you as you're analyzing the website.
Just like before,
I want you to find where the ridiculous
Jank in the timeline is coming from.
So what is causing it?
Is that there is too
much JavaScript running?
Is it because there is simply
too much painting happening and
the painting is being
caused by a CSS animation?
Is it because of compositing?
Is it because there's too much painting
which is being caused by JavaScript?
Or is it happening because recalculate
styles is taking way too long and
it's being caused by JavaScript?
Pick one of these answers.