So here's the idea of using SIFT for
doing things like alignment or recognition of objects.
And the idea is this, you're going to say that your image content,
whatever your image is, you're going to transform that into a representation.
The word I like to use is a constellation, I'll show you one in a minute.
A constellation of local features and that those feature descriptors will be
invariant to translation, rotation, scale and other sorts of imaging parameters.
So if I take the object and I move it over and I get closer to it and
I change the lighting, I would get the same descriptors.
And so here's an example of shift descriptors, so you see we've got a truck here
and it might take you a little while to really and in fact here I'll show you.
These are these little neighborhoods.
All right. And these little arrows are just showing you
these little neighborhoods.
Okay. So we've got ones by the tires, and
by this thing, and back here by the logo.
What might be a little harder for
you to see, is that we have the same truck right here.
All right.
And the point here is, is that a bunch of the same descriptors.
So here's one, and here's another.
They were both found in the two images.
All right?
And if I can find enough matches, then I can figure out oh,
this image has an object and that object is also in this objec,
in this image,it's just has been rotated, translated a little bit, maybe scaled.
And that's the idea about using SIFT for doing the recognition.
So if your descriptors were robust with respect to these transformations,
you could find them from one image to the next.
By the way, here's another description of the problem.
This one also comes I think directly from the original paper or,
or the second paper.
And suppose you want to find this box of crisp almond cookies,
because we always want to find boxes of crisp almond cookies, in this basket.
And what's really interesting about this grocery basket is it has basmati rice,
crisp almond cookies, and the computer vision textbook,
because when you go to Publix, you always buy a computer vision textbook.
Anyway, the idea is, can you find this box that's actually over here?
All right?
And the picture that's shown in the original paper which is kind of cool,
looks like this.
Although cyan lines are the connection between SIFT descriptors found here and
SIFT descriptors found here.
This is the original image.
This is the box located in the basket of groceries.
So because it could find all those features it was able to say
this object is really right over here.
This was very impressive at the time, in fact continues to be sort of
a strong way of doing certain types of computer vision recognition