Again, because this is my traditional
way of going through video.
Now we can play around and by having
it do other things in the path,
going there, jumping off diagonal and
coming back on the diagonal.
Right?
Now, let's actually mark these as four
of the interesting points in this space.
So, these are my four different you
know, one, two, three, four, right?
And, of course, what I'm doing is
I'm transitioning from one to two.
In this case, I'm basically showing
different paths through it,
and then I can actually just move
from two to three, three to four, and
of course I also have
the option of looping back.
I can loop back from four to three,
four to one, four to two.
So this basically starts giving
us a way of representing this,
in what is known as a Markov chain.
Basically, at one stage,
I'm looking as to how far I'm going to
go to the next stage,
and keeping that memory.
So this allows us now represent
how we're going to traverse this.
This representation
gives us a lot of power.
I recommend you to look at
the paper that we discussed.
A variety of extensions of this.
I'm going to talk about a few
of them in a few minutes.
But I wanted to kind of
also look at the paper and
see what kind of different things
we can do with this representation.
So here's an example of some of
the ways we can actually do this.
So here, for example, you notice that
just the same representation, and
depending on how we do the transitions,
we can actually make the same candle
frame have different looks and feels.
So one, of course you notice,
is jumping around a lot more.
The other one, this one here on
the right, is jumping around a lot less.
Same data.
We can actually,
just depending on how we do the
transitions, create a different impact.