[Male narrator] The answer is that in Sibiu, the action function gives us 4 actions
corresponding to traveling along these 4 roads,
so we have to add in paths for each of those actions.
One of those paths goes here,
the other path continues from Arad and goes out here.
The third path continues out here
and then the fourth path goes from here--from Arad to Sibiu
and then backtracks back to Arad.
Now, it may seem silly and redundant to have a path that starts in Arad,
goes to Sibiu and returns to Arad.
How can that help us get to our destination in Bucharest?
But we can see if we're dealing with a tree search,
why it's natural to have this type of formulation
and why the tree search doesn't even notice that it's backtracked.
What the tree search does is superimpose on top of the state space
a tree of searches, and the tree looks like this.
We start off in state A, and in state A, there were 3 actions,
so we gave those paths going to Z, S, and T.
And from S, there were 4 actions, so that gave us paths going from O, F, R, and A,
and then the tree would continue on from here.
We'd take one of the next items
and we'd move it and continue on, but notice that we returned to the A state
in the state space, but in the tree,
it's just another item in the tree.
Now, here's another representation of the search space
and what's happening is as we start to explore the state,
we keep track of the frontier, which is the set of states that are at the end of the paths
that we haven't explored yet, and behind that frontier
is the set of explored states, and ahead of the frontier is the unexplored states.
Now the reason we keep track of the explored states
is that when we want to expand and we find a duplicate--
so say when we expand from here, if we pointed back to state T,
if we hadn't kept track of that, we would have to add in a new state for T down here.
But because we've already seen it and we know that this is actually a regressive step
into the already explored state, now, because we kept track of that,
we don't need it anymore.