Great, now you've configured
the analytics tracker for your app.
The next thing is to
programatically create the tracker.
However, we want to make
sure that we only have
one tracker running each
time our app is running.
It's possible to have multiple
tracker objects, all sending data
to the same analytics account,
which would result in inaccurate data.
You might end up with the same
hits being counted multiple times.
For example, let's say the user goes
to the main screen in your app and
presses the What's for dinner button.
The app will take them to
the Show Dinner Screen.
But let's say you've got three
analytics trackers running.
They'll each report a hit to analytics
for the Show Dinner Screen, and you'll
end up with three screen views being
reported, when really you only had one.
We don't need to say it's a tracker
in between app invocations, but
we do need to make sure that
when the app is running
we have only a single tracker instance.
So to make sure that the tracker is
created only once each app invocation,
we're going to use
the Application object.
It's really very simple,
and I'll show you how now.