So now that we have built a one versus all classifier,
we will introduce to you, precision, recall, and F scores,
which are other performance metrics to validate these kind of models.
Let us now define this other metric called precision.
Precision is the ratio of the predicted positives that are actually positive or
true positives over the true positives plus the false positives.
The denominator here is the number of examples that are predicted to
be positive.
Let's quickly recall our confusion matrix.
In the top we have the actual values and
on the side we have the predicted values.
So actual positives and negatives.
Predicted positives and negatives.
In this case TP.
FP, FN and TN refer to true positive, false positive,
false negative and true negative respectively.
So the precision is now the true positive divided by
the true positive plus the false positives.
You see this is somewhat different from the sensitivity value which was
true positive divided by true positive plus false negative.
In this case we are dividing by this row of predicted positives.
You see precision is a good measure for classes where the same is skewed that is
the instances of positive classes is smaller than the total number of instances.
Can you think of an example of a classification problem where we
can use precision as a good metric to evaluate the classifier performance?