So, now you know some of the very basics of computer vision.
We talked about images, how images are being formed.
We talked about perspective projection as a mathematical tool
for understanding how cameras perceive images.
And we talked a whole bunch about features.
We talked about invariances, the type of things that affect
the appearance of a feature in the camera image,
and we went through methods for extracting edges,
for extracting corners,
and for extracting fairly sophisticated features like SIFT features.
This is one of the basic processing methods in computer vision.
Almost everyone who does computer vision preprocesses images
by feature extraction, and now you know
quite a bit about how to process images in computer vision.