Now, let's apply the JobScheduler API to
minimize the unnecessary wakeup cost of
the cellular radio because we know
that frequent reoccurrences of this
comes at a significant
cost to the battery life.
Instead, we're going to
use the JobScheduler to
avoid waking up the cellular radio and
schedule our network activity only when
the user's device is connected to wi-fi.
All right, so let's go ahead and
look at some code.
Now, in order to follow along, go
ahead and check out the 3.31, wait for
wi-fi branch in the repo for
your sample app.
Now just as a reminder when you
build this branch in code, you'll
notice another button just like similar
exercises added to your sample app's UI.
This one's called no wi-fi, no deal.
When you click on it, it'll launch a new
activity called find the wi-fi activity.
In this case when you press the button
download all the data signal or no,
we're going to be triggering some code
that we're going to be looking at.
It looks like it's trying to
make some connections, and
it looks like it's fetching some HTML.
All right, here we are back in
Android Studio, and I've gone ahead and
opened up the source code for
FindTheWifiActivity.
Now similar to our previous exercises,
we have a button's
OnClickListener basically invoking a
function that's doing a particular task.
In this case we call
the function downloadSomething.
Now, now,
this code should look familiar.
It's not too different than the previous
exercise when we're trying to
basically make a network connection and
do a simple download from a server.
Again, here in our downloadSomething
method, we're basically mocking
the behavior that an app would take to
essentially check to see if the network
is alive, and then execute a task in
the background to download some data.
Now if you remember from Colt,
we'll know that cellular network access
is one of the biggest offenders for
reduced battery performance.
So in order to conserve battery life,
we're going to try to reduce the amount
of times we start up the cellular radio,
thus incurring less of a tax when having
to start up the cellular radio incurring
this long network tail of energy.
All right, so let's go ahead and
hop back into our sample app code and
let's see if we can repurpose it and
focus on executing our network
tasks only when wi-fi is available.
Now what this really means is
we're going to want to repurpose
I would downloadSomething method.
This time around, we're going to
want to go ahead and schedule a job for
the job scheduler.
So let's take a look.
Now instead of trying to download
something in a manual fashion,
let's go ahead and
see how we can craft a job for
the job scheduler to check for
a wi-fi only situation.
So what I have up here is a comparison
view of basically the wait_for_wifi
branch, and then our
3.32_wait_for_wifi_optimized branch.
You can go ahead and check this out in
your sample app code repo if you want to
see the difference, but I'm going to
go ahead and describe the change.
Now in our optimized code,
we're going to look at a method
called downloadSmarter.
Now this is hooked up to our on click
listener for our button in our UI.
But mainly this downloadSmarter
method is going to go ahead and
use the job scheduler.
Now similar to previous examples, the
first thing we do is we get a reference
of the scheduler via
the getSystemService method.
Now in the area where we normally submit
jobs, we're going to go ahead and
bundle up a job info.
Again, that's the encapsulation of what
we want to do for our particular job.
Essentially it's the constraints for
running it.
In this case,
we've changed one particular
line from our previous example.
In this case we used internal method
.setRequiredNetworkType to specify
a network that's unmetered,
essentially, wi-fi only.
And then we go ahead and we call .build
and that's going to go ahead and
generate a JobInfo instance for us.
And then last but
not least, we go ahead and
we pass that to the schedule
function of the Scheduler.
Again the last app that we actually
have to do is called the scheduler,
with the schedule method passing
in our new job info instance.
And when it returns, our job service
will be called and the task will be run.
And when the system deems
that it's time to run our job
it's going to go ahead and
call back into our MyJobService class,
and it's going to call our onStartJob
method that we implemented before.
In this case we're going to go ahead and
check for a network connection,
in this case it should be wi-fii, and
then execute our SimpleDownloadTask.
Then lastly when we're finished doing
our network activity, which again is
implemented in our SimpleDownload class,
particularly in the doInBackground
method, we go ahead and we open up
an http connection and do a get request.
Then, lastly, when onPostExecute
is called on our Async task,
we go ahead and call jobFinished,
which is critical in telling the system
that we are done with our work, and
it can go ahead and release the wake
lot that is held on our behalf.
All right, so this was an example on
basically how to repurpose some of our
sample app code to use job scheduler,
this time to minimize
cellular radio wakeup.
Now as mentioned before, the framework
offers a lot more possible combinations
for specifying a particular job and
its associated requirements.
Now I suggest that you go ahead and
review the developer documentation for
all the detail information and
see the link in the instructor notes.