We essentially ran through the red
green refractor process in our heads.
I had some tests that were red.
I turned those tests green by fixing my
code and I'm confident I could continue
refactoring my function
without breaking anything.
But having these tests in our
head doesn't do us a lot of good.
Let's get these down into code.
I went ahead and
wrote the first two tests.
Now I would like you to try and
figure out the final one.
Don't focus much on these functions,
or what they do.
Just try and
take your best educated guess,
at how you would write, the final test.
Expect add 0.1, 0.2 to equal 0.3.
Use my examples as references
to get yourself started.