Let me tell you about a truly magical algorithm called value iteration.
In value iteration, we recursively calculate the value function
so that in the end, we get what's called the optimal value function.
And from that, we can derive,
look up, the optimal policy.
Here's how it goes.
Suppose we start with a value function of 0 everywhere
except for the 2 absorbing states, whose value is +100 and -100.
Then we can ask ourselves the question is, for example,
for the field A3, 0 a good value.
And the answer is no, it isn't. It is somewhat inconsistent.
We can compute a better value.
In particular, we can understand that
if we're in A3 and we choose to go east,
then with 0.8 chance we should expect a value of 100.
With 0.1 chance, we'll stay in the same state,
in which case the value is -3.
And with 0.1 chance, we're going to stay down here for -3.
With the appropriate definition of value,
we would get the following formula,
which is 77.
So, 77 is a better estimate of value
for the state over here.
And now that we've done it, we can ask ourselves the question
is this a good value, or this a good value, or this a good value?
And we can propagate value backwards
in reverse order of action execution
from the positive absorbing state through this grid world
and fill every single state with a better value estimate
then the one we assumed initially.
If we do this for the grid over here and run value iteration
through convergence, then we get the following value function.
We get 93 over here. We're very close to the goal.
89, 85, 81, 77, 73, 70, over here.
This state will be worth 68, and this state is worth 47,
and the reason why these are not so good is because
we might stay quite a while in those
before we'll be able to execute an action
that gets us outside the state.
Let me give you an algorithm that defines value iteration.
We wish to estimate recursively the value of state S.
And we do this based on a possible successor state
as prime that we look up in the existing table.
Now, actions A are non-deterministic.
Therefore, we have to go through all possible as primes
and weigh each outcome with the associated probability.
The probability of reaching S prime given that we started state S
and apply action A.
This expression is usually discounted by gamma,
and we also add the reward or the costs of the state.
And because there's multiple actions and it's up to us
to choose the right action, we will maximize over all possible actions.
See, we look at this equation, and it looks really complicated,
but it's actually really simple.
We compute a value recursively based on successor values
plus the reward and minus the cost that it takes us to get us there.
Because Mother Nature picks a successor state for us for any given action,
if you compute an expectation over the value of the successor state
weighted by the corresponding probabilities which is happening over here,
and because we can choose our action,
we maximize over all possible actions.
Therefore, the max as opposed to the expectation on the left side over here.
This is an equation that's called backup.
In terminal states, we just assign R(s),
and obviously, in the beginning of value iteration,
these expressions are different, and we have to update.
But as Bellman has shown a while ago,
this process of updates converges.
After convergence, this assignment over here
is replaced by the equality sign,
and when this equality holds true,
we have what is called a Bellman equality or Bellman equation.
And that's all there is to know to compute values.
If you assign this specific equation over and over again to each state,
eventually you get a value function that looks just like this,
where the value really corresponds to what's the optimal future
cost reward trade off that you can achieve
if you act optimally in any given state over here.