Storm provides exactly that.
So Storm is a platform for analyzing streams of data and
as they arrive or the moment it is produced.
So that you can react quickly based on that analytics.
Storm has a small set of primitives that you can use to express your
real-time computations without having to worry about how it's being done.
All you need is to like express what you want.
It knows how to do those things at the bar.
Now one of the biggest things people ask for is what is Storm versus Hadoop.
So they are actually complementary.
In a sense like Hadoop does a big batch processing,
where your regular map produce job and your final map produce job and
it runs on several nodes on the probably for a few hours or
days analytics and that is more of according to our definition is batch.
And as Tom predicted, fast reactive and real-time processing.
Because the model trains think the data is produced, storm takes over and
starts spitting all those analytics in a continuous fashion.
So those are the two and and I mean,
a lot of people ask why I need to use to Tom when there is Hadoop.
I mean, on thing that people think about saying hey, by the way,
like where can I use the Hadoop job.
Which is same as whatever this Tom job does.
But except the fact that I keep running it every few seconds.
Or every few minutes or whatever might be the case.
But if the data rate at which you are producing is even higher than the amount
data that can, that a Hadoop job can produce within the three minute or
every cycle of the job still you will not be able to produce the, using Hadoop.
So you are to still count on Storm.
And again Hadoop has this what do you call this two stage.
It's map phase, as well as reduce phase.
That's only two stages.
On the other hand, Storm can express multiple stages.
You can have any number of stages as much as you want.
And the data is kind of flowing within these stages continuously.
So that, those are the kind of underlying huge differences between Storm
and Hadoop.
In addition to these big big batch versus real-time processing.
So now, like, let's look at what is a Storm data model.
Hm, the Storm has a bunch of primitives so one is Spouts,
which is actually the, actually the source of that stream.
So it could, it could be anything.
So it could be coming from either Postgres or MySQL or we have the notion of
a distributed queues, where the data gets dumped the moment it is produced and
those data are available in distributed queues like Kafka and Kestrel.
And Bolts are the units of computations where the data is
actually transforming in certain fashion.
Either it is aggregated or filtered or
it could even be what you call joined with some other streams as well.
So you can do, what you call if there are multiple streams coming in.
For example, that tweet stream and there is a stock quote stream.
So I wanted to know in the window of the last ten minutes what is
the sentiment of a particular, what do you cal uml, stock?
For example, I wanted to know the sentiment of stock, named for
Google in the last ten minutes, then you need to join within the tweet stream,
as well as the stock stream.
So that you can see whether the price is reflective of the sentiment that is
expressed by people on Google for the last ten minutes or so.
So which means, actually it's a, a stream join.
So then there is the third one called Tuple.
A Tuple is nothing but a unit of data that is entering the stream.
And that is nothing, but an ordered list of several elements and Topology.
And the Topology is a kind of DAG that stitches the spouts and bolts
in a certain fashion, so that you have the desired computation that you want.
So bolt expresses smaller unit computation.
But the combination of the spout and bolt in a DAG fashion, which expresses
the data flow, as well as the computation will express your job structure or
the design computation that you want ultimately.
So for example if you look at simple Storm Topology,
this is the way it would look like.
Here are two spouts and these two spouts are the ones where the data is
getting produced or probably accessing the data that is being produced.
And that injects into three different bolts.
And finally, there are two set of bolts that in turn.
So it's only the data produced here goes through this data transformations or
data aggregations.
And which in turn goes into next stage where further aggregations or
even writing off aggregation writing in Tor.
Persistence Tor where you can query them back.
So that is what happened.
This is a gives again an idea of Topology.
And to give an example of the work on Topology,
which is one of the very simple topologies.
So we will have a something called a Tweet Spout that does
talking to what do you call it.
A Twitter current shells and getting the Twitter stream in a continuous fashion.
And after that, there is a Parse Tweet.
So you get the tweet and after that the Parse Tweet Bolt essentially,
kind of picks at tweet and breaks it up into small words and
figures out what other distinct words on those Tweet.
Then finally, like it sends to the word count bolt, which in turn picks up
the word from different parse tweet bolts and counts those distinct words.
And finally, it might be ready into process install like bolt or Hadoop.
And so, for
example, we'll have the like World Cup used to get one million tweets.
And out of that Soccer for two, 400K times.
Right?
So, and that is what I call is a logical plan.
I already express you spout and
bolt, you're just here describing your deck under.
But however, when it goes into execution in the actual missions,
physically in those host processes and, and missions.
This is what you have.
So there will be several instance of this Tweet Spout.
That are, you will be executing across different missions.
And similarly, you have bolt.
And similarly, your word count.
This is what we call lesser Parallelism.
So for every spout and bolt you're to express, what is called as a Parallelism.
So I want like tendencies of this spout and I want 20 instances of this bolt and
I want 15 instances of the, like word count bolt.
How do you decide this Parallelism?
Well, because like, so that also leads into grouping.
So now, we have seen the data flow from spout and bolt.
Now how do you say, where to go?
For if, for example, the spout task one and it has to go to the bolt task two.
I mean, how do you say that?
I mean like, because there is some semantic associated with it, right?
So when a parse street bolt and
it's a two pull, which word count bolt it should go.
And Storm provide as, what we call the notion of groupings.
So, so first is Shuffle Grouping, which means it can go anywhere.
So I slot it randomly can go to any task in the next stage.
So that is what Shuffle Grouping means.
And Fields grouping is essentially, hash based.
So you tell them that that these are the fields that you should care about and
based on the values of these hash fields this should go to the appropriate bolt.
So that is what is called a Fields Grouping.
And all grouping, in the sense like that every Tuple that I
produce goes to all the bolts of instances in the next stage.
And Global Grouping is you get everything to one single instance.
So with this and most of the time you end up using these two.
And with these two, you can pretty much get all your processing done.
I have not seen any examples so far, where this was not enough.
So pretty much, you can get everything done.