Now that you know about the importance
of not exaggerating your data.
Let's create an appropriate scale so
we can draw our circles correctly.
We have our x scale from before and
we also have our y scale from before.
So, let's create a variable and
the variable called r for
drawing the circles.
Remember that in
the gapminder visualization,
the size of each circle represents
the population of each country.
So the area of the circle for
China has to correspond to 1.38 billion.
The area of a circle is
equal to the constant
pi which is about 3.14
times the radius squared.
We need to figure out the radius
in order to draw circles on to our
SVG canvass.
So the Population is
equal to the Area and
we know that's equal to Pi r squared.
So if we divide both sides
of our equation by Pi.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Then we can simply take the square
root of both sides to isolate r.
So the radius should be equal to
the square root of our population
divided by PI.
It turns out that by multiplying by
a constant factor such as one of our Pi,
doesn't affect the relationship
between the radius and the population.
We really just need to capture that
it's a square root relationship.
This means the radius is really
just equal to the square root of
the population times some constant,
which we can ignore in this case.
To make this aspect of
the constant clearer,
let's say that you're looking at
this poster of the visualization.
If you viewed this
graphic from farther and
farther away, all the circles get
smaller by the same distance since
your eyes are a certain
distance from the graphic.
The proportionality of the circles
stays the same no matter
if you come closer to the graphic or if
you stand farther away from the graphic.
Now let's see if you can create
a scale to map population values
to radius values.