[Thrun] Wow! You learned a lot about hidden Markov models and particle filters.
Particle filters is the most used algorithm in robotics today
when it comes to interpreting sensor data,
but these algorithms are applicable in a wide array of applications
such as finance, medicine, behavioral studies, time series analysis, speech,
language technologies, anything involving time and sensors or uncertainty.
And now you know how to use them.
You can apply them to all these problems if you listened carefully.
It's been a pleasure teaching you with this class.
As I told you in the beginning, this is a topic very close to my heart,
and I hope it's going to empower you to do better stuff
in any domain involving time series and uncertainty.