Hi, I'm Lorenzo.
And welcome to Authentication and
Authorization.
In this class I'll be your instructor as
you learn to add security features to
your web applications.
Allowing users to log in on your
site using OAuth 2 providers.
By the end of this course you will not
only have an understanding on how to
securely implement log ins and
permission systems, but
also have a basic understanding
of how web security works.
And some potential
things to look out for
when exchanging sensitive
information across the web.
To accomplish this goal you will be
provided a restaurant menu application.
If you completed the fullstack
foundations course,
you've already created
a version of this application.
You will make the app secure
by restricting access to
unauthenticated users.
This means that you'll be able to share
it safely with the world as part of
your portfolio.
You will also have the knowledge and
hands on experience to implement
similar systems on your future sites.
In order to get the most
out of this course,
you should be familiar with Python and
the Flask web development framework.
A basic understanding of JavaScript and
using jQuery to make Ajax calls will
also be needed for this course.
If you'd like to brush up
on any of these topics,
check out some of the links
provided in the instructor notes.
We will be using Google+ and
Facebook sign ins for this class.
So that means you'll need accounts
on both of these sites in
order to do the exercises.
If you don't have these accounts
links are also provided in
the instructor notes.