I've clicked on one of
the paint records, and
now I've got the Paint Profiler.
Inside the Paint Profiler there
are a few things to pay attention to.
First off,
there is a whole new timeline here.
There is a list of paint commands.
And then there is the part of
the page that was painted.
Notice that, right now, this timeline
is the entire paint command, and
you see that it's the entire
page that got painted.
But if you limit the timeline
to just a small part,
you'll see what was painted then.
This is a fantastic tool to see
exactly what the browser is
painting at different points.
Here I've gone to this random
point in the middle of the paint,
and you can see that white box is
where some text is being painted.
Here on the side you can see
the drawTextBlob commands.
Going back to the whole timeline for
the paint,
you can see the first one is save, and
that is the answer to this question.
I want to point out one last thing,
and that is that all of these paint
commands, these green bars here,
are really close to the 60 fps line.
So right now it's running at 60 fps, but
it's extremely close to the budget, and
if there are any other work going on,
chances are you won't be
hitting 60 frames per second.
So let's see what you can do about it.
But first, the correct answer is save.