We apply the same trick as before
where we use the exact same prior of 0.01.
Our first + gives us the following factors: 0.9 and 0.2.
And our minus gives us the probability 0.1 for a negative first test result given that we have cancer,
and a 0.8 for the inverse of a negative result of not having cancer.
We multiply those together.
We get our non-normalized probability.
And if we now normalize by the sum of those two things
to turn this back into a probability, we get 0.009
over the sum of those two things over here, and this is 0.0056
for the chance of having cancer and 0.9943 for the chance of being cancer free.
And this adds up approximately to 1, and therefore, is a probability distribution.