[Norvig] There's a convention in situation calculus that predicates like At--
we said plane P was at airport X in situation S--
these types of predicates that can vary from 1 situation to another are called fluents,
from the word fluent, having to do with fluidity or change over time.
And the convention is that they refer to a specific situation,
and we always put that situation argument as the last in the predicate.
Now, the trickiest part about situation calculus is describing what changes
and what doesn't change as a result of an action.
Remember in classical planning we had action schemas
where we described 1 action at a time and said what changed.
For situation calculus it turns out to be easier to do it the other way around.
Instead of writing 1 action or 1 schema or 1 axiom for each action,
we do 1 for each fluent, for each predicate that can change.
We use the convention called successor state axioms.
These are used to describe what happens in the state
that's a successor of executing an action.
And in general, a successor state axiom will have the form of saying
for all actions and states, if it's possible to execute action A in state S,
then--and I'll show in general what they look like here--
the fluent is true if and only if action A made it true
or action A didn't undo it.
So that is, either it wasn't true before and A made it be true,
or it was true before and A didn't do something to stop it being true.
For example, I'll show you the successor state axiom for the In predicate.
And just to make it a little bit simpler, I'll leave out all the For All quantifiers.
So wherever you see a variable without a quantifier, assume that there's a For All.
What we'll say is it's possible to execute A in situation S.
If that's true, then the In predicate holds between some cargo C
and some plane in the state, which is the result of executing action A in state S.
So that In predicate will hold if and only if either A was a load action--
so if we load the cargo into the plane, then the result of executing that action A
is that the cargo is in the plane--
or it might be that it was already true that the cargo was in the plane in situation S
and A is not equal to an unload action.
So for all A and S for which it's possible to execute A in situation S,
the In predicate holds if and only if the action was a load
or the In predicate used to hold in the previous state and the action is not an unload.