So, why do you think these
commands have such short names?
>> There's a couple of
reasons I can think of.
Short names are a bit cryptic,
but once you've learned them,
they're quick to type.
The second reason isn't
really relevant today, but
shorter commands
are also more efficient.
Back when modem speeds were measured
in the hundreds of bits per second,
every character counted.
>> From a historical standpoint,
making command names as short
as they could be was very common
when the UNIX system was created,
even though later on it looks kind
of silly and harder to learn.
For instance, the system function for
creating files is called creat,
not create, but creat without the e.
When Ken Thompson, one of the designers
of UNIX, was asked later what he would
have done differently in the design, he
said he would've put the e on the end.