Hi and welcome to the fifth office hours.
Hey, welcome, everybody. We got a bunch of students
who are discussing in the forum and we picked
them out because we like what they contributed
to the forum and we’re going to give them a
chance to ask some questions. So I think,
Elia, you have the first question.
Yes. As I was saying, Dr. Norvig is a luminary,
he is one of the greatest experts
on Natural Language Processing and he's
head researcher at Google which is the most
famous company for taking text from users and
turning it into meaning across the vast wide
interwebs. So, given that we touch the tip of the
iceberg of NLP in Unit 3 with a little bit of regular
expressions and regex parser and I was
wondering if Dr. Norvig would, at some point in
the future, teach a 300 level or 400 level Udacity
class on using Python or maybe another
programming language to do NLP. I find this is an
absolutely fascinating field and I know it’s had
tremendous success such as at Renaissance
Technologies with Watson and so on. And I was
really hoping to learn it and I don’t think there
is a better authority for that in the world
than Dr.Norvig. So will he be teaching
us as class in the future.
Okay. So first of all, you have to be careful
about trying to become a teacher’s pet on an
online class as well as regular class. So let’s
calm down the praise a little bit. But thank you.
Secondly, I think that’s a great idea. I think that is
a good course, it’s one I would like to do at some
point but there is only so many hours in a day. So
we’re doing one thing at a time. It would be fun to
do it. It would be a more advanced level class. I
guess one reason why I am not doing it right now
is that there is another class being offered by
Jurafsky and Chris Manning and they are both
equally extremely well-qualified experts. So they,
I am sure, teach a very good class too, be fun for
me to do it. I have new colleague at Google,
Prabhakar Raghavan, who’s also an expert and
has published several books in his area, might be
fun for me to do it together with him. So I don’t
know exactly what the schedule is but I know
it is a goal of mine to get around
teaching their class at some point.
Alright. Alison, I think you have question.
I do, yes. I wanted to ask you a little bit
about spotting errors and optimization of
expected value functions where you’ve got these
really complicated mathematical functions.
I mean I think when I was trying to solve, to find
the bugs in my PIC code, all the easy cases
worked – all the ones I could check but there was
something wrong with the maths because I
wasn’t winning any of the games and that was
the only way I could tell because I wasn’t winning
the games. Everything looked plausible apart
from that. So how did you go – what sort of
strategies do you use to try and catch
our errors in computation workout?
Okay. So I can answer that both in terms
of strategies in general and then specifically
for this type of problem you mentioned.
So in general, you want a testing strategy
that does integration testing. As we’re
testing the whole thing and unit testing, you’re
testing a little bit at a time and what you were
discovering is you have this integration test of
how my function play against another function.
So that’s the whole program all at once. And you
were finding that you were losing. And so that’s a
great test to do. It’s an integration test and you
failed the test. It’s an important test to do because
if you succeed, then you are happy. But if you don’t
succeed, at least you know something wrong but
it doesn’t tell you very much at all about where
it’s wrong and that’s what you discovered. So that's
why we have the unit test that tests smaller
pieces and I guess the things to do there is to
start with pieces for which you know the right
answer. Say, here is a position that’s near the
end of the game, it’s clear, I should do this move,
does my function do the right thing on that case.
And then I think it’s that one right, then back up
one step and say, okay, the move before that and
I know that that’s the right move, what would the
right move be before that? And that maybe you
can calculate out your own in pencil and paper
and then you can test to see if they got that one
right. Anyway, you start moving backwards and
making the test complicated one more step at a
time and then you can get to the point where the
unit tests match up with the integration test
and then hopefully you got the right answer.
Alright. Tincher, you had a few questions.
Do you want to start asking for those?
Yeah, my questions have a general theme.
So the code that I’ve seen in this class.
so I’ve actually tinkered with Python a
little bit before this class but the code that I have
seen in this class is the code that I have never
seen before. So it’s been really cool to be
exposed to that but it makes me wonder what
else am I missing, what are the things – it makes
me wonder that there is a whole realm of
developing code that I don’t even know about
that’s not just the code. So I want to know your
development environment and I want to know like
what type of integrated development environment
you used whether you used GUI debugger,
whether you used a profiler and actually most
important question is what are some of the most
important third-party Python libraries
that you think we should study?
Okay. So that’s a great question and I might not
be the right person to answer that because
most of my use of Python is educational more than
sort of serious professional development. And so I
intentionally try to stay away from a lot of the fancy
tools because I want to say I want to do something
that I know all the students that are going to see
what I am doing can duplicate and so if it’s something
that’s proprietary, third-party fancy tool, I want to
not have that. And I guess I am also I am kind of
old-fashioned. I don’t know what the right IDE is
and I am playing around with some of them but
you know, I am used to using Emacs that I have
used for many, many years and so I’ve got all the
commands, sort of memorize them at my
fingertips and so I tend to use that. There are
some other IDEs that duplicate a lot of the
command. So I can be familiar using those as
well and I’m trying those out. And in terms of the
libraries, I guess the most important one to me is
the SciPy and the NumPy and I really would hope
that at some point they become sort of an official
part of the Python distribution and it’s all
packaged together. You can get them packaged
them together but you can't rely on everybody
having those installed. I think the reason that they
haven’t been merged together so far is that they
are on a different release schedules in terms of
the number of months or years in between
releases is at a different pace. But I hope
that can be worked out and that becomes
standardized, that would be really great. And
then in terms of how I do debugging and so on,
occasionally, I use the symbolic debugger not
that much, mostly just print statements and tests
and breaking it down into small pieces using the
interactive interpreter a lot. So I load the program
in and then start typing in calls to my sub-
functions in the interactive interpreter looking at
the results so you have those makes sense. I use the
profiler occasionally but I guess I usually find
that if it’s so slow that you need a profiler then
maybe Python isn’t the language for you. So often
I found it slow then the answer is to go and
recode it in java or something rather than to try to
make Python work faster. I know it all depends
on the problem what you’re trying to use and
what you’re trying to integrate with.
Alright, Alison, looks like you have another
question you’d like to ask?
I do, yes. Some of us started off with
CS101 and then move on to this class and
we all got a bit stuck on Unit 3 but we’re doing
okay now. And we’re now thinking about what we
should do in the next hexamester what do you
think would be a good step-on from CS212 in
terms of Udacity’s course is given that we
probably only got time to do one.
So first of all, I want to say congratulations to
you and all the others who really truly started with
101 as their first class. I think it’s quite
impressive that you’ve been able to come this far.
And we designed 101 so that it could be taken by
people with no experience before but a lot of people
in 101 did have some degree of prior experience.
So for those of you who didn’t, it’s a testament to
your perseverance and I think it’s something that 101
work in terms of being able to hit that broad
audience. Let’s see, and can you pull up the list
of classes that we’re going to have next? I’ve got.
You got it and got to pull up already. Yes. Okay.
Go ahead. The computer science classes that
we’re offering are going to be software testing,
software engineering, and data structuring in
algorithms. Maybe you can comment on which of
those three you’d recommend next. Let’s see.
And what levels are they at? That’s a good
question. It’s something I don’t have at the top of
my head. Yeah. But I think most of them are
going to be 200 level classes and perhaps the
engineering will be a 100 level. Yeah. Not
committed to any of these statements yet
because we’re still ironing out the details. We’ve
had a lot of professors in lately doing a lot of
filming. We have a new recording studio with five
recording setups. So that will have content now
Pretty exciting. But in addition to those three
computer science classes we are going to have a
discrete math course, a statistics course taught
by Sebastian and a physics course that I will be
teaching. Okay, yes, that all sounds good.
I guess I would probably say that the algorithms
would tend to be the next class if I look at the
way people usually learn in a traditional
university, you might have the algorithm class
would be the natural next one.
And who is teaching that one?
Algorithm is going to be taught by Michael Littman.
So – and I know Mike, he is a great teacher.
So I think you would enjoy that class, not to take
anything away from the other ones but they might be
something that you could take afterwards.
Alright. Ginger, it looks like you have another
question. Yes. And this was back to Unit 3 again also.
So I was curious as to whether commercial regular
expression and/or JSON parsers were written anything
like we saw in Unit 3 or was that just – was that
just called for academic purposes of presenting
grammars and the power of generalization?
Okay, that’s a great question. And the answer is
somewhat – so many systems like that do write
parsers where the grammar that you’re writing is
similar that you say, here is the left hand side,
here is an arrow, here is the right hand side and
there are lots of systems that have that basic
type of format and so that is familiar. You will see
that elsewhere and that is used in professional
level systems. Now, how that’s actually
interpreted is somewhat more complicated
because they wanted to be easy for you to
express the grammar but they also wanted to be
fast and efficient to run that grammar to parse
some and so there is more complications in
terms of how you turn the grammar into a data
structure that can be efficiently processed and I
didn’t want to worry about those complications, I
wanted to just show you that it was possible to do it.
Alright. Alison, you got another question.
Yeah, I – be prepared like I was told. I wanted to
ask a little bit about how the sort of optimization
function we’ve been doing in Unit 5 compares to
game AIs, because for a computer game a near
optimal strategy might not be as much fun to play
as one were…That’s right. …the computer
actually makes some mistakes and I know that
bad gaming programs people keep accusing the
writers of cheating with the die rolls because
we’re beginning to play well but it looks like
they are lucky. So what sort of approaches
work best in the real world?
Yes, so that’s a great question. So in the real
world, usually your goal is not just to win the
game, your goal is to keep the people that are
playing the games happy. And so that
means a couple of things. One, some of the
games are used partly as a teaching mechanism.
So particularly for things like Chess and Go,
chess players want to play it not just because
they want to play a game, but because they want
to improve their game. And so the system has to
do something, it has to be able to explain in some
ways why it did things so that you can learn from
that. So that really changes the focus of it.
Another part you bring out is it’s really boring to
lose all the time and there are several ways
around that. One is you can just have a setting,
right? So how much compute time do you spend?
How far do you look ahead and that can be a little
slider and if you’re losing, you can pull that slider
back so you can catch up and if you are
collaborating the computer, you can push the
slider up, so you can try harder and that going to
work. So in the more sophisticated games
actually have an internal model of what’s going
on and what makes sport interest and then they
all respond to that and not so much in the chess
and checkers types of games, but in things like
an auto race game where it would be boring if
you were far behind or far ahead. There is a
routines there that try to make everybody be
packed together. So the winning cars will slow down
if you are behind and they will speed up if
you past them. But they have to do it in a
believable way that doesn’t just look like the
system is cheating; it looks like it’s a real race.
And so we know it can be harder to make it look
realistic than it can be to just do the optimum
work thing. Alright. Elia, you have another
question? Yes. Dr. Norvig mentioned he uses
Python for an educational or recreational
purposes and I am wondering that what sort of
languages do we really need to know if we are
intent on pursuing a technical career, for example,
I have a BS in operations research,
Masters in statistics and I intend for my career to
actually use these skills and so I wonder as a
technical professional, which languages should I
really know so that I could show, yes, I can hack
this and when does Udacity plan on offering
courses using these languages because
it's such a great system?
Great. Yeah, so I didn’t mean to knock Python
anyway or say that it’s not professional level.
Certainly, there are lots and lots of people and
companies that are using Python all the time. I
was just saying I was using a subset of it sort of
the intersection of what you would use
professionally and what you would use
educationally. So Python is a good answer.
There are other languages that are similar to that
that are gaining in popularity, Ruby and Closure,
you hear about a lot. The – I guess the strongest
languages traditionally would be JAVA and C++
and so there a little more verbose in terms of
what you have to write but also a little bit more
explicit in terms of how you understand what’s
going on in the programme. So one of the
disadvantages of Python that we see for – used
by professionals is there is no declarations of
what the inputs and outputs functions are. You
could sort of see what’s going on just by looking
at the function and if you’re writing a small
program, and that’s probably fine, but as the
programs get larger, sometimes you can get lost
do not know exactly what do I pass in here. You
know and says, oh, I see I should pass in a
sequence to this function that is either a list or
triple okay or does it have to be one or the other,
sometimes it’s not obvious in Python and that can
be two errors in a larger project where it’s just
hard to keep tracking all of that stuff. And so a
language like a JAVA is more explicit that way
even though you have to write more stuff to get to
the same type of result. But I think, you know, in
the end, you look around at the jobs you want
and the community you want to be a part of and
see whether they are using. So you know, if
you’re a statistician, all the languages I
mentioned I know can be used for those types of
jobs, I know there is also people used math lab
and R and mathematical and other packages like
that. So you have to look at your community and
see what they use and then be proficient in the
tools that the community expects. The next
question is actually write-in question that came
Portchanista says that there seems to be a
widespread belief that during development,
educations make code more and more
complicated and less elegant and eventually the
lines of special case code becomes so much
greater than the amount of actual original design
that get this mess on our hands so is this
generally true or a myth? So you certainly see
that happening that larger portion of the code can
be error handling and then a very small portion is,
here is the core algorithm after I’ve taken care of
all the errors. And I think there are different styles
that lead to that happening more or less. One is
in terms of the flexibility of the language and so a
language like Python is very flexible. As I said, it
doesn’t care in many cases what you pass in, so
you don’t have to spend a lot of time checking the
inputs to say this is exactly the right type of input.
You just say, ah, go ahead and do it. So that
makes the code more concise that way, it could
be less so in another language. I guess it also
depends on how much control you have over the
whole system. So if you are writing your whole
system from scratch, then you can kind of set the
guideline that the only types of objects that I’m
going to create are objects of this type and I
know that this is all that I am passing around and
so I can pass them around with impunity and
never have to check. And that’s great if you are
building a system from scratch. In other cases,
you have to interface with existing systems and
you never know quite what’s coming out of those
other systems. So you will always have to check
and say, if I was passing in something myself to
this function, I know it would be the right thing but
I am getting it downloading it off of website or
calling another server and getting a call back and
being passed something. So now, the first thing I
have to do is check the inputs to see if they are
valid before I can do something. And, yes, true,
that can end up being more work than the sort of
actual real work of the code.
Alright. Well, it looks like maybe all the questions
we have for today. Thank you to you guys for asking
those questions. Anybody else so – got a last one. Oh,
factor sink. Okay. Would you like to – I don’t
know if your audio is working but if it is try and
give it a shot and otherwise I can repeat.
Oh, yes. I wanted to ask about the current research
in the big data that Google does. I think it’s a
very hot topic these days, and it’s going to be more
and more important using the probabilistic models,
something like my continuation of what we were
doing this week’s lesson. Yeah. So please, if you
could tell us something more about what you are
doing. Okay, that’s great topic. We’re doing a lot
and I think you are right that a lot of what we do
does rely on probabilistic models and the reason
is because we are collecting a lot of data and we
are collecting it from a lot of sources and work
hasn’t gone in to verify those sources upfront we
talk about that trade-off. So you can verify a data
first or you just grab it as it is. And when we take
stuff off the web, when we gather images, when
we gather text, it’s just anything is out there.
It is not like a well-formed database where
you know you got a database of employees or you
got a database of bank records and every record
is verified to be accurate. We don’t have any of
them. So we’ve got all the stuff; some of it is
right, some of it is wrong, much of it is duplicates.
And we can't just take it as is. So – and we don’t
know where the uncertainty is. So we need this
probabilistic model. So that’s certainly the
approach. Now, what does it mean to do
research in that area? Lots of bunch of things.
One is what is the data you want to work on? You
work on text of various kinds, web pages
obviously and then there’s all sorts of other new
forms now of blogs and tweets and comments
and everything else. There’s also audio and
visual, still images and movies, we’re collecting
lots and lots of those and learning how to process
them. Those are harder than text because you
can't deal just with the raw pixels or the raw
sound form; you have to interpret that first. And
so there is research in making models of what it
means to be an amateur, what it means to be a
sound. We have to do all that. Then there is
research in how to do this all efficiency, how to
move around this terabytes and petabytes of data
from once place to another, and get enough
computers into the right place and get the data
processed in the right place. We’re doing all that.
There is research in machine learning or in
optimization of saying what is the optimal result
for this – that there is so much data, it’s hard to
compute using a traditional algorithm. Can we
come up with algorithm instead of proximate the
optimal result and will run efficiently over this and
so in some case, that’s inventing new algorithms
for adapting existing algorithms to work on these
larger amounts of data and to take advantage of
the computing resources we have. So lots of
work left to be done. You know, I feel like we’re
just getting started but it’s an exciting area. So I
promise I won't solve it all before you guys learn
enough that you can contribute enough.
Alright. Well, thank you very much. Thank you
to Alison and Praseck and Ginger and Elia. Yeah,
thank you. And to all the other students
who are watching, thanks. See you next week.
See you next week.