To see hands on how the database
organizes data, let's connect friendly
chat to the database and
then write some code to send messages.
Now before we do anything, let's
double check that we have the pods we
need to make a connection to
the database, and send a message.
Which of these pods listed do you think
is needed specifically to set up and
use your database?
You probably guessed it right away.
The Firebase/Database
pod is the one we need.
Also for any Firebase app,
the Firebase/Core pod is needed.
The code included in this
pod is like the metaphorical
core of what makes Firebase
work with your app.
Remember, if you're just now adding
any of these pods to your pod file,
you still need to run pod install to
pull in all the correct dependencies.
In my case, I've already run pod
install, and these pods are ready to go.
Now let's tackle connecting our
app to Firebase and the database.
To connect our app to the Firebase
application that we've created in
the Firebase console,
we'll want to start in the app delegate.
Make sure the Firebase module is
imported because we'll want to use
a class that it contains called FIR app,
which is short for Firebase app.
FIR App, or FIRApp, is the entry
point for all Firebase features.
In the didFinishLoadingWithOptions
function, add the line FIRApp.configure.
This call sets up the default
connection to our Firebase app.
But wait a minute,
it can't be that simple, right?
Actually, yeah, it is.
The GoogleService-info.plist
file is the key.
The single line of code we've
written utilizes this plist file
to set up the connection.
Awesome, now that's half the battle.
The next step is to configure
the actual connection to the database.
Unlike the connection we just made,
we don't want to connect
to the database right away.
Instead, we want to ensure
the user has authenticated first
before we start doing anything
related to the database.
So let's jump over to
the FCViewController.swift file.
Here, in the viewDidLoad function,
we can determine when to make
the connection to the database.
Since we'll take care of
authentication in a little bit,
we'll just assume that the user has
already successfully authenticated.
That's what we're seeing here with
the SignedIn status function call.
It's being passed true,
which by default,
assumes the user
successfully authenticates.
Let's command click on signedInStatus
to dive into the function.
You'll see that the signedInStatus
function takes in a Boolean value called
isSignedIn as a parameter.
And based on its value, it decides
whether to show or hide UI elements.
Also, assuming the user is signed in,
there's a conditional block for
some additional setup.
This is where we can
configure the database.
Assuming isSignedIn is true, we'll call
our empty function configureDatabase.
Let's command click it too, which
jumps us to the empty implementation.
Remember, at this point,
we can assume the user is signed in and
that this function,
configureDatabase, is called.
The only thing left to do is
connect the app to the database.
To do this, we'll define
a reference to the database.
It looks something like this.
This series of calls gives
us a reference to the root
of our Firebase database, awesome.
So now we've established our
connection to the database, and
next, we'll send our first message.