Congratulations.
>> Congratulations on completing this
introductory course on JavaScript.
>From defining your first variables,
to writing functions,
to creating your very own objects,
you've come a long way.
>> In just a short amount of time,
you've built up a basic understanding of
the JavaScript programming language, and
how it works
>> If this is your first time learning
a programming language, you should
be incredibly proud of yourself.
>> But the fun doesn't stop here.
Now, it's time for
you to venture forth, and
use your new JavaScript powers
to see what you can create.
We also hope you'll consider taking our
follow-up course if you're interested in
learning how to use JavaScript to create
interactive experiences on the web.
>> See you in the next course.
[MUSIC]