I do go to Home Depot, I actually
have the credit card because I buy
things that I need around the house.
I have lot of iDevices and
have done business with Apple.
I held insurance at Georgia Tech,
a BlueCross Blue Shield at
parent company at this Anthem.
I'm sure I have or some family member
of mine has shopped at Target.
I have shipped packages at UPS.
So for me, it's at least five.
I'm sure many of you have Facebook,
Twitter accounts and things like that.
So, it's not just the data
that lives on our computers.
But it's the data that
lives on the computers of
businesses that we patronize.
And our data could actually be
breached from those companies.
And then we could become targets, or
harm can come our way
from malicious actors.