So far, we've uploaded
a photo to Firebase Storage.
Next we need to add functionality
to handle adding photo messages to
the database, so
that other people chatting in
Friendly Chat can see the photo.
We've already done part of the work
by saving the photo's path,
the URL,
as part of a message in the database.
This creates an entry in the messages
part of the database that has
a key value pair for the image URL, and
a key value pair for the display name.
But, unlike text messages,
these photo messages do not
include a key value pair for text.
This causes a problem when I want to
see a photo message appear in the app.
Currently the table code is implemented
to find values for the key name and
text.
Hence our problem, it's not looking for
the image URL for our photo messages.
There's one other thing I
want to mention about this URL.
It's really important that we're only
storing the URL here in the database,
because we don't want the database
to be bogged down with large files.
By having the URL here,
which is just a string,
we can recreate the image
using that URL in our app.
All right, enough talk.
Let's modify our tableView code,
so it can display photo messages