Let's play a game of connect the dots.
Instead of drawing lines by hand,
though, we'll use a polyline.
So here we are in 1.3.04 ConnectTheDots.
Let's try running just
what we start out with.
Hmm, not sure,
well maybe that's some legs?
Well, let's draw a line and
figure it out.
The TODOs in this file will explain
further what you're going to need to do
to draw that line.
But it looks like the dot positions are
wrapped up in this array of Vector2s.
What's a Vector2?
Well, if we right-click on it and
we say Go To, Declaration, we see that
Vector2 is a class provided by lib GDX
that just holds an X and a Y component.
Super convenient.
So what we're going to need to do
is convert this array of Vector2s,
into an array of floats
that polyline will accept.
And then we'll go ahead and start a
shape render batch, with Shapetype.Line.
Actually draw the poly line and then
as always, remember to end the batch.
Try connecting the dots and when
you're done, what animal do you see?
Remember, if you get stuck, or just
when you're done with your solution,
I'd go ahead and
check out our solution as well.