Remember how you could store pretty
much anything you want in a variable?
Well, in JavaScript you can also
store functions in variables.
When a function is stored
inside of a variable,
it's called a function expression.
Notice how the function
keyword no longer has a name.
This is called an anonymous function.
Because you stored the function
in a variable called catSays,
naming the function at that
point is pretty redundant.
If you need to access that function,
you can just use the variable name.
This line of code here, for example,
will return the function back to you.
Just add parenthesis after catSays
to invoke the function and call it.
So now you have two ways to
define a function in JavaScript,
a Function Declaration and
a Function Expression.
Deciding when to use one or the other
can depend on a bunch of things.
But one thing you'll
probably need to consider
is a quirky behavior in
JavaScript called hoisting.
Let's take a closer
look at what that is.