Here are the answers I got, for
the first question I got -41.382.
For the second question I got 56.397.
For the third question
I got 3.072 radians.
And for
the last question I got 60.276 degrees.
Let's take a look at how we can
code functions in Python for
computing these answers.
For the dot product, I followed
a similar pattern as before for
my time scalar function.
I use zip with a list comprehension
to compute products of corresponding
coordinates between self and v.
And then I use an outer sum function
to add these products together.
From my angle with function, I have
an optional argument called in_degrees
which is set to false by default.
If it's set to true, then it will
output the angle between self and
v in degrees, otherwise it will
output the angle in radians.
For the angle with function,
I start by computing
the normalizations of self and v.
I then take the dot product of
the resulting unit vectors, and
then that dot product is fed
into the arc cosine function,
which in Python is the function
acos from the module math.
The output of acos gives
me the angle in radians.
If in_degrees was set to true,
I can multiply the angle in
radians by 180 divided by pi.
Pi is also found in the math module.
This obtains the angle in degrees.
I also make sure to check for the zero
vector, by seeing if an exception is
raised with the message that comes from
attempting to normalize the zero vector.
If that message is seen, an exception
with a different message is raised,
stating that angles cannot be
computed with the zero vector.
I also want to point out that I made
some modifications to my vector class.
I'm now using the decimal package, which
gives me better numerical precision.
Specifically, I changed my
initializer to ensure all coordinates
are decimal objects instead of
floating point numbers or integers.
I also made some other
changes to ensure that
numbers coming from outside the vector
object are treated as decimals.
Why did I do all this?
Well, remember that if two vectors
point in the same direction,
their dot product is the product
of their magnitudes.
So If self and
v point in the same direction,
then the dot product of their two
normalized unit vectors should be one.
However, sometimes I was getting
a ratio greater than one due to loss of
numerical precission, and
this will give me a domain
error inside the acos function.
Now that I finished coding these two
functions, I can execute this code here
and it will output the answers
to the questions from before.