Let's move on to the third stage of
networking request where we talk about
how we receive the server response
on the device and make sense of it.
As part of the response you got
a response code that describes whether
the exchange was successful or not.
We hope that the result is successful.
However, if for some reason the server
had a problem with the request,
we may receive an error status
code explaining what happened.
This could be a page not found error,
some kind of application server error or
maybe an access denied error.
You may recognize some of these
response codes from visiting
broken links on the web.
For example,
if you try to view a GitHub project
under an account that doesn't exist,
you might see page that says, 404 error.
But did you ever wonder
what 404 means or
where that came from or have you
ever seen an access denied error?
There's always a status code
attached to the HTTP response.
Here's a few of the more common HTTP
status codes you might encounter.
Status code 200 means everything went
okay, the requests were received and
everything is normal.
A 301 might mean that the page
moved permanently, and
we want to re-direct you somewhere else.
404 is what you may have seen or
page not found, and
500 errors are internal server errors.
There is a more comprehensive list of
the HTTP status code on Wikipedia which
we've linked below.
Response codes that start with one and
are followed by
other numbers represented by xx,
are informational responses.
Codes that start with a 2
are successful responses, like 200 OK.
The 300 class of errors
are redirection errors.
This means things like the page is
moved temporarily or permanently, and
we'd like you to do something else
to proceed with your request.
The 400 errors are client errors.
This is when something
goes wrong on your device,
your browser, your computer or
your software.
This might mean that the URL is wrong or
you've malformed the request somehow,
and the server just doesn't know how
to process what you're asking for.
The most common 400 error is
the 404 page not found error.
500 errors are errors with the server.
This could mean that the server
handling has crashed or
the server ran in to some unexpected
error when handling the request.
Keep in mind all this stuff is happening
super fast in just a few click moments.
From the minute your client sends the
request a connection to the web server
is established.
The server processes and sends it
all back to you with in seconds.
When we're building software it's
important to understand that a lot of
things are happening.
And all of those things
need to work properly for
your app to be able to pull
down information from the web.
Having a response code can be helpful
because we can anticipate and
write code for
what should happen if a failure occurs.
We'll see this firsthand in the Soonami
app in a later coding task.
Now let's apply what we've learned
to better understand the responses
from USGS.
What HTTP response code do we get
if the response is successful?
How about if the request
is unsuccessful?
We've provided links to a valid and
invalid URL.
You can enter these URL's into a web
browser to find the responses,
then write the response codes
into the boxes provided.