An IPv4 address is actually a 32-bit or
4 octet value which we usually
write as a dotted quad.
But writing an IP address
as 4 decimal numbers is
just a convention to
make it easier to read.
When it's used between computers,
it's just a thirty 32-bit long,
string of bits.
However not all of the possible 32-bit
values are used for real addresses.
Some of them are reserved for
special protocols.
internal private networks.
Some of them are for
testing or for documentation.
In fact, just over 1/8 of all possible
IPv4 addresses are set aside for
something other than
addressing public hosts.
But as you'll see,
even if we did use all 32 bit
addresses to represent public hosts.
That still wouldn't really be enough.