Along the way we've seen a lot of different technologies in this class
and a lot of different techniques, that are focused at different parts of the agent
and environment mix and different difficulties there.
Here we have a quiz, and what I want you to tell me is for each of these technologies
what do they most address?
Some of them address more than one, but give the best answer for each line.
Do they address the problem of a stochastic environment--
that is one where the results of actions can vary?
Do they address the problem of a partially observable environment--
one where we can't see everything?
Do they address the problem of an unknown environment--
one where we don't even know what the various actions are and what they do?
Do they address computational limitations--
that is problems of dealing with a very large problem rather than a small one
and making approximations to deal with that?
Or do they deal with handling adversaries who are working against our goals?
And I want you to answer that for MDPs, Markov decision processes;
POMDPs, partially observable Markov decision processes and belief space;
for reinforcement learning, and for A* algorithm, heuristic function, and Monte Carlo techniques.