All right, use Cardview for
detail view shadows on all platforms.
So first of all grab the starting code,
then add the Cardview library dependency
under project structure dependencies.
For tablet portrait
replace the weather detail
container frame layout with a Cardview,
but use margins rather than padding, so
the Cardview edges get properly
moved in from the layout border.
For tablet landscape, replace the detail
fragment frame layout with a Cardview.
To do this without creating additional
hierarchy that prevents the shadow from
rendering correctly, create a space view
in the RelativeLayout to
align the Cardview with.
Again, a little bit tricky there.
One more note: this will create an empty
Cardview when nothing is selected,
because by default,
our detail fragment hides itself.
So instead of that in
our detail fragment,
check to see if the parent
view is a Cardview.
And instead of hiding ourselves,
hide that parent view instead.
So that's what that
this line means here,
when it says hide the card view
parent in the detail fragment.