Here's what you should've marked.
This set of vertices and
edges in the original graph is
called the projected separator.
Let me first point something
out about this separator, and
then I'll walk you through how I got it.
See this triangle here?
It includes two unnecessary edges.
You really only need this sub-path.
So the main point is that if you
use the coarsening technique,
you will probably need to refine
the partitions that you get.
The readings discuss this
point in more detail.
Now, in case you didn't
get the same separator,
let me walk you through the process.
I did the first separator edge for
you, so let's move on to the second.
This edge comes from the original graph.
This edge comes from the super vertex.
Okay, what about the next edge?
It's basically the same thing.
This next edge is the interesting one.
The separator edge maps ambiguously to
these two edges of the original graph.
The last two separator edges
are similar to the first few.