So we've written the code that goes
out to Google to authenticate.
Now let's write a callback method to
handle the response that Google sends
back to the client.
Remember that along with
a successful response,
the Google API server will also provide
a one-time code to authorize our server,
and an access token that the client
can use to make API calls from within
the browser as well.
Just before the closing body
tag in my login.html page,
I'm going to add opening and
closing script tags.
I will define the sign-in callback
function that takes in an authResult
object as input.
If that object contains
a parameter called code,
then we know that the authorization with
the Google API server was successful,
and our one time use code is present.
Now that the app has been authorized,
we can hide the Google+ sign in button.
Now, I will use jQuery to
create an Ajax call that
passes the one time code Google
gave the client onto the server.
I will specify it as a POST method here.
The URL this method will
call I will name /gconnect.
I will define this method on
my server in the next video.
Along with this method I
pass the server state token
as an argument to verify against
the cross-site reference forgery attack.
Setting processData to false indicates
that we do not want jQuery to process
the response into a string.
Furthermore this
application/octet-stream
indicates that we are sending
an arbitrary binary stream of data.
And the charset equal to utf-8 indicates
that it is formatted using a universal
character set called Unicode.
Here we specify the data that we're
going to send along to our server,
the one time use code.
When we receive a 200 or a successful
response code from our server,
let's return a successful
login message to the user, and
then redirect to the main restaurant's
page after about four seconds.
If the server has any additional
response information to pass to
the client, we can present it
with this result variable.
So, let's go ahead and add an empty div
named result that we can populate with
a response method just above
the opening script tag.
In the event that an error
was returned by Google,
I will report this error
to the console.log.
In the event that no response was
returned by my server to the callback
function, I will return this
error message to my result div.
Before I can test and see if this works,
I will create the server-side G-connect
page that will accept the one-time code
for my client's callback function.