CPC stands for cost per click and
this is how much an advertiser
pays you if a user or
visitor clicks on their ad.
CPM was the tricky one and
that stands for cost per thousand.
And that's how much you earn for
every thousand views of an ad.
eCPM is then the estimated cost
per thousand views of an ad.
CPI is the cost per impression and
its definition is the same as CPM,
the cost per thousand views of an ad.
CTR stands for click-through rate, and
this metric measures how many users
have actually clicked on an ad.
Don't worry if you didn't
get all of these in one go.
Acronyms are inherently tricky.
The important part now is just to
familiarize yourself with the lingo and
you can rely on Google for
any definitions that you forget.