MATLAB has a couple of ways of thinking about how to do this, right?
And we're going to use, again, old MATLAB nomenclature, and
then I'll tell you about the new one.
So there are a couple of different methods.
The first method is called clip.
Clip basically means I assume that that outside boundary is black.
I then apply my filter, so here I can see my filter.
And when I pull out the image,
you can notice that this thing has gotten kind of dark at the edges.
And that makes sense because that black has leaked in, all right.
But that’s referred to as clipping.
Another method is called wrap around.
It’s kind of a weird method.
It has to do with some Fourier analysis that we’ll talk about later.
Basically it says that I assume my picture continues and wraps around.
Which means that you see this stuff filled in here?
That's the stuff that comes from this side of the picture.
It's easier to see up here, right?
These, these red peppers came from down here.
And the, the yellow straw comes from over there.
All right?
And that was under assumption that what you were actually looking at
was a periodic signal.
So if you were looking at a periodic signal.
The next thing that would happen would be the stuff that was at the start of it.
Well, in filtering, in image filtering, that doesn't work so well.
Here, I'm going to apply the filter, and
then I'm going to cut back to the original size image.
And you'll notice that there's some red stuff here.
Where did that red stuff come from?
Well, it actually came from the bottom because it got wrapped around.
There is a method that's called copy edge or
replicate where you just basically extend out, right?
So I just extend out the same value.
And then I run my filter and then I pull out my picture and
that's reasonable, okay?
The replicate method is a, is an easy one, and it gives you a reasonable result.
It basically says that the image sort of stays the same.
Now the problem is is that the statistics, of course, are different, right?
Because you had this nice varying image, and
then you make everything be sort of the same going out.
So, another method is called reflection.
Okay, are sometimes called symmetric.
And what that does is you, you reflect the image out.
And here, I just did that.
In fact, here let me draw right here.
Here's the reflected edge.
It's actually, if I erase it, hard to see that edge.
Right? Because I basically re, I, I take the image and I fold it back out again.
All right.
So, then I take that.
I apply my filter.
And then I pull out the image, and it actually does a pretty good job.
So, often you either want to do what's called replicate, or
copy, the edge or reflect across the image.
In new MATLAB these are expressed using this function called imfilter,
which comes from the Image Processing Toolbox.
And you can do you put in a value.
Puts that value in, so we put in 0, it's like clipping.
You can wrap around with circular and
then the copy edge is replicate and reflection is symmetric.
And typically, you'll use either replicate or symmetric.