Okay, let's take a quick look at
the triggers and the variables.
You should also have variables for
each kind of food preference, fish,
meat, vegan, vegetarian.
If we look at fish one,
configure the variable value to
be a relevant daily special for
the food preference.
And trigger it on the appropriate
trigger, in this case the fish trigger.
Now there's several ways
to handle the situation
where the user does not
specify a food preference.
You can let it default to the English
special, since we already have it.
Or you can create a new trigger,
such as no food pref trigger, and
set it to fire when
the food pref contains unrestricted,
because that's what we set in our code.
Save Trigger.
Now that you've got that trigger,
you can either create a new variable,
especially for
People who don't specify a preference,
if you want to give them their
very own customized special.
Or you could just pick one
of the other specials,
I'm going to o for
the vegetarian special,
and show that one to the people
who don't specify a preference.
And the way you do that is just edit the
variable and add another custom trigger.
So we want this to trigger, not only
when the vegetarian trigger applies, but
when the no food pref trigger applies.
Save the variable, and there it is.
And it really doesn't matter
which way you decide to go.