This animation works, but it has a potential problem. We're basing the
animation entirely off of the number of frames rendered. Each frame rotated the
bird half a degree. However, what if your machine runs this demo at 60 frames
per second, and mine runs it at 30 frames per second? This means your drinking
bird is rotating 30 degrees a second. Mine is rotating only 15. This might be
fine for drinking birds but say we had a facial animation play and it was
supposed to be synced with the sound file of the character's voice. This would
be a disaster. What we really want to do is use the real world time to know how
far to rotate before rendering the next frame. For example, say our target rate
is 60 frames per second, meaning that the bird should rotate 30 degrees per
second. We'd like to know how much time has gone by since the last frame. In a
moment, I'll show you how this is done. As you can see from demo, once we
switch to the timed version of the code, the rate of the drinking birds motion
is unaffected by the frames per second shown. Give this demo a try yourself.