And welcome back to computer vision.
With today's lesson and the next we're going to close a circle that
we started it seems like forever ago.
I remember we were talking about trying to compute transformations between
images, and we talked about doing panoramas and mosaics, and o,
and other ways of doing this, and we said, and
also when we're talking about fundamental matrices.
Key to all of these things was if we knew the correspondences,
you could compute the various transforms whether it's or something else.
Then we talked about competing features, and
feature points detections, and descriptions.
So today we'll finish the story,
where we're going to actually do the approach for doing feature-based alignment.
We'll describe it as a form of model fitting,
since, really that's what you're doing, we'll show you more about that.
And then, we'll talk about a really cool method that let's you effectively find
the best global solution, or probabilistically the best global solution,
without being too exhaustive, too combinatorically challenging.