Like most other programming languages,
JavaScript gives us evaluators
to compare expressions.
We can see if data are less than,
greater than, equal to, or
some combination of those three.
For this lesson we'll be
sticking with equality.
>> And equal to uses three equal signs,
not two.
>> Sort of, it can use either
three equal signs or two.
But the three equal sign
version is slightly safer.
There's a link in the instructors
notes explaining the difference.
To check out the syntax and
give evaluation a try.
>> Like, if some condition is true,
then do something.
There's an if statement within the
parentheses and then, if it evaluates to
true, we perform whatever action
comes between the curly braces.
If the condition isn't equal to true,
we can use an else statement
to do something else.
In that case we simply use the key
word else, add another curly brace and
then an alternate set of
commands that performs
if this original condition is not true.
This syntax for
if statements follows the same
patterns as if statements in Python.
But notice that we have to include
our conditions in parentheses here.
And that the statements that
perform if this condition is true
come between curly braces.
Also note, there's no colon after
the condition in JavaScript.
>> Here's an example.
If ( tired === true) { drinkCoffee();
}else.
If I'm tired I'll go drink some coffee.
Otherwise I'll drink water.
So how do you think we'll use if
statements to build the resume?
Looking at our header,
we've got these skills, which we may or
may not want to include.
If we do decide to include this list,
we'll first need to create it, and
we'll need to create this
skills at a glance heading.
So, how can we see if we
need to create the list?
I think we should use an if statement.
You know what?
This is going to make a good quiz.
>> Yeah, I think so too.
>> Write an if statement that
checks whether there are any skills
in the bio object.
If there are skills, the if statement
should evaluate to true and
then .append()HTMLskillsStart
to the div with the id=header.
Once that's done, .append() each
skill to the element id=skills
by formatting them with HTMLskills.
You could find HTML skills in
helper.js if you're interesting in
what it looks like.
When you've finished up, and you can see
the skills on the page, check this box.