To evaluate the game tree, we work from the bottom up.
Let's start over here. This is a min node.
Min chooses the minimum, which will be 1.
In this position, Min would choose 2, the minimum of 2 and 4.
Over here Min would choose 0, the minimum of 0 and 10.
Now we have some chance nodes, so we have to choose the expected value.
Chance, the flip of the coin, doesn't get the choice of one direction or the other.
Rather both of them are possibilities.
So we just average the results, since the probability of heads and tails are equal.
So 7 and 1 is 8, divided by 2 is 4, and 8 and 2 is 10 over 2 is 5 is the expected value there.
The expected value of 0 and 6 is 3, and the expected value of 0 and 4 is 2.
Now we have a maximizing node. The max of 5 and 4 would be 5.
The max of 3 and 2 would be 3, and finally, we have another chance node.
The average of 5 and 3 would be 4, and that's the value of the final state.