In summary a metric is some measurable quantity that we
can use to reason about the behavior of the system.
Ideally we will obtain these metrics.
We will gather these measurements running experiments using
real software deployment on the real machines using real workloads.
However sometimes that's really not an option.
We cannot wait to actually deploy the software before we
start measuring something about it or analyzing its behavior.
In those cases we have to resort to experimentation with
some representative configurations that in some way mimic as much as
possible the aspects of the real system.
The key here is that such a toy experiment must be representative of this
real environments so we must use workloads that have similar access patterns,
similar types of machines.
So as closely mimics the behavior of the real system as possible.
And possibly we will have to supplement those toys experiments with simulation.
So that we can perhaps create an environment that somehow mimics up
a larger system that was possible with a small experiment.
Any of these methods represent viable settings where one can
evaluate a system and gather some performance metrics about t.
We refer to these experimental settings as a testbed.
So the testbed that tells us where were the experiments carried out and
what were the relevant metrics that were measured?