All right so we're still working
on the fourth task here,
which is to make sure that
the word adapter has the correct
instructions to create
each list item view.
So that means first we need to modify
the word class so that the word adapter
can tell if there is a valid image
associated with the word or not.
We've also provided a hint bellow
the the quiz if you need some help.
And then we need to modify
our WordAdapter class.
So it can create list items that both
contain images and ones that don't.
And this way the same WordAdapter
class can be used across our
different categories.
I want to introduce you to a new concept
that I hinted at in the last quiz.
So there's a method that you can call
to change whether a view is visible or
not, while the app is running.
So for a given view object,
as shown here in the view class,
you can call the set visibility method
on it and pass in one integer input.
So the possible inputs that we have
are visible, invisible, and and gone and
these may look like string values but
let's click in and see more.
So clicking into visible we
see this actually integer
defined in the view class and
it has an integer value of zero.
Now this is how you would
use the method in your code.
Assume that we have a view stored
in the variable named text view.
We can call the set visibility
method on this text you object and
into this method we pass in one input
which is the integer defined in
the view class called visible.
Now these are the different
inputs the set visibility method.
Now I won't tell you the exact behavior
of these three states just yet.
I'd like you to experiment or
read the documentation to figure
out what they mean on your own.
These three visibility states are
represented by three predefined integer
values that the view
class knows to expect and
will know how to behave
if ever sees any of them.
So if we were to pass in a random
integer value something like 2001.
Then the view class wouldn't
know to do with the view.
So to summarize, the view class only
recognizes these three numbers.
So for example if the method
receives zero as its input,
the view knows that it
should become visible.
I want you to notice something about
the variable in the documentation.
So it says here public
static final int VISIBLE and
we haven't seen static or final before
and both of these are Java keywords that
have special meaning and
they're called modifiers.
So last time we heard about modifiers
was we talked about how words such as
public and private were access modifiers
used to control who can use
a class variable or method.
So because the visible variable is
declared using the final keyword
the field can never change values.
So think of zero as being
the absolute final, final value.
So once a variable is initialized if you
try to assign a different value there's
going to be a Java error
saying it's not allowed.
In Java when a variable doesn't
change values it's called a constant.
So you can think of it as
constantly being the same value.
When we have a constant value,
the convention in Java is to give the
variable a name in all capital letters.
So, the capitalization
doesn't imply that were
yelling these variable names
like visible, invisible or gone.
They're just capitalized as
an easy way to help us indicate
that their constant values, all right.
So the final key word, explains why
this variables are constant value and
has its name in all capital letters.
Now what about the static key word?
Well, this means that this variable
is associated with the class and
not associated with an object
instance of the class.
So this is a very non-trivial concept,
but we won't go into that detail now.
All you need to know is that
since the variable is public and
static you can go ahead infer
to this variable directly.
Using the cost name
view followed by dot.
So in this case view dot visible.
So this dot notation
means that this variable
is part of the class that
comes before the dot.
So, other examples are view dot
invisible or view dot gone for
these other states.
After you finish modifying
the word adapter code,
allocating answers to
these two questions.
So, for this list item layout
that we're using just for
phrases should the visibility of
the image view be set to visible?
Invisible or gone and then for
this list item layout, which we're going
to use for all our other categories
should its image you be set to visible,
invisible, or gone?
And this is what the app should
look like when you're done.
So tapping into phrases
there are no images.
But when we tap into the other
categories, they all do have images.
[BLANK_AUDIO]