Right now, our app has all
the functionality that it needs.
It just doesn't look very pretty.
So, I'm going to be walking you
through how to make those changes.
So, the first thing we're going to do is
modify something called the Styles file.
And that's located in Values, and
then it's right here, this styles.xml.
So, I'm going to double-click.
Okay, now this is a file that
you've never really touched before.
And I'm not going to go into
the details of exactly how this works.
We've provided you with some code, which
will change your buttons to orange and
also change your action bar to orange.
And this code will do that because
the Styles file is responsible for
controlling the basic
default styles of your app.
Whereas right now in our XML,
if we wanted to change the color of
a background, we would do it for
each element.
But if you do it in the styles file,
it will do it for the entire layout.
Okay, so I'm going to paste
the code that I gave you over.
This color primary here is the color
that the action bar will be.
And this color button normal is
the color that your buttons will be.
Now a quick note.
Because of API updates,
this colorButtonNormal tag will actually
only work if you have API level 22 and
above.
So, what this means is that
if you have a newer phone,
you will see the orange buttons, and
you can check it out in the emulator.
And if your phone's a little bit older,
you'll still see gray buttons.
Now, there are ways to get around this,
but
I don't want us to get too caught up in
the weeds of how to color our buttons.
Okay, let's go back to
our activity_main.xml.
Okay, cool.
So we can see now that it actually
updated to show that our buttons
are orange, and
our action bar is also orange.
Our status bar also became a light gray,
which is due to us changing this parent
attribute right here to AppCompat.Light
instead of AppCompat.Dark.
It gave us a light theming
instead of a dark theming.
Okay, let me go back to the XML.
So, the next thing on our list is
to make a nice little divider bar
right here.
Okay, so if I click on this
linear layout right here,
we can see that it's sort of
this view that lives here.
If I scroll down a little bit,
I'll see the other linear layout,
when I click on it,
is this linear layout right here.
So if I wanted a bar in between the two,
I would put it right here, after which
the first linear layout closes, and
before the second linear layout opens.
And because the parents of both
of these two linear layouts
is another linear layout,
I'll scroll up to show you.
This linear layout right here.
Which has an orientation of horizontal.
When I put the bar right here,
it's going to show this linear layout,
the bar, then this linear layout,
all in a horizontal row.
Okay, let me go down.
If you just want to make a colored
square, which is essentially what a line
is that runs down the center here,
we can use a view called, well, View.
Okay.
Now, just like other views,
this view needs a width and a height.
Now, we want a thin line, so
the width of this view should be one DP.
This is what the thickness
of the line is going to be.
And what I want is for
this line to be just as tall
as all the text in the buttons
in the linear layout for Team A,
and the linear layout for Team B.
So, I'm going to make
the height match parent.
Now, this view is basically a box
that has one DP in width, and
has the height of the parent
linear layout of all of this.
But we can't see it because
the background color is white.
So, I'm going to change
the background color to dark gray.
Okay, so now we have a dark gray
line that's going down the center of
the screen.
But, if we zoom in,
we'll see that it's actually
going down the entire center of the
screen, even through the reset button.
And we actually want it
to stop right about here.
So the way that we're going to do that
is we're going to start telling things
to wrap content instead of match parent.
Specifically, for the Team A and Team B
linear layouts, instead of having their
height being the entire screen,
we're going to have it wrap content for
both of these, so that the layouts will
end right at the bottom of the buttons.
And then, for the parent layout,
the horizontal layout that's
laying out all of this,
we'll also tell it to wrap content.
Which will wrap the content up tight
against the bottom of the team B and
team A linear layouts.
And that should make the line the same
height as both of these layouts.
So, let's make those changes.
I'll start with this
linear layout right here,
which is the linear layout for team B.
And I'm going to change its
height to wrap_content.
Okay, good, it's wrapping the content
of the buttons right now.
I'm going to click on the Team A layout
and I'm also going to change its
layout_height, instead of
match_parent to wrap_content.
So now both of these layouts here are
wrapping the content of their children.
But the line down the middle is
still extending towards the bottom.
And that's because the parent of these
two linear layouts is still taking up
all this space,
because it has a height of match_parent,
which is the entire screen.
So now, I'm going to tell this,
as well, to wrap_content.
So now the gray line ends here at the
bottom of both of these linear layouts.
Okay, cool.
Now,
I didn't want the gray line to
extend all the way up here, but
that's an issue that can be resolved
with padding and layout margins, so
we'll do that in a little bit.
Right now what I want to
do is go through and
get all the appropriate text sizes,
colors and the correct fonts.
So, we're going to just start at
the top and make those changes.
What I've been told for
this first TextView
is that it's going to have a font
family of Sans Serif Medium.
And it's going to have
a text size of 14sp.
And finally, also that its text color
is going to be the hex code 616161,
which is a nice light gray text color,
okay.
So that's the font, the size, and
the color for this team A text view.
I'm going to move on
to the team A score.
Now, for the score, the font family
is going to be Sans Serif light.
The text size is going to be a large
56sp, so that our score is nice and big.
And the textColor is
actually going to be black,
which in hex is represented as 000000.
Okay, cool.
I'm going to zoom out.
So, for our buttons, we actually don't
change anything about the text styling
or text size or text color.
These are fine.
But I do want to change
the other side and
I change it exactly as I
change the first side.
So, let me do that really quickly.
Okay.
So I just updated so
that these two are exactly the same now.
And our text sizes,
text sizes, colors, and
font families are looking pretty good.
So really,
the only thing left is to work on
the spacing issues that I'm seeing.
Okay, we'll start with
the first text view here.
Instead of a padding of 4dp, we're
going to change it a padding of 16dp.
Now here in the score text view,
instead of a padding of 4dp,
we're going to change it
to padding bottom of 24dp.
And that's because with
the 16dp padding here,
We already have enough room
between these two lines of text.
Okay, now for the buttons.
Now, our buttons are looking
a little bit wide.
I don't want to give them
a specific width, but
I do want them to be a little
bit farther away from the edges.
Now, we can't use padding,
because remember,
padding is space added inside the view,
and
button views have a background color
that extends throughout the view.
So we're going to be using margin, here.
Now, right now,
I have a layout margin of 8.
But what I'm going to do is change
this to a layout margin bottom of 8.
And then a margin left and right of 24,
which will keep the same spacing,
vertically, but
will push in the sides of the button.
So let's do that now.
Okay, so that button's
looking a little bit better.
I'm going to do the same thing
to the other two buttons here.
And I'm actually copying and
pasting to do this.
All right, cool.
Now, I don't want to bore you, so
I'm just going to make the same changes
to this side that I just made to Team A.
So, give me one second.
Okay, great.
Now my two sides look the same.
The only other real margin that I
have to deal with is the margin for
this grey line here, and
the margin for the reset button.
Let's do the reset button first.
Okay, so i'm going to give the reset
button a bottom margin of 8dp, and
i'm going to give it a left
a right margin of 22dp.
Okay, now I'm going to
scroll up to the grey line.
Okay, that's this view right here.
And basically,
I don't want the grey line to be
touching the app bar right here.
I want to give it a little bit of space.
And I'm going to be using
margin instead of padding for
the same reasons that
I did on the button.
Because this is a gray background, so
any padding that I use actually is
not going to really change anything.
But margin,
which is space around the view, will.
So let's do that right now.
Margin top, and we'll do 16dp.
Yeah, there we go.
There's a little space
above the gray line there.
Okay, now my code's looking a little bit
sloppy because I was just kind of adding
attributes willy nilly.
So I'm going to do a Cmd+A.
Or if you're on a Windows
device a Ctrl+A to select all.
And then I'm going to do a Cmd+Option+L.
And if you're on a Windows device,
that's a Ctrl+Alt+L.
And that will automatically
reformat the code for me.
It'll look really nice and pretty.
Just as pretty as our
new Court Counter app.
Now, I kind of want to
see this on my phone,
so I'm going to load up my phone right
now with this newly skinned app.
Remember, if you have an older phone,
it's going to show the buttons
as a different color.
But you can always use the emulator.
Woo hoo!
What a stylish looking app.
Now the question is.
Is it still working?
Well, I didn't touch any
of the Java code, so yeah.
And the scores are nice and big now.
And I've got these wonderful colors for
my buttons.
Awesome work.