Let's look at another example.
In this case, let's look at rotation.
So in essence, the image moves and
is also rotated.
And let's call the rotation be,
the rotation amount to be theta.
Okay.
So just simplicity's sake,
let's say that we can claim c
theta is equal to cosine theta.
And s theta is sine theta, okay?
How many degrees of freedom do we
need which would be the answer here.
How many points or correspondences do
we need between both these images and
what would this matrix
approximately look like.
I'm just giving you this coach so
you can now basically use c theta,
with sines here, here, here, here,
here, wherever they need to show up.
And, of course, also remember,
this would be 1.
And the question comes up,
how many degrees of freedom?
And, also more appropriately, how many
points of correspondence do we need?