[Narrator] So here features that you might consider when you write
in an advance spam filter.
For example,
does the email come from
a known spamming IP or computer?
Have you emailed this person before?
In which case it is less likely to be spam.
Here's a powerful one:
have 1000 other people
recently received the same message?
Is the email header consistent?
So example if the from field says your bank
is the IP address really your bank?
Surprisingly is the email all caps?
Strangely many spammers believe if you write
things in all caps you'll pay more attention to it.
Do the inline URLs point to those pages
where they say they're pointing to?
Are you addressed by your correct name?
Now these are some features,
I'm sure you can think of more.
You can toss them easily into the
naive base model and get better classification.
In fact model spam filters keep learning
as people flag emails as spam, and
of course spammers keep learning as well
and trying to fool modern spam filters.
Who's going to win?
Well so far the spam filters are clearly winning.
Most of my spam I never see, but who knows
what's going to happen with the future?
It's a really fascinating machine learning problem.