PCP stands for
probabilistically checkable proofs.
It turns out that if you take
the verifiers we talked about
when we defined the class NP, and one,
you give them access to random bits.
And two, you give them random
access into the certificate or
proof, then they become extremely
efficient in a certain sense.
These types of verifiers are called
probabilistically checkable proof
systems, and the famous PCP theorem
relates the set of languages they can
verify under certain constraints
back to the class NP.
In a course on complexity, we would
place these proof systems within
the larger context of other complexity
classes and interactive proof systems.
For our purposes however, we can
state the PCP theorem in this way,
which is much more accessible.
We'll let capital phi denote
the set of all 3CNF formulas.
Remember we're assuming that all clauses
have exactly three literals, and
that they come from three
distinct variables.
Then a version of the PCP
theorem can be stated like this.
For any constant alpha
greater than seven-eighths,
there is a polytime computable function
f such that for every formula phi
over a sufficient number of variables,
the following two things are true.
One, if the formula phi is satisfiable,
then f of phi is also satisfiable.
And if phi is not satisfiable,
then every assignment for
f of phi satisfies fewer than
an alpha fraction of the clauses.
So if phi is satisfiable, there's a way
to satisfy all the clauses of f of phi.
If phi is unsatisfiable, however,
then you can't even get close to
satisfying all the clauses of f of phi.
We've introduced a kind of gap here,
and this gap is extremely useful for
proving the hardness of approximation.
Many, many hardness of approximation
results follow from this theorem.
The most straightforward of them,
however, is that you can't do better
than the seven-eighths algorithm
from MAX-SAT that we just went over.
Not unless P is equal to NP, anyway.
Why?
Well suppose that I wanted to test
whether strings were in some language,
where the language is in NP.
And at my disposal,
I had a polyton alpha approximation for
3-SAT, where alpha is strictly
greater than seven-eighths.
Then I could use the Cook-Levin
reduction to transform my string into
an instance of SAT that would be
satisfiable if and only if X is in L.
Then I can use the function
f from the PCP theorem
to transform this into
another set of 3-SAT clauses.
Where either all the clauses
are satisfiable or fewer than an alpha
fraction of them are, depending
on whether phi was satisfiable.
That way, I just run the alpha
approximation on f of V and
see if the fraction of clauses
satisfied is greater than alpha or not.
If it is, then from the PCP theorem,
I can reason that phi must have been
satisfiable and so from the Cook-Levin
reduction, X must have been in L.
On the other hand, if the fractional
clauses satisfied is less than alpha,
then f of phi can not have been
satisfiable, so phi must not have been
satisfiable either, so from the
Cook-Levin theorem, X must not be in L.
Using this reasoning, we just found
a way to decide an arbitrary language
in NP in polynomial time.
So if such an alpha approximation
exists, then P is equal to NP.
Since P probably is not equal to NP,
it seems like such an alpha
approximation can't exist.
Many hardness of approximation
proofs can be done in a similar way.
All that's necessary is to stick
in another transformation here,
transforming the three step problem
that has this gap into another problem,
while preserving a gap,
and thus showing that
certain approximation factors
would imply that P is equal to NP.