If that’s computer is, vision is why would you want to study this?
Well, I mean, a, you might want to get a Masters in
Computer Science degree at Georgia Tech, and everything else was filled.
And you got stuck with Bob, and well, so here you are.
But there’s actually some really good reasons to do that.
These days images and imagery have become ubiquitous in all of our technology.
cameras, video, you can stream them, you can send them etc.
So what's become fundamental to an awful lot of
systems is the manipulation in the processing of imagery.
And extracting information from that.
There are domains such as surveillance.
There are building 3D models for medical imaging.
Or capturing for motion capture.
These are all different current industries that leverage computer vision in
a variety of ways.
But most of all, the reason to do it is, it is just a really cool and
deep set of problems.
And it's way more fun that learning how to build compilers.
And now, I have to go apologize to all my compiler friends, but
they know it's true.