Great.
You're almost ready to get started,
but before writing any code you're going
to need to enable the Google Sign In API
on the Google Developers Console.
You can see the console here.
It's at console.developers.google.com.
And the first thing that you're going to
do on here is to create a project.
So, I'm going to select
the Create a Project button and
give my project a name.
So I'm going to call it
LaurencesSignInProject, and
then you're going to
give it a project ID,
the project ID has to be
unique across all of Google.
Projects in the Developers Console
are used for
things such as app engine, cloud
platform, and other stuff like that.
So you need a unique ID, so
I'm just going to try laurence-signin-1.
And that is unique so I'm good to go.
Then of course you also
need a billing account.
If you don't have one already,
you're going to go and create one.
If you need to see the steps for doing
that, check back to the maps lessons and
I did some steps on that there.
I'm just going to pick
an existing billing account and
I'm going to click create.
You'll see over in the activities window
here your project will start creating
and it will take a few moments
to create your project.
And now the project is complete and
the Project Dashboard is open.
In the next step you'll use the Project
Dashboard to configure the APIs and
configure your credentials.