Understanding the task or problem domain
is key to designing intelligent systems.
We call it the environment, and
we refer to the intelligence system or
software itself as the agent.
>> For instance, consider the Roomba.
An automated vacuum cleaner that moves
around the house in a consistent pattern
sucking up dirt.
Its environment consists of the room or
house it is operating in.
But more specifically the floor,
walls and
all the objects that are on the floor
that it may need to avoid bumping into.
A painting on the wall
is not much of a concern
>> Now in this case would you say
that the agent is the whole
physical robot itself, or
just the software that's running it?
>> That's an excellent question.
>From a Cartesian point of view,
you may only consider
the software itself as the agent.
While all the hardware components,
including the sensors,
motors would be external to the agent
and thus part of the environment.
>> I would totally agree with that.
My hands seem to have a mind of their
own when a bag of chips is placed in
front of me.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>> Okay, while that can be
a useful distinction when
analyzing different
internal parts of a Roomba,
at a high level I would consider
the entire robot to be the agent.
I like to include all components
that are directly accessable or
controllable with some reliability.
>> That makes sense, now let's
think about what information or
state a Roomba needs to store
in order to do its job.
>> Hm,
kind of like in the tic-tac-toe world.
A Roomba needs to store its current
position as well as all the different
areas that it has already cleaned, so
it doesn't waste time
going around in circles.
It might be helpful to store a map of
all the obstacles it has seen as well.
But they may move over time so
that information can change.
>> That's right.
We only represent those items in
the state that are necessary for
completing the task.
Things that are irrelevant, such as the
position of a painting on a wall like
you mentioned, can be left out.
>> Finally,
we can specify the result the agent
is trying to achieve as a goal state.
Note that this can be
a partial specification.
For instance, in a navigation problem,
we may need to keep track of our
orientation while taking actions.
But the goal state only needs
to include the final location.
It could also be a set of different
states that are all considered
acceptable goals.
[BLANK_AUDIO]