So at run time, it works like following.
So here I'm going to show you on two cars using just the tire patch as
the example, all right?
Suppose we have only one feature and it's the tire.
And suppose we try looking for it everywhere, okay?
So we look for it everywhere and we find these four.
Okay?
Well, when we find them, what we have to do is we have to
take the displacement vectors associated with that codeword and
vote with all those displacement vectors.
So let's remember for the tire codeword, there are two displacement vectors.
One to the right, one to the left.
So we vote for those.
And then we simply look for
spots, points that have more votes than other places.
So in the case, where is it, where are those points?
Well, just in the center of the cars.
As I said, this was originally proposed by some folks at the ECCV,
European Conference Creative Vision 2004 and
it subsequently been evolved from that.
And the, so the idea is that we're now using this notion of detecting features
and something about their configuration in order to try to find these objects