So here, I'll showcase a much more detailed example, and this is
something you will be experimenting with with various programming assignments.
Given an image A, and image B,
we want to blend them, but actually we want to add one more constraint.
So in the previous one we basically looked at, merge it at half from this and
half from this.
But now actually, I want to give it a mask,
a region where I want most of the blending happening.
Just to make it a little bit of fun, what I've done is in this example,
the mask region is based on the hair and face of Einstein.
because what we're interested in is basically taking the face from Tigger and
merge it with just this region, and
ignore all of the information that's black here.
So this basically gives us a way of now kind of doing the blending in
a specific region.
How would we do this?
Well, first we'll build our Laplacian pyramids.
Of course, that requires us to build Gaussian pyramids, too.
Also, we want to do is build a Gaussian of just this mask region.
We will actually use this because we want to be able to use that as a kind of
a filter, a binary filter, with only positive values where it's one,
we'll actually go through and zero where it won't.
So form a combined pyramid using Gaussian for R.
And, this would be the way basically we'd create each and every Laplacian.
So Laplacian would combine the Gaussian of this region here with that of an A,
because we want all the pixels from here.
And then, of course, then subtract it.
So then we get all of the other, the, the composite of this one from B.
Basically, this how we would actually use it to create a combined Laplacian
pyramid, which would actually be blending information from one to the other.
And then, of course, after this thing has all been done for each and every
level, we would collapse the Laplacian pyramid to get the final blended image.