The specific lesson objectives for this lesson are, to introduce to
you the concept of computational photography through a specific example.
The example I'm going to introduce today is that of dual photography.
It's actually based on a recent work by some people up at Stanford and
are the collaborators, who basically kind of suggest that you can now swap
a camera and a light source to actually now generate a newer form of imagery.
And the whole pipeline of how to do this basically impacts all the elements of
photography that we have covered so far.
And the reason for doing this introduction of this concept right now is to
kind of have you think about these concepts as we go
further into analysis of different methods and different technologies that
are underlying both a camera and the digital processing pipeline of images