I'm just asking cause the contrary, my company should not, it varied in
putting an as star me impression, but our concern is about the, to run in,
in the crass turf that we know in the, in from the stump documentation that we,
every time you want to change the topology, you shut it down and bring it up.
>> Mm-hm.
>> It seems it's not very practical for production.
Well we do that in production all the time.
I mean see the thing is like here whenever you from the stomp apology
whoever wants to likes the apology you never shut it off for days after that.
I know to that have been running for two or 200 days without even being touched.
The last one I looked at, it was 152.
That is not, that hasn't been touched at all.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So, so, so, if that is, typically, since these stipolis are long running.
>> You don't have to keep stirring what do you call it?
Kill it and submit it again.
So once in a while you do that, right?
So, it's a very now what do you call it?
Where you less frequent operation.
So that way, like even in production topology, your down time is so
low, as long as essays are mad, right?
>> Mm-hm.
>> Then you're fine.
>> So if we don't need to take the technology, if the,
we feel the class is not enough to deal with the, the, the, the, the, the data.
>> Mm-hm. >> The running data we can't a, add more machine and-
>> Yeah. That's all it is.
>> It's not do a run time >> Yeah.
>> [INAUDIBLE] With that?
[CROSSTALK].
>> Yeah, but not like, for example, so
there is two type of data that you have to look for.
When you, when you provision the proposal first, right?
You will have looked at all this data that you are getting and you would have
calculated some x number of instances in all the various things, right?
Then when you deploy topology,
you also would have seen the forecast of how much that is has going to grow.
And you would have accommodated for that, right?
So that's what we call and also you had to look for spikes.
Spike right because sometimes the data like going in like three comments
especially super human from like a 10k per second to close to 140k per second.
So it's hard to wield provision for that.
So, so these two are the key things that you look for and
when you approximation of the product and it goes to the production.
You would based on this calculation, you would of calculated some kind of and
all the instincts and you would have launched it.
Now if the topology is misbehaving during that time.
>> Mm-hm. >> Then you will know because of the way it is data that you get.
Even the open source com also has this notion of UI.
But you can see how much topo is [INAUDIBLE] every stage and
what amount of time took at every stage.
Even though it might not provide a CPU [INAUDIBLE] but you get a lot of data.
And using that you can figure out [INAUDIBLE] that I'm [INAUDIBLE] is
going evenly good or not.
For example if there is a data queue in some board.
Then if you look at the bolds and the corresponding image counter log and
immediately will know from the count itself.
You know oh, this is so
high on that guy so in between there is a skew inside right?
>> Hm. >> So, so you can figure out those issues right away.
Then so typically it starts calculations typically it will be
time to look for a year.
And according to probation.
So that we don't have to kill them again and again, right?
So now once the data grows beyond your certain limits
your reproduction And that's all.