So, why did our activity get
destroyed and recreated?
It's possible to create
different layouts and
resources for
different device configurations.
Everything from screen size,
to pixel density and device orientation.
Now keep in mind, that some of these
values, such as device orientation and
screen width, can change at runtime.
So the default behavior
is to destroy and
recreate Android activities whenever
a device configuration changes.
Let's talk about something
else you may have noticed.
When you rotate the device or
emulator you only see onCreate, onStart
and onResume show up in the text view.
What about onPause?
The reason is that the content of text
views that are populated dynamically,
like our log view,
are not automatically preserved when
the activity is destroyed and recreated.
To do that, we can take advantage of
the facility [INAUDIBLE] has to save and
restore this information.