The answer of this specific example over here is 3,
although you could argue it could be something else,
but 3 is a convenient and common answer,
which is this robot's state is determined by its xy location and by its heading direction,
which is often called theta.
Now, you could argue heading doesn't matter because it can turn itself on the spot,
and in some examples that is actually correct.
You might be able to get away with it with a two-dimensional state,
but if you're going to predict what's happened next when you, for example, drive forward,
the heading matters greatly.
In that sense, it's actually a three-dimensional state, so 3 is the best answer.
Let me ask you a few more questions about dimensionality of state spaces.