So, to summarize, in this lecture we basically covered the concepts how we
can merge two images.
I specifically talked about the cross-fading aspects of it.
We talked about different issues related to it.
And, in essence, how we can compute the size of the window.
And we actually looked at the whole concept of Fourier Domain again,
that we had looked at previously to help us coming up with some rules and
some processes that would allow us to look at different types of window sizes.
In the next lecture, we're going to take this process a little bit more forward,
how we can actually do merging and blending.
We have looked at merging and blending.
We have looked at how we can do this, and understand the issues of
window sizes with Fourier domain and all that kind of stuff.
But now, we'll put it to much more practical tests, and
look at how we can actually do this by use of pyramids, where we
can do the blending at the lower frequencies, and higher frequencies separately.
As we had discussed, again, we wanted to do feathering and stuff.
But we’ll come up with a much more well-defined approach of how to do this, and
of course, you’ll you’ll have the opportunity to play around with this also.
Again, just more information related to the material we covered right now and
additional information will be made available on the website.