In addition to disabling and
enabling certain services,
personal firewalls can also
provide advanced features.
For example,
a personal firewall can be configured
to hide the system from the Internet.
This is accomplished by
the firewall dropping
unsolicited packets from the Internet.
The firewall can also drop all
UDP packets or ICMB packets and
only allow TCB packets to certain ports.
A personal firewall can
also support logging.
For example, recording all
unwanted traffic and activities.
It can also allow the user to specify
only certain applications to
subconnections from the Internet.
For example, the user can specify that
only the applications signed by public
keys, issued by a valid certificate
authority can connect to the Internet.