Boosting is an iterative
learning method, right?
So you, you, you massage the data and
you keep co,
constructing a better and
better classifier.
And it focuses this idea on
every iteration of trying to
look at what's called
the weighted training error.
So initially,
you have a whole bunch of samples, and
you weight them equally, right,
so they all have a weight of one.
And then in each boosting round what you
have to do is you have to find a weak
learner, we'll talk about that in
a minute, that achieves the lowest, or
not even the lowest.
You have to find the weak learner,
and then for
that you want to find we'll
just call it you want to find
as without working too hard,
you want to find, pick the weak learner.
It gives you the lowest
weighted training error.
And then, what you're going to do is
whichever ones you made a mistake on,
you're going to raise their weights.
And then whichever ones you make
a mistake on using that current weak
learner, you're going to
raise their weights.
You could also alternatively lower
the weights of the other ones.
Typically, raise the weights of
the ones you've made a mistake on.
And then what you can do is you can
take these weak lay, learners and
you're going to combine them in a very
simple linear way to build your final
classifier.
So the question now becomes what
is a weak learner, all right?
Well it's simply a function
that partitions your space.
It doesn't always give the right answer,
but it gives you some information.
And the idea is you're
going to combine these.
So this is actually easier to
illustrate than to talk about,
regardless of how much I like to talk.
All right, so
let's develop our intuition.
All right,
let's suppose we have children, okay?
So as everybody knows, especially in
the American world somewhere around
the first of December, there are bad
children, and there are good children.
And somebody makes a list and
does something about it, I don't know,
whatever it is.
And suppose we want to a learn, a learn,
we want to figure out a classifier
that can classify children.
And maybe we've got two dimensions
that describe children.
You know, whether they put
their socks away and whether or
not they buy their parents presents.
And what we're trying to do is we're
trying to use these features to
discriminate between them.
So the first thing we do is we try to
pick a weak learner, and we say well,
how about this line right there, okay?
You know, what we'll say that
these are the bad children, and
these are the good children.
Okay, now of course,
that's not perfect, is it, right?
We have some errors here.
Okay, so the, the, the red is bad and
the blue is good by the way.
That's not meant to have any
military implications whatsoever.
So what we've drawn here is this
is our weak learner, right?
Our first level weak learner, and you
know, it does an okay job, all right?
So remember we said in each boosting
round we want to find the weak
learner that achieves lowest
weighted training error.
And then we're going to
raise the weights.
So what do we mean by
weighted training error?
Well here was the line that we drew.
This is a better version of that line,
but it has some errors, right?
And in particular, what we want to do
is increase the weights of the error.
So if we had said that the ones
above the line were bad or red, and
the ones below the line were blue or
good.
The, the blues that are actually
above the line, and
the reds that are below the line,
those are an error.
So, what do we do?
Well, now, we just do it again.
We have to find a new weak learner.
Well, how 'bout this one?
Okay, that's pretty good, actually.
Here's, it's called a weak classifier,
weak learner, same thing.
You can see that it
does a pretty good job.
In fact there
are no errors set over here if
this is the good side, all right?
And on the side that
it calls the bad side,
there are only these
two errors over there.
But in particular,
this nice big weighted one from
before has been classified correctly.
So that's our second weak learner or
weak classifier.
Increase the weights
of the mistakes there.
Say oh, okay now I need another one.
Well, how about this weak classifier.
Well, how many errors does that make?
Well, notice this particular one,
it's only got this bad one and
it's a small weighted error.
And the idea in boosting is that
you can take all of those learners,
those weak learners or weak classifiers.
And we're going to combine them in a way
in order to make a decision, all right?
So, in general, in boosting, you're
going to come up with a final classifier
that is a linear combination
of the weak learners.
And typically the weight is in some
sense proportional to how accurate it
is, a fixing the weighted error from
before, reducing that, all right?
There are a variety
methods of doing that, and
we're not going to go through
any of the exact formulations.
There's one of the schemes
is called AdaBoost.
And it's the one in fact that was used
in the algorithm I'm about to show you.
But there are lots of things and
you can go look up different ways of,
of running boosting.