So, we'll talk about the pros and
cons of SVMs.
I mentioned before that nobody
writes their own SVM code.
This is both good and bad.
We'll talk about why
it's bad in a minute.
But what's nice is their variety of
libraries, whatever language you happen
to use, everything from MATLAB
to higher speed languages.
And you can use that.
And because of your choice of kernels.
And then we can choose all sorts of,
it's a very flexible system.
So you can pull,
look at a variety of representations,
then given your representation,
a choice of kernels.
And then even then,
there's a bunch of parameters.
So, it's a very flexible,
way of doing things.
What's very nice is, after you do
the training, so the training,
you don't care how long
the training takes.
You can drink lattes all day
at Starbucks, all right?
But after the training,
you often come back with you only have
a modest number of support vectors, and
that means that at testing time,
it's going to be very fast.
You're taking your new value.
You compute the kernel function of
it in each of the support vectors,
sum up the weights, and
if it's greater than 0, it's a positive.
If it's less than 0, it's a negative.
All right.
And then the one,
the biggest pro is it just tends to
work extremely well in practice.
I will tell you that there
was a while that boosting,
remember the Viola-Jones thing?
Lots of people like the boosting.
It's clear, it's elegant.
You can understand what's going on.
My understanding is that for an awful
lot of systems, SVMs just beat boosting.
There are of course some cons to it.
Remember we said there's
no direct multi class.
You combine these two binary things
in sort of an unsatisfying way.
It's hard to know what
the right kernel is,
and it's dismaying to say which
kernel did you use, use this one.
Why?
Because it gave me the best results.
It, it's, it's very unsatisfying.
And yet we don't have a lot of the,
there is some theory but
not a lot of theory about why
you use some particular kernel.
I will tell you that the radio
basis function kernel.
The two kernels I see used more of,
actually three,
are exactly the ones we talked about.
Linear where you just have
a large feature vector and
you don't do any kernel trick at all.
because you're already in
a high dimensional space.
The Gaussian one which
essentially lets your surface,
move nicely near their support vectors.
And then this third one is this
histogram intersection kernel.
Because we have a lot of histograms
that are used as features.
Then I put down as a con that
nobody writes their own SVMs.
So that's both good and bad.
Good, there's a lot of libraries.
Bad is I've had students,
they're doing SVM and
they're getting certain behavior.
And all they can do is
tweak the parameters and
they don't have a good intuition for
what's going on underneath.
And part of that is that
they're using a package and
they're sort of at
the mercy of the package.
So it's good that they're
using a package, but you're,
but you lose a certain intuition
of to what's actually going on.
It is sort of very compute heavy
during training, all right?
You're basically computing a matrix
of kernel values between every pair,
all right?
So if you've got you know, tens of
thousands of training examples, right?
Let's suppose you had
10,000 training examples.
That's a matrix,
that's a 100 million big.
Now, you might not do it quite that way,
but the, in, in principle, you,
you have the entire pair-wise thing.
I guess the matrix is diagonal,
so you only need half of it.
That's fine.
So learning, the training and learning
part, that can take a long time for
our large scale problems.