All right so
we'll wind down a little bit.
>> Okay.
>> Don't look at the coded questions.
But, explain to me,
a time where you had like a technical
challenge, or like a big problem.
What was the problem?
And like how did you work through it?
How did you eventually solve it?
>> Okay.
Big technical challenge for
me recently, so
I've been learning some
back end stuff right.
>> Okay.
>> As well so
learning Python and backend.
So there was just learning how
servers work how databases work,
how to do it in Python using
certain web framework.
And i wantED to create a website that
basically just had a, You know,
just simple told website just be able to
figure out okay I want
to make a database.
I want to have a database
of pictures and
then i want to survey
I want make a point.
So the first thing i ask myself,
how do I make an API in place.
I know how to do in front end in
Ajax requests like okay I'll just
send off this request to a server and
I were to return your JSON.
But how do I actually return the JSON
in from the server side now?
>> The other side
>> The other
side of the picture
>> All right
>> So i had to like figure out,
okay does Python have a library so
i helped me write JSON, and it does.
So you know.
I'm okay great.
So if.
Maybe okay maybe if i can figure out,
you know, first of all.
Think about what's my input right like,
okay input just could be some sort of
parameter that the front end's
going to be hitting my server.
I need to unpack it.
Okay.
I have my corrie parameters.
But now how do i access my database and
like that was that was tough because
i was learning a new type of database
system so I had to like learn a lot of.
Look through a lot of stack overflow
look through a lot of forum posts.
Look through example code.
Make sure that I understand
okay how would I isolate this.
If i need to access this database
using this database system
because I'm using the Google App Engine.
>> Okay.
>> Basically and they recommend to use
their own data store system like okay,
well this basically like ORM,
like object relational mapping system.
That they have and it, yeah.
That was my first time using ORM.
>> Okay.
>> So, because i'm used
to running SQL commands.
>> Okay.
>> So I had to understand,
okay, if this object,
if I access is this object like I would
normally it would return the data to me.
>> Like that,
those could be confusing to me.
So it was a world that
was unfamiliar for me.
My first step was just
to look at tutorials,
look at videos and just try to figure
out ok what has our other people done.
Like to look at their example code and
just like really work at
that one aspect of like.
Okay I need to figure out
how to use this database and
then pulled its information.
Once I figure that out.
Okay i need to go back to my entire
project and figure out okay.
Once i get my data.
How do i transform it into a JSON?
Fortunately for me Python have
Dictionaries which is very similar
to JSON is so and i'm using The JSON
library, so the JSON library
will be able to convert,
>> Translate between.
>> Translate between the dictionary and
the JSON.
Okay, I got that, and my last thing, was
how do I tell the server to output JSON?
Because usually,
I would just output HTML.
That's how I learned.
That's the first thing I learned
was using service stuff so
I need to look around stack
overflow get my JSON.
Those are headers you need to like
write out to some headers and
tell them okay exactly the type
the content type that you were turning.
And there's a thing called
application slash Jason.
You need to change that header manually.
And then after that I have my
JSON library, which I could load.
I could refer to my dictionary,
because I got my data from a dictionary.
Then I convert that into JSON.
And then, from then on,
I just use the normal function to
actually write output to the server,
to the front end.
>> Yeah.
>> Which is just that converted JSON.
And then it worked.
So yeah, that was my whole story of
question how to figure out if i want to
do it that's all there is like all these
other days i had to figure out but.
On my own, step-by-step so
i always like trying to figure out okay.
Were the main steps i need to take.
How do i make sure that i unpack it?
And just focus on small little tasks,
once I had that then that task.
Those small tasks will build
a little book to like my project.