[Narrator] Let me ask you a second quiz.
Again, we haven't talked about any details.
I would like to get your intuition on the following question.
Suppose in a two dimensional space,
all data lies as follows.
This may be reminiscent of the question I
asked you for housing prices and square footage.
Suppose we have 2 axes, X1 and X2.
I'm going to ask you 2 questions here.
One is what is the dimensionality of this space
in which this data falls, and the second one
is an intuitive question which is
how many dimensions do you need
to represent this data to capture the essence,
and, again, this is not a clear crisp 0 or 1 type question,
but give me your best guess.
How many dimensions are intuitively needed?