So far, we've only considered the bivariant relationship between
price and carat weight. But there's much more to
this data set and I'd like to give it
a proper introduction. The diamonds data set ships with ggplot2
and contains the prices and the specs for more
than 50,000 diamonds collected in 2008 from diamondsc.info. Now,
analyzing this data is particularly useful. Because diamonds are
unique in a way that just isn't true of most
manufacture products that we're used to buying. You can't
just plug in the model number and just look up
the price. Though the diamonds data set is full
of prices and fairly esoteric certification ratings. Hidden in the
data are reflections of how a legendary marketing campaign
permeated and was subsumed by our culture. Hints about how
different social strata responded and how the diamond market
functions today as a result. The story starts in 1870.
When many tons of diamonds were discovered in South
Africa near the Orange River. Until then the diamond
market had been small, only a few pounds of
diamonds were mined each year from India and Brazil. At
the time, there was no use for diamonds outside
of jewelry, so price depended only on scarce supply. Hence,
the project's investors formed the De Beers Cartel in
1888, to try to control the global price of diamonds.
By most accounts, this has been the most
successful cartel in history. But World War I and
the Great Depression saw diamond sales plummet. In 1938,
the De Beers Cartel contacted Philadelphia ad agency N.W.
Ayer and Son to inquire whether, quote, The use
of propaganda in various forms Might help jump start
diamond sales in the U.S.. Which looked like the
only potentially viable market for diamonds at the time.
Surveys showed, however, that among couples contemplating marriage, diamonds
were low on the list of priorities. A luxury
for the rich, money down the drain. Frances Gerety
took on the DeBeers account at N.W. Ayer and
Son. And work towards the company's goal to quote,
create a situation in which every couple contemplating marriage
feels the need to acquire a diamond engagement rings.
A few years later, she would coin a famous slogan.