In the next set of lessons,
we will discuss in more detail
some of the key research management
components in operating systems.
First we will look at how the operating
system manages CPUs, and how it
decides how processes and their threads
will get to execute on those CPUs.
This is done by the scheduler.
We will review some of the basic
scheduling mechanisms,
some of the scheduling algorithms and
data structures that they use, and we
will look in more detail at some of the
scheduling algorithms used in the Linux
operating system, the completely fair
scheduler and the O(1) scheduler.
We will also look at certain aspects
of scheduling that are common for
multi-CPU platforms.
This includes multicore platforms and
also platforms with hardware
level multithreading.
For this we will use the paper
chip multithreaded processors
need a new operating system scheduler
in order to demonstrate some of
the more advanced features that
modern scheduler should incorporate.