The first thing we have to do is
define what's called optical flow or
optic flow.
Because what we're going to be
recovering today is the optic flow.
And the optic flow is the apparent
motion of objects or surfaces or pixels.
And the reason I say
apparent will be clear.
Here what we have is a Rubik's
cube looking device,
although here it's black and white, so
it's just a denuded Rubik's cube and
it's been placed on a turntable
that's been rotating around this way.
If you take a look at these little.
Patterns on the side,
you can see what the rotation is.
I'm pretty sure this was done by Rick
Zalesky because he's looked at these
gray codes to do the rotation.
Now what's a little bit hard to see is
that over here are these little arrows
that are showing you the motion.
And of course the motion is greater at
the front of the turntable than say,
on the cube, because it's closer to you
and it's rotating a further distance.
But you'll notice that there
are no arrows up here.
All right,
on the white part of the turntable.
Now, it's moving exactly the same way as
the part of the turntable that has the,
the markings on it.
But you can't see it.
There's no apparent motion, 'because
there's no contrast, there's no texture.
There's no indication that
the pattern is moving.
So, optic slow is recovering
the apparent motion.
Of objects or points or surfaces.
The actual motion, by the way,
is sometimes called the motion field.
We're not going to
talk about that today,
we're we'll talk about that not next
time, but time after, a little bit.
But what the underlying
physical motion is.
Today we're talking about
motion in the image.