So let's say we perform that search,
we had a big search tree, and
then we threw out all
the branches except one.
And this branch of the search tree
does itself have branches, but
this branch of the search tree,
through the belief state,
represents a single plan,
not multiple possible plans.
Now what I want to know is, for
the single plan,
what can we guarantee about it?
So, say we wanted to know is this
plan guaranteed to find the goal
in an unbounded number of steps?
And what do we need to guarantee that?
So it's an unbounded solution.
Do we need to guarantee that
some leaf node is a goal?
So for example,
here the plan it goes through and
at the bottom there's a leaf node.
Now if this were in problem solving,
then remember it would be a sequence
of steps with no branches in it.
And we know it's a solution if
the one leaf node is a goal.
But for these other branches, do we need
to guarantee that some leaf is a goal?
Or do we need to guarantee
that every leaf is a goal?
Or is there no possible guarantee
that will mean that for
sure we've got a solution, although
the solution maybe of unbounded length.
And I also want you to answer,
what does it take to guarantee
that we have a bounded solution?
That is a solution that is
guaranteed to reach the goal
in a bounded finite number of steps.
Do we need to have a plan that has
no branches in it, like this branch?
Or a plan that has no loops in it,
like this loop that goes
back to a previous state?
Or is there no guarantee that
we have a bounded solution?