In likelihood weighting, we're going to be collecting samples just like before,
but we're going to add a probabilistic weight to each sample.
Now, let's say we want to compute the probability of rain
given that the sprinklers are on, and the grass is wet.
We start as before.
We make a choice for Cloudy, and let's say that, again,
we choose Cloudy being positive.
Now we want to make a choice for Sprinkler,
but we're constrained to always choose Sprinkler being positive,
so we'll make that choice.
And we know we were dealing with Cloudy being positive,
so we're in this row, and we're forced to make the choice of Sprinkler being positive,
and that has a probability of only 0.1, so we'll put that 0.1 into the weight.
Next, we'll look at the Rain variable,
and here we're not constrained in any way, so we make a choice
according to the probability tables with Cloudy being positive.
And let's say that we choose the more popular choice, and Rain gets the positive value.
Now, we look at Wet Grass.
We're constrained to choose positive, and we know that the parents
are also positive, so we're dealing with this row here.
Since it's a constrained choice, we're going to add in or multiply in an additional weight,
and I want you to tell me what that weight should be.