Right now this application will
not do anything on order yet,
since it's just a standard Android app.
So we need to write a service
that implements media browsing.
So go into Java, and
in the package here,
right click New > Service > Service.
And let's call it
TestMusicBrowserService.
Leave all the defaults for
exporting and enabled selected.
Hit Enter to create the service.
This will add an entry to your
Android manifest.XML shown here.
We now need to modify the service
definition to mention that it is to be
used as a media browser service.
So we add this intent folder for
Android.media.browse.mediabrowserserv-
ice.
We're going to download some
music from the internet so
we need to request permission for
this in manifest file as well.
Now, let's open up the test music
browser service definition and
let's replace it with
the following code.
It's a bit long but we'll go through
it line by line so don't worry.
I also have to hit Alt+Enter a bunch
of times to import necessary packages.
Let's walk through the code and
discuss what it does.
Let's minimize the project window
here so we can see all the code.
Here is where we create
MediaMeta.objects that represent each of
the songs we want to play.
We can provide URLs and
they'll be fetched automatically for us.
You can set all kinds of information
such as song title, artist, and
duration which will be
shown on the display.
This creates the media player
which actually decodes and
plays back the MP3 file.
Here we create a media session.
Auto will use the media session object
to send playback commands requested
by the user to your app.
Here is where we'll create the callbacks
that'll execute when the user
makes a request.
This method searches for
a song in the music library by ID and
starts playing it.
This method is called when
the user presses the Play button.
And if we go in here,
if there's no song currently selected,
we'd pick the first one and
then start playing it.
If there's a song already active but
paused, then we could start playing it.
Down here, we also update the UI
to indicate we're in Play mode and
no longer paused.
If the paused button is pressed
we need to do the opposite and
stop the song from playing.
Now, we activate the media session.
And finally, we call the set session
token from the media browser service
class we inherit from.
This gives it the token
from the media session.
This token can be used later
to create a media controller
to interact with this session.
So, that's basically it.
Now, we have some helper methods to make
the above code a bit easier to read.
The buildState method builds up
a playback state object to tell the UI
what icons to show based on whether
we're stopped, paused and so forth.
We can also set the current
position in the song, but
we'll just hide code that
to keep things simple.
Here's some generic code that
we used many times above it.
It just starts playing a song
using the media player interface.
So we tell the media session
about the current playback state
which will update the UI buttons.
And here's where we copy over the meta
data for the song title, artist and
background art etc, and give it to
the media session to update the UI.
The reset method stops and
resets the media player.
Then we tell the media player
the URL of the song we want to play.
Now we schedule a call back to run
when the music has been buffered.
And is ready to be played.
And once that's ready
the onPrepared method is called and
we call the start method to
begin the playback of the music.
Once we have the onPrepared listener
created, we then tell media player to
schedule the playback,
which starts the buffering of the URL.
Then the onPrepared call back above.
And then start the playback
with mp.style.
The onGetRoot method is the first
method that Android auto calls into.
This method is responsible for returning
the root node of your media hierarchy.
It can also implement security
checks to help prevent other apps
from accruing your music.
In this case,
we're doing something super simple, so
this does nothing except returning
a simple root node automatically.
If you want to reject a request,
you'd return null here.
Once the remote app is coded onGetRoot,
it then uses that to
return a list of children.
This method needs to return that using
a result list of media item objects.
You can see here it is doing a full loop
over the array created at the side of
this code and building them up
into a list of media item objects.
You can implement tree structures, but
in this simple example
we're just doing two songs.
So that's everything the code
is now ready to run.