Let's discuss another collective.
It's called
the All-to-all Personalized Exchange.
In the business, you can just refer
to this as all-to-all, for short.
In an all-to-all,
every node wants to send a unique
message to every other node.
Now, this picture is not quite accurate,
because each node is just sort of
shouting a message to all other nodes.
But in fact,
in an all-to-all personalized exchange,
every node has a personal message
to send to every other node.
As an example,
consider a matrix transpose.
Start with a matrix,
initialize to some set of values.
A transpose rotates the elements.
More formally, every element A(i,j)
swaps positions with A(j,i).
Now suppose our initial
matrix A is distributed
column wise among several
nodes in a linear network.
So that might look like this.
After the transpose we want
the system to look like this.
So how do you implement it?
To make this a little easier to see
let's switch from a linear network
to a ring network.
And let's suppose that the size of
the data that every node wants to
send to every other node is m.
So each of these little
boxes is of size m and
the total length of a vector on
any node is n which is m times p.
Before I give you an algorithm I want
you to come up with a performance
target.
Start by considering one of these nodes,
and the P- 1 messages
that it wants to send.
So, let's start with node 0 and
let's look at the ith message
that it needs to send.
The ith message needs to go to node i.
So, how far away is that node?
I claim that that distance is min(i,
P- i).
Why?
On a ring,
the message could go either this way or
this way,
depending on which one is shorter.
Now, from this fact,
you can estimate the average
distance that a message must travel.
So, each of the messages from 1 to P-1
need to travel a distance of this.
We take the average over all messages.
For simplicity, this calculation
assumes that P-1 is even.
If you work it all out,
the average turns out to be P over 4.
So let's remember this handy fact.
Now all P nodes in the network
need to do these sends.
What's the total volume of traffic
that the network has to carry?
Well, it's the number of nodes
times the total volume per node for
all messages times the average
distance per message.
Here's another question,
how much bandwidth is available
to carry all of this traffic?
Well the total bandwidth is
the number of links in the network
times the speed per link, which is
just one over the inverse bandwidth.
Again we're setting
a performance target, so
we're making optimistic assumptions.
Now from these two facts,
we can estimate a lower bound
on the communication time.
It's just the total volume
divided by the total speed.
So now what we want to do is
write down an algorithm and
then compare that algorithm
to this lower bound.
Okay, let's talk about
a specific algorithm.
Here's an idea, which is to perform
a sequence of circular shifts.
Here's the initial state.
In the first step, each node will send m
times P-1 of it's data to its neighbor.
For example, node 0 will send
these words to the right.
What it is sending is all of
the data that needs to go somewhere.
So while node 0 is doing that, node
1 is doing basically the same thing.
It's packing up the data that needs
to go to other nodes and sending it.
Node 2 does the same thing.
It keeps the one piece of data
it's supposed to hang onto and
ships off everything else.
And so on.
Here's what the system will look
like at the end of this first step.
Compare this to our goal output.
So after one step,
you can see that every node has two of
the elements that it needs to retain.
So node 0 has a0 and e0, node 1 has
a1 and b1, node 2 has b2 and c2.
This is exactly what they
need in the final output.
So that means in the next step,
we could repeat the same process, again
retaining the data we're supposed to
keep and shipping off everything else.
So in step two, every node
would send m(P-2) of its data.
And this process will
repeat until we're done.
To analyze the cost of this algorithm,
let's consider some round.
Call it i.
In round i, a node sends m times
P-i of it's data to a neighbor.
So how much time does
this whole thing take.
First, the overall
scheme needs P-1 steps.
In each step i, nodes send m times
P-i words, so plug in our usual
per message cost model, then simplify
and finally enjoy your handiwork.
Now remember, our usual convention
is to let total size n be m times P.
So then this expression
becomes n over 2.
So notice that the bandwidth
term is now linear mP.
Compare that to this lower bound.
Hey, your algorithm seems pretty good.
It's within a factor of 2 of
our lower bound estimate.
Tofu the parting hypercube says oh yeah.
You know I 'm SCS no one
knows you're a tofu.