We just did something artistic with that
flower, so let's do something a little
bit more mathy and draw the Cantor
Gasket, also known as the Cantor Carpet.
To make the Cantor Gasket,
we take a square and
then consider it as a three by
three grid of smaller squares.
So there's nine squares total.
Then we remove the center square,
like so.
Now for the eight remaining squares,
we repeat this process,
punching out the center
of each of these squares.
Well, I'm freehanding this but
you get the idea.
Starting to look pretty cool right?
Let's do it one more time.
Now we're getting some
serious fractal action.
All right, I can't draw this any further
by hand, but you should be able to write
a program that can draw this
to a arbitrary level of depth.
This is going to be quite the challenge,
but give it a try.
Drawing with a recursion?
Super cool right?