In an ideal scenario, your classifier
will robustly detect vehicles and
record very few false positives.
However, in many cases, you'll find that
even though you are mostly detecting
cars, your classifier will return
a significant number of false positives.
Within the self-driving car industry, we
spend nearly as much time worrying about
false positives as we do
about real detections.
This is because when your algorithm
thinks it sees something that isn't
really there,
your car might end up swerving or
slamming on the brakes,
which can cause accidents.
As long as your classifier has a strong
preference for vehicles, you can filter
out the false positives by recording
the positions of all detections in
each frame, and comparing with
detections found in subsequent frames.
Where you find strong clusters of
detections you can conclude you have
found an actual car.
Whereas for
detections that appear in one frame and
not the next, you can assume
they were false positives.
If you're tracking a vehicles position
in a video stream, you will need to keep
in mind that a vehicle may change
direction, or speed up, or slow down.
So you need to let your tracking
algorithm be flexible enough to allow
for that.