You know what this code does, now it's
time to actually add it to your app, but
where?
Database operations are one of this
things that can take a pretty long time.
So in a similar way in how you make
network calls off the main thread you
should also be making your database
operation calls off the main thread.
There are many options for
how to do this.
But to keep things simple,you'll
be using an Async Task.
The query method will turn the close of
the object, which is exactly the type of
object returned by android
SQL like database class.
This cursor stores all of the data
that we're interested in.
It will be your responsibility to make
sure that the data from the cursor
is available in the main
activity of your app.
Go ahead now and follow along with
the tutorial to make an Async task