We'll now take a look at the various
components of Sun RPC using an example.
The client again will be contacting
a server that can perform calculations
except this time the client will
pass a single argument x for
which it will warn the server to
compute the squared value, x squared.
Here's the .x file for
this example with which the server
specifies its interface.
In the .x file, the server specifies
all the data types that are needed for
the arguments, or the results of
the procedures that it supports.
In this case, the server supports one
procedure, square underscore proc.
That has one argument of
the type square underscore in.
And the returns are resolved of
the type square underscore out.
The data type square in, and square out,
are both defined in the .x file.
If we take a look at them,
it turns out that both of them have
a single element and that's an int.
And in XDR an int, is an integer
just like the integers in C.
So it's a 32-bit integer.
Also note that this notation under
square_in, square_out is not any part of
the required syntax for specifying the
input and the output data types in XDR.
Other than the data types, the .x file
describes the actual RPC service and
all of the procedure it supports.
First there is the name
of the RPC service.
In our case that's square_prog.
And this is the name that will be used
by clients when they're trying to find
an appropriate service to bind with.
A single RPC server can support one or
more procedures.
For instance,
a calculator server can support all
sorts of arithmetic operations.
In our case, the square proc service
supports exactly one procedure and
that's square underscore proc,
procedure.
There is an ID number
that's associated with it.
This is one in this case.
This number is not
used by the programmer.
This will be used internally
by the RPC run time.
When it's trying to identify which
particular procedure is being called.
So it's not going to pass between the
client and the server in the packets.
The name SQUARE_PROC, instead it will
use this value 1 as a reference.
In addition to this ID number and
the input and
output data types, each procedure
is also identified by a version.
And in fact the version may apply to
an entire collection of procedures.
We see that in this case,
the version number for a service is 1.
Over time, however,
we may choose to refine
that SQUARE_PROC procedure or
add additional procedures.
And as we're doing that, we don't want
to be forced to immediately go ahead and
update all of the clients with this
perhaps semantically different or
syntactically different
square_proc procedure.
In that case, what makes sense is that
whenever clients and servers interact,
they reference the version number of
the procedure that they're requesting.
When a client contacts a server that
does not support a procedure with
the appropriate version number,
then the communication can be rejected.
What this also illustrates
is that it's possible for
a single server to support multiple
versions of the same procedure, and
this helps with, in general,
the evolution of the system.
We don't have to coordinate
an upgrade of all the servers and
all the clients at the exact same time.
Finally, the .x file also
specifies service ID.
This id is a number that's used by
the RPC runtime to differentiate among
the different services.
So the client will use things like
service name, and procedure name, and
the version number, whereas the RPC
runtime will refer to the service id,
the procedure id, and again,
it has to know the version id.
For the service ID, you're allowed
to specify a value in this range.
The remaining values for
service ID's either have some predefined
values like for instance, for
the network file system, or
they're reserved for future use.