For this quiz,
I'm giving you a sample DOM,
there's a body with a div
container underneath it.
And then a child div
underneath the container,
you can find a simple site with this
same DOM in the instructor notes below.
If you make changes to the geometry
of any of these elements,
the browser will have to run layout.
So, my question for you is, which of
these elements, well when changed
include more of their parent elements
in the scope of the resulting layout.
In other words, will changing
the geometry of any of these elements
trigger layout against most or
all of the page?
If so, which one triggers more?
You can use the sample site to find out,
clicking once
makes a change to the body, clicking
again makes a change the top level dev,
and the last click
changes the child dev.
If you're already familiar with
DevTools, you can record a timeline
trace to see what layout happened
after each click on this page.
If not that's no big deal,
you'll be learning how to use
the timeline next lesson, and i'll be
demonstrating how to find information
about layout in the solution video.
You can also check out the link
in the instructor notes for
a little bit more information.
So, do some analysis if you can,
but otherwise make a prediction.
Will changing the width of the body
trigger layout with a larger scope
than changing the width of this div,
or will they have the same scope?
Pick one of these answers.