For a third exercise, you'll probably
guess that we want you to open the third
exercise project, Add Scrolling.
And we're not going to let you down.
Go ahead and open the project, and
then navigate to the todo window.
This one is pretty straightforward.
You can see that our TextView contains
more toys than are visible on
the screen.
We want to place the TextView inside
of a ScrollView to fix that problem.
I'll click on the todo for
adding a ScrollView, and
then I'll complete the todo's.
First, I'll add a ScrollView
around the TextView.
Then, I'll make the width of
the ScrollView match_parent and
the height wrap_content.
Now, the list of toys
should scroll nicely.
Let's check out what that
looks like in the emulator.
Great, now it's your turn.
Add a ScrollView as the child of the
frame layout in the layout editor (using
either the visual tool or XML).
Set the height of the new
ScrollView to wrap_content and
the width to match_parent.
Move the existing tv_toy_names
textview inside of our scrollview.
And finally,
rejoice at the lovely scrolling we get.