There are lots of well known edge operators.
There's the so, Sobel.
Then Prewitt and Roberts which you can see does these different kinds of ways.
Matlab basically understands all of these.
And in fact, in Matlab there's this cool little function now called fspecial,
which will make filters for you depending upon the name that's in,
might be in the imfilter toolbox only or, or basic Matlab.
But the idea is that you can give it Gaussian, you can give it thing,
you can give it Sobel.
And if you give it Sobel,
what it'll do is it will reply back this operator, okay?
And in this case, by the way, turn everything into doubles in Matlab,
if I apply that to some image, all right?
So here's the double of my image,
I apply the filter, and then I display it, and I use a gray color map.
And you can see it gives me that gradient image, okay, and
that's the y gradient only.
It also will give you back the x gradient.