So here's a result.
And, you know, one of the interesting things is,
I mean, it looks pretty good, it's a good edge image.
But my very first computer vision courses from Berthold Horn,
who was one of the creators of computer vision.
And, you know, he expressed the concern that it's really hard to know when and
edge image is good.
Right?
Because the real question is what are you going to use those edges for?
So I'll just say that the canny edge operator gives us
better edges than other operators.
Meaning that they tend to pull out the edges that you would want for
future processing.
Now one question, of course, is since we're doing these smooth derivatives
is what size Gaussian kernel do we use in order to compute our edges?
And as we said before, the different sigmas, so here we have sigma one, sigma
two applied to this clown image, you can see what it does to the edge image.
Large sigmas detect large scale images, small ones detect small.
And the choice of sigma really depends upon the behavior that you want.