All right we finished coding
the Gaussian elimination algorithm.
Now we need to extract a system solution
from its reduced row-echelon form.
Given the system of equations,
you should use your previous function
to compute its rref and then use that
form to output one of three things.
The unique solution, perhaps as a vector
object, some indication that there is no
solution, or some indication that
there are infinitely many solutions.
For this quiz though, we won't try
to work out the parametrization of
the solution set,
if there are infinitely many solutions.
Once you are done, use your function
to solve the following systems.
If the system has a unique solution,
enter it in the appropriate answer boxes
with an accuracy of
three decimal places.
Otherwise, check the no solutions or
infinitely many solutions
box as appropriate.
The first system is 5.862x plus 1.178y
minus 10.366z equals negative 8.15.
And negative 2.931x minus 0.589y
plus 5.183z equals negative 4.075.
The second system is 8.631x plus 5.112y
minus 1.816z equals negative 5.113 and
4.315x plus 11.132y minus 5.27z
equals negative 6.775 and
negative 2.158x plus 3.01y minus
1.727z equals negative 0.831.
The third system is 5.262x plus 2.739y
minus 9.878z equals negative 3.441 and
5.111x plus 6.358y plus
7.638z equals negative 2.152 and
2.016x minus 9.924y minus
1.367z equals negative 9.278 and
2.167x minus 13.543y minus
18.883z equals negative 10.567.
[BLANK_AUDIO]