So I finished developing this
really great application.
And what I've noticed is every now and
then I'm getting in an ANR,
an application not responsive.
And I have no idea why that's happening.
Why do you think that could occur?
>> So there's lots of reasons
that this could happen.
Mostly from what I understand,
it's over, well,
okay Android Apps typically run on one
thread, and that is your UI thread.
If you don't declare anything else,
if you're just running all your methods
from on create something like that or
calling methods from there.
It's just running on one thread.
And if you're running in
a really intensive process, or
maybe making a network call or
something like that, if you don't get
a different area you could get the ANR.
Because you're
overloading on the thread.
>> Yeah.
So your theory is is that I
am sitting on top of the UI thread and
I'm blocking it for some reason.
I'm doing something intensive.
That makes sense.
And that's exactly why
it would create an ANR.
But it seems like my application so
far is behaving properly.
I don't know why it's triggering that.
So what other things could occur?
>> It could be related to user input
as well if it's been waiting for
some sort of input that it doesn't get,
or something like that.
That could cause it as well.
This I do believe.
And otherwise yeah, if it's like you
said it is just being blocked for
some reason by some process that it's
not going to necessarily be consistent.
>> Yeah.
So let's say in this application,
I can kind of tell you more about is,
it has kind of a background service so
as a user is,
maybe it fetches content eventually in
the back and maybe does a few things.
But I still can't figure
out why occasionally it's.
>> So are we talking about
like a network call or?
>> Yeah, so it's doing network calls.
>> Okay.
>> And it's doing them periodically.
>> Okay are they on schedules or does
it just sort of wait for user input for
those network calls or how does it work?
>> Let's say when the applications open,
it's doing a network call every
five minutes or something.
>> Okay so it's scheduled
to run every five minutes.
I suppose that,
depending on what content it's
trying to pull, could be an issue.
Maybe as the app is open longer
it's pulling more content.
And depends on what you're.
>> Well so I don't think it should be
an issue because I developed it as
a service, right?
So it's doing a network
call in the service.
>> So you're launching like an intense
service that should be using
[CROSSTALK]
>> It's
not an answering service
it's just a normal service.
>> So the idea of the service is that it
should be running on the background or
in the background on a different thread.
So it sounds like it could be that
you're doing background as maybe taking
little bait too long to run, or it's
taking a significant amount of time or
a significant amount of time
is going on before you call.
Well actually are you running a
broadcast receiver off of this service?
So when your service is done
do you send out a broadcast?
>> No I'm not doing that at all.
>> Are you calling on task complete
type thing where once your service
is done running, you call something
that's backed that's on the UI,
that's rendered on the UI thread,
or runs on the UI thread?
>> Yes, so I guess what I'm
trying to say is in the service,
it's just a generic extend service,
I'm doing that recall within there.
And I'm starting to isolate the problem
down to the service being the problem.
>> So
why do you think that could be an issue?
>> If I do it from an intense
everything works great.
But if I do it from a service
[CROSSTALK]
>> Okay.
Well, I would assume it's
just because your service
maybe is like directly calling that or
something.
It sounds like is not running
on a UI thread actually whereas
the intense service would be
running off the UI thread.
Sorry it's only the intense service
would be running off the UI thread
in the background, and it sounds like
that's not what's happening here,
it's doing some sort
of intensive service.
>> Yeah, so what are some of the
differences between, I think this comes
down to a difference between
an intense service and a service.
And so
in the intense service it runs okay.
I can run the network call and
it's completely fine.
But from the service it's blocking.
Why do you think that's different?
>> I'm not entirely sure.
Because I'm not too familiar
with the difference between
intense service and service.
>> Well, so for the service what
thread does the service run on?
>> I'm assuming it
runs on the UI thread.
>> Yeah, so the service runs on UI
thread, and intense service runs on.
>> The background thread.
>> Yeah,
some other thread executor respectively.
So that's probably where
the problems occurring right?
Because I'm running it on
the service thread and
which happens to be the UI thread and
so it's blocking.
>> Yes.
Yeah.
>> Yeah.