All right, you're done.
Let's talk about how I did this one.
First thing I did was added
the transition name to the detail icon.
In this case,
detail_icon_transition_name.
Of course, non translatable,
since there's no point in translating
something that's used by the system.
And I called it TN_DetailIcon.
Which isn't particularly important.
The next thing I did, and
this was specific to implementation.
But I suggested it so
some of you might have done it.
I added an attribute to
the ForecastFragment stylable
called sharedElementTransitions,
and it's a boolean fragment.
So, this way when I create the
ForecastFragment which I create in XML,
I can actually pass this as a parameter.
And that way I'll know whether to do
any shared element transitiony stuff
in the fragment.
All right, so
you can see I actually take advantage
of that attribute in activity_main.
And we only have to do this of course
for the non-tablet version because we
are only doing these transitions for
the non-tablet version.
And we set
sharedElementTransitions=true.
That's great, because now, my fragment
code can actually know that for
the phone version that I actually
want to execute this code for
postponing, etc.
Let's take a look at that fragment code.
So first of all,
I declare an mHoldForTransition flag.
And then, in uninflate, I set this flag,
based upon this stylable here.
Defaulting, of course, to false.
We actually use this,
sort of, in on load finished.
Remember, I actually want to
know when the RecyclerView
views are actually added.
So we use this view tree observer
here to find out when that happens.
So if we're in mHoldForTransition state.
Then, at that point once I see that
I have views in my view tree for
the RecyclerView, I can call support
start postponed enter transition.
Now not, it's actually pretty safe to
call support start postponed enter
transition in any case, because as you
can see I'm not even using the flag
in the case where there's no count.
It was kind of a impressive effort for
something that wasn't
particularly needed.
But there,
you can see that's how we're using
it in the case of ForecastFragment.
Now, for DetailFragment we do
something slightly different.
So, you can see I created a string
called DetailTransitionAnimation here
which is a string that is package
visible, inside of DetailActivity,
which of course only gets called
if we're not in two-pane mode,
if we're in phone mode.
We can add this argument for
the detail transition animation
to let our fragment know that
it's actually going to be executing
those shared element transitions.
So then, inside of DetailedFragment
we declare mTransitionAnimation here.
And then in onCreateView you can see
we're setting mTransitionAnimation.
Based upon that string being
set that we just created.
And then, the important
thing is an on-load finish.
We actually call support start
postponed enter transition.
One thing I should mention is where
we actually stop the transitioning
from stop the transition from happening.
That's really important.
So we want to stop it
as early as possible.
So we actually stop it inside
of detail activity right here,
supportPostponeEnterTransition.
And it's really,
really important that after we do this
we really start the transition up again.
Because we are now stuck in this state.
The system is waiting for
that to happen and we do a similar thing
inside of our MainActivity, so
we do this on ActivityCreated.
If we have mHoldForRransition, and
not ActivityCreated inside
of our Forecast Fragment,
we then stop the world to wait for
that transition to happen and
the only time this is actually important
is when we're transitioning back from.
Another activity, and
perhaps we've rotated the screen so
we've been destroyed.
So this'll give us a shot at actually
having that icon transition back
even though it's transitioning
into a brand new activity.
It's kind of cool and it works.
On the other things that I did,
which are probably worth mentioning is I
wanted to align up the animation better.
So I actually changed the duration of
these animations to 250 milliseconds,
which is a lot closer to what
the systems actually using for
these transitions, so it just lines
up all the animation really nicely.
And as I like to try to do,
let's run this in the emulator and
see what we get.
So here we are, as you can see
when we click on one these guys
we get a nice little animation.
And we can even rotate the device here.
And if we're lucky, it'll animate
back down, which is pretty cool.
Even though you're even off the screen,
it still sort of found it.
So that is activity
transition animations.
And it really is pretty
fun to play with.
Now, inside of our forecastAdapter we're
actually going to give that icon view
a transition name of its own.
And we're going to do
this based upon position.
And the reason why that's important
is all of these have to be unique
within the RecycleView.
This is the name that Android will
use when we return from the activity.
If you try to restore the animation.