Here are the answers I got.
For the first question,
I got 7.089 minus 7.230.
For the second question,
I got 15.342, 7.337.
For the last question, I got 12.382,
-7.499, -2.356.
I could have computed these
relatively easily by hand but
I'd like to go ahead and code functions
to compute sums, differences in scalar
products of vectors that way I
can use these functions later.
To fill in the plus function
I used a list comprehension
after zipping together
the coordinates of self and v.
This allows me to add
corresponding coordinates and
form a list from the sums.
If you're not familiar with
list comprehension in Python or
if you're using a different language you
could obtain the same result using a for
loop to loop through each of the two
vectors coordinate lists and
insert their sum into
another data structure.
We can mimic this pattern
in the minus function.
I again used a list comprehension.
But this time instead of adding,
I just subtracted the corresponding
coordinates of the vectors self and v.
Finally, in the time scalar function.
I again used a list comprehension
to compute the product
of each coordinate of the vector self,
with the number c.
One difference this time is, since I'm
only dealing with one vector in this
function, I didn't need to use
zip in the list comprehension.
Now if I execute this code
below the class definition,
I see the output of
the vectors as expected.