Let's try something that will
require a bit more problem solving.
Given some code that draws
a bunch of concentric rectangles,
could make some small changes so
it draws a spiral instead.
Open up the exercise project and
give it a try.
All right,
because this one's pretty tricky I'm
going to give some visual spoilers.
So I'm going to show you how to move
some line segments around here so
that these rectangles
instead turn into a spiral.
So all we're going to do is move this
little chunk of each rectangle so
that it faces this way instead.
So we're going to connect and
then erase, and
connect and erase,
connect and erase, and
erase, and now we've got a spiral.