Right so we're back in Android studio.
Let's make sure that our
phone is reconnected.
So we're going to go ahead and
type ADB devices once more.
Just to confirm that it's
back here in our list.
All right so now it's time for
the real fun.
Let's go ahead and
look at some battery statistics.
And the way we do that
is we run this command.
You type in ADB shell.
Dump Sis, which is stands for
dump service battery stats.
Let's go ahead and pipe that to a file.
Now the next thing we're going to
do is run the same command again,
however we're going to restrict
the data that it outputs.
By passing in the package name of
the application we're profiling.
Let's do it for sunshine.
All right, so with these commands
we've partially generated some
data that we're.
going to use.
Unfortunately the data in these
files aren't very readable.
So we're going to use the historian
Python script to extract the battery of
information and turn that into some HTML
that we can then view in the browser.
So this is how we do it.
All right, so let's go.
Go ahead and
invoke that Python script called
historian.py that we downloaded earlier.
That's the battery historian script.
So I'm going to type in
python historian.py.
Let's look at the sunshine file.
And let's generate a sunshine
battery stats HTML file.
Okay let's go ahead and
open this file in a browser.
All right, here we are looking
at the battery story and
output now as an HTML
file in our web browser.
Now there's a good amount of
information in this file.
Let's go ahead and
see what some of it is.
And what it might mean.
And at the top left,
you can see the file name and
some overall information
such as the battery level.
In this case, we're at 67%.
This can give you a quantitative
idea of battery drain over time.
As you see, this point here is
actually when our battery went down.
By 1% to 66.
All right, so if we scroll down a little
bit, towards the bottom here,
there's a timeline and a scale.
And then, the time in this table
runs from left to right, and
everything that is vertically
aligned happened at that same time.
Now you can see the scale here but
you can also adjust.
That zoom level right here.
Now, when you see these little
bars here that represent activity,
you can actually mouse over and
you can actually see
when this particular item started and
how long it's been active.
Now, what battery storage does not tell
you is how much battery was used for
each individual action, only how
often and how long it used battery.
But you can look at the battery level
over time to get a general sense of
the absolute battery drain.
Now the rows are pretty obvious from
their names so we're not going to
explain them right now, you'll get that
more deeper during the tools exercise.
Now you see these bars, and you can
actually mouse over each one of them.
To find out when it started and
how long it took.
Now battery storage does not tell
you how much battery was used by
each individual action.
Only how often and
how long it used battery, but
you can look at that overall battery
level over time to get a general sense.
Of absolute battery drain.
Now the rows here, they're pretty
obvious from their names, so
we're not going to explain
all of them right now.
We'll get deeper into
the tool during the exercise.
Check out this item here,
this one called screen.
Now, this represents how
often the screen is on.
In this case,
when I was interacting with the phone.
You could see that screen
was on the entire time.
We also have this section for top which
actually lists which application was
in the forefront at the time.
In this case, we've interacted
with Sunshine for a little bit and
then if we scroll to the right here,
this is when we hopped into Maps.
And this is actually when
we switched to YouTube.
Now what's neat about this file is we
see a lot of things additionally that
might impact the battery.
For example, we have stats of when WiFi
was one, in this case all the time.
Video playbacks seems to be happening.
You'll.
Notice the GPS started here.
And if we scroll up,
this is the time that we actually
hopped into the maps application.
So that would make sense that when
our maps application was started,
our GPS was turned on.
And this time the GPS was
using a bit of battery here.
We also see bursts of spikes
here in our WiFi strength.
And that's changing over time as well,
dynamically.
Now here's a more in depth example
output from a battery store and capture.
You can see that there's a very
large amount of mobile radio and
wave clockwork that's
occurring on this device.
It looks like away clock is turning
on running some networking work and
then going back to sleep over and
over again.
This level of behavior definitely
deserves a closer look to see if it's
using too much battery.
In the next section,
we'll use battery storing to find
out battery problems in our code.
Let's go ahead and do it.