[Thrun] This is a great segue to one of the most successful algorithms
in artificial intelligence and robotics called particle filters.
Again, the topic here is robot localization,
and here we're dealing with a real robot with actual sensor data.
The robot is lost in this building.
You can see different rooms, and you can see corridors,
and the robot is equipped with range sensors.
These are sound sensors that measure the range to nearby obstacles.
Its task is to figure out where it is.
The robot will move along the black line over here, but it doesn't know this.
It has no clue where it is.
It has to figure out where it is.
The key thing in particle filters is the representation of the belief.
Whereas before we had discrete worlds like our sun and rain example
or we had a histogram approach where we cut the space into small bins,
particle filters have a very different representation.
They represent the space by a collection of points or particles.
Each of these small dots over here is a hypothesis where the robot might be.
It's a concrete value of its X location and its Y location and its heading direction
in this environment.
So it's a vector of 3 values.
The sum or set of all those vectors together form the belief space.
So particle filters approximate a posterior
by many, many, many guesses,
and the density of those guesses represents the posterior probability
of being at a certain location.
To illustrate this, let me run the video.
You can see in a very short amount of time the range sensors,
even though they're very noisy, force the particles to collect in the corridor.
There's 2 symmetrical point dots--this one over here and this one over here--
that come from the fact that the corridor itself is symmetric.
But as the robot moves into the office, the symmetry is broken.
This office looks very different from this office over here,
and those particles die out.
What's happening here?
Intuitively speaking, each particle is a representation of a possible state,
and the more consistent the particle with the measurement,
the more the sonar measurement fits into the place where the particle says the robot is,
the more likely it is to survive.
This is the essence of particle filters.
Particle filters use many particles to represent a belief,
and they will let those particles survive in proportion to the measurement probability.
And the measurement probability here is nothing else but the consistency
of the sonar range measurements with the map of the environment
given the particle place.
Let me play this again.
Here's the maze. The robot is lost in space.
Again, you can see how within very few steps the particles
consistent with the range measurements all accumulate in the corridor.
As the robot hits the end of the corridor, only 2 particle clouds survive
due to the symmetry of the corridor, and the particles finally die out.
This algorithm is beautiful,
and you can implement it in less than 10 lines of program code.
So given all the difficulty of talking of probabilities and Bayes network
and hidden Markov models, you will now find a way
to implement one of the most amazing algorithms for filtering and state estimation
in less than 10 lines of C code.
Isn't that amazing?