Hey cool.
>> Hey what's going on man?
>> So I found this stack overflow post,
that says if I change the syntax of my
for loop, and use a pre-increment
over post-incrementor,
I'll get like a hundred x
performance on my for loops.
Pretty awesome yeah?
>> Mm, that's not a thing, Chris.
What do you mean?
That seems really useful all I need to
do is plus plus i versus i plus plus,
I mean, then I get a boost for
every loop I write.
>> Chris you should probably stop now,
I mean we are recording, it's,
it's not a thing.
>> Jeez.
That's kind of harsh if you know better,
why don't you show me then?
>> Let me check this out.
Okay, so here's the deal, you need to
remember that Java running on Android
is effectively executing in
a virtual machine environment,
which means there's lots and lots of
layers of complexity going on here,
from the precompiler to the compiler
to the optimizer to the code itself,
actually running on the device.
What you're identifying here
is something that we call
compute performance.
>> So, like,
the performance of my computer?
>> No, more like how the algorithms or
the computing processes are performing.
Which has everything to do with how
the compiler is generating the code and
how the virtual machine itself is
actually executing it on the hardware.
See, what this post has identified
was a very, very specific instance
where the compiler could make
a pre-fetching optimization on gigantic
four loops where a collection class
has more than 20,000 elements in it.
Effectively by changing
the syntax there for
your incrementer it was able to hint to
the compiler that this particular type
of optimization could actually be made.
>> Totally.
You know, I was hoping,
I could use it in general, though.
>> Well, see, it's not that easy
when you actually want to get
huge wins in computer performance
scenarios, it actually means
understanding what each piece of code
is actually doing on the hardware.
Which usually means, having to go and
make small little changes
throughout your entire code base,
just to get the performance wins
that you're actually looking for.
>> Jeez, that sounds like a lot of work,
I'm already exhausted.
>> Chris, my friend it's
the whole reason I'm bald.