>> We've got a simple
write example up and
running where we know that we're
creating one shopping list.
And that shopping list is stored as
JSON data in the Firebase database.
But that's only half of the story.
Let's see how we can get data
from the Firebase database and
display it in our app.
In the standard database model,
you might think of your data storage
as a resource to get data from.
If I wanted to display, say, the name
of a shopping list, I'd probably start
a different thread in the app that's
requesting the shopping list.
Something like an asynch task.
And I'd use this separate thread
to connect to the data storage and
ask it for
the data that I'm interested in.
Then, that thread would wait a bit and
the server would respond.
Finally, the app would then take the
response that it got from the database
and update the UI.
Now, if I expect this value to change,
I might regularly ping the data storage
to see if the value has changed.
And then, I'd wait.
And each time I'd wait a little bit and
the server would respond back to me.
And to make things a little bit simpler,
I could do this with something
like a sync adapter.
Now, this model of making a request,
waiting, and then receiving data and
putting into the UI is known
as the request response model.
The issue with this model is that,
because you're constantly pinging
the server, it can create a lot of
unnecessary network traffic and
be a bit annoying to manage.
Firebase takes a much
different approach.
Instead of constantly refreshing data,
you tell the server once let me know
if anything about this data changes.
Then, let's say,
something about the data does change.
Once Firebase gets the change it'll
send it out to all of the apps that
are connected to it.
And then, it's up to your app to
take this data and update the UI.
So, the Firebase steps are,
you set up a listener once and
then whenever the data changes you
receive the data and put it into the UI.
So, in Firebase data ping you.
So, what does this
look like in practice?
Here I have drawing of
a table in Firebase.
This is the root node.
It has children a and b.
And it has a children c,
which has some value.
B has a children d and e.
E has some value.
And d has one child f
which has some value.
Reading a Firebase database
is all about listeners.
Okay.
So, this is
my best attempt to represent a listener.
It is a drawing of an ear.
And the listener will be attached to
a specific node in your database.
And it will also be connected
back to the app itself.
And that's this first step
where we attach a listener.
When the data changes, this listener
will trigger part of your Android code.
It's a lot like how, if you press
a button, a on-click listener is called.
It's just the button press is
changing a piece of data somewhere.
When your Android code is triggered,
it's actually also passed an argument
which is the updated data
which was in Firebase.
You can then use this updated
data to change the UI.
In this way, you've got a connection
with some sort of data in Firebase
that'll immediately update
the UI whenever it changes.
I should mention that the listener
doesn't need to attach with the location
with a single piece of data.
It can actually be attached
to a location with multiple children,
like B here.
The location can even have grandchild.
And so on.
Then, if any part of this tree changes,
the listener here will be triggered.
So, if this value here changed to nine,
the listener here would trigger.
And it wouldn't just
send b back to the app.
It would sent b and
all of it's children, including d and
f, even though f and d did not change.
What's neat is that the Firebase SDK
deals with all of the threading and
all of the asynchronicity.
So, you'll notice that I
didn't make an async task.
I don't have sync adaptors.
Basically, the only things that I need
to worry about are choosing which data
to listen to, and
then providing a method that can
handle the data that comes
back from the listener.
Which will usually change something
that the user sees or experiences.
Okay.
So, here I am in my apps dashboard.
My data tree is right here.
It has a root node, and then one child,
listName, with one piece of data.
In this case,
I want to know when listName changes.
So, what URL location do you think that
we should be listening to for changes?
And when that location changes,
what should we do with the data?
Here's a box to enter the URL.
And here you can describe,
in your own words,
what you want to do when
the listener is triggered.