There are lots of sources of dirty data. Basically, anytime
humans are involved, there's going to be dirty data. This
is a lot like any time my kids are involved,
there's going to be mud tracked through the kitchen. There
are lots of ways in which we touch data we
work with. Let me get some hand sanitizer and then
we'll get started. So, we're going to have user entry errors.
In some situations, we won't have any data coding standards,
or where we do have standards they'll be poorly
applied, causing problems in the resulting data. We might
have to integrate data where different schemas have been
used for the same type of item. We'll have
legacy data systems, where data wasn't coded when disc
and memory constraints were much more restrictive than they
are now. Over time systems evolve. Needs change, and
data changes. Some of our data won't have the unique
identifiers it should. Other data will be lost in transformation from one
format to another. And then of course there's always programmer error. And
finally, data might have been corrupted in transmission or storage by cosmic
rays or other physical phenomenon. So hey, one that's not our fault.