hi my name is Andrew Trask and the PhD
student at the University of Oxford
studying deep learning from natural
language processing. Deep learning as i'm
sure you come to understand is a suite
of tools that allows us to take what we
know and predict we want to know using
their own networks natural language
processing is a study of human language
using tools such as machine learning in
this case deep learning. In this tutorial, we're
going to be learning about
sentiment classification, or classification of
whether or not a section of human
generated text is positive or negative
in this case we're taking what we know
which is a unit of text written by human and
predicting we don't know which is all we
want to know which is these two labels
our goal is going to be to training
neural network to make this prediction
What we're really going to be learning in
this course is about how to frame a
problem for a neural network
sentiment classification is a good example for
this because neural networks don't naturally
accept text as input. They accept numbers. So what
we're going to have to do is consider
what underlying patterns in the text we
want the neural network to be able to
discover and then convert our text into
a numerical form in such a way that that
pattern is well preserved and easily
discoverable in the neural network. You'll find that
the frameworks such as tensorflow or
torture you know many others are quite
good at automating the process of
backpropagation or choosing your error
measures or regularization or any kind
of suite of mechanical tools. However
sort of that the art of understanding
what's going on inside the neural net
and then framing the problem such a way
that your neural net can discover the
patterns of the most important pretty
much remains up to the scientists and
it's really really important when you're
actually helping the wild trying to
train his neural Nets. So, that's what this
course is going to be about. I'm already
going to assume you know everything
that's been provided to you in the
Udacity course so far. So, neural nets
stochastic gradient descent, mean squared
error and training testing splits. If you
need help along the way, just review
previous Udacity lectures, and if you
would like to have them explain
in a different form or in a textual form, you
also have recommended reading material
along with Udacity course called
Grokking Deep Learning, which is a book that i
wrote and my publisher, Manning
Publications is offering a forty to
fifty percent discount code in which I
will provide in the notebook accompanying
this course. And that discount is just for
Udacity students. So in this course we're
going to be tackling six different
projects. Now the first project is about
curating a dataset and developing kind
of predictive theory what we think is
going to work when the pattern we think
we want to be able to train our neural network
defined. Then what we're going to, in the
first project, validate this theory with
some simple statistics. The next steps
are going to simply be developing
neural networks and then iterating to
increase the amount of signal as it's
present and obvious to the neural network and
reduce the amount of noise that is present to
our neural networks
By iterating in this process, what
we're going to do is make it easier for
our neural network to discover the underlying
patterns that we think are most
important and we're going to evaluate
the quality of our network along the
way to see how they do. So that's for all that
we'll do. Let's jump in.