Okay, so first of all, open a simple
project with a single scene.
Now, let's add a few labels.
Later on we'll put
them into a stack view.
However, since stack
views are invisible,
let's give our labels different
backgrounds and font sizes.
Now, in order to put them into stack
view, first select the labels.
And then click on this button
on the auto layout bar.
And yes, I know that there are many
other mysterious buttons in here.
We'll get to them at the right time.
For now, let's just spec those labels.
Okay, so what on earth just happened?
All the sizes changed.
Is this a bug?
Did Auto Layout go crazy?
No.
Let's step back and
try to think what happens when you
add a bunch of views to a stack.
The first and last views are anchored
to the left and right side.
Both views are resized to
their intrinsic content view.
That's why their size is changed.
The rest are distributed
along the remaining space
according to the distribution algorithm
and the space property if present.
In the next video, we'll play around
with some of the properties of
stack view that allows us
to modify its behavior.