At this point we've defined all
of the transitions we need for
our state machine, but
now how do we control them?
This is where parameters kick in.
If we look at the top left
of our animator window,
you'll see there's a tab for
layers and parameters.
Let's click on parameters.
In short, a parameter is basically
a value that we can use to indicate
when a transition should occur.
If we click on the plus icon we'll
see that there are four types,
float, int, bool and trigger.
If you're familiar with coding float,
int, and
bool are all variable types and
they can all take on different values.
As a quick recap, floats represent
decimals, ints represent real numbers,
and bools represent the values true or
false.
Separate from those is the trigger which
is what we're interested in right now.
The trigger is like a bool in
that it's either true or false.
The core difference is that you set
a trigger to become active or true.
And once the transition occurs the
trigger is automatically deactivated, or
set to false.
In our scene we want to use the trigger
to switch between the clock hand
rotating clockwise versus
counter clockwise.
To do this let's hit the plus button and
select trigger, let's call it reverse.
Now we need to tell our
transitions to use the trigger
parameter that we just created.
Let's click on a transition and
then look up the inspector.
In the inspector we'll see
a section called conditions.
Lets go ahead and click the plus button.
When we do that it'll automatically
add our reverse trigger parameter
as a condition since we will
only have one parameter to find.
If we had more than one,
we could click this drop down to choose
which trigger we would want to use.
Let's also add the trigger
parameter to our other transition.
Now let's undock the animator so
that we can see our scene view, and
then hit play to run it.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We can now manually activate our trigger
to switch between our hand going in
the clockwise direction versus
the counterclockwise direction.
Now you might notice the transition
doesn't take effect immediately.
This is because on our transitions
unity defaults to waiting for
the animation to fully complete.
We can turn this off by
clicking on a transition and
disabling the has exit time.
Let's do that on both transitions.
And now if we do that we'll instantly
transition when we click the trigger.