Let me show you some simple examples of Arithmetic Blend Modes.
For example, I can do a divide, which lets me brighten photographs.
I can take two pixels of information from each one of them and
do some sort of division and then scale them up again.
I can do addition, and we've seen examples of this in
our lecture where I've taken two images and just added them together.
In this case, rather than looking at images from the values of zero to 255,
let's assume they're from zero to one.
And if I have two images over pixels with more than value one,
they'll all become white.
And in this simple addition we'll let that be the case so it,
of course, makes the image have too many whites.
Subtract is again something we've looked at.
And in this case again for
the range of zero to one, and we subtract, we get a lot of values below zero.
And of course we just replace them by zero, and
of course this image shows a lot of blacks.
A most important type, and
again we see an example of this is when we do a difference.
But we do subtract but whenever we get to zero we kind of do a scaling up
to make sure all of the range of values between zero and one are covered.
The more wildly used simple blend mode is that of darken which is
shown by this equation here.
Which basically takes the minimum of the pixel value from the top and
the bottom layers for each and every color channel, R, G, and B.
In essence, what darken does, it creates a new novel image
that creates basically represents each and every pixel that retains
the smallest component of the foreground and the background pixels.
Smallest meaning, of course, the darker.
And therefore of course it's referred to as darken.
It actually starts giving you more of the darker pixels that's a combination of
both and of course finds the lowest value between both of them.
On the other hand lighten does the opposite.
Where it basically takes the maximum value.
Basically it attempts to select the maximum of both the top and
the bottom layers in RGB and
showcases that and actually allows you to see a much more lighter image.
Again, I encourage you to try these types of things out on your own.