So, let's take a look at a, sort of,
a very simple definition of the problem
of optical flow or optic flow.
So, here, I have four points
conveniently color coded, so
you can tell their difference, and this
is their location x, y at some time, t.
But, they're all going to move, okay?
So, they're all going to move
in some direction, such that at.
T plus one,
they're at a different location.
And that's drawn here.
So the points move in
the direction of the arrow.
You don't actually get to see them
doing the movement between t and
t plus one because we only get
samples of t and t plus one.
But that's just showing
you how they move.
And in some sense, our goal is to
actually recover those arrows.
So the question we want to ask is, how
do we estimate pixel motion from image
I, x, y, of t, to image I of x,
y, t plus one?
We're trying to estimate that motion.
So, what we have to do
in order to estimate this pixel
motion is essentially solve
a different kind of correspondence
problem than we had from stereo.
Kind of, sort of related,
but somewhat different here because the
pixels can move how, however they want.
Given some pixel in Ixyt, so here's one,
here's one, here's one, here's one.
Look for nearby pixels of this
same color in xyt plus one.
Solving this problem is what's referred
to as the optic flow problem or
optical flow problem.
And in particular.
We're going to have
to look at two words.
One is this notion of nearby, and
we have to look at what we
mean by the same color.
What we want to do is we want to look
at these terms, nearby and same color,
a little more carefully.
So, we have two key assumptions.
This notion of the same color and
nearby.
This same color is referred
to here as color constancy.
And basically this says that a point
at xyt if we knew how it moved to some
point x prime y prime at t plus one
that point will be the same color.
Okay?
So, and if this is a monochrome image,
grayscale image,
then that point would
be the same brightness.
Okay?
And that's the color constancy or
brightness constancy.
Allright?
And then the second thing is that we're
going to to assume that these points
don't move very far from one time
to the next time, from t to t plus one.
And if you think that's because
we're going to do something in
the Taylor Universe,
you're absolutely right