The Firebase Security Rules are a
comprehensive set of rules that make it
easy for you to protect
files in Firebase Storage.
These rules can be accessed and
modified from the Firebase console.
You can find the rules under
the rules tab for storage.
It's very similar to the security
rules for the database.
Firebase Storage provides
a default security role and
this rule limits reading from and
writing to all pods and storage for
authenticated users,
just like the default database rule.
You will notice that the storage rules
look a little different than database
rules.
The syntax is a bit different from
the JSON base security rules for
the database.
Let's examine the components of
Firebase Storage Security Rules and
then see how they apply
to this default rule.
Every storage rule lives
under the first two blocks,
service firebase.storage indicates that
these rules are for Firebase Storage.
Match /b/ your Firebase storage bucket
/o matches the path specifically for
your particular Firebase project.
Every rule you'll add will
be under the second block
in the same level as the match
rule that's provided by default.
Rules are broken down into several
key parts, the match, the rule, and
the context.
In order to fully understand
Firebase Storage Security Rules
we will examine each of these parts in
detail and then put them all together.