In this new notation, instead of writing plans
as a linear sequence of, say, suck, move right, and suck,
I'm going to write them as a tree structure.
We start off in this belief state here,
which we'll diagram like this.
And then we do a suck action.
We end up in a new state.
And then we do a right action,
and now we have to observe the world,
and if we observe that we're still in state A,
we loop back to this part of the plan.
And if we observe that we're in B,
we go on and then execute the suck action.
And now we're at the end of the plan.
So, we see that there's a choice point here,
which we indicate with this sort of tie
to say we're following a straight line, but now we can branch.
There's a conditional, and we can either loop,
or we can continue on,
so we see that this finite representation
represents an infinite sequence of plans.
We could write it in a more sort of linear notation
as S, while we observe A,
do R, and then do S.
Now, what can we say about this plan?
Does this plan achieve the goal?
Well, what we can say is that if the stochasticity
is independent, that is, if sometimes it works
and sometimes it doesn't,
then with probability 1 in the limit,
this plan will, in fact, achieve the goal,
but we can't state any bounded number of steps
under which it's guaranteed to achieve the goal.
We can only say it's guaranteed at infinity.