It is now time to discuss
the experimental approach in
the Flash paper.
In the paper, the experiments are
designed so that they can make stronger
arguments about the contributions
that the authors claim about Flash.
And this is something that you
should always consider when
designing experiments.
That they should help you with the
arguments that you're trying to make.
To do this,
to achieve a good experimental design,
you need to answer
a number of questions.
For instance,
you should ask yourself, what is
it that you're actually comparing?
Are you comparing two
software implementations?
The hardware the same.
Are you comparing two
hardware platforms?
Make sure then the software is the same.
You need to outline the workloads
that will be used for evaluation.
What are the inputs in the system?
Are you going to be able to run data
that resembles what's seen in the real
world or are you going to
generate some synthetic traces?
These are all important
questions you need to resolve.
Not to forget the metrics, we talked
about them earlier in this lesson
is that execution time or
throughput or response time.
What is it that you care for and
who are you designing this system for?
Is it the manager?
Is it resource usage in the system?
Or is it ultimately the customer's?
So let's see now how these questions
were treated in the Flash paper.
Let's see what were the systems
that they were comparing,
what were the comparison points?
First they include a comparison
with a multiprocess version
of the same kind of Flash processing.
So a web server with the exact same
optimizations that were applied in Flash
however, in a multiprocess,
single-threaded configuration.
Then again, using the same optimizations
as Flash, they put together
a multithreaded web server that
follows the boss-worker model.
Then they compare Flash with
a Single Process Event-Driven model, so
this is like the basic event-driven
model that we discussed first.
And then they also use as a comparison,
two existing web server implementations.
One was a more research implementation
that followed the SPED model, however
it used two processes and this was to
deal with the blocking I/O situation.
And then another one was Apache and this
is the open-source Apache web server.
And this was at the time when this was
then an older version obviously than
what's available today and at the time
Apache was a multiprocess configuration.
Except for Apache, every single one
of these implementations integrated
some of the optimizations that
Flash already introduced.
And then, every single one
of these implementations
is compared against Flash.
So this basically means, is that
they're comparing the different models,
multiprocess, multithreaded
SPED against the AMPED,
the asymmetric multiprocess
event-driven model.
Given that all of these
really implement,
otherwise the exact same code
with the same optimizations.
Next let's see what are the workloads
they chose to use for the evaluations.
To define useful inputs,
they wanted workloads that represent
a realistic sequence of requests.
Because that's what will capture our
distribution of web page accesses.
But they wanted to be able to reproduce,
to repeat the experiment with
the same pattern of accesses.
Therefore, they used
a trace-based approach where they
gathered traces from real web servers.
And then they replayed those traces so
as to be able to repeat the experiment
with the different implementations.
So that every single one of the
implementations can be evaluated against
the same trace.
What they ended up with were two real
world traces, they were both gathered at
Rice University where the authors
are from, actually were from.
Some of them are no longer there.
The first one was the CS web trace, and
the second one was
the so-called Owlnet trace.
The CS trace represents
the Rice University Web Server for
the Computer Science Department.
And it includes a large number of files
and it doesn't really set in memory.
The Owlnet trace,
that one was from a web server that
hosted the number of student webpages.
And it was much smaller, so
would typically fit in
the memory of common server.
In addition to these two traces,
they also use the synthetic
workload generator.
And with the synthetic
workload generator,
as opposed to replaying these traces of
real world page access distributions.
They would perform some best or
worst type of analysis,
or run some what if questions.
Like what if the distribution of the web
pages accesses had a certain pattern,
would something change
about their observations?
And finally, let's look at what are the
relevant metrics that the authors picked
in order to perform their comparisons.
First, when we talk about web servers,
a common metric is clearly bandwidth.
So what is the total amount of useful
bytes or the bytes transferred from
files, over the time that it
took to make that transfer?
And the unit is clearly
bytes per second,
megabytes per second and similar.
Second, because they were
particularly concerned with
Flash's ability to deal
with concurrent processing.
They wanted to see the impact
on connection rate as a metric.
And that was defined
as the total number of
client connections that
are serviced over a period of time.
Both of these metrics were evaluated
as a function of the file size, so
the understanding they
were trying to gain was.
How does the workload property
of requests that are made for
different file sizes impact
either one of these metrics?
The intuition is that
with a larger file size,
the connection cost can be ammortize.
And that you can at the same
time push out more bytes, so
you can basically obtain
higher bandwidth.
However, at the same
time the larger the file,
the more work that the server will
have to do for each connection.
Because it will have to read and send
out more bytes from that larger file.
So that will potentially negatively
impact the connection rate.
So this is why they chose that file
size was a useful parameter to vary.
And then understand it's
impact on these metrics for
the different implementations.