So some user interactions need 60 frames
a second, but so do transitions and
animations, like card expansions or
menu sliding in.
Those need to be at 60 frames a second,
too, which isn't always simple.
It's so easy to accidentally
trigger performance issues,
unless you're very careful about which
properties you animate and when.
There are many ways to
tackle animations, and
it completely depends on your project.
I'll give you an example
of one approach I've used.
Feel like I'm kind of getting into
one weird trick territory here, but
seriously this one actually works.
For the 2014
Chrome Dev Summit web sites,
I wanted to animate these cards like so.
I couldn't expand the cards fast enough
to maintain 60 frames a second, so
I had to try something a bit different.
I tried working backwards.
I call my strategy FLIP.
First, last, invert, play.
I took advantage of the fact that once
the browser had done the initial hard
work to run the animation once, I could
run it backwards at very little cost.
It's like pre-calculating
the expensive work.
My code took the start point of a card,
and then it took the end point
when the card was expanded.
So let's say the card was about
here when it started, and
the icon was like that.
The title there.
Using getBoundingClientRect,
I measured all the elements'
positions before and after.
That then meant I knew how far
everything needed to move on the page,
and if it's opacity changed,
I also knew that as well.
So back here again.
First, that's where the card starts.
Last is where the card finished.
Now we need to talk about inverting.
I use the information from first and
last to apply transform and
opacity changes to
reverse the animation.
With a little bit of
extra work with clipping,
it was like the card had never moved.
So, now we've inverted the animation.
We can just simply play it,
and it looks like that.