So, we just encountered our very first Bayes network
and did a number of interesting calculations.
Let's now talk about Bayes Rule and look into more complex Bayes networks.
I will look at Bayes Rule again and make an observation
that is really non-trivial.
Here is Bayes Rule, and in practice, what we find is
this term here is relatively easy to compute.
It's just a product, whereas this term is really hard to compute.
However, this term over here does not depend on what we assume for variable A.
It's just the function of B.
So, suppose for a moment we also care about the complementary event of not A
given B, for which Bayes Rule unfolds as follows.
Then we find that the normalizer, P(B), is identical,
whether we assume A on the left side or not A on the left side.
We also know from prior work that P(A) given B plus
P of not A given B must be one because these are 2 complementary events.
That allows us to compute Bayes Rule very differently
by basically ignoring the normalizer, so here's how it goes.
We compute P(A) given B--and I want to call this prime,
because it's not a real probability--to be just P(B) given A times P(A),
which is the normalizer, so the denominator of the expression over here.
We do the same thing with not A.
So, in both cases, we compute the posterior probability non-normalized
by omitting the normalizer B.
And then we can recover the original probabilities by normalizing
based on those values over here, so the probability of A given B,
the actual probability, is a normalizer, eta,
times this non-normalized form over here.
The same is true for the negation of A over here.
And eta is just the normalizer that results by adding these 2 values over here together
as shown over here, and dividing them for one.
So, take a look at this for a moment.
What we've done is we deferred the calculation of the normalizer over here
by computing pseudo probabilities that are non-normalized.
This made the calculation much easier, and when we were done with everything,
we just folded it back into the normalizer based on the resulting
pseudo probabilities and got the correct answer.