Now we've covered a lot of work
on fading and blending in images.
Here's an example of how we can
basically apply this to video.
Here I'm going to show a cut and
then I'm going to show where it fades.
And then of course,
we're going to do morphing and
feathering to kind of clean it up.
So you notice this again,
I'm just looping over this.
But if you do a cut,
you kind of see a much sudden jerk.
In case of fade, you should be
seeing a little bit of gho,
ghosting artifacts between the frames.
And then of course,
when you do morphing and
these types of things with cuts,
you get a much better.
So, in essence here, we kind of start
modeling all of the different types of
things with morphing and
warping kinds of stuff with
a little bit of feathering.
So this is the morph here and
you can see much cleaner
transitions between all of them.
Again something we can actually to much
better as we know more about the images
and how we can actually do all
the processing in-between all of them.
Again, please see the paper for
to here for
more details on how we
can do all of this.
Couple of other things to notice here
is the original video of, of course,
it stopped.
Here I can actually make the original
video be infinitely long.
Here we just do a single fade.
Of course,
there's a little bit of blurriness here.
Of course, we do multiple fades,
which basically kind of merges it.
And here the water gets
a little bit more blurrier.
This one is less blurry, because
we're just doing very single fades.
There's another bit of work that I
actually refer to in this paper,
in this presentation that
actually improves and
makes this completely crisp, which is
called the Graph, Textures Method.