So far, we've seen how to send data
from Tag Manager to Analytics,
so it shows up as a screen view.
But what if you want to
track specific events?
In that case, create a tag, and
set the tracking type to Event.
Each of these fields corresponds to
a parameter you can set in your code,
when you send an event hit
directly to Analytics.
Here's an example of code from our app,
where we sent an event hit to Analytics.
You see that the code sets the Category,
Action, Label.
Now, the Value must be an int, and
we didn't set a value in this case.
So go ahead and add the code,
to send an event, every time anyone
clicks the Show Daily Special button.
Previously, we just
sent a screen view hit.
This time, send an event hit and
set the label to food preference.
So you don't need to create new
triggers or change your code.
And then, as always,
don't forget to publish your changes.
Start and stop your app and try it out.
If your phone's connected
to Android Studio,
you can look in the logs to
see if the hits get sent.
And for event hits,
you should see the parameters ec and
in our case, in my case, I set it to
button clicks, but this is a category.
A-n is the application name, language.
And in this case, t,
which is the hit type, is event.
E-a is the action,
I set mine to Show Daily Special.
And el is the label, so when this got
sent, the food preference was fish.
And check for
activity in the real time screen.