I'll be going over these
answers pretty quickly, but
we're going to go into more detail
about if else statements after that.
For this code snippet in
the weatherActivity.java file,
we create a boolean that's called
isRaining and we initialize it to false.
Then we go to the next line of code,
which prints out a log statement
that says, thank you for
using the weather weather app.
Then we have an if else statement.
If the isRaining boolean is true,
then we should run the code in between
these opening and closing braces.
Otherwise if the isRaining
boolean is false,
then we should do the code inside
these opening and closing braces.
Since isRaining is actually false,
as shown up here,
then we skip this if condition and
go all the way down to this else case.
Within this else block of code,
we have one log message that
prints It's unlikely to rain.
Reading through all of this code,
it should say, Thank you for
using the whetherweather App.
And then it should skip down to here and
say, It's unlikely to rain.
That leads us to answer C.
Continue on for more practice.