So what I'd like to do is kind of talk
you through the process by which we
could show that these different metrics,
at least these three metrics that I was
claiming are equivalent,
can be reduced to each other.
That if we have a solution to one,
we can use it to solve the others.
So the first step of this that I
want to show is that, if we have
an algorithm that can find the best arm,
or lets say the epsilon best arm,
with high probability in some
bounded number of pulls,
then we can use that to build an
algorithm, that will have low mistakes.
And by low mistakes, I mean the number
of trials at which it pulls
a non epsilon prime close arm is small,
is bounded.
>> Okay, so by low mistakes,
you mean few mistakes?
>> Low mistakes, I mean few mistakes.
I can change it to few mistakes.
>> Yeah, that's your choice.
>> That's just one of my many mistakes.
So we want to construct an algorithm
that if we give it epsilon prime and
delta prime, that it can choose a tau
prime K epsilon prime delta prime,
that is going to choose an epsilon
prime close arm on all pulls except for
this bounded number, this tau prime
number, with high probability.
And all we've got to work with
is this first algorithm that
finds the epsilon best arm in
tau K epsilon delta pulls.
So what we have to do is to find,
if we had that algorithm,
what epsilon do we give it, what delta
do we give it, and how do we use it so
we have this guarantee?
>> Wait, why can't you just use the
original algorithm to find the epsilon
best one, and
now you can do an epsilon close arm?
>> Okay, so we are going to
set epsilon to epsilon prime.
Delta to delta prime.
Then we're going to run algorithm A and
what do we do?
So, after tau K, epsilon, delta,
pulls, we know an epsilon or
epsilon prime nearly optimal arm.
And we just pull it then forever, right?
>> Yeah.
>> And how many mistakes do we make?
>> From which point?
Once we've chosen the epsilon prime arm.
>> Well, no.
In the whole run, right?
because the idea is that
we have the bound the total
number of mistakes that are made.
So the total number of mistakes,
this tau prime is equal to what?
>> Well whatever number of
mistakes algorithm A would have
made in finding it.
>> We have a bound for the number of
steps before we have identified, or
before this algorithm is
going to find a near optimal arm.
>> Oh, I guess it's in fact tao.
>> Yeah.
So
we just run the original algorithm
until it finds a best arm and
we pull it there after.
The maximum number of mistakes it will
make is exactly the number of steps that
it took to identify that arm.
It may be that on some of those trials
it actually was taking the best arm, but
this is just a nice upper bound.
>> You don't have to worry about
the mistakes that I'm going to make at
that point on?
>> No, because we're not going to make
any more because with high probability,
we found an epsilon close arm.
So with high probability,
we'll never make another mistake.
Now there's some probability
that it fails, but
that probability will match across
these two problems, so it's okay.
>> Right.
So the mistake is having pulled the
wrong, a non-epsilon prime close arm.
>> Yes.
>> Not some other notion of the state.
>> Exactly so, right.
So we'll say that a mistake means we
pulled an arm that wasn't very close
to optimal.
>> Right.
>> And so we just whittled down
the total number of
mistakes that we make.
>> Okay.
Well yes,
that was pretty straight forward.
>> Good, that was an easy one.