Just like when you start a new job or
you sign a lease,
the contract is what both sides
agree on before they move forward.
In Android, it's important to define
in the very beginning what your
database design would look like.
So that when you're writing the code for
your app, you can always
use the contract to tell you any
information you need about the database.
More specifically, the contract in
Android is a clause that defines
the tables and the colons for each table
that are included in the database.
A good way to organize the contract
clause, is to put the definitions that
relate generally to the whole database
directly in the contract clause.
And then create an inner clause for each
table, and then includes the colons for
each of those tables
inside that inner clause.
Here's an example contract,
from the Android developer's website.
It's supposed to define a database for
a feed reader.
It only includes one in our clause,
called FeedEntry, which itself includes
the constants, defining the table name
and the names of each of its columns.
Notice that the constructor here
has been declared to be private.
You should never need to create
an instance of the contract class,
because the contract is
simply just a class filled,
with DB related constants
that are all static.
So, it make sense to make
the constructor private.
Also notice that our
feed entry interclause,
is implementing
the interface base columns.
The base columns interface,
automatically includes
a constant representing
the primary key field called _ID.
Some android adapters will expect your
contract to have this constant defined.
It's not always required to implement
base columns interface, but
that can help your database fit in
better with the Android framework.
>> Great, now that you know what
a contract should look like,
let's create one of our own for
the wait list toy app.
Make sure you try and
write the code changes yourself,
after watching these videos.
All of the changes that you need
to do are marked as to-do's
inside the exercise code.
>> But before we dive into coding,
let's spend some time mapping out
what our table should look like.
We need to store the guest's name,
number of those in the party, and
the timestamp in which each
guest was added to the database.
So that we can display them in order.
Finally, we need a unique identifier for
reach row, to be able to delete
particular rows when needed.
That looks neat, and
everything we need seems to fit in one
table, which makes things a lot simpler.
So let's start coding.
This is the first exercise
titled Created Contract.
Open up WaitlistContract, and
inside the WaitlistContract class create
an inner class called WaitlistEntry that
implements the BaseColumns interface.
And inside that inter
class waitlistEntry
create a static final string
to finding the table's name.
Let's call our table waitlist, and then
after that create a static final string
for each of the columns, in the waitlist
table representing the guestsName,
the partySize and the timeStamp.
Notice that we didn't need to
create a string for the Id,
because that's what the base columns
interface already does for us, remember?
>> Perfect that looks
like a solid contract.
I'm sure both bodies
will be happy to sign.
Next, we'll be creating
the actual database,
that complies with this contract.
But before we go there,
try to complete this exercise yourself.
And to verify that everything
works after you're done,
we've created some unit test for you.
If you are not sure
how to run unit tests,
check out the next
video in how to do so.