Well, let's first look at gender.
If we split them by gender, then
the females downloaded Pokemon Go and
WhatsApp and the males downloaded
Pokemon Go and Snapchat.
So, there's not much of a split there.
But if we look at age,
we realize that everybody under 20
year old downloaded Pokemon Go.
And everybody who is 20 or older didn't.
This is a nice split.
So the feature that best
splits the data is age.
Therefore, if you said age,
that is correct.
So what we'll do is we
add a question here.
The question is,
are you younger than 20?
If you are,
then we'll recommend Pokemon Go to you.
If not, then we'll see.
If you're 20 older,
then we'll look at the gender.
It seems that if you are a female,
then you downloaded WhatsApp.
And if you are a male,
you downloaded Snapchat.
So we add another question here.
Which is, are you female or male?
If you're a female,
then we recommend you WhatsApp.
And if you're a male,
then we recommend you Snapchat.
What we end up here,
is with a Decision Tree.
The decisions are given by
the questions we asked.
And this Decision Tree
was built with this data.
And now, whenever we have a new user, we
can put them through this Decision Tree.
And recommend them whatever app
the tree suggests to recommend.
If it's a person under 20,
we recommend them Pokemon Go.
If it's a person who is 20 or
older, then we check the gender.
If it's a female,
then we recommend her WhatsApp.
And if it's a male,
then we recommend him Snapchat.
Obviously, there won't always be
a tree that perfectly fits our data.
But in this class, we're going to
learn an algorithm which will help
us find the best fitting
tree to a table of data.