So, let's recap the major changes
we just made to the Miwok app.
We changed from using a loop to
populate a vertical Linear Layout,
to display a list of words,
to using a more efficient ListView
+ ArrayAdapter combination.
And then we build a list item layout
that contains two text views.
So next we wanted to create a single
list of objects that we could pass
the array adapter so
we created a custom word class.
That contains both the English and
Miwok translations for a single word.
With that we could have an array list
of word objects they would pass to
an array adapter.
Now, let's navigate to
the numbers activity.
Here will need to change our array list
of strings into an array list of words.
So, we need to update the generic type
parameter, what's in between those
brackets in creating an array list
where each element is a word object.
So when you type in a word here, you
might get two autocomplete suggestions.
And this is because the word class
already exists in the Android framework
under a different package name.
So here,
you'll see it's under a user dictionary.
So these are words that you can add
to your auto complete dictionary
say when you're messaging your friends.
So be sure to pick the correct
option for the word class.
We want the one that's in our
package com.example.android.miwok.
So now we've updated our
ArrayList to contain word objects
instead of string objects.
So remember that I specifying word
as a parameter of the ArrayList.
This means that when we add elements
to the list we will need to add
objects of data type word and
if we were to say call the get method
which is used for getting elements
at a specific position on the list we'll
receive an object with a data type word.
So currently all these and methods or
adding a single string object
to the words list each time and that's
why we're getting all these errors.
So we need to update each of these
lines to pass in a single word object.
So let's just focus on
this first element here.
So I want to comment out, so below it,
I'm going to write in the version of
the code where we're adding in a new
word object to the word's list.
This is the typical
way to go about this.
We would have created a new Word object,
stored it in a variable here called w,
and then added that
variable to our words list.
So now here then we're
creating our new Word object,
we're passing in two inputs
into the constructor.
So the English and Miwok words.
So since we only need to reference
this w variable once here
there's actually a more concise way
to write these two lines of code.
So this method of creating a word object
and adding it to list does work, but
there's actually a more
concise way to do it.
So you notice here that we
only reference this variable
w once, down here.
So we can go ahead and actually cut out
this substantiation of the word object
and paste it directly
into the add method.
So doing it this way we don't need this
extra step up here to create a new
object on a separate line of code and
then store into a temporary variable.
So, we can actually go ahead and
just remove this line completely and
said we've directly added our
new Word object into the list.
So, to summarize the input into
this list is a new Word object
which is created in line.
By using the new keyword.
I'm going to go ahead and
finish populating the ArrayList
with the word objects.
All right when your are done
this is what the code for
creating an ArrayList of
words should look like.
So let's move down here to where
we're passing our ArrayList
into the adapter now.
So we'll need to update this Jeric
type from string to be words.
And this change reflects that
the ArrayAdapter now contains a list of
words as its data source
instead of strings.
We'll also need to update the layout
resource to be our new list item layout.
So instead of this we'll
have R.layout.list_item.
All right so there's no errors in the
code now, so I'm going to go ahead and
run the app on my device.
All right so here's the emulator
running this version of the app.
Let"s navigate into
the numbers activity.
That just crashed.
I wonder what happen.
Let's check out the android monitor and
check out the android logs.
On the very top of
the log message we see
here that it says
java.lang.illegalstateexception.
ArrayAdapter requires the resource
ID to be a text view.
I'm not exactly sure
what this error means.
So I'm going to have to go
into the documentation.
And see if I can find any clues.
Here's the developer documentation for
the array adapter.
So let's read through
the class overview.
Alternatively you can also
pause the video here.
If you want to read through it yourself.
So what I've learned from
these couple paragraphs.
Is by default the class expects
that the provided resource ID
references a single text view.
Well that's probably why
the list item layout
from the Android
framework itself worked.
Because the whole layout just
consisted of a single text view.
And here in this next paragraph.
We see that we can also add lists or
arrays of custom objects.
So that's perfect for us to help
display our custom word objects.
Now all this makes sense,
because remember that the ArrayAdapter,
uses generics.
Which means that we can substitute any
object data type in here for this T.
Now moving down to the third paragraph.
In order to display more
complicated list items that contain
more than a single text view,
we'll need to override and
provide our own implementation
of the getView method.
So ListView, calls the adapters,
getView method.
>> When it needs a new
view on the screen.
And one of the input arguments into
the method is the desired element of
the list.
So in this case we have
positions 0 that we need.
Knowing this information, the adapter
returns a view to the list view
that's populated with
the information from the position 0.
So think of the relationship between
the ListView and getView similar to what
happens between a surgeon and a surgical
technician in an operating room.
So in this analogy the surgical
technician like the getView
hands the surgeon the ListView
the correct instrument or
the correct view when the time comes.
So the ListView of surgeon requests for
the view or
the scissors in this case the getView
gets what's needed the view or
in this case the scissors and
passes it to the surgeon.
So by default the ArrayAdapter after
class expects that i'll be populating
a single text view.
So because the list item layout that
we will be populating is more complex.
So, it has two text views and
eventually it will have an image view.
We need to override the get view
method with our own custom behavior.
In order to do this, we need to
subclass the ArrayAdapter class.
So, to elaborate this means we
need to create a new Java class.
So we'll call it the WordAdapter class.
And he's extend the ArrayAdapter class.
So I'll show you how
to get that done now.
So it's not a get over
here to the project view.
So I click the package,
right-click, New and Java Class.
So we wana name this file WordAdapter.
We'll need to modify this autogenerated
file from Android Studio.
We want this class declaration to
specify that the WordAdapter extends or
inherits behavior from
the ArrayAdapter class.
Now to show the available methods to
overwrite from the ArrayAdapter class
our cursor will have to be
between these two brackets.
We'll hit Code, and
then Overwrite Methods.
Alternatively, your keyboard
shortcut is Ctrl+O.
Now in this list here go down and
find getView and then click Enter.
All right so this method gets
auto generated by default.
Now I'm going to take a step back and
let you finish the steps that are needed
to make this app display
the list of vocabulary words for
the numbers activity.
So, the steps,
will include finishing them
implementation of the getView method.
When you're done with this entire
quiz the app should like this.
Each list item should
display a new app word.
On top of the English translation for
that word.
Now, to help verify you're on track.
I'm going to provide you
with some code changes
that are needed in the numbers activity.
So, instead of the ArrayAdapter
we'll be using an WordAdapter.
The constructor for the WordAdapter
class takes in two inputs, so
just the context and this list of words.
And then also remember to update
the adapter variable down here.
Now make sure you WordAdapter
class works with these number
activity changes.
Otherwise you need to go back and fix
your WordAdapter class now I know this
coding exercise will be a bit of
a challenge because you've never created
a custom ArrayAdapter before or
even overwritten the getView method.
This task involves many steps but I
think you're definitely ready for this.
Now just be patient with yourself
because this task will require
a bit of time.
Now I want to give you one
more hint before you head off.
Here is an example app which
handles a similar use case to ours.
So this project is hosted in
a platform called GitHub and
it's an open source project.
So that means the code is available for
anyone to look at.
So as a note there's different
licensing for each open source project.
So be sure to check out
the license limitations
on whether the code can be modified or
distributed again for
different open source
projects that you find.
So this app in particular
was created by Udacity.
So you're free to use and
adapt to it as you wish.
To give you another hint,
I'll point you to an example app
which handles a similar use case.
So this project here is hosted on
GitHub as an open source project and
this means that the code as available
for anyone to take a look at.
So note that there's a different
license on each open source project.
So remember to check out the license for
limitations on whether the code can
be modified or distributed again
if you're taking a look at
a particular open source project.
So in this case this app
was created at Udacity so
you're free to use it and
adapt it as you wish.
So our custom adapter sample app is
called the Android Flavors app and
it displays a list of
all Android releases.
So each release is
represented in a list item.
And each list item contains an image,
a title, and the version number.
So this app is using
a custom ArrayAdapter,
they were calling the FlavorAdapter,
to display a custom list item view that
contains an image and two text views.
So we're having you practice the skill
of reading code from other apps.
And figuring out how to
adapt it into Army walk app.
So as a developer you often look at
tutorials or other open source for apps.
And try to apply those skills
into your own application.
So you can start browsing
this Android Flavor app code
by either clicking this downloads zip
button and downloading all the code and
then importing it into Android Studio
as an existing project or
you can browse the files
directly in the web browser.
So, for example I can click here app,
source slash main and
then navigate through the Java files or
the Rez files.
Another cool GitHub shortcut here
is to type T on my keyboard so
I'll hit T here and
that activates the file finder.
So this solves me to easily browse
through the files in my project.
So if I want to look
up that main activity.
I can type activity and
it pulls up our mainactivity.Java.
Or if I want to search up the
FlavorAdapter that I mentioned earlier
I can easily find that here.
So hopefully this example will help
you in the next coding exercise.
So check out the quiz for specific
instructions on how to get started and
best of luck.
Now scrolling to
the bottom of this page.
We see that this custom
ArrayAdapter example.
Displays a list of all
the Android releases.
So each release is
represented in a list item.
That contains an ImageView,
title, and version number.
So it's using a custom ArrayAdapter, one
that's called FlavorAdapter to display
a custom list item that contains
an image view and two text views.
Now we're going to have you practice the
skills of reading code from other apps
and figuring out how you can
adapt it to your Miwok app.
As a developer you often
look at tutorials or
other open source apps and then try to
learn how to apply it to your own app.
So there are a couple ways you can
browse for the Android Flavor app code.
First you can download the zip file
here so you download the code and
import it into your Android Studio
as an existing project.
Secondly you can start by browsing the
files directly within the web browser.
So say click App, now I go to Source and
lastly, you can use
the keyboard shortcut by clicking T and
that takes you to a search page.
So for example I can type in activity
and try to find the main activity.
We could also try looking up the Flavor
Adapter that we talked about earlier.
Hopefully this example will help
you on this coding exercise.
So check out the specifics
of the quiz for
more information on how to get started.
All right best of luck.