To train any classify,
you need label data.
Lots of it.
In this case,
the two classes you would like to
distinguish are car and non-car images.
So you need samples of both.
If you only have full
video frames available,
you need to crop out regions and
scale them to a fixed size.
Ideally you want a balanced data set.
That is the number of car and
non-car images should be roughly equal.
If that's not the case,
you're under risk of the classifier
trying to predict everything as
belonging to the majority class.
There are some techniques for
handling imbalanced data sets, for
example, duplicate some samples from
the smaller class to balance the counts.
For vehicle classification, if you don't
have enough non-car images you could
simply extract more from video frames.
Okay, once you have a sizable data set,
you need to split it
into two collections.
A training set and a test set.
As the names suggest, you will
only use images from the training
set when training your classifier and
then check how it performs on
unseen examples from the test set.
To avoid any possible ordering effects
in the data, you should sample or
shuffle the data set randomly when
splitting it for training and testing.
Even within the training and
test sets, you should aim for
a balance between the number of car and
non car images.
All of this preprocessing might
seem like a lot of work but
machine learning logarithms work on
a principle of garbage in, garbage out.
So you need to be careful
about what you feed them.