To understand Marshalling,
lets look at the ad example again.
The variables i and
j are somewhere in the memory of
the client processing address space.
They're two separate variables so
there's absolutely no guarantee that
they will be next to one another.
The client makes a call to
the RPC procedure rpc.add and
passes i and j as arguments to it.
At the lowest level of the RPC run time,
this will somehow need to result in
a message that's stored in some buffer
that needs to be sent via socket
API to some remote server.
This buffer needs to somehow be some
contiguous location of bytes that
includes the argument as well as some
information about the actual procedures,
some identifier for the procedure,
so that on the other end.
The server can make sense of
what needs to be done and
how the rest of the bytes in this
packet need to be interpreted.
And this buffer gets generated
by the marshalling code.
The marshalling code will
take these variables i and j,
and then it will copy
them into this buffer.
It will serialize the arguments of
the procedure into a contiguous
memory location in this manner.
In case the previous example is too
trivial, here is what would happen if we
need to perform a array add procedure,
which takes as arguments and integer i.
And some array,
j and then adds this integer to
all of the elements of the array.
Then again, the marshalling code will
need to serialize the arguments i and j.
Serializng the array j can
be done in different ways.
For instance, the agreement can be that
arrays are serialized in a way that we
first place the size of the array.
And then we add all of
the elements of the array.
So then the total
buffer that's produced,
as a result of the marshaling process,
will include both the specification
of the procedure, in this case,
it's a different procedure.
Array_add.
The first element, i, the first argument
and then the second argument of
the procedure, j,
that happens to be an array.
And in this particular process,
the agreement is that the array includes
the array size and then the elements.
Another type of agreement that can
make sense for a marshal in arrays
is that we would just list all
of the elements of the array.
And then we would include some special
character to denote the end of array.
That's, for instance,
what's typically used for strings, and
then the null character is used
to denote the end of array.
Either way, what this means is that
the marshaling process needs to
encode the data into
some agreed upon format.
So that it can be correctly
interpreted on the receiving side.
The encoding specifies the data layout
when it's serialized to the byte stream
so that anybody that looks at it
can actually make sense of it.