Now that we have written our word in Pos
function, let's put it all together.
In this quiz, you'll write code for
a final function, play_game,
which will be our new and
improved madlibs generator, which can
replace words other than noun and verb,
and keep all existing punctuation.
The function takes in as inputs,
parts of speech, which is a list
of acceptable replacement words.
And ml_string,
a string which can contain replacement
words found in parts_of_speech.
Your play_game function will return the
joined list replaced, which will have
the same structure as ml_string, only
that the replacement words are swapped
out with corgi, since this program can
not replace those words with user input.
After we write code for this function,
we'll show you how to integrate user
input, which will be a very simple task,
and walk you through the steps on how to
run this program on your Mac or
Windows machine.
We already went over how we'll approach
writing code for this function a couple
videos back, but the basic idea is
to convert ml_string into a list,
iterate over it, check if the current
iteration is in parts_of_speech,
using the word and
post function we wrote.
And if it is,
we replace the word with corgi, but
make sure to keep the punctuation and
add it to replaced.
If the iteration or word we're looking
at is not in the list parts of speech,
we'll just add it to replaced.
We continue this process until we
reach the end of the split ml_string,
convert the list replaced into a string
by using the join function and
return the new replaced string.
All right, good luck.