So the third question was about
cross-site request forgery.
And the reason I asked that question was
a fundamental part of building a website
is not just whether it's performant and
looks good, but nowadays is it going to
keep users safe from basic attacks?
XRF attacks,
cross-site request forgery attacks,
are a very basic form of attack, but
they still affect tons of websites, so
we want to make sure that
the full-stack engineer who joins us
is aware of what these attacks are,
and how you protect against them.
I was looking for
Philip to have some understanding
of cookies, HTTP-only cookies.
He ended up deriving the solution.
I was looking for
him to have an idea why you need to
protect what a user puts into your site.
He clearly did.
And I wanted him to have a basic idea
of what the attack is in the first
place, which he did.