[Norvig] Here we see a more complete representation of a problem solving domain
in the language of classical planning.
Here's the Fly action schema.
I've made it a little bit more explicit with from and to airports
rather than X or Y.
We want to deal with transporting cargo.
So in addition to flying, we have an operator to load cargo, C, onto a plane, P, at airport A--
you can see the preconditions and effects there--
and an action to unload the cargo from the plane
with preconditions and effects.
We have a representation of the initial state.
There's 2 pieces of cargo, there's 2 planes and 2 airports.
This representation is rich enough and the algorithms on it are good enough
that we could have hundreds or thousands of cargo planes and so on
representing millions of ground actions.
If we had 10 airports and 100 planes, that would be 100, 1,000, 10,000 different Fly actions.
And if we had thousands of pieces of cargo,
there would be even more Load and Unload actions,
but they can all be represented by the succinct schema.
So the initial state tells us what's what, where everything is,
and then we can represent the goal state:
that we want to have this piece of cargo has to be delivered to this airport,
and another piece of cargo has to be delivered to this airport.
So now we know what actions and problems of initial and goal state looks like
in this representation, but how do we do planning using this?