So, here's one approach to fixing up
this code that you might have taken.
This code here actually has a bad
bug that we'll be looking into next.
So, please don't go copying this
into all your production apps.
So, whenever we want to read or write
to database, we first connect to it.
Then establish a cursor.
Then we do an execute.
In the case of GetAllPosts,
we execute a SELECT statement.
And then we fetch all the results and
reformat them into the dictionary
that our code expects.
And of course, we close
the connection and return the posts.
In the case of AddPost, we still
connect to the database just the same.
We execute an INSERT query,
substituting in the post
content into the query string.
Commit the change and close.
Now, this seems to work, but
I did just say this has a bad bug, and
we're going to see that right up ahead.