Using the model of just buying new
hardware whenever there is a need to run
a slightly different operating system or
to support slightly different
applications, in that process,
data centers became too large.
At the same time, some of these servers
were really very underutilized.
In fact, on average,
the utilization rates in data
centers were around 10, 20% tops.
So as a result, companies,
now that they had to manage these large
data centers with lots of machines,
they had to hire more system admins.
So this is a correct choice.
And at the same time,
they had to spend more money to host all
of those machines, to power them, so
they have higher electric bills,
to cool the data centers since
the machines need to operate within
certain temperature variability.
So this was basically burning
through their operating budget.
The fact that all of these choices
are correct also translated at that
time of something like
companies spending 70% of their
IT budget on operating expenses
versus on capital expenses,
like actually buying new hardware or
new software services.
So then it became apparent that it was
important to revisit virtualization
technology as a mechanism for
consolidating some of these workloads on
fewer hardware resources that
will be easier to manage them and
more cost-effective
to actually run them.
And this is why the industry and
the community overall revisited these
solutions that were in existence for
certain types of platforms for
decades at the time.