Let's return to our diagram of the HTTP
request and response lifecycle and
talk about step one,
forming the request.
We mentioned earlier that a client
can request data from a web server by
accessing it via URL.
In conversation,
you may hear this URL be
referred to as a query URL where
query means a request for data.
In our case, we can get the earthquake
information from the USGS by going to
a very specific URL.
Note that the different USGS URL's
will give us different data.
These are known as different server API
endpoints that the client can talk to.
For this example, this URL gives us
the top earthquakes in the world from
January 1st, 2016 to January 31st, 2016.
Now this is a completely different URL
that gives us the top earthquakes over
the same time period but
with a magnitude of 5 or higher.
Later in lesson four, we will explore
the different parts of a URL and
how you can modify it to
get the data that you want.
All right, here's another
example if you're curious.
Now Spotify is a popular music
streaming service today.
And they provide the developer API
that you can use to create an app or
website that communicates
with their service.
Assuming a base URL,
you can add additional parts to that
URL to hit different Spotify endpoints.
For example, you can get albums, you can
get specific tracks within an album.
And you can get an artist's top tracks
simply by just changing the pieces that
you add to the base URL.
In other words, by adding this
additional text to the URL,
you're actually hitting different
end points on that API.
Okay, so back to our tsunami app.
We query specific URL and
our app shows the first earthquake that
comes back in the list of results.
For this quiz,
I want you to look through the app
code to find where it's located.
What's the name of the variable
that holds the query URL?
Then I want you to modify the value
of that variable to be a different
USGS URL.
Use the link in the notes below.
Now once you change that URL,
build and run the app on your device.
You should see a different
earthquake displayed on the screen.
So write down the location of that
earthquake that you see in the app here.