Let's break down the operations we
just saw on My Favorite Movies and
determine which API
methods we should use.
Obviously we need to be able to login.
And this is going to
require us to authenticate.
And this step can be very complex.
It involves a number of substeps and we
are going to cover each of them later.
So for now, we'll just assume
we've already logged in.
So on the genre tabs,
we need to be able to get a list of
movies by the genre that's selected.
Then for favorites, we need to be able
to get a list of our favorite movies.
Finally once we selected a movie,
we need to able to add or
remove it from our favorites lists.
So to complete this exercise, we need
to determine which methods to use.
So to start your search, you want to
open up the documentation for
the movie database API.
When you've found
the correct method names,
enter them in the text boxes
next to each question.
I've included a link to the
documentation in the instructor notes.