Over here where we'll still know we're
in one of four states rather than in one
of eight states.
Note that it's possible to form
a plan that reaches a goal without
ever observing the world.
Plans like that are called
conformant plans.
For example,
if the goal is to be in a clean
location, all we have to do is suck.
So we go from one of these eight
states to one of these four states
In every one of those four,
we're in a clean location.
We don't know which of the four we're
in, but we know we've achieved the goal.
It's also possible to arrive
at a completely known state.
For example,
if we start here, we go left,
we suck up the dirt there,
we go right, and suck up the dirt.
Now, we're down to a belief state
consisting of one single state.
That is we know exactly where we are.
Here's a question for you.
How do I get from the state where I
know my current square is clean but
know nothing else to the belief state
where I know that I'm in the right
hand side location and
that that location is clean?
What I want you to do is click on
the sequence of actions, left, right, or
suck, that will take us from
that start to that goal.
[BLANK_AUDIO]