The answer is 1D. You can actually search along this line over here.
You can't really know where along the line the point is,
because where it is is a function of the depth of the scene, which you don't know,
but it can't be the full image.
To illustrate this, let me look a little bit from above.
Here was have two image planes from the two cameras.
There is a point over here that finds itself in the image plane over there.
If we don't know the depth, we know that the point must lay on this ray over here,
and each of the points on this ray get projected into this imager along a line.
If the point is over here, it might be the projection over there,
and as we go out to infinity, it might be the point over here.
Now this camera array is a little bit more general than we talked about.
The image plans aren't parallel anymore,
but even if they're no parallel, each point in the left image corresponds to a potential line
of corresponding points in the right image.
It makes the search for correspondences much, much easier.
Let's talk a little bit more about correspondences.