There are some subtle differences to air
handling strategies that can come back
to bite you if you're not careful.
So for this quiz, I want you to think
through a few different scenarios
with this long chain.
Now, you normally wouldn't want to mix
and match different syntaxes like I've
done here, but I want you to think
through some different situations.
In this example, async returns
a promise, as does recovery.
The idea is that the recovery method
gets the chain back on track and
continuing to resolve if
something goes wrong.
My question for you is, for
each of these four lines,
what numbers will be logged
if an error occurs there?
Note that you can assume
that no other errors occur.
I'll go ahead and
give you the first one.
If an error occurs with async then the
first reject function will get called,
which is right here.
So that logs A1.
If the recovery works,
which you can assume it does,
then the next result function
will get called, which is here.
And that puts a 3 on the log.
Okay, now it is your turn
to finish up the rest.