All right, so here we are back in
Android Studio looking at the source
code for our Soonami app.
And we can go ahead and
find the query URL by going directly
in the main activity source code.
Now, you'll notice there's a string
constant declared with the name
USGS_REQUEST_URL.
We know it's a constant,
because it's declared as static final,
which means that there is only
one value, and it can't change.
And the other convention for
a constant value is to name it in
capital letters, as we also see here.
Now the value for this constant,
is this really long USGS URL.
If you copy and
paste this URL into your browser,
you can verify that it returns
a list of earthquakes back in JSON.
All right, so as you can see,
we have a really large JSON response,
so let's go ahead and
make it a little bit more human readable
by putting it into a formatter.
The first earthquake in the list is
the one located in Papua New Guinea,
which is also what also
shows up in our Soonami App.
In the upcoming notes and quizzes,
we read more about the actual job
source code that allows us to perform
this HTTP request to this URL.
So the answer to question one is
the variable named USGS_REQUEST_URL.
Now for question two,
we asked you to modify the URL to
use the one we linked in the notes.
So if you open the new
URL in a web browser,
you can see a new list of earthquakes.
The first earthquake is in Kota Ternate,
Indonesia.
I'm going to go ahead and copy and paste
this new URL, and move it into our app.
So when I do this,
I'm actually changing the value
of the USGS_REQUEST_URL constant.
Then I'm going to go ahead and
rebuild and run the app on my device.
All right, so
this is what the app should look like.
As you can see, we have the details
of our earthquake at Kota Ternate,
Indonesia, with a magnitude of 7.1.
And it happened on Friday, November 14,
2014 at this time, and check this out.
At the same time, there's actually
a tsunami alert for this earthquake.
Now back to our quiz, the location
of the new earthquake that shows
up in the app is Kota Ternate,
Indonesia.
Okay, awesome, now you can see how
changing the URL that we query in
the app can change the type of data
that actually shows up on the screen