Basically, remember,
what you're going to do,
is you're going to say,
here's our origin.
Where when I put this,
structuring element down will its
1's touch the 1's in this picture,
all right?
Well, the answer is here and
you realize actually almost everywhere.
In fact, the only places you can
put this structuring element down.
And not touch a 1, is over here.
Right, because this is a 0 and
this is a 0.
And there's nothing over here,
all right.
And I can put it over here.
Because this is a 0 and this is a 0.
Everywhere else.
So, for example, if I put that
structuring element here, I touch that.
If I put structuring element here,
I touch that.
Likewise, everywhere else in
the picture, I touch a 1 and
that's why that, it looks like that.