So you should promote everything, right?
You know, we'll change all the things?
>> Yeah I think that'd be helpful.
>> No it would not.
>> Okay.
>> 'Kay, like i said earlier,
layer management and compositing are not
free and so this is a balancing act.
There's no magic number of layers that
you should aim for but you are shooting
for no more than two milliseconds in
update layer tree and two milliseconds
in compositing, for 60 frames a second
critical work like animations.
>> Of course, if you're still going
over that by hitting 60 frames
per second, that's not bad.
The key is knowing about the tradeoffs
and then finding the right numbers for
your own project.