You've covered the theory behind
loaders as well as the code sample.
So, [SOUND] you're ready to practice
implementing a loader on your own
in the Quake Report app.
Your app already successfully fetches
earthquake data from the Internet, so
in this task, you'll be refactoring
your app to use an AsyncTask
loader instead of an AsyncTask.
Code refactoring mean changing the
implementation details of how your code
is structured, while still maintaining
the same external behavior.
The UI will still look and
behave the same, so the end user of
the app won't notice the difference.
But now, will be more memory efficient
because loaders can handle device
rotations and
the activity cycle much better.
There are three pieces we need to put
together to swap out our AsyncTask for
an AsyncTaskLoader.
First, we need to write a subclass
of the AsyncTaskLoader,
which we'll call
the EarthquakeLoader class.
The most important method
is LoadInBackground,
which works just like
AsyncTask's DoInBackground.
Next, we need to do some plumbing
to allow EarthquakeActivity
to use our loader.
So we need to implement
the LoaderCallbacks interface.
That way the LoaderManager can either
notify us to create a loader, or
notify us when our loader
has results to deliver.
Finally, when the EarthquakeActivity
is created, we should ask the loader
manager to initialize a new earthquake
loader, or reuse an existing one.
Here's another way to think
about the code refactoring.
In essence, you want to move
over the code that was in
the AsyncTask's DoInBackground method to
the loader's LoadInBackground method.
As for
the AsyncTask's onPostExecute method,
that code should be moved over to
the earthquake activity's onLoadFinished
method, because that's
run on the main thread.
In this method, we take the result
from the loader and update the UI.
As an extra hint, you can check
the notes below the quiz for
a gist of some partial code
to help you get started.
It doesn't have all the details of a
proper Java file such as a package name
or import statements, but hopefully
it points you in the right direction.
When you're done with these three steps,
check this boxes right here to continue.