Before we get started,
let's look at memory management from a
high level with another visual metaphor.
Here is an idea.
Operating systems and toy shops
each have some sorts of mechanisms
to manage the state that's required for
their processing actions.
In the case of the operating systems,
this state is captured
in the system memory.
In the case of the toy shops, this
state is captured in the various parts
that are needed for
the toy production process.
Beginning with the toy shop,
here are few elements required for
its part management system.
First, the process uses
intelligently sized containers.
Second, not all parts
are needed at the same time.
And finally, the process is optimized
for achieving high performance.
So what do we mean by
intelligently sized containers?
Well, for storage purposes,
it's convenient to make sure that every
container is of the same size so that
it's easier to manage those containers
in and out of the storage room.
Regarding the next point, you can
imagine how certain types of toys,
like teddy bears,
would require fabric and
threads, whereas other types of toys may
require wooden parts or something else.
Given that toy orders
are completed in stages and not
every single one of the toy orders is
processed at the exact same time, these
parts can be brought in and out of these
containers as necessary, for instance.
How that's done should be optimized for
performance because if we can reduce the
wait time for bringing the parts in and
out of the containers,
ultimately we can make more toys.
The memory management subsystems
that are part of operating systems
have some similar types of goals.
In an operating system,
memories typically manage
the granularity of pages or segments.
We will discuss this more later on, but
the size of these containers can be
an important design consideration.
Like with the analogy of the toy
orders and the parts needed for
the toy orders, similarly processes
that execute in a computing system
don't require all of
the memory at the same time.
Some subsets of the state
that's needed for
the computation of the task can be
brought in and out of memory as needed,
depending on what
the task is performing.
And finally, how the state that's
required for these tasks is brought in
and out of memory and into memory
pages or segments is optimized so
as to reduced the time that's
require to access that state.
The end result again is improve
performance for the system.
For instance, to achieve some of
the performance related optimizations,
memory management subsystems rely on
hardware support like, for instance,
translation lookaside buffers, or TLBs.
They rely on caches and
also in software algorithms such as for
page replacement or
for memory allocation.