So here we're going to show you some example of disparity, okay?
In the left hand side, you'll see,
that there is a point, at the bottom of this window, okay?
And in this image on the right over here, and by the way,
it took me a while to figure out which image was left and
which image was right, and I did that by looking right up here at the trees.
You can see that, in the image on the right, that the chimney has moved to
the left with respect to the tree behind it, so that's the right image.
What happened is, if I go to the same location in this image as in
the first image, I don't land on the window.
I actually have to move this far, in order to get to that window point.
That's the disparity.
And in fact, you can build what's called a disparity map, for every point x, y,
you can say what's the disparity.
And you'll notice something about this disparity image,
right, notice that the stuff here is brighter than the stuff there.
Well, I just made an image of disparity, and remember, disparity is
inversely proportional to depth, so the brighter values are the closer zs.
All right.
And the smaller values are further away, and, the really small values,
which are very dark, are going to be further away yet.
Okay, and that's this notion of, from disparity being able to get to depth.