And the fourth module will get deeper into the images again,
where we learn more about how we take multiple images and
blend them together, to generate weird images like this, or
also kind of find information within images that allow us to do analysis.
So this will lead us to thinking about images and
the concept of what are the sampling rates of images, what are the frequencies,
and how do you look at images on the frequency spectra.
We will learn about things like blending images together to generate novel,
perhaps crazy images.
We will learn about features, again these are points here that actually would be
used to combine these two images together if that's the goal.
And you'll learn more about how to do image blending, again with an exercise.