Here's how I completed the quiz.
First, I reviewed the different
tests that needed to be passed.
Then, I opened up Developer Tools
to start making changes.
To make the code easier to read,
I zoomed in by pressing the command and
plus keys.
If we're on a Windows or Linux machine,
I could have used control and
the plus keys instead.
Next, I moved the Developer Tools
to the right side of the screen so
I could see the slack card on one
side and the tools on the other.
If I wanted, I could even pop out
Developer Tools into its own window.
For example, if I wanted to put
the Developer Tools on another screen
while I focused on the main screen.
Needless to say,
there's a lot of flexibility on
where you can put developer tools.
Next, I just worked from
top to bottom on each test.
The first three tests involved
adding style to the buttons.
So to quickly jump to the button styles,
I inspected one of
the buttons on the card.
Now, at first, I wanted to add styles
directly to the element itself.
But notice the note at
the bottom of the page.
The buttons have the class,
profile-action.
This was telling me to instead
use the profile-action class to
add additional styles.
If I had decided to add the styles
directly to the element instead,
the test wouldn't pass, which makes
sense, because the styles would only be
getting added to one of the buttons and
not all of them.
To complete the first three tests,
I added a border radius of four pixels,
changed the mouse cursor to a pointer,
and changed the font to use Open Sans.
To figure out the buttons
needed the font Open Sans,
I just investigated one of
the other elements on the page.
Notice how when I scroll
down the style section,
I can see all the styles
being applied to the element.
At the bottom, I could tell the rest of
the page inherited the font Open Sans
from the statement right here.
The next test involved adding
a background image to top.
So I searched through the HTML to
find a DIV, using the class top, and
added the background image there.
Pay attention to how I pass
the placeholder image.
Because the value is an image,
I passed a URL, or
path, to the image by specifying URL,
and then the path to the image.
Finally, to pass the last test,
I located the typo in the HTML and
changed it.