The layout starts with an opening
tag for a ReativeLayout.
The closing tag is all
the way down here,
and the children XML
elements are in the middle.
The width and
height of the RelativeLayout
is set to be match_parent.
Since this is the only layout for
our app, this is going to take up
the full width and height of the device.
Then we have our first Text View
that says I'm in this corner.
It's aligned to the parent's bottom and
left edges.
That puts it in the bottom
left corner of the screen.
Going back to the quiz screen,
the TextView I'm in this corner is in
the bottom left edge of the screen.
The next TextView says No, up here.
This is aligned to the parent's top and
left edges.
That puts it in the top
left corner of the screen.
And indeed, we see that No, up here is
in the top left corner of the screen.
The third TextView says Wait, I'm here.
This is aligned to the parent's
bottom and right edges.
This puts it in the bottom
right corner of the parent.
And we confirm that's it
in the bottom right corner.
For option B to be fully correct,
the last TextView should be located in
the top right corner of this screen.
And it should say Actually, I'm here.
And indeed the last
TextView says Actually,
I'm here and it's aligned to
the parent's top and right edges.