So to make this all work out,
what we're going to do is introduce
state-based bonuses, the sort of idea
that instead of just giving little bonus
rewards every time that you do a certain
thing, instead we're going to keep track
of what the state of the world is.
And as we move to states of
the world that are more desirable,
we're going to get reward for that.
Which I guess is not that
different from what we had before.
But then we're going to have to subtract
that off when we move away from those
states.
So the basic idea is we can still keep
track of things like how near are we to
the ball, and we can have a score that's
associated with the inverse distance.
But now the idea is that
the rewards that we get for
taking an action are going to
be the increment that we get in
this value instead of
actually this value.
>> Right, okay, so that's important,
right? So that means if I went from
being, let's say, 10 pixels away from
the ball to 5 pixels away from the ball,
I get an increment of, let's say,
+5 or one over the distance somehow.
But for simplicity's sake, let's say +5.
But if I went from-
>> Well, wait,
these are numbers that I
actually know how to do.
So this is like 0.1 and this is like
0.2, so we'd get a bonus of +0.1.
>> Okay, good, good, I like that.
All right, but that would mean, then,
if we went from 5 pixels to 10 pixels,
we would end up losing 0.1.
>> Right, and this kind of keeps the
account balance in a good shape, right,
because it's saying that, sure, we'll
give you a little bonus for doing good
things, but you can't just continue
to get that over and over again.
If you relinquish it, we actually
have to take those same points away,
so that we can give them back
to you if you re-accomplish it.
>> Would it be more accurate to say
it's not so much state-based bonuses,
which I think you could argue is sort
of what we were doing before, but
it's sort of
changes-in-state-based bonuses?
>> Ohh, good, yeah, I like that.
So change-in-state-based bonuses.
>> Yeah, I like that.
>> All right, so we can continue
to fuss with this, but I think it
might be easier, believe it or not,
to not get bogged down in details but
actually talk about this
at a more abstract level.
>> Well,
before you do that can I ask a question?
>> Sure.
>> So I did make the claim that we
were sort of doing state-based bonuses
before, we just weren't
doing the change in state.
But I'm going to claim that of the four
things you have written up there,
score in goal, near the ball,
hitting the ball and
ball near goal, is hitting the ball
count as a state-based bonus or not?
>> It probably would want to
be like touching the ball,
something that is actually something
that's measurable in the state.
Hitting is a set of actions or
is a sequence of actions.
>> Right, okay.
So would that just be
captured by near the ball?
>> Yes.
>> So okay, that's fair.
>> Let's write down what the formal
definition of these bonuses are,
and then we can think again, if we want,
about how we might define it for
a particular problem.
But let's look at
the general form first.
>> Okay.