[Norvig] I'm going to talk about first order logic
and its relation to the other logics we've seen so far--
namely, propositional logic and probability theory.
We're going to talk about them in terms of what they say about the world,
which we call the ontological commitment of these logics,
and what types of beliefs agents can have using these logics,
which we call the epistemological commitments.
So in first order logic we have relations about things in the world,
objects, and functions on those objects.
And what we can believe about those relations is that they're true or false or unknown.
So this is an extension of propositional logic
in which all we had was facts about the world
and we could believe that those facts were true or false or unknown.
In probability theory we had the same types of facts as in propositional logic--
the symbols or variables--but the beliefs could be a real number in the range 0 to 1.
So logics vary both in what you can say about the world
and what you can believe about what's been said about the world.
Another way to look at representation
is to break the world up into representations that are atomic,
meaning that a representation of the state is just an individual state
with no pieces inside of it.
And that's what we used for search and problem solving.
We had a state, like state A,
and then we transitioned to another state, like state B,
and all we could say about those states was are they identical to each other or not
and maybe is one of them a goal state or not.
But there wasn't any internal structure to those states.
In propositional logic, as well as in probability theory,
we break up the world into a set of facts that are true or false,
so we call this a factored representation--
that is, the representation of an individual state of the world
is factored into several variables--the B and E and A and M and J, for example--
and those could be Boolean variables or in some types of representations--
not in propositional logic--they can be other types of variables besides Boolean.
Then the third type--the most complex type of representation--we call structured.
And in a structured representation, an individual state is not just a set of values for variables,
but it can include relationships between objects,
a branching structure, and complex representations and relations
between one object and another.
And that's what we see in traditional programming languages,
it's what we see in databases--they're called structured databases,
and we have structured query languages over those databases--
and that's a more powerful representation,
and that's what we get in first order logic.