For this problem, we're going to be doing something
similar to what we've done in a previous homework where you were given
a magic function to use for a reduction.
You're provided with a function solve_vc
which solves vertex cover for a given graph represented
as an adjacency matrix, as we've seen previously.
Now, it returns a minimum cover of the graph as a list of 0s and 1s
where 1 means the corresponding vertex is in the cover,
and 0 means that it is not.
Now, what you should do here is use solve_vc
to write a function multisolve which takes as its inputs
an adjacency matrix and a string.
The adjacency matrix is simply a graph,
and the string is either vertex cover, independent set, or clique,
and it returns a list of 0s and 1s, which are assignments of the vertices
where 1 means the corresponding vertex is in the solution
to the corresponding problem, and 0 means that it is not.
Now, you can feel free to use any additional functions you might feel are necessary.
But to be graded correctly, you have to use solve_vc in the solution to your problem.