Whenever I'm learning a new framework,
I never quite feel like
I've really got it set up until I
can start making changes myself.
So before we quit for the day,
let's make one simple change.
That background seemed a little too,
well, orange.
Let's swap that out for a nice blue.
If you open up the TODO pane down
at the bottom of Android Studio,
you can see that there's a to do item
to make this UDACITY_BLUE instead.
Let's double-click on that to
see what it's talking about.
So now we're in the actual game code
itself which we haven't talked at
all about yet.
We'll be getting into that next level.
But looks like there's a TODO to
make this UDACITY_BLUE instead.
Think you can take care of that?
Go ahead and make this first project
your own by swapping out these colors.
Open up the TODO pane in Android Studio.
Double click on the TODO make
this UDACITY_BLUE instead item.
Follow those instructions.
Then try launching the Desktop
run configuration to see the new
game running on your desktop, and
run it on your phone again and
enjoy the nice blue color.
By the way, if you can't quite
figure out how to do this, there'll
be a solution video following this quiz
that shows you exactly how to do it.
So, if you run in to any troubles,
just hit view answer and
I'll show you how to do it.