Probably the best known example and this
is one of the, the even though SVMs had
started making their way into
computer vision beforehand.
I, I think the one that really sort of
helped put it on the map was this paper
by, this work by Dalal and
Triggs in CVPR 2005 for just doing
person detection and basically they
were taking upright person detection.
The thing that you need to
know is basically they cut,
I'm not going to do any more than that,
they cut their pictures up into cells
and they built little histograms of
the oriented gradiance in that cell.
Okay?
So the features were called HoG's.
Histograms of Oriented Gradients,
that's what this HoG's stands for.
And then you take one here and
here and here, and
you just stack them up into one great,
big, long feature vector.
Okay, you just have a great,
big, long, feature vector.
They took a whole bunch of
windows that somebody had put,
drawn a little box around and
said, that's a pedestrian.
Then they took a whole bunch of
other little windows that said,
not a pedestrian.
They played with rescaling things
etcetera, whatever, training it and
basically trained an SVM.
And how well did it work?
Well obviously relatively well or
I wouldn't be talking to you about this.
Here you see, taken from this movie,
the ability to detect people,
here's some more of their work.
You know, here's a snowstorm.
I suppose it's in England,
but I don't know.
You know, you don't get too much snow.
Here's another example.
And and every now and
then you'll see a false alarm.
Now remember,
it's doing this all instantaneously.
It doesn't remember anything
from the previous image
about there being a person in here.
Here's another example.
I'm not exactly sure why they chose
these examples, but you know, whatever.
Now, you see where it's losing
that person in the background?
One of the problems there was that
there was no gradient between
the side of her dress, and the,
the dark background behind her, so
it sort of failed in
terms of the signal.
And here you can see, you know, pulling,
pulling out some things and not others.
A, a lot of work has been done
to improve this kind of stuff
going forward.
Pedestrian detection has become
a big deal in computer vision.
Partially because we have databases
to train on and to test on, so
you can compare your
results to somebody else's.