All right, let's just talk quickly about a couple of the geometric properties of
perspective projection.
What this figure is trying to show is a few things.
The first of all is that points go to points.
So that seems pretty clear.
I have some point out here.
And I'm going to put that point sort of out on my ground plane, right?
So I'm, here's my center of projection O.
I'm looking at some point on the plane.
And here's that point in the image, right?
Because it's just the single ray that are, that moves through.
Something else that's true in perspective projection is that lines, so
here's a line here, project.
So one way to think about it is here's my origin, think about it going
through here, and, and coming through there, and it sweeps out this whole plane.
And that plane, intersects this, the plane made by that line on the ground and
the point, the center projection intersects the image plane, along this line.
So what that's saying is, not only do points go to points, but
lines go to lines.
And if lines are going to go to lines, and points go to points,
then polygons go to what?
They go to Mercury.
No polygons go to polygons.
All right?
Not rocket science but it is this invariance of lines in prospective projection.
Lines mapping to lines that we leverage quite a bit.