So let's suppose we're
trying to extend a stack.
So what are some common methods
that you see, first of all for
just a stack as a data structure.
>> Well the most important
ones are push and pop.
You want to be able to push items
to the stack and get them back.
And then peak is usually a common one
too, or top, sometimes it's called.
And that's to get the top
element of the stack, so
what would be pops next
if you were to pop.
>> If you were to pop it.
So I want to expand on
the standard methods that you see.
So push pop and peek, but
I want to add a min method as well,
and so the min method, the constraint
is, it needs to run in constant time.
So if we didn't have that constraint and
I have a stack for
instance, what would be some method
that I could do to retrieve them in?
>> So if you had no, if you weren't
worried about run time at all,
you could save those items
over to a new data structure,
you could sort it in ascending order
descending order and get the first
element or the last element depending
on if it's ascending or descending.
You could just loop through it and
keep track of min elements,
replace them as you find a lower one
that type of thing those are things
are much slower, but-
>> Yes, if we were inefficient,
we would just say, we could search the
entire space find them an element and
then just retrieve that.
But the constant time
restriction is important,
because now we have to design the stack
in such a way that we can keep track of
the bin at any moment, no matter what I
push in, or what I pop from the stack.
How would we start to
approach that problem?
Where, as I'm pushing in values,
let's say they're integers, and
that I want to be able to track them in.
What are some ideas
you have around that?
>> Outside of increasing the memory
complexity, this isn't really possible.
As far as I understand, because you need
to keep track of what's going in and
what's going out and
that requires more storage.
But the way that I would do this is to
have sort of a secondary stack to my
regular stack and push them in values.
>> If it was in a two second method.
So we have two separate stacks,
one striking them in,
one striking in where you would
expect a normal stack to look like.
So let's draw some sample data, so
that we can start to build
the problem around this.
So maybe you put like five or
six integers,
something interesting
that we would test.
>> Okay, so something like.
Say 5, 6, 3,1.
>> Okay and we can just draw out some
boxes for your two stacks, all right?
>> So this will be my My
normal stack right here,
something like this.
And this will be my.
Main stack.
>> Cool, so let's assume that we're
starting with five, so we push five on.
So what happens here?
>> So five will get pushed
here to my regular stack, and
then also get pushed to my admin stack,
in this case.
>> And yes, we cross 5 out,
we go on the 6.
What happens with 6?
>> So, then we push 6.
So this will go into the stack.
>> So let's say, yes, we push 6 on.
So let's cross out 6.
And then, let's push 3 on.
So we push 3 onto the stack.
So the 3 goes on to the regular
stack and as usual, and
now 5 and 3, we compare the 2,
3 is less than 5,
we would push 3
>> Yup, perfect, so
this is still consistent, we can clear
in, it's correct the top is correct.
So we can cross 3 out.
But let's say, before we push one
on that we pop two off of here.
>> Okay.
>> Right, so let's say,
I get rid of three.
So we pop 3 and 6, so
when we pop this we could run them
on this as well and compare the two.
If they're equal because-
>> Conceivably,
if this happens to be
the item that were popping,
then we could safely assume
that we can get rid of it.
>> Yes.
Yeah, if they're the same value,
we could get rid of them even
if there is another 3 in here.
What we could do is, so say,
I wanted to push 3 twice.
So, I'd have 3 and 3.
When I push that second 3, if I compared
the two, and they were the same,
then I'd have to push 3 again,
because I know there's two.
I would know there is two 3's there.
>> Yeah, because I feel like, if you're
checking the top of this, and you're
always making sure that this is the min
So, I think what you're saying is,
you would have a situation in which
the min is the same for two values.
So let's say right now, that if we
didn't pop 3 and I push another 3, you
would have to push that one here again,
because it's equal to the current min.
>> Yes, if we just pushed it once and
removed one 3, we couldn't just
pop that, we can remove it.
I suppose,
if we could do a similar thing,
where instead of pushing 3 twice,
when we pop 3 here, we could say.
>> I think what you're hinting
at is a good edge case,
where if we were to have
two sequential min numbers,
that we have to make sure that it's That
this value is essentially less than or
equal to what we think is a minute or
a sec, so that's that's good.
So, yeah, so we pop 3 off,
so it crosses.
>> So this would be popped, and
then we would run a second pop.
When we run that second pop,
we could compare the two.
If we see that this is greater
than what we'd be popping here.
We would want to keep that,
so we wouldn't pop that.
>> Yeah, so that makes sense.
Okay, and then, so
easily we would push, like I don't
think 1 is very interesting.
But if I was to pop 5,
then you pop five here, and
then you also pop from here as well.
>> Yeah, which you could do
is have a check to see if,
if this were the last item
if you know the size.
Your stack were one or
something like that.
>> Yeah, I feel like the.
Well, I think we'll see when we start to
program, but yeah, we'll see if that's
a condition we have to check for
as we build up the algorithm here.
So let's start to draw out the new
interface that we're expecting.
So maybe having just some
simple pseudo-code around,
what this new stack
class would look like.
>> Okay, so what I might do is
something like within my stack class.
I would have something like this,
I'd have another class.
>> And
you can use a standard Java stack.
Like this structures shows they're fine.
>> I'm totally not familiar
with like the generic class.
So like are we overriding.
>> Yes, so.
>> We're trying to
override them correct.
>> Yeah, so for,
if I have a stack here, so
let's say that this is a public class.
>> Right.
>> And then we call it like Min Stack.
>> Yeah.
>> And so using-
>> Would we not be extending
stack for that?
>> We could but,
in this case, the solution we're
proposing was having two separate.
You have a min stack, only this
min stack, and a regular stack.
>> Right.
>> And so, if we wanted to Instead,
we could just have effectively
this would be private final stack.
And then using generics,
we could just put integer.
Right?
>> Right.
>> And then this would be stack.
Right.
And then equals new stack.
>> Yeah.
>> And then we would do the same thing,
so private.
Final stack.
>> For them in stack.
>> Yeah, for them in stack.
>> So same thing have been stack.
>> Yeah.
>> So that's fine.
And then, so
if we were doing it this way,
let's assume that we're
doing our push right.
So then, you have let's say.
It's public, it's a void and it's push
and like sure, we could use generics
if we put generics on here, we can make
this easier and have generics and here.
But since we're doing ints, let's just
say, here's an int and here's a value.
>> Great.
>> For now.
>> And so, from here, what we're
doing is, we before we actually
push the value to the min stack
we're going to do something like if.
Yeah, if so, yeah ,if not min stack.
Every time we're going to to push
to stack, no matter what, but
if in this case,
if not minstack.isempty whatever,
yeah, it was like that.
We compare it with the top,
we would do something
like, if it's in this list for
now we'll go if it's
If value is less than or
equal to min stack.
going to erase this peak.
>> I guess before you go there.
Like we know that.
So before we even start to
tackle like any of the.
Like interesting pieces that
could make this different.
We really do want to just push
onto the stack, so we don't
>> Yeah, that's what I was saying, so.
>> We're going to push
>> Every time we're
going to push to stack.
Yeah, no matter what.
>> So let's do that.
>> Stacked out push in value.
You know that happen every time.
>> Yeah, that happens every time.
>> And then From there, you would
check your edge cases for this one.
>> Mm-hm, so the edge case really
that we're trying to check, and
based on the example we had,
was you just have to.
You're looking to peak at the min stack.
>> Right.
>> And
then make decisions based on that.
>> Yeah, so
this is sort of a sanity check for.
Other, I mean if we, if I suppose
it'll return because it could return.
No, is what I was thinking
when stacked up he.
>> Yeah.
I think it's, that's okay.
So it's we going to erase this and
let's do mean start up peak.
>> All right.
>> But we still we have a chance.
So we still have value with the two.
>> So yeah we could say Int minTop or
something like that.
Yeah, it would be minStack.peak.
From there I would still
want to do that comparison.
>> Yes, and then this would be
where you have to do a comparison.
>> Value is <=
minTop.
Then we would push two min stack.
Yes, that's
right push
>> And let's write out.
So I think this makes a lot of sense.
And let's write out
our pop really quick.
>> And then pop Pop doesn't
need to take any value.
>> And we know throughout the whole
thing, but generally the logic.
If you can describe the logic.
>> Yeah, so essentially.
There.
We want to say.
We want to stagger going to get pop.
We want to say what gets.
Popular stack, so we would say,
Stacked up pop, and then save that,
and something like-
>> Just some type of variable.
X = stacked up pop.
And then if X is equal to.
Yeah, if X is equal to min stack.peak.
Then we want to remove it.
So we would also run a min stack.
>> So you're just trying to do
a sanity check to make sure that
as the stacks are changing,
that they're being kept in sync.
>> Yeah, and so that's the reason
why I just, if they're less than or
equal to, so if the three got pushed
twice it's in here twice, and
that way we can just say, well you know,
whatever's getting popped from
here they're consistent sizes.
If this is equal, if this is equal
to this, then we just we pop it off
of stack, otherwise we leave it,
we don't do anything to it.
>> Yeah, I have level this makes sense.
I know we can write this out, and
then also whenever I need to query, so
I have this new method called min.
What happens when minutes call,
just in general.
>> Min, at this point is just going
to be Basically, minstack.peak.
Is what it returns, so
min is really just returning that.
>> Cool.
Perfect.