All right, that ends this lesson.
What we've done so far is we've derived how the extrinsics and
the intrinsics are combined to form a single calibration matrix.
And this matrix maps from some arbitrary world coordinate all the way down to
a pixel value.
What, you know, some x, y,
z in the world, what UV does it end up in the, in the image.
All right?
So what are we going to do in the next lesson?
Well, the obvious thing in the next lesson is,
how would you go about finding that matrix, all right?
And basically, the requirement's going to be, if I gave you the location of some
3-D points in space, and I gave you the location of those points in the image,
I should be able to recover that camera calibration matrix.
And that's what we're going to do next time.
And then, a couple of times after that, we'll say, well if we're less interested
in going from a world coordinate system to a camera coordinate system, but
instead, we're interested in going from one camera coordinate system to another,
remember that stereo thing?
How would we do that calibration?
But first, we go from the world to the image.