Firebase notifications is a tool to
send targeted notifications in your app.
Built on Firebased cloud messaging,
Firebase notifications let you
send notifications to your users.
Configuring Firebase notifications
requires little code to get started and
primarily uses the Firebase console
to handle sending messages.
You can send a notification to
all users, a group of users or
even a single user.
You can even use analytics to
determine which group of users
should be sent notifications.
For example, he may want to target only
users who have made in App purchase.
That way, you can send him a
notification about maybe a special offer
and encourage more in App purchases and
user engagement.
You could then check analytics to
determine how the notification
affected user engagement.
Analytics automatically records when
a notification is in the foreground,
when it's received, when it is
opened and when it's been dismissed.
And this provides you engagement data
on notifications you send to users.
As you can see, notifications and
analytics go hand in hand
to boost user engagement.