For product form, it's important to
remember that your competitors offer
nearly the exact same thing as you do.
So we found a competitor
that did just that.
They had a few small differences,
such as allowing the sitters to stay
in the owners home rather than
the dog going to the sitters home.
Now for product category,
it's important to remember that
the scope was a little bit larger.
Now your competitors here don't do
the exact same thing you do, but
are pretty close.
So for
aBARKment, the local dog kennel is our
main competitor at the category level.
It's more like a hotel for dogs rather
than having your dog stay in a home
with someone, and
it's a little bit more expensive.