For this quiz,
you're going to be comparing the time
it takes two functions to run.
One function will run when
you hit Sort by name, and
the other when you hit Sort by number.
You can find a link to the site
in the instructor notes below.
I want you to use DevTools to
analyze what happens when you hit
these two buttons, and make sure you've
got the JavaScript Profiler enabled.
One of these buttons will take longer
to sort this list than the other.
I'll give you a hint that the slow
function, one of these two,
is going to be using a bubble sort
which happens to be super, super slow.
The other of these two functions is
going to be using JavaScript's built in
sort function which is way faster.
The point of this quiz question
isn't necessarily about which sort
function you should use, though in fact
the built in one is normally great.
This question is about
being able to see,
at a glance,
how much work is going into a frame.
So, with that in mind, which function
takes longer to run, onSortOne or
onSortTwo?