Before we go on, let's do a simple and
quick review of what we have looked at so far.
We have looked at the concept of images and
cameras as they form the foundations of computational photography.
We have discussed at length how rays of light go through a camera, and
then register on the sensor to be able to give us an image.
We've looked at how aperture and all of the different parameters or different
controllable quantities within a camera are used to generate an optimal image.
Then we have studied how a sensor or
a film, converts the light information into an image.
Which then we have discussed how we can actually convert to digital
information in case of a sensor.
And then of course, we have learned about how we can process an image to
be able to take something like this and find interesting, and information
theoretic features out of it that we can use for a variety of things.