All right, so let's take a look at all
these blanks in this end-to-end flow.
So starting from the beginning
is our CatalogActivity,
which is part of our Uri code.
Next, the CatalogActivity can call
on any of the CRUD methods, so
our query, insert, update, or delete.
And passing a Uri to it which
specifies the specific set of data
that it wants to interact with.
So, this specific data can be maybe
a particular name in a particular row in
a table in the database.
So, given the information
in the Uri,the resolver
will then route the message to
the proper content provider.
The content provider will then
interact with the pets' DbHelper and
then the database in order to
fetch the appropriate data and
return it back to our caller.
So the result that gets back will be
sent back to the content resolver.
And then ultimately back to our catalog
activity to be shown in the UI.