Another set of examples are this.
So here, basically, what I want to do is I want to now merge two images.
I have a background image, and a foreground image, and this is basically showing
you the UI, that by taking pixels from the background and the foreground, I can
now find a best possible seam that lets me merge these two images together.
Let's look at this example again.
I have a original source image and a target image.
this, of course, is a blurry, you know, stream.
And then I want to, on top of it, put this raft.
What I do is, of course, take the source image.
And we have a nice UI for doing this.
And I basically say, take all the pixels from this image here.
But now, take this image.
But in this case, take the pixels from just the region I'm touching.
Find all the similar ones from there.
And of course, what it does, it finds the best possible seam and
blends it together.
Now, for those of you who are very good at this, you may notice that yes,
this is not the best possible photographic output, because there's blur in
the water and sharp water here, but this is just to prove the point.
It can really, just by doing simple two clicks here,
generate a new image by merging, and but
it can find the best possible seam between one image to the other.
So just to show this in detail, I have two images.
I generate this image, but basically what has best happened is that we have
actually found a seam between these two images that lets me merge them.
And again, you see my problem here with blurry and sharp water.