Years is interval data. The time spent between the year 1848 and 1849 is the
same as that between 2000 and 2001, but there's no absolute zero. We had the
year zero, and we had the year 200 B.C. Etcetera. College majors of Republicans
and Democrats are not ordinal, interval or ratio. This is nominal data, or
categorical. And we're going to focus on this type of data throughout this
lesson, after we finish talking about the different kinds of numerical data.
The time it takes for rats to finish a maze is ratio data. They're are equal
intervals between values, but length of time in seconds or minutes, or whatever
has an absolute zero. Finally, level and college is ordinal data. Freshmen
preceed Sophmore which preceds Junior which precedes Senior