Throughout this course you'll be
working on a bunch of samples with
performance issues.
But by the end of the course,
you'll be applying what you've learned
to make silky, smooth experiences.
>> But first, in order to develop an app
that runs at 60 frames per second,
you need to understand what
goes into creating each frame.
In this lesson, you'll be getting the
background knowledge that you need about
the browser's rendering pipeline.
If you've taken web performance
optimization with Ilya Gregorich and
me, this will seem pretty familiar.
>> Right.
The point of this lesson is to help you
experience what potential bottlenecks
may slow down rendering.
In the next lessons,
you'll be diagnosing and
solving common performance issues,
as well as getting a sense for
how to approach performance at different
stages in your app's life cycle.
>> Right-o.
Let's get going.
>> Wow.