You now have an understanding of how
endpoints simplifies dealing with
authentication.
There are a couple things you have to
do to make sure authentication works,
not only in your development environment
on local host, but also on F-spot.
To do both of these,
you'll go to your developers console at
console.developers.google.com/project
and select your project name.
The first thing you'll need to do
is to configure your App's user
consent screen.a Google won't
tell your app anything about
the user without the user's consent.
So, the user will have to accept this
consent screen before the app can work.
This screen will display
your app's name and
give the user a chance
to know what's going on.
So, go to APIs & auth,
and then Consent screen.
Select an email address that you
want to associate with the app.
And, put in a product name.
And, that will be displayed over
on the user consent screen when
the user logs in.
Second, you need to make sure that your
app's front end will be allowed to
access the backend.
To do this, under API and
auth, go to Credentials.
In the Auth section say,
Create New Client ID.
Then, pick Web application, and
under Authorized JavaScript Origins,
change the URL field
to contain two URL's.
One for the https URL of your appspot
app, and one for your local host,
including the correct
port your server runs.
Bearing in mind, if it's the second
app you have running on local host,
because you still have the hello app
running, it'll be 9080 instead of 8080.
Now, copy this client ID value.
Yes, this big long noisy string
that ends in googleusercontent.com.
And open up settings.py.
And, put it here under Web_Client_ID.
In the next exercise, you'll get some
practice adding functionality to
the Conference Central app.
Previously, we used dummy data in
the get profile from user function.
Instead, you'll now be able to get
the data from the logged in user, and
create a profile for them.