The answer surprisingly is 0, 0, 0.
It just survives the way it was before.
To see this, [ ] initially faces east.
Next direction, it'll move forward 40, and then its heading direction changes
by 4 x pi/8, which is pi(1/2), so it's going to start pointing up.
It repeats the same action 3 more times, and eventually arrives at the original location
and points right again.
So this is a square motion. The results are in the exact same initial state as it started out with.
Now in reality, if we didn't use these equations over here, it would be on a circle,
but even in a circle, it would arrive back at the original location with those
parameters shown over here.
So the fact that our simulation simulates a square
doesn't effect the end result of this question,
and I didn't even ask about the circle.
I just asked about applying those equations over here, so 0, 0, 0 is the correct answer.