Now in Android,
there are different types of views that
can recycle views besides the ListView.
So this includes GridView or
RecyclerView.
But now, in the next few slides,
I'm going to point out to you some cases
where the developer should
be reusing views, and
other example cases where they
didn't need to worry about
reusing views because maybe they were
just a small number of views anyway.
So in the Twitter app there
are millions of tweets.
You could keep scrolling, but
chances are you won't be scrolling for
hours on straight.
So that's why it's a smart decision
to just create the views on demand
when the user scrolls to them,
which means we can recycle our views.
The Google Fit app gives users
insight into their daily fitness.
A user can track information
about their daily activity,
such as an afternoon time run.
And the app presents a summary page
listing the active time, total time,
estimated distance, steps and
calories for that specific activity.
Now, because there's a fixed number
of metrics that the app displays,
there's no need to recycle views.
This portion of the app can just
use a vertical in your layout.
Now for those interested in finance,
the stocks real time stock quotes
app allows users to track and
add stocks that they're interested
in into their portfolio, and it's
quite common for users to have a lot of
companies that they're interested in.
So the list could get really long.
The app could officially display all
this information about these companies
by recycling views as the user
is scrolling through the list.
Now, for this exercise, I'd like you to
take some time to explore either apps on
your device, or maybe other popular
Android apps, and find two examples.
So, the first example is one where
using a vertical linear layout for
all the list items is a good idea.
And for the second example,
to find an app that should recycle
views using something like a ListView.
And then I'd like you to share your
answers in the discussion forums
to get some conversation
started with other students.