So number of opponents moves
would actually do the opposite
of what we want.
It would label words as good where are
opponent has a large number of moves.
When we actually want to isolate
them and prevent them from moving.
Number of squares remaining doesn't
reflect the goodness of the board.
It's constantly decreasing
with each move.
Number of squares remaining minus number
of my moves would penalize our computer
player for boards with more potential
moves, which is counterproductive.
Finally, number of my moves minus
the number of opponent moves
is a good potential evaluation
function for isolation.
It continues to take in account boards
where the current player can make
a larger number of moves, and
also penalizes boards where the opponent
can make a large number of moves.