In JavaScript you have two different
kinds of scope, global scope and
function scope.
If you define an identifier
outside of all of your functions
it is considered part
of the global scope.
That means the variable can be accessed
everywhere within the program.
It is available globally.
All functions in your program can access
variables defined in global scope.
On the other hand,
you also have function scope.
If an identifier is defined inside of a
function, it will be visible everywhere
inside that function even inside
other functions inside that function.
In this example here, the variable
james is defined in global scope.
The variable librarian,
has fiunction scope.
And it's accessible in both
the library function and
the classic literature function.
The book also has function scope,
but it's only visible in
the classic literature function.
If you try to access the book variable
outside of the classic literature
function, you will get
a reference error.
The way this works is,
when the JavaScript engine tries to find
an identifier,
let's say the James variable here.
It first look to see if that identifiers
define than the current function and
if it finds it there then
it's job is done, but
if it can't find it in the current
function it then moves out one level
and then another level,
and then another level.
And it keeps moving to the outer
functions until it's no longer
in a function.
That means it has reached
the global scope.
If the JavaScript engine checks all of
the outer functions and global scope,
and it still can't find the identifier
then it will return an error.
Here it did find the identifier.
James out there in global scope.
Now that you have
the basics of global and
function scope, let's take a moment
to practice what you've learned.