Congratulations, together
we've learned many
main algorithms used
in machine learning.
We learned to predict house
prices using Linear Regression,
to detect spam email using Naive Bayes,
to recommend apps using Decision Trees.
We learned to create a model for
an admissions office using a Logistic
Regression and Support Vector Machines
and we learn how to improve it using
Neutral Networks and the Kernel method.
And finally we learned how to locate
pizza parlors around the city using
clustering algorithms.
So many questions may
arise in your head,
such as are there more algorithms and
the answer to that is yes.
Which algorithm to use?
So if I give you a dataset,
how do you know which algorithm to pick.
So we learn how to compare them based
on many things like running time,
accuracy, etc.
Can I combine these algorithms?
The answer is totally.
[MUSIC]
Will I get to work with real-life data?
Absolutely our projects will get you to
analyze existing data to solve real life
problems.
I look forward to answering these and
many more questions in learning together
in Udacity's machine learning
nano degree program.