The last required element
that you have to implement
to wire together a RecyclerView
is the LayoutManager.
Whereas a ViewHolder determines how
an individual entry is displayed,
the LayoutManager determines how
the collection of items is displayed.
LayoutManager is a key part of the way
recycling works in RecyclerView,
since it determines when to recycle
items views that are no longer visible
to the user.
Android currently comes with three
implementations of LayoutManager
to fit most needs, LinearLayoutManager,
GridLayoutManager, and
StaggeredGridLayoutManager.
LinearLayoutManager allows items
to scroll either vertically or
horizontally.
Vertical scrolling is the default.
GridLayoutManager, a subclass
of LinearLayoutManager,
arranges items in a grid that can also
scroll vertically or horizontally.
Lastly, StaggeredGridLayoutManager
displays an offset grid of items.
This LayoutManager is commonly used for
applications that have views with
content of varying dimensions.
If none of those [LAUGH] built in
LayoutManagers satisfies your needs,
you can directly extend from
LayoutManager and create your own.
For our toy app and Sunshine,
we'll be using LinearLayoutManager
to scroll vertically.