So, as we're learning about gradients now,
let's spend a minute to kind of review what we know about gradients.
I've basically shown you four sample images here and the question is,
which of these gradients, for this whole range from zero to 255,
for four of these images, is the largest in terms of magnitude?
From this point to that.
So, this is the region.
And we're interested, basically, in which one has the lost,
largest change as I move from this location to that.
For examples, all of them are exactly, as I said, starting from zero to 255,
but if you notice, each one of them in the direction that I'm pointing out,
does have different changes.
Answer by basically choosing which of the boxes applies to the correct answer.
Thank you.