So up until this point,
the way we've learned how to store
data is by storing it in variables.
But variables only live as
long as the activity lives.
You can think of it
as temporary storage.
>> So this was a problem we
saw in the core counter app.
We stored a team score in a variable,
and
when we rotate the app,
the activity is destroyed.
So we lose the score.
Then the activity is created
again in the new orientation and
the score is brought back but
with the default value of zero.
>> Yeah, we need a more
permanent way to save user data.
So if you close the app and you reopen
it, the user data will still be there.
>> Mm-hm.
Now, this concept is called data
persistence because we're persisting
the data which means saving
the data in a permanent way.
So some ways to do this are to save
it in a file or in a database.
And we'll be exploring the database
option in this course.
>> I have another example of why
data persistence is important.
Imagine that you're at a party and
you meet a cute guy.
And you enter his phone number and
maybe a photo of him into
your phone's contact app.
But say you want to call him later, but
without data persistence his
contact information would be gone.
>> What?
>> And you wouldn't be able to
call them, you would never know if
you guys were meant to be together.
>> No, star crossed lovers never cross.
And as you can see,
data persistence is super important.
So dare I say critical for most apps
to function including our pets app.
Now, if we don't properly store the pet
information that we entered into
the app, once the activity is no longer
running, it will just all be gone.
>> Yeah, so persistence is important,
and that's why this whole
course is important.
>> Mm-hm.
Now, this is a big
exciting topic to explore.
And let's get started by
learning a little bit
more about computer storage in general.