As promised, the answer is nontrivial.
The importance weight for x1 will be 8/27, which is the same as 0.2963,
and the one for x2 will be 1/27 or 0.037.
How did we get there?
Let's look at the non-normalized importance weights before normalization.
The guys on the lane markings will all get a 0.8.
The guys off the lane markings will get a 0.1. So the three guys over here.
The reason is the probability of seeing bright, which is what we saw,
off a lane marker is 1 minus 0.9. That's 0.1.
Now we have 3 guys that are on the lane markings and 3 off the lane markings.
The total weight over here is 2.4, and the total weight over here is 0.3.
Our total weight for all particles, not normalized particles, will be 2.7 or 27 tenths.
We have to really normalize the weight by dividing by 2.7.
0.8 divided by 2.7 is 8/27 or this number over here.
0.1 divided by 2.7 is 1/27, which is this value over here.
That's how we get to these final weights.
If you got this, you understand that the measurement probability effects
the weight before normalization, which is multiplying in the measurement probability,
and you did this correctly.
Afterwards we have to normalize to make sure all the weights add up to 1.
So we divide by the total weight of all particles,
and we get out those probabilities over here.
Put differently, this particle x1 that sits on a lane marker
is being regenerated in the resampling phase with a probability of 0.2963.
The same is true for the 2 other particles that sit on lane markers.
For the 3 particles that are off lane markers like the one x2 over here,
the resampling probability is a small as small as 0.037.
That's true for x2, but it's true for all 3 particles.
In total, these probabilities add up exactly to 1.