Avoiding jutter is extremely
important to users.
You just saw what a difference it
made in Jenk Invaders just now.
But, it's not just games.
It can affect all sites and web apps.
>> Let's put that in the context
of native apps a second.
Think about what you do when you're
choosing between two native apps
that do the same kinds of things.
How do you decide between two?
>> Well, I'll look at reviews and
see what people say about the app's
features and, you know,
I'm also interested in performance.
>> Right.
A quick look around poorly rated
apps tells you that users notice and
they care when an app judders or
stops for,
like, one to two seconds
whenever I click on this thing.
When that happens they, and you, would
choose an app that performs better and
it's no different with the web.
Bad performance kills good sites.
Equally, users love experiences that are
smooth, that stick to their finger and
react quickly.
Another colleague of mine Paul Kinlan
ran a survey about the features that
people want from a news app.
And the most requested feature
was smooth navigation.
Smooth, as in, no jank.
In fact, 77% of people wanted it.
>> This course will explain how you can
think about your project's performance
and what tools you have at your
disposal, and what you're looking for
and how to fix common issues.
You're going to hunt down causes of
sticky scrolling, flickering updates,
and juttering animations.
But first, you'll start your 60 frames
per second journey by exploring
what goes into a single frame.