For our last algorithm,
we'll consider Maximum 3-SAT.
This will tie together randomized
algorithms, approximation algorithms,
and complexity.
We're given a collection of clauses,
each with three literals
all coming from distinct values and
we want to output an assignment to
the variables such that a maximum
number of clauses is satisfied.
First we're going to show that for
any formula there is an assignment
that satisfies 7/8 of the clauses.
Consider an assignment that's
chosen uniformly at random.
And we'll define Yi to be 1 if
the clause Ci is satisfied and
we'll let Yi be 0 otherwise.
And we'll let Y be
the sum of all the Yis.
The then expectation of Y is just
the sum of all the possible values of Y
times the probability of that value.
This is just the definition
of expectations.
Bilinearity, this is the sum of the
expected values of the individual Yis,
and I claim that each of these is 7/8.
Since the literals all come
from distinct variables,
there are 8 possible ways to
assign them true and false values.
But only one of those assignments
will cause the YI to be equal to 0.
The rest satisfy the clause and
cause YI to be 1.
Therefore, we get
an expected value of 7/8.
And summing over all M clauses,
we get 7M over 8.
The key realization is that this value
here represents a kind of average.
That means that not all the v in this
sum here can be less than this average.
There has to be a v where
the probability is positive and
the associated value
of v is at least 7m/8.
Because the probability is positive,
however, that means that there
has to be a way to assign
the variables to get that value of v.
Therefore, there's always a way
to satisfy 7/8ths of the clauses
in any three set formula.
This technique of proof by the way,
is called the expectation argument.
And it's part of a larger
collection of very powerful tools
called the probabilistic method,
which were developed and
popularized by the famous Paul Erdos.
Note that the statement of the theorem
doesn't involve probability at all.
But the proof did use probability
as part of the argument.
That's characteristic of
the probabilistic method.