You've seen how to create
objects using the Unity Editor.
Now let's learn how to create
new 3D objects using code.
This is called instanciating an object
and it's called that because,
you're creating a new
instances something.
Okay, let's load up Unity and
create a new project.
First, create a new script
called object maker.
This script is going to
make new objects for us.
Let's open up this script and
add some code.
We want to create an object
right when the game starts.
So, we know we want to put
some code in the start method.
Now, we want to instantiate an object,
but which object?
There are many ways to do it.
For now, let's try to do
this as simply as possible.
We're going to use something
called a reference.
References allow you to pass objects and
components into a script and
control them.
In this case, we're going to
use a reference to determine
which kind of object to create.
You're basically saying,
using the Unity Editor,
I'm going to specify which
object I want to create.
Above the start method,
type the following code.
We'll break this down in just a second.
But first, save your script and
go back to the Unity Editor.
In the editor, create an empty game
object, and call it my object maker.
Then drag and
drop your object maker script onto it.
Notice the little field
called object to create.
This the type of object that
will be created by the script.
Let's go ahead, and fill it in.
Create a new cube, and
call it my cube, great.
Now, drag and drop that cube
into the object create field.
Cool, you just assigned
your first reference.
References are often the best way
to control objects using code.
They're fast, easy, and configurable.
Okay, now let's hope
back into the code and
break down the command we just wrote.
Okay, the first part is public.
This part makes sure that
the reference shows up in the editor.
If you leave it out,
your code will work.
But you won't see the slot,
in the editor and that means,
you won't be able to drag and
drop objects.
Okay, the second part is, game object.
This is called a data type.
And it tells Unity,
what kind of reference you want.
In this case, you'll be dragging and
dropping game objects into the script,
like our cube.
The data type could also be a number,
a word, or all kinds of other things.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then lastly, object to create.
And this is just the name of the
reference, it can be anything you want.
Notice how the first
letter is lowercase and
then every subsequent new
word has an uppercase letter?
This is called CamelCase and
it's the preferred style for
naming variables and
unity c-sharp programming.
Lastly, the semicolon at the end just
tells unity that you're done with your
instruction.
Okay, now you know how
to setup a reference.
And the next step is to actually create
an object based on this reference.
Let's do that now.