An Android application needs to register
with GCM servers before it can receive
messages.
To help us with this,
we are adding two new services.
The first is MyInstanceIDListenerService
which extends from
GCM's InstanceIDListenerService.
This service is what checks the validity
of a registration token and
requests a new one if a token
is not present or is expired.
Google Play services will
automatically start the service and
invoke on token refresh when it
detects that a new token is needed.
To get a new token,
we have a registration intent
service which will communicate with
the GCM servers off of the main thread.
Keeping the registration work
in its own service instead of
the InstanceIDListenerService means
that it can be invoked only when needed,
which may not always overlap
with a token refresh
such as the initial registration
when the app starts.
It also makes for cleaner code so
that you can easily track buys and
make future changes.
But you could also have done all of
this work in one service if you prefer,
which is why I mentioned that this was
our fourth class when we were talking
about the Android Manifest.
To perform the registration, we use
the InstanceID class to call getToken.
This class needs a SenderID which is
pulled from our google-services.json
config file.
Then it also needs a scope for
the permissions that will be granted by
the token and
any parameters required by that scope.
In our case, there are none.
Once we have our token, we store
our Boolean in sharedPreferences
to let us know we've got it.
Normally, you would also want to
send the token to your server.
The server needs the token in order
to send the message to this specific
device in the future.
However, because we don't have a server,
you should log the token so
that you can use it
later in our website.
But generally, a token should be kept
secret and not just logged willy-nilly.
All of this takes place
in the background so
as not to block the main thread.
And since our GCM feature
isn't a core piece of the app,
we don't need to worry about letting
a user know when they are registered.
But if your feature is necessary to your
app's behaviour, you may also want to
let the users know their registration
status somewhere in your UI.
Finally, we'll need to modify our
Google Play services check in on create
inside of main activity to see if
our app is already registered.
We can do this by checking
the boolean that we stored
with the default value of false.
This means that if we
cannot find the boolean,
assume we have not registered and
if we haven't already,
we will register the app by invoking
our new registration service.
If an app is not registered or if
Google Play services is non available,
this device will simply
not receive any messages.
This is convenient, because it also
means we do not need to hide layouts, or
features, as may be
the case in your app.