So here's a solution to the exercise.
As you can see,
each pet was made a row of the table.
And each column represents
an attribute of the pet.
All right, so
that checks off number one.
Let's move through
the rest of the questions.
So for the second question,
how many rows will we have,
excluding the column header row?
Well that'd be three.
The three represents the three pets, or
three objects that we have in our table.
And next, how many columns
does the spreadsheet have?
Well, it would have four.
Each pet will have four
different attributes.
So it could have a name,
a gender, a weight, and a breed.
So last question is, which one of
these could be a column header?
So like I just mentioned,
weight was one of the attributes that
each of these objects will have.
All right, so good job on the exercise.
Knowing this information
is a great way for
us to begin structuring the data so that
we can begin building out the Pets app.
So see you in the next video.