Recall, one basic premise
we started this class off.
And that is photography is
about capturing rays of light.
We came up with this whole pipeline that
we want to capture a 3D scene that's
illuminated.
We want to use optic, sensor, processing
and display to generate an image.
But one thing we actually also looked
at was while the rays of light were
the most important
primitive in the 3D scene,
we basically took that whole pipeline
to give us pixels at the end.
In essence, that was the goal
of the part of the pipeline.
So, in essence to us an image
of a scene was nothing else,
but 2D array of pixels.
While we did actually believe that rays
of light are the fundamental primitives
that we'd like to capture.
Most of the illumination in a scene
is actually rays of light that follow
a straight path most of the time
from the scene to a sensor.
We have looked at a variety of ways,
where we have actually taken
rays of light through a lens or
even a pinhole camera and put it on
a sensor where the image is formed.
And we argued that
computational photography,
basically controls the various
set of parameters.
And the optic sensor and illumination
and that's how computational
photography is now impacting
the whole discipline of photography.
So the question I have really
in this lecture is, are pixels,
you know, are rather limiting
form of what we can capture.
So, in essence, we are doing a whole
lot of this and ending up at pixels.
Is that a limitation?
Can we do something not to be just
stuck with pixels at the end?
Can we do something that will let
us capture more of the environment?
So then, for example,
we can do something at the end
to generate the right image.
So this whole pipeline, of course, we do
a lot of processing after we get pixels.
Can we do something by capturing
something a little earlier that would
let us actually generate the pixels at
the end, like the way we want them.
We saw various examples of this already.
Now we're going to actually kind of come
up with a formulation that will let us
understand the both the parameters
of how this can be done and
what are the variabilities faulted.