Okay. Let's take a look at what's happening in the system.
In the first case, we have ten toy orders.
Both solutions have six threads each.
For the boss-workers case, that means that one of the threads will be the boss,
and then the remaining five threads will be the workers.
For the pipeline model, each of the six threads will perform one stage,
one step in the toy order application.
So, for the boss-workers case, because we have five worker threads, at any given
point of time, these workers will be able to process up to five toy orders.
So, if we have ten toy orders, for the boss-worker model,
the workers will process the first five orders,
given that we have five workers, at the same time.
And every single one of them will take 120 milliseconds, so
the first five toy orders will be processed in 120 milliseconds.
The next five orders will take additional 120 milliseconds for
a total of 240 milliseconds.
For the pipeline case, the very first toy order will
take 120 milliseconds to go through the six stages of the pipeline.
So 6 times 20 milliseconds.
Then, once the first toy order exits the pipeline, that
means that the second toy order is already in the last stage of the pipeline.
So we'll take another 20 seconds to finish.
And then the third toy order will be immediately afterwards.
It will take additional 20 milliseconds to finish.
So given that we have nine remaining orders after the first one, the total
processing time for the pipeline case when we have ten toy orders is as follows.
120 for the first one, and then 9 times 20 to
complete the last stage of every single one of the remaining nine toys.
That's 300 milliseconds.
Now, if we have 11 toy orders,
we will process the first ten in the exact same manner as before.
We have five worker threads.
They can only process five toy orders at the same time.
So the first ten out of these 11 will be processed in 240 milliseconds.
Then, the 11th order will take another 120 milliseconds.
Only one of the workers will be busy.
Only one of the workers will be processing that toy order.
However, it will take an additional 120 milliseconds to complete all
of the 11 toy orders for a total of 360 milliseconds.
For the pipeline case, applying the exact same reasoning as before,
when we have 11 toys, it will take 120 to process the first one.
And then for the remaining ten, it will take another 20 milliseconds for
every single one of them to finish the last stage of the pipeline.
So we'll take a total of 320 millisecond for
the pipeline approach to process 11 toys.
If we look at these results, we see that the boss-worker model is better in
one case, when there are only ten toy orders in the system.
And then the pipeline approach is better in the other case,
when there are 11 toy orders in the system.
This illustrates the fact that there isn't a single way to
say that one pattern or the other is better.
As this example illustrates, the answer to that
can depend very much on the input that that application receives.
For one input, an input of ten toy orders, one implementation is better,
whereas for another input of 11 toy orders, the other implementation is better.
And finally, you should note that we really simplified the calculation of
the execution times of the different models because we
ignored overheads due to synchronization, overheads due
to passing data among the threads through the shared memory queues.
In reality, you'd actually have to perform a little bit more
complex experimental analysis to come up with these answers and draw
conclusions as to which pattern is better suited for a particular application.