Let's look at this concept of the frequency domain of
a signal in a different way.
Let's create this three-dimensional axis.
A is amplitude, t is time.
This is exactly how we've been looking at signals.
But, now, actually, let's look at also the third dimension here,
which relates these things, but now we're measuring the frequency.
So the first one, f1, we looked at, was basically our first frequency, right?
Which basically had this amplitude and
this variations for, again, a period of 4.
f2 basically is, again, A and t are the same,
but what we did was we basically added and multiplied the frequency by twice,
to be able to have the same, twice the number of cycles in the same period.
So f2 was basically a step up in the frequency domain, here.
And similarly, f3 was another step in the frequency domain.
If we were to look at the same plot in a and
T, of course, it went from here to there to this.
This is how we actually looked at all of those four different, f1, f2,
f3 and f4, in the previous slides.
So in essence, what we're trying to do is now look at the signal in these two
axes, amplitude versus frequency, not just amplitude and time.
In amplitude versus frequency, we have three different plots here,
of course we want to look at it from this direction.
For, in the time domain, we have been looking at it in this direction, and
we have seen these plots before.
But now we want to be able to look at these things from that side in this axis.
So one big question is,
how many samples do we want in different frequency domains?
Here we just showed three.
As I showed you before, if you went from N equals to 3 to N equals to 10 to
N equals to 50, we were actually much closer to the final signal that we wanted.
And of course, as N grew larger, we were even much closer.
So, of course, one big question remains is,
how many samples do we want of different frequencies?
Another part of it is, in the frequency domain, as we go down this axis,
what each and every one of the signals contributes to the overall signal, and
how we can control it.
And finally, the most important part,
why we want to do this kind of analysis in the frequency domain is, for
example here, if I'm looking at f1, I'm only looking at a very coarse signal.
When I'm looking at f3,
I'm looking at A comparatively from f1 a more finer signal.
So if you go down this axis where N is increasing, we basically,
here we're going to be looking at a very coarse signal.
And here we're going to be looking at a very fine signal.
So if you notice, one important part of it is, now we can do
analysis differently for coarse signal and differently for fine signals.
And that's an important part of what we want to do,