So look at this framework here.
Again, what we're interested
in is simple translation.
Have an image.
This image, in this case, has been
translated by certain tx and ty.
Question for you to think about is,
how many points do I need to have to be
able to now model this transformation?
So please put in,
how many points correspondences we need?
So in the previous case
I showed you before,
do we need all four of them here?
That's one question.
And also, how does, how many degrees
of freedom can be used to model this?
Please fill out these boxes.
And then, in this matrix,
tell me which parts of this three
by three matrix do we think that
the values would have to be, related to
the parameters that we need to change.
Just for simplicity sake, know that
we already know this will be one.
So, fill out the others, please.