Okay, so now you've decided which
features to extract from each image, and
you've trained a classifier
using label data.
Great work.
The next step is to implement a method
of searching for objects, in this case,
for vehicles in an image.
So how are we going to do that, Drew?
>> Well, you've seen that
you can consider cutouts or
subregions of an image, and
run your classifier on each subregion
to see if it contains the object
you're trying to detect.
So what you'll do next is implement
a sliding window technique,
where you'll step across
an image in a grid pattern and
extract the same features you trained
your classifier on in each window.
You'll run your classifier to
give a prediction at each step.
And with any luck,
it will tell you which windows
in your image contains cars.