Now we're going to talk about how to do inference on Bays Net.
We'll start with our familiar network, and we'll talk about a method called enumeration, which goes through all the possibilities,
adds them up, and comes up with an answer. So what we do is start by stating the problem.
We're going to ask the question of, "What is the probability that the burglar alarm occurred, given that John called and Mary called?"
We'll use the definition of conditional probability to answer this. So this query is equal to the joint probability distribution
of all three variables, divided by the conditionalized variables.
Now, note I'm using a notation here where, instead of writing out the probability of some variable equals true,
I'm just using the notation, "Plus," and then the variable name in lowercase.
And if I wanted the negation, I would use negation sign.
Notice there's a different notation where, instead of writing out the plus and negation signs, we just use the variable name itself,
P of E, to indicate E is true. That notation works well, but it can get confusing between, "Does P of E mean E is true,
"or does it mean E is a variable?" And so we're going to stick to the notation where we explicitly have the pluses and negation signs.
To do inference by enumeration, we first take a conditional probability and rewrite it as unconditional probabilities.
Now we enumerate all the atomic probabilities and calculate the sum of products.
Let's look at just the complex term on the numerator first. The procedure for figuring out the denominator would be similar, and we'll skip that.
So, the probability of these three terms together can be determined by enumerating all possible values of the hidden variables.
In this case there are two--E and A. So we'll sum over those variables for all values of E, and for all values of A--
In this case they're Boolean, so there's only two values of each.
We ask, "What's the probability of this unconditional term?"
And that we get by summing out over all possibilities, E and A being true or false.
Now, to get the values of these atomic events, we'll have to rewrite this equation in a form that corresponds to the
conditional probability tables that we have associated with the Bays net. So we'll take this whole expression and rewrite it.
It's still a sum over the hidden variables, E and A. But now I'll rewrite this expression in terms of the parents of each of the nodes in the network.
So that gives us the product of these five terms, which we then have to sum over all values of E and A.
If we call this product F of EA, then the whole answer is the sum of f for all values of E and A.
So it's the sum of four terms, where each of the terms is a product of five numbers.
Where do we get the numbers to fill in this equation? From the conditional probability tables from our model.
So let's put the equation back up, and we'll ask you for the case where both E and A are positive, two look up in the
conditional probability tables, and fill in the numbers for each of these five terms, and then multiply them together and fill in the product.