A* Search works by always expanding
the path that has a minimum value of
the function f, which is defined as
a sum of the g and h components.
Now, the function g of a path,
it's just the path cost.
And the function h of a path is equal to
the h value of the state,
which is the final state of the path,
which is equal to the estimated
distance to the goal.
Here's an example of how A* works.
Suppose we found this path through
the state space to a state X, and
we're trying to give a measure
to the value of this path.
The measure f is a sum of g,
the path cost so far, and h,
which is the estimated distance
that the path will take to
complete its path to the goal.
Now, minimizing g helps
us keep the path short.
And minimizing h helps us keep
focused on finding the goal.
The result is a search strategy
that is the best possible,
in the sense that it finds
the shortest length path
while expanding the minimum
number of paths possible.
It could be called best estimated
total path cost first, but
the name A* is traditional.
Now let's go back to Romania and
apply the A* algorithm.
And we're going to use a heuristic,
which is a straight line distance
between a state and the goal.
The goal, again, is Bucharest, and so
the distance from Bucharest to
Bucharest is, of course, 0.
And for
all the other states, I've written
in red the straight line distance.
For example, straight across like that.
Now, I should say that all the roads
here I've drawn as straight lines, but
actually roads are going to
be curved to some degree.
So the actual distance along
the roads is going to be
longer than the straight line distance.
Now, we start out as usual,
we'll start in Arad as a start state.
And we'll expand out Arad,
and so we'll add three paths.
And the evaluation function, f, will
be the sum of the path length, which
is given in black, and the estimated
distance, which is given in red.
And so, the path link from this
path will be 140 plus 253, or 393.
For this path, 75 plus 374, 449.
And for this path, 118 plus 329, 447.
And now, the question is, out of all
the paths that are on the frontier,
which path will we expand
next under the A* algorithm?