Let's pop open Unity and
create some perimeters.
The first screen you see lets you
open projects or create a new one.
Let's create a new one.
Name our new project ModernApartment.
Great, now we have a blank
project to work on.
So let's check out some
of Unity's primitives.
Go up to GameObject &gt; 3D Object &gt; Cube.
See the cube up here?
Cool, let's move the cube out of
the way and make another parameter.
Select the Move tool then click and
drag one of the access arrows
to move the cube out of the way.
Great.
Now go to GameObject
&gt; 3D Object &gt; Sphere.
Let's move the sphere
out of the way too.
Now add a cylinder.
Awesome.
All of these shapes
are examples of 3D primitives.
You'll use them all
the time in VR development.
And now you know how
to make them in Unity.
Nice work