We've seen a custom 404 response
served by the service worker.
But what if we wanted to
serve an image instead?
Jake's done most of the work here.
So to get your code into the same state
as Jake's, in the project folder,
run git reset --hard to remove
any local changes you have.
Then git checkout error-handling
to get the project
into a state where it's handling
404s and the service worker.
Take a look at the code
in public/js/sw/index.js.
Here's the code where
the 404 is handled.
Rather than responding with custom text,
your task is to respond
with the dr-evil GIF.
This involves fetching
the GIF from the network,
which we covered in the last section.
Write the code and
refresh a non existing page to
confirm your changes have worked.
Remember to have DEV tools open and
use force update on reload so
you only need to refresh
once to see changes.
Once you've got it working, head over
to the settings page and type gif-404
into the test field and press enter,
this will confirm it's all working.