Stack Views are UI element introduced
in iOS 9. And as the name suggests, they
make it easy to stack views. You can have
any UI View subclass inside of a UI Stack View.
In Pitch Perfect, we're going to
place our playback buttons inside a set
of Stack Views. Stack Views can have
either a horizontal or vertical
orientation. You can control the
alignment distribution and spacing of a
Stack View. Stack View can be nested
inside each other. Here you see a
vertical Stack View for the entire
screen, with horizontal Stack View nested
inside for each row of buttons. The real
beauty in using Stack Views is that you
only need to create AutoLayout
constraints for the Stack Views
themselves. But what about all the UI
elements inside of a Stack View, like the
buttons for Pitch Perfect？ Stack Views create
their own AutoLayout constraints for
the UI elements contained within them
based on the alignment distribution and
space settings that you provide. Let that
sink in for a second.
Instead of having to create constraints
for all of these buttons, we can just
embed them in UI Stack Views and let
the Stack Views do all the work.