The answer is these last two. We'll go through
these one by one. In the first case, the
owner of the file is another user, and I'm
not in the group either, so I fall into
the other category. The other category has read permissions,
so I can read the file, and the command
succeeds. Now let's see what happens when I try
to read dir/bar.txt. I am the owner of bar,
and the owner has read permissions, but to get
there I have to pass through the directory dir, and
since I don't have execute permissions on dir, this generates
an error. The same thing happens for touch. Writing to
the directory file is okay, but actually creating a
new file in the directory requires the ability to pass
through. It is interesting to note what would have happened
if I had reversed the permissions on dir. Then cat
dir/bar.txt would have worked, since I just need to pass
through the directory. The touch command would not have worked
however, as I would need to add the new file
name to the directory, and I don't have write permissions.