Continuing on with our basic installation,
you can use your favorite text editor for this course on your local machine.
If you do not have a favorite text editor,
I recommend using the open source tool, Atom, for it's simplicity.
This requires OS X 10.8, or Windows 7 and 8.
So please check that your computer's compatible.
For Windows users, be sure to unzip the file after downloading.
So you can simply go to atom.io, you can copy and
paste, or simply type in atom.io.
And depending on you operating system, I'm using OS X,
it should give you the correct download button here.
So, simply click on the button, and begin the download process.
Another option includes Sublime Text Editor 2.
This is a great option to test out, and we do encourage you to purchase it
after your review period, if you decide to go down the Sublime Text option.
You can also complete the course using complete virtual box commands in
Ubuntu like Vim or Emacs, but we will not cover this in this course.
Once you're done with your option, click Next.