In fact, here's a nice little example of the thing running.
And this is taken from a very ancient photo but you can see right in here,
there's a bowling ball, and that's where the plus, the crosshairs are drawn.
And just as a, sort of to show you some other way of trying to find this
ball that's moving, you could image just looking for the stuff that's moving.
After all, it hasn't hit the pins yet.
But when you'd look for the stuff that's moving, they find this bounding box.
How come we could find more than just the ball?
Well actually if you take a look really carefully,
you'll see that this lane is very shiny.
Okay. In fact, in a little while we're going to talk about reflectance functions
and specular reflectance functions, and
you'll talk about why on this lane you actually see the image of the ball.
And because of that, there's motion in here as well, so
you get this bounding box.
But that's okay,
all of we're saying is basically, that it was able to find the, the circle.
Here's another example taken.
In fact, if you go and you type Hough transform circles or
something like that into Google, in Google, and
you look for images, you'll actually come up with this image.
This image was actually taken by Vivek Kwatra back when he
was a wee graduate student, TA in my class, back in 1811 or something like that.
And what we did was we took a picture of of these coins on top of
a textured background.
We, he did it because he had to, because he was my TA.
He's now a really famous guy doing cool research stuff, all right.
So, basically, you can take this and you can compute the edges, and
here's an edge image of that, and then we can look for circles.
Now, we're going to use the known radius method.
So, let's suppose we start with the radius for a penny.
All right.
And you can probably see that there's this nice bright spot right here in
the middle that corresponds to the penny.
Now what you may also notice is that there are these kind of blown ups areas.
Not so much here.
It's a little harder to see.
We'll go back here.
And that's because you could fit a penny.
Sort of around the edge of the circle, and the centers would be rotating around
the middle of the circle, and that's what this little circle of centers is.
But at the real penny, they all align up, and so you get even a brighter spot.
So how would we find the quarters?
Well, we just use a bigger radius, the radius of a quarter, and
we vote again, and again you'll see these spots here, here, and here.
And now the penny edges, well they, they again vote for
this bit of a circle, but not nearly as strong as the quarters do.
So this was the original is, image, and these are the combined detections, and
so that's pretty cool, you know, you can just find the circles.