In this course we will be using Maven, a build command tool,
in order to compile and package our storm program.
This is another top level open source Apache software foundation project and
more information on Maven can be found at maven.apache.org.
So, in step 1, navigate to your top level/vagrant/ file.
So, again, if you're following along with optional exercises, we are in
our viz/static, and we can do cd/vagrant/ and ls.
That will show the lesson 1 through lesson 4.
And again, this is the file that shared with your local machine.
In step 2 of the routine instructions, navigate into the folder lesson 1,
by typing cd lesson 1.
cd lesson 1, again, you can use tab completion, and you that there's one, two,
three, four different lessons, so we need to specify lesson 1.
And we'll type ls to see stage 1 through stage 3.
Finally, in step 3, let's go in to stage 1.
Again with cd stage 1.
cd stage1 ls.
So in step four we're going to run our first maven command by typing the command
letters mvn followed by a space and clean.
Mvn stands for Maven.
So the full command is mvn clean and hit Enter and you should see,
after downloading files, a build a success.
If you don't see build success immediately don't worry about it,
what's happening is Maven is downloading dependencies for
our project and depending on your download speeds you
may not get all the dependencies in the timeout session.
So if you don't see build success simply run mvn clean again until you
see build success.
Next in step five we're going to compile and
package our storm program by typing mvn package.
So again remember that you want to be in lesson 1,
stage 1 type in mvn package, and hit Enter.
The first time we hit maven package we will see a number of
dependencies downloaded that are needed to support the storm program.
This process may take five to ten minutes, so please be patient.
Finally once you see build success you can type in a command tree, T-R-E-E, and
you'll see that your new class files ExclamationTopology,
ReporterExclamationTopology including jar files two jar files,
one with dependencies and one without, are created.
So congratulations on building your first project.
Please continue on to learn how to submit your project to Storm.