The objectives for this lesson are for
you to learn about how to merge two images.
A specific approach that we will also be looking at is, what amount of one
image and the signal from one image, do you want to merge with the other image?
And we will look at the whole concept of window sizes, that will allow us to
quantify how much of one image we want to merge with the other.
And then of course, we'll go back to the whole concept of Fourier analysis to
help us look at how we can do this merging and understand more
about the frequency domain and the sampling that's available in each image,
that could be used to generate a novel image.