Mom and pop are working on building
a backend Flask web API for
their bagel shop.
Download the code in
the instructor notes
to see the code they have thus far.
There's a /bagels route that exposes
all of the bagels in their inventory.
A feature that only users that are Mom
& Pop's Bagel Shop members can view.
Don't worry.
Becoming a member is free and easy.
Help Mom and Pop by adding a user
class in their models.pie file
that securely stores user names and
hashed passwords.
Add a route for
users to register their accounts by
sending a post request to /users.
And protect the / bagel's endpoint such
that only members can view a bagel
directory.
When you are finished,
use the bagel tester,py file to test and
see that your code works.