Well, clearly you'd like to have a description of what those components do
orf what those connectors do. ACME doesn't provide this, but you
can well imagine some additional syntax for describing those kinds of behaviors.
Also, ACME doesn't have representation for functional properties. So going back
to our original understanding of systems having function behavior and structure,
ACME tells you a lot about structure, but it doesn't tell you much about
function behavior. Also, ACME doesn't directly provide a way for connecting code
with architectural elements, and you can imagine that going in either direction.
That is, you might like to take an architectural description and
automatically generate stub code for it. Similarly, if you've got some existing
code, you can imagine a tool that can do some kind of analysis on that code to
generate an architectural description that can then be imported into ACME and
you can visualize it using the ACME Studio Graphical Editor. Also, of course,
is the fact that ACME doesn't say anything at all about non-functional
requirements other than what the property sub-language allows you to describe on
your own. The essential role of non-functional requirements in any
architectural description means that it would be of value to come up with some
way in a standard fashion, trying to characterize these particular requirements.