So let's now visualize this
light-field from this perspective.
I have my uv plane and my st plane.
Any point on the uv plane is now
looking at this whole st plane.
So any ray of light arriving at
one point on the uv plane is
arriving from all
points on the st plane.
What is the st plane?
Well, here is a simple
way of looking at it.
The uv plane has variety
of arrays of images.
Now you can imagine that at this point,
I've basically taken a bunch of
different images at
different orientations.
So, again, if I could basically
create a pinhole here,
this would see the scene differently.
So what I would have this and
the st would basically just be one
single image, from different viewpoints.
Now by just reversing
this versus that again,
imagine this to be in the st plane and
this to be in the uv plane.
I actually now have
an array of images and
I can traverse them one by
one by looking at them.
Of course, the interesting parts of
this is I can now of course, be looking
another one and interpolation can be
used to generate in between images.
What happens in the other case?
Where now, I'm looking at the st
plane and extracting information,
so on the uv plane.
So rays arriving at one point in
the st plane, that were bound for
all points on the uv plane.
Again, the same light structure here,
but except this time around,
we're not seeing the object,
but we're actually seeing more
local details of the same objects.
And of course,
this would actually give me a uv plane.
So this shows me local details in the uv
plane, while sd plane was actually
showing me in the previous case
a lot more detail of the object.
So the best way to think about it is
imagine, we can create an array of
cameras and I would put a bunch of
different cameras in a grid pattern and
use that to take a bunch of pictures.
And now, I would have a huge
amounts of pictures there.
And what I can basically do is using
this kind of stuff, move from one view
to the other, interpolate between
one of them and actually,
that would actually create a light-field
rather than pixels themselves.