Now I'm going to look at the issue of reducing m, the depth of the tree.
Here, I've drawn a game tree and left out some bits,
but the idea is that is that it keeps on going and going.
There'll be too many nodes for us to evaluate at all. What can we do?
The simplest approach is to just by fiat cut off the search at a certain depth.
We'll say we're only going to search to level three,
and when we get down to level three,
we're going to pretend that these are all terminal nodes.
We'll draw them as the square boxes for terminals rather than the max nodes
and cut off the search at that point.
Now, of course, they aren't terminal, so according to the rules of the game,
we haven't either won or lost at this particular point.
We can't say for sure what the value is for each of these nodes,
but we can estimate it using something called an evaluation function,
which is given a state S and returns an estimate of the final value for that state.
What do we want out of our evaluation function and how do we get it?
We want the evaluation function to be stronger for positions that are stronger
and weaker for positions that are weaker.
We can get it one way from experience--
from playing the games before and seeing similar situations
and figuring out what their values are.
We can try to break that down into components by using experience with the game.
For example, in the game of chess it is traditional to say that a pawn is worth 1 point,
a knight 3 points, a bishop 3 points, a rook 5, and a queen 9.
You could add up all those points.
So we could have an evaluation function of S
which is equal to this weighted sum of the various weights times the various pieces--
positive weights for your pieces and negative weights for the opponent's pieces.
We've seen this idea before when we did machine learning
where we have a set of features, which could be the pieces,
and they could be other features of the game as well.
For example, in chess it's good to control the center,
it's good not to have a double pawn, and so on.
We could make up as many features as we can think of to represent each individual state
and then use machine learning from examples to figure out what the weight should be.
Then we have an evaluation function.
We apply the evaluation function to each state at the cutoff point
rather than doing a long search.
Then we have an estimate, and we back those values up just as if they were terminal values.