All right, welcome back to Computer Vision.
Last time, or whenever it is you chose to watch.
The last thing I talked to you guys about was how surface appearance involve
the interaction between the lighting and the surface itself and the shape.
So that's what it says here that the image intensity that we'll see will be
a function of the lighting or the illumination, the surface reflectance, and
then when we say the shape what we actually mean is sort of the surface normals.
That is, how the shape is how the surface bends depending upon its
direction with respect to the illumination.
And so one of the challenges that this poses is, if you wanted to recover
say one of these, like you wanted to recover the shape or you wanted to recover
the reflectance of what's there, you know the texture or how bright it is.
In some sense you can't do one without knowing the other.
And this is a classic example of what's referred to as an ill posed problem in
computer vision.
That in some sense you cant do it without making some sort of an assumption.
And a simple example can be seen here.
All right, so what do you see here?
What you see is an image stolen from the web.
But probably what you're probably seeing, is you see some sort of matte,
or, light-textured sphere, with a light shining,
probably from say this direction here.
You might even see this is just a little ridged in it there, and
then the light falls off and then there's a shadow-cast here.
Is that what you see?
>> Yes.
>> But actually, what's really there, of course, is this very flat monitor
with different pixels that are sort of violating the whole illumination thing.
Because they actually emit light themselves,
which violates the entire principle of what we were saying before.
And, in fact, your stereo, right?
My two eyes are looking at this thing and saying, this thing is totally flat.
And yet, my brain says okay, yeah, there's this nice rounded thing there.