Now that we our animation all set up and
hooked up in code,
we tie some sound to the experience.
For that, we need an audio clip.
Unity supports a variety
of sound formats.
And once we drag that audio
file into our project,
Unity automatically converts
it into an audio clip.
For this video,
we'll be using waves.wav.
In order to place that
audio clip into our scene,
we need to create an audio
source component.
Once we do that,
all we have to do is is drag our waves
clip onto the audio clip property.
Of all the components in Unity,
the audio source has a lot of
different properties that we can
play around with in order to
tweak how an audio clip sounds.
There's some really simple effects
like volume, pitch, and loop but
we also have some more complex
effects like bypass effects,
audio mixer groups, and reverb zones.
For VR, one of the most important
effects is spatial blend.
This dictates whether
the position of our audio and
the scene affects how we hear it.
Some sounds, like background music,
will want to be heard from any location,
in which case,
we use a 2D spatial blend.
Other effects, like an animal chirp
will sound much better if they come from
their own location,
in which case we'd use a 3D blend.
In VR, the spatial blend of our
audio gives us clues as to what
action is happening around us,
especially when we can't see it.
And at this point you might be asking,
how does Unity know how far
an audio source is from our camera?
And, to answer that,
if we look at our main camera,
we'll see an audio listener component.
In our scenes, we're only allowed
to have one audio listener, and
this acts as the position for
calculating all spatial audio.
Luckily, we get that by
default on all our cameras.
But if you ever notice
you don't hear any audio,
make sure to check that you have
this audio listener enabled.
Since we're using a background noise for
our waves,
we can keep our spatial blend for
the audio stores at 2D.
And if we hit play now, we can hear our
ocean in the background of our scene.
[SOUND]