For getting a list of movies by genre,
we use the /genre/(id)/movies method.
And as the documentation indicates,
only movies with ten or more votes, or
ratings, are included.
Then, to get a list of
a user's favorite movies,
the /account/(id)/favorite/movies
method should be used.
There's also a fun method called
/account/(id)/rated/movies, and
this returns a list of
the movies that users rated and
the movie's associated ratings.
To add or remove favorites, we'll use
the /account/(id)/favorite method.
This method is different than all
the methods we've seen before and
it uses the HTTP POST method.
It'll let us post data and
close in our request.
In this case, it'll be whether or
not this movie should be
added to our favorites list.