Here's a story about
a company with a problem.
Noodle Search runs the world's
best site for finding pasta.
Management rewards the developers for
shipping new features,
like gluten free rice Noodle search.
So the developers want the operations
team to push out new releases as quickly
as possible.
But sometimes when releases go out,
the production systems slow down.
Then the users start complaining to
tech support that they can't find their
linguine in a timely fashion, and half
their wonton queries are timing out.
Then operations goes and
installs additional servers and
everything gets better,
until the next release.
What are the causes of this problem?
Is it that the development
environment doesn't match production?
That new releases aren't
being tested for performance?
That operations should
automate the release process?
That the business isn't
anticipating its scaling needs?
Or that developers are being too
harsh to the operations staff?
Mark which ever of these
that you think apply.