Okay, cool, so
I can start adding different list names.
And I'm updating now to both
show the name and the owner.
And even though the owner's
not going to change in my
app from anonymous owner If I
was able to change this.
I could see that it actually
does update in the app.
So that's pretty cool.
All right but let's break the app,
that's a bit more fun.
Okay, so here I have this shopping
list class that we both just made.
And I am going to delete one of
these public getters because
no big deal this is probably
not that important.
And we'll go ahead and compile that.
We don't need that anymore.
Okay, so it compiles just fine, okay so
I'm going to run it on my phone.
And the first thing it
does is it crashes.
Well, that's no good.
Let's see what's going on here.
Okay, and I'm sorry that this is so hard
to read but if you have very good eyes,
you'll see that right here it says,
failed to bounce type.
So, if you accidentally forget one of
your getters you get a failed to D
bounce effort.
So, if you forget to add
one of your getters,
you actually get this
failed to D bounce error.
And this is what happens when
the underlying serialization library,
which is called
the Jackson Object Mapping Library,
can't turn your firebase data into
the Java object that you want to.
And this is the error that you get when
the underlying serialization library
which by the way is called
the Jackson Object Mapping Library.
Can't turn your fire base data into
the job object that you want it to.
It'll compile, but
it'll blow up at you and
give you this sort of
cryptically named error.
If you get errors it's probably
something that's happening in
your model POJO.