Let's show how you actually
compile a .x file.
Assume that we're using the same squared
example as in the previous videos.
In the file, the .x file for
that example is square.x.
You'll see that by using this .x file,
we will automatically generate
a bunch of the code that's used for the
client and the server-side processing.
To do this,
Sun RPC relies on a compiler, rpcgen.
And to generate C code,
rpcgen is used with the option -c,
so that full command is rpcgen -c,
and then square.x.
That's the .x XDR file.
The outcome of this operation will
be that a number of files will be
generated.
First, they will generate a header file,
square.h, that will have
all of the language-specific definitions
of data types and function prototypes.
Next, they will generate the code for
the client and the server-side stubs.
For the client, this is a proper stub,
for the server side code,
this actually also includes
the skeleton of the actual servers.
It has the main retaining.
The only thing that's not available
will be the actual implementation of
the service, of the procedure, and this
makes perfect sense since the compiler
has no way of knowing what exactly what
do we want a particular procedure to do.
In this case, clearing a number.
Finally, the compilation stub will also
generate a separate files, square_xdr.c.
And this will include some common code
that's related to the marshalling and
unmarshalling routines for all of all
of the data types, the arguments and
the results, that are used both at
the client and on the server-side.
If you take a look at the file
square_svc, which stands for
service, you will see
that it has two parts.
The first part is the main function for
the server and
that will include the code that,
that does the registration step and
also some additional
housekeeping co-operations.
In addition to main, the stubble
contain all of the code that's related
to the particular RPC service.
So in our squared case,
this is the square_prog service.
And, it is the first version of
that particular service so for
all of the procedures in that particular
service, the file will include
automatic regenerate code in
order to parse the request.
So as to determine which
particular procedure to be called
to generate the arguments,
all of the argument
marshalling corporations will be
invoked here, and other steps.
In addition, in the step file,
the auto-generated code will include
the prototype for the actual procedure
that's invoked in the server process.
For the square_proc procedure that we
describe, this is the procedure name.
And that will include also the _1,
that refers to the version number.
And this piece if code has to
be implemented by the developer,
this is not automatically generated.
The client stub will include a procedure
that's automatically generated,
squareproc_1.
And this will represent a wrapper for
the actual RPC call that the client
makes to the server-side process where
the implementation of the service,
this squareproc_1.svc
is actually called.
Once we have all of this, the developer
then writes the client application and
makes call to this wrapper function
that looks something like this,
y equals squareproc of x.
This very much looks like
a regular procedure call.
There is no need to create sockets,
create buffers,
copy data into the buffers, and
this is what makes RPC appealing.