Welcome back to Computer Vision.
The last lesson, we started talking about filtering as a way of
finding a specific pattern in an image.
We talked about template finding.
And the idea was that given some pattern, correlation or
convolution would be some way of finding that pattern in the image.
And the assume, we assumed that the,
that the goal thing that we were looking for was given to us.
And then there was also this idea that, well,
maybe we could just take the locations where this pattern was found.
And that became sort of a description of what we were looking for.
You could even think of that as describing the image,
although we didn't talk too much about that.
But again, that's the idea that you have,
you know what the important thing is that you're looking at.
But what about generic images?
Ones that you don't know in advance.
What's going to be in the picture.
What are some good, the word we sometimes use is features,
what are some good things to try to find in the picture,
that might capture a lot of the information there, and
sort of give you the essence of what you need to work on.