You mean like this board?
>> Hold on.
I have to think about this one
for a second.
I see that there's only one current
attack on this diagonal, so
when I move one of these queens,
I should be done.
>> Sure.
Why not try it out?
>> Okay.
Let's work with the queen
in the fourth column first.
I can't put it in the top most row,
because it gets attacked by the same
queen, as well as its diagonal neighbor.
But the next row down,
it's attacked both here and
here, in the next row down it's
attacked both here and here.
Hold it, there's no place on this board
I can put it without being attacked
horizontally, except where
I had it originally.
In fact, every possible spot makes the
problem worse, will cause more attacks.
>> Is there anything else we could do?
>> We'll have the same problem with
the queen in the second to last column.
Moving it down one row leads
to two attacks, here and here.
Going to the next row causes
two attacks, as well.
Every single move with this queen
gets more attacks, as well.
Moving any of the other six queens will
also cause an increase of attacks,
because they will be
attacked horizontally,
plus we'll still have
the original attack.
For example,
look at this leftmost queen.
Every row, except for the one it's in
currently will have another attack.
>> Does that mean
the problem is unsolvable?
>> No, I know the problem's solvable but
I seem to be stuck.
No one move will improve my situation.
This puzzle hurts my brain.
>> Maybe we can use a simpler
problem to figure out a solution and
then come back to this one later.
>> That's a great idea.