As a quiz, I would like for
you to consider DMA and
programmed IO in a hypothetical system.
For a hypothetical system,
assume the following,
it costs 1 cycle to perform a store
instruction to a device register,
and it costs 5 cycles to
configure a DMA controller.
Also, the PCI-bus is 8 bytes wide.
And also assume that all devices
in the system support both DMA and
programmed IO based operations.
With this in mind,
which device access method is best for
the following devices?
Keyboards or NICs?
The options to consider
are programmed IO, DMA, or depends.
These are the three answers you need
to provide for each of these devices.