Let's be a little more formal
about the nQueen's problem.
Given a current board,
we want to make the one move that can
most greatly improve the situation.
In fact, to simplify the discussion,
let's constrain ourselves to moving
a single Queen up or
down within its column.
Then we keep iterating until we reach
our goal of having zero attacks.
>> Given this board which
currently has 17 attacking pairs,
the best we can do with a single move is
to get the number of attacks down to 12.
For example,
if you move this queen here, you
reduce the number of conflicts to 12.
>> That's right.
But how do we figure
out which one to take?
Do we just select it randomly?
>> Seemed as good an idea as any.
>> Okay, so we can continue to iterate.
Hopefully reducing the number
of attacks with each move.
But what if we get into a situation
where no move decreases our number of
attacks?