It's pretty simple to fix that linear solution that we did before.
So do what we said before, solve for F.
And you can do SVD where that minimum eigenvector or you can
use the linear thing where you set it to 1, although I don't like that method.
Okay, you solve for an F.
Then what you do is you decompose your F using SVD again.
This is another SVD, another singular value decomposition.
And you're going to get out three terms, all right.
Remember SVD gives you UVD transpose, V is the lower-dimensional orthogonal
matrix of all unit vectors that are orthogonal with each other.
U is also orthogonal but of the full dimension.
Now, what did D stand for?
No, not dalmatian, not dysfunctional, despite what you might think.
D stood for diagonal, okay?
So it breaks down, it gives you a diagonal matrix.
Now if F is really a full ranked three by three matrix,
D is going to come out as a diagonal matrix with three non-zero elements.
And D, normal SVD, is produced in a decreasing magnitude, okay?
So it goes from largest to smallest.
So what we do is, we take the D that comes out,.
And I just wrote that as rst here, okay?
And t is smaller than s which is smaller than r.
And what we're going to do is we're going to create a new D, D hat.
And just set that less, that least value to 0.
Because it was supposed to be 0,
because that would be a rank 2 F would have a r, s, and 0.
So we make it 0, great.
Once we've done that we can build a new F,
which I'll call F hat, using the same U that we got the first time.
The same V that we got the first time, but
we substitute in this new D, right, D hat.
Which is the one that has only got two diagonal elements.
And that gives us a new fundamental matrix that has just rank 2.
When I apply that to the example that I showed you before,
you get epipolar lines that look like this.
Way, way better.
In fact, you can see here the camera was not moving perfectly straight.
It was moving off to the side just a little bit in that direction,
and here is the epipole, right?
All the epipolar lines go right through the epipole, so
we've got the good F, and all is happy in Oz.