This is pretty ugly, and we'd like to make it nicer, and
we're going to do that through two ways.
First, so here we have those uglier equa, equations and the first thing you'll
notice is kind of like before, we're dividing the x's and the y's by z.
All right.
And so that should tell you that see I've
wrote up here intrinsic parameters in non-homogeneous coordinates.
Well, guess what?
We're going to move to homogeneous coordinates by putting this whole thing in
a matrix formulation.
So now we can express the whole thing in homogeneous coordinates.
Notice that here we have z times u, z times v, z, so later when we convert back
from homogeneous to non-homogeneous, we divide by z, and we get what we want.
We have the x y z one over here, and we have this matrix in the middle.
So we can rewrite this as, sort of, this very simple equation where we have
a three-dimensional point in the camera frames.
So remember, we've gone from some world,
arbitrary world frame to the three-dimensional frame of the camera.
And we go from that to the homogeneous pixel representation,
like that, in the image.
And the matrix that takes them from the camera to the image,
that's the intrinsic matrix.
Okay, so that matrix represents the intrinsic parameters, all right.
Now fortunately, we can make it look even nicer than this.
The first thing to notice is that the last column of K,
when I write K as a three by four, the last column of K is zeros.
And that doesn't really do very much, so we can get rid of it.
And then we can do even more.
Here we have our kinder, gentler intrinsics.
We can use a simpler notation.
Like I said, we're going to remove that last column.
And we've gotten rid of the explicit thetas and things.
And you'll notice that we have the five degrees of freedom.
We have f, which is focal length, a, which is aspect ratio, s,
which is for skew, and cx and cy, those are the offsets.
By the way, remember I said we can have two different scales, right?
A scale for one, and, for u and a scale for v?
Or what we can have is a focal length and a relative scale between the two.
Normally, we tend to think of it that way, as a focal length.
That's the overall focal length of the image.
And then, if there is a non-uniform relationship between the width and
the height, we include that as an aspect ratio.
And that's why there are five degrees of freedom, okay.
Now, it turns out, this can get even easier, all right.
And the way it gets really easy is we assume a certain niceness of
the universe, okay.
The niceness of the universe that we might assume is, if we have square pixels,
if there's no skew, and if the optical center is actually in the middle, okay.
Then we have no a, we have no s, we have no cx, we have no cy.
All we have left is f.
F is the only degree of freedom left.
So when you're doing a calibration, sort of a lightweight calibration,
what you'll do is you'll just search for f, assuming that your optic axis is in
the middle, assuming there's no skew, and assuming that your pixels are square.