One of the big differences
between mobile and
desktop VR platforms is the concept
of 3DOF versus 6DOF tracking.
Now you might be wondering,
what's a DOF?
Well, DOF is short for
Degrees Of Freedom.
And it deals with how accurately
the VR system can track you.
For a VR headset, it's the difference
between knowing only where
you're looking and where you're
looking and located in the room.
Three degrees of freedom means your head
can be trapped when it rotates along
the x-axis, the y-axis and the z-axis.
This is what most
mobile VR platforms do.
Six degrees of freedom means your head
can also be tracked when it moves
along the x axis,
the y axis, the z axis.
Six tough tracking allows you to be
tracked as you move around the room.
High NVR systems allow you to do this.
So to recap, 3DOF means your head
rotations are accurately tracked.
Whereas, 6DOF means your head
rotations and positions are tracked.
Great.
Now that we've covered 3DOF versus 6DOF,
let's learn about how this
tracking is accomplished.