Before we start with the examples,
you should become familiar with
two cheatsheets I have for you,
the seven commandments of AutoLayout and
the guiding principles of AutoLayout.
Let's take a look at them.
The guiding principles of AutoLayout
are generic rules about wisdom
related to AutoLayout.
So the first one is,
we always start with StackViews and
only use constraints if we cannot
solve the problem with StackViews.
So StackViews first.
Start small, or not at all.
What this means is you should choose
a small part of your UI and start
from there, not the other way around,
from the bigger picture to the details.
Start with the details.
Work from the inside out.
This is related to the previous one.
We're always going to start with
some inner small part of the UI and
then grow from there.
This is a very important one,
trust the simulator only.
Why, because even though Xcode or
Interface Builder will provide you
with a pretty decent preview of how
your UI will look, it still has bugs.
So it will not always work.
So if you are sure that
your layout is correct but
it's not showing the way it
should on the preview simulated,
tried it on the simulator or
on a device.
And the most important of all,
don't panic, okay?
So AutoLayout is complex, but
trust me, there is a logic to it,
a bizarre one, but there is a logic to
it and you will soon understand it.
So stick to the principles, the
commandments, and remember, don't panic.
Let's take a look at the seven
commandments of AutoLayout.
These are specific techniques that you
will apply in all of the examples and
in any usage of
AutoLayout in the future.
First thing you should do is tweak
the properties of the StackView.
If that doesn't fix it,
we're going to use another StackView.
Usually we'll put that first
StackView inside of another one.
Still in trouble, then we tweak
the compression resistance or
the hugging priority of
the views inside the StackView.
Only if we reach this point should we
add constraints, but to the StackView.
If it still doesn't work, then we add
constraints to the views themselves.
Still in trouble?
If you have to connect views that
are within different StackViews,
then you should use
the fifth commandment.
We'll see this in an example.
And if everything else fails,
then use a filler view.
We will also see later what this means,
a filler view.
You're not expected to understand
all of this at this point.
So don't worry, we'll go through all
of the commandments along the examples.
Although I highly suggest that you write
these down or even tattoo them somewhere
because you're going to use them very,
very often.
Anyway, enough talk,
let's fire up Xcode.