Let's look at how this Gaussian filters can be used for smoothly.
Let's start off with our simple image here.
again, I'm just showing a simple example image.
Of course, now take a Gaussian with a variance of 1.
again, if you notice,
it's a much more peak and less distribution as you go away from the peak.
But gets down to 0 pretty quickly.
So the image, of course, is blurred, but appears to be relatively sharp.
As you go and increase the the variance here,
and now we have a Gaussian with a sigma of 3, gets more blurred.
Furthermore, as we go down and actually go to sigma 6 it gets even more blurred.
As we get to sigma 9 you can see the blurring, the Gaussian blurring,
is much more increased.
So here from this point to that point we're basically changing the variables of
how the Gaussian kernel sigma changes and it
basically then represents the extent of smoothing that we can play around with.