One piece of missing functionality from
the Conference Central application
is a function to return the list of
conferences that a user has registered
to attend.
We've implemented the functionality
to register for a conference, and
now user profiles have web
saved keys of conferences.
But you don't want to display keys,
you want to display conference names and
dates and such.
We've provided a code outline of the
getConferencesToAttend endpoints method.
Your task is to use all that you've
learned about dealing with entities and
keys to write the code that retrieves
these conferences from the data store.
You can find this outlying
code in TODO_7_Conference.py.
As usual,
as you complete this steps, check them
off here, then answer this question.
The instructions for this method
ask you to use ndb.get-multi,
instead of doing a loop over key.get.
Why do you think that is?
Do you think it's because the return
values fro ndb.get_multi are smaller and
use less memory than
the ones in key.get?
Do you think it's that get_multi makes
fewer requests to the datastore, or
do you think that it's just
the programmer's preferred style?