In this one we're talking about
a company, in particular payroll data,
who gets paid how much.
And so we have a file that stores data
that is created by a user who works for
the payroll department.
And obviously this user is
an employee of the company.
But let's say it has
a compensation information.
By the way, there is a large company
right next to the Georgia Tech
campus had a situation where
people's salaries were leaked.
And that happens when somebody shares
the information, either by mistake or
by design, with others of whom
this information should be shared.
So here we're talking
information of that kind.
Access to it has to be controlled.
So what kind of policy is going to help
us provide the right kind of access
control for it.
There are two options.
It could either be DAC or
it has to be MAC.
So I want you to think about it and
then we'll discuss which
answer is the right one.