So it's time to introduce
the Kalman filter.
The Kalman filter is a method
of tracking linear dynamical
systems with Gaussian noise.
And what's really cool is,
both the predicted states and
the corrected states are Gaussians,
right?
So you're only maintaining the mean and
the covariance of your state,
in order to run your filter.
And also, the calculations
are very straightforward.
I'm not even going to
derive the equations here.
We'll be able to get some intuitions.
But you can show that it's a relatively
straightforward manipulation of
these linear matrices.
So in pictures,
the Kalman Filter can be,
can be described as the following,
all right.
You start off in the blue here is top
left, that's your prior belief, right?
So let's oppose we have some density.
Now what kind of shape is it?
It's a Gaussian, why?
because this is a Kalman Filter, okay?
Kalman filters are built on Gaussians.
You want to have a non-Gaussian?
Too bad, this is a Kalman filter,
things are Gaussians.
We'll do some other little stuff later.
For now, everything is.
So the first thing that happens is,
in this picture,
it's referred to as
a deterministic shift.
Remember when we multiply
it by that linear system.
So basically, that's the part
that you know what happens.
And that's shown here in green,
where the,
the Gaussian bump is just
slid over to the right.
So if I'm a Gaussian bump, which I've
been accused of on a variety of times,
the first thing that happens
is I slide over to my right.
That would be your left.
Now Megan is wondering,
should I move the camera?
I don't know what this
guy's going to do.
I'm going to come back in a minute.
All right.
Anyway, so the first thing
we do is we slide, beca, and
we know that's the deterministic part.
Then comes the part that's referred to
in this picture, and I left it in here
because I think it's a cool way of
thinking about it, stochastic diffusion.
But it's basically
the addition of noise,
and this is referred
to the process noise.
So now we've done two things.
We've deterministically stepped one
way and we've grown a little fatter.
Both problems.
Anyway, the idea is,
when I'm taking a step forward in time,
I use the part that I know.
I know, I think I was moving,
you know, three meters per second and
it's a second later.
So I think I've moved three,
but I also know that I'm not
perfect in my knowledge, right?
That's never my problem,
that's somebody else's.
But, no, anyway, I know I'm not
perfect in my knowledge, so
therefore, you know over
here my variance is wider.
Okay.
So I've now expanded my uncertainty.
Then what happens is I take a
measurement, and that's shown here as Z.
Okay, so I take some measurement and
what happens is if you take a look
at the density in the blue here,
you'll notice that it is shifted
back a little bit based upon the Z.
And it has also gotten narrower, okay.
It's very important to think about
this in the Kalman sense, and
we're going to do more of
this in a minute, right.
We shift, expand, measure, shrink.
Okay, actually, shift, expand,
measure, correct, shrink.
That shrinkage happens because
whenever you take a measurement,
you're getting new information.
New information can only
reduce your uncertainty.
That's going to come back in
a minute to be a little strange.