So, rotation tends to be difficult for
a lot of developers, and
I think especially new developers,
they don't completely understand.
So, I think just having a very basic,
hey,
do you understand some
of the life cycles.
You don't necessarily, I don't think
there's much use in having you draw all
of it out, because you have
that your documentation.
But understanding when and where sales
persist and what to expect from that.
So, Sam for instance,
he understood that partiables would be
a great solution to what he was
looking for, and that's great.
I didn't fault him for
not knowing why serializable is
bad because it's a bad solution.
So, that's completely fine.
And, I think if you had
more Java knowledge,
you understand why that's probably
not a very performance option.
But, it's still good that he knew
the correct answer in Android.