To figure this out,
I first created a variable to store
the number of problem students.
Then I wrote a similar loop to earlier,
where I look at each account
key in the enrollment table and
check whether that account key was
present in the daily engagement table.
I also added another check to see
whether the join date was equal to
the cancel date.
I could have also looked at whether
days to cancel was equal to zero.
Then, if there was a missing student for
whom the two dates were not equal,
I added one to the total
number of problem students.
At the end of the loop,
I looked at that number and
I saw that there were still
three surprising records left.