Clark-Wilson, remember, defines as
transactions or procedures that
you're able to execute, and you can
define who should be able to do what and
things like that, based on what
they're doing in the organization.
It doesn't address the conflict thing.
The conflict thing is addressed.
So, the correct answer is Chinese Wall.
So remember,
we talked about conflict classes?
So similar, for example, airlines all
because they compete with each other
would be in a single conflict class.
And then we said, as soon as you
access one company's information,
you're not allowed to access from any
other company the same conflict class.
That was the Chinese Wall policy.
That's what would work here in this
case, because if lawyers lurking on this
competing companies, if the same
lawyer does that, that is a conflict.
We want to avoid that, and
you avoid conflict of interest by
using the Chinese Wall policy.