In the build.gradle for your app, you'll
need to tell the app that you're using
the service libraries and
you can do that with this line, compile
'con.google.android.gms:play-services:6-
.5+'.
Now, one thing to note is that you
really should use the full version
number here instead of
the + the way I've done.
At the time of recording this,
this would be 6.5.87.
But you might have a later version.
If you have any problems compiling, it
might be because this number is wrong.
To check what you have installed, you
can look in your maven repository and
you'll see the libraries
with their version number.
Check the instructor notes to see how
to find the repository on your machine.
But I'll just demonstrate it here for
this machine.
So first of all,
you need to find the SDK path.
And in Android Studio, there's a nice
little trick that helps you to do that.
Simply open the SDK Manager and you'll
see the SDK path is listed at the top.
So once you have the SDK path,
if you use a terminal like this,
you can change to the SDK path by just
saying cd and the path directory itself.
In my case, Wacky Users, Wack Udacity,
Wack Library, Wack Android, Wack SDK.
Now once you're in the SDK path,
you can take a look at
extras/Google/M2repository/com/Google/A-
ndroid/GMS/play-services.
And you'll see all the versions of the
play-services library that are in there.
And in this case,
the most recent one is 6.5.87.
So if I were to go into my build.gradle,
I could just use 6.5.87 instead of 6.5+.
But I'm just leaving it here for
convenience right now.
But, again, strongly recommended.
Find the latest version
that you're using and
put that full number here instead of
the 6.5+ that I'm actually doing.