All right, you're done.
Here's how I ended up changing
the layouts in the forecast view.
Let's first look at what I had to do
in activity_main.xml to the toolbar.
This one was pretty easy,
because I already had a linear layout
containing a toolbar in our image view.
As well as this fragment.
Basically, all I had to do was add this
new margin top for action bar size and
set the layout_height, or image view,
to listpreferreditemheight.
Then, I set the layout_gravity
to center_horizontal and
I have it wrap our content,
rather than match parent.
This will create the additional
height we want for the app bar.
And it'll actually center the image
view inside of the entire toolbar.
So if we had left this as match parent,
when it tried to center the image it
would've actually not known how to
take into account the fact that
we have an overflow menu, and so
it wouldn't actually be centered.
Other than that, we set
the background to color primary here.
That's really not helping us,
because we don't really need it [LAUGH].
And finally, for
the toolbar, we actually set
the layout height to wrap_content.
So it'll grow in response
to this margin top.
It's very important.
And that's it, pretty straight
forward for activity main.
Lets look at list item forecast today.
Now, if you were paying attention,
you notice that this grid layout looks
almost identical to the grid layout
that's actually in the detail view.
Now you guys didn't actually
end up coding that one up, so
if you took the time to code
this one up, all the better.
It's pretty straight forward and
we covered it pretty completely
in the previous lecture.
We just remember we have
two columns in our grid.
Breaking apart our grid view,
we start off with our date,
which it uses to add vertical
white space by about 16 pixels.
All right, let's take a look at
how our date text view works.
It has a margin bottom and top, and
that adds 16 DP of space above and
below the layout.
We're actually centering
the text inside of the layout,
rather than centering the layout itself.
So we're actually going to fill
the entire space horizontally.
And we're going to span both columns.
And then we have our icon.
Once again, we're using maxHeight and
maxWidth, based upon our dimensions.
So that if things come in from the net,
it's not going to change our layout, or
at least it's not going to make our
layout bigger than we want it to be.
We set a column weight of 1 here,
because we want to make sure that
all of our columns are participating
in getting extra space.
Same thing here for the high textview,
the forecast textview, and
the low textview.
These are all handled
pretty much the same.
So the one thing to note here is
that the layout margin bottom here
actually provide 16 DP of margin for
the entire row,
even though it's actually only
a part of this particular cell.
Finally, let's take a look
at list item forecast.
In this one we're not doing
anything particularly special.
We're using frame layouts and
linear layouts, as we always have.
The biggest difference between this and
the last one is that, one,
we're using proper
dimensions everywhere,
We've actually eliminated a linear
layout that used to be in this section.
As you can see,
we've really tried to make sure that
we're using dimensions everywhere.
This helps to create a sort of style for
our application that's consistent,
especially since we're trying to go for
material design, which is very explicit
about how the spacing should be.
And here's what this looks
like when we run it.
As you expect, it looks pretty
much like our original diagrams.
Nice stuff.
And that's it!
Pretty similar to what you
came up with or different?
Again, there's not
necessarily a right answer.
But the goal is to try and
create a fairly simple layout.