We know how to handle an explicit intent
where we know exactly what activity we
want to start.
But what about the times
when we don't know or
don't care how our requests
will be fulfilled?
Enter implicit intents.
If we want to retrieve a contact or
an image,
or call a number, implicit intents
indicate an action to be done and
an optional bit of data
on which to execute it,
like picking a contact from the contacts
content provider, or dialing a number.
Do we really need to know which
application will fulfill the request?
No.
And if we try to specify the app, it may
not even be available on your user's
device, and if it is installed the user
may have different preferences.
For example, they may want all of their
camera requests to go to Open Camera
instead of the full camera app.
If I only have one app on my phone that
can fulfill a particular intent request,
it's automatically run.
Otherwise, the Android OS
will let me choose and
indicate if I want all future requests
to be handled by the same app.