Before you go any further, let's take
a quick moment to look at the truth
tables for Logical AND and Logical OR.
Now truth tables are just the way
of representing all the possible
combinations of inputs for
a logical expression.
Here, I have the truth tables for
Logical AND and Logical OR.
The way to read these tables is
the first two columns, A and
B, are representative of Boolean values.
When both of these values are combined,
the third column represents what
the resulting outcome would be for
Logical AND and Logical OR.
Now, what is interesting
about these tables, and
you might have noticed this already
is that in some combinations,
the value of B has no impact on
the result of the logical expression.
Let me highlight these tables in
another way so you can see what I mean.
There we go.
So, if you look at these rows,
you'll notice that regardless of the
value of B, the value of A is the value
that's actually determining
the result of the logical expression.
For logical AND, if the value of A is
false, the value of B doesn't matter.
The combined value will always be false.
And for Logical OR, if the value for
A is true, then the value of B doesn't
matter because the combined
value will always be true.
And this makes sense,
just think about it.
In our previous example,
where we were trying to decide if
Julia was going to the park,
two conditions needed to be true.
Colt had to not be busy and
the weather had to be nice.
If the value for the variable Colt
happened to be anything other than not
busy, it wouldn't have mattered if
the weather was going to be nice.
Julia would not have gone to the park
because both conditions weren't true.
This type of behavior is
called short circuiting,
because later arguments in a logical
expression are not considered because
the first argument already
satisfies the condition.
For logical AND,
if the first value is false,
you don't need to see what
the later argument is going to be.
The entire expression will
always evaluate to false.
And for logical OR,
if the first value is true,
you don't need to see what the later
arguments are going to be because
the entire expression will
always evaluate to true.