Now, we're talking about what
the user is going to type in.
So the user for the login field we have
in the form, that's the value that
goes to this variable that we have here,
is actually typing something strange.
So what your types is, in these codes,
it's the space code, or 1 = 1.
And it's important that these
two dashes here that we have,
they really say that everything
that follows is a comment, and
is to be ignored, is not to be executed.
So the way to think about this is that,
I'm not typing anything for password.
I'm not typing anything for PIN.
For login, I'm typing this
information that I have here.
So, if I did that, this script that we
have here is going to generate a query.
And that query is going to be run
against the database that we have
as we did before.
So the quiz question here is asking,
well what is going to happen
when this query is run?