We're now ready to run our test and
collect data from our stores for
March 20th to May 28th.
The first treatment group of stores will
change the price of their facials to
76.99 and the second group will change
the price of their facials to 87.99.
After collecting data for
ten weeks, we'll be ready to
perform the A/B Analysis.
Let's start by preparing our data.
We have two data files
available to use our analysis.
The point of sale transactions
file contains transaction data for
each invoice where each row contains
a line item for the invoice.
The point of sale transaction file
has transactions from January 1st,
2013 through June 29th, 2014.
We also have an Excel file with
information on the stores that we used
as treatment units.
This data file contains the store
identifier and the price level for
facials at each store.
We need to prepare the data, so we can
leverage the Altiris A/B Trend tool and
A/B Controls tool to create
sets of control stores
that we can use to compare
to the treatment units.
Using our two data files,
we'll create three data files.
The weekly store traffic for
the A/B Trend tool, the store list for
the A/B Controls tool that will use
to match treatment units to control
units and the sales data for
the A/B Analysis tool.
To start with, we need to filter the
data to only include transactions from
February 7th,
2013 through May 28th, 2014.
Remember that the test period lasted ten
weeks from March 28th to May 28th, 2014.
Data is arrogated to a weekly level
turn move missing values which
would cause the A/B Trend and
A/B Controls tools to error.
First, we'll create a table that holds
the weekly store traffic information
that contains the number of
invoices per week at each store.
We'll use this data with A/B Trend tool
to create measures of trend and seasonal
patterns that can be used in helping
to match treatment to control units.
For our analysis, we use the week and
week begin fields to
calculate the weekend date.
The weekend date is the field
that we need for analysis, but
we might be able to use the other dates,
so we'll leave them in our data.
Next, we need to create a data table
that shows the stores, the region and
the group that the store is in,
controller treatment.
And if treatment, what was the price
of the facial at that store?
This data will be used with the A/B
Controls tool using information from
the A/B Trends tool to create control
treatment pairs for the analysis.
Finally, we'll aggregate the sales data,
to show the weekly sales and
gross margin per store of all
transactions that included a facial to
perform an analysis.
Sounds like a lot data preparation, but
it's much less work than it sounds.