Okay, great, but what do we do when we
get to level nine in our mini-max tree?
>> That's when things
really get interesting.
We want to evaluate
the goodness of a node at level
nine based on how much we expect it to
lead to a win for our computer player.
Can we create an evaluation
function that takes in each
game board generated level nine of our
mini-max game tree, return a number that
we can use to compare that node to
all the other nodes at that level?
>> Well we know the only way to win
is to have our computer player have
moves left at the end of the game.
Maybe our computer player should
maximize the number of moves it has?
>> That sounds right.
We want an evaluation function that
returns a higher number depending on how
good the board is for
our computer player.
With ann evaluation function like
simply counting the number of moves our
computer player has
available at a given node.
The player would select
branches in the mini-max tree
that lead to spaces where our
player has the most options.
It seems like a really good idea.
Let's call that evaluation function,
Number My Moves for convenience.
Why don't we test it out on our
simple five-move game board and
see how well it works?
>> Let's do it.