Creating one cube is kind of cool.
But what about creating 100 cubes?
What about 1,000?
Try doing that in the Unity
editor just using your mouse.
Ouch!
Stuff like that is
better done with code.
Let's try it.
Okay, back in the Unity editor,
go ahead and
create a new script
called ManyObjectMaker.
Okay, go ahead and open that up.
Just like last time,
let's add two lines of code to
create an object using a reference.
Now, let's write some code to
create a long line of 1,000 cubes.
First of all, comment out the line
that starts with Object.Instantiate.
This way we can reference the code for
later, but Unity will ignore the line.
Let's talk about comments for a second.
Comments are a great way to write
programming notes to yourself and
others.
And in this case, they're also a very
useful way to keep code around so
that we can reference it later.
Okay, let's go back to the code.
Below the comment,
add the following lines.
This is called a for loop, you'll see
them all the time in programming.
Loops are a big part of programming,
and this is just one kind of loop.
So, what does a for loop do?
Well, this loop executes a set
of instructions 1,000 times.
And how do I know that?
Well, let's talk a bit more about for
loops.
So here's a for loop that looks very
similar to the one we just wrote.
When Unity hits this very first line,
it creates a variable called i.
And it sets its value to zero.
Right after that, it checks to
see if i is less than 1,000.
Since it is, because i equals to zero,
Unity executes the command
between the braces.
In this case,
we mark that with do stuff.
When Unity hits the closing brace,
it jumps back to the top, and
it adds one to i.
That's what the ++ means here.
So, now i holds a value of one.
Right after that, Unity checks again
to see if i is less than 1,000.
And it is, because i is equal to one,
so we execute the same code again.
So, do stuff happens again.
Now this goes on and on and
on, until i is equal to 1,000.
And at that point, Unity exits the loop,
because i is 1,000,
and 1,000 is not less than 1,000.
So, the next thing that it executes
is the line labeled finished.
Okay, so a for
loop is really just a very succinct way
to tell Unity to do
something a bunch of times.
All right, let's go back to the code.
Let's add some new code
below the do stuff comment.
This line looks almost exactly like the
last instantiate command, doesn't it?
Notice we're just changing the location
where the object will be created.
We're setting the x coordinate to i.
And remember, that i goes from 0
to 1,000, because of the for loop.
Okay, save the script,
and go back to Unity.
Just like last time,
let's create a new empty game object.
Let's call it MyManyObjectMaker.
Let's drag our script onto it.
Let's go up and create a new cube, and
drag our cube into the Object to
Create slot, and now press Play.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Voila.
You just created 1,000
cubes in an instant.
That's a lot of cubes.
At this point,
take some time to play with the loop.
Can you make the cubes be stacked on top
of each other instead of laying side
by side?
Can you make X, Y, and
Z change at the same time?
Have fun.
Loops are an incredibly
powerful programming tool.