Hey, there!
Welcome to the content providers lesson.
Now, in the Android framework,
there are four key app components that
all developers need to understand to be
truly effective Android app creators.
They are activities, services, broadcast
receivers, and content providers.
>> In this lesson,
we're focusing on content providers.
Here you'll learn how to use
a pre-existing content provider
which is an important skill to
master before building you're own.
>> Now you're probably wondering
what exactly is a content provider?
To start off, we'll talk a little bit
about content providers in general.
When to use them, when not too, and
why you'd ever want to create your own.
>> After that you'll learn how to use
a content provider to grab user data
from your user's phone and
display in an app you build.
>> All right, well I'm pretty excited
to talk about data persistence.
Are you excited to talk
about data persistence?
>> Yes.
>> Yay!
All right.
Let's dive in.