Now, if I were to diagnose
what's wrong with our app,
I'd see that it's suffering from
an acute case of long term memory loss.
Meaning that it doesn't have
proper data persistence.
So this is exactly what we were
talking about in our last lesson.
Everything now is currently
stored in temporary memory and
we're not persisting data to
long term storage, as needed.
So in the previous lesson,
you learned all about SQLite.
So the next step we need to do
is figure out how to create and
modify SQLite databases
in our Android code.
So as a side note here,
you'll commonly see databases
represented as a cylinder like this
in diagrams even outside this course.
And if you'd like to learn more
of the history of why, well,
I suggest checking out the link
in the instructor's notes below.
And if you're a history buff like me I
think you'll find it pretty fascinating.
Now, I could just tell you how to
do this creating the database, but
instead let's take a look at
the official android documentation
which has a lot of good steps
that you can refer back to
When using SQLite in
Android in the future.
So to get us started,
let's do a Google search to find
where that information lives
in the Android documentation.
So I'm going to search up,
SQLite Android database example.
Now, looking to our results,
this second one here is what we want,
Saving Data in SQL databases.
Now, from this documentation,
we see that it takes two basic steps
to setup a SQLite and Android.
And then, after that, we can start
interacting with the database in a way
that mirrors our interaction that
we did in the terminal before.
So the first step needed is to create
a schema in the contract class and
in step two, is to create
a database using an SQL helper.
After we do those two steps,
this web page gives instructions for
how we can do the various CRUD
commands that we are familiar with,
the ones such as creating, reading,
updating, and deleting our data.
So here they're listed as put
information into a database,
read information from a database, delete
information, and then update a database.
So right now let's focus on the first
two, putting data into the database, and
then reading it back out again.
But before we do those two,
let's start with step one.
So creating a schema and
a contract class.