So let's now actually think
about creating a parametric
representation of it.
Put some variables and
see how those variables change.
Let's basically say that we
are looking for a function P,
which is basically the intense
distribution at any point in space.
So P is the intensity
distribution at this point and
now we'd like to figure
out how that changes.
Again, just to simplify, we can
always imagine this to be a sphere.
So just to look at this now,
how would we parametrize it.
Of course, any point on the sphere,
if i was to traverse it,
there are two ways I can traverse it.
Right?
I can traverse it on the axis of
rotation this way, which basically
captures the slice in any direction.
Then of course, force the elevation.
The lo, longitude,
latitude kinds of information.
So two angles could actually let me
traverse any point of this sphere.
So that basically says,
I have two angles, theta and phi.
If I had those two angles if I could
measure at any point here in this
sphere, I could now
traverse this whole sphere.
Okay?
So from this point on, I basically
need to be able to take any vector and
I have two different angles
that could represent it.
So P would be determined by these
two parameters, theta and phi.
Now, in the extreme case, let's imagine
this is a huge sphere very far away and
in the infinity.
Then of course, each and every one
of those regions would be a plane.
Traverse that plane I would actually
just be looking at x and y.
So, in an extreme situation,
we can almost kind of say, as the other
parameterization to point out any
information and this way would be,
this as I said was a far away point
on the sphere would be just x and y.
So, of course, another parameterization,
we looked at in these two dimensions
would be P with the parameters x and y.
Of course, remember,
light has color, has,
which of course is represented
by various wavelengths.
So we need to actually also model that,
which is the wavelength of light.
And of course, as we learn, when we
actually start looking at videos and
stuff like that.
Any scenes changes over time and
we actually interested capturing of
course the dynamics of the scene.
Irrespective of captured on video or
not scenes are always changing, so
we need to represent
the time aspect of it too.
So, of course,
now we need to add two more parameters.
Lamba, which is of course is
the wavelength, t which is the time.
We can do it for both the angle
version or the string x and y version.
So that's how we would now start
representing a light field.
Let's dig deeper into this one.
So now of course, this point,
the one we're looking at,
also is basically a viewing point.
Right?
In the whole 3D world, I have a point,
I need to know where the location
of this thing is too.
When we talked about where
are two ways of capturing images,
we also said that we need to know
the location of the camera itself.
So now the viewing point
is also important, right?
If I view a scene from this point or
that point, things are different.
I need to capture that and
that's another set of parameters.
So we can add those into our function.
So now, if you notice we basically have
the orientation of the ray of light.
Location of the ray of light in 3D,
lambda colors and frequencies and
stuff like that and time.
Again, a similar version for
this could also be generated,
where now we basically look at x and y.