If you think about it, the only thing
that we can directly observe is the x,
y coordinate of the target.
Yes, we could try to detect
the pendulum rod or other components,
but that may not be as reliable.
So, this is the only thing that needs
to be in our measurement model.
The same x, y location can
serve as our system state.
However, since the motion of
the pendulum is constrained by the fixed
length rod, assuming it is fixed length,
it's better to compress the state.
It really only has one state variable.
That is theta.
Again, this is assuming that l and
r are constants.
When analyzing a dynamic system,
it is very important to identify what
are its real degrees of freedom.
Sometimes, the state variables
you need to keep track of may
not be immediately apparent.
We will see examples of
such systems later on.