So let's go through each of
these audio focused states.
So for this first one here,
AUDIOFOCUS_GAIN, the description of
this would be that it gains audio focus
back again after having lost it earlier,
and what we should we do in our
Miwok app when we enter this state?
Well we should resume
playing the audio file.
Now for the second audio focus state,
AUDIOFOCUS_LOSS, a description of it is
that it's a permanent loss of audio
focus and as it applies to our
Miwok App, audio focus loss will stop
the MediaPlayer and release resources.
Now the third state,
AUDIOFOCUS_LOSS_TRANSIENT, so
this state temporarily
loses audio focus.
In our Miwok app,
that means we pause the audio file.
And in this last audio focus state,
AudioFocus_Loss_Transient_Can_Duck,
that means a temporary
loss of audio focus.
And we can duck or
lower volume if applicable.
In our Miwok app, that means that
we can pause the audio file.
Remember that each part of the word
pronunciation is important to be heard.