Wouldn't this also be dependent on
the position of the handle as well?
>> I just want to know
the number of lines displayed.
>> Okay, so
the view port's height would give
you the number of lines that you need.
>> Well, not exactly, go on.
>> So.
In some cases.
Assuming that the file is big enough,
then whatever the size of your
viewport is, say it's 100 at the max.
Then you can get all 100 lines because
there's going to be maybe some extra
[CROSSTALK]
>> Okay, so
the maximum number of lines that you can
display is the size of the viewport,
if there's enough lines in the file.
>> Right.
>> Okay?
>> And I guess conversely, you could
have a situation where you have a plenty
big enough view port, but your,
you might have a one line file.
So you'd only need the one line.
>> Okay, so
what is the number of lines displayed
as a function of those two factors?
>> Okay, so,
given the size of
the number of lines and
the file, it would be, okay.
I guess start with view port size,
view port height.
So view port height minus the-
>> So as you can kind of guess here,
it's a little tricky to come up with
an answer to this on the fly and
it's clearly not going to be the case
that our UML diagram can't express it.
And we're going to need some
other mechanism to do that.
Clearly the number of lines is
limited by the size of the view port.
You can't display more
lines than will fit.
It is also limited by the number
of lines in the file.
It can't display lines
that aren't there.
The actual number of lines that's
displayed is the minimum of these two.
>> Okay.
>> Okay?
And we can't express
this in the diagram.
We'll have to use some
other mechanism and
that mechanism is called OCL which
is the Object Constraint Language.
This is a part of UML that's
a textual part that allows us to
more precisely express various
requirements that we have to deal with.
And we're going to have to
bring that into our model in order to
deal with this particular situation.
The fact that the number of lines shown
depends on both the file size and
the viewport size indicates that there's
a relationship between these two
components.
We call this the line's
visible association.
We can show its existence graphically
with a labeled line between the two
classes.