It's important that you
use the view holder.
To cache the view objects that you're
going to be populating with data or
images.
When the Recycler view is
first being populated.
You call find view by ID for
each view that will be showing
data from the adaptor.
This search can be expensive,
especially if you have a hierarchy
of views in your list item.
So it's best to do it once and
cache those views in a view holder.
This way,
you can access those views later without
having to look them up repeatedly.
If you don't use a view holder
calling find view by ID for
each view can get out
of hand pretty quickly.
But don't take my word for it.
Let's try a quiz to
understand it a bit better.