So building on that concept let's, define, what computational photography is,
and what it combines, basically it combines computing, the ability to convert
information into a digital representation, also using digital sensors,
which they basically provide us with digital information, this makes it all
computable, that is processing, and all that kind of stuff can be done with it.
We can actually use, a more advanced optics with this cameras do require optics,
we'll cover this in detail also.
Actuators, because now I can actually put an actuators to actuate, for
example, each and every optic,
how the sensor does a variety of things, then smart lights, I can actually also
put in,lights that have some sort of computation associated with them.
So this computation is involved with the sen, the sensor, the optics,
the actuators, and also the smart lights, so in essence, what that basically
means is, it combines all of them to generate newer forms of cameras, sensors,
newer forms of artifacts that actually let you do a lot more with photography.
So in essence, computational photography aims to
do a lot more than traditional film or even traditional digital cameras do.
So it basically now gives you a newer paintbrush to draw with light, all right,
not just the traditional one where the passive process of exposing a film, or
even a sensor to the light in an environment capturing and preserving it or
sharing it afterwards, while that is actually a great pipeline, we all love it,
but now, using computational photography, perhaps we can do more, and perhaps
extend beyond the limitations, assuming we consider those to be limitations,
I personally think there's nothing wrong with traditional photography,
I love to do it myself, but this now gives us a newer medium.