But look down here into
this safe profile method.
This is supposed to save a profile
that the user has submitted and
return the updated profile.
But right now all it does is well,
very same thing as get profile.
Now what this should do
is take display name and
t-shirt size from a post request and
update the output accordingly.
It's not going to save anything yet, but
it should return the same
thing that it's given.
And that's your job in the first
programming exercise for
this conference central app.
You should modify the save profile
function to use the appropriate
messages.message class from models.py,
and
pick the one that can send two fields,
displayName and teeShirtSize.
Then for the method to be able
to return the changed values,
you'll have to pass that request
up to the doProfile function.
Complete the steps outlined in TODO
1 and deploy the app locally and
test by changing display name and
t-shirt size in the request.
You should see the changed
values in the response.
Once you're done,
check off the completed steps and
enter your appspot project ID.