Well, now we have fixed our web app so
users can't post JavaScript into it and
create endless spam.
But all of that spam is
still in the database.
How do we clean it up?
Or for that matter, if some user of our
forum posted something awful into it,
how would we get rid of that post?
We have a couple of options here.
First, let's try replacing the spam
post to something innocuous like,
say, the word Cheese!
We can do that from the psql
database console, but to do it,
we're going to need a new SQL command,
the update command.
Update is the SQL command for
changing values in existing rows.
Unlike insert,
it doesn't create new rows.
Instead, it replaces the value
of a named column with a new
value in each row where
this restriction is true.
The where restriction on update
works like the one on select, but
if you leave it off entirely, the update
will apply to every row in the table,
which is usually not what you want.
But you can always do a select first
with that restriction to make sure that
your update affects the right rows.
But how are we going to
find the right posts?
It would be a big pain to have to type
out the whole spam post contents so
we can match it with
the equals operator.
Here's a more fitting operator,
the like operator.
Like takes a value,
usually a text column,
on the left side and
a pattern on the right.
And just because you really
needed one more meaning for
the percent sign, SQL patterns use
it to mean any string can go here.
So, now in the psql console,
use the update command to replace all
the horrible spam posts in your database
with something innocuous like cheese.
To check your work, reload the forum
page or do select star from
posts in psql and check that
all the spam has been replaced.