[Narrator] This is the belief state space
for the sensor-less vacuum problem.
So we started off here.
We drew the circle around this belief state.
So we don't anything about where we are,
but the amazing thing is,
if we execute actions, we can gain knowledge
about the world even without sensing.
So let's say we move right,
then we'll know we're in the right-hand location.
Either we were in the left, and we moved right
and arrived there, or we were in the right
to begin with, and we bumped against the wall
and stayed there.
So now we end up in this state.
We now know more about the world.
We're down to 4 possibilities rather than 8,
even though we haven't observed anything,
and now note something interesting,
that in the real world, the operations
of going left and going right are
inverses of each other, but
in the belief state world
going right and going left are not inverses.
If we go right, and then we go left,
we don't end up back where we were
in a state of total uncertainty, rather
going left takes us over here
where we still know we're in 1 of 4 states
rather than in 1 of 8 states.
Note that it's possible to form a plan that
reaches a goal without ever observing the world.
Plans like that are called conform-it plans.
For example, if the goal is to be
in a clean location
all we have to do is suck.
So we go from one of these 8 states
to one of these 4 states and,
every one of those 4,
we're in a clean location.
We don't know which of the 4 we're in,
but we know we've achieved the goal.
It's also possible to arrive
at a completely known state.
For example, if we start here,
we go left; we suck up the dirt there.
If we go right and suck up the dirt,
now we're down to a belief state
consisting of 1 single state that is
we know exactly where we are.
Here's a question for you:
How do I get from the state where I know
my current square is clean,
but know nothing else, to the belief state
where I know that I'm in the right-hand side
location and that that location is clean?
What I want you to do is click on the
sequence of actions, left, right, or suck
that will take us from that start to that goal.