First, the answer for generalization is D, subclassing.
Subclassing is one way of expressing generalization relationships in code.
The answer for aggregation is A, Collection Classes.
Collection classes are designed to support aggregation.
Examples in Java include ArrayList, List, Set, and so on.
The answer for Invariants is B, Methods and Constructors.
Constructors are responsible for establishing invariants in the first place.
Subsequently, each method is also responsible for maintaining them.
And the answer for States is C, Enumerations.
Simple states can be modeled as enumerations, such as moods like happy,
sleepy, sad.
Java supports adding behaviors to enumeration instances,
enabling custom actions.