So I'd like to quiz you a number of times on something that's really essential to
the problem of Object Recognition.
In Object Recognition, you're given an image of an object
and you care to understand what the nature of the object really is--
like, for example, you might look at the image of a plane and say it's a plane.
You might look at the image of a person and say it's a person.
A key concept in Object Recognition is called invariance,
which means there is natural variations of the image
that don't affect the nature of the object itself
and you wish to be invariant in your software
to those natural variations.
So what I will do is I'm going to run a couple of
invariances by you and I'd like you to help me
which invariance I'm referring to.
And here are the possible invariances:
Scale, Illumination, Rotation, Deformation, Occlusion, and View Point.
I understand--none of these words you've seen before,
so I am really appealing to your intuition here
and your sense of the English language.
So here is the object,
and we wish to recognize this object.
And, as I'm illustrating, the object might vary in some important dimension.
And I wonder what type of invariance you or I, with it, must possess
to be able to recognize this object.
So here is the list.