To briefly summarize the Viola-Jones
face detector, couple of key ideas.
First of all, they're going to use these
rectangular features and really the big
idea was the integral image that makes
it easy to compute those rapidly.
Second, they used AdaBoost for
doing both feature selection and
for training the classifier in general.
We didn't talk a lot about that here.
Sometimes I talk more about it, but,
these days you just go look up AdaBoost,
it's easy enough to implement.
The really useful idea
was the cascade filter,
an, and
other people had done cascades and
various kinds of things, but, the way it
was applied to face detection was here.
Training is very s,
not very s, training is slow.
Remember those 180,000 different
possible features, and you try them and
you're looking for
all these weak learners.
So there's a lot of potential
weak learners to choose from.
But, detection run time is very fast.
So when I pick up my little camera or
I point my I my smartphone,
it can find the faces very quickly.
And it is really, really effective.
It is rare to see a paper turn into
a both commercial technology and
impact the field so
dramatically, so quickly.
And, you know, that's some measure
of the effectiveness of the paper.
And neither Paul nor
Mike gave me any funds to endorse them.
All right.
So let's summarize
boosting real quickly.
It combines feature selection
with classification.
Remember that selecting
of the weak learners?
So you can think of that as
sort of selecting, not to,
you can think of that as,
as finding features.
And pretty much any scheme you come up
with for defining weak learners and
trying them will work.
The complexity is linear in
the number of training examples.
You're basically trying
different weak learners.
You pick however many you want.
And you apply them against your
various training examples.
We mentioned that here because the
method that we're going to talk about,
some of the bets we talk about later
become sort of somewhat quadratic
because you have to compare each of
the points to each of the other points.
You don't have to do that here.
Testing is very, very fast,
it's ve, very easy to run.
You can write boosting code,
in fact, most, many people have.
You might ask,
why wouldn't you write your own code?
>> Why wouldn't you write your own code?
>> because the me,
some of the methods that we're
going to talk about are actually,
the bookkeeping is very difficult,
and people use other libraries.
And then when the stuff doesn't work,
it's much harder to track down,
was it the classification method,
was it the parameters within, etc.?
Because it's kind of a black box to you,
boosting you can write your own.
There are some disadvantages.
It does need lots and
lots of training examples.
But remember, that was an assumption
that we made, not this lecture but
the one before, that when we're
doing discriminative training,
we're assuming we've
got lots of examples.
Now it's sometimes found to not
work as well as some other methods.
For example, support vector machines
which is something we're going to talk
about in a little bit.
And lately, there's been a lot
of work on random forests.
Which I won't do in this class, but
is sort of the, I a even newer
approach to, to doing that.
And it's been particularly taken it a
bit on the chin for many-class problems,
so not a binary classifier, etc.
But it is still a, a pretty
effective way of doing these things.