So, any region with two or more edges coming in at different angles is a pretty
good feature, like the fat lip that shows up in both images, corner behind
the ear, base of this nose in the left image, green corner on the pink wall,
also in both images, and this top section of the wall in this right image.
The cropped portion of the eye is also pretty good.
So is this tooth that shows up in both images,
although it could be hard to match given other teeth that look similar.
These two regions involving the cycle and
cyclist in the right image are useful as well.
However, they're missing from the left image.
Now look at the remaining regions.
This one with the vertical edge in the left image cannot be located precisely.
Same for these two regions with horizontal features.
Also, this diagonal could be anywhere along the wall.
And even these two with slight curvatures are no good.
They could be part of larger curves and would be hard to localize.
So what makes certain image regions good for feature matching and not others?
Think about any common properties you can see.
How would you define these mathematically?