For the rest of this lesson, you
are going to be working on Python code
that should already be in the forum
sub-directory of your vagrant directory.
You can edit this code with your
favorite text editor on your computer,
and when you save it,
those changes will be visible
from inside the virtual machine.
So, what is this code?
It's a web forum,
just not a very good one yet.
You could run it like any Python
program from the command line.
And once it starts up, it'll tell you
it's listening on port 8000 and then you
can access it at http://localhost:8000
in your web browser.
And when you do,
you'll see something like this.
Hm, it's pretty empty.
Let's put some posts in it.
Now, if we go back to our terminal, and
kill the web server with Ctrl C,
and then restart it and
go back to the web browser and
reload all our posts are gone.
What's going on there?
Now, if we look over in the source code
for this module that forum.py is using,
we'll, see, it's not actually
using a database at all.
It's faking it with plain old variables
which go away when the program exits.
So for the next few exercises,
you're going to be adapting this code to
use a database to make posts persistent.
First off,
let's say hello to the database system
that we're going to use, PostgreSQL.