Now let me talk about
the problems of magnification and
minification that applied to,
in both forward and inverse mapping.
So let's take this region, of course
it's being copied over a warped in this
region and be much,
bigger in this and so and so.
So this is the issue of magnification.
Where this, all of the information
from here, is now much larger here.
Of course, the problem that you can
expect is going to be because of
aliasing, there's now lot of information
here, much more information here, so
it will be blocky and choppy.
In case of the inverse,
we'll have a region and
what's happening really is basically
this part is going there so
of course now I have to figure out how
to do computation of this from here and
of course this is
a problem of minification.
To solve this, what I would do basically
is kind of even discretize this
region here and copy out the discretized
information, from here to there.
So this allows me to now
generate a much larger thing.
And of course I would take all of
the values from here and inject in here.
And similarly, this one would be here.
And that's how I can actually start
doing, and of course we can do a variety
of other things that allow you
to basically, anti-alias this.
However, in this case,
of course we would actually have
problems because we don't exactly
know how to do the inverse warp.
Again, we'll talk about that briefly
again in the next few slides.
But one thing I want to point
out is that, in essence,
what we want to do is, we want to be
able to sometimes figure out the best
computational mechanisms to support it.
There's a lot of literature of this
kind of stuff in texture mapping and
stuff like that in computer graphics,
that's aimed at addressing this problem
with both forwards and inverse mapping.
One specific method I want you to
look at is a Two-pass transform that
basically does the geometric
transforms that we had looked at
in the previous slides.
Which was basically the whole concept
of doing rigid map line warps and
then basically being able to do
smaller warps to be able to get
smaller differences, and
by combinations of those.
And the fact that these current
processors can actually deal with
these geometric
transformations much better.
You would actually have much quicker
ways of deforming regions and images.
You'll be able to generate nicer
artifact free visuals and videos