Now, it's going to be your turn to
implement the task for POSTMethod.
This method should look
very similar to task for
GETMethod with one major difference,
the HTTP body.
Remember, HTTP POSTRequest can send
extra parameters through the HTTP body.
So, you'll need to account for
this by modifying the request object,
which should be a NSMutableURLRequest,
and
then have the appropriate HTTP body,
HTTP method, and header values.
Also as a hint when you're creating
this method, I'd recommend looking at
the post requests that you made
in the My Favorite Movies app,
the one that you made to add or
remove a movie from favorites.
When you're done, check this box.