So, I think, I guess in today's day and age, somebody, a lot of customers I
could see wanting some kind of GUI interface to be able to see this index.
>> Okay.
>> And then also, if we're going to have a GUI, there needs to be a smart,
intuitive way to search through what we've just sorted,
the keywords that we've just sorted.
And, I think finally we want to a way to have that data persist.
So if we wanted to add more titles later, remove some titles out,
because they're outdated or something then supporting that as well.
>> We certainly wouldn't want to have to go through the whole parsing,
sorting, cer, shifting process, anytime anybody want to be using this.
>> Mm-hm. >> Okay.
So, in fact, there's a lot, there, there are all these needs and
there's lots more.
For example it may be the case that the form of the input changes over time.
People might want to have input that if we're talking about titles,
comes out of some bibliographic databases in a different format.
We might want to use, re-use some of these components in other applications.
That's, that's a, a form of, of evolution as well.
We might want to for performance reasons, or, or other reasons
change the processing algorithm, so that we do the shifting of lines as they're
read in or we wait until, doing the shifting until they're all read in.
We might want to shift lines on demand we might want to
use an incremental rather than a batch sort.
That is, have some kind of sorted pre-structure that we add each title to as it
comes in rather than when you get them all in and do a sort.
You might want to add new functionalities such as we indicated before,
in terms of stop words and eliminating those.
We might want to support deletions, like, like you mentioned.
We might want to use external stores, that is along the lines of
persistence we might imagine the database on disc that holds these either in
their original format or in some partially processed format.
We might want to change the data representation.
Imagine that we are moving to
a different library to support our our in-memory storage.
And we, so we might need a new representation of the lines and, and so on.
Variety of changes.
And the question then is, of the various approaches to the architectural
breakdown of things, which ones are resilient to which changes?
If you could anticipate the changes coming in,
you could pick an architecture that, if not already able to provide
that particular change would be able to easily adapt to that change.