Let's start by dividing these terms and
just talking about what continuous means
since it appears in all
these process names.
Continuous in this context means that
you're checking code into the main
branch of a version control system.
And you're doing this fairly often,
usually several times a day.
And when this code is checked in
it initiates some sort of process.
This is why it's called continuous, as
opposed to once a year, or nightly, or
whenever Leila felt like it.
And this need to have constant code
check ins applies to all the contiguous
processes.
Whatever the full process is,
it always starts with a code
check into repository.
And these check ins
are happening very frequently.
Now the smaller the check ins that
go into the main code base are,
the easier faster it is to resolve
any sort of merging problems.
Let's look at an example.
So say that your security team
gets a report from a user that
they found a bug.
And the user isn't
particularly happy about it.
Because your team is continuously
committing code, the security team can
work with developers to quickly
create a security patch.
And this patch could be delivered
to the customer very fast.
This differs from other release cycles
that can take months, or even years, for
major releases.