So here's the URL that we
spoke about in the last video.
And here are the Sign-in button
styles that you can see.
On the right hand side here,
you can see a Download Files link.
And it says that it includes
Sign-In buttons in PNG and
PSD format in many
different resolutions.
It also includes base,
hover, and pressed states so
that you can show some animation
as the user clicks on the button.
If you click the Download Files link
a zip file will get downloaded,
and if I open that zip file you'll
see a directory structure like this.
Here are my sign in assets, and
in my sign in assets we can
see different drawables.
So we can see I've buttoned
google_focus, buttoned google_normal,
pressed, etc.
And as I select them you can
actually see the buttons
here in preview on the Mac.
And it's got them in drawable.hdpi,
mdpi, tvdpi, xdpi, and xxdpi.
And you may notice that in
Android Studio you have a very similar
collection of directories.
Here under res I have drawable,
drawable-hdpi, drawable-mdpi, etc.
So, all you have to do is copy
the files from the zip folder, into
Android Studio, so that they can become
available to you in Android Studio.
So here, you can see my drawable-hdpi,
and I have the different Google
buttons available to me.
So this is the small
button in disabled mode.
This is the small
button in focused mode.
This is the small button in normal mode.
This is the small button in press mode.
You can see the subtle change in colors.
Similar for the sign in button,
disabled, focused, normal and pressed.
You're going to be using the sign in
button and customizing your app for
the sign in area over
the next few steps.
So go ahead and download the zip file
and then unzip it into Android Studio.
You can work from the same app as
you used in the earlier module, or
if you prefer, you can create
a new one that's exactly the same.
I've actually created a new one for
this.
But do remember that if you do create
a new one; on the developers console,
you'll have to create credentials for
the new one,
using the naming of the new one or
you won't be able to sign in.