If we look at the execution here,
we see that P3 and P4
observe the updates to the memory
allocations M1 and M2 in reverse way.
We take a look at what's happening here,
we see that M1 and
M2 are not causally related.
So regarding causal consistency,
this is okay.
This execution is correct with
respect to causal consistency.
However, regarding
sequential consistency,
we said that that all the processors
in the system must observe
the same order of the events that
are occurring on some other processors.
So, in this case,
this would not be legal as far as
sequential consistency is concerned.
So, the correct answers for
these questions is this is
not a valid execution for
sequential consistency, but it is
with respect to causal consistency.
Meaning that, if we're running
an application on top of a memory model,
that we know [INAUDIBLE]
causal consistency,
if we observe this kind of behavior,
this is perfectly legal.
We cannot complain to anyone.
However, if we observe this kind of
behavior when running an application
on top of a supposedly
sequentially consistent system,
we have the rights to complain,
this is not correct.
Somebody has made a mistake with
their implementation of this system.