As we saw in the spec runner page,
the use of describe and it, are to
create sort of an outline, as if they
are just used to organize information.
In fact,
that's exactly what they are for.
It, is used to identify a specification,
or a spec, for short.
A spec is just a container for a test.
A way to identify the exact
feature we're testing.
For example,
it should be able to play a song.
If all of the expectations within a spec
return true, then that spec passes.
If any of these expectations were to
return false, the spec would fail.
You could think of it as defining
the boundary around this test.
Describe is used to identify a suite,
which is a group of related specs.
In this case, the suite is called
"Player", which tells us that everything
contained within this block
is related to the player.
There's no right or
wrong way to organize your tests.
It's up to you and your preference.
Describe is just there to
provide an organizational tool,
a level of indentation.