The correct answer is
everything except for
the news text and
the basic critical functionality.
In order for the app to even work,
you've got to deliver the basic
critical functionality.
So this shouldn't be
coming after the load.
Also, people would be visiting a site
like this specifically to read the news
text, so they should be there as soon
as the first pixels are being painted.
Everything else though,
like images, videos and
the comments section can come later.
In fact, this is probably a pattern
you've seen before on other apps.
Keep in mind, however,
that user actions could actually still
happen during the post load idle state.
And in a moment you'll learn that you
only have one hundred milliseconds to
respond to those actions.
This makes it all the more important
to keep the post load task that you're
performing to fifty millisecond chunks