Okay, let's recap.
So for changing your POJO, you should
change your shopping list item.
And I think it'd be good to change it by
adding a Boolean for whether the item
is bought or unbought, as well as a
string that includes the buyer's email.
Next, when you're buying or unbuying
items, it's probably good to use update
children to flip the bullion and
set the buyer.
We're not making a whole new item,
so push and
set value don't really
come into play here.
Run transaction is used in situations
where users could overwrite each other's
data, and it would be disastrous,
which is not really the case here.
And no, it doesn't just happen
magically when we change the POJO,
we do need to call method.
To show whether an item is bought or
unbought, you should update
the populateView method in
your active list item adapter class,
because the populateView method
is where you determine what each
of the item list items look like.