This, then, clearly represents
a single threaded process.
One easy way to achieve concurrency
is to have multiple instances
of the same process.
And that way we have
a multi-process implementation.
This illustration is adapted from Vivek
Pai's paper, Flash, An Efficient and
Portable Web Server, and
it appears as figure two in the paper.
The benefits of this approach
is that it is simple.
Once we have correctly developed
the sequence of steps for one process,
we just spawn multiple processes.
There are some downsides, however,
with running multiple
processes in a platform.
We'll have to allocate memory for every
one of them and this will ultimately
put high load on the memory subsystem
and it will hurt performance.
Given that these are processes,
we already talked about the cost
of context switch among processes.
Also it can be rather expensive to
maintain shared state across processes
because the communication mechanisms and
the synchronization mechanisms that
are available across processes,
those are little bit higher overhead.
And in some cases it may even be
a little bit tricky to do certain things
like, for instance,
forcing multiple processes to be able to
respond to a single address and
to share an actual socket port.