So for the next question I wanted to
do a more general programming question
which you can solve any language.
I want to see so
given a certain array of integers.
I will allow you to tell
me which indexes will give
you the maximum difference between
them so let's say index i and j so
you want to know that
direct is called x.
Which X I minus X J gives
you the largest difference.
>> Okay, so for any I and
J in the array.
>> Where J is greater than I.
>> Okay, I see.
[NOISE] And I'm going to just think and
draw an array to start with.
>> That's sounds perfect.
>> And play with it.
So I've got integers.
So you know they've been here and
they could be more fun.
[LAUGH]
And so
I want the biggest difference
between two of them where
the bigger one is to the right
of the small one, right?
Is it the size of the difference.
Or.
>> Yes so we want to know.
>> Okay so it has to be a positive
difference otherwise it wouldn't matter.
>> Exactly [LAUGH] Yeah.
>> Yeah.
Okay.
So really
like the stupidest method.
Would be to look at every pair.
And the cut the difference and
pick the largest difference.
>> That is one way to do it.
>> That would be relatively inefficient
i bet you there's a better way.
That does that.
>> That is okay.
>> Maybe i'll just start with
because then i've coated it.
Yeah.
I want to loop through,
I think i'm going to try and
loop through the J's and
then loop through the i's
less than each j.
>> Okay.
>> So that's so.
So.
I'm just trying to think maybe I should.
No, it doesn't matter.
I was going to think about storing
the length of the array somewhere but
I'm only going to use it once.
So for j in range
length of, and
you called it x didn't you?
>> Yeah.
>> And then I want to do my inner loop.
For I In range (J).
Okay.
So maybe I need to think about
storing the maximum so far,
or something somewhere.
>> Okay.
>> So like I could start with a max of
zero because if they're all the same
then it's going to be zero.
Hang on.
No if they're descending, so
if they were just getting smaller and
smaller then, okay.
So, I should start with my first one,
my first difference.
So max = X.
One.
No, zero counts.
Zero counts because you could take, does
j need to be strictly greater than i,
or could it be greater than or equal to?
>> It has to be strictly greater, yeah.
>> Okay, we'll start with that then,
because this is the first thing,
I'll come across.
And.
I'm going to I'm going
to store those as well.
So best J so far equals one.
Best I so far equals zero.
So, I'm going to say if the difference
of x j and x i is bigger than max,
then I'm going to update all of these.
>> Okay.
>> So if x j
>> Minus x [ i ] is greater than,
Max.
Then, max = x [ j ]- x i
Best-j=j, best i=i.
So, do you want this inside
a function or something?
>> Yeah.
Let's put it inside a function
for a formality.
>> Okay.
So we'll call it
find_max_difference, and
it's going to take an array x.
x, and it's going to return
Max s j.
Best i okay, so.
Let me just think, have I, have I,
does this seem to be right?
And then maybe I'll try a test case.
>> Okay.
>> So okay, the very first attempt.
Okay, so
what Ive missed already is empty array.
Array with With nothing with one number.
>> That's okay.
>> So yeah, I guess both of those
like, you can't say the problem so
they don't count
>> You can have some where you can get
a proper array
>> So then I take the first
difference and then I'm going to
loop over the size of the range and
I'm going to come
up to okay does this
include the j element?
No it doesn't.
It doesn't.
That's okay.
So, I think I've missed out
accidentally having i equal to j.
So I was worried about.
And then if the current difference is
bigger than the previously best one,
then I update it and
then I'm going to come back here and
do it again.
And then come back here and
do all of that again.
And then return, yeah.
Okay now for test.
Let's say do you have any suggestions
of a test or should I pick them myself?
>> Just go ahead and pick one.
>> Okay so I said that something that
decreasing seem to be a problematic one
so let's try [4, 3, 2,1]
>> So
here max will be a match
will be start off being.
Minus one.
And then we'll go to.
So that minus one will also come
up as the first thing here and
then we'll go to difference
between two so we'll have.
Minus two minus one but
it won't update because this.
This is strict and then we'll go to
minus three, minus two, minus one and
nothing will update so
that seems to work in that case.
What about something a bit
more scattered [1, 5, 2, 7].
So here we'd start with for,
then at the max
because that's 5 -1,
then we would go to.
It would be one, I guess we're looking
at this, one and then minus three,
so neither of those would do anything,
then we go back up here.
And then we come to six,
which would update,
and then it wouldn't get any better.
Okay, I think I'm okay
with this solution.
>> I think this solution will work.
I haven't heard that in the time
that you have written this.
Do you have any ideas on how
you can make it more efficient?
because right now, actually.
Can you tell me what
order it is right now?
Well, you kind of looping
through everything twice because
you've got a loop over entries and
then loop over those.
So i really think there
must be a better way.
And I can't say off the top
of my head to code it.
But there must be a way
to maybe compare.
If you step along, then does this
next one make it better or not.
Okay.
So How, okay, I'm not completely clear
on this yet, but looking at this one,
imagine so you start with like we did
before then you look at the next j.
Does that make the difference better or
not?
No, hm I think there
must be a better way.
And it would involve stepping
through the array only once.
But like in tandem.
I can't quite see it.
I'm sorry, I don't think I can code
it right now, it's fucking me.
[LAUGH]
>> That's okay, that's okay.
This is a solution that works.