All right, so I'm going to create
a new project called MusicPlayer, so
click here on Start a new
android Studio project.
I'm going to name my
application MusicPlayer.
Click Next, I'm going to accept
this default minimum SDK.
And then I'm going to choose
the Empty Activity template,
click Next and then Finish.
Now once that's done,
first I'm going to modify the layout so
there are two buttons on the screen.
So I'm going to open up my
activity_main.xml file and
then head over to the text view and
then close this up.
So with activity main
XML layout file open,
I'm going to open up my preview pane.
I'm going to modify the existing
activity main XML file
from a relative layout
to a linear layout.
So make that change here and this is so
that the play and pause buttons stacked
on top of each other and feel free to
arrange the buttons however you want.
Perhaps in the middle of the screen or
even horizontally in a row and
I'm going to move these so
I can view them all vertically.
I'm also going to add in
orientation of vertical here.
Next I'm going to modify this
textView and change into a button.
And then copy and paste it so
that we have two buttons.
Now I want the text of
the first button to say Play.
And the text of the second
button to say pause.
I'm also going to add view IDs to each
button because we'll need to refer to
them in the Java code to define the
ButtonClick behavior for each of them.
Now taking a look at the layout in
the preview pane that looks good.
Now let's switch over to
the main activity file.
Here I want to hook up click
listeners to each button and
similar to lesson one, we'll implement
an anonymous click listener for
this button and
it's on a click callback method.
So inside the onCreate method, I'm
going to find the playButton we created
using the findViewById method and
passing in the ViewId.
Then I'm going to set the
OnClickListener method on the button.
So for the instructions inside the
onClick method, right now I'll just have
it pop up a Toast message until we
figure out how to play the song file.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I can use the same logic for
the pause button.
So I'm going to select this whole
block of code, copy and paste,
now all I have to do is change
the variable name the view ID and
the toast message to
reference the pause button.
Now let's make sure this code works so
far by running on our phone.
Awesome.
So
each button pops up with
a different toast message.
One for play and one for pause.
All right so
now let's add in a song file.
So I clear the raw folder
as I showed you earlier.
So this is the song file
in my computer and for
those of you who are curious, it's
actually the trailers video song from
the entry developer's YouTube channel.
So now I'm going to copy and
paste this file into the raw
folder in Android Studio.
Great, there you go, so
the song file is now in our app.
Now let's figure out
how to play that song.
Well one way we could do it is, we could
go back to our earlier Media Player
article but I want to show you
a different way of finding the answer.
So let's go online and search for
Android media player tutorial.
So, this first result here looks good.
Ooh, and these code snippets
look helpful as well.
Now, by reading the description,
it looks like this line of code
creates a media player object for us.
So, notice that we passed in two inputs,
a context and the resource ID for
the raw audio file.
In this instance here,
song is the name of the file.
So, once a media player is created, we
can call methods like start and pause.
So that seems like what we want for
our play button and what we need for
our pause button.
So the rest of this article talks about
other methods that you can call and
you have a chance to go back and
redo this later.
All right so this first line of
code here looks pretty promising.
I will just copy and
paste it into our app.
So back in our code,
where should we create the media player?
Well as suggested by
the hint in the quiz,
let's make the media player a global
variable because we want to
reference the media player from
the OnClickListeners for each button.
So if that reasoning isn't clear, it's
okay, as you get more experience with
Java, you'll get a better understanding
of the requirements of variables
that are used within anonymous
classes like these click listeners.
So for this case, let's go ahead and
make sure that the media
player is a global variable.
Now here in the main activity file,
when should we set up or
initialize the media player?
Should we do it when
the play button is clicked?
No I think we should
set it up before that.
Let's initialize the media player
when the activity is first created,
then the media player object will
be ready whenever we hit play.
So I'll paste the code that we
copied from the tutorial in here.
And now,
I want to modify it to fit our app.
Now I don't need to declare
the object that I type again
because the variable was already
declared as a global variable.
Also renamed the R.raw.song to
R.raw.android_trailer because
that's the name of our song file.
All right,
then in the playButton ClickListener,
we can delete the toast message and
call mediaPlayer.start.
And do something similar
the pauseButton ClickListener,
we'll delete the Toast message and
call mediaPlayer.pause.
All right, so now, let's test the app.
[MUSIC]
Nice.
That sounds fantastic.
So, the song is playing,
and the play and
pause buttons are working as expected.
Now, back to the tutorial
that we found earlier.
If you had some additional time,
maybe you had a chance to experiment
with the other media player methods.
So for example here,
the seekTo method which is used for
skipping to a different part of
the song or this setVolume method here,
which is used for
changing the volume so great work.
As you can see,
writing a small sample app is a nice way
to become comfortable with a new API in
Android without all the extra
complexities of a real full fledged app.
All right ,so let's put
the music player app aside and
we'll return to it later but
now let's go back to Miwok app.