Let's look at a simple case of
iterative deepening on a tree
with a branching factor of two.
At level zero only one node is searched.
At level one we touch
the first node again, and
then look at the two child nodes.
We've had to explore three nodes for
level one, plus one node
from level zero, so our total for
iterative deepening nodes is 4.
At Level Two, we add four nodes
to the bottom of the tree.
To add these nodes, we are looking
at the three above it as well, for
a total of seven for this level.
Adding Level Two to our running tally is
eleven nodes for iterative deepening.
At level three, we add eight more nodes.
So we examine 15 nodes for
this level in total.
Our iterative deepening total is now 26.
Note that at each level,
the sum total of nodes visited, and
revisited by iterative deepening,
is actually under two times the number
of nodes expanded by that level.
A depth limited search to level
four would examine 31 nodes, but
the iterative deepening total was 57.
Depth limited to level five would be 63.
Iterative deepening would be 120.
While researching the tree may
seem like a waste in practice.
It is a small multiplier compared to the
exponential increase from searching each
level deeper.
With the branching factor of two,
iterative deepening expands less than
two times the number of nodes a depth
iterative search would have
done at the same level.
When the branching factor is greater
than two, as the most games,
then the redundancy caused by
iterative deepening is even less.
Perhaps a quick quiz would help.