If we look at our spec runner,
we'll see that we have three specs and
one of them failed.
It says expected false to be true.
This is the value of our
initial complete variable and
we wanted that to be true.
The reason this is failing is because
our test, or our expectation,
is running before the asynchronous
function can complete its tasks.
Let's go back and fix that test,
so we can properly test
this asynchronous function.
You might think to just put our test, or
our expectation here in the call back
of our asynchronous function, but
that won't work either because then this
expectation will be run within the scope
of our application, and not within
the scope of the testing framework.
We can solve this problem by using
beforeEach, like we did before.
And we'll also use a new
special function, called done,
that signals to the framework when an
asynchronous function has completed, and
we're ready to go run our tests.
We've refactored our test a little.
First we moved addressBook up
into the suite level scope.
We then added a beforeEach function, and
you can see that we passed
done to the callback here.
We call addressBook.getInitialContacts,
just as normal, but within its callback
we then call the done function.
This will signal to the framework
that our asynchronous function
is done doing what we needed it to do.
And we can continue testing.
The only other thing we need to
do is signal to the framework
which of our tests rely upon
that asynchronous execution.
Again, we use done to signal this.
We passed done to our
function within our spec.
We then just called
done after our tests.
If we go back and run our spec runner,
we'll see that everything's green.
3 specs, 0 failures including
our asynchronous function.