Hi, welcome back.
So we've been discussing sets and
groups in Tablo and
they have a lot of commonalities but
they also have a lot of differences.
So I was wondering if you could
explain to us the differences
between sets and groups?
&gt;&gt; Sure, that's a good question and
it's something that a lot of
people get confused about.
So a set is a subset of your data
that meets a certain condition or
criteria based on existing dimensions.
So for example, it might be your top
five most profitable food items.
Whereas a group consists
of dimension members that
form together to build
a higher level category.
So it might be breakfast
items that is the group.
And the items would be coffee,
bagels, and donuts.
&gt;&gt; Thanks, I know that's something
that I've had a lot of problems with.
And the way you explained it helps
me understand a little better.
&gt;&gt; Great.