Let's take a look at the continuous
delivery portion of the pipeline.
This includes the continues integration
portion of the pipeline, so
some of the steps will be very similar.
Like continuous integration, continuous
delivery starts with a code check-in,
after that an automated build and
test process is triggered.
This part of the continuous
delivery pipeline is
also known as continuous integration.
Developers can get quick
feedback from the system
about the status of the build.
If it fails, they'll know pretty quickly
and they should be fixing it right away.
If the build works and is good though,
the continuous delivery pipeline will
continue and the developer
to work on their next task.
Next in the pipeline, the code gets
deployed to a testing environment.
At this point,
several things could happen.
The testing server that's set up is
going to have as close a configuration
to production as possible,
except it's going to usually run
on scaled down infrastructure and
won't have a live database.
It's probably going to have a test
database with generated data or
a copy of the actual data.
Either a comprehensive
testing suite will be run or
a QA team will be running tests or both.
Once that's finished and they've given
the green light, the code could be
deployed to the next stage which is
usually called the staging environment.
The staging environment is a mirror
of the production environment.
This means that it uses
the actual databases.
It's used to test the deployment process
itself as well as possibly to run some
last minute manual tests before
the code is released to users.
If everything looks good
in the staging process and
it's given a quote unquote green result,
the code is assumed to be production
deployment ready and it will go out
to the world to all the happy users.
At any point in the process,
the pipeline can fail
in which case the failure is reported
to the developer and the process stops.
When a developer finds that a test or
a build process fails,
they can fix whatever caused the failure
and then recommit the fixed code.
Now you might be wondering,
why do we call this a pipeline?
The most obvious reason is because
it looks like a linear process
where code goes in one end and that it
flows to the customer on the other end.
You want to make sure that
the flow is good in the pipeline,
that there aren't any bottlenecks and
there isn't waste.
But the authors of The Continuous
Delivery book originally were thinking
of a different analogy and that analogy
is instruction pipeline in a CPU.
This is a technique that
implements a form of parallelism
called instruction level parallelism
where multiple instructions are run in
parallel on a single processor.
While I've drawn the pipeline
as a linear pipeline,
you should realize that some parts
will necessarily be run in parallel.
One example is testing.
It's very important that in
continuous integration, build and
test run fast, and that's so that
developers can get feedback quickly.
Unfortunately, it's not always
going to be possible to
have tests give immediate feedback.
For large projects, running the full
test suite of acceptance tests can take
a pretty long time.
You probably also want to run
manual user acceptance tests and
that can take even longer.
Performance tests also take time,
maybe if it's just a product
on many different platforms.
Making developers wait until all of
these tests are done is unreasonable.
The continuous delivery approach
optimistically assumes
that the commit is good.
iI it passes the continuous
integration process,
the developers can go back to writing
the next feature while the commit
continues to go through more testing.
They'll still get immediate feedback if
a problem happens in the process, but
if everything goes well,
that time was gained for development.