Here's a neat algorithmic trick.
You can use it to improve the bandwidth
term on some of the collectives.
It's called bucketing.
Let me illustrate the idea
using all gather.
Remember that an all gather starts with
all of the data distributed across all
the nodes and ends with the data
replicated on all the nodes.
One scheme might be to first do
a gather followed by a broadcast.
So the gather part is fine.
It attains the lower bound.
What about broadcast?
If you only have the tree based scheme,
then you'll be off on the beta
term by a factor of log P.
I think you need a fresh
perspective on all-gather.
Let's go back to the initial state.
Intuitively, the bandwidth or
beta term is fundamentally about using
as many of the links as possible.
One way to do that is to have every
process perform a send to a neighbor
in say a ring like fashion.
So, for example, we'll have zero
send to one, while one sends to two,
while two sends to three and so on.
Now we also one need P minus
one to send back to zero.
You might be thinking to yourself,
wait a minute, there's no link
between P minus one and zero.
But in fact there is.
Remember that the links
are bidirectional so
in fact you can send from P minus 1 to 0
by just going in the reverse direction.
So if we try this scheme and
we execute one round of communication,
let's see what we get.
Let's keep going, in particular,
let's have every process take
the data it just received and
pass it along and continue on and on.
All told,
that will be P-1 communication steps.
So what's the total cost?
Well, each process and each step sends,
M equals N divided by P words.
But it does so in parallel.
So, writing down the cost,
each message is alpha, plus beta,
times N over P, and
there are P minus 1 rounds, and
that gives you something that's
roughly alpha times P, plus beta.
And with respect to the beta term,
this is optimal.
Woot.
But you can also see
that there's a catch.
It's sub optimal with
respect to the alpha term.
But that's okay.
If the message is large so
that this term dominates this term, then
the following relationship has to hold.
The per process message
size has to be much
less than the ratio of an alpha to beta.
So, provided that's true,
we'll say that this algorithm is good.
So, now you have a bandwidth
optimal all-gather.
Since reduce scatter is the dual,
you also have a bandwidth
optimal reduce scatter.