And the way to sort of think about this
role is sort of more based on a function
or job, which is closer to what kind
of resources you need for that.
If you're a payroll manager you need
access to payroll files, for example.
That's what you're talking about.
So roles are sort of characterized
more by function and
the resources that go
along with that function.
Groups, on the other hand,
are basically what set of users or
what UIDs or what subjects have
some sort of similarity so
they can be grouped together.
Okay, so
roles are sort of more resource-related
versus groups are more subject or
user-related.
So that's sort of the way
to think about the two.
And then the question is
can we get the benefits.
So depending on how you
actually implement groups,
role activation could be like
activating a group for yourself.
And deactivation is
leaving the group and
having permissions
associated with the group.
So only when you activate your members
in the group you able to access it.
So in theory, the answer is that you
could actually do the kind of things you
can do with roles with groups as well.
But there's sort of this,
basically the difference is in how
the two come about that we talked about.
But the way, actually,
groups are typically implemented in
Unix-based systems, actually they don't
work the way that I was talking about.
You don't join a group and
then leave it and things like that.
If you used how we implement groups and
define access based on those groups,
if you want to say I want to go and
basically use that to get RBAC,
you're not going to be able to
get that in systems that we have.
So there is a difference
between the two, and
I said the difference
is somewhat subtle.
Possible to sort of think,
subject-focused then centric,
then you are sort of in the groups.
Or object or resource-centric,
then you are with roles
based on the job function.
But if we look at how we
implement groups, and
what kind of functionality that
you want to have with roles,
I would go with the false
answer here to this question.