So, now we've covered a lot of different
ways that you can animate things
with script in Unity.
It's a lot of material, I know.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, we went over interpolation,
C# events, and
variables all within
the span of a few videos.
But it is important
to get your feet wet.
And once you do that,
you can see what's possible.
&gt;&gt; So true, I mean, with just a few
lines of code, we were able to take our
island and animate it, and
make that beautiful sunset come down.
&gt;&gt; Right, and it was beautiful.
It's the animation that
really brings things to life.
&gt;&gt; So, now that we've gone
over animation, what's next?
&gt;&gt; Physics and audio.
&gt;&gt; Time to make our scenes feel and
sound amazing.
&gt;&gt; That's right.