The Bricks a Bunch Store, and
the Lots O Brick Store have been
bought by the same company.
Since management doesn't want to keep
track of two separate inventories,
we need to combine them.
Your mission, should you choose to
accept it, is to create a Brick
warehouse service and
extract each store's inventory to it.
Make sure to inject this service
back into each controller, so
that the stores still have
access to their information.
Then create an add to cart button for
the Bricks a Bunch items.
Clicking the add to cart button should
decrease the stock for the item by one.
Since you're changing the stock for
this item in the warehouse, the total
count should change here and here.
A link to this project is
in the instructor notes.
When you've completed these steps, the
feedback extension will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.