The first couple of times you've
run an app from Android studio,
you might have noticed a console popped
up with a series of messages about kinds
of things, like a slow app needing
to skip frames to keep up.
An error occurred, or perhaps
some request or process finished.
These are all log messages.
Developers use log messages to
communicate information about their
applications.
These messages can be fairly trivial
like noting that an application has
refreshed some data or
indicate deeper problems like an error
that crashes the application.
When you're logging a message in
your app you need to determine what
log level it should be displayed at.
The levels are ERROR, WARN,
INFO, DEBUG, and VERBOSE.
In terms of increasing
verboseness in severity.
ERROR, WARN, and INFO level messages are
always preserved in release versions.
So, if you think only to
capture that later to diagnose
a problem after your app is
released to the public, use them.
As I explain the different log levels,
I'll be showing the signatures for them.
They take the general form
of log dot some letter.
They take a String TAG and
a message as parameters.
Tag can be any string you want but
a common strategy is to use
the class name as the tag.
This make sit easier
to search your logs as
all apps dump their log
messages into the same bucket.
Use ERROR to log obvious errors.
WARN is best suited for things that
don't make your application ERROR or
crash but remain a concern.
For example, a media app might
log that there is low disk space.
This would help you diagnose why
a user's app won't download videos
anymore.
INFO is commonly used for
purely informational messages,
like being connected to the Internet.
During development, you can also
use DEBUG and VERBOSE log messages.
I've often used DEBUG messages for
things like outputting the URL that
a function has composed, or
response from a web service.
VERBOSE messages are meant for
times when you want to give
very granular information.
In most cases it isn't
what you want to use.
If you've used a logging library
in another programing language,
you might already be familiar
with these logging levels.
Android has another very special logging
level that is more severe than ERROR.
It is called WTF for
What a Terrible Failure.
What did you think I was going to say?
The WTF level is for errors that
should never, ever, ever happen.
And most developers should never,
ever, ever use it.
On a DEBUG build of a device,
a WTF error may force the device
to halt and output a debug report.
Because the behavior of WTF isn't
clearly defined, it might be best to
only use the knowledge of this special
log level to impress your friends.