Oh, hey.
[SOUND] Congratulations on
running your first task.
While the Gradle wrapper is
an incredibly convenient feature,
let's also go ahead and
install Gradle locally.
Keep up the great work.
[SOUND] In this course, the solutions to
the quizzes are all in the course code.
So just this first time,
let's take a look together at
where to find the solution.
So here's the directory where you found
the instructions for your first task.
Here is the build.gradle file that
specified what we were to do for
the first exercise.
And in the same directory we
have the solution.gradle file.
Let's open it up and sublime.
So here we go, we have some nice
explanation of the commands needed to
run a task using the Gradle wrapper
on various operating systems.
We even find the cool tip that
if we want to run tasks from
this solution.gradle file instead
of the build.gradle file,
we can easily do that using
the -b command line flag.
Also, we find the answer to the really
important question at hand.
[SOUND] I swear I don't have a problem.
[SOUND] [COUGH] Anyway, if you ever
get stuck on an exercise, don't sweat.
Just check out the solution.gradle file.
By the way in later lessons,
we end up switching to a whole Felician
directory so watch for that, as well.
Awesome work with this quiz and
good luck on the rest.