So last time we talked about how entropy can be used to measure the degree of
skew of a probability distribution.
And it's defined to be the expression here.
The sum of pi times log of pi times minus 1.
Now let's examine the properties of H of x.
H of x has a minimum value of zero.
This happens when the probability distribution is maximally skewed.
And, by maximally skewed, I mean it looks like this.
The probability that x will take on any of its values is zero, except for
a single value which has a probability of one.
This represents a state of absolute certainty about what value x is
going to take on.
Conversely, H of x takes on its maximum value
when x's probability distribution is at its most random.
Meaning, if it can take on k possible values.
The probability that anyone of them will occur is one over k,
thus as the distribution of x becomes more skewed it's entropy goes down