Now that you know what the product
actions are, you can add code to
your app to track when users view
products and add them to the cart.
So for our app we are going to
consider the activity Order Dinner
as the first step in the viewing and
shopping process.
So when you create a product,
you specify a product Id that
uniquely identifies the product.
But unfortunately for
our dinners, we haven't actually
given each dinner a unique Id, so
you're going to need to do that now.
So the dinner choices
are all defined in the file,
arrays.xml in values in the res folder.
And each dinner is just a string.
And they're grouped together according
to whether they're vegetarian,
vegan, and so on.
So as a somewhat hacky, hack to quickly
be able to get unique product IDs,
we're going to add a product ID as
the first two characters of each item.
So we'll start with 01, 02, and so on.
So your task is to add the prefixes
to the dinners in arrays.xml.
One consequence of our change
though is the list of dinners
is going to include the number for
each of the dinner choices.
It's kind of a cosmetic thing,
and if you don't like it,
I leave it to you to fix the code for
that.
So now each of the dinner options
includes the Id as the first two
characters.
So it's going to make our life
a lot easier if we just quickly
add a utility method to get those first
two characters to return as the Id.
So go ahead and
add getDinnerId to the utility class.
Very simple method, it just gets the
substring of the first two characters.
Okay, so now we're really getting to
the meat of thing, excuse the pun.
You're going to write the code for
the method that actually sends
the ViewProductHit to analytics.
So we're going to consider
the Order Dinner screen
as equivalent to the View Product.
So when the user goes to the Order
Dinner screen, they're indicating
an interest in viewing and
possibly purchasing the dinner.
So, in the OrderDinnerActivity, go ahead
and add a method sendViewProductHit.
It's going to create the product action,
which in this case is ACTION_DETAIL,
because we want to indicate
that we're viewing the product.
Get the tracker,
we all know how to do that.
And send the hit as an event.
The Category is Shopping steps,
the Action,
I mean these can be the things you like,
but I used View Order Dinner screen.
The Label is the selected dinner.
We add the product, this is critical.
And we set the ProductAction,
and then we build the hit.
Then you'll also need to make sure that
you call sendViewProductHit() from
the onStart method in
OrderDinnerActivity.
So I use a Toast also to double-check,
but
you don't have to if you don't want to.
But so here's where I call
sendViewProductHit in onStart.
And you will need to make sure of course
that you add all the imports you need.
And that's Product,
ProductAction, Tracker, and
HitBuilders, and they're all in
com.google.android.gms.analytics.
Then make sure, of course, that your
phone is connected to Android Studio,
deploy the app, run the app,
and use the app.
And make sure you list all the dinners.
And you go to the Order Dinner
screen and look for
the events to come in in the real time
section of the Analytics dashboard.
And now it's the quiz.