This is a particle filter question.
Suppose we had a world with 4 states.
In these 2 states over here, we tend to observe A property 80%.
The remaining 20%, we'll observe B.
In these 2 states, we tend to observe B with 80% probability
and with 20% probability, we observe A.
Suppose we have 3 particles--1 over here, 1 over here, and 1 over here,
and we observe A.
Let's call this particle over here particle A. Lower caps a.
Lower caps b.
Lower caps c.
What is the probability that the sample a, given that we just observed A,
which means it will be more likely to be in 1 of these 2 states over here.
What's the probability of sampling b? What's the probability of sampling c?