In this case,
how does the ACL traversal happen?
That's what the question is about.
You have a couple of different options.
Remember in this case,
we want to grant access
when there's a positive access right,
and no negative access, okay?
Because negative takes precedence over
positive, that's what we have discussed.
So for someone, there's a number
of cases you can think of.
If there's no positive and
no negative access,
then access should not be granted,
because there's no access.
If there's positive and no negative
access then access should be granted.
If there's both positive and negative,
the negative takes precedence and
negative should not be granted.
So in this case,
how does this get implemented
is what the question is about.