To get started, let's recall a few things we've looked at.
One, we looked at the whole concept that if you were to do blending of
two images, we have to look at and
find the best window size that will allow us to do the blending.
We studied that basically, to do this you have to account for
the size of the largest prominent feature,
because that allows us to kind of blend things together.
We also studied that, the window size depends on
some information about the size of the prominent features, and
to avoid ghosting, you'd have to have a window size that is less than or
greater than, the twice the size of the smallest feature.
And also, this motivated us to look at us to look at the Fourier domain,
where basically we look at the largest frequency and
the smallest frequency [INAUDIBLE] find the size of the window, and
also looked at the concept of octaves where powers of two allowed us to
start looking at different frequency domains and, and
let us calculate of course, the different Fourier transforms that we use.
to figure out how to dress do the blends.