Let me introduce a special guest student
from a previous class, Malcolm Haynes.
Hi Malcolm.
>> Hi Thad.
>> When working on the five by
five isolation game in the class,
you believed you managed
to search to end game.
>> That's right.
But when we talked about branching
factor earlier, we said it would be
impossible to search to end game
in a reasonable amount of time.
So how did you do it?
>> First, I implemented the minimax
algorithm with alpha-beta pruning.
As you know, this reduces the size
of the search space from B to the D,
to B to the D over 2.
Thus, reducing it from approximately
8 to the 25th, to 8 to the 12th.
Next, I realized that some
moves are equivalent.
For example,
let's look at player one's first move.
If player one moves to (0,0) it's
the equivalent of moving to (4,0).
You can simply rotate
the board 90 degrees, and
you have the same board state.
Therefore, if you know the game tree for
our first move of (0,0),
you know the game tree for
our first move of (4,0),
which is the same as (4,4),
but also (0,4).
This is useful especially at
the beginning of the game,
when the branching factor is high.
For example, while player one has
25 possible moves, in reality,
there are only six unique moves
as you can use symmetry about
the horizontal and vertical axis, and
about the diagonal axis and,
of course, there is the center move.
We've just shown player one's six unique
first moves and their equivalents.
A similar analysis is possible for
any board state, which is defined
as a series of ord moves.
Let's run through an example.
In this example, O moved to [(2,2)].
Now it's Xs turn.
X is considering possible moves and
first evaluates a move to [(2,1)].
X now knows the value of
the board state [(2,2)], [(2,1)].
Now let X consider a move to [(2,3)].
X will check to see if the outcome
of this move is already known.
To do this, X checks to see if he
knows the value of the board state,
[(2,2)], [(2,3)].
He does not.
Next X rotates the board 90 degrees, and
checks to see if he knows the value
of the board state, [(2,2)], [(1,2)].
He does not.
Next X rotates the board 180 degrees,
and
checks to see if he knows the value
of the board state [(2,2)], [(2,1)].
Ah-ha, he does.
X returns the value of the board state,
[(2,2)], [(2,1)],
and does not need to expand
the game tree further.
If X hadn't found a solution,
he would have checked the board
states created by rotating the board
207 degrees, and flipping the board
along it's diagonal axis.
Only then would X have needed
to expand the game tree.
>> So you found that symmetry
really cut down on the number
of nodes you had to expand.
>> Only until about level
three of the search tree.
After that,
I gave up because symmetry was rare,
and the amount of effort needed to check
for symmetry just wasn't worth it.
>> So you're telling me that just those
tricks are sufficient to be able to
search to end game?
>> Not quite.
Well alpha–beta pruning, and
equivalent boards tremendously reduce
the number of possible game states,
they still weren't enough.
Luckily, while searching for a good
evaluation function, I discovered that I
didn't need to always search
to the end of the game tree.
It turns out, that I know the outcome
as soon as there's a partition.
>> Why is that?
>> Well a partition separates
two players completely.
Therefor the player with
the longest path wins.
For example, in this game,
player O moves next, but
the outcome of the game
is already known,
because player eight has eight possible
moves, while player two only has six.
Okay, so partitions, alpha-beta,
and symmetry allows you to finish.
After you've completed looking
through all possible moves,
does somebody always win
if they play optimally?
>> Yes Thad, it turns out
that player two always wins.
>> Well that's unexpected.
But you mentioned, you also found a good
first move for player one, right?
>> That's right.
At first, in fact, I thought player
one was always going to win.
This is because of reflection.
>> Reflection, what do you mean?
>> Reflection is just a 180 degree
rotation of the opponent's move.
In trying to solve the game,
I discovered an interesting phenomenon.
If player one's first move is to the
center, and player two's first move is
one that player one can reflect,
then player one can always win.
All she has to do,
is reflect every move player two makes.
Okay then, so
then how does player two avoid losing?
>> By moving to a location that
player one cannot reflect.
There are eight such possible moves
of the 24 available to player two.
I'll leave it as an exercise for the
student to determine those eight moves.
>> We're going to have a competition,
where the students are going to try and
make the best isolation
players they can.
Do you have any advice for them?
>> I sure do.
If you're player one,
move to the center square.
Then if possible, reflect player
two's moves and you will win.
But it's better to be player two.
In this case, create a good book
of opening moves and hints.
We've discussed the best first move if
player one occupies the center square,
and it turns out that in most cases,
if player one does not occupy
the center square, then player two
should occupy the center square.
Anyway, once you have a good book of
opening moves, use your understanding of
equivalent moves and hash tables to load
and search your order book efficiently.
Remember, you only have a limited
amount of time to complete your move.
After exhausting your book of
opening moves, implement minimax,
then add iterative deepening and
finally, alpha-beta pruning.
Finally, focus on your
evaluation function.
Now a good evaluation function is,
well, that's up to you to decide.
Good luck.
>> Thank you, Malcolm.