Hi, I'm Jamal Eason, product
manager on the Android Studio team.
Android Studio is the official
integrated development environment for
Android app development.
It is based on a powerful
IntelliJ IDE platform.
An IDE is a great code editor and
framework.
And we get that from IntelliJ.
>From that foundation we enhance your
productivity when building Android apps,
providing features such as code
templates to help you build common app
features.
A rich layout editor with support for
drag and drop editing, Net Tools to
catch performance, usability, version
compatibility and other problems.
A flexible, Gradle-based build system,
with Instant Run for high speed coding
iteration, and debugging support for
both Java and C++ languages.
We are always working to
improve Android Studio for you.