Here's what I think.
Of these four options,
I think only squaring Z and L or
doubling the bandwidth will work.
Let's go through each option and
see why.
First, recall the balance principle for
this system.
If the original system was
perfectly balanced for sorting,
then you can plug in
the given ratio of W to Q.
Of course, these L's cancel.
Now suppose you double the cores,
let's then go through the options and
see which ones work.
Option one says half the bandwidth and
double the peak.
Your boss must have suggested this
one because it is a terrible idea.
Why?
Because if you do this,
then this factor quadruples, so
you've effectively made
the system even more imbalanced.
Bad monkey!
Ooh ooh sorry.
What about option two?
If you square Z and L,
that will effect this term, but
that just might do the trick.
Squaring the factor inside
the log results in a factor of 2
outside the log.
So this factor of 2 on the left-hand
side will balance, or cancel out,
the factor of 2 on the right-hand side.
Voila!
Unfortunately, if you stop and
think about it, it's a really
expensive way to maintain balance.
It sort of suggests that you
might have to go from, say,
a one megabyte cache in one generation,
to a one terabyte cache in another.
That does not seem without
a little heartache and pain.
Let's move onto option three,
doubling the fast memory size.
That will not work.
The factor of 2 will just
pop out as an additive term,
not a multiplicative one, so it can't
compensate for the cores doubling.
That brings us to the last option,
doubling the bandwidth, that could work.
Doubling the bandwidth is a factor of
2 in the denominator which cancels
out the factor of 2 in the numerator.
In principle, a great idea but
can it actually work?
Well, think about those exponential
trends you're always dreaming about.
Increasing transistor density gives
you the ability to increase on chip
resources, like, the number of cores,
or the size of fast memory, or
even the speed.
But the historical trends say that
bandwidth just does not grow as fast as,
say, R0 times P.
Okay, so these are these four options,
are there others?
Well, there's at least one other,
what about cutting our zero in half?
Now, if you cut our zero in half,
I wonder what the problem
would be with doing that?
Dun, dun, dun.
All told, the results of this quiz
are just a little bit depressing.
It would seem that for a computation
like sorting at least there would appear
to be some fundamental limits that just
make it hard to build balanced systems.
Anyway, it's a research frontier.
Maybe one of you,
my pretty little geniuses,
will come with a brilliant
idea that circumvents it all.