My preferred way of tracking down this
problem is to set a breakpoint in
the add book to view method of
the breakpoint of the breakpoint
bug view controller.
Then, if we run the application, we
notice that when we tap the screen and
we hit play, it seems like the add bug
to view is just being called over and
over again,
almost in a recursive fashion.
And by recursive I mean that
the frames keep adding and
they don't decrease until we've
reached some large number of bugs.
And if we drag out the navigator,
we can see that after our first
add bug to view call, we have this
move bugs animation,that's then
calling addBugToView again and it just
continues all the way up the stack.
So let's tap this one and we can see
that we are making an extra call or
what appears to be an extra call here so
we'll delete that.
Whoops, I shouldn't have stopped
the application because now I'm missin
any debug information I have.
So my bad, let's do this again.
We'll hit play and now it just,
oh, now we just have two bugs.
So how are we hitting this?
Let's run it one more time.
So we hit it once from
handleSingleTap and there we go.
We have an extra call here,
that's why we're getting two bugs.
So let's go ahead and
blow that one away and we'll try again.
This time, when we tap,
we'll disable that, play,
just one bug crawls onto
the screen at a time.
And that's the behavior that we want.