In almost all the previous lessons,
you are focusing on building
the functionality of the Android toy
apps while we provided you
with pre-built UI screens.
>> These next two lessons will
switch our attention into turning
a simple app that just works,
into a professional-looking app that
looks pretty and user-friendly.
>> In this lesson, you'll get to
try different views, view groups,
organize them in alternative layouts,
and perform data binding.
You will also get to design your app in
a way that's accessible to people with
visual and physical limitations.
And those who speak other languages.
And closer to the end of the lesson,
you'll get to build notifications
in Android, as well.
>> Then in the next lesson, we'll talk
more about making our design even
prettier by using the right colors and
font styles.
As well as creating touch selectors.
>> But first, let's recap on some of the
basic UI building blocks that we've been
using so far.