Let's recap where things stand
by connecting the idea of
the lower bound to the one d-block row
algorithm and the two d-suma algorithm.
First, there's the one d algorithm,
who's communication time is this.
Then, there's the two d-suma algorithm.
Remember, there are two variants
depending on whether you assume
a broadcast is tree based or
bucket based.
Also remember that the suma algorithm
has a tuning parameter, a little s.
At the maximum value of s, a lower bound
on the communication time would be this.
So what I've done is taken the maximum
value of s, plugged it into these two
parameters, and just taken the best
case latency and bandwidth bounds.
This way we don't have to fuss with
tree based versus bucket based analyses.
So, these are times for
concrete algorithms.
Then, there's the lower
bound on communication.
So, relative to the lower bounds,
SUMA looks pretty good.
Matches in the beta term, and is just
off by a little bit in the alpha term.
So, can you do even better than SUMA?
In fact, you can, using an algorithm
called Cannon's algorithm.
It has a communication time that
exactly matches the lower bound.
It's an impressive algorithm in the
sense that it predates the lower bound
analysis.
In fact, Cannon developed the algorithm
as part of its PhD dissertation in 1969,
groovy baby.
I wish Mike Myers was here.
Unfortunately, Cannon's Algorithm
suffers from a few restrictions that
make it not quite as easy and
practical to implement compared
to the SUMMA algorithm.
Anyway, if you want more details
head to the instructor's notes.
Now what about beating the lower bound?
The lower bound analysis
makes a critical assumption.
Can you spot it?
The assumption is this one.
That is, you assumed you only had
enough memory on each node to store
n squared over p data.
Recall the cube of
multiplications concept.
This assumption is akin to distributing
surfaces of the cubes across nodes.
So a good question is whether
having more memory would let you
replicate some data, and
thereby reduce communication.
One example of such a scheme is
a three dimensional algorithm.
It says rather than distributing
the surface is why not distribute
the volume.
That is suppose you took the nodes and
arranged in them in a 3-D mesh,
instead of a 2-D mesh.
So suppose you have capital P nodes
now put them in a 3D mesh of
size cube root of p on a side.
You could then assign chunks of
this n cubed work to each node.
Each chunk consists of n
cubed over p multiplications.
Ideally you'd like to set up this scheme
in such a way that every node can update
its cube concurrently.
Now to do that you're going to
need to have cube root of P
copies of each submatrix.
For instance,
consider these three processes.
So you either need to predistribute
copies of the matrices, or
depending on how the operands are
allocated, do some kind of broadcast.
Here's what such
a broadcast might cost you.
In this case, i've assumed
a tree-based scheme, and of course,
you'd incur the same cost
to ++broadcast b and c.
Now, once all the upper
ends are replicated,
you can do local multiplications, and
depending on where you want the final
results to be, you might need
to combine the copies of C.
You can, of course, do that with a
reduction, and since reduce is the dual
of broadcast, the overall communication
cost still matches the broadcast cost.
At least asymptotically.
You could also do an all reduce to get
replicated results
within a block column.
So let's compare this
to our 2-D lower bound.
If you have enough memory to replicate
by a factor of cube root of P,
you can get a cube root of P
reduction in the communication time.
So what if you don't
have this much storage?
Well, you could imagine a hybrid or
2.5-D scheme.
Rather than full replication,
you could use partial replication.
That could reduce the memory
requirement, but perhaps at a cost of
a slightly increased communication
time relative to the 3-D case.
But wait.
You know what?
Let's save the two point five
d scheme for another time.
Like, an exam!
Oh, no, not an exam!