Similarly to the generic description of
RPC, like some other PC, the client and
the server are allowed to interact
via a procedure called interface.
The server specifies the interface that
it supports in a .x file written in XDR.
Also Sun RPC includes a compiler
called rpcgen that will compile
the interface specified in the .x
file to language specific stub.
It will generate separate stubs for
the client side and for
the server side stuff.
The server process when launched
will register itself with their
registry daemon that's
available on the local machine.
The per machine registry will keep track
of information that includes the name of
the service, the version, many of
the protocols that are supported with
the service, and also the port
number that needs to be contacted
when the client side RPC sends
a request through the server.
The client must explicitly
contact the registry
on the target machine in order to obtain
information about the server process.
When the binding happens,
the client creates an RPC handle, and
this handle is used whenever
the client makes any RPC calls.
And in this way,
the runtime is able to track all of
the per-client RPC-related state.
I should note that with Sun RPC,
or any other RPC, for
that matter, the client and the server
process that are communicating
amongst each other may be
on different machines.
Or they may be on the same machine,
just two processes running
on the same physical node.
So, the RPC in that case works
like other forms of IPC,
except it has a much
higher level semantics.
It has procedure called semantics,
which is more complex than the IPC
mechanisms that we saw before.
Before we look at the key
components of Sun RPC,
if you would like to view
a more complete reference.
Then, take a look at these
Sun RPC tutorial and
examples that are now
maintained by Oracle.
Oracle purchased Sun in 2010.
The link to this is provided
in the instructor notes.
At that link, you will find references
to TI-RPC as opposed to Sun RPC.
TI stands for transfer independent RPC.
And that means that the protocol
that will be used for the client and
server communication doesn't have
to be specified at compile time.
It can be specified
dynamically at run time.
Other than that and a few smaller
issues the documentation and
the examples closely follow
the original Sun RPC
specification as well as the XDR
interface definition language.
Also, a number of older online
references are still valid reference
points.
And you can, finally, look at the Linux
man pages by looking for man rpc.
This will give you all of
the Linux supported APIs.