Now some more advanced examples.
This is a bit of work we also did.
Here, basically,
we videotaped a hamster and then,
of course,
we made the hamster walk a line.
So we basically gave it
a trajectory to follow.
In essence, what we did was we
actually did this analysis,
not over the whole frame but
just the region where the hamster is.
So basically extracted what we
refer to as a video sprite.
We took a background picture and
made the video sprite find
the best possible path.
So no longer are we actually just trying
to figure out the whole video volume and
finding the best possible frames and
transitions.
We can do this for a small region,
the pixels that just where the hamster
is and, of course, using that we can
make it now, figure out a best possible
transition set from the data that it
has to be able to walk this path.
Here's basically how we do it.
We actually analyze the the hamster
in a green screen like this, so
we can remove the hamster out of
the background whenever they're visible.
So here, of course, when it's
the green screen is what we want and
we can separate that layer out.
The kind of stuff you know
you can do in Photoshop.
We did this for video and, of course,
we get all the rich motions including
the shadows and stuff like that.
There's a little bit of machine learning
involved in this work to kind of
differentiate from the front and
the back of the hamster and that
allows us to model all of the phenomenon
of different types of things and
then, that's used to generate
this segment that you just saw.
So here's a final result by just
basically compositing all of them but
also doing the resyncing to
locate the hamster back, and
I think it looks kind of interesting.
If you look at my website, you'll
find many examples of both this and
some additional work
we've done in this space.