Before we go on I just wanted to have
you, kind of, think about one specific
thing, and that is that can we determine
what kind of pattern gives you the most
discriminating information between
images at different defocus scales.
So, here basically are the four
different types sample aperture patterns
and a conventional aperture just
simplified to look like this.
Now, the score basically is the which
one of them is more discriminative.
Remember again,
when moving the object away
the pattern changes at the, sensor and
each one of them is going to give you
more detail about how far things are,
you know, and also that could be useful
figuring out defocus planes and depth.
I'm just putting in you, know you, five
different examples on the score of which
one is more discriminative
versus less discriminative.
So what I'd like for you to do here is,
just put in a number.
Which one is the most discriminative,
and
which one is the least discriminative?
What would help you to look at is,
again, a little bit more on the
structure of these obstruction patterns.
And again, symmetry is there in most
of them, but kind of starts giving you
a little bit of x and y, but at the same
time, you also want to start looking at,
you know, what are the variations in,
the diagonals and stuff.