Now let me talk a little bit about image
transformations versus image warping.
Specifically what we were
interested when we talked about
image transformation or the related
warping that came with that kind of
image transformation was, we were able
to convert an image like this to another
image and if you notice in this one
all of the lines remain straight.
So you look at the capitol
t it's still the same here.
In essence,
all of the shapes remain consistent.
Of course, there's stretching going on.
The H is a little bigger.
But in essence, if you notice
is all the lines remain lines.
Warping basically comes down to
is when we basically want to take
points in an image like this and
map it to another set of points and
of course not stick to the constraint
that lines remain lines.
For example, in this case now,
if you notice, the T is curved,
E is curved a little bit, C and H.
In essence you can see
a swirl coming in, to the T.
And in fact you notice this
is no longer a line either.
And you see a lot of different
types of warps going on.
So here essentially what we mean is,
we need to now find a mathematical
function for
warping from a plane to another plane.
And in this case of course,
there are two planes, but
we're doing a lot of
non-rigid warping in-between.
So, in essence, that's what we're
going to talk about now is how we go
from image transformations
like the one we looked at.
Most of them were rigid, but they
were projectives and -line warps and
stuff like that.
In this case, we're really going to
start talking about non-rigid warps.