Now that we've coded the insert
method in our provider class,
we can call it from the AddTaskActivity
using a content resolver.
We'll want to link a call to the insert
method to this add button, so
that it's called whenever a user
inputs a task and clicks add.
And in the starter code, in
the activity_add_task.xml layout file,
there's already a method that's
called when this button is clicked.
If you scroll down to the very bottom of
this XML file, you'll see the XML for
the add button.
At the end is the OnClick attribute
which assigns a method to this
button called OnClickAddTask.
And this corresponds to a method of the
same name in the add task activity code.
So let's go to AddTaskActivity.
In here,
we can see this method onClickAddTask.
Right now, we can see that this
method is empty with some to does, so
nothing happens when
the add button is clicked.
We'll have to fill this in
to get a user's input and
insert it into our tasks data base.
Let's start by getting the task
description that a user inputs.
To retrieve a user's input description,
we have to retrieve the text they
entered into the edit text
view in the add task layout.
First we'll identify that edit text
view with a call to find view by ID and
its ID passed in.
Then we can call getText into string.
This retrieve is the input
task description and
then I can store it as a string
variable, which I've named input.
Let's also only create new
data when there is input text.
We don't want any empty
tasks being created
if someone presses the add button
without typing in a task to do.
So we'll just add an if statement that
checks if the input string has a length
equal to 0.
If it does,
we'll break out of this method, and
if it doesn't, we'll continue on.
After this,
we'll create a new ContentValues
object to place this task data into.
Then let's put this string input into
our contentValues with a call to the put
function.
You've seen this function before, and
to review, the put call first takes in
a key string that identifies
the kind of data being input,
which will just be the name
of the column it belongs to.
In our case, the description column.
Then the second argument is the actual
value that will be stored in the tasks
database, which is the input
string we retrieved.
Great, now we have
the description of the task, and
next, let's put the priority
into the content values too.
This time, the key will be for
the priority column.
And the data we want to save
is the value one through three
that a user selected.
And that's already stored in this
int variable named mPriority.
The variable mPriority is actually
changed in this onComplete method called
onPrioritySelected.
This method is called whenever
the priority buttons are clicked.
We just need to focus on onClickAddTask.
And these two lines of code
complete our ContentValues object.
It now holds a task description and
a priority.
Then we need to insert these
values into our database with
a call to a content resolver.
Here's the content resolver,
and we call insert on it.
We then pass in the correct content
URI for accessing the tasks directory,
which is the content URI constant
we defined in the contract.
And the last argument here
are the content values we just created.
This insert method should
return a URI if it works.
So let's actually create a toast so that
we can see what URI this insert returns.
That way, we can see if it
successfully inserted new data.
First we'll check if the URI exists, and
if it does, we'll display it as a toast.
Then at the very end of this method,
call finish.
Finish tells us that this
activity is over and so
we should return to the main activity
after an insert is complete.
And that finish is hooking
up our insert to the UI.
Now our insert should be
linked to the add button, and
it's time to test this out
on an emulator or phone.
So here's what our app
looks like right now.
Let's go to our add task activity, I'll
select a low priority and click add.
And you should see this toast
pop up with an ID of 1.
Next, it'll be your turn to code, and
then we'll move on to actually
displaying this data.