Now that we know all this cool history
about notifications in Android,
let's go ahead and add some to our app.
We'd like to get our Hydration app to
launch a notification every now and
then to remind us to drink our
much needed glasses of water.
We also want the notification to
launch the app when we click on it, so
that we can click on the cup and update
the count when we're done drinking.
Creating notifications
are pretty straightforward,
as we will see very soon.
But to get the notification to
launch the app when clicked,
we have first need to learn about
something called PendingIntents.
You've already seen and
used intents a couple of times before.
Intents allows your application to
launch various activities within
the same app, or
launch other applications altogether,
either explicitly or
implicitly using URIs.
Launching other apps or services
from your own application requires
the manifest to include
the appropriate permissions.
But, what if we want another application
to launch an activity in your own
application?
Like in the case with notifications.
Any notification in Android is
displayed by a system service
called NotificationManager.
A system service is a service that
starts by the Android system itself, and
is not part of your application
processes at all, which means,
if you want the NotificationManager
to be to launch an activity
in your application, you needed
to have the permissions to do so.
And since you can't modify
the system's service permissions,
pending intents come to play.
A PendingIntent is a wrapper
around a regular intent,
that is designed to be used
by another application.
The PendingIntent gives that
application the ability to perform
the included action,
as if it was your application,
with all the permissions your
application has been granted.
It can launch services,
private activities, and
broadcast protected intents, even if
your application is no longer running.
This works great for
the notification service, because we
want to be able to launch the hydration
activity from the notification
pop-up even if the app was closed.
To create a PendingIntent instance,
you can use one of those static
methods in the PendingIntent class.
Either getActivity or
getService or getBroadcast,
depending on what intent you want
to wrap in the PendingIntent.
All of those calls require
four parameters when called.
In the getActivity for example,
the four parameters are as follows.
The first one is the context.
The first one is the context in
which the PendingIntent should start
the activity.
The second is a requestCode integer that
helps you if you need to cancel that
PendingIntent in any time.
So make sure that this is a unique for
each PendingIntent you create.
Then, the actual intent you want
the other application to launch, and
then finally one of those flag
options to handle creating multiple
PendingIntents for the same intent.
If you plan to just create a single
PendingIntent for an intent, then you
could use either FLAG_UPDATE_CURRENT,
or FLAG_CANCEL_CURRENT.
Here's a sample code for
creating PendingIntents
using the getService method.
Notice that this method
call returns an actual
instance of the PendingIntent that
you will pass to another app,
which in our case will be
the NotificationManager.
And then you can expect
the NotificationManager to launch our
activity when the user
clicks on the notification.
Okay, enough talk.
Let's get back to coding and
get this notification up and running.