So the first one I've checked
here that it could defeat is any
password of length
greater than 12 bytes.
So then what happens when give it a
password that is greater then 12 bytes?
This get s that we have here,
Is going to read whatever
string you provide to it.
The one we have here is only for
12 characters.
So it's 12 bytes long.
But when we executing this
function says, get string.
It has no idea.
It's going to accept a string.
Whatever length you provide.
Since it's greater than 12 bytes.
The first 12 characters is
going to get stored here.
And those are going to
compared with this.
And where would
the remaining characters go?
Well remember this
variable starts some place
In the stack frame that
we are talking about.
On the stack, it's allocated space.
And when the 12 bytes run out, and
we have more input, what do we do?
We keep going.
So, starting address, and
then we fill the memory starting at that
address, as with the data that we have.
So, if it's 20 characters,
we're gong to store these characters we
get in the string in the next 20 bytes.
So think about what happens if
this variable allowed login is
right after this variable
password string.
If that's the case, then the bytes
of password string, that are beyond
12 okay, the characters in these
string that come after the first 12,
actually going to going to memory
we have assigned to this variable.
Initial value is zero, this characters
that we're going to read and
store in the locations or
memory that is actually allowed for
that's allocated for allowed login.
Well, that value zero is going to change
to something else depending on whatever
character that we're reading.
Even if the string doesn't match here.
Because this is whatever string
we are saying, any password so
it doesn't match.
We are not going to assign one here.
We're not going to come and
sign allow login one here.
After the comparison that we do,
but some data has already
over flown when we read this
strength into this variable.
And because that's what's
going to happen when we check,
do this check here to this side if
login could be rejected or allowed.
Is it going to be zero?
It won't be zero because some data.
That was input as a result of
get as function that we called,
has written into this location that was
allocated, so we have this overflow.
Remember, we started talking about
memory overflow, or buffer overflow.
So, if you sort of assume that there was
some likelihood that this variable was
sitting right next to this variable.
And if that is the case,
then if we had too much data for
password string it will end
getting stored into this
variable that will change it's value
from zero to something else, and
the outcome of this check
will be very different.
So even if the password Is different
from my password one, two, three, and
this check fails and
we don't set it here.
This is still going
to say login allowed,
because it's going to
find a known zero value.
Because this zero value
has been corrupted
because of the overflow that we have.
Because the string that we read
was greater than 12 bytes.
So it keeps going, writes into the space
that belongs to this variable and
as a result it's value
is no longer zero.
It's value is no longer
what it initially was,
which was in the case zero.
So this is the way to think
about how we defeated
is by changing the value of a variable
that is important obviously for
making, deciding which
way this check goes.
Corrupting it by supplying input.
Okay, that exceeds the amount
we had allocated for
this variable in which we
we're reading this input.
So all our flows always going to
be something like this.
It's going to all float,
over write something, and
we going to talk about
read only book flows also.
But typically, it's going to write and
corrupt those values or going to write
some values that attacker wants.
So in this case,
that hacker wants log in to be allowed
so, doesn't have to guess the password.
By carefully crafting input and
over writing this variable that hacker
is able to achieve the outcome,
which in this case is going to
be able to log in by doing this.
The same thing would happen in case
two because we haven't all four here
as well.
So any password of length
greater than 16 bytes,
it doesn't matter where it begins with.
Lets say after that because
we had checking 12 bytes,
we going to check the eight
that we have here.
So the next set of
characters may be different
than what the initialized
value here was.
So even if there isn't a match.
There is an overflow and
because of that we have the same
stuff happened that happened before.
Again, our input is not good here.
It is larger than the expected
input which is no more than 12,
so that's why we can
potentially defeat is.
And we'll see exactly
how that is happening.
If the password is
greater than eight bytes.
Well as long as it's not.
So it's any password.
It doesn't have to start with my or
my password or whatever it is.
But if it's nine bytes
ten bytes 11 bytes.
As you keep going.
Until the amount of
space that we have here.
This will not fail.
Because we're not overflowing.
But if it's greater than 12 as we saw
before, then we get into the same.
So if the password was nine characters
long, the check will not fail.
And that's why I did not check this.
The password check
code is going to output
the right value because we
don't have an overflow.
So, here we talked about playing with or
manipulating the logic of this program,
which is the password checking,
and achieving that or
accomplishing that by
providing input that is bad.
We considered some examples of input
where the password is different than
this password that was expected for
a certain user, but
we still able to get this program to
say that our login should be allowed.
Our login request is proper and
should be allowed.
So this is what bad input
can do to a program.
We're not changing the instructions.
Before we call the function,
we didn't get our hands on this code and
modify, okay, that's a lot harder to do.
We just calling a function
that we're allowed to do, and
give it a password, except we're
giving it a bad input when it ask for
a password and that's how we're
manipulating the execution of this code.