The vertex numbering is arbitrary,
so any choice will do.
Here's one.
Given a numbering,
just go through each vertex,
and, in the corresponding matrix row,
record its outgoing neighbors.
For instance, I'll start with 0.
Its outgoing edges lead to 1,
3, 5, and 6, so
you can record these in
Row 0 of the matrix.
Repeating this process should lead you
to the following matrix, or, if you did
a different vertex numbering, some
permutation of the rows and columns.
By the way, you might notice that
this matrix has three empty rows.
These correspond to vertices
with no outgoing edges.
Similarly, there are two empty columns.
These correspond to vertices
with no incoming edges.