What do you got?
>> So, like all of our other statements,
we start with context, patron and
then talking about the age
attribute right now.
>> So this is the first time we've
seen a situation were the context
has to do with an attribute.
We saw it where it could
be the class as a whole, or
we saw it where it can be an operation.
You can also have it association
with an attribute, and
the attribute here was age.
What else?
>> And
then our derived key word followed by,
I wrote currentDate minus birthDate.
So, birthDate is something that we have
access to based on our diagram, but
I wasn't quite sure how we
would get our currentDate.
I'm assuming you might have a date,
within some software systems
there's usually some way
to get the current date so.
>> Okay so
clearly any information system is going
to live within some context in which
there's going to be libraries and
system calls and that sort of thing.
So, we're assuming here that there's
some class which I've called
Operating System and it's got
a operation associated with it called
getDate and we can then compute
the difference between those two.
And, the difference will be
what we call the person's age.
Now notice that we're also
finessing some details here.
In this case, the subtraction
operation has to work on dates, and
we often, when we say age,
think of age in terms of years.
We did that for
the amount that could be checked out.
But the subtraction between dates might
be years and month, and days, and
sort of thing.
We would have to get that right
depending upon how we're going
to use dating within the system.