From our previous discussion about file
systems, we said that modern operating
systems hide the fact that there may
be different types of storage devices
with different types of internal
file system organizations.
And this is done by exporting a higher
level virtual file system interface.
Underneath this virtual
file system interface,
the operating system can also hide
the fact that there isn't even
local physical storage on a particular
machine where the files are stored.
But that instead everything is
maintained on a remote machine, or
on a remote file system that is
being accessed over the network.
These kinds of environments,
where there are multiple machines
that are involved in the delivery of
the file system service together
form a distributed file system.
In this case, simply the client, where
the data may be cached, and the server,
where the data is stored,
sit on two different machines, and
that's enough for
us to have a distributed file system.