You've started identifying the important
fields in the JSON response
that we'll need to extract in order to
display the correct data in our app.
Now, remember that once we know what
key value pairs we're interested in,
we also need to figure out how to
traverse the JSON object tree in order
to write app code that will parse those
same fields automatically for us.
By examining the formatted JSON data,
figure out the traversal path from
the root to the keys that
are specified in the quiz.
So here's your task.
I'd like you to describe in words,
the traversal path that you'd have to
take to get the specific pieces of
information within the JSON
response from the earthquake API.
Now here, I'd like you to describe
the path to find the magnitude of
the first earthquake.
Next, I'd like you to describe the path
you need to take to get to location,
then the same for time, and
the same for the website.
Also, be sure to use a JSON formatter
to make it easier to read the response.
You could write your answer in the form
of say, root node, right arrow,
JSONObject with name X right arrow,
and so on.