What I'm going to basically talk about
how we can go beyond the concept
of panoramas.
Now, we started this lecture
with panoramas being as
one of the foundational things of
computational photography, and
we learned different steps to get the,
get towards the end of building
a panorama,
which by now of course you know.
But now we're going to kind
of step both backwards and
forwards to kind of start thinking
about what can we do with
just a bunch of photographs that we
take in the space and use that to.
We could of course make panoramas out
of it about other types of things.
And within that basically, I'm going to
talk about the concept of taking a bunch
of pictures of space and
being able to kind of move around it
equivalent to what is
referred to as photo tourism.
And again, using that concept, I'm
going to introduce a variety of things,
how to put photographs on maps,
and also get into well-known
concepts which of course, you may
have already used, like street views.
So let's get started.