So you don't get any credit for d.
You have, even if d is true, you have no idea.
You get no credit for d, all right?
The answer, actually, is the original image.
And the way to think about that is, when I was doing the convolution or
the correlation.
There’s really no distinction of what’s the image and what’s the filter, right?
It’s just an operation where I combine these things.
So, before when I was convolving an impulse with a filter and
getting back the filter.
We were thinking of the impulses, the image, and the, and
the filter as the filter.
But you could have just thought of as the filter as the image, and
the impulse is the thing you're doing the convolute, convolution with.
And basically all the impulse is doing out,
is pulling out the single pixel and sticking it in the results.
So when you can convolve something with an impulse,
you get back just the original image.