Let's see a bunch of different examples.
This was one of the first classic
examples we looked at was ice skating.
And again, we wanted to find pure
YouTube examples do this and
these kinds of examples are hard because
finding the features that actually
have corners and stuff like that and
ice are relatively difficult.
But you'll see actually it works
quite well in this example.
So again, this is the output,
the red box is showing you
what the region we found that
actually synthesized this out.
Hopefully, you'll agree that
this works quite well and
you know, it works quite well on any
of these types of videos and it can be
either extended video sequences and
it works quite well on most of them.
Here you'll actually see even a little
bit of zooming going in and out.
Now of course, it did crop her
leg off a little bit at the top.
It doesn't know anything
about the content.
In fact, it's not doing any kind of
tracking of a person in that video.
It's just trying to figure out
the best possible camera path.
The advantage, of course,
of doing this kind of stuff is now we
have lots of videos that we've seen.
Here's a video that
also was from YouTube.
Here you can actually see
a couple of different things.
Here you see a lot more shake.
We'll talk about this shake in a bit.
This is actually because of the fact
that this actually is a camera that has
rolling shutter.
We'll talk about that in a bit.
But this is the output.
You'll hopefully agree,
much better and much more viewable.