[Narrator] To understand the beauty
of a policy, let me look into stochastic environments,
and let me try to apply conventional planning.
Consider the same grid I just gave you,
and let's assume there's a discrete start state,
the one over here, and we wish to find
an action sequence that leads us to
the goal state over here.
In conventional planning we would create a tree.
In C1, we're given 4 action choices,
north, south, west, and east.
However, the outcome of those choices
is not deterministic
So rather than having a single outcome,
nature will choose for us the actual outcome.
In the case of going north, for example,
we may find ourselves in B1,
or back into C1.
Similarly for going south, we might find
ourselves in C1, or back in C2, and so on.
This tree has a number of problems.
The first problem is the branching factor.
While we have 4 different action choices,
nature will give us up to 3 different outcomes
which makes up to 12 different things we have to follow.
Now in conventional planning we might have to follow just 1 of those,
but here we might have to follow up to 3 of those things.
So every time we plan a step ahead,
we might have to increase the breadth of
the search of tree by at least a factor of 3.
So one of the problem is the branching
factor is too large.