Before moving onto concrete examples,
I want to explicitly mention
one more design dimension when it
comes to distributed file systems.
We said that the clients and the server
can be distributed to different
machines, but the file server
itself can also be distributed.
This can be achieved via replication or
partitioning.
With replication,
the file system can be replicated onto
multiple machines, such that every
single machine holds an exact replica
of all of the files in the system.
The benefit of this can be
that the client request can be
load balanced across all replicas,
across all machines.
And this can lead to better performance.
The system overall can
be more available,
it will return responses more quickly.
And also it is more fault tolerant.
When one replica fails,
the remaining replicas can continue
serving the data for all the files.
The downside is that now
the write operations
that update to the file system state,
may become more complex.
Not only do we have to worry
about the consistency among
the clients that may cache the file,
and the servers, but
also about the consistency
among all of the replicas.
A simple solution is to force every
single write to each replica.
And only after that is done to
actually return to the client and
to consider that the write
operation has completed.
This will slow down all writes.
An alternative would be to allow
the writes to be applied to one server,
to a single replica copy.
And then to have some background process
that asynchronously propagates these
writes to the other replicas.
If it turns out that there are any
differences among the state of a file on
different replicas, then these
differences need to be resolved.
For instance, we can use
a simple technique like voting,
where the votes are taken from
all servers and majority wins.
There are many other techniques how
these sorts of issues can be resolved,
but these are beyond
the scope of this course.
The other technique is to distribute the
file system state using partitioning.
As the name suggests, in partitioning
every single machine has only a portion
of the state, only a subset of
all the files in the system.
This may be done based on file names.
For instance, all the files from
a to m sit on one machine, and
all the files from n to z
sit on another machine.
Or we may choose a policy where
different directories are stored on
different machines, where we'd somehow
partition the hierarchical name
space of the directory tree structure.
There can be various criterias that
can be used to decide how to partition
all the state in the file system.
Using this technique, we can definitely
achieve greater availability compared to
a single server design.
Each server here will hold
fewer files and therefore,
will be able to respond to a request for
those files more quickly, so
will appear to be much more available.
The most important benefit of this
design is that it provides for
greater scalability when we consider
the size of the file system,
the overall size of all the files
stored in that file system.
With replication, given that every
server has to hold all the files,
the size of the file system
will be limited by the capacity
of a single machine.
In partitioning,
if we need the bigger file system,
we just add more machines and
problem solved.
And finally,
unlike in the replication case,
in the partitioning case when we need
to perform a write to a single file,
that will remain localized
to a single machine.
So that's much simpler
than what we have here.
One of the main problems with this
approach is that when there's a failure,
a portion of the data in this
file system will be lost.
So, all of the files that are stored
on that particular machine,
the machine that's failed,
will not be accessible anymore.
In addition, balancing the system is
more difficult because we have to take
into consideration how
the specific files are accessed.
If there is a particular file
that's more frequently accessed by
most clients in the systems,
then that will create hotspots.
Finally, these two techniques can
be combined to have a solution
where the files are partitioned
across different groups or
in different volumes.
And each of these groups
is then replicated,
potentially with different
degree of replication.
For instance, you can have partitions
of read-only files versus files that
are also written to, and
you can replicate the read-only
files to a greater degree.
Or you can consider having
smaller partitions where there
are files that are more frequently
accessed, versus larger partitions
that consist of more files but
less frequently accessed files.
And then you can consider using
different degrees of replication for
the partition that has more
frequently accessed files,
versus less frequently accessed files.
So that overall each machine has
approximately the same number of
expected client requests.