All right,
let's add Firebase Storage to our app.
The user flow will look like this.
In the app,
when we press the Photo Picker button,
we'll create an intent to Android's
general image picker activity.
We'll launch the intent using
startActivityForResult.
The reason that we're using
startActivityForResult,
instead of just start activity,
is because we'll want to do something
with the user's chosen photo.
And the user's chosen photo is
the result of the activity.
After you've chosen a photo from
the Photo Picker, our app will receive
the photo in the onActivityResult
callback, which we'll then override.
In onActivityResult, we'll send
the photo straight to Firebase Storage.
Once the file is stored in Firebase
Storage, we can refer to it by its URL.
In Friendly Chat,
we'll take that URL and
send it directly to
our messages database.
Adding the URL to the messages
database will then trigger our
ChildEventListener.
Finally, our adapter is already
set up to display either text or
photo messages.
So when we add a friendly message object
to our adapter that has a photo URL,
it'll already know how
to display that photo.
Okay, let's start by setting
up our Photo Picker.