In an earlier lesson,
we described the process like
an order of toys in a toy shop.
In this lesson, we will see how
processes can communicate with
each other during their execution.
But first let's see how inter-process
communication is achieved in a toy shop
illustration.
IPC is like working
together in the toy shop.
First, the workers can
share the work areas.
The workers can call each other.
And finally, the interactions among the
workers requires some synchronization.
Looking at this list, it is fairly
obvious that the workers have many
options in terms of how they
can interact with one another.
When sharing a work area, the workers
can communicate amongst each other
by leaving common parts and tools on
the table to be shared among them.
Second, the workers can directly
communicate by explicitly requesting
something from one another, and
then getting the required response.
And finally, good communication
using either one of these methods
requires some synchronization so that
a worker knows when the other one has
finished talking or the other one
has finished with a particular tool.
One way of thinking about this is that
a worker may say I will start a step
once you finish yours.
As we will see, processes can also
interact amongst each other and
work together in similar ways.
First, processes can have a portion
of physically shared memory,
and any data they both need to access
will be placed in such shared memory.
We will discuss this
further in this lesson.
Second, processes can explicitly
exchange messages, requests, and
responses via message passing
mechanisms that are supported through
certain APIs like like sockets.
For both of these methods, processes
may need to wait on one another and
may need to rely on some synchronization
mechanism like mutexes to
make sure that the communication
proceeds in a correct manner.