Let's stop and review the 3 main forms of learning.
We have supervised learning,
in which the training set
is a bunch of input/output pairs--
X1,Y1; X2, Y2; et cetera--
in which we try to produce a function:
y equals f of x--
and so the learning is producing this function, f.
Then we have unsupervised learning,
in which we're given just a set of data points--
X1, X2, and so on--
and each of these points, maybe, has many
dimensions, many features.
And what we're trying to learn is some patterns in that--
some clusters of these data--
or you could just say what we're trying to learn
is a probability distribution
or what's the probability that this
random variable will have particular values;
and learn something interesting from that.
In this Unit, we're introducing the third type of learning--
reinforcement learning--
in which we have a sequence of action and state transitions.
So: state and action, state and action--and so on.
And at some point, we have some rewards associated with these.
So there's a reward, and maybe not a reward for this state;
and then another reward for this state--
and the rewards are just scalar numbers, positive or negative numbers.
What we're trying to learn here is:
at optimal policy, what's the right thing to do in any of the states?