Now, let's move on to the next
step of the authentication flow.
According to Eden's diagram,
the next thing we need to
do is log in with the API.
If we look back at the code as
soon as we get our request token,
this is where we need to
continue to the next step.
First, let's store the request
token in the app delegate
in case we need it later, and then
we'll call the loginWithToken method.
If we skip down to this method,
we can see that it's currently empty,
and I did this on purpose.
I want you to get more exposure writing
the networking code involved in
all 7 steps, so that the code
just becomes second nature.
For this exercise,
start in the API's documentation, and
find the proper method for
logging into the movie database.
Once you find it, take a look
at any required parameters and
also what an example response
looks like for that method.
Then, implement the 7
steps in order to login.
And once you're able to successfully
login with the API, print a message that
says you're ready to get the session ID,
and when you're done, check this box.