In the previous example, we saw how we can divide an image by a number.
Dividing by 2 is the same as multiplying by 0.5.
And the order of writing these two doesn't matter either.
The constant 0.5 is known as a scalar.
This potentially comes from the fact that it scales the image values.
Let's see what the result looks like compared to the original image.
Halve the intensity values, clearly darker.
Note that we can potentially multiply by any number, even greater than 1.
Multiplying the intensity values by 1.5 makes the image brighter.
And we see the same washed out effect in certain areas.
This is due to the image values above 255 getting truncated at that limit.
In Octave, we can write a function to perform a common operation.
Let's turn the scaling into a function.
We write a function by typing in the word function,
followed by a variable name for the return value.
Then an equal sign, the name of the function, and parameters in parentheses.
This is followed by the body of the function.
In this case, we want the result to be the product of value and image.
To ensure that we are performing element-wise multiplication,
let's change the star to a dot star.
This doesn't make any difference when one of the values is scalar, but
when the two quantities being multiplied are vectors or
matrices, then star and dot star produce different results.
We end the function by typing endfunction.
Let us load an image and try out this function.
And there is the scaled image.