Let's take a short digression and discuss why we're building a model.
In fact, this is a very important question because the answer to
this will determine how we validate our models.
We have discussed various models that we've built and the ways we
can quantify the errors in terms of the loss function for each model.
We've also encountered various ways to calculate the loss
function of each model.
We have seen that the choice of the loss of the risk function is dependent on
how we formulate the problem.
In fact, we're free to choose our loss or risk function and
a choice of a loss or risk function can result in a well performing model.
Now this choice is very dependent on the problem formulation.
The problem formulation itself is in
turn dependent on this question of the purpose of the model itself.
In natural sciences, we often build very well behaved, sometimes linear and
first order in time, models with simplifying assumptions of the parameters.
In this case a good fit to the model parameters, often their point values,
is desired and we find the best fit of the parameters to the data.
This is often referred to in fields like economics and
many branches of engineering as the Model Identification Problem.
In statistical learning, we accomplish more than just identification.
We choose systems that are quite complex and
often models with many non-linearly correlated variables to describe them.
In this case, we want to recognize the patterns in the data,
to not only solve the identification problem, but
also to accurately predict such patterns for all possible future
data where the patterns are similar but not necessarily the same.
Validating a statistical or machine learning model does not
only requires us to validate the model on the data we have, but
also to hedge the model's prediction abilities with probabilistic bounds