The blue line has the biggest extremes.
It's got to be the original.
The green line is smoother, but has some uncharacteristic segments.
For instance, here.
While the original sequence decreased significantly,
the green line actually increased a little.
Similarly here, the original sequence increased, but the green line dipped.
This indicates that values other than the central value at
each point are affecting the results too much.
Looking at the first unusual spike, it seems that the peaks on
both sides are contributing as much as the central value.
The green line is a result of a blindly uniform filter.
The pink line is also smooth, but more importantly its peaks and
troughs are well-aligned with the original.
This seems to indicate that the central value had more weightage compared to
the neighboring values.
So yes, the pink line is a result of applying the center weighted filter.
One minor detail, when applying these filters,
we would want to scale the weights so that they sum to one.
For the uniform filter this would be dividing by 5.
And for the non uniform filter we'd divide by 16.