Congratulations.
You just wrote your
very first test suite.
Sure, it was a pretty simple one but
you've seen firsthand
the importance of testing.
We identified a number of problems with
the first version of our ad function and
we refactored our code
to fix those issues.
More importantly,
now that we have tests,
we can be confident we don't break
anything during our refactoring
because our tests will always be there
to tell us when everything is okay.
And more importantly, when things break.
In the next lesson, I'll introduce you
to a testing framework called Jasmine
and we'll start writing
some more real world tests.