So, one of the other ideas
that was very interesting and
novel in this paper on photo tourism
was let's try to do this incrementally.
There's a lot of work on trying to do
this model adjustment and structure for
motion, basically doing it for
the entire graph.
That is figuring out all the matches and
then trying to connect all of them and
rather completely for
each and every image.
One of the interesting things that
they proposed was lets try to do this
incrementally.
Let's not try to solve
the entire problem.
Let's do it as a new image comes in.
So which basically means is
let's just take two images and
use that to build a kind of
correspondence and matches and
as another one comes in,
let's keep on adding them in.
Say, for example here you see
two cameras looking at a scene,
the claro point is a scene here.
And basically,
how can we use this incrementally to not
compute the structure for the scene, but
at the same time if more cameras
come in, how can we model more?
So here basically, just by two, you get
a little bit of sense of the scene.
But next, what we'll do is
basically start adding cameras.
More cameras, more points are visible.
Incrementally, you add to it.
And now, actually you can see a much
detailed plot of points generating for
the scene and that's what we want.
Now we know the orientation of each and
every camera.
We also know a cloud of points.
I'll show you examples of this in a bit,
that'll clarify this.
So basically, now you see a cloud
of points and using the mouse,
we can basically browse and
click on one picture that basically
shows the registered image through
the whole 3D cloud of points.
And then of course,
we can move around and
find other images as we have seen
before in the other example.
You can also then, of course,
click into different parts of am image.
Zoom in and see other image that
may be best registered things.
See more details and browse around.
Quiet an interesting and intuitive way,
looking around the scene like this.
So these are researchers who developed
this whole photo tourism system
were able to then work with the whole
concept was actually then taken over and
generated into a technology preview
referred to as photosynth.net.