Let's quickly talk about what the toy
shop manager should want to evaluate.
It should be something like this.
Given that the most complex case of
toy orders includes trains, then we
should have in each of the trials a set
of orders that are really for trains.
Second, the toy shop has
three working areas.
We can perform any kind of toy order
in each of the working area and
multiple workers can share an area.
So, as we're trying to see how many
more workers can we add in the system,
how many more toys can we process,
we really should be trying to get as
many more workers per working area.
Now, if we take a look at
configuration one, configuration one
has correctly in each trial order of
trains, the sequence of train orders.
That corresponds to our
worst case scenario.
However, the way the workers
are varied in the first case,
there are a total of three workers,
so there is one in each working area.
In the second case,
there are a total of four workers, so
the first working area
has one extra worker.
So the number of resources in that case,
is larger for the first working area,
and then lower for the next two.
Similarly, in the third trial We have
in two working areas, two workers and
in the last one just one.
It's really hard to
draw any conclusions.
The amount of resources that's
available in each of these for
handling the toys is not equal,
therefore,
it doesn't really tell us anything about
the worst case capacity of the system.
If we take a look at
the second configuration here,
we have the first trial
is an order of blocks.
The second trial is an order of bears.
The third trial is an order of trains.
Again, it doesn't tell us anything about
the worst case capacity of the system.
This could tell us something, but
it really is not the question
that the manager is asking.
The third configuration similarly,
it could provide some information.
In every single one of these,
the workload is mixed.
So this could correspond to the average
number of toys that can be processed
with different number of workers.
So how is the average throughput
impacted by adding more
workers in the store?
Again, however, this doesn't
address the question of how is
the worst case impacted by adding
more workers to the store?
So that basically gives us the answer
to the final configuration.
The last configuration is identical
to configuration 3 in the number of
workers, but it uses the worst case
scenario, so it's just orders of trains.
So this tells us how much better will
I be able to handle the worst case,
of just receiving trains,
if I add more and more workers, and
then really adding an even amount
of workers per working area.
This is a meaningful set of experiments
that will let me draw some conclusions.
It will also likely ultimately
demonstrate what is the capacity of
the individual working area.
So, let's say, if I tried maybe to
add another trial where I'm running
train orders with 12 workers, so
four workers per working area.
Likely, I will, at some, point no longer
start seeing any kind of improvement,
simply because I cannot squeeze
in more workers per working area.
So performing this type of
experiment will actually be useful.