In the consistency models
we discussed so far,
the memory was accessed via read and
write operations only.
In the weak consistency models,
it's possible to have something
beyond just read and
write operations when memory's accessed.
In the models we've described so far,
the underlying memory managers, or state
managers in general, had to determine or
infer what are important updates and
then how to order and propagate
the information regarding those updates.
For instance, there's no way for
the distributed memory managers
to understand whether or
not indeed the value of
y was somehow computed based on
this value x that was read from m1.
So it's perfectly possible that p2
really just completely randomly came up
with this value y that was written in
m2, and that had nothing to do with this
fact that it previously read
the value of x from location m1.
So it saw this particular update.
However, with the causal
consistency model,
it will be forced that every process,
every processor in the system
has to observe that the value of the
memory location m1 has been updated to
x before the value of the memory
location was updated to y.
However, for instance, in the same
process, p2, maybe at a later
time there is another update that's
happening to memory location m3,
and the value z is written there.
And perhaps this particular value,
z, was directly computed,
based on the value that was
read from memory location 1.
So there maybe is a dependence
between this particular write, and
the value that was read here,
but not between these two.
How can a memory system
distinguish these?
To do this, the memory system
introduces synchronization points.
The synchronization points are
operations that the underlying memory
system makes available to
the upper layers of the software.
So, in addition to being able to
read and write a memory location,
you'll also be able to tell
the distributed shared memory sync.
What a synchronization point does,
it makes sure that all of the updates
that have happened prior to sync,
the synchronization point will
become visible at other processors.
And also, synchronization point makes
sure that all of the updates that
have happened on other processors will
become visible subsequently at this
particular processor in the future.
If p1 performs a synchronization
operation at this particular
point after this write was performed,
that doesn't guarantee
that p2 will see that particular
update at this moment.
Although this read operation is
happening according to some real time,
some external observer,
at a later point in time than
the synchronization point
in the preceding write, p2
has not made an attempt to synchronize
with the distributed shared memory.
So p2 has no guarantees that it will
see the updates performed by others.
So this synchronization point, it has
to be called both by the process that's
performing the updates, and also by
the processes that want to see, and
want to see the guarantee
that they will see updates.
However, once the synchronization
operation is performed in p2,
afterwards, p2 will be guaranteed
that it will see all of the previous
updates that have happened to any
memory location in the system.
So if we perform a read operation of
the memory location m1 at this point in
time, after the synchronization, we're
guaranteed that p2 will see this update.
In this case, in this model, we use
a single synchronization operation for
all of the variables in the system,
for the entire shared memory.
It is possible to have solutions where
different synchronization operations
are associated with some
subset of the state.
For instance,
with a granularity of individual pages.
It is also possible to separate the
steps when a particular process requires
that all of the updates performed by
other processors are visible to it.
We call that the entry point, or
the point when we are acquiring
the updates made by others.
For instance,
at this particular synchronization point
we can perform an entry operation and
synchronize with all the updates that
were performed on others,
in this case on p1.
And then we can have a separate
synchronization primitive,
that's the exit point or this is
the point where we release to all
other processes or processors the fact
that we have performed certain updates.
So for instance,
at this synchronization point,
only the updates made by p1 will
be forced to other processes.
The idea with these finer
grained operations or
these mechanisms to
really directly control
what kinds of messages will be sent by
the underlying state management system,
by the DSM layer at a particular point
of time, is to make sure that the system
controls the amount of overheads
that are imposed by the DSM layer.
The idea is to limit the required data
movement, the required messages and
coherence separations, that will be
exchanged among the nodes in the system.
But the downside of this is that
the distributed shared memory layer
will have to maintain some
additional state to keep track of
exactly what are all the different
operations that it needs to support and
how it needs to behave when it
sees a particular type of request.
In summary, all of these models that,
in addition to just pure read and
write operations, introduce some
types of synchronization primitives
are referred to as weak
consistency models and
they allow us to control the overheads
of the system from one aspect.
However, they introduce some additional
overheads that are necessary in order to
support that the added operations.