Okay, this problem's goal is
exactly the same as the last one.
So really, it's just the code that's
changed, and let's see what's different.
To start off with our hand simulation,
we're initializing and declaring
a variable here called raspberryPrice,
and we're setting it to 5, and
this next line here is the first
time we're display something, and
we're saying 1 box: $ and then whatever
the current value of raspberryPrice is,
which right now, is 5.
So this is going to print out 1 box: $5.
Seems pretty good.
Now, in the next line,
things change up a little bit.
We're taking raspberryPrice and
we're changing its value to 10.
Note, that doesn't change
what gets displayed here.
This is already displaying 1 box: $5.
In area 2, we're saying, 2 boxes: $, and
then the correct price of
raspberryPrice, which is ten.
So, 2 boxes: $10, looks good.
Now we move to the next line, which is
going to be displaying in textbox 3.
It says 3 boxes: $ and
then raspberryPrice,
which is currently 10, times 3,
which would make this 30.
That's a little bit problematic,
because now we're saying 3 boxes is 30
dollars, where it should be 15 dollars.
So we see this difference arise,
because unlike the previous example, we
are changing the value of raspberryPrice
in the middle of the program, and hand
simulating sort of helped us see this.
This is an example where it's so
important to keep track
of your instructions, and
exactly what's going on.
If we didn't really record the fact
that the variable had changed to 10,
we wouldn't have seen the error here.