Once we've permitted multiple
copies of the same data page or
object to be stored in multiple,
locations,
the question of maintaining
consistency comes up.
Since distributed shared memory is
intended to behave in a similar manner
to shared memory in shared memory multi
processors, let's remind ourselves what
we did in shared memory multi
processors, for consistency management.
In the lesson one synchronization,
we explained that in shared memory
multiprocessors consistency is
managed using two mechanisms,
a write-invalidate or write-update.
With write-invalidate, whenever
the content particular memory location
that's cached to multiple caches is
changes on one CPU in one cache.
Back via the coherence mechanisms will
be propagated to other caches and
in the case of write and
validate the other caches will
invalidate their cache content.
Or in the event that we have
a write update coherence mechanism,
then the other caches will receive
the newly updated copy of that
particular memory location.
These necessary coherence operations
are triggered by the shared
memory support in the hardware
on every single write operation.
And the overhead of supporting that
in the distributed shared memory
system where the latencies and
the costs of performing distributed
communication are too high is
not going to be justifiable.
For these reasons for
distributed shared memory,
we'll look at coherence
operations that are more
similar to what we discussed in
the distributed file systems lecture.
One option is to push invalidation
messages when a data item is written to.
This is similar to the server-based
approach that we talked about in
the distributed files systems lesson.
But remember that the state management
in DSM systems is done by all peers.
We don't have clients and
servers, per se in this case.
The other option is for the nodes to
pull information about any modified
state from one or
more of the other nodes in the system.
This can be done either periodically or
purely on demand whenever some process
needs to access that state locally,
it will check with others to see
whether it's been modified or not.
I intentionally chose the terms push and
pull since these are commonly used
to distinguish between this more
proactive versus this more reactive
approach to accomplishing some tasks.
In this case,
maintaining the consistency among
two notes in the distributed system.
Another set of terms associated with
these types of actions is eager
versus lazy.
The push based method is eager
since it forces propagation of
information immediately, eagerly.
in contrast, the pull method is lazy,
since it lazily gets the information
when it's convenient or
when it becomes absolutely necessary.
And yet, another set of terms to
distinguish between these two types of
approaches is pessimistic
versus optimistic.
This push based eager method
is pessimistic in that it
expects the worst.
They expect that the modified
state will be needed
at other places at other
nodes immediately.
And so with these methods,
nodes are in a rush to notify others
that a modification happened.
In contrast, these optimistic
methods hope for the best.
Here the hope is that the modified
state wouldn't be needed elsewhere
anytime soon.
And that there is plenty of
opportunity to accumulate information
regarding modifications before anyone
has to pay for the cost of sending
an invalidation or moving data
across the distributed system.
Regardless of whether we talk about
the push versus pull based methods.
When exactly they get triggered,
whether its after every single data has
been modified or whether its with a
period of five seconds or ten seconds or
one millisecond.
Or in some other manner that really
is going to depend on the consistency
model for the shared state and
we will discuss what are the options for
consistency models a little
bit later in this lecture.