In our discussion of computability and
complexity, we focused
on deciding languages.
As we began our discussion of
algorithms, however, we began to talk
about optimization problems instead
without ever formally defining them.
This was fine then, but
as we discuss approximation algorithms,
we're going to circle back to some of
the ideas we encountered in complexity.
And we need a formal
way to connect them.
Therefore we're going to
define an optimization problem
using the min vertex cover
as an example to illustrate.
And this will allow us to
give a formal definition
of an approximation algorithm.
The first thing we need to
define an optimization problem
is a set of valid instances.
For the minimum vertex cover problem
this is just a set of undirected graphs.
For each instance,
there's a set of feasible solutions.
For Min Vertex Cover, this is the set
of vertex covers for the graph.
And we need an objective function,
the thing we're trying to optimize.
For min vertex cover,
this is just the size of the cover.
And of course we need to say
whether we're minimizing or
maximizing this objective function.
Naturally for min vertex cover,
we're minimizing.
Relating this back to our
treatment of complexity,
we say that an MP optimization problem
is one where these first three criteria
are computable in polynomial time.
That is to say, there's
a polynomial algorithm that tells
whether the input instance is valid.
There's one that can check whether
a solution is feasible for
the given instance, and there's one that
can evaluate the objective function.
All these things being
done in polynomial time.
Now every optimization problem
has a decision version of a form
is the optimum value at most
sum value for the min, and
a least sum value for the max.
For minimum vertex cover,
we ask is there a cover of size
less than some threshold T?
With this in mind,
we say that an optimization problem is
NP-hard if it's decision version is.
Our problem is NP-hard,
by the way, if an NP complete
problem can be reduced to it.
In our example, min vertex cover is
NP-hard because the decision version is.
Remember that we reduced maximum
independent set to vertex cover.
So that's how optimization
relates to complexity.