Here is the answer.
No.
If you replace four with par four,
the algorithm will be incorrect.
Replacing four with par four
is a bit like running with
running with scissors, don't do that.
If by chance you've taken
the other awesome systems and
architecture courses that
are a part of the OMSCS.
Then you probably know about
multithreading and locks.
You could use those constructs to
protect these updates to the variable K.
But were you to do so, you really
wouldn't get much parallelism anyway,
because any simultaneous threads would
most likely contend for the lock.
I think what we need is a different and
more algorithmic approach.