And the answer is just 5.
If you look carefully for K=1,
this guy will be mis-classified.
It's closer to a plus than a minus.
Similarly, for K=3, this guy has 2 nearby pluses and 1 minus,
so it would be positive.
For K=5, to get the correct answer,
the 5 nearest neighbors of this guy are
those 3 minuses plus perhaps those 2 pluses over here.
This guy has in his 5 neighborhood
these 3 pluses over here, plus a minus, plus a plus.
This data point over here has 2 pluses with 3 of the surrounding minuses,
and they are all classified correctly.
For K=7, this minus data point will have
4 pluses, 3 minuses over here,
and then everything in the vicinity becomes positive,
so it must be 4 plus and it will be mis-classified.
The same is true for K=9.
The minus over here will have 1, 2, 3 minuses,
5 pluses, and the minus over here,
which makes 4 minuses.
It will be classified as positive.
So K=5 would have been the only correct answer.