Now let's build on an example using the simple point arithmetic.
Let's say I get this image, image one.
Here I have Einstein, I was coming, visiting the office, and
he's sitting in front of, on the desk here.
And now what I actually want to also do is kind in tract with this image.
But Einstein, actually, before he visited,
I was able to take a picture of the same location before Einstein came in.
So now I have two images, Image 2 and Image 1, here there's no Einstein.
There is of course Einstein.
So now the question is, by just doing simple point arithmetic,
or pixel additions and subtractions and such at each and every pixel.
Again these two images are the same size,
can I actually now find interesting information between these two images?
So by just doing subtraction of this first image from the second image what
will we get?
We will basically now be getting all of the pixels that actually have
changed from first to the second.
So this actually becomes an example of almost doing something which is
referred to either as change detection or you on background subtraction.
So using this I should be able to figure out all of the pixels that
are in this image, that are also in this image by subtracting it.
But then all the pixels I should find are the ones that have
changed from one to the other.
Of course, in this case, I've taken the exact same images,
the location of each and every part of this image is the same as this one.
That is, you can imagine this camera was on a tripod, did not move at all, and
was a controlled situation.
So of course, they're exactly the same background, and
therefore I can do background segmentation or background separation.
So by just doing a simple point arithmetic of Image 1 by Image 2,
I get, just all of the pixels.
Again, I haven't, I mean, this is an illustrative example.
I haven't actually done clean-up or anything else like that.
But you'll notice that all of the pixels that get highlighted are the ones where
Einstein is.
So now you start seeing the pixels over here, and
of course these are the ones I wanted.
I wanted to find all of these but I did not want to find these.
So, basically now I want to find all the red parts, but not the green ones.
Of course, this gives me that result, gives me all the pixels, and
of course, now I can do, start doing various types of processing on this one.
Here's an example.
One, I can basically just look for the ones and zeroes.
That is, everywhere there is a value of certain things, I basically say,
okay, make it be black.
So all of the smaller values become black.
All of the bigger values that are closer to much more you know,
the white of things, become white.
So this becomes 1, this is 0, becomes a binary image.
And I can run this process, between, the subtraction that I have,
between the two images.
And this allows me to now find pixels, which basically are where Einstein is.
Now, I know those of you paying attention to this,
you should have gotten the head and all that kind of stuff correctly.
It kind of implies that in some of my computations I didn't pay attention.
Again, I'm showing this as an illustrative example more than anything else.