Welcome back to computer vision,
today we're going to continue our exploration of future detections.
Remember last time we started talking about interest points of ways to
detecting locations the image we can get back to.
And we, focused on finding corners, and why corners?
Well as we talked about.
Corners had this nice property that if you put a little operator over,
over an area that was a corner, whether you moved it left or
right, or however you moved it, you would see a pattern changing.
And that was not true if you were over a flat region, or
over an edge, or an edge if you moved in the direction parallel to the edge,
you couldn't see, any change.
And, we derived some, nice mathematical formulations,
where we talk about the error as you slid things around.
We said how the error was zero, before you do any sliding at all.
And that, as you move, the error changes a little bit.
And, what we did was, we said, well, can we build a model.
Or can we approximate that error,
by looking locally at the structure of the image.
And then we wrote this out as a expression really just involving what's called
the second order moment matrix.
That moment matrix being the sum of the squares, of the first derivatives.
So I x squared, I y squared, or I x times I y.
And even though it was a second order,
moment, there were no second derivatives, right?
No I, I sub, xx.
Cause those all went away when we evaluated around u and v being zero, zero.
You can go back and re review that lecture.
And then we talked about how Harrison who?
Harrison who, yeah who knows.
No Harrison Stevens, did this thing where you derive an operator based upon that
little matrix based upon it's demonstrative trace.
And you could use that to find good points.
And we showed this horrible giraffe image and we said,
yep, the thing seems to work pretty well finding those points