Okay.
So now that we
know that recipe is a class, let's
see what that looks like in the code.
Let's start by saying
that it is a class.
And since we want to store
it in the datastore,
it's going to be a subclass
of the datastore model.
That means that I'm going to
take a generic data model and
define something specific called Recipe
to store in the App Engine datastore.
Now let's take a look at the properties.
Just as we saw for fields and
message classes, we're going to have
to construct the properties, so
let's put some parens in here.
Notice that unlike ProtoRPC fields,
we don't have to put a number here.
But we do have to put for ingredients,
because there are multiple ingredients
in a recipe is that we'll say
that it's a repeated field.
Repeated field is basically like
an array of values of a particular type.
Here, ingredients is going to
be like an array of strings.
This is looking more and
more like real working Python.
There's just a couple of things left.
First off, where do all these
property classes come from?
They're provided by
the App Engine datastore library,
which is called
google.appengine.ext.ndb.
And since all of these come from ndb,
we're going to have to be ndb
dot on each one of these.
And hey, that's it.
What we have here in real Python isn't
very much different from the outline
that we started with, but
now it's fully functional.
So that's our intro to using
the datastore from Python.
I think you've got it now.
Let's go back to Magnus to learn
some more about properties.