So Sam's answer to implicit
versus explicit intents again,
was structured as a very broad question.
And a lot of developers they may
know some of the intents but
they don't necessarily know the names
and, it was okay in this case for
Sam didn't know the difference
between the two.
Because he actually had used them in the
past he just didn't recognize the name
and I think it's important
to say that I wouldn't
view him negatively because he
didn't know the names per say.
I just wanted to know that he's
used that functionality before.
And so I think just being able to
describe it even if you don't have
the answer immediately is
usually very important.