So now I'm going to look at the code
that I added to implement the scrolling
list of all the dinners.
So the first thing I'm going to do is in
the com.example.android.dinner package,
I'm going to add a new Java class
called ShowAllDinnersActivity.
This class extends ListActivity.
It knows how to get a list
of all the dinners.
It uses an adapter to display
all the dinners in the list, and
it defines the onListItemClick, so
that when an item on the list is
clicked we send an intent to start
the OrderDinnerActivity, and
passing in the selectedDinner.
Now over, in Main Activity, we add the
showDinnerList method, which is going to
be invoked whenever somebody clicks on
the show me all the dinners button.
And all this method does,
is it sends an intent to start
the ShowAllDinnersActivity.
So that's it for the code, but
now we need to do the layouts.
The first thing I'm going to do is
add the button to the main screen,
to list all the dinners.
And there it is, show all the dinners.
But I'm not done with the layout yet.
I need to add
the listalldinners.xml file,
which is a list of all the dinners.
So we need to add
the showdinnerinrow.xml layout file,
which is a layout for
each dinner entry in the list.
All right, that should do it.
So, I'm going to redeploy my app and
hopefully we'll see
the changes in the UI.
So of course, one more thing you
need to do in the code is to update
the AndroidManifest.xml to include your
new class, ShowAllDinnersActivity.
If you don't do this, it It won't work.
So that's all there is to it.
Now I'm going to run my app again,
and let's see if it works.
So, I press my Show All the Dinners,
and let's see.
Oh, and there's my list of dinners.
Cool.