So again the question
is which of these five
problems could cause a TCP
session to time out, for
instance between your browser and
a server that you're connecting to.
So the first one,
the other host is powered off suddenly.
If the computer at the other end of
your connection is shut down properly,
then programs running on
it including web servers
will be able to close down any
connections they have open.
But if it's just powered off suddenly,
yes,
that can cause those connections
to time out for the other end.
So this one is true.
Number two, a windstorm blows down
the cable between you and your ISP.
If a windstorm takes out
your internet connection,
that means that any traffic you try to
send will be dropped by your router.
So, yes this can certainly produce
time outs, although some routers and
operating systems will come up with
a more useful error message than that.
But basically number two is true.
Number three,
your DNS server stops working.
Keeping a TCP session open
doesn't rely on the DNS.
A client uses DNS to look up a server's
IP address before connecting, but
after that, it's normally not needed.
So the DNS server breaking should not
cause open TCP sessions to timeout.
Number four, you're connecting
to a server that doesn't exist.
If you try to access a server that
doesn't exist, you might get a timeout,
or you might get a different error.
We saw it earlier in the lesson.
Since you might get a timeout,
we'll call that true.
Number five, you're using a Windows PC
to watch this course, and
Microsoft's website is down.
But a Windows PC is not going
to lose its network clues just
because the vendor's website is down.
You might get errors accessing
Windows software updates,
but microsoft.com having an outage is
not going to cause random Windows PCs to
time out the network connections to
other sites like Udacity or YouTube.
So number five is false.
So the correct answers here are the
first, second, and the fourth ones.