the work with justed building and
training a multi-layer convolutional
neural network would have taken hundreds
of lines of code just a few years ago
that's right is deep neural networks
become increasingly important to
everything from self-driving cars the
voice recognition new libraries are
making it much easier to use deep
learning to solve real problems
next up you're going to learn how to
take networks that have already been
trained and fine-tune them to accelerate
your own work
this is called transfer learning
transfer learning is a standard tool in
deep learning it can really reduce your
training time and improve your results
see you soon