A simple way to deal with
the problems of the test and
test and
set lock is to introduce a delay.
Here's a simple implementation
which introduces a delay
every single time a thread
notices that the lock is freed.
So the delay happens after release.
When the thread sees
that the lock is freed,
we'll come out of this while loop.
And then before going back to recheck
what the value of the lock is and
if it's indeed free to try to
execute the atomic operation,
the test and set, the thread will
wait a little bit, will delay.
The rationale of this is yes,
everybody will see that the lock
is free at the same time.
However, with this delay,
not everybody will try to issue
the atomic operation at the same time.
As a result, the contention in the
system will be significantly improved.
When the delay expires,
the delayed threads will try to
recheck the value of the lock.
And it's possible that if somebody
else in the meantime came and
executed the test and set, it's possible
they will see that the lock is busy.
And then they will go in this inner
while loop and continue spinning.
If the lock is free, the delayed thread
will execute the atomic operation.
However with this delay it's
more likely that not all
the threads will try to execute
the atomic operation at the same time.
And also that we're not going to
have these situations where threads
are repeatedly invalidated while they're
attempting to spin on the cached value.
That is because after
the delay in the second check,
a lot of the threads will see that
this lock has become busy already.
And they will not even attempt
to execute the test and and
set instructions.
So, it'll be fewer cases
where the lock is busy and
somebody's attempting to execute
the test and set instruction.
And that was what caused one of
the issues with the contention effects
in the previous examples.
From a latency perspective,
this spinlock is still okay.
Yes, we do have to perform one memory
reference to get the lock first
into the cache, and
then perform the atomic instruction.
But that's similar to what we saw
with the test and test and set.
From a delay perspective, clearly,
this lock will be much worse,
because once the lock is freed, then we
have to delay for some amount of time.
And if there's no contention for
the lock,
then that delay is just waste of time.
Another variant of the delay-based
spinlocks is to introduce a delay after
every single lock reference.
So every time we go through this
while loop, we include a delay.
The main benefit of this is
that it works in non-cache
coherent architectures.
Because basically we're not
going to be spinning constantly.
In every single spin loop,
we will include a delay.
So if we don't have cache coherence and
we have to go to memory, using this
delay will help with the reduction
of contention of the memory network.
The downside of this is clearly that
it will hurt the delay much more.
Because we're basically building up the
delay even when there is no contention
on the network.