Even though the algorithm
we just discussed for
a minimum vertex cover was very simple,
it illustrates some key ideas found
in many approximation schemes.
Consider this figure here,
illustrating the possible sizes
of the minimum set cover.
We have the size of the set
returned by our algorithm here, and
the size of the optimum one here.
And we would like to be
able to find some guarantee
about the relationship between the two.
The trouble, of course,
is that we don't know the optimum value.
Actually, finding the optimum
value is NP complete,
and that's why we're searching for
an approximation algorithm anyway.
We resolve this dilemma
by finding a lower bound
on the size of the optimal cover.
That's the role played by the maximal
matching that the algorithm finds.
And then we find an upper bound
on our approximation then,
in terms of this lower bound.
The cover that we returned has sized
twice that of the maximal matching.
Note that the approximation does not
tell us enough about the optimum value
to allow us to solve the decision
version of the problem.
Does the graph have a vertex
cover of some particular size?
Our algorithm might be twice the optimum
value, as in these two graphs here,
or it might find an exact solution,
as in this case here.
So you can't tell what
situation we're in.
We can't tell where the actual
minimum vertex falls.