You'll also notice an instructor note section next to the
discussion section at the bottom. Sometimes we'll have additional information
there, or a link to another page. You should see
a link there now. Oftentimes this link will go to a
Google spreed sheet with data for you to analyze. That's
right. In this class, you are going to learn how to
use spread sheets. A super practical, and useful skill. We've
found that Google spreadsheets is the best way to share data
with you for free. But to view the spreadsheet, you'll
need a Google account. Pause this video now, and click
the link below in Instructor Notes that says create a
Google account. If you already have one, you could skip this
step. Once you create your Google account, click the link
to view the Google spreadsheet. You'll see a bunch of
words written in various cells. A cell is one of
the rectangles in the table. And each cell has a name.
For example, this is cell c3. This is cell b5. This is cell a1. Once
you open the spreadsheet, write the words in
the following cells to get the hidden message.