[Norvig] I think it's a good time to return to hand_rank,
the most complicated function we'll have to deal with.
We know hand_rank takes a hand as input, but what does it return?
We want it to return a value indicating the ranking of a hand,
but we're not quite sure what that value should be.
It has to be something that's comparable by max,
so, well, why not a number?
There are 9 different types of hands that we know about,
from straight flush at the top to high card at the bottom,
and we can number them from, say, 0 to 8,
with 8 being the highest for the straight flush.
So here's a sketch of a solution.
We know it's going to be important to look at ranks, so let's get them first.
We can extract the ranks with our card_ranks function,
and then we can say first we want to check and see if we have a straight flush.
So if the ranks form a straight and the cards form a flush,
then we can return 8, the highest value.
Otherwise what's next?
Four of a kind.
And the only thing we need in kind is the rank, so I'm going to just pass that in.
If the ranks form 4 of a kind, then return 7.
And we could go on from there.
I go through the cases 1 by 1.
We have straight flush, we have 4 of a kind,
we would next go to full house and then flush and so on.
The question is, would this work?
If we continued to flesh this out and we defined the 9 different cases
to return the numbers from 0 to 8, would that give us a definition of hand_rank
that's a working program?
And I want you to tell me yes, it would work fine in all cases;
no, it would signal an error condition and crash the program;
no, it would get some inputs wrong and some of them right;
or no, it would get all the inputs wrong.
Which do you think is correct?