So as we saw earlier on, you specify
the center point of the circle, and
then its radius in meters.
So here you can say I've set
the .center of my circle.
I just call map.addcircle
a new circle options.
And I set its center to be renton.
And renton of course,
is the latitude and
longitude that we created earlier for
the location of the rank and renton.
I set a radius of 5,000,
which means a 5 kilometer radius
around the rank and renton.
I've set the stroke color,
which is the diameter of the circle will
be drawn in this color, Color.GREEN.
And then I've set using a fill color,
using Color.argb.
And you see I've set the A to be 64,
which means it's going to
be semi transparent.
It's going to be slightly translucent.
So, we can see the color, the 0, 255,
0, which is going to be green, but
it's a partially transparent green.
Now when I run the app, I'll actually
see the circle projected properly,
including taking into account
the tilt and zoom of the camera.
And it will be drawn on
the surface of the earth.
Let's take a look at that.
So here you can see it, I have my
green circle, my semi translucent one.
So as I zoom in,
you'll see that my stroke is green.
You'll see that my circle is
five kilometer radius around
the renton ice rink.
Because I've colored
it with translucency,
we can actually see through
to the map underneath.
And also because my camera
is tilted a little bit,
we can see that it's
slightly oval in shape.
I'm not looking straight down at
90 degrees to make it a circle.
I'm tilted a little bit, because I'm
looking somewhat up from the horizon
direction, towards the Earth,
and this part of Seattle.
So there we can see it.
The circle was added.
Pretty straightforward.
Pretty simple.
Right?
Of course if I rotate my map,
the circle rotates with me.
So it's all properly calculated for
me and all properly drawn
as a five kilometer radius circle
around my home rank and renton.