In the case where the occlusion costs are low,
it is best to assume that those Bs over here correspond as indicated.
That means we have an occlusion cost to pay over here
and an occlusion cost to pay over here.
Our total cost is 20 for 2 occlusions, but we have a perfect match.
As a result, this B moves over here.
However, there is another viable solution when the occlusion costs are large,
because you would pay a total of 200 with the occlusion cost.
If we match pixel one to one like this, then you get two mismatches--
one over here and one over here.
The cost of those in total are 40.
That is still smaller than the 200 occlusion cost we had before.
Therefore the B gets matched to this point over here.
Notice how the different occlusion costs give different results
for the correspondence program in this dynamic programming question.