You can combine basic array algorithms to perform more complicated tasks. For
example, we can calculate the final score, which is the sum of all the scores
except the lowest one. This is related to several of the algorithms that you've
just seen. Let's write a method to drop the lowest score, and I'll give you
some methods that you can use. One removes the score at a particular index. One
finds what the minimum score is and one finds the index of a given score. Skip
to the quiz and code up remove lowest if you're pretty sure you've got this.
I'm going to do a demo on a small data set in case you want a little more info
first. Let's say our set of scores was eight, seven, eight point five, nine
point five, seven, four and ten. We'd also have some zeros left over at the end
of the arrays since it's paritially filled, but current size will tell us not
to go past there, I'd first find the lowest score, it might be 8, but 7 is
better, it's not 8.5 or 9.5, there is 7 again, okay 4 is better not 10, okay so
4 was the lowest we say, now, I want to find the index of that element. So,
I'll go through again this time looking for the number four and remembering the
index. And it looks like I found it, the index I want, is five, now, I remove
the fifth element, which will move ten down and I'll need to decrease current
size. You won't actually have to implement remove. But now you can see why it
might be important when you're calculating the sum, to only look at the items
that you know are in the array. Because this ten will show up in two places
now. And you wouldn't want to add 10 to the sum twice. If you already have
methods to remove, and to find a minimum element and to find a location of a
given element, how would you code remove lowest?