Our next quiz question is about
the right to be forgotten.
So last year,
the European Court of Justice ruled that
EU citizens have the right to be
forgotten in the Internet world.
I think the court ruled that Google
must not return links to information
that can be shown to be inaccurate,
inadequate, irrelevant, or excessive.
This kind of information about me,
I should have the right
that it be forgotten in the Internet
world, so people can't get to it.
The question is,
the two examples that we have here,
which one of the following is
an example of kind of information that
Google decided not to
return as a search result?
Okay, because of this ruling
that we're talking about.
Remember, this information should not be
returned if it's inaccurate, inadequate,
irrelevant, or excessive.
If it meets these criteria,
then Google shouldn't return it.