So in the first of the series
of three lectures by Aaron,
he talks about extrinsic
camera calibration.
In this one,
basically, the goal is if you take
a series of pictures of an environment,
with a camera like this, we want to be
able to figure out, by those pictures,
what is actually the word model with
respect to where the pictures are.
That is more of understanding where
this camera is in the real world,
with respect to anything
else in the environment.
Again, remember when we talked about
photosynth we talked about the whole
concept of figuring out pictures
as they relate to each other.
What this process of camera calibration,
especially the extremes of calibration,
is aimed at locating the camera
in the 3-D world and
giving the position and
all the degrees of freedom of it.
You'll be building on all the concepts
of homogenous coordinates and
the transformations that
we have looked at, and
actually will use some
of the similar notation.
Be warned, some of the notation that
Aaron uses is slightly different.
Pay attention to the concepts
in these lectures and
that's where the foundation
of this approach comes in.