Third module, we're actually going to look inside the camera.
We will look at the basic foundations of a camera using a pinhole
camera concept.
We will learn more about the importance of optics, how does and you know,
various types of lenses, what kind of a role they play in photography.
And what computation has to do with them.
And also the basics of how does a camera work.
We learn more about sensors within a camera, again, these are the represent,
these are the systems that will take the information that a camera has and
converts them to digital information that we want to do some things with.
And in this one, we learn about concepts of epsilon photography and
also a fun experiment that you will do is try to build your own pin hole or
a camera obscura.