Okay, let's summarize our
overall tracking pipeline.
In each frame of the video,
you will run a search for
vehicles using a sliding
window technique.
Wherever your classifier
returns a positive detection,
you'll record the position of the window
in which the detection was made.
In some cases you might detect the same
vehicle in overlapping windows or
at different scales In the case of
overlapping detections you're going to
assign the position of the detection to
the centroid of the overlapping windows.
We also have false positives
which you'll filter out
by determining which detections
appear in one frame but not the next.
Once you have a high confidence
detection you can record how it's
centroid is moving
from frame to frame and
you eventually estimate where it will
appear in each subsequent frame.