In the last video, I briefly
mentioned that a constructor is
defined within the class, and it's used
to actually create the object instances.
So, we call the TextView constructor
to create this instance,
and we call it again to create
another instance, and so on.
Let's look at the code for
how to actually call a constructor.
Do you remember how we created a new
integer variable named quantity and
we set it to have
an initial value of two?
Creating a new object and
storing it inside a variable is
going to follow a similar format.
It'll look something like this.
Instead of the int data type though,
we have an object data type.
The object data type is whatever
we call the class name.
In this case, it's TextView.
It can be anything as long as it follows
the conventions for variable names.
So, we just call it priceTextView.
Then we set it equal to new object.
But we can break down this
right hand side further.
The right hand side follows the format
of new followed by the object data type,
which is TextView in this case.
This is calling the constructor
defined in a TextView class so
we have parentheses with the input
arguments to the constructor.
So, if the constructor
requires a context object,
then we need to pass a context here.
Remember that the context object helps
you access application resources and
other things about
the application environment.
So, altogether this is
creating a new TextView object
by calling the constructor and
then it's storing this new object
inside a variable called priceTextView.
And this variable can only
hold a single TextView object
as defined by its data type.
Here's another example of
creating an ImageView object and
storing it inside a variable.
The data type is ImageView,
the variable name is coffeeImageView.
And then we have the assignment
operator followed by new ImageView.
This is spelled the same exact
way as the object data type here.
Since we're calling the constructor and
we have to pass in any inputs,
we have parentheses and
then we put the inputs in there.
Here's a third example that
creates a button object and
stores it in this variable.
The date type is Button,
the variable name is submitOrderButton,
and then we say,
new Button to call the constructor.
You can even define your
own object data types.
Say, for example, I created
a class definition for CatView.
Then I could use this line
to create a new CatView.
In this case, the constructor
requires an input string for
the name of the cat so that's why
I put Tiger in parentheses and
pass that in to the CatView constructor.
To determine what to pass as
input to these constructors you
have to look at either the class
Javadoc file or the class source file.
All these cases use the word
new to create a new object.
If we go back to the Java keyword list,
then indeed we do find that
the word new is in that list.
Sometimes when you're
looking at the documentation,
it may advise you to use a factory
method to create an object.
That is instead of a constructor.
Here's an example.
To create a new MediaPlayer,
the documentation advises you to
use the method MediaPlayer.create.
And this returns a MediaPlayer object
that can be stored inside this variable.
It follows the format of object
data type, the MediaPlayer with
a capital m dot and the factory method
name, which is create in this case.
Then you pass in the input arguments
to initialize that media player.
Here's another example of
how to create a Toast.
A toast is a message that pops
up temporarily in your app and
then disappears.
So the code starts with Toast
with a capital T because
this is the object data type.
And then we have a dot and then makeText
which is the factory method name.
And then we pass the input
arguments to create this Toast.
To know what the factory method name
is and what the input arguments are,
you have to check the documentation for
the Toast class.
In general, in order to know whether
you should create an object using
a constructor or with a factory method,
you can just Google search for
how to create that object.
Using a constructor is the most
common way to create a new object.
It's less common that you would need to
use a factory method, but to know for
sure which one you should use,
you can just Google search for
how to create that object.
Here's a chance to practice
with creating objects.
In each of these lines of code,
there's an error.
Figure out what the error is and
then write the correct line
of code in these boxes below.