Here's what our toy app looks like,
there's this giant glass which when
clicked should record a record a drink.
But right now it does nothing
except this toast message.
This app is also suppose to be sending
notifications to drink every 15 minutes.
But that's not implemented yet either.
Down here is where should
display account for
how many times you've
been notified to drink.
You'll be adding all of
the functionalities about this lesson.
The code is pretty straight forward.
There are two classes,
Main Activity and Preference Utilities.
Let's take a look at
Main Activity first.
The MainActivities onCreate method said
something in a shared count values and
registers the
OnSharedPreferenceChangeListener.
This listener is then unregistered
in the onDestroy method.
This is important because for
our app, shared preferences is where
the two major pieces of data are stored.
How many drinks the user has taken and
how many times the user has
been notified to drink?
Whenever the value of those
shared preferences change,
the listener calls
the appropriate update method.
Either update order count or
update charging reminder count.
Both of those methods grab
the appropriate value from shared
preferences and
then modify the text shown on screen.
Notice that
the updateChargingReminderCount method
uses the pluralization feature
to generate the string.
I've linked some information
about this in the notes below.
The final method is incrementWater.
This is called when the giant
water glass is pressed.
Currently, it just shows
this Toast message.
The other class we have is this
PreferenceUtilities class.
It's simply full of static utility
methods meant for updating and
getting the water and
reminder count from Shared Preferences.
Now that you know a little
bit more about the code,
check it out yourself and
answer the questions.