In order to write messages for the app
to the database we'll first need to add
the firebase realtime database
dependency to our project.
So here I am on the Add Firebase to
Your Android Project Guide on firebase's
website and
I've linked this in your notes.
If you scroll down you can find
the list of available libraries for
the different firebase services and
right here next to realtime database is
the library that I need for
the database.
These library version numbers change,
so it's good to get it from this site.
I'm going to go ahead and copy this, and
I'm going to add it here
to our dependency block.
Android Studio is smart enough to know
that we just changed the gradle file,
and so we'll need to re-sync.
So I'm going to Click Sync Now.
Okay, and just like that,
the new dependency is added.
So now I'm going to go over to our
Java files and open up MainActivity.
To be able to start using the database,
we'll need to use two classes for
the FirebaseDatabase API.
I'm going to go ahead and
add instance variables for both.
This first object is a fire
based database object.
This is the entry point for
our app to access the database.
Next, we have a database
reference object and
this object is called
mMessagesDatabaseReference.
A database reference object is a class
that references a specific part of
the database.
So, for example, this database reference
here is actually just going to be
referencing the messages
portion of the database.
Let's go ahead and set that up below.
In onCreate I'm going to go ahead and
instantiate these two objects.
We'll go ahead and
use FirebaseDatabase.getInstance
to get a instance of the class.
This again is just the main
access point for our database.
Then using this access point,
we're going to get a reference to
a specific part of the database.
This part of the code here is getting
me a reference to the root node.
And then here, I'm specifically saying
that I'm interested in the messages
portion of the database.