We finished implementing these
steps in our diagram that work with
the Android Intent
system to pick an image.
Let's now code this
portion of the flow chart.
That goes to the Firebase Storage and
saves an image to the cloud.
To start I'll find the Gradle dependency
for Firebase Storage, copy it.
And in this dependencies block
in my build.gradle file I'll add
the dependency.
And of course, sync.
With that finished, let's go ahead and
head over to our main activity file.
As with any Firebase service,
you're going to need an instance
to be able to use it.
I'll create an instance variable
at the top of MainActivity for
the Firebase storage component.
And I'll initialize it
down here in onCreate.
Like with the database
we're also going to have
something called a storage
reference object.
I'll make an instance variable for
it up here.
And I'll initialize it down here.
This Firebase storage reference has
been initialized to a specific location.
Much in the same way that the message's
database reference was set to
the location messages.
In this case, I'm setting it
to the location chat_photos.
Okay, so now that we have our reference,
let's do something with the photo
result from our image picker.
To do that, we're going to need to
scroll down to onActivityResult.
And we'll add another case for
handling the PHOTO_PICKER result.
When we handle the intent,
the chosen photo will come in
as a Uri from data.getData.
So I'll take that Uri and
put it in the variable selectedImageUri.
Okay, now I'm going to make
a reference to the specific photo.
Let me explain this line here.
So we're taking our
reference to ChatPhotos, and
then we're making a child.
Which will be named after the last
part of the path segment for the URI.
So, for example, if we have a URI
like content://local_images/foo/4.
Then the file name that we're saving
our stored image at would be 4.
Because it's the last part
of the path segment here.
At this point we've got
a reference location for
the file that we're going to save.
And we've got the URI of that
image that we're going to save.
We still need to actually do the saving
of the file to Firebase Storage.
But instead of me telling you
exactly what to write in the code
I think you're ready to do it in a quiz.