To explain what's happening, let's consider a sequence of different situations.
The first case we'll look at, both the user-level signal mask and
the kernel-level signal mask had the signal enabled.
Let's say this is the user-level thread that's currently actually executing on
top of this kernel-level thread.
Now when the signal occurs, no problem.
The kernel sees that the signal is enabled, so it will interrupt the currently
running user-level thread that's running on top of this kernel-level thread.
And there's absolutely no problem because that user-level thread
had the signal enabled as well, so the processing will be safe.