When a table invokes the cell for
row at index path method, it passes
the control object and index path.
An index path is a struct
that holds the row number.
In order to populate our table cells,
there are a few steps we need
to perform in this method.
The first step is to dequeue
a reusable cell from the table.
Using the correct reuse identifier.
The second step is to find the model
object that corresponds to the row in
question.
The third step is to set the images and
labels in the cell using
the data from the model object.
And last but not least, return the cell.
For the favorite things app,
we'll use a standard table of U cell.
It comes with the UI label
property named text label.
And our reuse identifier
will be FavoriteThingCell.
Here are three different implementations
of cell for row at index path.
Which of these three performs all four
of the steps previously outlined?
To try out the different methods,
check out the branch in
the instructor's notes.