Using the method set persistence
enable should the trick.
You can put in the application class for
shopping list plus plus
to ensure that it gets called
as soon as the app starts.
You can look at the solution code in the
instructor notes but I just wanted to
take a second to show you what
the app actually looks like now.
Before we set persistence
enabled as J.P.
showed you, when you navigated
between different screens,
the listener would be destroyed,
and with it the data.
Now that we have separate
systems enabled,
let's see what happens going to
go into these two shopping lists.
They're the same shopping list, and
they're currently sync
up because I'm online.
Now let's go offline with this phone,
and will add an item.
And then we'll kind of
navigate around a bit.
As you can see,
even though I navigated away and back,
and the listener was destroyed,
this item is still here.
And I can navigate around
the app a little bit more.
Create another shopping list.
Go take a look at that.
All this stuff while offline and
then when I go online again
we can see that it syncs up.
Pretty sweet.