Consider the problem of searching
in an ordered collection.
Here's a list of several classical
data structures from CS 101,
that you might use to store
the collection, besides a sorted array.
An ordered doubly-linked list,
a binary search tree,
a red-black tree,
a skip list, and a B-tree.
Note that the sorted array A is what you
get if you do an in order traversal of
a binary search tree, and then throw
out the left and right pointers.
Here's my question for you.
Which of these classical
data structures,
if any, attains the I/O lower bound?
The I/O lower bound for search,
you will recall, is log n over log l or
log base l of n.
Note that this quiz is
actually a lazy quiz.
By that I'm referring to myself,
not you.
Hey, sorry I need my beauty rest.
By lazy, I mean that after you submit
your answer, I will tell you my answer
and I'll explain part of it,
but I won't fully explain it.
To do that would be quite involved as
I'd have to explain what each one of
these things is.
That takes all the fun out of you
thinking about it on your own.