Now that we've been
learning a few tricks,
let's reexamine the challenge question.
We'll use our constraint hypergraph for
the problem, where the top square
represents the global constraint that
all the letters have to be different.
In addition, we know that O plus O
has to be equal to r + 10 times X1,
where X1 represents the carry to
the tens place, and can be 0 or 1.
Similarly, X1 + W + W has
to equal U + 10 times X2,
where X2 represents the carry
to the hundreds place.
Also, X2 + T + T has got
to equal O + 10 times X3,
where X3 is the carry
to the thousands place.
And F has to equal X3.
We also know that F cannot be 0,
because the problem does
not allow leading zeroes.
So now we're going to use the strategy
we learned of back tracking with forward
checking in the MRV and
least constraining value heuristics.
There are a couple of ways
to follow this procedure,
and we'll show one here for
illustration purposes.
First, let's choose the X3 variable,
if the mean is 0 and 1.
Choose the value 1 for X3.
We can't choose 0.
It wouldn't survive forward checking,
because it would force F to be 0, and
the leading digit of
the sum must be non-zero.
Choose F because it has
only one remaining value.
Choose the value 1 for F.
Now, X2 and X1 are tied for
minimum remaining values at 2.
Let's choose X2.
Either value survives forward checking.
Let's choose 0 for X2.
Now X1 has the minimum remaining values.
Again, arbitrarily choose 0 for
the value X1.
The variable O must be an even number,
because it is a sum
of T + T less than 5 because
O + O equals R + 10 times 0.
That makes it most constrained.
Arbitrarily chose 4 as the value for O.
Now R has only one remaining value.
Chose the value 8 for R.
T now has only one remaining value.
Choose the value 7 for T.
U must be an even number less than 9,
choose U.
The only value for
U that survives forward checking is 6.
The only variable left is W.
The only value left for W is 3.
This is the solution.
This puzzle's rather easy
because it is underconstrained.
It is not surprising that we arrive
at a solution with no backtracking,
given that we are allowed
to use forward checking.
We could've used iterative
improvement for this problem, and
it probably would have converged
quickly as it's underconstrained.
But I find it difficult to keep all
those numbers and letters in my head.