Here's a data analyst diagram we
will use to help orient ourselves.
This will help us better understand
where we are and where we'd like to go.
First, let's pretend we
were trying to predict
which items will sell the most
depending on what the weather is like.
We'll also say we have a lot of data
about the sales patterns of our
products.
So for this example,
where are we on this chart?
We know we have a business problem where
we're trying to predict an outcome.
That rules out needing
to do any data analysis.
What we also know is we have lots of
data, so we can call it data rich.
Now we are divided between two sections,
numeric and classification.
We're working with weather, so
we need to decide if that is
a numeric or non-numeric variable.
Since we need to categorize
the weather by sun, rain, or
anything else, this makes it a category,
which is non-numeric.
This puts us on the classification path.
And in this course we'll learn what is
going on within this classification
section.
To do this, we divided
the lesson into four sections.
In the first section,
we're going to learn what this
whole classification thing means.
We're also going to start
to prepare data for
the various types of models
taught throughout the course.
In the second section,
we're going to compare binary models
against each other to determine
which model to use for prediction.
We are also going to be building
out this prediction model.
In the third section, we're going to do
exactly the same thing as in the second
section, but in the context of
predicting non-binary data.
And finally, we're going to give you
a classification business problem.
Here we'll work with some data and
let you loose using the techniques
you've learn throughout this course to
present and explain the model you chose.
We've got a lot of work to do,
so let's begin.