So here you can see I'm getting
the list of geofences and
I'm going to call it
triggeringGeoFences.
And I get this by calling
the getTriggeringGeoFences method on my
geofencing event.
So no matter how many geofences have
been triggered, be it one, be it many,
they will return to this
list of geofences for me.
Now the getGeoFenceTransitionDetails
helper function.
We'll turn all of these into a string.
So, I just say string,
geofenceTransitionDetails equals
getGeofenceTransitionDetails, and
I pass at this,
I pass at my geofenceTransition, and
I pass at my triggeringGeofences.
Let's take a look at this function.
Here's the getGeofenceTransitionDetails.
And you can see it takes the context and
it takes the geofenceTransition,
which was just an integer.
And it takes a list of geofences,
which are my triggeringGeofences.
So first of all I'm going to
get the transition string for
my actual transition.
And I'm just going to call that
string geofenceTransitionString.
And then I'm going to iterate
through each of my geofences,
and get a string out of them.
Load that string into an array list and
then use TextUtils.join on that
array list to join all of those strings
together and to concatenate them.
There are a number of ways
that you could do this, but
ultimately what you're
interested in is this.
The geofence.getRequestId.
This gives you the ID of the geofence
that triggered the event and
it's up to you how you would
handle that ID, in this case.
Like I said, I'm just concatenating
them all together, so,
if there were a number of
different geofences triggered,
I would get their IDs all listed in
this single notification, saying, for
example, Lawrence has
entered Mountain View.
Lawrence has entered entered
the Audacity Studios.
Lawrence has entered Studio X.
That type of thing all in a single
notification instead of multiple
notifications.
And then, as a result, I just return
my geofenceTransitionString and
the list of IDs that came.
So it would be entered plus the list or
exited plus the list.
That type of thing.
So this helper function
achieves all of that for you.