So the answer is yes,
but maybe, probably yes.
This code uses UI kit
in a background queue.
Will this make the code
crash every single time?
No, and that's the bizarre
beauty of concurrent bugs.
They are impossible to reproduce.
If you run this code ten times,
it will likely crash a few times, but
not always.
Make sure you always use UI
kit code in the main queu, or
eventually you will have to face the
toughest bugs ever, concurrency bugs.
How would you get the offending line
of code to run in the main queu?
We'll see how to do
this in the sample app.
But in the meantime,
try to do it yourself.
Remember Inception, the movie,
dreams within dreams.