Since we talking about health
information, remember the BLP model was
talked about in the context of military
or intelligence setting where we have.
We're going to see that
confidentially is the reason for
it, but information that's
classified and things like that.
So this is an for the health care
environment that we're talking about.
For health care, we actually have HIPAA,
that's the regulation.
And HIPAA is
the Health Insurance Portability and
Accountability Act,
I think goes back to the mid-90s
when this was put in place to
protect patient privacy and so on.
This HIPAA requirement
is why hospitals must
have these policies for controlling
access to patient records and those
policies are often mandatory access
control nature that we're talking about.
Just because someone did data
entry about a patient record,
of course they create that file but
they don't have the discretion to decide
now who all they can share it with.
It's governed by the hospital's
policy on how patient
records should be accessed.
So that's what makes it mandatory.
So the answer here would be
HIPAA because we're talking
about patient records in
the hospital setting.