Another way to search is called
backwards or regression search,
in which we start at the goal.
So we take the description
of the goal state,
C1 is at JFK and C2 is at SFO.
So that's the goal state.
And notice that that's
the complete goal state.
It's not that I left out all
the other facts about the state.
Is that, that's all that's known
about this state is that these two
propositions are true and
all the others can be anything you want.
And now we can start
searching backwards.
We can say,
what actions would lead to that state?
Now, remember in problem solving we did
have that option of searching backwards.
If there was a single goal state,
we could say, what other arcs
are coming into that goal state?
But here, this goal state doesn't
represent a single state,
it represents a whole family of states.
So with different values for
all the other variables.
And so, we can't just look at that.
But what we can do,
is to look at the definition of possible
actions that will result in this goal.
So let's look at it one at a time.
Let's first look at what actions
could result at C1, JFK.
Well, we look at our action schema,
and there's only one
action schema that adds an at, and
that would be the unload schema.
So unload of CPA adds CA, and so
what we will know is if
we want to achieve this,
then we would have to do an unload where
the C variable would have to be C1.
The P variable is still unknown,
it could be any plane.
And the A variable has to be JFK.
So, notice what we done here, we have
this representation in terms of logical
formula that allows us to specify
a goal as a set of many world states.
And we can also use that same
representation to represent
an arrow here, not as a single action,
but as a set of possible actions.
So this is representing
all possible actions for
any plane P of unloading
cargo at the destination.
And then we can regress this
state over this operator,
and now we have another
representation of this state here.
But just as this state was uncertain,
not all the variables were known,
this state, too, will be uncertain.
For example, we won't know anything
about what plane P is involved.
And now, we continue searching backwards
until we get to a state where enough of
the variables are filled in, and where
we match against the initial state.
And then, we have our solution,
we found it going backwards, but
we can apply the solution
going forwards.