The question is, what do you do about these effects?
And the answer is you spend money.
What I'm showing you here, and
I'm assuming I can show this to you because you can just go and get it, and
it comes directly from the literature, is a beautiful lens, a Nikon 24-70 zoom.
Now you know that I don't own Canon equipment.
Well, actually I own some Canon.
I own some equipment of every brand out there.
Well, any brand that has a lawyer.
I own some of your equipment, okay.
Here's showing you the elements, that are in this zoom lens.
And you'll notice it's not just one thin lens that's moved in and out.
It's made up of 1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12,13,14,15 pieces
of glass that are moved in different ways depending upon whether you're
changing the zoom length or you're changing the, the distance in focus.
These days it's a, it's a combination of computer design,
plus knowledge on the parts of optic engineers about how to do this.
And what this does is, it helps remove vign,
reduce vignetting, chromatic aberration, geometric distortion and
other kinds of perturbations to a perfect pinhole image that we like to see.