So, tell us what you've got.
>> So I just drew a box so
I can say we're talking about
the mode state machine.
And within the mode there are four
possible states we can be in.
We can be in on, off, music, or alarm.
And it seems that the transitions
between those states kind of follow
this order because the switch itself
can't jump all the way from, for
instance, alarm, back to on.
It's not circular.
It just goes kind of back and forth.
So, we go on to off, off to music,
music to alarm, and vice versa, and
go backwards.
>> Straight forward.
I hope all of you were able to
get that particular solution.
Notice that this machine.
That is, the machine that
describes the mode switch,
can execute concurrently
with the clock time display.
So, that these are concurrently
executing machines.
You can see the time on the clock at
the same time you're moving that switch.
Notice, also, that this kind of
sequential state machine, going back and
forth between these four states,
is essentially the same
thing that we would use to model
the bandswitch between AM and FM.
That's in two states and
we can go back and forth.
So, we'll just go ahead and plunk that
one into our composite machine now.