Get more comfortable with
the LLDB command line.
You're going to have to dive
right into the documentation and
just start playing with things yourself.
In the instructions notes I've
linked to the LLDB documentation.
And I want you to use it to answer
the following questions for the so
many bugs app.
So what we want to know is, what LLDB
command will set a break point on
line 26 of the BugFactory.swift file?
We want to know what command
will set a breakpoint on
all Swift methods whose
selector is viewDidLoad.
And if you don't know what a selector
is, a selector is another word for the.
So viewDidLoad, that'll correspond
to say the viewDidLoad and
UI view controller, the base class,
but it'll also refer to
the viewDidLoad that we've implemented
in the break point bug view controller,
or any sub classes of
UI view controller.
Next, what command will list all the
breakpoints that are currently set for
application, and what command will
show the stack trace for all threads?
So I want you to
experiment in X code and
write your answers in the boxes
next to each of these questions.
Note, for all of my answers I'm using
the non abbreviated commands and
their options, so your answers may not
exactly match mine and that's okay.
The most important thing here is
that we get the same outcomes, and
you get practice using the command
line and the documentation for it.
So go ahead and attempt the problems and
then check to see if your answers
behave the same way as mine.