So we've got stuff going
into the database now, but
stockpiling these isn't really useful.
We need to show them.
We want to get posts that
are in the database and
display them before connecting to
the web socket that gets us newer posts.
And lucky you, I think you're going to
take it from here because we have
an incoming call from Mike.
Think you're up to this one?
>> Definitely.
You should now have
stuff in the database.
But we're going to get it on screen.
Some of the methods have
been stubbed out for you, so
you want to check out that code.
To do that, run git reset --hard to
remove any local changes you have.
Then git checkout task-show-stored
to get the stubbed methods.
Refresh the wittr page,
this should populate the database with
posts which you can verify in dev tools.
Once you've got post in the database,
head over to public/JS/main/
index controller.js.
Previously, we were calling
_opensocket in the constructor.
But now we're calling
_showCachedMessages,
then opening the socket.
_ShowCachedMessages isn't
fully implemented yet.
That's your job.
Get the messages out of the database and
pass them to this method.
Index controller._postview.add post.
Make sure they're in date descending
order which may not be the order
they come out of the database.
Once you've made changes to your code,
you need to bump the cached version
number in the service worker so
the changes are picked up.
Also if your database gets into
a bad state, go into dev tools and
run indexDB.deletedatabase and
pass the parameter witter.
This will remove the database and
let you start afresh.
If everything's working,
you should see posts being displayed
even when you load the page offline.
To double check everything is working,
head to the settings page and
type IDB-show into the test field and
press enter.