Let's review some projects that
mobile developers might work on.
Wagoon Pool is a simple app that
calculates sharing costs for carpooling.
It allows me to put in my distance in
miles among other things to calculate
how much each person owes for gas.
This app also adjusts to
different screen sizes.
Wagoon Pool includes which
elements of mobile programming?
Does Wagoon Pool app use
responsive design principles
in order to adapt to
different screen sizes?
Does the app have a clean and
intuitive user interface?
Does the app connect with an external
server to access data and
display it to the user, or
does it utilize mobile device hardware
such as cameras or microphones?
Check all the boxes that apply.