One of the biggest distinguishing
features of VR from
other forms of media, is that we're able
to know exactly where a user is looking
at any given point in time,
by tracking their head rotation.
So, let's implement that.
This will be our first taste
of programming in Unity but
we'll walk through everything slowly and
honestly there's not that much to it.
So first up,
we need to create a C# script and
we do that like any other game object.
Let's create it in our scripts
folder by going to Create C#
script and let's call it head rotation.
Double-click on the file and
it should open up into model develop,
which is Unity's default code editor.
By default Unity creates a C# class
with two methods, Start and Update.
Start is called when the script
is first instantiated.
Update is called every frame
we want to create an image.
We'll use these two
methods to access the gyro
which is the sensor in out phone
that tells us it's rotation.
However, for
us to use the gyro we must enable it.
We'll do this in the Start method by
setting input.gyro.enabled to true.
Awesome.
Now that we have it enabled,
we need to get data from it every frame.
To do that, we go to the update
method and we type in quaternion
at equals input.gyro.attitude.
This line gets the attitude,
which is the rotation of the device,
from the gyro and
saves that in a variable called apps.
Which is a quaternion.
If you want to learn
more about quaternions,
you can check out our
additional resources, but for
our purposes it's just a means
to store rotation data.
Unfortunately, the role rotation data
we receive from the sensor is not
oriented with our head.
So we need to rotate the rotation so
that it matches our head movements.
We do this with
the following line of code.
This line flips our gyrotation
about the Z-axis and
then rotates by 90 degrees
around the X-axis.
Don't worry if that seems confusing.
But know that we need this line
to orient our sensor's data
with the head rotation.
Lastly, we need to assign
a rotation to our camera,
which we can do easily
with this line of code.
And that will pretty much do it.
We now have a script that captures
our head rotation and applies it.
All we have left to do is take our head
rotation and apply it to our camera.
Let's do some quick housekeeping by
changing the name of our camera system
to main and
then dragging our camera into position.
You can task this out by deploying
our project to your phone