To solve this I first start a function
to remove any data points corresponding
to students who canceled
during the free trial.
Next I called this function on
each of the three tables and
saved the results in new variables.
I also took a look at the length of
these variables to see how much data had
been removed.
Next, I started off the variable
paid_engagement_in_first_week
as the empty list.
Then I looped over each record
in the engagement table and
saved the student's account
key in this variable.
I also looked up the student's join
date by using the dictionary I
created earlier.
And I saved the data of the engagement
record into this variable.
Next, I checked whether the two dates
were within one week of each other.
And if so, I appended this record to the
variable paid_engagement_in_first_week.
Finally, I printed out how many records
there were, and you can see that about
21,000 of the engagement records
come from the students' first week.