Whew, that was a tough lesson.
Content providers are one of the more
challenging topics in Android,
so kudos to you for
getting through that.
In this lesson, we modified the app,
so we added a content provider.
Now the UI code doesn't talk
directly to the database.
Instead it called into the provider and
then the provider communicates
with the database.
Since all communication has to
happen through the provider,
now we have a place to put
our data validation logic.
We can check if there is bad data and
reject it and
throw an exception instead of
allowing it to pass through.
There are also a lot of other
advantages to content providers,
such as they work well with other
framework classes provided by Android.
And we're going to get to see a little
more of that in the next lesson.