So let's look at our app now when
we've implemented interstitial ads.
So if we click on Interstitial Ad here,
you can see that we have two buttons
here now, Load Interstitial,
Interstitial Not Ready, and
Interstitial Not Ready is disabled.
Once I click on Load Interstitial,
the text of this button should change,
we should get an onAdLoaded() callback.
And once the interstitial is loaded,
the text of this button should change to
Show Interstitial, and it should
be enabled, so let's try that out.
So I click Load Interstitial here,
title changes, onAdLoaded(),
is called,
Show Interstitial is now enabled.
All right, so that works.
Now if I press Show Interstitial,
you can see onAdOpened() is called and
we can see our interstitial ad.
And if I click on it,
onAdLeftApplication(), and
we get into the details
of the interstitial.
Can go back, close the interstitial,
the ad is closed, and now you see
we're back to the original state.
So what if I disable
network connectivity here?
So now we're in flight mode and
pressing Load Interstitial should fail.
So I press Load Interstitial,
you see onAdFailedToLoad, so
this is the callback with the reason for
the error.
And you can also see that we've
displayed the error reason here and
the button is disabled.
All right, so everything works.