Can you give me a broad overview
of how core data works.
>> Sure, yeah, I'll try.
So I like to think of
core data as kind of like
a way to represent an object diagram
that's backed by a database.
I don't really say it's like a database.
I don't think that's like
an accurate description but,
with Core Data you can model objects and
relationships between those objects and
then those will be persisted, if you
use the API correctly, to a data store.
Which can be a SQL like database or
it could be like an XML file or
is there are varying other types of
data sources that you could use.
>> And what's a managed object?
A manage object or manage object context
is I believe the object that Apple
describes as kind of being the sandbox
where you can make changes and
updates to objects if you
want to be persisted and
then save those changes but, everything
is like this Sandbox mode until you
actually explicitly tell the Core Data
to save a particular object.
>> Okay.
And when you would use Core Data instead
of using some other system
mechanism such as MS User default?
Or just writing to
a file in your Sandbox.
>> I would use Core Data in cases where
what you're trying to persist isn't just
simple like bowls and
strings and integers.
Things that would work well for
maybe small settings.
But something that's
more larger in scope,
that's kind of the beefy data
model in an application.
Ones that are interconnected like
objects that are connected can be
persisted quite quickly with Core Data.
So things that are larger
than basic data types.
>> Okay, and are there any issues
that you should keep in mind with
the current quarter day
when using Core Data?
>> Yeah, there's issues kind of like
the same issues you'd see in traditional
databases where if you're trying to
write to a particular object, and
the object's being written to in
something some other location at
the same time,
there could be a merge conflict.
Now, you can overwrite and tell
Core Data how to merge an object that's
being written to from
two different places.
But that's an issue and
there's also issues with threading,
so if you're updating an object
on a background thread, and
it's trying to update an object
while on the main thread,
you're trying to update
that same object.
That can be an issue.
>> Okay.
Sounds good.