Up ahead in this course, you'll be using
a Python language feature that you might
not have seen much of before.
This feature is called
the decorator syntax.
If you're already comfortable with
decorators, feel free to skip ahead.
A decorator is way of
modifying a function or
class definition by wrapping
it with another function.
A decorator can modify how
the decorated code works or
even hook it up to other
pieces of code entirely.
For instance, to register a class
as being part of an API or
to connect a function
up with a framework.
Here's what a decorator call looks like.
You will always appear on the line
before a def or class block.
That is before a function or
a class definition and
it will always start with an at sign.
And some decorators have arguments
of their own while others don't.
The decorator syntax is a shortcut for
calling a function that wraps
the function or
class that's being decorated.
Right after the function somefunc is
defined, Python will call the function
special to wrap that function
up with extra behavior.
Hey, how about you try it out?
Up ahead, you'll see a piece of code
that you can add a decorator to,
then you can tab over and take a look at
the source code of the decorator itself.