Now that we've learned
a bit about audio,
why don't we spice things up a bit?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, let's use a bunch of sounds
in a scene, rather than just the one.
&gt;&gt; Well we could do that, but
it might sound very discoherent.
&gt;&gt; No, we're not going to
play them all at once.
We can organize it, and
then pick out sounds to play so
that it gives it a lot more variety.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, we could create
a collection of our sound clips and
then just pick a random one from that.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, you mean using an array.
&gt;&gt; Exactly, so an array is basically a
collection of variables that we can then
put into this list and
reference them by a specific number.
&gt;&gt; Right, first you say,
how big is the array?
Then you put your stuff in it, and
then you can access any one of them with
an integer, right,
like sound three or sound five.
&gt;&gt; Exactly, so why don't we do that?
Let's build up our array and
then pick a random value that will
act as the sound clip we play.
&gt;&gt; Sounds fun, let's do it.