Earlier we talked about how the cloud
of the internet is held together by
routers that forward packets from
their source to their destination.
Each forward from one machine
to another is called a hop.
And you can see all of the hops
involved in getting your traffic
from you to a distant server
by using a traceroute tool.
Now the most common traceroute tool
is called just that, traceroute.
You can give it a host name or an IP
address and it will display the route
all the IP addresses of all the routers
that it took for traffic to get there.
There are more advanced traceroute
tools such as MTR which will repeatedly
trace and can sometimes show you
different routes the traffic may take.
Try it out yourself,
use traceroute to list the hops
between your Linux host and
some other host such as a website.
What side did you choose, and
how many hops did it take for
traffic to reach that site?