Hi, and welcome to the course on
programming VR inside of Unity.
We're going to be learning some
really cool ways to write scripts and
do some really cool VR.
You're going to be building a world that
is based on an island scene created by
this gentleman right here.
This is Chris Burke.
And Chris, why don't you tell
them a little bit about yourself?
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Matt.
I'm Chris.
I've got seven years experience
in the video game industry across
all disciplines.
And in the last two years, I've been
focusing on creating virtual reality.
I have a specialty in
computer graphics and
a particular focus on
procedural algorithms for
generating natural landscapes and
realistic life-like simulations.
We're going to be working on some
really cool stuff in this lesson,
some simple things for
those of you who are new to programming
to get you started off
with a functional VR app.
And some more interesting things for
those of you who are a little more
experienced, like a flocking algorithm,
which is actually what underlies
a lot of data science.
And a procedural OceanShare
that's on a GPU, so
you get your feet wet with
a little shader programming.
I'm really excited.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it sounds awesome.
So, before we dive in,
I just want to qualify one thing.
If you've already programmed before,
you can skip the first two lessons and
just jump right into lesson three, where
we talk about VR specific programming,
but with that, let's get started.