So, why on earth would we ever want to blur an image?
There are generally 2 reasons why you might want to do this.
One is for down-sampling.
If you have an image of super high resolution,
maybe 5,000 x 5,000 pixels,
and you'd like to go to a web image of much smaller resolution,
it's better to blur by Gaussian before down-sampling
then picking each nth pixel.
And the reason is called aliasing.
If you pick each nth pixel without blurring,
you sometimes get very, very funny effects
because each nth pixel might by chance
correspond to something that's somewhat irregular.
For example, if you have a checkerboard and you pick each nth pixel,
you might only end up with black pixels.
The second reason is called noise reduction.
In noise reduction, you respond to pixel noise
that might otherwise make it hard to compute things like image gradients.
If you blur the image first,
you get a smoother result that isn't quite as pronounced
but has much less noise in the image.
Here's the original gradient magnitude image to find edges,
and here's the same applied to the blurred image.
And you can see the original one is much more succinct,
but also it's more subject to noise.
Take the area over here, which has lots of image noise,
and compare this to the area over here, which has [s/l many few edges.]
The same is true over here and over here.
I wouldn't really claim this is a much better result.
In fact, it looks kind of funny and very coarse,
but it does have less noise.
Just to complete the issue on blurring,
what we just did is we took an image,
we blurred it with a Gaussian kernel,
and then we applied a gradient kernel.
If you dive into the math of convolution,
you'll find that convolution is associative,
so you could apply this one to the image and then this one over here,
or you can combine these 2 guys over here
into a Gaussian gradient kernel
and apply this Gaussian gradient kernel to the image.
So, f convolved with g is this big
maybe 9 x 9 Gaussian matrix convolved by a single
+1, -1 kernel g.
And here's what this Gaussian gradient kernel looks like.
It's really interesting.
It is the same gradient kernel we had before
but smooth now and spread out
by Gaussian.
And it really responds to an area over here similar to a Sobel operator
that might have a strong negative value.
And the area over here on the right side
has a strong positive value,
so you can think of Sobel and many other kernels
as a combination of smoothing and taking a gradient.
I find this really interesting because
we can now devise a single, linear kernel that does both smoothing
and find gradients at the same time.