Maybe you can apply the same
approach as last time.
So previously we had a list of English
words that we want to store in a certain
sequence from one through ten and now we
have a list of ten Miwok words that we
want to store and maybe you should
store them in an ArrayList as well.
So that seems like
it'll all workout well.
Now we just need to make sure
that the ArrayAdapter constructor
allows us to pass in two lists.
So one list for the English words and
one list for the Miwok words.
So here we are in
the numbers activity and so
let's take a step back and
think about our strategy.
So we want to pass in our new
layout into the ArrayAdapter, so
instead of
android.R.layout.simple_list_item_1 I'm
just going to replace it with the layout
that we created the list item layout.
So this third input is wrong.
So we're passing in words but the words
list is only composed of English words
and we want to pass in the corresponding
Miwok words as well so
that each list item
displays both translations.
So let's go back to
the documentation for
the ArrayAdapter then go down to
the public constructor section.
And again we see that these are ways
to create a new ArrayAdapter.
So we've been using the second to last
constructor, where we pass in a context
which refers to the numbers activity,
the layout file and list of objects.
But it doesn't look like there's
another constructor here that has
to lists as the input.
This one only takes in one list.
And so that's the same with
this constructor as well.
It only takes in one
list as its last input.
So remember we talked about generics?
So the data types of
the object is marked as T.
but this is just a place holder
that you can substitute in
any other object out of type.
So we're currently replacing
T with a string data type and
so we're passing in a ArrayList
of strings to the ArrayAdapter.
So the constructor here above
requires an array of objects and
T here is a placeholder for
any object data type that you want.
Well so far we've been unlucky
we can't find a constructor
that allows us to pass into
list to create an ArrayAdapter.
But we can take advantage of the fact
that ArrayAdapter can take in a list
of any type of object.
So how about instead of
passing in a list of strings,
we create our own object type.
So a Word object.
Now we can define our own Word class and
create word objects from it, and
then we can create a whole
list of Word objects.
Remember from the last course.
Tha a class definition contains
both state and methods.
In the upcoming quiz.
I'm going to ask you how we
should define a Word class.
What state and method should it contain?
So before we jump into the Word class.
I'm going to show you some other
apps that have used custom classes.
So here's a screenshot from
a popular flight booking app.
Called Kayak.
So a user selects the departing and
arriving cities and
the date and the app presents
a list of potential options.
Notice that the information
is presented in a list view.
And each list item has a flight and
then information is always
presented in the same pattern.
Kayak has likely created a custom flight
class and each of these list items
represents information about a single
flight object from that class.
So using our box analogy
we can represent
each of these flight objects
as a big box that holds state.
So state in this case is made up of
different fields such as airline,
departure time, arrival time,
cost, and length the flight.
Now we can also add
methods to this class and
other parts of the app can
call on these methods.
So all this together is
called encapsulation because
all the logic is being encapsulated or
combined into this class.
Now other parts of the trial up can
know that a flat object exists and
that it's possible to call these
methods, such as cancel on that object.
But outside callers don't
need to worry about
the internal details of how
these methods actually work.
The caller just knows the contract, but
they can expect the fight to be
canceled when the method is called.
They could care less about how it's
actually accomplished under the hood.
So this concept is called abstracting
away the details of what goes
inside the class.
Now let's take a look
at another example.
Here's a music app called SoundCloud
that allows users to save their
favorite music tracks in a playlist.
The tracks are displayed in a list and
each track is a list item
displaying the same information.
So we have album name, album art,
song title, song length,
number of listens and all of this is
always presented in the same pattern.
So all the information
can be stored as fields
in a state of a custom song class.
In addition to the states we
can encapsulate methods into
this class as well.
So this song object could have different
methods such as getSongTitle or
getAlbumName.
So similar to the flight class,
here we're abstracting away
the details of the class so
outside callers can use these methods
without knowing the details of them.
So as you can tell from these examples,
there are advantages to encapsulating or
grouping information into
the classes that you've defined.
So now it's your turn to think
about the problem at hand.
I want you to show the English and
Miwok words in the list and
how can you model that data?
Now this is a data structure question
because you have to decide how to
structure the data in your app.
If all that information is stored as
individual global variables in the app,
it would become really hard to manage.
Instead we want to organize the data so
it's easier to retrieve.
And display onto the screen.
So you've already started doing this,
being familiar with data structures.
For example, putting the list
of English words in an Array or
ArrayList was an example
of picking a data structure
to organize information
better in a sequential list.
Now we're going to take
it one step further and
create our own data structure for words.
Because the built-in solutions for Java
just aren't sufficient for our needs.
So we're going to give you a hint
that you create a Word class.
We're going to leave it up to
you to determine what state and
methods it should contain.