Now remember, our generic data types for
AsyncTasks are params,
progress, and result.
These data types are handled by the
doInBackground, onProgressUpdate, and
onPostExecute methods, respectively.
We can replace the first generic
type with a string object.
According to the AsyncTask reference,
DoInBbackground is the method that
handles the first generic data type,
which is params.
And when we look at
the DoInBackground method,
you can see here that it takes
string as the input type.
So, string would be the correct answer.
The second param uses
the onProgressUpdate method.
As I look at this code, I can see there
is absolutely no sign of on progress
update method anywhere to be seen.
So what does this tell me?
That's right,
we aren't using progress updates here.
In the spec, it's said to use Void
if we aren't using a data type so
that's exactly the right answer here.
Note that Void here is capitalize
because it's an object data type.
The third param is handled
by onPostExecute, and
here the code uses a string,
so string is the right answer.
Awesome work.
So to sum up how to use the Async Task,
you need to first create
a subclass of Async Task.
You can call it something Something like
DownloadWebpageTask, or SortDataTask, or
SaveVideoTask, or
whatever makes sense for your app.
Use doInBackground to perform whatever
task you need to do in the background
that's going to take some time, such
as making a call to another web server,
or running a filter on a photo.
Use onProgressUpdate to provide
status updates to your app.
And lastly use onPostExecute to get
the results of your background task.