Okay so the answer is log n.
Why?
Now notice when you insert an element
you might need to traverse
the entire length of the spine because
you might have carries that take you all
the way from 0 to the last bit.
Now the spine has a length
of ceiling of log n.
If you don't remember why or
you don't see why,
just remember the duality with integers.
An integer of size n needs
log n bits to store it.
Now each time we visit a slot on
the spine we might need to combine two
penants.
But remember, combining penants is just
a matter of reshuffling some pointers.
Therefore, a single combine operation
can be done in constant time.
So we have an overall cost of
of log n times constant time and
it gives us an overall log n.
So, that's pretty efficient.
Lots of other kinds of data structures
we know and love like heaps or
balanced binary trees also have log and
insertion costs.
So, bag it baby.
[SOUND]