Now what I'd like you to do,
is to find a relatively new startup and
connect it to one or more of
the idea types that we discussed.
If you think it fits
a different type of idea,
be sure to describe that idea type.
We recommend you use Product Hunt,
a curative platform containing
the days best new products.
Because of its smart and
highly engaged community,
Product Hunt has become a powerful tool
for marketers and entrepreneurs to
use it to launch products compared
to doing a traditional press blast.
We'll be hearing from an investor in
Product Hunt, later in the course.
For now, I'd like you to write
a post that describe the product,
the types of ideas that apply to that
product and why you think it's so
great in the first place.
Don't forget the five categories
that we talked about, or
maybe there's another idea type
that you might be thinking of.