Another design question is how
large should a segment be?
That will work really well if the size
of the data is known up front and
static.
It doesn't change.
However, in addition to the fact
that data sizes may not be static,
that they may be dynamic, the other
problem with this is that it will limit
what is the maximum data that could be
transferred between processes because
typically an operating system will have
a limit on the maximum segment size.
If you want to potentially support
arbitrary message sizes that are much
larger than the segment size,
then one option can be that you
can transfer the data in rounds.
Portion of the data gets written into
the segment, and then once P2 picks it,
up P2's ready to move in
the next round of that data item.
However, in this case, the programmer
will have to include some protocol
to track the progress of the data
movement through the rounds.
In this case, you will likely end up
casting the shared memory area as some
data structure that has the actual data
buffer, some synchronization construct,
as well as some additional
flags to track the progress.