Here I am in
the MovieDetailViewController file.
Let's write the code to finish this out.
First, let's set the parameters,
which for this method are the ApiKey and
the SessionID.
Then let's build our URL, and this
time the pathExtension is going to be
/account, and then we'll substitute
in our userID, and then favorite.
Now the next steps are really important.
We need to make sure the HTTPMethod for
this request is set to POST.
Then we want to add the value
application/json for
the Content-Type and the Accept headers.
The Accept header tells the API that
we will accept JSON in the response,
the data that comes back to us.
And the Content-Type header tells the
API that the data that we'll be sending
in the HTTP body should be treated like
JSON, which leads us to our next step,
creating the HTTP body.
This can be done in one line using
Swift's nice string interpolation.
And here you can see that we're using
that movie property so that we can get
the movie's ID, because that's what's
required here in the media_id argument.
And then for favorite,
we're going to use shouldFavorite
to determine whether that
should be true or false.
All I've done here is adapted the
example code from the documentation and
set the values we want, specifically
the movie!.id and the shouldFavorite.
Then I can make the request.
Now parsing and
using the data is nothing new.
Let's scroll down to
the interesting part.
Here we go.
Now once we have converted the JSON
into a useable dictionary,
we need to check for the status codes.
So let's pull up the status code here.
And then if we are favoriting, so
if we are setting favorite to true,
then we'll want to look for
12 or 1 as the status code.
And if we're not favoriting, if we're
removing it from our favorites list,
we need to look for a status code of 13.
Then we need to update the UI
to reflect those change.
So if we just favorited a movie,
that's true,
then we'll set the tint color to nil,
which will give it that blue color.
Otherwise we'll set
the tint color to black.
All right,
if we've done everything right then
we'll be done with My Favorite Movies.
I'll enter my user name and
password, one last time.
We'll it Login.
And let me go to a movie I
haven't looked up before.
How about The Martian?
We'll click the heart to favorite.
And let's go to our Favorites.
And it's added The Martian here at the
bottom, so it looks like it's working.
And let's go back to this and
let's remove it.
Go back to Favorites.
And it has been removed from bottom.
If we go back to here,
you can see that it also updates and
it's been removed from
this particular view.
By removed, I mean that it's
been removed from our favorites.
And this is it.
We've made our first POST request and
we're done with My Favorite Movies.
Way to go.
Now, if you want to download the
completed version of this app, there's
a download link and instructor notes and
I encourage you to check it out.