So here let me make simple observations about how we can actually do
this kind of stuff.
Again, notice in this case, looking at it carefully,
there is two dominant directions, one in the, one up and
down, and the other one this way on this image.
We can look at it and actually create a two dimensional axes here.
And now we want to actually start looking at what we
can actually extract out of.
Now recall, when we talked about Fourier transforms we said that when,
in a Fourier transform, for every frequency omega that goes from zero to
infinity, the Fourier transform holds the amplitude A and
the phase phi, of the sine function.
That's best represented, and we looked at this before, by this equation.
Amplitude A, sine omega t plus phi.
So now we're interested in, of course, representing this.
So we can actually extract information in axes like this.
The two dimensional axes of an image.
Basically what we do is, we can use the real and
complex numbers to achieve this.
So we'll represent F omega as a real part and an imaginary part here.
Imaginary part and the real part.
So now if I can start representing my Fourier transform in this way,
which basically means now it's a vector in an imaginary and
a real space, we can start doing things like simple vector calculus or
vector arithmetic to able to compute things like the magnitude and the angle.
So the magnitude of the amplitude, basically, is nothing else but the square and
the real part plus the square of the imaginative part over in a square root and
that gives me the magnitude, which would be the A here and v would basically be
the arctangent, or tangent inverse of the imaginary over the real number.
So that, in essence, starts giving us information,
like we can start computing things, like this axis and
the angle, and it can also compute, of course, the magnitude of this vector.
Using these types of things, and again, depending on what kind of signal you're
looking at, and what variables you're looking at,
we can start computing these kinds of things for an image like this.