Okay, so let's go through this.
>> Good.
>> So let's look
at the outcome based estimate.
>> Good.
>> I think you kind of gave me
everything I need here.
>> [LAUGH]
>> So-
>> Yeah, it's possible I spelled it out
too detailed.
>> You can never spell that
out in too detailed way.
So if I look at it,
we encounter S2 exactly once!
Exactly once.
>> And so
the average of one is pretty easy.
It's that thing.
>> Okay, and
what is the estimate for that one?
>> Well, 2 plus 0 plus 10 which is 12.
Because gamma's one.
>> Yeah.
So, good.
So, this is saying, because we only ever
encountered S2 once and the one time
that we saw it we ended up with a reward
of 12 getting to the final state.
That's going to be our estimate.
That's what TD one would actually
do moduled learning rate and
how you initialize the values and
so forth, but
that's sort of what it's trying
to be like given this data.
>> Right.
>> All right, so now, does that match
with the maximum likelihood estimate,
the estimate that we'd get if you
use the data to build a model and
then solved it?
>> So for
the maximum likelihood estimate,
>> All I really need to do is to
compute, let's see, the probability
from going from S3 to S4 and
the probability of going from S3 to S5.
Because everything else
is deterministic, and
in all five of those transitions, I get
to see every state and every reward.
So I have everything that I need.
>> So let's just go ahead and
estimate the probability.
So looking it through I go
from S3 to S4 three times.
>> 2, 3 out of 5 times we're in S3,
good.
>> Right.
So that would be .6.
3/5 is .6 yes, got it.
>> And by process of subtracting
that means that going from S3
to S5 happens .4 of the time.
Yeah.
And we could compute that directly too
by just counting,
we get twice out of five times.
>> So those aren't right.
It should be 0.1 not 0.4, and
it should be 0.9 not 0.6, but hey,
that's the data that we've got.
>> Yeah, you're right.
It's much more even, but
S4 is more common than S5.
Right.
Okay.
Good.
So with that I can just propagate
values backwards through the NDP,
just like we did on the final exam for
7641.
Okay.
So.
>> Good.
>> So let's see.
The value of SF is 0.
The value of S4 is 1.
1 more.
>> 1 plus 0.
And the value of S5 is 10.
>> Good.
>> Plus 0.
>> All right.
So, and that's all actually correct.
>> Yeah, that is actually correct.
Thank you determinism.
Okay.
[LAUGH] So S3 then.
.6 of the time we'll get a value of 1,
and
.4 of the time we'll get a value of 10.
So that would be .6 plus 4.
>> 4.6?
>> That is indeed 4.6.
Cool.
>> All right, so
who cares what S1 is but
I guess we can go ahead and compute it.
It would be 5.6.
>> Good.
>> because it's plus 1, 4.6.
>> But the actual question was about S2,
dun dun dun.
>> And so it is 6.6.
>> 6.6, all right.
>> Truth by addition
>> And it works out pretty well.
Okay, so 6.6 is very different from 12.
>> Sure.
I'm not sure either one of
them is right, so let's see.
If I recall when we went over this MVP
before using the actual transition
probabilities, .9 and .1.
We figured out that
the value of S3 was 1.9?
>> Yep.
>> Yeah, and we can check that.
That would be 0.9 times
1 plus 0.1 times 10.
So yeah, that'd be 1.9, which means
the value of S2 would be 3.9.
>> All right, so the actual value's 3.9.
The maximum likelihood estimate is 6.6,
which is more.
But the outcome-based estimate is 12,
which is a lot more.
Right, so
everybody's wrong except for 3.9.
But maximum likelihood
estimate is less wrong.
>> Right, and so why in this case?
What's the difference
between these cases?
First of all, why are these so far off?
And second of all,
why is the outcome-based one even
further off than the maximum likelihood?
>> Well,
I think it’s pretty simple, right?
When we computed the outcome-based one,
we basically only used one of the five
trajectories to propagate
information back.
>> Mm-hm.
>> But
when we did the maximum
likelihood estimate,
we used information from all
five of the trajectories.
Even though we only encountered S2 once.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And so that's just more information
and it's more accurate, and
you would imagine that if I triple
the amount of data the 6.6 would very
quickly get closer to 3.9.
And the 12 might not move at
all if I never see S2 again.
Hm.
Good.
So
this maximum likelihood estimate is
actually using more of the data.
I think that's accurate.
The reason it's higher than it should
be is because we got, I don't know,
lucky I guess, and had a bunch more
transitions to the high reward state,
S5, than we would expect on average.
And we got really unlucky,
or really lucky,
depending on how you think about it
from this one trajectory we did from S2,
we got the unlikely outcome
which is high reward and so
we ended up with an estimate that is
way higher than it really should be.
>> Yeah, but look.
Let's imagine that we had
gotten lucky the other way,
there's only one other possibility,
right, S2 to S3 to S4 to SF.
And if that had happened then we would
have seen the value of 1 instead of
a value of 10 and we would have had 3.
>> That's right, and
on average it's going to turn out
to be the right answer, this 3.9.
But this estimate is based on
the limited data that we've got.
>> Right.
Okay, fair enough.
All right, but the punch line
here is that this TD(1) idea,
it's not using all the data,
it's using just individual runs.
And so when a rare thing happens on
a run, you could end up with an estimate
that's quite far off, and it could
maybe stay that way for a long time.
Whereas the maximum likelihood estimate
seemed to push you in the direction
of using the data that you've
got to do the best you can.
And so what this is pointing out is that
maybe we don't want to just do TD(1).
There's some nice things about TD(1),
but maybe we can shore up some of these
other issues and
come up with something even better.
>> What, without actually
building an entire model?
>> Yes!
>> Okay, well I look forward to that.