Let's say we are simulating a nondeterministic RAM machine
inside of a deterministic RAM,
so the main cost of that is simulating the if_better function since
it's really the primary difference between
a deterministic RAM and a nondeterministic one.
But what exactly is the cost of simulating if_better?
Let's say we have a polynomial time algorithm,
and that algorithm uses if_better a constant number of times.
Then does that mean that the simulation on the
deterministic RAM takes a constant number of time,
a linear number of time, a polynomial amount of time,
or an exponential amount of time?
And similarly, if we use the if_better function
a logarithmic number of times in the input
or a linear number of times in an input,
and just for kicks,
let's do something a little bit more challenging.
How about if we use the if_better command
every 3rd instruction in the execution,
then how much time does this simulation cost us?
Please check once for each row.