We're going to start with
a fully built workflow.
Where we have a master database of all
people who've been contacted in the past
for direct marketing campaigns.
Notice that the fields at the end of
the file are marked with zeros and ones.
The ones represent the customers
who were contacted on that date for
a particular marketing campaign.
The second data set are customers
who were contacted on the last
direct marketing campaign,
on January 15, 2013.
Whenever we fuzzy match
two datasets together,
the dataset's actually need to
be merged into one dataset.
However we use an ID field
to identify each record and
we use a sort field to identify
where the record is coming from.
So that in that way we can differentiate
the data that comes from each file.
In our scenario,
these fields already exist.
However, if we don't have
these fields in our data sets,
we need to create them.
Coming back to the merging, what we're
actually doing is appending the records
from the customer file to
the records from the master dataset.
So we use Union tool.
We can see the fields from the two
datasets lined up, with the date fields
not lined up, because they're
unique to the individual files.
That's okay.
In the next step,
we'll do the actual fuzzy matching.
We choose the Merge mode because,
as mentioned earlier,
we're working with two datasets that
were merged or unioned together.
The Source ID is the field that
contains the source of the data.
This field is called source and
you can see the contents contain
the words master or customer.
We can see that by running the workflow.
The Record ID field is the field
that contains the unique ID,
identifying each record.
In our case, it's called, HHID.
Lastly, we have to set
the match threshold.
The match threshold is the minimum score
achieved by the fuzzy matching, for
it to be considered to be a match.
The higher the score, the closer or
the more accurate the match.
The lower the score,
the less accurate the match.
However, more records will pass through.
We have set this to 60% here.
Now we have to identify
the match fields,
these are the fields that we'll
use in the Fuzzy Matching process.
We're going to use pre existing
templates, that have been
set up as standard ways that you
can Fuzzy Match to those fields.
The field we're going to match on
are primary address, zip, and last name.
The primary address is
the address field, but
I'm not sure if it has any suites or
apartments in it.
So we can simply choose
address in the match style.
If we are sure that
there are no suites or
apartments, we could choose
the Address No Suite option.
We're then adding the ZIP field as
an additional field to match on, and
using the ZIP Code style.
Last, we're matching on last name, and
for this, we choose the Name style.
Out of the Fuzzy Match tool,
we can see the records that
match between the two datasets.
Household ID 100390855 matches
to Household ID 200011862
in the second dataset.
We may find that there are duplicate
matches to the same records based on
the way that
the Fuzzy Matching tool works.
So, we use the unique tool
from the preparation category,
and set the fields to HHID, and HHID2.
The unique tool pulls one set of records
that are unique through the U side,
and the duplicates come out the D side.
We don't need the duplicates so we
continue our workflow out of the U side.
Now that we know which
records are matches,
we need to link to IDs
back to the original files
to pull through the rest of
the information about those records.
To see how well the address name and
zip code fields matched.
If we look closely at the numbers,
we can tell that the Master files have
numbers that start with a one
in that Household ID field, yet
the customer file starts with
a two in the Household ID field.
So we use a join tool and we connect the
Household ID field to the Household ID
field of the Master dataset,
pulling through all of the fields.
We do remove the Household ID field on
the right though, since it's duplicated.
You can tell it's duplicated
because it's added Right_ as
a prefix to this field.
Additionally, you might notice
that we've renamed some
of the fields with a prefix of Master_.
We add this to the additional field
names, so that we can identify these
fields more easily after we
join to the customer records.
Now we use a second join tool,
so that we can join the records
to the customer file, to pull in
the customer fields by joining
Household ID2 to Household ID
in the customer file.
In this case, we again remove the second
Household ID field by unchecking it.
And we reorder the fields in the Join
tool so that the address, zip code and
name fields are side by side for
the two files.
Also, the fields that we have done the
Fuzzy Matching on also have a prefix,
in this case, of Customer_.
So we'll move
Customer_Primary_Address so
that it's next to
the Master_Primary_Address.
Customer_Zip, so
it's next to the Master_Zip.
And Customer_LastName, so
it's next to the Master_LastName.
Now we can see how all the records
matched, and how the Fuzzy Matching was
able to match the records that
are not spelled exactly the same.
Notice how the Fuzzy Matching was able
to match many names that sound the same,
but are not spelled the same.
The Fuzzy Matched records are just
a subset of the master dataset.
So next we need to union in the records
that did not match the ones that fell
out on the left side to put the entire
master dataset back together.
And then, deselect out
the fields that we don't need.
The final output represented in the
browse, is the entire master dataset.
Notice how the top records
represent the records that matched.
And the bottom records represent
the original master records that did not
match to any records
in the customer file.
Note that all of these records,
have the value of 1,
in the date field,
the new date, January 15, 2013.
And the rest are empty with nulls
because they did not match.
We can replace these later
on with zeroes if we like.
So this final dataset, shown in
the Browse tool, represents the entire
master file with the records
that were Fuzzy Matched,
identified as 1's in the January 15,
2013 column.