So to build this app
just get started with the typical
steps that you would do.
First you create a blank activity app,
then you'll edit your Build.gradles
at the services libraries.
Then you'll edit your Android
manifests with the meta keys for
the services libraries.
The metadata for your API key and
don't forget to go onto
the Google Developer's console.
And add a new instance of the SHA1
followed by a semicolon followed by this
app's name, so
that it will be valid for that API key.
You've seen how to do that before.
Add permissions for Internet, network
state, and write external storage.
And then the meta for OpenGL.
If you're not familiar with the meta for
open GL there is a link in the speaker
notes below but we also covered it
in previous parts of this course.
When you're done with all of this,
check this box.