[Thrun] It's interesting to see how to minimize a loss function using gradient descent.
In our linear case, we have L equals sum over the correct labels
minus our linear function to the square,
which we seek to minimize.
We already know that this has a closed form solution,
but just for the fun of it, let's look at gradient descent.
The gradient of L with respect to W1 is minus 2, sum of all J
of the difference as before but without the square times Xj.
The gradient with respect to W0 is very similar.
So in gradient descent we start with W1 0 and W0 0
where the upper cap 0 corresponds to the iteration index of gradient descent.
And then we iterate.
In the M iteration we get our new estimate by using the old estimate
minus a learning rate of this gradient over here
taking the position of the old estimate W1, M minus 1.
Similarly, for W0 we get this expression over here.
And these expressions look nasty,
but what it really means is we subtract an expression like this
every time we do gradient descent from W1
and an expression like this every time we do gradient descent from W0,
which is easy to implement, and that implements gradient descent.