The first approach,
a network monitor that analyzes traffic
to detect anomalies or
known bad traffic.
For example, traffic to known bad or
suspicious domains.
This can be useful, for
example, if the APT malware,
after stealing credentials from
the sysadmin, now steals data
from the company's server and sends it
to attack a server on the Internet.
A network monitor may be able to detect
or at least log such traffic for
further analysis.
So this is useful.
A host monitor that examines
operating system activities
such as access to files.
Again, this is useful because,
for example, if the APT malware
is stealing data from the server,
it needs to access files on the server.
Therefore, if the monitor can
log such access to files,
it may be able to help
detecting such APT malware.
So this is useful as well.
The third approach,
a malware analysis system that
identifies malicious logic, for example,
by running the browser in a sandbox and
tracing its detail execution.
This is useful, for example,
if you run the malware in a system,
such as a sandbox, and trace its
execution at the instruction level.
Then we can identify that there
is a part of the browser that
modifies the PDF document.
And this part of the browser
is the malicious extension.
So this is useful.
This quiz illustrates that to detect
a malware, in particular APT malware,
we need a comprehensive approach
such as including network monitor,
host monitor, and
malware analysis system.