And in fact that's shown here.
So it says, you know,
what if the template in the scene is not identical to some sub image.
So here we have a scene and we have a template, well it turns out
that the best location of this template in this scene is right there.
It actually finds the same car.
Now you have to worry about scale and orientation and
all that stuff, stuff that we're going to talk about later in the class.
But even though the cars are quite different the fact of the matter is
it has sort of bright stuff here and dark brown things there.
This has bright stuff there and dark brown things there.
So as a template it's not awful.
So that's using these filters as templates