Recall that a bitonic split takes
a bitonic sequence as input and
produces two bitonic
subsequences as output.
Now suppose I give you an eight
element bitonic sequence.
You can implement an eight
element bitonic split
using a comparator circuit.
I want you to show me how.
I want you to do that by adding
plus comparators to this circuit.
Insert no more than one
comparator per column.
Here's an example of
what I want you to do.
Suppose you wanted to connect this input
and this input by a plus comparator.
You would do that by
checking these two boxes.
If you left these three columns blank,
then this would be the output.
Okay, now I want you to try.