So this question asked us to replace
the instance of noun with duck, and
verb with waddle,
in the string sentence.
Let's start with the noun replacement.
Since we're using the replace function,
we don't need to do any complex string
slicing or
concatenation like we did before.
But we have to get our three variables
in the proper positions to use
the function correctly.
Let's set up the skeleton
of our function.
The first value passed into our
place function is a string we're
looking to replace.
So in this case, NOUN and
the second value
is the string we want to replace
the first value with, so duck.
Finally, the string before the duck,
is a sentence where all this
replacing will take place.
So, we'll add sentence here.
And there we go,
with this line of code, NOUN is replaced
with duck in the string sentence.
Let's do the same thing for
our verb replacement.
And there we have it.
Rather than having to slice, create new
variables, and concatenate, our new
knowledge of their place function allows
us to do this all in two lines of code.
Pretty cool, right?