So you still don't believe all
this particle filter mumbo jumbo?
Let's try a simple example.
Here's an ant scurrying along
on top of this crossword puzzle.
It's one of those
computer-sciencey ants, so
it only moves one step at a time,
either horizontally or vertically.
It can sense whether it's on
a black square or white square.
But that is it, it has no other way
of knowing where on the puzzle it is.
Here is a sequence of
steps that the ant took.
The first column is time, t.
The second column is its observation,
z, which is one for
white, and zero for black.
The final column is that action taken,
or
u, which is basically what
direction did the ant move in.
For instance, at t equals 0,
the ant saw that it was on a white
square, and then it moved up.
At t equals 1,
it observed a black square.
This was the result of moving
up in the previous step.
Okay, the next action was moving left,
and so on.
Can you figure out where
the ant is at t equals 5?
Mark the appropriate checkbox, or
boxes, if you're still unsure.