So what is competition photography?
Well, before we get that let's ask the question, what is photography?
And of course the best way to do this these days, if you believe that,
is to go search for it on the internet, and of course I will.
Just take a chance and see what the Wikipedia page on photography says about it.
Couple of things too we should look at here.
One, photography is a science and art.
It's a practice of creating images by recording light.
It could even be some other forms of things like electromatic,
electromagnetic radiation, but let's just stick to light.
Either electronically or by means of an image sensor.
Or chemically.
So that's of course film.
Electronic sensor is digital.
And to generate an artifact, an image.
So in essence, if you really think hard about it is, photography is a process of
taking light from a natural environment and storing it in a form of an image.
The literal definition of the term photography is drawing with light, all right?
I mean, that's the exact literal definition of the word photography.
In essence, what we are interested in is taking the light from a natural
environment most of the time and creating an image to store that information.
And of course, what we I do this it depending on the application,
could be scientific, could be art, aesthetics, depends on the user at the end.
Of course to do this,
we have a variety of things that we can use, there is a lens that we
can play around with which of course then has variety different types of things.
A camera has a lens and we look at all those types of things again.
And again this part gets into the whole process of how an image would be
created from that kind of stuff and then what we do with it at the end, right.
So we can share it, we can print it.
So, basically the whole process of drawing with light and
using that to share the image, for a variety of purposes, either art,
science, is an important part of what we do with photography.
Of course it's related to many disciplines in science and manufacturing and
all that kinds of stuff and many different applications come in.
That's what makes photography very interesting and exciting.