We've improved the initial experience
feedback in the case of poor
connectivity, but what happens if
the weather server goes down or
if from behind a captive portal?
In that case, we could get either no
data or some form of corrupted data and
the user still will have
no idea what is happening.
Let's start by enumerating the states,
we want to communicate
with the user about.
While Java supports enumerated types,
they're somewhat expensive and
inefficient by comparison to using
static final integer constants.
So at Android,
we recommend avoiding them.
That being said, it would be nice
to have some type safety and
that's where the annotations we've added
to the Android Support Library can help.
Well, first of all,
what are annotations?
In Java, annotations are specified
beginning with an @ sign,
such as the commonly
used @override here.
They contain information or metadata
that gets associated with the code in
our app, but do not directly change
the functionality of the code.
They may be used by
development tools and
depending on the way they are retained,
may be read at runtime.
To use the support annotations,
we just go to Android Studio
to the Project Structure dialog and
add the support annotations dependency.
Since the integer we are storing for
our state can only have a few
predefined values, it would be nice for
our tools to be able to help us.
Cache assigning unsupported
value to our state,
an auto complete the typing
of variables of this type.
The support annotations and
library provides functionality that does
just that using the IntDef annotation.
Here's how this works.
When we define our integer constants,
we also create an interface annotation.
As in this example from inside
the app from PAD Library,
we then annotate this new
annotation with IntDef,
containing the different integer
constants that are supported.
The retention policy of source tells
the tool chain that we do not need
to preserve this annotation
in the class or at runtime.
Making the annotation not have an impact
on our runtime or distribution sides.
The IDE will now flag cases where we try
to return a value not in this set from
getNavigationMode or
pass an integer not from this set
into this set, @NavigationModeMethod.
So what location states do
we need to think about?
The first stage is that
everything is okay.
The second stage is that
our server is down.
The third stage is that our
server is malfunctioning.
The fourth stage is that we don't
know if the server is up or
down, because we haven't
tried to contact it yet.
We'll continue to add states here, as we
work to make our app production ready.