Right, the first question.
Should scoreTeamA be local or global?
I'm going to answer this before
even moving onto the code.
Now, you had a little bit of practice
with this in the earlier exercises.
Given then the score needs to be saved
and modified for a longer period of time
and in between button clicks,
it should be global variable.
Okay, so I'm going to go ahead and
define it now because I have a little
bit of a better idea of where I should
define it because I'm making it global.
Okay, here I am in the code.
I'm going to go over to the Java file,
and
you might see that
a couple things changed.
Actually, really, the only thing that
changed is I added some comments here to
say what each of these methods does.
Besides that, everything's the same.
Okay.
So, I need to define a global variable.
I'm going to scroll up, and
the reason that I scroll up
is because by convention,
when I have global variables, I put
them right here at the top of the class.
The difference in location of where you
define a global variable versus a local
variable is that local variables
will be defined within methods,
whereas global variables will
be outside of the methods.
So I'm putting it outside right here.
Well, I know it's a number, and
because you're always going to score
at least one point, and you're
not going to score 1.5 points, this
number isn't going to include decimals.
So, a type of integer is actually
a pretty good choice here.
So, I'm going to type int.
Okay, and
after the data type comes the variable
name, and I'm going to use scoreTeamA.
Okay, and if I was just doing
a declaration, I'd be done.
But, I was also told to
initialize this to zero.
So, forget the semicolon for now.
I'm going to write the equal sign also
known as the assignment operator and
I'm going to set it to zero.
Oh, and don't forget the semicolon.
Okay, so, there's the answer for that.
Good work so far.