That ends this lesson on the relationship between convolution in
the spacial domain and the frequency domain.
In particular the convolution in the spacial domain is multiplication in
the frequency domain.
We've also made good on the promise of explaining some of some of
these ugly artifacts that we saw particular ringing is sort of
a Fourier transform of a box that is if you cut off the frequencies hard.
You get this ring or if you have a cutoff in space that's hard,
you get this ringing in frequency.
What we now have are the tools that will allow us to tackle aliasing.
That is when you do something to an image that involves sampling that causes it
to look really ugly.
And the high frequency stuff.
It's a little bit of of a bumpy ride, so strap yourself in and
get ready for the next lesson.