When we press this button, we want to
let the Location Services know about
the list of geofences
that we're working with.
And this is called adding
the list of geofences.
To do this,
in LocationServices.GeofencingApi,
there's a method called addGeofences.
And addGeofences requires
these parameters.
First is the GoogleApiClient,
which you'll have already.
Then it's the Geofencing Request,
which you're going to create shortly.
And then is the Geofencing Pending
Intent, which you created earlier on.
It also requires you to set
a callback called onResult(),
and we'll see how to
create that shortly.
You've already implemented
GoogleApiClient, so
let's take a look at the others,
starting with this Geofencing Request.
Check this box when
you're ready to continue