The answer for reusability is A, increased system fragmentation.
High reusability means high cohesion.
That is, that each module has a single purpose.
This might lead to more modules, and
hence, to more connections among the modules.
The answer for performance is B, reduced system understanding.
Performance requirements often are dealt with via introducing special cases or
Achaean data structures, which can make the code harder to understand.
The answer for security is C, increased coupling.
Security means data security, and
data security is provided by controlling access to the data.
This means that in order for modules in order to access the data,
they need to go through some form of data access control.
Which is typically provided by a centralized control module,
to which all the other modules must be coupled.
Finally, the answer for reliability is D, compromised delivery schedule.
Increased reliability typically means extra code to check for
potential problems.
Extra code means extra coding, checking, documentation, and
so on, which can lead to difficulties delivering on time.