In Part 1 navigate to Lesson 3,
Stage 6 and simply import both spouts and add them to your topology.
So we navigate to our exclamation topology and add import statements for
udacity.storm.spout, MyNames, and MyLikesSpout.
Next we scroll down to our topology builder section, comment out our word, and
simply add the spouts.
I added a parallelism of 10, but you could have chosen what you liked.
And here's the MyLikeSpout, MyNameSpout, and
I have chosen component IDs my-likes and my-names.
So in the remainder of the solution, I left the component ID up to
you just to demonstrate that whatever component ID you choose in your topology,
you'll then need to use that in your definition of each bolt.
So my-likes and my-names are mine.
And in Part 2 we connect the report bolt to exclaim1, not exclaim2.
And we update the report bolt using integer count of 30.
And a way I approach this is, is I first commented out our word tuple.
And I instead use getValue at position zero and
cast it to a string and use that as our word.
I commented the count.
And simply uncommented in the integer count.
Remember that the count drives the visualization, but
here we're not longer counting using a count bolt.
We're simply displaying it and so we need to synthesize.
And finally, I connect the report bolt to exclaim1 using the globalGrouping.
In part 3 without modifying the ExclamationBolt,
I use two shuffle groupings to join and connect exclaim1.
You can refer to the streaming join syntax video, but
this is simply shuffle grouping my-likes and shuffle grouping my-names.
And don't forget your semicolon.
And remember that this is the streaming join syntax,
when tuples have the same characteristics.
So I'll be accessing the first position in each of these.
We simply use making package and submit.
And we see that our visualization has names, but also names and favorites pairs.
And finally the exclamation bold already appends three exclamations.
In step 4 we modify the MyLikeSpout to emit name and favorite instead of a pair.
And remember that this requires the declare output field to be updated.
We navigate to the MyLikeSpout.
I'll comment out the collector emit statement, and
instead we emit name and favorite.
And instead of outputting the fields pair,
we output the fields name and favorite.
In part 5, we modify the exclaim bolt to create a favorite map,
when a name and favorite tuple is received from the MyLikeSpout.
We first navigate to the exclamation topology and
at the class level we declare a favorites map, or
whatever you called it, as a map that takes in a string and a string.
Remember that this will the name and the favorites.
Next in the prepare method we initialize our map.
I called it favoritesMap.
That's a new hash map that takes in a string in a string.
And the execute method would we define what
happens when the ExclamationBolt receives a tuple.
You can use the component hint and simply declare a string.
I called it componentId, that takes in the tuple received and
used the getSourceComponent method.
Next we can remove the previous logic.
And use the componentId to modify the behavior,
depending on where the tuple came from.
First, if the componentId equals my-likes, and
remember, if we scroll down to our topology that my-likes is
the componentId that we chose for the MyLikesSpout.
We know that the tuple is of the form name favorite.
And therefore at position zero we have name and
at position one we have favorite in both our strings.
Therefore we're able to query the tuple and
get back the string name and string favorite.
Next we simply check if the name exists in our favorites map, and if it
does not then we simply put the name and the favorite as our key and value.
And finally, notice that if we receive a tuple from my-likes we do not emit.
In the next step, if the tuple is received from the MyNameSpout,
we instead check our favoriteMaps to see if the name exists.
And if so, we emit the sentence of names favorite is favorite.
And finally we append three exclamation marks to the end of the sentence.
In code we simply add in an else if statement that checks if
the componentId that we obtained from the tuple equals my-names.
And remember, again, that my-names is the component id that I selected when I
defined my MyNamesSpout in our builder.
And finally, we build in the logic or
what we do if we receive a tuple for my-names.
We simply extract the name, and we see if the name is in our favoritesMap, and
if it exist we simply query the map to get our favorite.
Remember that this map was constructed from tuples received for my-likes.
And then we build our sentence.
We simply create our exclamated favorites,
we append the name, name's favorite, favorite with three exclamation points.
And to complete, remember that we need to emit in this stage our new values,
which are exclamated favorites.
And for completion I am still using the exclamated word as
our declare output fields.
And finally we package and run our initialization and we see that our name and
favorites are constructed to create kind of
fun sentences with three exclamation points appended.
In part 6, we connect our report poll to exclaim2 now.
Modify the ExclamationBolt again to append three more exclamation points for
a total of six.
We scroll down to our topology builder section and
simply change exclaim1 to exclaim2, and in our ExclamationBolt definition we
simply add in our new else if clause if the componentId equals exclaim1.
Finally if the tuple comes from exclaim1 we extract the sentence from
the tuple at position zero, create our exclaim,
exclamative word, and append three additional exclamation marks to it and emit.
Finally, after building and submitting, your final visualization should
have our words with names and favorites constructed into a sentence.
And six exclamation marks appended to the end.
Optionally, in stage seven you can update your MyLikeSpouts and
MyNameSpouts to personalize your sentences.
And take a screenshot or a screencast and put it up on the forum.
Congratulations on finishing lesson three.