Again, what we're trying to do now
is explore a deterministic MDP and
have low mistake bound.
The number of actions that we take that
are sub-optimal by more than epsilon is
going to be,
we need to bound it in terms of things.
I don't know.
Let's try a little experiment.
You're going to be
the reinforcement learner.
>> Okay.
>> And I'm going to be the environment,
and tell you what's going on.
So let's say we start
of on this state here.
Which action do you want to do,
one or two?
>> Do I get to cheat and
look to see what the?
[LAUGH]
>> You could, but
I think that somehow isn't
going to be quite as pedagogical.
>> Well, we'll learn a lesson for sure.
I'll do one.
I don't even know which one is one and
which one is two anyway.
I'll do one.
>> Yeah, I get to pick that.
That's the good news
from my perspective.
[SOUND] I'm sorry that
cost you 8 points.
>> No!
>> Yes, but now we're here.
So do you want to do one or two?
>> Let's do one again.
>> [SOUND] That's not bad.
You got plus 2, and
you didn't go anywhere.
>> Just like grad school.
Well, I've done one.
I know what that is, so let's try two.
>> Okay, [SOUND] plus 10,
so that's really good, but
now, you're some place new.
>> Can I invent a time machine?
Let's do one.
>> Let's do one.
Minus 6, ouch.
Now you're here.
>> Ugh.
All right, let's do one.
When I was in that other state and
I got a plus 2,
I could have just stayed there forever.
In fact,
that probably was the right thing to do,
because I get infinite reward.
>> Well it's discounted.
>> I said by discount to be one.
>> [LAUGH] No,
you don't get to choose that.
>> [LAUGH] That's not fair.
Okay, so I'm sorry, I interrupted you.
>> So you chose action one.
So I'll give you one point for
choosing action one.
>> And I end up in another state.
All right, well,
let's do action one again.
>> [SOUND] All right, so plus 1,
and you get to be there again.
>> If I just keep doing action
one over and over again forever,
I'll accumulate infinite reward.
>> No, sorry.
You'll get one over one minus gamma.
>> Aah!
Okay, I'll set gamma equal to one.
>> [LAUGH] No, that's not one
of the choices I was giving you.
You could choose actions.
I should have probably told you gamma.
I guess that would only be fair, right?
>> Well, I'm not sure it's going to
matter just as long as gamma's
less than one.
All right, so, I now know something.
>> You now know something.
You know a lot of things.
>> I do know a lot of things.
I'm still in the same state.
But I've got another action.
And I'm going to think about it.
Let's try action two.
>> [SOUND] Plus 6, yay.
And now you're at a state
you've never been to before.
>> This reminds me of Zork.
Okay, I'll take action one.
>> [LAUGH] It is like Zork.
>> It's exactly like Zork.
>> [SOUND] Hey,
you're back to the state that you
started in in the very beginning.
>> I know minus 8 sucks.
Actually, I now could basically
do that cycle forever.
>> The series of actions that you just
did that take you around this loop.
Yes?
>> Mm-hm.
>> Is that near optimal?
>> Well, if it involves minus 8,
probably not.
Let's do action two.
>> Good idea.
[SOUND] All right, so you're back to
another state you've been to before.
>> And I got a minus 3 along the way
which is better than the minus 8, but
not better than the minus 8,
plus 2 some number times,
plus 10 except gamma by 0.9.
Okay, so I know what action one gives
me there, so let's do action two.
[SOUND]
>> Good job, you got a plus 4.
And you're back here.
>> Oh, I'm in a nice little state, too.
I can do some other cycle.
>> Yeah, and
you tried action one from there.
>> Oh, but I never tried
action two from here, did I?
Let's do action two.
>> All right, so action two turns
out to be identical to action one.
>> Oh, okay.
That's complicated.
>> Cool,
now you're back at the initial state,
the state that you started
in the beginning of time.
And both actions that you have here,
you've tried already.
>> I can say something about what
can happen after that point, right?
I know, sort of,
if I take action one, I get minus 8,
plus 2 for some amount of time,
plus 10 through the best I could.
>> Minus 10.
Oh, plus 10, you're right.
>> Plus 10.
Or I could do minus 3 and
get immediately to this thing where I
could go get plus 4s and plus 3s,
which actually is better I think.
Hm, so I should pick one of those.
>> Well, okay, so here's an important
point that we need to get to.
So actually, you've explored the entire
MDP, except for one state action pair,
this one here.
And so
if this edge is like a self-loop with
a reward of a million,
then you have to find it.
You have to get it, because otherwise
you're not going to be near the optimal.
>> Right, and I don't know that,
so I have to get there.
>> Right, but on the other hand, let's
say that we know that the highest reward
is 10, we have some bound,
we'll call it Rmax,
on the largest reward in any state,
that could be really helpful, because it
could be that I can get a value by
acting in the MDP that I have now.
Even if this were 10, even if it
were its highest possible value
with let's say a self-loop,
we can still do better than that.
>> This feels very minimax.
>> Well, it's R and max.
>> No, I mean, this feels like it's
a tree and I could do pruning.
What you're basically saying is I should
prune things if I already know that I
can't do any better than some
other choice that I have.
>> Yeah, that's right.
So it has a boundish kind of feel to it.
So what I'm suggesting is for
any edge that we don't know,
let's just be super optimistic and
assume that it has value Rmax.
>> Yeah, that makes a lot of sense.
If I pretended that's true for
everything that I don't know,
then that would tell me what to do sort
of in what the best worst case would be.
And then, I obviously try to get to the
place that I think is good because I'm
optimistic.
And if it turns out that I'm wrong,
well as soon as I get there I
will know that I was wrong.
And I just keep doing that.
>> All right,
let's write down the steps, so
that we don't have to hold
them in our heads so long.