Here are the steps that you'll
be implementing for signing in.
It's a little bit involved, so
let's go through each step one by one.
First things first,
you'll add the correct dependencies
to friendly chat for authentication.
Second, you'll add a special listener
which is called an AuthStateListener.
This listener is triggered when
the user's authentication state changes.
An authentication state change
is something like signing in or
logging out.
Third, now that you have this listener,
you can redirect the user to log in
if they've opened the app and
they're not already logged in.
At this point,
you'll basically have an app that
detects if the user is logged in or not.
And if they're not logged in,
it'll force them to log in.
For step four, the log code which
changes the UI to reflect whether
the user is logged in or logged out.
That change comes in two parts.
When the user is logged in, you'll
have the access to their user name.
So you can use it when they're
writing messages to the Database.
You can also attach the Database
read messenger at this point.
You'll only attach the Database read
listeners after user is sign in.
This is because unauthenticated user
doesn't have permission to read from
the Database.
And when a user signs out, they'll tear
down what you set up in the sign in
which will mean things like unsaving
the user name of the signed out user.
You'll unset the user name of
the user that just signed out.
You'll detach your database listeners,
and you'll clear the message list.
And after all that's done you'll
open up the sign in flow again.
Okay, onward to the code.
The first step is to add
the appropriate dependency.
Here is the dependency for
authentication.
So if you're using any kind of firebase
oath, you'll need this dependency.
Ill go ahead and add that to my apps
bill dot great file right down here.
Since you're also using Firebase UIR,
you'll need that dependency as well.
Okay, so there are my new dependencies.
I'm going to go ahead and synch.
Remember to check that the Firebase UI
version that you're using
matches the Firebase SDK
version that you're using.
All right, now that you've added your
dependencies you're ready to get coding.
So let's get to it.