So I had used Google sheets to
organize information about three pets
from our previous exercise.
Now the object of our pets table are
the pets represented by each row here.
And each column was
an attribute of the pet.
Now whenever you know that you're
going to use an SQLite database,
the first thing to figure out
is what tables you need, and
what the columns of the table should be.
So for a database, we only needed
one table for our pets, and
the structure included the column names,
name, breed, gender, and weight.
So coming with this probably
wasn’t too difficult.
So let's take a look at another example,
so
you can practice taking in data and
then organizing it into a table.
Now let's say you're making an app for
an e-commerce website called
ConstantNoize, and
they sell over 100 kinds of headphones.
So they need to organize all
the headphone styles into a table
in their database.
Here's an example of their sales
page for one of their headphones.
Now what information about the
headphones should we put into the table?
So I'll like you to
answer that question.
If ConstantNoize wants to store all
the headphone products in a single table
in a database,
what attributes would that table have?
And go ahead and
check all the attributes that
they should store in their table.
Realistically, there could be a lot
of other information, such as
customer profiles, shipment addresses,
all for the different headphone orders.
But for now, the table should simply
just store product information
about the hundred different kinds
of headphones sold by the store.
So give this exercise a try,
and remember to check out
the website down below.