And I've got an incoming call from Mike.
I guess that means you'll
be coding this one up.
Hey Mike, you think they're ready for
this one?
>> Yep, they certainly are.
Well, you know what you've got to do.
Tell the user when there
is an update available.
First to get you started,
you need to get your project
into the same state as Jake's.
Go to the project directory
in the command line and
run git reset --hard to remove
any local changes you have.
Then get checkout task update notify.
We're going to edit
a different file this time.
In public /JS/main/indexcontroller.JS.
You might remember this file
from earlier in the course.
It's where you registered
the service worker.
There's a new method here, _updateReady.
Calling this will show
a notification to the user.
Your job is to call it
at the correct times.
There's a series of comments
to guide you along the way.
Once you've coded it up,
you'll need to get those changes
picked up by the browser.
This is a little awkward.
The easiest way is to delete the service
worker then refresh the page.
This will refresh and
cache your JavaScript.
Now make a change to
your service worker.
Adding a comment will suffice.
Then refresh the page.
If your code's working,
you'll see the notification.
Once you've got the notification
working, head over to the settings page.
And type update-notify into
the test field and press enter.
This will confirm it's all working.