Google has created a web application
where developers can test making
API calls for
the Google suite of products.
Let's walk through how to
use this Playground, and
then you'll have a chance to
practice using it on your own.
Visit developers.google.com/ofplayground
and follow along.
Once you login,
you'll see a layout like this.
Here on the right hand side, we have
a list of all the options of Google
products we can use to make
API calls using OAuth.
Let's go ahead and
select Google OAuth 2, API version 2.
Here, we're give a list of URLs,
with descriptions of the APIs
that they implement.
Let's select userinfo.profile and
see what that does.
We now must grant authorization from
Google OAuth Playground to use this API.
The app is given an authorization code
that it can exchange for access and
refresh tokens.
Clicking here initiates this
trade of a code for tokens.
And we see that we are granted
an access token for
about 3,600 seconds, eh,
which is about an hour.
Now, using the access token we can
make calls to the Google+ API server.
Here we can see a list of all
the possible operations we can use.
I will click the V2 user info option,
and then go ahead and
send off the request.
Here I can see that Google+ responded
with a JSON object, complete with my
name, picture, gender, locale,
and a link to my Google+ profile.
If I click on this link for
picture, I can see that it is indeed
my account that it's connected to.
Now, it's time for
you to play in the OAuth Playground.
Explore some of the other options and
data that you can retrieve using
OAuth and the API functions.
Depending on the products you
have tied to your Google account,
you may be able to retrieve information
for more of these accounts.
Share your findings with
some of the other students.