Personal firewall is similar
to a host based firewall.
It controls traffic between a personal
computer and the rest of the network.
Personal firewalls
are also often deployed at
home routers to protect home networks.
These firewalls tend to be
simpler because the home networks
are less complex than
the enterprise networks.
Similar to firewalls
at corporate networks,
the main function of personal firewalls
is to track traffic in both directions.
For example,
the personal firewall on the home router
can stop attacks from reaching
the internal home computers.
It can also monitor outgoing traffic.
For example, it can detect connection
to an extended server as known for
performing botnet command control and
it can block such connection.
Therefore, even when a home
computer has been compromised,
it cannot participate
in botnet activities.
As an example, these services
are typically not allowed, but
a personal firewall can selectively
enable any of these services.