We are going to now look at the distribution of the variables of interest.
Let's first define f0, to be the average submitted charge.
F1 to be the average payment amount.
And f2 to be the average allowed amount.
It's clear that this data is aggregated, and
shows us only the expected or average values for charges.
For our purpose,
we could treat them as the representative of the actual charges.
This however, is not always a good assumption.
But we will work with this for illustrative purposes.
Now, let's switch to the i path in notebook and
look at the distributions of the average values in the data.
So here, we have now defined the three variables f0, f1 and f2.
Once we have defined the three variables we can
now plot histograms with these variables.
The code block here, plots two histograms on the same graph.
Let's execute this code.
Once the code has run, it will show you a histogram that looks like this.
It's a simple histogram, with the average charged amount shown in green and
the allowed amount shown in blue.
We can try to draw the same histograms for the average charged amount,
and average payment amount.
You can do that by running this piece of code here.
Once you run that code, you will have a very similar histogram,
with the average charged amount shown in green again.
And the average payment amount shown in red.
Let's inspect this histogram a little bit further.
We had plotted both the green and
the red histograms in the range from 0 to 1,000.
We also had bins of 50 each.
What that means is the entire range from 0 to 1,000,
was divided into 50 different bins.
Each bin then contains the range between 0 to 20, 20 to 40 and so on.
The Y axis shows us the number of times a data value was in that given range.
This is the simple concept of a histogram.
Now you will also notice, that the values here are fractional values.
This is because both of the histograms have been normalized.
What this means, is that the area under the curve of
the histogram adds up to the number 1.
To achieve this, we take the original histogram and
divide by the area to get the value for each of these columns.
Also notice that the shape of the two histograms are quite different.
What this means is that the probability of charges between 200 and
1,000 are a lot more,
than the probability of payments made between 200 and 1,000.
The probability being given by the integral between 200 and 1,000 of this curve.
In the case here, the integrals are merely the sum of the numbers in each bin.
The histogram is, in fact, an example, of a non parametric statistical model.
In the following few videos, we are going to inspect what it
means to have non parametric statistical models, in greater detail.