Try moving between applications
on your phone or emulator.
You can watch some big ones,
like the browser or Google Maps and
some comparatively small ones,
like the calculator.
Android will kill background
applications as needed and
your apps should be ready for this.
The very last lifecycle method you
will get in these cases is on stop,
i.e, you won't ever get on destroy.
Try to reproduce this with
our lifecycle app and
you'll find it's pretty hard to do.
Our lifecycle app is tiny, so
Android won't prioritize killing it off.
It's only going to do
that if the device or
emulator is under
extreme memory pressure.
Let's take a closer look at
how you should prepare for
an untimely app death.