For the first question, what would you
use for a News reader or for messaging?
The correct answer is
probably BoxInsetLayout
because you want the text will be
completely visible on the screen.
What about for an Alarm clock?
In this case, you'd probably pick
WatchViewStub because you want different
layouts for round and square devices.
What about for Map navigation?
In this case you'd probably use
WatchViewStub as well because you'd want
the layout to be customized to fit
the edges nicely of a round or
a square display.
What about the,
List of the weeks weather?
In this case, maybe BoxInsetLayout
might be the right choice
because you have a long list and
you want it to fit on the screen nicely.
What about a Photo of a face?
In this case you'd use WatchView Stub
because you wouldn't want the face photo
to be confined to fit within
a small box on the screen.
You want the face to consume
the entire size of the watch.
What about Photo of a landscape?
Same thing here as well.
You'd probably use WatchViewStub
because you wouldn't want the image of
the landscape being confined to
a small box on a round display.
In most cases you want to use
WatchViewStub to give you a custom
layout for both round and
square devices.
But sometimes, when you're dealing
with large slabs of texts,
a BoxInsetLayout is the best way
to ensure it's properly visible.
When dealing with pictures, these look
okay on round display when the corners
are not visible, particularly
when the subject is centered.