Before we talk about the kernel-level
allocators, I want to describe
a particular memory allocation
challenge that needs to be addressed.
Consider a page-based
memory manager that needs
to manage these 16 physical page frames.
Let's say this memory manager takes
requests of sizes two or four page
frames, and let's say it's facing the
following sequence of memory requests.
The first memory allocation is for
the request of two page frames and
then the rest of the requests are for
four pages.
So let's say the memory allocator
allocates these requests in order,
and the end result of this will be that
this will be the memory allocation,
how the physical memory is used
to satisfy these requests, and
their two free page frames.
Let's say next the two pages that
were initially allocated or freed.
So now you likely can already
imagine what the problem is.
If at this point a next request
comes to allocate four pages,
there are four free pages in the system.
However, this particular allocator
cannot satisfy this request
since these pages are not contiguous.
Let's say the requirement with
these allocation requests was for
these memory pages to be contiguous.
So in that case, this allocator
cannot meet this requirement.
This example illustrates a problem
that's called external fragmentation.
This occurs where we have
multiple interleaved allocate and
free operations, and
as a result of them,
we have basically holes of free
memory that's not contiguous.
And therefore, requests for
largest contiguous memory
allocations cannot be satisfied.
In the previous example,
the allocator had a policy in
which the free memory was handed
out to consecutive requests in a sort
of first come, first served manner.
Let's consider an alternative in which
the allocator probably knows something
about the requests that are coming.
It knows that they will be coming for
consecutive regions of two and
four page frames.
In the second case when
the second request for an,
allocating four pages comes,
the memory allocator isn't allocating it
immediately after the first allocation
but instead is leaving some gap.
The second allocation for four pages
comes in at a granularity of four pages,
and then the rest of the allocations
are satisfied further below.
Now when the free request comes in,
these two first pages are freed.
The system again has four free pages.
However, they're consecutive.
Therefore, this next request for
four pages can actually be
satisfied in the system.
What we see in this example is
that when these pages are freed,
there was an opportunity for
the allocator to coalesce,
to aggregate these adjacent areas of
free pages into one larger free area.
That way, it was more likely for
the allocator to satisfy
these future larger requests.
This example illustrates some of
the issues that an allocation algorithm
needs to be concerned with to avoid or
to limit the extent of fragmentation and
to allow for quick coalescing and
aggregation of freed areas.