First, RSA is a block cipher
in which the plaintext and
ciphertext are integers between 0 and
n- 1 for some n.
This is true because for
RSA we require that the plaintext input
is smaller than n and the server text
has the same length as the plaintext.
Therefore the servertext
is also smaller than n.
Second, if someone invents
a very efficient method to
factor large integers then
RSA becomes insecure.
This is true because if you can factor
efficiently that means for public key n,
you can factor n equal to p times
q where p and q are prime numbers.
And knowing p and q,
you can compute [INAUDIBLE] n.
And given the public key e,
then you can compute a private key d,
which is the multiplicative
inverse of e, marked n.
In short, if you can factor efficiently,
that means you can recover
the RSA private key.
Third, The Diffie-Hellman
algorithm depends for
its effectiveness on the difficulty
of computing discrete logarithms.
This is true, because if it is easy
to compute discrete logarithms,
then given the publicly
exchanged value cya,
an adversary can compute
the local secret xa.
And knowing the xa, the adversary
can then compute a [INAUDIBLE] s.
Four, the Diffie-Hellman key
exchange protocol is vulnerable
to man-in-the-middle attack because it
does not authenticate the participants.
This is true.
Because the protocol
does not authenticate.
When Alice receives a message,
she has no way of knowing that
the message is really from Bob.
That is, Alice has no way of
knowing that the value of y b,
which she uses to compute a shared
secret s, is really from Bob.
Which means Trudy can
send y x to Alice and
fool Alice to believe that it is y b.
Fifth, RSA and Diffie-Hellman
are the only public-key algorithms.
This is false.
For example,
there are other public key algorithms
such as the digital signature standard
and the elliptic curve cryptography.