In this last programming assignment before the final project,
I've added two new spouts.
The MyLikeSpout and MyNameSpout.
You will update the exclamation topology and
ExclamationBolt to process these two spouts.
Your new ExclamationBolt will create a dictionary of
key value pairs that are received from the MyLikeSpout.
And emit a sentence appended with three exclamation points when a name or
key is received from the MyNamesSpout.
In Part 0, navigate to Lesson 3, Stage 6.
And in part 1 initially both spouts emit similar tuple schemas of string.
Import both spouts and add them topology.
In part 2, connect the ReportBolt to the exclaim1 bolt and
remember that you must modify the ReportBolt to make this connection.
I've used an integer count of 30 and
remember that this count changes the text size of the visualization.
In part 3, without modifying the ExclamationBolt yet, use two shuffle groupings
to join and connect to exclaim one, build and submit your visualization.
Once completed with part 3, your visualization will have names and
name favorite pairs, but they're not connected.
So, in part four we modify the like spout to emit name and
favorites instead of pair.
Also remember that this requires the declaration output fields to be updated.
In part 5, modify the ExclamationBolt to dynamically create a favoritesMap when
a name, favorites tuple is received from your MyLikesSpout.
I also give you a few syntax hints if you need them in the written instructions.
Next, if a tuple from the MyNamesSpout is received,
check your favoritesMap that you've created and see if it exists, and
if so, emit the sentence, NAME's favorite is FOURITE.
Append three exclamation marks to the end of your sentence and build and
run your topology.
Once your basic visualization is running with name and
favorites dynamically joined using a streaming join and
three exclamation marks appended, it's time to move on to stage six.
Connect your ReportBolt to exclaim2.
Modify the ExclamationBolt again to append three more exclamation points for
a total of six.
Finally, build and submit your visualization.
After your visualization is running and
six exclamation marks are appended at the end of your sentences,
all using the single ExclamationBolt, in step seven, simply change
the my like spout and my name spout to omit names and favorites of your own.
Or change the ExclamationBolt as well to omit sentences of your choice.
And finally if you like, take a final screen shot or
video and post it to the forum.
Comment on two other posts and how about posting to your Twitter followers.
Good luck with this final programming assignment.