In the previous lessons,
we discussed several mechanisms for
Inter-process Communication.
But we said that these were fairly
low-level mechanisms because
they focused on providing
the basic capability for
moving data among address spaces.
And didn't really specify anything about
the semantics of those operations or
the protocols that are involved.
In this lesson we will talk about
Remote Procedure Calls, or RPC.
This is an IPC mechanism
that specifies that the processes
interact via procedure call interface.
For the general discussion of RPCs,
we will roughly follow Birrell and
Nelson's paper,
Implementing Remote Procedure Calls.
This is an older paper, but
it discusses very nicely
the general design space of RPC.
Then, we will discuss
in more detail Sun RPC.
It's a concrete implementation
of an RPC system,
that's common in
operating systems today.