Another popular type of
RPC-like system is Java RMI,
Java Remote Method Invocations.
It's also pioneered by Sun as a form
of client-server communication method,
among address spaces in
the Java virtual machine.
Java is an object-oriented
language where objects interact
via method invocations and
not via procedure calls.
For this reason, this inter-process
communication mechanism matches the Java
object-oriented semantics as in
the form of remote method invocations.
Its architecture is similar to what we
saw with the remote procedure calls.
Client and server processes have
client-side stubs and server-side stubs.
The server-side stub is
referred to as a skeleton.
In the Java virtual machines,
all of the processes, all clients and
all servers, are written in
the Java programming language.
For that reason,
the interface definition language for
the Java RMIs is also Java.
It doesn't make sense to adopt a
different interface definition language,
like in the case of XDR for
RPC, where in this case, everything will
be written in Java in the first place.
So RMI uses a language-specific
interface definition language choice.
And in this case, that's Java.
The runtime layer is separated
into two components,
the remote reference layer and
the transport layer.
This bottom layer implements all
of the transport protocol related
functionality.
This can be TCP, UDP,
shared memory based communications
if the two processes are running
on the same machine.
Above that is the remote
reference layer.
This component captures all of
the common code that's needed
to provide different
reference semantics.
For instance, it can support unicast,
where a client interacts with
a single server, like what we
had in the previous examples.
But RMI can be used for other types
of server reference semantics.
For instance, with broadcast, the client
will contact multiple servers.
And then the reference semantics
can be such that it will return
only once the first response arrives, or
only when all of the responses
arrive and the responses match.
It also makes sense to design other
types of reference semantics.
These are not the exclusive list.
Regardless of the underlying
transport protocol,
this type of functionality will
be implemented in a similar way.
So RMI separates it and
captures it in a separate component,
this remote reference layer.
As a developer, you can either just
specify the reference semantics you want
from the RMI interactions and
the system will take care of the rest.
Or if you want something exotic, you
can implement just this component and
the rest of the system
can remain the same.
We're mentioning in this lesson
Java RMIs just for completeness.
We're not going to
discuss it in any detail.
If you would like to know more,
visit the resources that are linked
in from the instructor's notes.