All right, well done.
Now let's hop back
into Android Studio and
take a look at the solution for
this quiz.
All right, first,
let's look at our applyFilter method.
See the instructor notes for
the code snippet, specifically.
Now here, we call checkForPower and
if it returns that the phone is not
charging, we then change the text to
inform the user to plug in their phone
and return before completing the method.
Simple enough.
All right, let's take a look at
the logic within checkForPower.
Again, see the instructor notes for
the code snippet.
Okay, so
here we are within checkForPower.
Now the first thing we do is we set
an intent filter to describe for
changes to the battery state.
And then we actually get an integer,
right here,
representing the battery
plugged in status.
We then compare this
integer to various constants
within the BatteryManager class.
For instance, one for whether it's
charging via AC or alternating current.
This means it's plugged into the wall.
Another for USB.
And finally,
whether it's charging via wireless.
We wrap the wireless check in an if
statement to make sure that the SDK
build version is high enough.
And then finally, if it was charging via
USB, AC, or wireless, we return true.
Otherwise, false.