Here are the claims that
are definitely true.
The adoption step is pointer jumping.
Wee!
However, the method is not work optimal.
This outer loop of log n iterations
is the root of the problem.
No pun intended.
That pun was obviously intended.
What about the span?
Well the span is polylogarithmic.
This outer sequential loop
is polylogrythmic and
the parallel four loops of
adopt are polylogrythmic.
Now what about this claim,
works on a forest, not just one tree.
That is in fact a feature
of the algorithm.
An array pool might contain
a forest rather than a single tree.
So this procedure would make every node
point to the root of it's own tree.
That's kind of neat.