It's now time to connect your topology, to the real time Twitter sample stream.
To do this, we need to obtain actual Twitter credentials.
So, in step one navigate to twitter.com, and
either create an account or log in, here.
So, you can either sign in, or sign up for Twitter.
I'll simply sign in with my username, which is Lewis@udacity.
Now once you're signed in you can go to a new window, and
following the reading instructions in step two navigate to apps.twitter.com.
You can see here I already have one app created, but for you,
you would create go to the upper-righthand corner and click on Create New App.
In step four, enter the name of your app this could be your
name-udacity-twitter-storm for the description
you can put in udacity and twitter course real time analytics with apache storm.
Here in the website, put in the fully qualified URL address, and
you can use http://www.udacity.com/ud381.
Next, scroll down to the developer rules of the road and
read through these very carefully.
And finally click on Yes, I agree, and create your Twitter application.
So, here in Details, Settings, Keys and
Access Tokens, click on the tab Keys and Access Tokens.
Once your consumer key and consumer secret keys are shown, copy and
paste these into either a text editor,
or directly into a topology in the order they are provided.
Once your consumer key and consumer secret are copied and stored safely,
scroll down and click on create my access token at the bottom of the page.
Finally, once your status is updated scroll all the way down and
copy your access token and access token secrets.
Remember to copy them in order, so
you have your consumer key consumer secret access token and access token secret.
Finally remember that the key going to be entered in the topology builder phase
and one caveat if your uploading and sharing your project publicly on Github or
Bitbucket, remember to always delete your secret keys.
These keys should remain secret only to you.
Congratulations on obtaining your credentials,
please continue on with the course.