Now let’s look at yet another case.
This is case three now.
So here we have a similar thing in that the user level thread that’s currently
executing on top the kernel level thread where the signal actually occurs,
this user level thread has the signal disabled.
In the process overall,
there is another user level thread that has the signal enabled.
And unlike in the previous case when this user level thread was just on
the run queue, now in this case this user level thread
is currently running on another kernel level thread on another CPU.
So when the signal is delivered in the context of this kernel level thread,
the library handling routine will kick in.
The library handling routine knows that there is a user level thread in
the system that can handle this particular signal.
And it sees that this user level thread is currently associated,
it's executing on top of a kernel level thread,
or rather a lightweight process that's managed by the threading library.
Since the library knows this, the library will
then generate a directed signal to the other kernel level thread
to the lightweight process where the user level thread currently is executing.
When the OS delivers the signal to this particular kernel level thread,
it sees signal mask enabled.
Great.
And it moves up.
Now technically it will still go into the library handling routine first, right?
Because that's a wrapper for all of the signal handlers.
Here the library handling routine will see grade at a current user level
thread that's running in the context of this kernel level thread.
Can handle the particular signal of the signal and so
it finally will allow the execution of the signal handler.