So I'm on the Mozilla developer
network and I have a list of inputs.
I see a few relevant inputs like date,
datetime and datetime-local.
datetime and datetime-local
are both really useful, but
they both obviously include times.
Given that there's a separate input for
time in this quiz,
I want to go with date.
So I'll scroll down, and there is time.
Well, that's pretty straightforward.
This is what the form looks like
before you enter date and time.
You'll notice that these two
are just defaulted to text inputs.
And then after you enter date and time
for the types, you will see that now
you have a nice date selector for dates,
and a nice time selector for time.
That looks pretty good.