I'm here in the shopping
lists fragment class.
When you click on an item
on the shopping list screen
this code here triggers.
Get ref is a method in
firebase list adapter
that returns the firebase
reference of an item.
The key of the shopping
list is the push ID.
So you can use get ref and get key
together to get the push ID and then
pass it to ActiveListDetailsActivity
as an intent extra here.
Opening up ActiveListDetailsActivity
here, and scrolling down, we see
the first thing we do is grab that push
ID from the intent, use it here to make
the fire base reference, and then attach
a value event listener to that location.
So this ensures that we're listening
in the appropriate location.
Now you're also going to want
to make sure that the dialog for
editing the list name works.
If you look at the edit
list name dialog fragment,
you see it extends this
edit list dialog fragment.
This is a super class that I made that
abstracts out some of the common methods
setup and variables that
are needed by the edit list name,
edit list item name and
add list item dialogue fragments.
Since all of these classes edit
a single shopping list in one way or
another, they will all need
the push ID eventually.
So I'm going to open up this edit
list dialog fragment super class.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And what you should of done is in
this new instance helper here,
added the list ID as something that
gets passed into the super class.
And then down here in the onCreate
I'm setting a member variable
to that list ID.
So basically in all those classes
that then extend this super class,
I have mListId available to me.
I know you didn't write this code, but
hopefully the connection between
the dialog fragments makes sense now.
So going back to making sure that
EditListNameDialogFragment works,
I'm back here in that class.
I'm going to scroll down, and
doListEdit is the method that
gets called when the positive
button gets clicked.
And again, this is something
that's set up by the super class.
And we can see that I'm using the
mListId here and generating the correct
reference that you need to be
able to update that list name.