The first thing you need to do is to
get the list of Geofences that you
may have triggered.
So you can just create a list
of Geofence and call it,
triggeringGeofences.
To get them,
the geofencingEvent has a method that
returns them in this data structure.
Check the documentation to see if
you can find it and enter it here.
When you have the list
of Geofence objects,
you'll note that each Geofence object
has a request ID associated with it.
Again, can you figure out what
the method is to return this request ID?
Now, write a helper function that
takes this list of Geofences and
concatenates all of their
IDs into a single string.
Call this helper function,
getGeofenceTransitionDetails.
When you're done creating it,
check this box.