Here are the answers.
Breadth-first search,
as the name implies,
expands nodes in this order,
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7.
So it's going across a stripe at a time,
breadth first.
Is it optimal?
Well, it's always expanding
the shortest paths first.
And so wherever the goal is hiding,
it's going to find it by
examining no longer paths.
So in fact, it is optimal.
Cheapest-first.
First we expand the path of length 0,
then the path of length 2, now there's
a path of length 4, path of length 5,
path of length 6, a path of length 7,
and finally, a path of length 8.
And as we've seen, it's guaranteed
to find the cheapest path of all
assuming that all the individual
step costs are non-negative.
Depth-first search tries to
go as deep as it can first.
So it goes 1, 2, 3, then backs up,
4, then backs up, 5, 6, 7.
And you can see that it doesn't
necessarily find the shortest path of
all.
Let's say that there were goals
in position 5 and in position 3,
it would find the longer path to
position 3 and find the goal there, and
would not find the goal in position
five, so it is not optimal.
[BLANK_AUDIO]