Now, we are going to look at the mean square error and
the bias variants trade off.
Remember, we had the risk function given as this expression.
The integral expression here denotes the expectation value of the loss function.
Now, let's define y as the true value and f hat of x knot as the estimated
value evaluated at x knot for this value of y which is the true value.
We can now calculate the expectation value of the square error loss.
The expectation value of the square error loss.
Is given as the expectation value of this expression in here, which is the true
value minus the estimated value at x not squared, evaluated at x not.
We can now work out this expression.
And you will get the following expression.
This term here is the irreducible error.
This term here is the square of the bias.
And this term here is the variance.
Now let us inspect each of these terms separately.
Remember the irreducible error is this first term.
It comes from the variance around the true mean inherent in the data.
It is very difficult to get rid off the irreducible error, hence the name,
through the modeling process.
We have also seen how bias and variance, plays into how one can select a model.
For non parametric models, like histograms and kernel density estimators.
In lesson three, we discussed the role the bin size or
bandwidth plays in determining the variance and bias of the model.
Our goal is to minimize the square error loss.
This, in turn, means that we are minimizing the bias term of the variance term.
The problem is,
minimizing both is not always possible due to the complexity of the model.
We will look at this problem, thus we have a situation where we have
to have a trade-off, between minimizing the bias square, or the variance turn.
This is what is refered to as the bias variance trade-off.
The goal in statistical and
machine learning models is to minimize the loss function, and in turn, the risk.
You may recall an introduction to machine learning class,
how the cost function was defined and minimized to converge to a model.
Notice it is simply the use of the least square loss function.
Although we often choose the square loss in statistical learning,
you must understand that you are in complete control of the way you
choose your model through the choice of the loss function.
Our decision is also based on how well we
want the model to fit the data measured by the variance, versus how
well we want the model to generalize to new data, which is measured by the bias.
Remember, there's always the bias variance straight off.
The cost function can be calculated.
On the training data set, the validation data set, or the test data set.
Minimizing each of these cost functions serve to optimize the model for
different purposes.
Let's take a look at the cost function calculated on
the training set versus this test set.
The following example is taken from a book named The Elements of
Statistical Learning.
Please see the instructor's notes for more details on the book.
Let's take a look at the following diagram.
What we have on the X-axis here, is model complexity.
Think of it as the number of variables in your model.
On the Y axis we have the prediction error.
The red lines here, represent the error, calculated on the test data set.
The blue lines here,
represent the prediction errors calculated on the training data set.
Notice how the error on the training data set
reduces as the complexity of the model goes up.
However, this is not the case for
the prediction error calculated on the test data set.
The solid curves here represent the expected values of all
the prediction error curves.
The model complexity can be thought of as the number of
features in the model being used.
Intuitively you may already have an idea.
Of chow the number of feature can affect the way your generalization or
prediction error can be affected.
A less complex model with a low number of features will have low variance and
high bias and we might end up under fitting the model.
In contrast, a more complex model will have high number of features,
resulting in high variance, a low bias.
And thus, will be overfit.
Remember, always, the tradeoff between the bias and the variance.
In the next video, we will try to quantify the complexity of a model.
And look at bounds on the training and
testers that we can calculate on the samples.