Understanding how to make
a great performing app has
everything to do with understanding
what's going on under the hood.
See, if you don't know how
the hardware's working you've got a good
chance of using it poorly.
Now the main question is this.
How does your activity actually
get drawn to the screen?
Or rather how does all
that crazy XML and
markup language turn into pixels
the user can see and understand?
At its core, this is done with
a process known as rasterization.
This is the process of taking some high
level object like a string or a button
or a path or a shape and turning it into
pixels in a texture or on your screen.
Now rasterization is a really,
really time consuming process.
And as such, there's a special piece
of hardware in your mobile device
that's designed to make
it happen a lot faster.
The graphics processing unit, or
GPU, was introduced to mainstream
computers back in the early 90s, to help
accelerate the rasterization process.
Now, the GPU itself is designed to
use a specific set of primitives.
Dominantly that is polygons and
textures, a.k.a, images.
And your CPU is responsible for
feeding these primitives to your GPU
before it can draw
anything to the screen.
This is done through a common API
on Android known as OpenGL ES,
which means that anytime your UI
objects, like buttons or paths or check
boxes, need to be drawn to the screen,
they're first converted to polygons and
textures on the CPU, and
then passed off to the GPU to rasterize.
And, as you would imagine,
this process of converting a UI
object to a set of polygons and textures
is not the fastest of operations.
Likewise, actually
uploading that process data
from the CPU to the GPU
isn't that fast either.
So it makes sense then that you'd want
to reduce the number of times you have
to convert an object,
as well as the number of times you
have to upload it for drawing.
Thankfully, the OpenGL ES API allows
you to upload content to the GPU and
then leave it there.
When you'd like to reference drawing
a button again in the future,
you simply have to reference
it in GPU memory, and
then tell OpenGL how to
go about drawing it.
The general rule of thumb is this.
Optimizing for rendering performance
means getting as much data
onto the GPU as fast as possible, and
then leave it there without modifying
it for as long as possible.
Because every time you update
a resource on the GPU,
you lose precious processing time.
Now, since the release of the Honeycomb
version of Android, the entire UI
rendering system works with the GPU,
and with every release since then,
more improvements have been made to
the rendering system performance.
The Android system does a lot, and,
and I mean a lot of work to reduce,
reuse, and
recycle GPU resources on your behalf so
that you really don't
have to think about it.
For example, any resources that are
provided by your theme, that is Bitmaps
and drawables, et cetera, are all
grouped together into a single texture,
and then uploaded to the GPU on your
behalf alongside commonly used meshes,
like Nine Patches for instance.
This means that you, anytime you
need to draw one of these resources,
you don't have to do any conversions.
See, all the content is
already stored on the GPU,
making these type of views
really fast to display.
However this whole rendering
process gets more and
more complex as your UI objects
get more and more advanced.
Take for example, displaying images.
This actually means uploading the image
on to the CPU into its memory and
then passing it off
to the GPU to render.
Using paths is a whole separate mess.
As you might need to create
a chain of polygons in the CPU or
even create a masking texture to
define the path shape on the GPU.
Now, drawing text is a complete
double whammy, right?
I mean first, we have to draw
the characters in the CPU to an image,
and then upload that image to the GPU,
and then go back through and
draw a rectangle on the screen for
each character in our string.
Now, the performance of those operations
are mostly handled by the Android system
on your app's behalf, and
unless you're doing something excessive,
you really shouldn't see
much of a GPU problem there.
However, there's one GPU
performance bottleneck
that challenges every
single developer equally.
It's called overdraw.