Before we make everything beautiful a couple of reminders.
Actually this is the, the first reminder.
Or an aside, I should say.
And it's about cross product.
The second one's about cross product, too, but.
So the first one is to remember that a cross product.
So a cross b gives you a new vector, c.
And that vector c has the property of being perpendicular to both a and b.
So it's in the direction that's perpendicular.
And you may also remember that the magnitude of that vector is equal to
the sine of the angles between them.
Which should make you realize right away that if I
take any vector a across itself, that's going to be zero.
Because the angle between a vector and itself is zero, the sine is zero.
So, a cross a is 0 no matter what a is.
Okay?
So a cross b gives you c, c being perpendicular to a and b.
And a cross a is equal to 0 no matter what.