As we've seen,
there's a small problem with this app.
When I try to send a message,
nothing's happening in the database.
Looking at the console message,
setValue or removeValue, failed,
permission_denied, that
gives us some clue.
And, if we go back to the Firebase
Console and to the Database tab,
we can find another clue.
Here at the top it reads,
Default security rules require
users to be authenticated.
The security rules refer to
Firebase's security rules file,
which can also be seen in this tab,
just click rules.
These rules are use to control which
users can access information on
the database.
There's a rule for handling who
can read data from the database.
And there's a rule for
handling who can write to the database.
By default, these rules are set so
that users can read from and write to
the database if they're authenticated,
aka, if they're logged in.
But we haven't implemented
the login functionality yet.
So it's impossible to get the app into
a state where a user can read or write.
We're going to talk more about
authentication later on.
But for now, we can change these rules
so we can quickly experiment and
test the Friendly Chat app.
I want to set the read and
write rules to true.
This should allow anyone using the app
to read and write to the database.
But I should emphasize, you should
never set these rules to true for
a production application.
It makes it possible for a savvy user
with a bit of programing experience
to do anything to your database,
including read the entire database,
and maybe erase all of the data.
So setting read and write to true is for
development purposes only.
With that said, I'll select PUBLISH.
I'll go back to the app and
try to send some messages again.
So I'm going to type hello and
I'll click SEND.
And I'm not seeing anything in
the output here, so, so far so good.
And for good measure,
let's send another hello.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Also not seeing anything in
the console here, so that looks good.
If I jump back to the Firebase console,
I can see messages showing
up in the database.
Awesome, congratulations, you just wrote
your first messages to the database.
Isn't that cool?
Our structure starts
with a messages node,
which then contains a list
of individual message nodes.
The paths we see here are the same
paths we configured in our code with
the database reference.
Each individual message can be
considered as a child of messages.
You can also see the random ID
that identifies each message.
Recall that every time data
is pushed to the database,
a unique ID is created as a key for
the data.
So even though I said hello twice, the
database knows that these two messages
are different, and
that’s because of the unique ID.
If we look at each message individually,
they consist of a name key value pair,
and a text key value pair.
Right now, all messages show our name
as a anonymous because we haven't
started authenticating users yet.
You'll learn how to do this shortly
when we talk about authentication.
For now, we'll remain anonymous.
Great, Friendly Chat now sounds
messages to the database.
The next task is to read messages
that are in the database.