So that's the end of this lesson.
You will undoubtedly go back and
look at this pretty carefully since this algorithm and the manipulation of data
sets are going to serve as the basis of the first part of the Hough problem set.
And when you look up this stuff on the web,
which many of you will you'll want to relate that back to what we've seen here.
And I'll tell you this,
implementing the Hough transform feels relatively straightforward.
That's why people, when it was on a course where the problem set was
due Sunday night at 11:55 p.m.,
many of them started at around 6:00 p.m.
They later reported that it
took them more like ten hours to do this problem set.
And that's because the extensions and so, etc.
Nothing quite works exactly like I say it does.
That by the way, is going to be a lesson of this class.
The papers, first, what we say in class never works.
because it's a distillation of the simple stuff.
What we say in papers hardly ever works,
because we have to make it very you know, sound great for publication.
In reality, stuff works, you take the theory and
then you have to massage both the imagery and the al and the algorithms.