So what if you organized
the reduction DAG as a tree?
Now we need a specific
technical assumption,
which is called associativity.
That is,
assume that a + (b + c) = (a + b) + c.
In other words, assume that you can
put parenthesis wherever you want and
you'll still get the same answer.
Let's start by writing down
the end loads, just as before.
Then, let's add pairs of inputs.
Then, let's add pairs of
these intermediate results.
And let's keep going until
the final sum remains.
Here's my question: if I give you
a PRAM with P = n processors,
what's the minimum time it could
possibly take to execute this DAG?
Let's do this as multiple choice.
Here are your options.
Constant time, log time, linear time,
and log n time or n squared time.
Choose one.