The answer is Greenwich Mean Time.
You may have noticed that Greenwich
Mean Time has no offset from UTC.
This is because
Greenwich Mean Time now is UTC.
The reference line, the prime meridian,
was determined to be in London.
So UTC was created as
a scientifically defined standard.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
By the way, that coordinate you just
looked up is actually the set of
Diagon Alley in the UK.
It's awesome.
You can check it out
on Google Street View.
Even if you aren't making
magical trips to Diagon Alley.
A global audience on your site can
benefit from the Time Zone API.
Converting times or
schedules to a user's specific location
can deliver a much
better local experience.
Speaking of which,
how can we use Google's APIs to
actually retrieve a location?
We'll look at the Geolocation API next.