Now schedule is defined in terms of specifying for every task in the network
the earliest start that, which we'll call "ES," and the latest possible start time,
which we call "LS" for which it's possible to complete the task network
in the shortest possible total amount of time.
We can define these with a set of recursive formulas
which can be solved by dynamic programming.
The earliest start time of the start state is defined as being zero.
The earliest start time of any state B is defined as being the maximum over all As
which have an arrow leading into B--
that is all As that are defined to be predecessors of B--
of the earliest start time of A plus the duration of A.
For example, the earliest start time of this state here would be the maximum
over all the ones that are coming in, which is only this one.
The maximum of its start time, which will be here, plus its duration, which would be 30.
Then the latest start time is defined by saying the latest start time of the finish,
is the same as the earliest start time of the finish,
because the finish by itself has no duration--
it's just there to give us a point to end at.
The latest start time in general of any node A
is the minimum over all B which come after A,
of the latest start time of B minus the duration of A.
These formulas together define a unique schedule, which is the fastest possible schedule.
What I want you to do is fill in for me in the upper left hand the earliest start time,
in the upper right the latest start time for each of these nodes.
Here I've zoomed in a bit just to give you a little bit more room to fill in the blanks.