We're very sensitive to this structure of parallel lines and
what they convey to us.
Now, most of you have seen this Muller-Lyer illusion,
right, of which one of these lines is longer?
And you probably all know that well, actually, they're the same length, and
you probably saw that back in grade school and it's kind of cool.
Let me show you another version of it that shows you why this
can be an interesting effect.
Okay, so here we have a picture, okay?
And you can see the red arrow in here and the same red arrow in there.
And let me take that away.
And now the question is, which of those is longer?
And that one's a lot harder to, for you to say that, you know what?
They're actually the same length.
So you go back there.
In fact, when you pull them away, when I stare at them,
they look like they're different length.
But of course they're actually length.
And that's because you're using this perspective projection as a way of
saying that in the real world, okay, the distance from
here to here is more than the distance from here to there actually.
All right?
That is, this is the height of the whole wall.
This is just the height of the ticket window.
So, it looks the same on your image, but
your brain automatically wants to undo that projection transformation.