[Thrun] You can also learn the transition probabilities of a Markov chain like this
from actual data.
Suppose you look out of the window and see sequences of rainy days
followed by sunny days followed by rainy days
and you wonder what numbers to put here, here, here, and here.
Let me assume you see a sequence rain, sun, sun, sun, rain, sun, and rain.
These are, in total, 7 different days,
and we wish to estimate all those probabilities over here,
including the initial distribution for the first day using maximum likelihood.
You might remember all this work with Laplace smoothing,
but for now we keep it simple, just maximum likelihood.
We find for day 0 we had rain, and maximum likelihood would just say
the probability for day 0 is 1.
That's the most likely estimate.
Then for the transition probability we find we transition from rain
to something else twice here.
We sometimes transition to sun and sometimes stay in rain.
In both of the transitions we go from rain to sun. There is no instance of rain to rain.
So maximum likelihood gives us over here a 1 and this over here 0.
And finally, we can also ask the question what happens from a sunny state.
We transition to a new sunny state or a rainy state,
and those distributions are easily calculated.
We have 4 transitioning out of a sunny state to something else--
this one, this one, this one, and this one.
Twice it goes to sunny over here and over here,
twice it goes to rainy over here and over here,
so therefore the probability for either transition is 0.5.
So we have 0.5 over here, 0.5 over here, 1 over here, and 0 over here
for the transition probabilities.