In this example,
we'll start to build a common UI.
We'll start with a row of an input form.
We'll have a label and a text field, and
it should stay at the top and
take all the available width.
We'll learn how to position a stack
view containing these items, and
also how to preview this
UI in different devices.
Let's get started by dragging
a label and a text field.
Now, let's put them into the stack view.
The sizes have changed, but
now we understand why it happened.
The label was resized to
intrinsic content size.
The text field, as it's empty
was given a default value for
it's intrinsic content size and
was resized accordingly.
Now, let's add two constraints
to the stack view.
First, I'll stick it to the top,
the boarder of the stack view
became red to warn us, the horizontal
position is undefined or ambiguous.
No problem, let's fix it by
sticking it to one of the sides.
Now, auto layout seems to be happy.
In the next video,
we'll learn more about constraints and
we'll make some changes to
the one that we just created.