This is great. Now you have your recordAudio
function executed every time
the user presses the Record audio button.
This is an example of going from a user
face element, in this case the Record
button to your code using an IBAction.
But what about going the other way
around, from code to a user interface element?
Maybe we want to disable or
enable button, or maybe we want to change
the text of a label. When you want to go
from code to a UI element, we’ll use a
connection called an IBOutlet, otherwise
known as an outlet from the code to the
UI element. Let's add one of those in now.
I’ll stop our simulator and I’m going to
go back to our AppDelegate. I’m going to
remove our print(“hello, world”) statement,
because we don't need it anymore.
And then let's go back to our Main.storyboard
we’ll hide the debug area. we'll go
back to our standard editor view and
will reveal the utilities panel. And we
need to add some new UI elements.
I'll clear out our filter and I’m going to
scroll down to a label and let's drag a
label into our view. I’ll drag it below
our Record button and let the blue lines
kind of guide me at least for now.
And in the attributes inspector, let's
change the text from Label to Tap to Record.
And then in the interface editor,
I’m going to drag it out, so that we can
see all the texts. And reposition it in
the center. Next I’m going to drag over
another UIButton and I’ll also try to
center it here. There we go. And let's change
the button’s text to Stop Recording and
also drag it out so we can see all the
text and kind of centered up. We'll
worry about the layout later, so that's
not super important.
Now pay attention, because here comes the
unintuitive part. We want to make
connection from the code to a UI element,
in this case the Tap to Record label.
Let's hide away the utilities and go
back to the assistant editor. Now in the
document outline, select the Tap to
Record label and then hold down the control
key and click drag from the Tap to
Record label to our ViewController.swift
file over here on the right.
This time let's place it above our
functions, above this viewDidLoad
function that we have already. And we’ll
let go and in the dialog that appears, we
want Outlet and then let's set the name
to RecordingLabel. Give ourselves a
little space and you can see that Xcode
has created an outlet linking the UI
element into our code. And now we can use
this IBOutlet to change the text after
the Record button was pressed,
specifically what we want is for the
text of the recording label to change
when the Record button was pressed.
Now we already know that this function
recordAudio gets called when the
recording button is pressed. That's the
function that we wired up earlier as an
IBAction.
Add the following line to the recordAudio
function to change the text of the
label to Recording in Progress. If we
run the app now and press the Record
audio button, we should see the text of
the label change to Recording in
Progress. So let's run to test this.
Right now the controls that we added have not
been positioned correctly, but that's ok,
we should still be able to test this.
Let's click on our button and we can see
that the text for the label has changed.
Our interface may look a little wacky,
but now we've used a IBAction to
receive an interaction event on our
button, and then we've used an IBOutlet
to reach back to a UI element, in this
case the label and changes text.
Great job