Now it's your turn again.
Take a look at width in the Knockout documentation to see if
there's a way to make a reset HTML changes a little bit simpler.
We want to avoid seeing current cat again and again and again and
again in our HTML.
Now this one might require a little bit of extra research.
You'll have changes here in your HTML and
also likely in your app dot js in the increment counter function.
You'll find the documentation page for with in the instructor notes.
Take a look at that documentation and
their examples to wrap your mind around what with is for.
And if you're having trouble with your bindings,
I'd also recommend giving Knockout's page on binding contexts a read.
That link is also in the instructor notes.