So here's the solution to this exercise.
For our first scenario here, where we
need to update an existing pet and
we're give its ID, we can go ahead and
use option B where we
specify the ID in the URI.
And that's the same situation for
our delete scenario here where we're
deleting existing pet and
we know its ID.
So we can go ahead and also use
option B where we know the ID given.
Next in EditorActivity,
if you want to save a new pet though,
perhaps you going to use option A and
this is because
we're using a general pet URI in
order to save off a brand new pet.
So next in the CatalogActivity,
when we need to insert a new dummy pet,
we will actually be using option
A because similarly, we'll also be using
the general pet content URI to
insert new pet information.
And lastly, to delete all the pets,
we'll need option A to grab the whole
table and
remove all the information from it.
So the two trickiest once here
might have been these two for you.
Saving a new pet and then inserting
new dummy pet information.
And the reason that these two use option
A is that because these don't have
any URIs for
that pet available just yet.
So we need to use the general pet
content URI to access
the whole table as we see here