In summary, user/kernel transitions are a necessary step
during application execution.
Applications may need to perform access to certain types of hardware.
Or, may need to request change in the allocations of
hardware resources that have been made to them.
Only the operating system,
the kernel, are allowed to perform those types of operations.
The hardware provides support for performing user/kernel transitions.
We explain that the hardware will cause a trap if the application from
unprivileged mode tries to perform some instruction, or
a memory access for which it doesn't have permissions.
For instance, the application cannot change the contents of certain registers,
and give itself more CPU, or more memory.
Only the operating system can do that.
The result of this trap is that the hardware initiates transfer of
the control to the operating system,
to the kernel, and marks this by that special privilege bit that we mentioned.
At that point, once control is passed over to the operating system,
the operating system can check what caused the trap, and
determine what's the appropriate thing to do.
Whether to grant or
deny the specific request that caused the trap to occur in the first place.
This will, of course,
depend on the policies that are supported by the operating system.
Performing all of this, despite of the fact that hardware provides support,
still takes a number of instructions.
For instance, on a two gigahertz machine running Linux,it can
take 50 to 100 nanoseconds to perform all the operations that
are necessary around a user/kernel transition.
This is real time, real overhead for the system.
The other problem with these transitions is they affect the hardware
cache usage.
The application performance is very dependent on the ability to
use the hardware cache.
If accessing cache is order a few cycles,
accessing memory can be order of hundreds of cycles.
When we perform a system call, or
in general when we cross into the operating system, the operating system,
while executing, will likely bring content that it needs in the cache.
This will replace some of the application content that was in
the hardware cache before that transition was performed.
And, so this will have some impact on the application performance,
because it will no longer be able to access its data in cache,
it will have to go to memory.
In summary, these user/kernel transitions, they're not cheap.