This is a tricky question,
because it turns out that the occlusion answer is better than the bad match answer.
If you were to correspond each pixel in the left scan line
straight to each pixel in the right scan line,
you find that the total penalty will be 20,
because there's one bad match between the black pixel over here and the red pixel here.
However, you can also correspond as follows.
You end up paying two occlusion penalties for this guy over here and this guy over here.
Because the occlusion penalty is only 5, you pay only a total of 10 as a penalty,
which is better than a single bad match penalty.
As a result, this would've been the right answer over here.