Okay, so the Melissa virus actually
did the following, it sent email.
So once it infected a computer,
it'll find your address book and
send an email to everybody else.
And as these emails got to people and
more computers got infected, of course,
more and more emails got sent.
As a result essentially servers and
various networks were saturated with
the traffic that we generated because of
this and they basically became unusable.
So it was abuse where it
wasn't destruction of data,
that wasn't what this virus was doing,
but it was consuming resources and
sending all these
irrelevant email messages.
Because of it we authorized
people who were not able
to use the systems and the network.
So the fact that you did something
such that, that was unauthorized
obviously what you did, the fact that
you made these computers unusable.
That was the reason this person
was actually sentenced to
something like several years in jail and
fined.
Again it's not destructions of data but
it's essentially exhaustion of resources
through this denial-of-service attack
which makes the system essentially
unavailable to everybody else.