ok so now I've taken a grayscale dimage
and using edge detection turned it into
an image full of dots but only the dots
that represent edges in the original
image now let's connect the dots
I could connect the dots to look for any
kind of shape in my image but in this
case I'm looking for lines defined lines
i need to first adopt a model of a line
and then fit that model to the
assortment of dots in my edge detected
image keeping in mind that my image is
just a function of x and y i can use the
old familiar equation of a line y equals
MX plus B in this case my model includes
two parameters m and B in image space a
line is plotted as X versus Y but in
parameter space which we will call space
i can represent that same line as
Emerson's be instead the hough transform
is just the conversion from image space
to have space so the characterization of
a line image space will be a single
point at the position mb in half space