Most apps interact with
the Internet in some way.
They almost always need a place
to store information going to and
from the user, as in a database.
Firebase provides a realtime database
that's easy to set up and use.
We're going to talk about how
the Firebase Database handles data and
provide suggestions on
how you can use it.
Then we will write app code to talk
with the Friendly Chat database so
that you can get hands
on experience with it.
Finally, we will look
at best practices for
data structures that will keep your
apps snappy with realtime access.
I'm going to be talking a lot of
the Firebase Realtime Database.
So from here on,
I'll just call it the database.
Remember, I'm referring to
the Firebase Realtime Database, and
not just any database.
because there are many other types of
databases out there, but ours is unique.