So to further improve the user
experience of the app,
we need to think about
touch feedback for
anything that is clickable in our app,
and that refers to the feedback
that we get from the user interface when
they touch something that's clickable.
Now before we discuss the topic further,
I'm going to let you experiment on
your own with the main activity.
So first, I like you to temporarily set
the background of the numbers category
TextView to be this selectable item
background value, which was defined in
the Android framework and while you're
at it change the text color to be black.
So the text is easier to read and
here's what those changes will look
like in your main activity xml file.
After you've made these changes,
run the app on your device and
describe what you observed when
you click on the numbers category.
So how is this different
from clicking on
other categories in the main activity?