a very first project in the self-driving
candle will be to find lane markings
why is that important but i can tell you
if you can't find the markings you will
have no clue where to drive you probably
don't pay much attention to him as a
self-advocate engineer they become your
best friend
they tell you a lot yesterday to drive
we're here at rolling me instead our
learning problem with copy and cologne
you would behave yourselves are steering
actions and brake gas actions and you
get a chance to try it on yard when we
train people who don't train them even
the rules between environmental examples
so this unit you want to apply for that
works deep learning to Cameron ridges
and do some the very things in the
surface are to the right
what is computer vision but you and i
drive a car we use our is more than any
other woman to understand what to do
division this is the same capability
into computers use cameras and we learn
how to extract things like markings and
other vehicles lot of cameras
it's a lot of fun and they're really
excited to get into the world of sensor
fusion or sensor fusion is the science
how to integrate different types of
sensors south africa's have things like
lighters and they have Raiders and also
cameras and the internal sensors
controller scopes and inertial
measurement units sensor fusion is the
science how to color with a single
Korean picture based on these different
modalities organization is the simple
question where relative to the world is
a
and it's important because as you're
going to see you in a bit maps on the
environment lots of detailed information
some of it might even be invisible to
the robot leg where the danger zones
where do pedestrians typically cross and
to make sense of those Maps one must
know where it is right for the neck and
the alignment of the sensor data current
position to a map that's what's called
an opposition so now we're entering the
fascinating world of what's called
control in technical terms of the
controller does it's a computer program
that steers your wheels you're gasping
your brake pedal so as to me given
objective so for example if your
objective is to stay centered in the
boat and you start driving and your cart
is little to the left your controller is
the unit decides okay we accomplish it
with a slight writer the seal that might
sound trivial but it's really easy to
screw it up half bending is the science
of how to find a valid sequence of steps
for instance in amazed when you weren't
stuck in manhattan for example even
across the city you have to find a plan
a sequence of streets you want to go
down to make it all the way in the end a
path planning algorithm isn't i wouldnt
that finds that sequence of actions for
you we can apply to city navigation can
also apply to part interrogation order
for example across the parking lot
so now we're ready for the most
fascinating part of this telling me you
would take your quote on to a physical
car and drive around in California
sounds scary
yes some slightly scared but also really
excited because there's no great number
that we would be complete actually
writing finding actual software actually
cars so let's do it