And the correct answer is 0.043.
So, even though I received a positive test,
my probability of having cancer is just 4.3%,
which is not very much given that the test itself is quite sensitive.
It really gives me a 0.8 chance of getting a negative result if I don't have cancer.
It gives me a 0.9 chance of detecting cancer given that I have cancer.
Now, what comes (inaudible) small?
Well, let's just put all the cases together.
You already know that we received a positive test.
Therefore, this entry over here, and this entry over here are relevant.
Now, the chance of having a positive test and having cancer is 0.009.
Well, I might--when I receive a positive test--have cancer or not cancer,
so we will just normalize by these 2 possible causes for the positive test,
which is 0.009 + 0.198.
We know both these 2 things together gets 0.009 over 0.207,
which is approximately 0.043.
Now, the interesting thing in this equation is that the chances
of having seen a positive test result in the absence of cancers
are still much, much higher than the chance of seeing a positive result
in the presence of cancer, and that's because our prior for cancer
is so small in the population that it's just very unlikely to have cancer.
So, the additional information of a positive test
only erased my posterior probability to 0.043.