So how do we do that?
Well, there was originally something called the eight-point algorithm.
It, it was done by, I think it was done by Christopher Hagens and for awhile,
it got sort of a bad rep, because people thought it was a very unstable and
that's why I put down that it was they infamous eight-point algorithm.
Now you might say,
well, why can I do with just eight equations, I've got nine unknowns.
Well, remember p, f, p prime equals zero, I can scale the f any way I want.
Which means, for example, I could set that last value to a one.
Not a very good way of doing things, but it does mean that if you gave me
just eight points, I'd have equations and because I set the last one to one,
I would have eight unknowns and I'd be able to solve it.
If I have more than eight equations, right?
So then I've got this, you know, suppose I've got n, so
I've got n equations with nine values that are homogeneous.
Have we seen that before?
Yes.
Remember when we solved very early on, when we were trying to solve for
the total calibration matrix?
Between the world and the image and we had the M matrix.
So we said, well, there's 12 elements in here, but there's not really 12.
Right? There was really only 11, but if we used a whole bunch of points
we talked about, you could set 1 element M 1, but that wasn't such a good way.
What was a good way the SVD, remember you, you take,
you've got this A times M equals 0 or in this case, A times f equals 0.
You've take a A transpose A.
Take the singular value decomposition or you just find the eigenvectors and
you pulled out the eigenvector with the smallest eigenvalue.
We've actually seen this now three times.
I did it explicitly for you in the very first example, so
you can go take a look at that.
But that's how you solve it.
And by the way, you would typically use more points than just eight or nine or
you use however many points you have.
So you solve this and what happens?
Well, your point matches aren't exact, are they?
No, so you solve this.
Get an F.
With an F, I can draw some epipolar lines.
Right?
And if I use an, and these numbers were meant to represent coming from that
picture, I would see this.
Okay?
And that's technically called a mess, all right?
Because you'll notice that the epipolar lines,
they're not all intersecting at that single point, are they?
No.
Why not?
Well, I'll tell you.