my name is Sebastian and welcome you to
our self driving car not agree Stephanie
car started when I was 18
one of my best friends and neighbors
died in a traffic accident his life when
the way in no time and back in the day I
ask myself why is it that we have these
machines great on one hand but still
kill so many people
it stuck with me for a long time and
when a drone stanford in 2003 the US
government had just launched a
competition called the dr grand
challenge it's a competition where a
suffering car to drive to an empty
desert in California our cast Stanley
named after stand for it was a blue
beautiful
aux1 toric and lo and behold we won the
competition my team joined google in
2009 to build a self-driving car that
could rival public streets where your
drive and when we were ready to tell the
public about it we had driven not just a
hundred thousand unique miles with
self-driving cars we also driven pretty
much the hardest streets in California
could imagine completely self-driven
video from San Francisco to Los Angeles
the technology has been in development
for many many decades but the
breakthroughs are often the most recent
years more than self-driving cars now
with Bergman others can drive safe for
the news can drive and automotive
companies and tech companies are
struggling to find great engineers to
keep up this is the self that we cannot
agree program and then you are finished
you will have the skills to join this
cutting-edge industry we are super
excited to have you with us