Okay, so, so far, we've done the first three steps.
And we're really just looking at this last step here for our program where we
display the information that we get from the query to the UI.
What we haven't talked about yet
is what the query method returns, which is a cursor.
So, what's a cursor?
A cursor is an iterator that gives access to the underlying data in
tabular form.
If you're not familiar with what an iterator is,
there's a link in the instructor notes.
Also, if you Google iterators, you'll get more than enough reading material.
So let's think about something.
This picture of a database right here is pretty small.
But theoretically it could be thousands of lines long.
Do you see these nulls?
The first three are used to say exactly which rows and which columns that
you want to include in the cursor so that if you do have thousands of lines of
data you don't have to load them all in your cursor at once.
Now the fact that we are using these nulls is saying that we want to load in
all the data in this table without being more specific about the exact rows and
columns that we need.
If you want to learn more about these parameters,
I've provided a link in the instructor notes.
All right. So let's talk about what we could actually do with our cursor.
You could get the number of rows in a cursor using cursor.getCount.
Since a cursor works like an iterator,
you could travel through its data by calling the moveToNext method.
Specifically, if you want to iterate through all the rows in a cursor,
you can use while(cursor.moveToNext()).
At each iteration in the while loop,
the cursor will be pointing at a different row.
If, when the cursor is pointing at a row you want to get the value at one of
the associated columns, you can use the cursor.get method.
Whatever you put here will be what you're trying to get.
So there's cursor.getString, cursor.getInt, so on.
The method takes the index of the column you want.
Let's see how that works.
Okay, so when your cursor is pointing at a specific row,
you might want to actually get the data at one of these columns.
To do that, you can use two methods.
The first method is cursor.getColumnIndex.
This takes the name of the column as an argument.
For the user dictionary this name is stored in this constant.
Once we have the column Index,
we can use the getString method to get what's actually in the column.
Note that the type here changes depending on what the type of the column is.
So in this example, I'm getting string, but
if I was trying to get the frequency, I would get int instead.
Finally, and important to note, you should always remember to call cursor.close,
which closes the cursor by cleaning up associated objects.
Why?
Well, every time you don't close a cursor, you leak a little memory.
If your code keeps opening up cursors without cleaning up after itself.
It can eventually get so bad that it causes your app to crash.
So close your cursor.
You can even take your code and wrap it in a try block.
Then just make sure to follow with a finally block and
put your c.close in that block.
By doing this, you'll be 100% sure that you're not leaking memory.
Okay, so I want you to take everything that we've been talking about and
finish the onCreate method in your app.
In this method,
you should print the number of words that are in the user dictionary.
And for each word you should print the ID, word, and frequency.
What do I mean by print?
All I want you to do is append the values to the text view.
When you're finished, your app should look like this.
The starter code for
your app is in the instructor notes as well as some helpful links.
When everything's complete check this box.