All right, welcome back.
So we're in project six where we're
going to be reducing noise by
strategically reducing the vocabulary.
So what we've done is we've taken
these metrics that we've kind of used
earlier as a juristic to see
whether an idea was a good idea.
And we're going to use it to carve
out a little bit of the noise so
that the neural net can
better see the signal.
Now in this case most of the action
happens in this pre-processing step,
right?
So instead of,
we kind of updated the training before.
Here we're going to try to reduce
the vocabulary to this vocab object,
which gets turned into the word index
object and used to create our indices.
We want to reduce this in specific ways
according to different cut-offs and
thresholds.
So, in this case, I created a
polarity_cutoff and a min_count cutoff.
Now what the min_count cutoff does,
it says okay, so in order for a word
to be included in the review_vocab,
Vocab, one of those created vocab.
It has to exceed a minimum count,
all right?
So, if it doesn't get into vocab,
it doesn't actually get trained
on according to the pre-processing
step down here.
So if the word Is not in the vocab,
it's not in words2index.keys.
It doesn't get added to this indices
list, it doesn't get trained on, so
it gets ignored.
So that's the first thing.
And the second thing is
this polarity cut off.
This is saying that this pos neg ratio
has to be greater than or equal to
the polarity cut off or less than or
equal to negative the polarity cut off.
because if you remember,
this thing centers around one.
So we're saying a word has to either
be less than the negative ratio or
more than the positive ratio, right?
So it's excluding this really tall, and
yet irrelevant, section in the middle.
That's the idea.
One other thing I did was I required
that it be a minimum count for
this pos_neg_ratio to
really take effect.
And a reason I did that is that
occasionally you have really infrequent
terms that have very little correlative
power or a lot of correlative power.
But they only happen once or twice.
So the metric, it's a simple rule,
it's a simple cutoff.
I can't have it be,
it's perfectly positively correlated
would only happen once, right?
So in this case I found
this was a good number.
So those are the two thresholds.
There's not really a right way or
a wrong way to do this.
Again, we're trying to
cut out the noise and
this is different for
every data set, right?
So you're in kind of
a new data setting and
you're trying to take a neural net and
you're going to try to frame the neural
net a problem where it
can succeed a data set.
This is just the method you go
about by framing the problem
when you're in a domain.
Like these are not hard and fast rules,
these are techniques to be able
to make sure that your neural net has
the best chance to capture new and
interesting patterns.
So, all of this is the same,
none of these has changed at all,
testing is not different,
running is not different,
other than the real
vocabulary is smaller.
So let's give it a shot,
I'm going to set the min count at 20 and
the polarity cut off at .05 which
is a really small polarity cutoff,
like this doesn't cut out
too much of the vocabulary.
We can get more aggressive
about it later,
and yeah, we'll see how this
thing goes here in a second.
So what it's doing right now is it's
calculating all the statistics as it
started, so we had do it then, and
then it's going to start training.
So yeah, so
when you call the constructor,
calls pre-processed data and
pre-processed data runs all these stakes
from before to help kind of identify
signal we're going to train.
All right, very.
Very good.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So this is actually a little bit
of a speed lift from before.
Not a lot, just a little bit, because
we've reduced our vocabulary size.
And then we look at our testing data,
85.9.
Not a huge lift, but
a small and significant lift.
Like, and you can pick your battles and
I didn't do this too long.
So you kind of keep playing with this
min count and polarity cut off and
find which one seems to
work the best for you.
Now the other thing that I wanted to
show here is that if we take this and
just crank it up, right?
So, if we set this to be more like,
I don't know.
We'll keep min count the same.
We'll set this to be .8.
We really carve out
the middle of this guy.
We're just going to take a big chunk.
.8, that's like right here to right
here, and we're going to say,
you know what?
This thing stuff has little correlation,
but I just think it's ambiguous,
so just carve it all out.
And we say, okay,
we're going to train on that.
Then we can really crank
up the speed of this thing.
The speed by which it trains,
with a relatively small effect
on our testing accuracy.
So sometimes you'll find that this
can be beneficial for two reasons.
For some problems you want to be
able to train on so much more data,
you want to be able to run a lot faster.
Let's see how much faster it goes.
Straining, my gosh, look at that.
So 7,000 reviews per second.
I mean, it trained whole
thing in a couple seconds.
And let's see how,
let's see the damages in the test.
82.2, so we lost 3%.
Not bad, we got a 7x increase
in speed for a, well,
almost 7x, for a 3% decrease in quality.
Now, you're going to find in neural
nets there's usually a speed
trade out quality.
The only time that I know of when
there consistently isn't is when
you can reduce noise.
because reducing noise tends to reduce
the amount of data that you have to
process, which increases both speed and
accuracy.
It's why I like it so much.
But this can actually
be really beneficial.
One, for production systems.
When you just need something to fly,
to get through a ton of data.
To really solve a real world
problem that exists out there.
Like the most laboratory
kind of sterile, highest possible
score isn't always the best answer.
Sometimes the best answer is hey,
we want to fly through
a million medical reports a day so
that we can save the most lives.
Give me something that's faster.
And this is the something that
you can do to try to do that.
And once again, we got almost 10X and
if we cranked it up even further,
we probably could.
And so the cool thing about this is that
the more you carve out you're saying,
hey, I need to go faster and
I'm trying to do the minimum amount
of damage that I can to go faster.
So I'm getting rid of the terms that
are most ambiguous in my prediction and
it's saving me lots of time.
So now why is it saving me time?
Well, we do fewer sums.
When we have fewer terms we do fewer
sums in the display matrix and
we do fewer back propagation
in the display matrix.
Because there are fewer words in
the review that we've allowed to pass
through that were candidate
words that we could train on.
That's just all we did, and
fortunately it increases
the speed very significantly.
Now, the other reason that sometimes
people will increase the speed
like this or in a variety of
other ways is if you have so
much training data that you could
never train over all of it.
It turns out that just being able
to run faster over more data,
even if you choose a more
naive algorithm or
your limiting a lot of stuff,
makes the accuracy really, really high.
The most famous example of this
that maybe people don't know is
taking its effect is Word2Vec.
So Word2Vec is a close approximation of
other language models that people
have been training forever.
But the problem was other language
models took like a month to train on
a billion tokens and even then it wasn't
making as aggressive weight updates.
What Word2Vec showed was that if
you striped out everything and
you skip some steps, yeah it's an
approximation, but It's so much faster.
You can train it on,
was it eight billion tokens in like
six hours on a 32 core machine?
I mean it's so much faster that
you can train so much data.
You can gather so much more information
that even though the backhoe is dropping
dirt while it's driving back to
the dumpster, it can do it so
much faster, in so many more iterations,
it just doesn’t matter.
So, there's a lot of cases where
we might make it way faster and
then we'll train on seven
times more data, and
then that'll actually get
us to a higher score.
Actually I can almost guarantee you
that if we had seven times more data and
we trained this with something that's
seven times faster relative to this,
it's going to get a way higher score.
Because once again,
you're covering more ground.
We lost a marginal
amount of accuracy here.
So if training over more
data was the problem,
then this can often be a really,
really good solution.
So, I hope you've enjoyed and
in the next section we're going to talk
a little bit more about what's actually
happening under the hood in the weights.
How are they adjusting to each other,
what's happening on the terms, and
really see some kind of cool
visualizations that help us
get a more intuitive feeling for
what's going on in the neural net.
See you there.