Let's go back to our app now.
I want to focus on understanding
what's going on behind the scenes
when a click happens in Android.
If we click on the Numbers
category in the app,
how does an openNumbersList
method magically get executed?
Well, we saw here in
the activity_main.xml file
that we were able to define
button click behavior
by adding an android:onClick attribute
to a view in the XML layout.
So this is actually a pretty convenient
shortcut in XML that Android provides.
However, we want to teach you
how professional developers
typically hook up button
code logic to their app.
Now by the end of this lesson,
we're going to accomplish the same
button click behavior in the Miwok app,
but this time with only Java code and
no XML changes.
When a user's interacting
with their Android device,
they interact with the apps
by touching the screen, and
these correspond to user
input events in Android.
For example, there's a click
event when a view pressed.
Other types of events include long
click, drag events, key events,
this is when a key on the keyboard is
pressed, and there are many others.
Say the user clicked
a button on the screen.
The screen hardware will
detect the touch and
notify Android that
a click has occurred.
Android will then identify the view
at the location that they touched
the screen.
Now what's really cool is that
you can choose to get notified
when certain events happen
on a specific view.
In the code you can say, I want to know
when this particular event happens.
So developers often refer to
this paradigm as listening for
a certain event.
In a way, you can think of your
app as having an ear to listen for
certain signals that you care about,
the signals being certain user events.
Once you know the event has happened,
you can program exactly what should
happen when a user interacts
with a specific part of your UI.
So how do you get this
set up in your app?
Well, you can create an event
listener object for this view and
you specify what should
happen when the event occurs.
So in this diagram,
we're interested in click events.
So we create an OnClickListener and
fill out instructions that should happen
when the onClick method is called.
These instructions can
be anything you want.
You can open a new screen when
the user clicks on this view,
change the appearance of this view,
change the background color of
the whole screen, or anything else.
So once you've created
the OnClickListener, the last step is to
attach it to the view that we
want to listen for clicks on.
This way, when the click event occurs,
if the view has a click
listener associated with it,
Android will execute the code
that you've specified over here.
This process happens all very quickly,
and
you don't need to remember
all the details of each step.
Your key role as a developer is
to set up the event listeners for
the input events you care
about in your application, and
Android will take care of running
the code as you've specified.
This is a list of some of
event listeners in Android.
Each event listener offers
a single callback method
that you can provide code for.
It's named callback method
because you'll be called back
when the event happens.
Now let's focus here this part
of the article mentions that if
you're interested in a click event
you must create an OnClickListener.
So let's navigate there and that
contains the onClick method where you
fill out the instructions for
the onClick method.
Then Android will take care of
calling this method whenever the user
clicks on a view.
As a side note,
we refer to a tap on the screen as
a click because of historical reasons.
Desktop computers use a mouse to
navigate around the screen and when you
press a mouse button to select something
on the screen the mouse went click.
And here's an image of
the very first mouse.,