In the beginning of parallel
sorting algorithms,
people were obsessed with
the idea of sorting networks.
So what is a sorting network?
A sorting network is a fixed
circuit that sorts its inputs
using a special type of circuit
element or gate called a comparator.
For instance,
here are two examples of comparators.
Each one takes two inputs and
produces two outputs.
The increasing or
plus comparator puts the smaller of its
two inputs on the top wire, and
the larger on the bottom wire.
By contrast the decreasing or
minus comparator does just the opposite.
For example,
suppose you feed the values of 1 and
6 into a plus comparator, the output
would just be a mirror of the input
because one is the smaller
of the two input elements.
Now suppose instead we replace
them with a minus comparator,
then the output would be
reversed relative to the input.
Like an electrical circuit, you can
compose comparators by connecting wires.
For example, suppose we have these
three values and you want to sort them.
I claim that this circuit will do it.
It takes three inputs,
produces three outputs, and
contains three plus comparators.
Let's trace its execution.
The first comparator would
produce this result.
What about the second?
The second would produce this result.
Notice that the second takes its
two inputs, three and one and
puts the smaller one on the top wire and
the larger one on the bottom.
Finally, the last comparator
would produce this result.
Here's some symbolic mumbo jumbo that
describes what this circuit does.
Yikes.
Stare at it for a minute and
convince yourself that for
any input it will
produce a sorted output.
Now I want you to notice
something else about this circuit.
As we said before it
has three comparators.
It also has a depth or
critical path length of three.
Here I've drawn arrows show
the dependencies among the comparators.
This analysis should remind you
of the concepts of work in spam.
So if you can take an algorithm and
encode it as a circuit,
we can analyze a circuit with respect
to how many operations it performs,
and what the critical path length is.
By the way, here's a question.
Suppose you're only allowed to use
these two types of comparators.
Compared to this circuit, do you think
there's a way to sort three elements
using fewer comparators or in a way
that has a shorter critical path length?