Here you go.
>> Thanks.
All right.
Let's give this a shot.
First thing is let's just draw
a box to represent our browser.
It looks like at the top of the page
we've got some sort of list, maybe.
It's hard to tell because
it's a lot of divs but
I'm just going to do something
like this to represent this.
Next, there's just a lot of
text here and it's nested so.
Maybe we have like some text at
the top and maybe some sections.
Like three sections.
Looks like there's three sections
the pre and pre-store and pre-soon.
So let's do it like this.
And then finally looks
like we've got some
contact information here at the bottom
and maybe another paragragh.
I think this looks good.