Does hill climbing have any other
problems we should worry about?
>> Suppose we start at
the left edge of the graph.
Using small steps,
we gradually climb higher,
until we get to the shoulder here.
However, if we stop when we no
longer see a way to improve,
we can get stuck at this shoulder.
>> So you mean we get to this point,
and if the step size is small enough,
we never see the sudden
increase in gradient here.
>> Yep, for flat areas,
how do we know which way to travel?
If we just choose a direction randomly,
we can wander on this plateau for
a while.
The code needs to return a result at
some point, so how many times in a row
should we allow a zero improvement
in score before we stop?
We could just keep going in the
direction of the last positive gradient,
but with a small enough step size, we
can easily think we are not improving,
and the algorithm should stop.