You've been doing very well, Lorenzo.
This might be a good
time to ask you about
some of your experiences
with machine learning.
So, can you describe a project,
problem, or
challenge that you applied machine
learning to, and how you went about it?
>> Definitely, so
a project that I'm working on
right now is called A Cappella.
This is a music accompaniment
application that uses machine learning
to listen to a musician,
or a singer, and
from the audio input that's taken in,
it will try and
predict where you are in a song and
play the appropriate accompaniment.
So it's kind of like having
your own live jazz band.
>> Wow.
>> Just taking in a few seconds of
audio input, it makes a prediction and
tries to figure out where in the song
the user is, play the appropriate music.
And if at any time it feels like
the predictions are getting off, or it's
incorrect, it will stop and recalculate
and try and catch up with you.
>> Wow, that's very impressive.
I'm curious how you're
dealing with the input data.
Is that raw audio as a wave form,
or how do you process that?
>> Yes, so training the audio was
quite a challenging task for me.
I ended up taking a perfect
version of the song and
adding noise, and pitch bend,
and phase shifting multiple
time to end up making 50 to 100
copies of the exact same song.
After that, I chopped it into
a lots of small pieces, so
that way I can make predictions
on very short pieces of audio.
Because making the prediction
early was really valuable for me,
because I needed this
to run in real time.
So, it would make several slices of the
song that had a few seconds of overlap,
and then run all of the transforms
I wanted to run on it.
So I did a Fourier transform and some
peak analysis, fed that into a machine
learning algorithm, and
then out came a prediction.
On my labels were the timestamps
of different parts of the song.
So it would make a prediction
as to a timestamp,
as to where it thinks the singer is.
And then it would feed that into a,
or once it got the prediction,
it would open up an audio file that
would play the perfect accompaniment,
and start it at that timestamp.
>> That's very impressive.
What machine learning
algorithm did you use here?
>> So, I tried quite a few machine
learning algorithms to see which one
would give me the best output,
and the best accuracy.
When I did my cross validations,
I noticed that random forest was giving
me very reasonable accuracy scores and
something I was really happy with.
But when it actually came to
implementing it in the application,
the predictions were
happening a little too slow.
So by the time it made the prediction,
the musician had already moved on.
So, I tried using some more
lightweight algorithms.
So, using support vector machines.
I had a little bit less of an accuracy,
but the predictions were super fast.
And I was really happy with the product.
>> That's very good,
thanks for sharing with me.
>> Thank you.