Hey Charles.
>> Hey Michael.
>> We've got a quick little
mini-topic to talk about
which I'm calling Messing with Rewards.
>> Okay.
>> And so just to give you a sense
of what that's about, I mention Ng,
Harada, and Russell.
They wrote a paper that covers
the ground that I'm going to talk about.
And then to make it more vivid,
I drew a picture of me messing
with the reward function.
And when I asked Google for a picture
for this, this is what it came up with.
So that's Debra Messing
winning an award.
>> [LAUGH] And
that seems absolutely appropriate.
because she's got the same look on
her face that you had on yours.
>> I know,
I thought that was really interesting,
I was surprised that Google
did such a good job.
I think Emma Church is getting
better because of machine learning.
>> Probably,
probably reinforcing the learning.
I hope you gave it a little reward.
>> I forgot to do that.
All right I owe it one.
So I wanted to start off with question
two, which is if we're going to
be tinkering with the reward function,
why might we want to do that?
Why might it make sense to
take a reward function for
MDP and then turn it into
some other reward function?
>> Because it's easier?
>> It's easier to change
it than to not change it?
>> No, just we might get a reward
function that's easier to solve.
This is the whole point
which is to solve the MDP,
we should just make that really easy.
>> Yeah, so if we can find a way to
changing the reward function in a way
that makes it easier for
the learner to work with.
Then without actually changing what
it's going to learn as a result.
That's a win.
>> Oh, I wasn't going that far.
I just figured we'd set
the reward to zero everywhere.
And then everything would be easy.
>> That would make it easy.
But I think it should
be easier to solve and
similar to what it would
have learned otherwise.
>> Okay, I guess that's fair.
That seems like less cheating.
But it does invite a question,
maybe we don't want to get into
a philosophical discussion here, but
where did the reward function
come from in the first place?
I mean, I think the way you pose this
question sort of suggests that there's
a true, original reward function.
>> That's a good question.
So, why wouldn't we want to
change the reward function?
because, we don't have one yet.
>> Right.
>> I think that is a really good point
and you're right I'm not
going to get into that.
But this is a topic that you know that I
have a lot interest in because you and
I have been meeting on this subject for
a year or so trying to figure out.
If we think about reward functions
as being ways of encouraging
reinforcement learners to exhibit
certain kinds of behavior.
Then they're kind of like
a programming language.
They're kind of like a way
of specifying behavior that
then is going to get compiled by the
learning algorithm into actual behavior.
And so there isn't actually
a lot of work on how to do that.
If we have some idea of
what behavior we want.
What reward function would be
appropriate to make that happen?
So you're right.
So in some sense I'm finessing that
question and instead staying yeah,
somehow we have reward function and
we want to tinker with it.
Maybe to make it easier to solve.
Maybe make it easier to represent.
Or, easier to reason about, or
any of a number of possible reasons, but
without actually undermining what it
is that the behavior is supposed to be,
that's being specified
by that reward function.
because, as you said,
it's really easy to just turn
the reward function into all zeros.
And then all policies maximize
that reward function.
In which case, learning is done.
>> Yeah, and then we solved a problem,
just not necessarily the problem
we were trying to solve.
>> Yeah, that's right.
And that's always an issue in AI,
I think, we have to worry about turning
the problem into an easier problem
that isn't really interesting anymore.
>> Right.
So, by the way, something you said
made me think about something.
Well two completely unrelated things.
So, you call the reward function
sort of like a programming language.
I like that.
One nice thing about that is let us
think about this easier to solve thing
while still being
similar to saying well,
if you have a program
that allows you to sort.
Well there are many different
programs that allow you to sort and
some are actually more
efficient than others.
And they're more efficient both in
terms of the time it takes them to run.
More efficient in
the space that they use.
And they're more efficient in
the sense that they're easier for
a human being to write or to think
about, even though they're ultimately
going to exhibit the same behavior,
which is sorting a list.
So I like that, then it makes the
question of why would you want to change
a reward function make
a little more sense?
And that ties in to the second
thing I wanted to say,
which is you say easier to solve, but
you haven't said what that meant.
I can think of at least
two things it could mean.
Easier as in faster, or
easier as in might be solvable at all.
Like there maybe a reward function that
becomes extremely difficult to solve.
>> So okay, so I summarized what you
were saying to me as first of all,
if we think about reward
functions as a certain way.
At least gives us an idea
about what semantics is.
Like what is it that we want a reward
function to make the agent do?
And at the moment we're going to
finesse that and just say, well,
whatever it is that the old
reward functioned me to do.
But then we can also think about
changing it in a way that doesn't change
the meaning, but
does make it more efficient.
Either in terms of the amount
of data it needs to learn or
the computation that it needs to learn.
I guess speed really has
those two different pieces.
Right?
One could be how much experience does
the agent need?
And then how much computation does it
take to actually carry out the learning
process?
And that can be easier or harder.
If you don't have to plan ahead super
long then it might actually be faster in
terms of computation.
And other kinds of
efficiency include space,
sort of the complexity of writing
down the reward function.
And maybe whether it makes
a problem solvable at all.
Maybe that the efficiency is
the difference between infinity and
not-infinity.
>> Yeah, this is a pretty big difference
most times, I mean in the limit.
>> So good, all right.
So let's think about some ways that we
can actually change the reward function
without changing what it is optimizing.