So, what are we doing with
these filters, anyway?
Well, in the app,
we want to allow users to search for
conferences according to
any of these criteria.
That's why we're storing
an index in them, after all.
As usual, the front end for
this is already implemented.
Next up,
we'll be adding the back end logic.
Currently, if we add a filter over here,
all that happens
is the query conferences method gets
called, and the filter is just ignored.
It just returns all the conferences.
But if you look up here in this message,
you'll see the filter data
that the front end is
sending to the back end API.
We see filters, fields, city, operator,
eq for equals, value, London,
just like this, and field max attendees
operator gt for greater than value ten.
But it isn't actually
applying these filters.
That's because currently,
our query conferences method takes
a conference query forms message,
which contains all these filters.
Right now it doesn't
do anything with it.
The next chunk of code we'll be
seeing will interpret this filter
data structure, and turn it into
actual data store filters, and
you'll be modifying query
conferences to use them.