In the case of this abstract action,
we know all the possible outcomes are somewhere within here
and none of those intersect with a goal,
so there's nothing we can do to make this one work.
For this abstract action, we see that there is an intersection,
and there's an intersection even in the under estimate of the state.
We know that we can reach someplace in here,
and since we have the choice of where we want to go,
we know we can reach there,
so we know that we can always refine this abstract action to achieve the goal.
Over here there's an intersection,
but it's only in the over estimate--the outside part of the search space.
So we're not quite sure.
We have to look more carefully at the refinements to see if there is
a combination of refinements that allow us to reach this state,
or if the combination of refinements leave us somewhere over here,
which is not inside that state.
So that would be questionable or unknown yet.