All right, you're done.
Let's take a look at how I did it.
Now we only want this parallax scrolling
to work in phones in landscape mode.
So we're going to edit
fragment_main in landscape.
And what we did is we took app_bar and
renamed it to parallax_bar.
This way our code will find that,
and only actually do parallax scrolling
when in the landscape orientation.
Everything else we're going to
do is going to be inside of our
actual fragment.
So, inside of onCreateView, so
inside of forecastfragment, we're going
to look for that parallaxView, which is
the view that we just renamed that's in
that layout landscape for our fragment.
And then, if we're on that end,
we're on Honeycomb or
greater because what we're going
to use this setTranslationY,
is only available on builds
greater than Honeycomb.
And we really have two options here,
we could actually use
these very very cool classes
that do view compatibility.
So I could have actually
done this in here and said.
You know, ViewCompat.setTranslationY,
and then put parallaxView
inside of this.
But, since I don't want
this code to run at all and
waste any time for
running anything less than Honeycomb,
I'm just going check to see whether
this build version is greater than or
equal, and then if it is then
we add the onScrollListener.
So pretty straight forward.
And then what we do, is we get
onScrolled here and this actually one of
the beautiful advantages of RecyclerView
for us, is that it actually gives us dx
and dy, for our scrolling which is much
much better than what ListView does.
ListView just tells us which list
item we're scrolled on and then
makes it rather challenging to actually
calculate the dx and dy correctly.
And so what we're going to
do is set a max here.
And we're calculating this every time.
This isn't really necessary.
A little bit expensive.
But, not too bad.
And that's going to be the max
we're going to scroll.
Max is here, so we just scroll it just
off the screen when we're scrolling up.
And this actually causes a little bit,
because we set
the max to the exact type, you'll notice
this causes a slight bit of artifacting.
Because you'll actually
see the shadow is
actually going to be still slightly
visible on screen when we scroll up.
So setting it exactly to match,
probably not the best idea, but
it works pretty well.
And then we're going to take advantage
of this function that again was added in
Honeycomb called setTranslationY.
Now you'll notice that these deltas
are actually going to be
in positive quantities, but
we're actually going to be setting our
translation in negative quantities.
So positive means we're scrolling up,
negative means we're scrolling down,
in terms of the onScrolledListener,
but in the case of our translation,
we're actually going to be translating
it the opposite direction.
Not that that's particularly confusing,
but you'll see what we actually do here.
And just to make it a little easier I'm
going to add some very nice spacing.
So we're going to setTranslationY to
do that, and in that case, and again,
if we're greater than zero,
it means we're actually scrolling it up,
and so what we're going to want to
do is scroll the reverse of that.
So we're going to take the existing
translation, subtract dy, then in order
to get it to scroll half the speed of
the outer view, we're going to say
that divided by 2, and because of order
of operations, this is actually going to
turn into parallaxView.getTranslationY
minus half of dy.
And then when we're going in the other
direction when dy is less than zero.
We do the same thing, we subtract dy.
Except that we're only going
to scroll until we hit zero.
And here we're going to scroll
until we hit negative max.
Pretty straight forward.
And that's it.
That's all the code we need to do
this whole parallax scrolling, so
it's actually really really simple.
It looks really pretty, and this is one
of the nice things about RecyclerView,
again, is that it gives us the ability
to do this kind of thing really,
really easily.
And on destroy, I do go and
clear all on scroll listeners.
And it's important to do this in general
when we have any listener going on.
It can prevent the garbage collector
from being able to clean up our whole
activity if we don't do this on destroy.
So it's kind of important to do this.
I don't know if it was really needed
here, but put it there anyways.
And that's it.
That's all we have to do and
we have beautiful parallax scrolling and
let's bring that up in the emulator to
take a quick look at what that
should look like for you.
There we are.
This is the cool version of sunshine,
as you can see.
We now have exciting parallax
scrolling which is really cool.
And, you also notice we have the margin
here at the top, nicely done now.
That's because RecyclerView actually
will respect those margins that we put
into an element.
So that's also kind of a nice
little advantage we get there.
And that's it.
That is parallax scrolling.
You can see it works very nicely.
We scroll off, we scroll on and
it actually scrolls at half the speed.
Follows it quite nicely.
So, pretty easy to do that kind of
effect, and it's nice that we have these
toolbars where we're actually scrolling
the toolbar on and off as well.
I'll be doing this.
And actually if you notice,
because translationY actually translates
everything correctly, we're actually
maintaining the correct position there.
So then we scroll that off,
we really can't click there anymore.
It really is truly scrolled off,
which is pretty nice.