The perspective camera is where things get interesting. This camera is more
like real life, with objects in the distance being smaller. That said it uses
the same sort of pipeline as before. Internally you define a view matrix
exactly the same as for the orthographic camera. However, then the projection
matrix is formed differently. In a perspective view of the world, objects get
smaller in the image, as they get further away from the viewer. Another way to
say it is that if something is farther away, it needs to be larger in world
space if it wants to appear the same size on the screen. This gives us the idea
of similar triangles. Y2 divided by Z2 will be equal to Y1 divided by Z1, and
so on. So perspective projection is going to involve division, but when we
multiply a vector by a matrix, it's just some dot products, a series of
multiplies and additions. This is where the fourth coordinate for our points
comes into play. Up to now this fourth value has always been equal to 1. We run
a point through any set of modeling transforms and the fourth coordinate value
of 1 is left untouched. This all changes with perspective projection.