First of all,
you'll grab the starting code.
The next thing you had to do was add
the library to point to the CardView,
which will be nicely inside
of your greater files for
you if you added under project
structure dependencies.
For tablet portrait it was really easy.
All you had to do Was replace it with
currently there in the frame layout with
the CardView, and it just worked.
You would want to, of course,
set the card elevation correctly, and
say PreventCornerOverlap=False.
So that on older devices you didn't
end up with that little white line.
Now for tablet landscape,
it was slightly more complicated.
So you see, what we did is, we actually
added this CardView aligner here.
And we set the marginRight to 64dp, and
we set the alignLeft to layout_center,
and this allowed us to add
an additional calculation.
But without adding any layout hierarchy,
we still were able to add margins
in this case, which is pretty cool.
This allows us to the put the card view
in the right place on both seven inch
and ten inch tablet layouts,
which is pretty cool.
And the other thing we had to do was,
of course, replace the frame layout
that was here with the card view.
So that makes sense, so you can see it's
aligned with the card view aligner, and
of course it has card elevation and
pard prevent corner over lap false.
And of course the one other
note about all of this is that
we needed to do something
in detail fragment.
And so what we're going to do is,
when we are loading up
instead of setting ourselves to be
INVISIBLE like we did before, we're
actually going to look at our parent and
see oh, is our parent a CardView?
If so, let's set that to
being INVISIBLE instead.
In onLoadFinished we're
going to do the same thing.
We're going to say oh If
the parent of us is a card view,
then let's set that to be visible.
And that'll keep the same behavior
of when the fragment isn't loaded,
we don't see anything.
Which is important especially
in the case of empty view.
Now we really don't want to see
that kind of artifact going on.
And so that's it.
Pretty straight forward.
That one little challenge I think with
the space in the relative layout, but
it's a good example of how one can use
another view to do arithmetic for you.
And sometimes you have to
do that in Android views.