.map is an array method
that accepts a function,
here represented by this box and
a rocket ship, and it returns an array.
The array that it returns is going
to be the result of executing
this function against every
element in this array.
Here, let me show you what I mean.
It starts with the first element.
It creates the array and
passes this element into the function
and executes it immediately.
So at this point,
this function is running.
Then .map moves to the next element.
Now it is in the array and
executing as well.
It goes to the next, and so
on until it's created this new array.
And for each element in the array,
the function has already executed.
In this case, the array you want to
iterate against is the URLs, and
you'll want to call getJSON and
createPlanetThumb against each one.
Okay, and
I lied about sequences earlier.
You don't actually need to create
a sequence in order to use .map,
however there is a bonus challenge
at the very end of this course.
Your solution to this quiz is going to
be the starting point for it.
You'll probably find that you'll
need a sequence to solve it.
Anyway, map the URLs against the methods
you need to load the thumbnails.
When you're done you should see
the thumbnails appear on the screen, and
you should see the request
go out in parallel.