Okay, so hopefully you've planned
out the logic for your Reset button.
I want you to take a stab at
coding the Reset button yourself.
This is a fairly freeform and
challenging task
compared to what you have been doing,
but I think you're ready for it.
If you're feeling a little bit nervous,
here's some advice.
You're going to need to change
both the xml and the Java.
As far as which one to do first,
you should start with XML.
This will involve actually
making your button.
Don't worry about it functioning.
Just get it to appear on
the screen in the right place.
And getting it to appear on
the screen in the right place,
is going to require a bit
more nesting with views.
After you've gotten you're
button on the screen.
You can function on
making your button work.
This will involve taking
the pseudocode that you just wrote and
turning it into code code.
And once you're done, here's a check
box, to check this one off your list.