So now let's take a look
at how to define and
create entities in
the App Engine Datastore.
To continue the food theme that Magnus
started at the Big Table restaurant,
let's imagine that you want to
store recipes in the datastore.
Maybe you like chocolate cake or
maybe you prefer rhubarb pie, but
whichever kind of dessert you like, your
recipe's going to need some properties.
What are some things that we'd want to
store about a recipe in any database.
Well obviously it needs
to have a name and
a list of ingredients,and
some instructions.
And it could also have properties about
whether or not it's vegetarian, and
how many servings it makes.
All of these are parts of a recipe, so
that would make them
fields in a recipe record.
Now our data store also needs to know
which type each of these values has.
And earlier Magnus told you that fields
like these are called properties and
app engines.
Let's add that.
You might have noticed that these
are an awful lot like the field classes
that we saw in pretoRPC
messages in lesson two.
Like those, these are a way of saying
what types the various fields have.
But data store entities aren't
the same as pretoRPC messages,
so these property types
have their own names.
So if name, and ingredients,
and instructions, and so
forth are properties,
what is the recipe then?
Let's go back and revisit what you
learned from Magnus with a short quiz.
What sort of a thing is recipe?
Is a data store entity, or maybe a kind,
or is it an object oriented class,
or a property?
Select any of these that might apply.