What I just showed you was a formula for
the one dimensional case.
We almost always do this in the n
dimension because even when we were
having x move in just one direction,
we had a two dimensional vector
of position and velocity.
In the two dimensional case,
these are the Kalman equations, okay.
We have our state vector x.
We assume, our prediction is just
based upon a linear transformation.
Our covariance prediction, or the pre,
the covariance of the prediction,
this is that squaring operator,
remember before, we did D squared sigma?
Well, when you're doing
this in matrices,
it's D times the old sigma times
D transpose, that's the squaring.
Plus you add in the noise,
the process noise.
So those are your
prediction measurements.
And then your correction looks
like the things on the right.
The thing for you to notice here,
is, you see the,
the quantity in the green box?
This is the residual, right there, and
you're multiplying it by this
Kalman gain matrix, all right?
And the Kalman gain matrix has
less weight on the residual
as the prior covariance
estimate approaches 0.
So as this value's, it's,
it's hard to say what it means for
covariance to go to 0, but
let's talk about its traits, but
the idea is that it's getting smaller.
As it gets smaller,
the Kalman gain goes down,
which is what you want to have happen,
right?
If your covariance of your
prediction is very tight,
I don't want to pay a lot of
attention to my measurements.
So I don't want to weight
the residuals very much.
On the other hand, if my measurement
covariance goes down, okay?
So now, what happens,
is this value is very small,
which means this value is what's
getting put in the inverse, right.
So now this sigma t goes away.
What happens is the Kalman gain matrix
goes up, its magnitude, if you will,
goes up and
it weights the measurements more.
So, these matrix equations
are doing exactly the same thing
as the scalar equation did of balancing
the prediction, and the measurement.