Earlier in the lesson we
talked extensively about how
everything on a web page is a box.
Now, before you start positioning boxes,
you need a better understanding of
the box model, which is what
you see on the screen here.
There's the concept of margins and
borders, padding and
content, all of which makes
up the box on the web page.
A link to this demo is provided
in the instructor notes section.
So, feel free to follow along.
If we explore this box in developer
tools, you'll find a similar
box to what you see on
the page in the computed tab.
You see we have a margin,
a border, padding, and content.
Let's explore each of these items.
Starting at the very center,
we have our content, and
this is the image or
text that's appearing on the website.
You can think of it as the nucleus.
It sits at the very center.
And the other layers
serve to protect it so
that other items on the page
either don't overlap, or
sit too close, so that the website
isn't very visually appealing.
And the next layer we have the padding.
And this is the green color.
The padding clears an area
around the content.
And it's affected by
the background color of the box.
So, you can think of it as the space
inside of the box that protects
the content directly.
Border, then goes around the padding and
the content, and
the border's inherited from
the color property of the box.
And lastly,
our outer layer is the margin, and
this clears an area around the border.
The margin doesn't have a background
color and it's completely transparent,
and you can think of this
as the space between boxes.
Now, you can play along with
the widths of each of these and
see how it affects the box both here and
in the Computed tab.
For example, if I changed the margin
from 20 pixels to 30 pixels,
you'll notice that we got a little
bit of extra space here at the top.
And if you move to the Computed tab,
you see that we have 30 pixels here at
the top, and 30 pixels at the bottom.
Moving back to 20,
we now go back to 20 pixels.
Feel free to stick around here and
play a little bit,
changing the widths of the margin,
border, padding, and content.
And see how it affects the box
both here and in the Computed tab.
Don't worry,
I'll still be here when you get back.
Now, by default, the size of your actual
element is equal to the sum of
the border, padding, and content width.
So, if we wanted to compute the width
of the element shown on the page,
we would have a left border of ten,
plus a left padding of 30,
plus a content width of 200,
plus the right padding of 30,
and the right border of ten.
So, our actual element width
is actually 280 pixels,
not just the 200 pixel
width of the content.
Now, this makes it kind of hard to
know how much space the box will
actually take on the screen
without recalculating it each and
every time you change
one of these values.
But luckily, an easier to use
model has been developed and
we should plan to use that.
This is CSS style,
box-sizing; border-box; this makes
the calculation of the element size
include both the border and padding.
So, that it's easier to make layouts.
You can just set the width of the
overall box and no matter how you tweak
the padding in border sizes, the size
of the box will always stay the same.
Remember, though, that margin
is not included in this size.
However, there is one
drawback with this model.
I mean isn't there always a catch?
It's been developed fairly recently, so
if you want to be sure that older
browsers are also able to display it,
you need to add what's called
browser-specific prefixes.
Now, these prefixes are webkit,
moz, and ms.
You can just add them in front
of the style definition, and
they're defined like so.
As always, see the instructor notes for
more information.
Now, you may have noticed that we've
been setting the size of a box
in pixels, but it's also possible
to do it as a percentage.
If we go back to the My Favorite App
page as an example,
we can see how changing
the content box from
a set pixel to a percentage
affects the screen size.
You can also set the size of a box
as either a pixel or a percentage.
If you set it as a percentage,
the size will change depending on how
big the screen is or
how encompassing the boxes.
If you set the box size in pixels,
it will take exactly that size and
will not change no matter how big or
small the screen is.
This can sometimes lead
to a bad user experience.
For example,
if we look back at our My Favorite App,
you'll see that this paragraph is
defined as a set number of pixels.
If I resize the screen,
you'll see that it stays the same and
disappears as I make it smaller.
However, if I instead set this to be
a percentage, say we want it to take up
50% of the screen, notice how the size
changes as I make the screen smaller.
You can also set a max width for the
box, and in that case, it will resize
and become smaller when necessary,
but not larger than the set max width.
And now, it's time for you to put this
info into your own style sheet file.
Add the border box definition and
then, add max width attributes
to the divs encompassing the image and
description of the app.
Now, if we look back at our design mock,
we got notes from the designer that
the image should be 460 pixels wide,
and the description should
be 705 pixels wide.
Then, what happens when you add
these changes to your CSS file and
explore the result in Developer Tools?
Did nothing change?
Do we have different box sizes?
Or do we have a different layout?