Remember, when you're making XML,
there are three steps that you can
follow to help create your layout.
Step number one is to select the views.
Here you're going to think about
which views you're going to use and
how many you'll use.
To help you plan, I want you to tell
me how many TextViews, ImageViews, and
Buttons you plan on using.
If you don't plan on using one of
these views, just go ahead and
put zero in there.
Next, step two is positioning the views,
and, if you remember,
this has to deal with view groups.
I want you to tell me which view group
you think you're going to use for
this layout and why.
And hint, really we've only
learned about two view groups, so
it should be pretty easy to
figure out which one it is.
And finally,
step three is to style the views.
And this is where you think about what
kind of attributes you'll use to change
things like text color.
And really the attributes here that
I want you to pay attention to
are attributes that will
help make the app readable.
We're going to make it
pretty in the final stage.
So think about things like margin and
padding.
There's also two helpful attributes,
layout and
layout gravity,
which help you align and center views.
I've provided a link to their
documentation in the instructor notes so
that you can read more
about these two attributes.
Okay, and finally,
when you're done, go ahead and
click this check box right here.
If you forgot what the app looked like,
it looked like this.
Go ahead and use this picture to
help you answer these questions.