Labels aren't too tricky.
And you may have noticed that in
previous quizzes like this one and
this one, I was actually using labels.
So, now it's your turn.
In this quiz, you're going to
be working with this page.
There are two inputs
that need some labels.
The first label will be for this check
box which is asking users if they
want to use their shipping address,
for their billing address.
And then the second one is for
this telephone number.
For the billing address
check box just use the for
attribute, but
don't nest the input inside the label.
And then for the telephone number input,
nest the input inside the label but
still use the for attribute.
Using it make sure that the screen
readers connect the label
with its associated input.
If you get stuck, you'll find the link
in the instructor notes to the Mozilla
developer network
documentation on labels.
And one last thing.
Eto and I,
highly recommend that you test this
input on an actual mobile device too.
Check the links in the instructor notes,
for more information.
Good luck.