Let's begin the process of building our
MDP to represent this state diagram.
Our first step will be to define
the set of states for our MDP.
Let's take a look at a short program
I've written to accomplish this task.
Notice that I am importing several
packages at the beginning of
the program.
If you'd like to run this code locally,
you'll need to make sure
you've included the burlap jar
file in your Java build path.
The jar file is available at the URL
listed in the instructor notes.
The class I built, FirstMDP,
currently has two fields,
a Domain, and a DomainGenerator.
in my constructor for FirstMDP I'm
instantiating a new GraphDefinedDomain
object, and assigning it to the
FirstMDP's domain generator field, dg.
I then use a method from
the GraphDefinedDomain object
to generate an appropriate
domain object,
which is then assigned to
the FirstMDP's domain field.
I've left two blanks in this code
which I'd like you to now fill in.
Using the documentation for the
GraphDefinedDomain class, please fill in
the appropriate argument or
arguments for the constructor I called.
And also fill in the appropriate method
that needs to be called in order to
create a domain object using
the GraphDefinedDomain.
Again, a link to the documentation
can be found in the instructor notes.