If you take a look at
what's happening on P3 and
P4 in this case, we see that now P3 and
P4 are observing reverse order of how
they saw the updates to m3 and m2.
As far as P3 is concerned, P3 observed
that this update to m2 happened,
and it also observed that
this update to m3 happened.
As far as P4 is concerned
it observed this update of
z to the memory location m3.
But it still has not seen that P2
updated the memory location m2
with the value of y.
It thinks that still the memory
location m2 holds value zero.
So P4 thinks that this write
occured before this write from P2,
and then P3 thinks the other way around.
This is clearly illegal as far as
sequential consistency is concerned.
Now if we take a look at these two
updates we see that on P1 before
the value of the memory location
m3 was updated to z, P1 read
the value of the memory location m2 and
it saw that that value was y.
So it saw the effects of
this particular update.
What that means is that these operations
are potentially causally related, and
therefore every processor in
the system has to observe that
this particular update
happened after the update to
m2 given the causal
relationship between the two.
Therefore the answer is no for
both of these questions.