So given this formula and given our input string--
let's stick with the familiar one--
we can start enumerating the possibilities for splitting up this string S
into a first word and a rest part and figuring out the probabilities.
So the first could be "n," could be "no," could be "now," could be "nowi," and so on,
and then the rest would be "owis..." or starting with "w" or starting with "is"
or starting with "s," and then what's the probability of the first.
Well, that we get from our corpus by counting and then smoothing,
and in our Shakespeare corpus "n" occurs infrequently"--
about one in a million times--"no" occurs fairly frequently--about 0.004,
"now" 0.003, and "nowi" doesn't occur at all,
and so we'd use some factor based on smoothing.
Then if we take the rest and multiply out this whole term,
the best segmentation of the rest times the probability of the first that comes from this column,
then that column will give us about 10 to -19 for the segmentation that starts with "n,"
10 to -13 for the one that starts with "no,"
10 t the -10 for the one that starts with "now,"
and 10 to -18 for the one starts with "nowi."
Again, that depends on exactly what type of smoothing you choose to do.
But it turns out that this row here is at least 1,000 times better than any of the other segmentations.
That is the segmentation that comes out "now is the time."
So this model, simplified though it is, coming up with this naive Bayes assumption,
gets this one right, and it does about 99% of the segmentations accurately.