What are the best practices for your customers?
>> For the people you take I mean, the best practices so far,
whatever we have today is that low key has more value.
And, the topography, the CEO output is doing well online.
Another way to do that is you can actually construct a topology.
>> Yeah. >> So, you have this spout.
And then this [INAUDIBLE] is out and think about that it,
that apology has only one of it's [INAUDIBLE] >> Mm-hm.
>> And, see how, you know?
Output looks like [INAUDIBLE] >> Yeah.
>> Then, if it is fine and not doing well.
The you have the bolt.
>> Mm-hm. >> Then, you'll look at what is output of them both is
suppose to be, right?
>> Yeah. >> So, so you, [INAUDIBLE] stage by stage and ,.
You're breaking up the topologies.
RIght? >> Mm-hm. >> That's one way to do it.
And, then of course the open model cluster is it allows you to do that kind
of integrating testing except without a distributed cluster in a local cluster.
Right? >> Mm-hm.
>> So, that's one.
I mean, I do really wish that we can do some kind of simple unit testing on
IV pole.
Than the spout level where you will say this is my input that is my output for
every spout or every volt that you have right?
>> Is there a way to say like what is your throughput per you know,
like say like, how much data you gain from your spout and
then like how long it takes for your bolt to run.
>> Mm-hm. >> because you know, because you gave that example of say you have.
>> 200,000, you know- >> Mm-hm.
>> [INAUDIBLE] per second, but your [INAUDIBLE] can only do, like 50,000.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, so but the way we do that is, I mean, that is different from testing.
>> Yeah. >> But, it's more of a what we call as a capacity planning to
determine how much [INAUDIBLE].
>> Yeah. >> And, typically, your testing occurs on a smaller amount of data.
Like what we used here on the sample data, right?
So, like a 10% sample, 20% sample, or 50% sample, right?
>> Yeah.
>> When you go into full blown data that is all you,
when you know what your decide about the right?
So, what we do is like we take the same samples that you use to
debug your program on.
>> Mm-hm. >> And, when the sample and look at your Yeah.
>> So, what we do is at every bold and
every spot level in the customer intacts that we have we look at the CP usage.
>> Yep.
>> So, we have a climbing dumps of how much CPU it say.
Because even if for a few days before it goes into production.
>> Yep. >> So, that then so
that you can capture the traffic radiations or what a.
Or, during a particular time of the day and for a particular time of the week.
Or, or all the things, right?
So, once you have know the CPU usage.
Then, you can work.
By the way, you want topology that can tasks seem to take 90% of the time.
>> Yeah. >> 90% CPU usage, which is not a good thing,
because you needed some head room for, if any, or any surge in traffic.
>> Yeah. >> Right?
So, between, so you should not be doing a 90% identity census.
Instead we should be going down to like the, say keep it at 60%.
Like 60%, 50% to 60%'s the normal.
So, that you are determining the number of [INAUDIBLE].
Where the CPU is saying it's 50% approximately, right?
So then, and you keep that running, then you have a, another HTML file that the,
the person to go up and down.
>> Mm. >> That is saying, you really shouldn't need it that good, right?
>> Mm-hm. >> So, that's a way then.
For the 50% CPU utilization, based on our current number of instances,
current number of sample set that you have.
And, what is your least sound currency using.
Then, you can determine okay this many number
of things inferences we give the [INAUDIBLE] for direction.
>> Okay. >> So, that's the way you decide that.
And, we have the CPU map for every bulge and every [INAUDIBLE] So
then you can determine at every stage how much [INAUDIBLE]