Okay, now that Randa has walked
you through setting up your files,
let's go ahead and
try running this locally.
Let's test out our application.
I'm back in
the Google App Engine Launcher, and
I'm going to add this existing
project that we just made.
To do that, let's click on File,
then Add Existing Application.
And then what we're going to want to do,
is we're going to find the directory
that you just created,
the location of that.
Let's click Browse.
It's on the desktop, let's scroll down a
little bit and there it is, helloworld.
We'll select it, click OK, and
now we have everything set up.
Let's click Add.
And as you can see,
our new application was just added
into the Google App engine launcher.
To test it out, let's highlight it,
and then click run.
Okay now that it's running,
let's go ahead and click on browse, and
look at that, we opened a new
page that says, Hello, World!
Now let's say we wanted
to make some changes,
what's nice about Google App engine,
is any changes you make to your files,
will be automatically modified in
the site while you're working on it.
Okay, I've opened Sublime Text up again.
And we're going to go ahead and
edit our existing file, and
watch it change in the browser.
So, instead of outputting Hello, World!
Hello World, but
we're going to output Hello Udacity.
Okay, I'm going to go ahead and save it.
File > Save.
Now lets ahead and go back to
the browser, and see our changes live.
We're going to refresh the page and
look at that, it changed.
Hello Udacity.