Hopefully this was
pretty straight forward.
If not, these terms will become
more familiar with practice.
The first description should be
matched with 3 for a GET request.
A get request is where a client requests
a specified resource from a server.
Next, you should have marked 5 for
HTTP method.
An HTTP method is another word for
the type or
kind of HTTP request that's being made.
For example, a GET request
is one type of HTTP method.
Then for specifies a location for
retrieving data over the network,
we should have marked 2 for URL.
As we'll come to see,
URL's can be much more complex than
something like www.udacity.com.
The next answer is 1, for status code.
A status code is a number returned
by an HTTP response that indicates
the result of the request.
They can be values like 200 or
success, or 401 for unauthorized.
Finally, the last answer is 4 for
client.
If we're downloading images
from Facebook to an iPhone,
then the iPhone is the client and
the computer that's providing
the images from Facebook is the server.
All right, enough of the terms.
It's time to start making
requests in Swift.