There are a few different tools you
can use when thinking about tracking
metrics.
However a great place to start
is with Google Analytics,
which is a free tool Google offers
to help you easily collect and
track valuable metrics about
your marketing campaigns.
It can help you determine the efficacy
and choose the best marketing channels.
You can see how people are interacting
with your interface or
even how long it takes your app to load.
You can learn about user behavior,
you can track acquisitions,
you could track specific goals, and
you can even see what your users
are going to do real time.
You'll want to know
what your specific and
measurable goals are so
you can easily track them.
If your goal is to get more users,
what is it that you want to look at?
Is it traffic to your site, is it how
long new users are staying on your site,
is it how many sign ups you get?
You get the picture.
Also you're going to want to know
what exactly it is that you want your
customers to do or
complete when they're on your site,
that way you can set up your account
to actually track those things.
Many entrepreneurs and
marketers become addicted to
Google Analytics and they spend
hours staring at the screen learning
their user's behavior on their site.
There are so many things you
can learn based on the data and
we definitely want to encourage you
to check this out periodically.
Every once in a while you'll have
research you actually want to conduct or
an experiment to measure, so make sure
you wisely track your performance.
Add this to your routine.
So maybe once a week,
check out some of the basic metrics.
For example,
what's going on with your audience?
Do you want to know how
many users you had, so
how many unique visitors to your site?
How many sessions have occurred?
So, if the user visited twice,
it would count as two sessions.
You also have the chance to
see your mobile overview.
So, check out how much your site is
optimized for the mobile web, and
if your users are likely to have a
positive experience on your mobile site.
Also how are your customer
acquisition efforts going?
You can check out referrals
in the acquisition section.
You can learn how much traffic you
get from each of the different social
platforms.
Also, learn the behavior of the users
on your site and act on it.
Now under the user behavior
section you can find site content.
Check out the behavior flow,
it's really fascinating.
You're going to want to make sure you're
optimizing the pages that people visit
the most.
For example, if people are visiting
a certain landing page more than others,
make sure you have a call
to action on that page.
And finally, measure your goals and
track your performance.
You can look at the different
sections for this.
So in the conversion section,
you can track your goals and
measure how people are responding
to your calls to action.
Or you can see if people
are signing up for your newsletter.
But make sure you are looking at
your specific goals that you're
interested in.
>> There's two main different ways of
tracking the metrics that are most
important to you.
One way is to define your own
analytics within the app.
That requires a little bit more work
because you have to set up the databases
and everything that goes
along with it on your own.
The other option that's quicker and
easier, although not quite as flexible,
is use third party providers
like Google Analytics.
And they can provide most of the key
metrics you need and it's really,
really easy to get going.
If you do go about trying to build your
own analytics, then make sure you build
some business logic on top of your raw
data so that it's actually usable.
If you just keep the roll logs then
you'll end up with hundreds of thousands
or even millions of rows of data so
that you can actually use.
Make sure you aggregate and summarize
things in an effective manner so that
you can actually see trends at the time
>> Okay, so
my name is Aykut Karaalioglu, I'm
the founder and CEO of Mobile Action.
Mobile Action is a company to help the
apps be more visible in the apps store.
Apps optimization inside
an intelligent company and
used by forty thousand companies so far.
I started this twelve and a half years
ago and we're based in San Francisco.
And we're helping the app developers to,
the product managers or marketers in
the horn app business to know what's
happening in the app store and
play store and then make their app more
visible without spending any money.
And then I help a lot of
companies as a Grow Techer
to help their companies
from zero to hero.
And everyone wants to hire me or
work with them, then I, instead of work
in one company I can work everybody.
So that's how I started.
I'm in the app business, I think so
the building an app is just
20% of the total business.
So tracking or measuring stuff,
it's very important before
even launching the app.
So, if you know your ideal customer
profile or who the right user,
they can download and then start using.
You should definitely start
using some analytics tools, and
a lot of tools in the market.
And then the most important thing,
that is your retention and
engagement numbers.
So because, so four things that you
should be the successful app company,
user acquisition, retention, engagement,
and finally you can make monetize.
So but the user acquisition perspective,
you can get user or you just do,
pay their unpaid channels.
But after that, retention and
engagement numbers
are the best thing because even if you
have a small number of the users but
they're all engaged and retained, so you
can definitely figure out your growth.
That's the reason we do believe
that 1st day, 7 day, and 30 day,
your retention numbers are important.
And then you've got to be able to know
what is your ideal customer profile
benchmark data which means what is
the average of the user that type
of profile they're retaining
the app after seven or 30 days.
And if your numbers is lower
than that benchmark data,
you should fix your prolog,
you should fix your audience.
These are the stuff in the beginning
you should be able to know.
Who's that app for?
Or, why I'm launching
today instead of tomorrow?
Or, what is the best time for
the seasonality for this app,
then I should maybe wait or
I might be late for this app.
These are stuff we can go for
details if you wanted,
but the most important things
we figure out is, for example,
if you're doing an app only for
holy season, so you should not, and
if you're doing the US, right,
is the market is also important.
Don't launch it early, like March or
April because holy season is in late,
Q4 which is like going to start early
October until the late December.
So, or
if your audience are just only teenage,
don't launch the app in the summer
season because they're probably going
to go for vacation or you're not
going to build that right audience.
And also, after that, if you know
the right time or right place and
then the seasonality is also right, so
how are you going to gamify your app or
just build out the audience
network in the app?
One user can be turned into
your loyal customer or user and
then bring the other user.
So these are the metrics so
you should check it out every day.
As a company owner or,
let's say, product owner,
you should be able to know every
single details about every events or
everything's happening in your app.
So starting from the signing to
the log out or the user activity.
You can able to know okay, what is
frequency of the usage of my app?
So why people,
maybe using your app too much.
It might be not good sign.
So this is something like you should
be evaluated and daily check it out.
So a lot of fun stuff,
you can build it your own because your
final should be like the healthy.
It should not be like too noisy.
That's another thing,
you should be able to understand,
each signals can make
your product better.