Let's start with a number of nodes.
There are eight nodes.
What about links?
There are ten links.
What about bisection?
You need to divide the eight nodes
into two subsets of size four each.
There are many possible cuts,
let me show you one.
This partitioning cuts one,
two, three edges.
As it happens, all other partitionings
will cut at least three edges as well,
therefore the bisection width is three.
What about diameter?
For any pair of nodes you can check
that the shortest path between them is
never more than three.
For example, consider the corners.
I'll let you check all other pairs.
What you should find is
that the diameter is three.