In this first debugging challenge, the
action is not set on the blue switch.
There are a few ways we
can find this error.
If you run the app, you'll notice that
the red switch seems to be working fine,
the green switch acts as expected, but
the blue switch isn't doing anything.
This is characteristic
of a missing action.
The control seems dead.
Let's go back into our
View Controller file for a second.
In a more complex app, you'll
often check to see if an action is
being called by adding a break point
in the method in question, like this.
You could also add a print
line statement, like this.
We'll talk a lot more about debugging
in the networking course, but
in this case, the best strategy might
be to just poke around in Storyboard.
If you know the actions that
your app is supposed to have and
you're comfortable finding
them in popup menus,
you can usually track down
a missing action pretty fast.
If we look here at the green switch, you
can see that value change is connected.
If we do the same with the blue switch,
we see that that value changed
action isn't connected.