There are a bunch of applications for
drawing in geometry.
One of which is land surveying.
Imagine you're starting
a lawn mowing business and
want to charge your clients based on
the square footage of their back yards.
Simply map your properties, zoom in,
and draw a polygon to get the area.
Using the app we built so far,
complete the following exercise.
Using an event listener on a polygon
completion event, add a feature that
calculates the area within the polygon
and alerts the number to the user.
Check out the geometry
library documentation
at the page listed below for more info.
Were you able to calculate the area and
display it to the user?