As a quiz, let's look at a possible
spinlock implementation.
Here is a possible pseudo code.
To be clear, the lock needs to be
initialized as free and that will be 0.
And 1 will indicate
that the lock is busy.
To lock the spinlock,
we first need to check to make
sure that the lock is free.
And if so, then we can change
its state and block it.
So change its state to busy.
Otherwise, if the lock isn't free,
we have to keep spinning.
So we have to keep repeating
this check and this operation.
Finally, releasing the lock means that
we set the value of the lock to free.
These steps are listed
in the Instructor Notes.
The questions in this quiz are does
the implementation of the lock
correctly guarantee mutual exclusion?
Also, is this implementation efficient?
Mark your answers here.