Before moving on, I want to show you one
more useful approach to print debugging.
You may have noticed that while print
statements can help us solve problems,
they're kind of hard to maintain.
For example, if we wanted to temporarily
remove certain print statements from
code, we'd either have to comment them
or we'd have to delete them completely.
And there is also other considerations.
For example, if you wanted to
have print statements in some
debugging version of your code but then
not in the ship version of the code.
You'd also have to remove them and
this kind of maintenance just gets
tedious and one commonly used
solution for this is logging.
Logging or logging systems and
frameworks
allow us to write log statements, much
like print statements, that can include
additional information such as data,
function names and the line numbers.
And most importantly, you can specify
level of severity for each log
statement, which will control the actual
statements that get printed based on
the overarching severity that you've
set for your particular application.
And I'll show you how this
works in just a second.
So one such logging framework is
Dave Wood's XCGLogger for Swift.
And this is the GitHub project for it.
I've posted a link in the instructor
notes if you're interested.
So I've already downloaded
the project and
I'm going to run the demo
application that comes with it.
You can see stated at the bottom
of the view that the XCGLogger
will only log messages that are set for
the same or
higher log level or you may hear it
referred to as a severity level.
So the current log level is debug.
And if I click this Debug button,
we see that the execute
debug code block was logged.
Because it corresponds to
a debug log statement.
Let me hide this away so
we can see it a little bit better.
If I click Info.
Info is also log.
but if I click Verbose, nothing happens.
And the reason that
nothing happens is because
verbose is a lower level than our
current level which is debug, but
if I drag it down to verbose,
now verbose is executed.
So we can play with this again,
we'll go up to error, so now error and
severe are the only ones that should
work, here we go, both of them.
The Warning nothing, Info nothing,
Debug nothing, Verbose nothing.
And it's that simple.
If you want to know more feel free
to play around with the demo app
before moving on.