So the number that is
displayed here is 33.
Now the real question is was
the goal accomplished, yes or no?
I'm going to remove
all this down here and
just figure out what should the answer
actually be, should it be 33?
Okay, so here's just the result problem.
Now to figure out sleep debt, you should
be taking the amount of sleep that you
need and subtracting the amount
of sleep that you actually got.
So what is the amount
of sleep that you need?
Well we're assuming that you need
8 hours of sleep in a night.
So we have 8 hours, and
we should multiply the number of hours
that you need in a single night by the
number of nights in a week, which is 7.
Okay, and that number is 56.
So the next question is, how much
sleep did this person actually get?
Well, on the average weekday
night they slept 5 hours.
Well, how many weekdays
are there in a week?
There are 5.
So I'm going to multiply the 5
hours they slept each night
by the 5 week days there are in a week.
Now on the weekend, this person
got a little bit more sleep and
they slept 9 hours.
Saturday and Sunday are the two weekend
nights where they averaged 9 hours, so
I'll multiply the 9 by 2.
Now you're going to need to add
the weekday sleep that they got.
And the weekend sleep that they got, to
get how much sleep in total they got for
the entire week.
25 plus 18 is 43.
So now we have the sleep that they
got and the sleep that they need.
If we take the sleep that they need and
subtract out how much they actually got
we'll see how many hours of
sleep debt that they acquired.
Basically, how many hours of extra
sleep that they should be getting.
Now 56 minus 43 is 13, which is bad
if they need 13 extra hours of sleep.
But it's not nearly as bad as the 33
hours that our program calculated.
Okay, so what went wrong?
Well, let's remember the calculations
we did here and go back to the code and
see if it's basically
doing the same thing.
Okay, so here's the numbers that
I calculated in my head before.
Again, I need 56 hours of sleep,
on weekdays I'm getting 25,
on the weekend I got 18,
which equals out to 43 hours total
sleep which is 13 hours of sleep debt.
Issue is, here I'm printing 33.
So what went wrong?
Well.
I started things off well
by saying that a week day,
I get 5 hours a sleep,
in a weekend I get 9 hours of sleep.
That matches up.
And then, I also calculate the number of
optimal hours correctly, by taking the 8
hours that the user should be sleeping
each night and multiply it by 7.
The issue here is the calculation
with actual hours.
It's kind of a mess.
I am calculating the number of
weekend hours I get correctly.
I'm taking weekend,
which is set correctly up here, and
multiplying it by 2, so this is good.
But I'm not doing really this
calculation where I take the number of
weekday hours I need and multiply it
by the number of weekdays there are.
There's no multiplication by five here.
This line of code actually
isn't very helpful.
I'm going to remove this line of code.
Now I haven't declared actual hours
anymore, because I just removed it.
So I have to put the end here.
To actually properly
declare actual hours.
And then this shouldn't be actual hours.
It should be this calculation over here.
The amount of sleep that
I need in one weekday,
which is stored in the variable weekday.
Multiply it by 5.
And the solution is again
the subtraction of the optimal hours,
minus the actual hours that I got.
Which is the same sort of
calculation that I'm doing here, and
it should be 13.
So let's see, with this change,
if it actually works.
I'm going to hand simulate again.
Okay, looking at the first line, as I'm
hand simulating, weekday is equal to 5.
And then we have weekend equal to 9 and
optimal hours equal to 7 times 8.
Okay, I removed this line of code,
so I'll go down here.
We have a new variable,
actual hours, and this is equal to
the value of weekday times 5 plus
the value of weekend times 2.
The value of weekday,
if I go over here I see that it's 5 and
the value of weekend,
I see over here, is 9.
5 times 5 is 25, 9 times 2 is 18,
add those two together, we get 43.
And then we have a new
variable solution.
And solution is the optimal
hours minus the actual hours.
Optimal hours is currently set to 56.
Actual hours is currently set to 43.
I do 56 minus 43 and I get 13.
And that basically followed
the same order of steps that I
did mentally when I was
trying to solve this problem.
Okay, looks correct, looks good.
Again, we looked at sort of two powerful
tools here, the first of which was using
hand simulation to kind of get a general
sense of what the code was doing.
The other thing that we did was look
at the goal for the program and
sort of think about the steps
that we ourselves as humans,
thinking humans would do
to come with the answer.
And we compared the two.
What was the code doing?
What would we do?
And in this case,
where there are differences between what
the code was doing and what we would do,
we resolved those differences
by changing around the code.
And that fixed things.
So let's move on to the next problem.
You're going to be seeing a lot
of problems in this format and
I highly suggest that you
use both hand simulation.
And sort of calculating itself in your
head to help solve these problems.
Okay so you're going to get
a lot more practice in part two.
Go ahead and
move on to the next exercise.