We've solved several examples of
systems of planes now using galaxy and
elimination.
Before we start tackling
the programming aspect of this problem,
let's take a few minutes to
review some characterizations
of systems of equations that will
help us in programming the algorithm.
Here's the first question.
Which of the following statements
will be necessarily true
about a system of equations
that has no solution?
And which statements are sufficient to
prove that a system has no solution?
And let's assume for now that we're only
talking about systems of equations in
three dimensions.
The first statement is,
the planes defined by the equations do
not have a common intersection point.
The second statement is, there are more
than three equations in the system.
And the third statement is, we encounter
an equation of the form 0 = k for
some non-zero number k while
doing Gaussian elimination.
Check the appropriate boxes
next to each statement.