In the last lesson, we explored whether or not me singing a song that I write
about hypothesis testing, will increase students' engagement and learning. In
our example, we pretended like we were testing this special musical lesson on a
sample of 20 students. And then, asking them to self-assess their learning and
engagement in the course as a whole. Then we pretended that after getting the
results from this pilot test, we found that both the average learning and
engagement scores were above those of the entire population, all of whom,
except for these 20 students, had not seen the musical lesson. Furthermore, we
found that the probability of getting at least the mean learning score that we
did in this pilot test was about 18%. So, that's a probability of getting this
mean or higher. However, the probability of getting at least the mean
engagement score for thse 20 students was less than 1%. So, here's a way to sum
up our findings. Here are the dependent variables, student engagement and
student learning. And we've found that when we tested this musical lesson on 20
students, we got these means for engagement and learning, when students
reported these measures on a scale from 1 to 10. And the probability of getting
this mean is less than 0.01, or 1%. The probability of getting this mean was
about 18%. And remember, that's when we look at where these means fall on the
distribution of sample means from all samples of size 20. So now, do you think
that these probabilities are likely or unlikely? At this point, there's no
right or wrong answer. In fact, this is an example where statistics is up to
your own interpretation, so tell us what you think.