Our next question is
about a botnet operator.
So let's say it compromises a number
of computers in an organization.
These computers are running malware
[INAUDIBLE] by the bots, and
they're sending lots of spam email, but
they don't look at any sensitive data.
They're all just using
the computational resources and
the network resources to
pump out lots of spam.
So, sensitive data, they don't do that,
or they don't even interfere with any
legitimate activities that may
be going on on those machines.
So, if this happens,
tons of spam email sent by computers
on your network, what should you do?
I guess this is one of those situations,
again, where compromises happened, and
when something goes wrong,
how do we respond to it?
That's what we're thinking about here.