This question is answered the same way we discussed this kind of questions in class.
A and B are d-separated. Therefore, they are actually independent.
The first question is true.
However, if we know E, they are not d-separated any more by the evidence that we get at E.
It's the explain away effect.
A and B are now dependent. The statement is false.
The same is true for G back here, because G gives information about E,
and therefore breaks the d-separation of A and B. The statement is false.
If we add F, the state is true between A and B,
because F is not in the line between A and B.
Finally, the final statement is also true.
A and C meet at H, but G doesn't really give evidence
that would allow us to explain away A versus C. The statement is actually true.