So at the bottom of this stack of
turtles is a turtle named Hoeffding and
Hoeffding gives us the solution to
all of the rest of the turtles.
There's actually a bunch of
different names for this.
I've heard churn off,
I've heard other things, tail bounds,
which you can see that the tale is
bound, I kind of forgot to draw it.
That all kind of boiled
down to the same thing.
So, I apologize to any person who may
have derived one of these bounds who I
didn't show proper appreciation to.
But, this is the general flavor of it.
>> Well, I think the most important
thing is that you find someone,
who did the derivation, who's Greek.
Since all the turtles are greek.
>> Except for Hoeffding,
as it turns out.
So, here's the form of
the Hoeffding bound.
So, Hoeffding bound says that if we
have a set of n random variables,
X1 through Xn.
And let's say that they're all iid,
which is independent and
identically distributed.
And each one has a mean of mu.
And let's, so
let's say that we observe these values.
So it's bunch of zero ones.
Mu hat could be a good estimate of mu,
right?
It's like add up all the variables that
you saw, all the zeroes and ones and
divide by the number
of them that you saw.
>> In other words,
the maximum likelihood mean.
>> Yes, which is exactly
the maximum likelihood estimate.
But so
it's the maximum likelihood estimate.
But the bigger n gets, the more
confident we get as to how we are to it.
So this gives us a way
of quantifying this.
So the following is a 100 times 1 minus
delta percent confidence interval
for mu.
Right?
So we don't know mu, but
we know mu hat because we can get it
just by averaging these values together.
We're going to say that the real mu
is highly likely to be between mu
hat minus z delta over root n.
And mu hat plus z delta over root n.
Where z delta is the square root of
1/2 times log of two over delta.
>> Oh right, that's obvious.
>> Well, it's maybe not obvious but it
does have the right kind of properties.
Like I don't think I could
justify this 2 without
going through the detailed
derivation of the bound.
But why is delta where it is?
Well, the more confident
that we want to be.
The smaller delta gets.
And that means that this
quantity gets bigger.
The log of that is still very big.
The square root of
that is still very big.
So this Z delta is very big.
And so the width of this
bound ends up being very big.
If we want to be really, really sure,
we need to give a big window, so
that we're really sure
that we're in that window.
But on the other hand,
if we have a lot of data,
if we have a big n here,
that tends to make the bounds smaller.
They shrink with the square root of n.
So if we have a billion for n,
then it's going to be mu plus or
minus some quantity,
divided by something really big.
So it's going to be just a small
little interval around our estimate.
So it has the right kind of properties.
But the fact that it's a square root of
a log and there's a 2 and a one half,
that's maybe not so obvious.
>> Well, it looks a lot like.
In fact, we use Hoeffding bounds
when we were doing pack learning.
>> Yes, yes and again these learning
results that we were just talking about
have a very pack kind of feel to them.
So, it's maybe not so
surprising that the bottom of the stack
of turtles is a turtle name Hoeffding.
>> That's cool.
So basically,
everything really does all tie together.
>> Yes.
At least as long as you think about
things this way.
So, okay, but this isn't quite
answering our question, but
this is going to be the key tool for
answering our question.
So given that we have a way of
knowing how close we are to
estimating a hidden
parameter from a sample.
We can then use that to figure out how
many times do we have to pull an arm
before we know fairly
accurately what its payoff is.
And therefore,
if we have K arms, how many times we
have to pull each of those arms, so
that we are very confident that we find
something nearly optimal amongst them?
>> Beautiful.
I don't yet know how this is
going to solve everything, but
I can see how it is a step
in the right direction.