So, let's talk about your orientation assignment.
Computing the best orientation, okay?
Well, that's actually pretty easy.
Remember the gradient and we had different operators for doing the gradients?
So, what we're going to do is we're going to computer the image gradient out
all these points and
then, locally, we're going to compute some estimate of orientation.
And the way we do that is really pretty simple.
So nominally, this is your image area with a little line drawing and
it just shown here.
But the idea is, you're going to build a histogram.
Okay, this is our little histogram where you've cut the angle of
orientation into some number of bins.
In this particular case, they're using 36 bins of orientation.
You know, which, what's the right number to use is, is a question.
All right, and then what you do is you say I've got a peak, and
I'm going to say, okay, that peak.
That's my dominant orientation.
And that's going to be the the orientation that we use.
Okay? Once we've picked that, that becomes essentially our new north.
Okay? We're saying that's,
that's the way we're going to think about our window here.
Now once we've done that, notice, we found it in x, y so
we've removed the translation problem.
That is we know where it is.
We found it in scale when we detected the the, the interest point to begin with.
We've picked this scale.
And now we have a new orientation.
So what that means is that whatever descriptors we build are going to be
invariant to the transformation in x, in y, in scale, and in orientation.
And that's what we wanted.