I hope you're starting to
get the hang of Promises.
I've got another challenge for you.
I want you to wrap an Ajax
request in a Promise.
You're now officially in
the catching stage, and don't worry,
it's pretty similar
to the venting stage.
In the instructions I'll be asking
you to add .catch to your promise
as a way to see if there are any errors,
and then do something about it.
Right now you won't be recovering.
You'll simply be console.logging them.
To take this quiz,
you'll be doing your work here,
inside the xoplanetexplorerapp.js file.
Check the instructor notes for its path.
I want you to wrap this XHR
helper method with a Promise.
Unlike the last two quizzes,
a lot can go wrong with a XHR so
you need to include error handling.
Reject if there's an error,
or if the request status
is anything less than 200.
Remember, any value that
you pass to resolve or
reject will get passed to
the next then or catch.
And of course, don't forget to
return the promise from get.
Test your Promise wrapped with this URL,
which, by the way, it might change.
Use whatever you see in the rebuild.
The file that's requested contains
a simulated search response for
the exoplanet explorer app,
and it contains the URLs for
some JSON data of some
Earth-like planets.
Pass the response to add search header
when it resolves, or if it fails to
resolve, catch it by passing unknown
to add search header on reject.
You might try messing up this URL to
make sure your .catch works correctly.
While you're working, I recommend
using gulp serve to watch for
changes and
automatically reload the page.
This is definitely
the fastest way to work.
Anyway, make sure you check
the instructor notes for help and
some more instructions.
Good luck.