We said that inodes play a key role in
keeping track how file is organized on
disk, because they essentially
integrate an index
of all of the disk blocks that
correspond to a particular file.
First a file is uniquely
identified by its inode.
In the virtual file system,
inodes are uniquely numbered, so
to identify a file we use the number
identifier of the corresponding inode.
This inode itself will contain a list of
all of the blocks that
correspond to the actual file.
So it will be like an index into
the blocks of the actual storage device.
That when stitched together
give us the actual file.
In addition to this list of blocks,
the inode also has some
other metadata information.
And this is useful to
keep track of whether or
not certain certain file
accesses are legal, or
to correctly updated the status of
the file if it's locked or not locked.
Or other things.
One simple way in which this
can be used this as follows.
A file name is mapped to a single inode.
And an inode, let's say here
that it corresponds to a block.
So the file jeep points to the block 19.
That is the inode for
this particular file.
The contents of this
inode block are all of
the other blocks that constitute
the contents of the file.
If you look here we see that this
file has five blocks allocated to it,
and if we turn aside that
we need more storage for
these files, as per, pending per
writing more data into the file.
The file system will allocate a free
block, lets say in this case,
this block 30.
It will correctly update
the inode data structure,
the list of blocks to say that the next
node in the system is this node 30.
And so the actual representation of the
file on disk will now look as follows.
The benefit of this approach is that
it's easy to perform both sequential or
random accesses to the file.
That for sequential we just need to get
the next index into this list of blocks.
For random access we just,
based on the block size need to compute.
Which particular block
reference do we need to find.
And so
it's fairly straightforward to do this.
The downside is that this limits
the size of the file to the total
number of blocks that can be indexed
using this linear data structure.
Let's take a look at this example.
Let's say we have 128 byte inodes.
And let's say they only contain
these indexes to the blocks on desk.
Supposedly, we have 4 bytes to
address individual block on this.
So that means that the maximum
number of block pointers,
of block addresses, that can be
included in this inode is 32 of those.
That's if we don't have
any metadata in the inode.
If we assume that a single block is 1
kilobyte, that means that the maximum
number of a file that can be addressed
using this inode data structure.
That's represented in this way,
is 32 kilobytes.
That clearly is very restrictive.