So let's take a look at some spectra of some real images and
some examples, okay?
So here's one.
Now, if you remember, this is Lena from way back in 1972,
and this is no relative of Lena whatsoever, okay?
You'll notice that, just looking at the image, you know,
there's a lot of power in the middle and then stuff falls out towards the edges.
And that's to like I'd said, it's often the case,
that natural images have similar power spectra.
And what really matters for reconstructing the image would be the phase.
We're not doing reconstruction here, we're only looking at the magnitude.
So suppose I wanted to get rid of the high-frequency content.
Well here's what you could do, and
we'll talk about using the inverse Fourier transform next time.
But I could take Lena, I could take her power spectrum.
I could remove all the stuff out here, and then I could reconstruct it.
You can see that there's all these ugly lines in here, okay?
That's what's referred to as ringing.
This ringing happens because this actually doesn't have any high frequency at
all, but
you actually needed the high frequency to smooth out those little edges.
Okay, and so when I remove them, I end up with having just these little ripples,
and that's referred to as ringing.
And here's an example of doing the other thing, we take Lena, okay?
We remove the stuff out of the middle so you can see this thing zeros there, and
you'll notice that what's left here is essentially an edge image.
And if you think about that,
the high frequency components are giving you where the edges are, 'kay?
And we'll, we'll also look a little bit
more about that when we talk about aliasing.
Couple more things real quick here.
Remember our sharpening filter?
So our sharpening filter sharpened the image by subtracting,
by giving you twice the original image, minus a little bit of blurring.
So what's happened here is this is our Lena again.
And if you compare this one to this one, you'll notice that there's a little bit
more bright stuff out here than there was there.
And you'll notice that this picture is, in fact, sharper than that picture, and
that's because we've accentuated the high frequencies.
And one more here.
So here's a cool texture.
Here's our brick texture, right, that has mostly these lines here but
a few of these there.
And what you can see is you basically have just the verticals here,
horizontals there.
Okay. And then in this picture, okay, you've got all these angled lines and
that's what's showing up as all these angled sinusoids in here.