Before we try to optimize our UI for
tablets and larger screens,
we need to first understand what
we're optimizing the UI for.
Let's dig into a couple of
things we should be watching for
when designing for larger screens.
For starters, we know we want to
optimize for a balanced use of space.
If you look at your UI
as blocks of black and
white, it shouldn't feel lopsided.
And you shouldn't see big
seas of white space that
throw off the horizontal symmetry.
Content should be relatively even across
the screen, or at least centered.
We also want to optimize the reading
comfort for blocks of text.
That includes a couple of things.
First, you obviously want to make sure
that your font size isn't too small.
Next, you want to sure that your
line length isn't too long.
Lines under 45 characters long or
over 75 characters long
are considered harder to read.
So staying within the 45 to 75
character limit is recommended.
You'll also want the text
margins to be large enough
to visually separate
text from its container.
Margins make it easier for your eye to
jump to the next line as you're reading.
And you'll want the right spacing or
leading, too.
Too little will make text feel cramped.
But too much, may make lines
of text seem disconnected.
As a general rule,
your text margins should be larger
than the space between each line.
Remember the Gestalt
principles from lesson three?
They apply to lines of text too.
So, reading comfort is important.
Image quality is another focus area.
If we show photos in the app,
we need to make sure they don't scale up
too much from their original size so
they remain sharp and beautiful.
We may also want to
minimize cropping and
try to maintain
the original aspect ratio.
These will play big factors
in layout decisions.
Additionally, we want to optimize for
maintaining context when we have space.
If a detail screen doesn't
need a lot of space,
let's try to think how we can show it
in context of its previous screen,
using something like a dialogue, or just
showing surrounding auxiliary content.
And finally, let's optimize for
a clean, clear and beautiful aesthetic.
There's an art to this, and
practice makes perfect.