Well, for data buffering, that's really a facilitation.
It makes the system work better, but
it's not in itself a major communication of either data or control.
Acknowledgement, guaranteed delivery, multiplexing, transactions,
scheduling, synchronization, all about the collaboration aspects of,
that a particular connector could provide.
As far invocation is concerned, there is a collaboration aspect there, but
there's also a data transmission aspect as far as the parameters are concerned.
Dynamic reconfiguration is a, an advanced technique for
making a system run better at runtime.
So that's a facilitation operation, as is load balancing.