In this example, I'd like you to calculate a gradient image.
I'm giving you a relatively simple image of size 3 by 3
with the following greyscale pixel values:, 2, 0, 2, 4, 100, 102, 242.
And for the sake of this exercise, I'd like to retain another 3 by 3 image,
so we'll assume that all the values outside the image are just zero.
What I'm asking you is to compute a 3 by 3 matrix
that is the result of convolving this image with the following kernel:
minus 1 on the left, zero, and 1.
Then take the absolute value of each pixel, so you're going to ignore the minus sign,
which is clearly an nonlinear operation.
Please apply this kernel to the image over here.
For each pixel, down here you get a linear combination of applying this kernel
from the values over here, assuming these off image values are all zero.
We then take the absolute--drop the minus sign--and please plug in the number over here.