Here are the conclusions that
we can draw from these results.
If we look at the cases for a and b, if
we remember from the table that we saw
with the actual experiments,
in these cases we had a fairly
nice mix of tasks with different
CPI values on each of the cores.
So in these cases, the processor
pipeline was well utilized and
we're obtaining a high IPC.
It is not the maximum IPC of 4, so
the maximum performance that one can
obtain on the processor that they will
be simulating, but it's fairly high.
If we'll look at the cases for c and d,
in these experiments each of the cores
was assigned tasks that have
much more similar CPI values.
In fact, in the case of d,
every single one of the cores ran tasks
that had the exact same CPI value.
So if we take a look at these results,
we see that the total IPC is much lower
than what we saw for the case a and b.
The reason for that is that on some
cores, like on core zero in particular,
but also on core one, there is a lot
of contention for the CPU pipeline.
So these are the cores that mostly
had tasks with a low CPI, so
mostly the compute
intensive tasks were here.
On the other hand, cores two and
three, they contribute very little
to the aggregate IPC metrics.
So basically, they really execute only
very few instructions per cycle or
a few, small percentage of
an instruction per cycle rather,
given that a maximum is one.
The reason for that is that we
mostly have memory intensive tasks
on these two cores and
that leads to wasted cycles on them.
So by running this experiment,
Fedorova confirmed her hypothesis
that a running tasks that have
mixed CPI value is a good thing,
that that will lead to an overall
high performance of the system.
So the conclusion from these results
is that CPI's a great metric.
And therefore,
we should go ahead and build hardware
that has a CPI hardware counter and
tracks this value so that we can then go
ahead and also build operating system
schedulers that use this value in order
to schedule the right workload mix.
Not so fast.
In our discussions so
far in the experimental analysis,
we used a workloads that had CPI
values of one, six, 11 and 16.
And the results showed that if we have
such a hypothetical workload that has
such distinct and widely spread out CPI
values, the scheduler can be effective.
But the question is, do realistic
workloads have CPI values that
exhibit anything that we used
in the synthetic workload?
To answer this,
Fedorova profiled a number of
applications from several
benchmark suites.
And these benchmark suites are widely
recognized in industry and
in academia as well that they include
workloads that are representative of
real world, relevant applications.
And let's look at the CPI values for
all of these benchmarks.
We see that they're all
sort of cluttered together.
They are in such distinct CPI
values like one, six, 11,
and 16 as what she used in
her experimental analysis.
What this tells us is that although
in theory it seems like a great
idea to use cycles for
instruction as a scheduling metric for
hyperthread of platforms, in practice,
real workloads don't have
behavior that exhibit significant
differences in their CPI value,
and therefore CPI really
won't be a useful metric.
So I showed you a paper about
something that doesn't work.
There's still some very important
takeaways from this paper.
First, you learn about SMTs and some of
the resource contention issues there,
specifically regarding the processor
pipeline as a resource.
Next, you learn how to think about the
use of hardware counters to establish
some kind of characteristics about
the workload, to understand it better so
that you can better inform the operating
system level resource management.
In addition, you learn that it is
important to design schedulers that will
also think about resource contention,
not just about load balancing.
For instance,
a scheduler should think about choosing
a set of tasks that are not going to
cause a resource contention with
respect to the processor pipeline, or
the hardware cache, or the memory
controller, or some type of I/O device.
So these principles generalize
to other types of resources,
not just to the processor pipeline
in hardware multithreaded platforms.
And by the way, in Fedorova's follow-on
work, as well as several other efforts,
it's been established that particularly
important contributor to performance
degradation when you're running
multiple tasks on a single hardware,
multithreaded or multi-core platform,
is the use of the cache resource,
in particular the last level cache.
So what that has told us is to,
for instance,
keep track of how a set of threads
is using the cache as a resource and
pick a mix that doesn't cause contention
on the last level cache usage.
And this is just for your information.
We're not going to look in any
additional papers that really further
explore this issue,
not in this course at least.