So this one is intended
to be kind of a warmup.
So you might want to go just
with your intuition on this.
So what would you think the value of Q
prime (s,a) is as a function of Q(s,a).
Keep in mind that we
scaled all the rewards up.
Think of it like by
a factor of a thousand.
>> My intuition about that is
actually pretty straight forward.
What I want it to be is just
I want Q prime of s,a just
to be c times Q of s,a.
>> In other words,
if we double all of the rewards,
it should double all of the Q values.
If we halve all of the rewards,
it should halve all of the Q values.
That sort of thing.
>> Right and that makes sense at least
to me conceptually if nothing else.
Reward is your reward and
the Q value is the true reward you get.
The summation of all of
the rewards you're going to get.
So, if I double the rewards,
then I should double the value.
>> Yeah that's good.
So that is the right answer.
And I just want to go through a quickie
derivation to show why that's the case.
Alright so here's how I like to think
about this is what we want to show
is that our Bellman equation for
Q prime and R prime is correct,
that it solves and we get a solution
to the Bellman equation and
since the bellman equation is unique,
the solution
to the bellman equation is unique, then
we must have found the right solution.
So what I did here was I took you
know imagine the Bellman equation
for q prime.
It's like q prime s a equals r
prime s a plus gamma q prime.
So what I'm going to substitute in here
is our guess as to what Q prime is so
that is here and here.
And our definition as to what
R prime is, which is that.
Okay so if this is true, then we have
a solution to the Bellman equation.
>> Right and it's derivitively true.
>> Right.
And so why is this true.
Right because the C here we
can pull it out of the max.
That doesn't, again because C is
positive, it doesn't influence the max.
If c were 0 or
negative it would mess up the max.
But we can factor it out of
the max because it's positive so
it doesn't change the order.
Of what's largest.
It's going to then get multiplied by
these C's, and it's inside the sum, but
it's common to everything in the sum,
so that gets pulled out there, so
we actually get to move this C
all the way out to here, and now,
notice that we can factor it out, well,
it's obvious now, I guess, right?
We just factor the C out from
both sides, and they cancel.
So what we are left
with is this equation,
which is the Bellman equation
that we had already solved.
So this has to be true, so
the original thing has to be true.
>> Right.
That makes sense.
>> Yeah, which is probably
the way you think about it.
>> Yeah, in fact this is exactly
the way I would think about it.
>> Awesome!
All right so
now that we have this down we should be
able to do these other modifications.
The other messing around with
the reward function next.