Now you might be like, XML isn't there
a way in which I can avoid having to add
more code into another language XML,
just to avoid more Java code in my app?
Well, there is something we can use.
As we mentioned before,
Android Studio comes with a full
featured visual layout editor which
is accessed through the design tab.
This layout editor allows us to place
all sorts of stuff onto our layouts.
Such as view the displayed text, or
images, add a text, or
have interactive buttons.
We often refer to these single
purpose views as widgets.
Let's create a new project for this one.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
This is a bit of a free form exercise,
meaning that your solution doesn't
have to be exactly the same as ours.
We're going to practice building
a layout using the layout editor and
the ConstraintLayout.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
A ConstraintLayout is a special kind of
layout that uses complex constraints on
the child views to allow for
dynamic layouts that respect
different window sizes.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So we added ConstraintLayout
to the project and
we changed the root layout of our main
activity to be a ConstraintLayout.
The editor has some special buttons and
controls for
building the ConstraintLayout.
We're going to turn off the second
one that looks like a magnet,
that automatically creates
constraints as we change things.
Let's switch to landscape mode.
Keep dragging stuff around and adding
views until you end up with a layout
that looks approximately like this one.
Or just design something
cool on your own.
Proud of your creation?
Post in in the forums.
There's a really cool code lab
if you want to learn more about
ConstraintLayout in the link.
But we'll cover it in more detail later
on when were fine tuning our UI design.