There are a lot of differently colored
bricks, so the color should be dynamic.
Each brick will also have
a different size and price.
The section heading will not change no
matter what brick is being displayed, so
it doesn't need to be dynamic.
Now for the description,
this one's a little tough.
It really depends on what
the rest of the text is.
If it's a generic description of bricks,
then the same description
can be used for every brick.
If it's specific for each brick,
then it will need to be dynamic.
This description looks kind of generic,
so
I'm choosing to leave this hard coded.
So these three should be
converted to dynamic expressions.
To convert these into variables that
will be set in a brick controller,
I'll convert green to brick.color,
two by four to brick.size and
three cents to brick.price.
Don't forget the double curly braces
to actually make these expressions.
We've looked at tempelating and
how it works in angular,
now let's take a look at controllers
to see how a template gets its data.