The host command is a basic utility for
looking up records in DNS.
It will query your OS name service.
Which usually ends up sending a request
to whatever DNS server your computer's
configured to use.
If you're running it on an easy
to instance like I am here.
It will send a query to Amazon DNS
server which can in turn retrieve
records from other
servers on the Internet.
There are lots of kinds of DNS
records but the default one for
looking up the addresses of IPv4 hosts
is an a type of record for address.
You can use the host command and to
look up a DNS name such as google.com,
and get back an IP address.
Take a quick look through the beginning
of the manual page for host or
man host and then try it out yourself.
Use the host command to
look up the IP address for
any website of your choice and here,
you put what site you chose and
in here what results you
got from the host command.