(Sebastian) So welcome to our last and final office hours in the introduction to artificial intelligence.
The fact that you're watching them means you're an amazing student, you've gotten this far,
and you're just about to hit the final exam.
(Peter) Congratulations to everybody for making it this far. It's been a great experience interacting with you
and getting a chance to teach this class. Let's go to some of the questions you had this week.
(Sebastian) So here's a question by (Dudur) from New Jersey. "I thoroughly enjoyed this class." Thank you.
"Would it be possible for us to use our email addresses," that you provided, "to notify you of future classes?
"I would be very interested in taking additional online classes. Thanks for an awesome class."
(Peter) Yeah, so I never had somebody say, "Please spam me," before, but if that's what you want, then yes,
We can notify you. (Sebastian) But that isn't spam, come on. (Peter) No, no. (Sebastian) Email you want.
(Peter) This would be welcome mail. So, sure, we'll keep you posted. (Sebastian) Yeah, it's been a privilege,
actually, having all of you in class, and it'd be great to have you in future classes, if we do some.
"It's been an amazing experience. I'd just like to know if there's going to be a continuation of the class next semester?
"Say, advanced A.I.? Or something along those lines, like introduction to robotics." This is from Vikram360
in Bangalore, India. (Peter) Well, Sebastian and I are about to take a little vacation at the end of this week.
We're both taking off. So there won't be anything right away. In the spring there'll probably be more,
although I think we're looking more at lower level courses rather than advanced classes as the next step.
But there'll be more classes coming up. Stanford is offering another set of classes.
There's one on natural language processing in A.I. and one on machine learning and one on probabilistic graphical models,
so there is lots of opportunities for other classes.
(Sebastian) ]"How long will the lectures be available after the class? I've missed a few--work plus seven-month-old twins."
(Peter) Congratulations. (Sebastian) Congratulations, (unintelligible--children's names)
"And would like to refer back to them, without the interactive bits, perhaps, or at least I would like to be able to take notes.
"And thanks for the excellent course."
(Peter) Well, you're welcome. Yeah, so the videos are up on YouTube, and I guess they'll stay there.
We're a little bit torn about trying to figure out what to do with the class after it's gone.
We want the materials to be available for everybody to see whenever they want to see them.
But on the other hand, we really appreciated what happened in terms of the interaction in this class,
where you all were participating in discussion forums with each other, and the material is always there,
then there's not that possibility of bringing people together at a specific time.
So I think that at least the videos themselves will always be available, but in terms of running it as a class,
we'll probably keep doing that at specific time periods.
(Sebastian) So Anwar Asharia from Kathmandu, Nepal, a city I'd love to go to at some point, asks the question,
"I'd like to suggest providing a download package for the quizzes and videos on Flash or some app,
"for future reference or for the advanced track students."
(Peter) Yeah, I think that's a great idea. We've certainly had a lot of people talk about the problems of
getting enough bandwidth and slow connections and so on. So I think we should have some way of
delivering that locally or mailing out media or some way to get it available to you.
(Sebastian) Julia (unintelligible) asks, Italy, "I would like to know your opinion of your goal to make this class
"to make this class the same level as Stanford's class is achieved, but I think you have to make adjustments."
And she says, "Thanks so much for this opportunity."
So I think we did achieve the goal. It's somewhat different from the in-class experience, which is more lecture-centered,
and we deliberately made it more tutorial-esque, which is we asked lots of questions.
But the material covered is the material we cover in the Stanford class, and the quizzes and homework assignments,
exams are identical. And we will, of course, release statistics afterwards to see how online students scored
in comparison with the Stanford students. But I can assure you, what you've learned is as much and
as little as Stanford students learn in this class.
(Peter) I agree with that in terms of material--it's the same material. The only difference was in terms of
the programming assignments that the Stanford students did, and we just didn't feel like we could handle
the logistics of doing all that. And hopefully next time we'll figure out how to handle programming assignments as well.
(Sebastian) Question by Sayitt, no location. "What would you recommend for someone who might be interested
"to pursue research in artificial intelligence? For example, as a Ph.D. Whose only exposure (unintelligible) was this class."
(Peter) I would say get some more exposure. Take one of the other classes, read some books, read some articles,
work on a project. Either start a project of your own or join an existing project, and get some more experience,
both to see if you like it and it's really for you, and to get a chance to prove yourself.
(Sebastian) Yeah, and to me it's all about pursuing passion. So if you're in the age where you can afford
taking time off and get into a university--maybe you are a student already--just do it.
When I worked at my initial college in Hinterstein, there wasn't anybody teaching A.I.
And when I moved to University of Bonn, there was one professor, but what he taught wasn't relevant to modern A.I.
So I mostly just did it by myself because I really cared. And if you work really hard and you're going to be excited,
then, and you wait long enough, then all of a sudden doors open themselves, and you find yourself,
I don't know, as a professor, if you wait long enough and work hard enough.
It's a fascinating thing. The Ph.D. in general I think is an amazing experience, in that it really affords you a couple of years
of time to do free thinking, and you learn the skill of how to become a researcher.
And I wouldn't want to miss a day of Ph.D. experience at this point. In fact, I often think back how good life was
as a Ph.D. student, when I didn't have to work really hard, because I didn't have to teach classes
and bring in research grants and all this work.
Okay, here's one from Siri in Rockford, Illinois. I like your iPhone app.
The question is, "What's the criteria for getting into Stanford? Will taking this class help?"
(Sebastian) So I just want to point out, this is not the Siri of Apple. It's a marketing--it's a real person named Siri.
(Peter) It's a different Siri. (Sebastian) Which is much more interesting, much more valuable than what Apple
has put out, even though I like Siri on Apple. Now, it turns out getting into Stanford is a bit of an art.
There's a number of formal requirements, such as you have to take, for undergraduate, an SAT,
and for graduate admission, a GRE. And if you look at the test results, you'll already have a good guess
whether you have a chance. Specifically for graduate admissions, it's good to have research experience.
It's really important to write an enticing, engaging, but really honest statement of purpose.
Honesty is a really big thing here. Be excited, but we get a good number of statements that we think aren't quite
kind of overdone. And then the last thing that's really important is, if you have done great work
and done it in a university setting or some other setting, there's probably who could attest to this.
So find really good letter-writers. It's not important that the letter-writers are famous; it's much more important
that they know you really well. So don't go for famous people, go for people who know you really well.
And they have to write you a really excited letter to get into Stanford, of any other college.
(Peter) I'd say when I finished my undergrad and then I worked for two years and then I decided to go back
to grad school and I looked at the Stanford application. And at that time they actually published the scores
of everybody who was admitted the previous year. And I looked at those and I saw all the perfect scores,
and I said, "Maybe I should apply someplace else," and I ended up, Berkeley took me and Stanford didn't.
(Sebastian) Oh, what a loss for Stanford. What did they know? I guess the first time I applied was as a faculty member
at Stanford. That was my first interview. Don't get intimidated. There's many, many amazing people out there.
What I find generally sad is that there's many more amazing people than Stanford and MIT and Berkeley can take.
And I wish this was a more open situation, that people could also-- I don't know, not everyone's life is perfect.
Sometimes you spend a couple years doing something else, and it looks a little bit shabby on a c.v.,
but usually an amazing person. I'm pretty sure that my c.v. would have been completely inadequate to be admitted
to Stanford, because I came from what, at the time, was the worst computer science department in Germany.
Ranked number 53 out of 53 computer science departments. And there's a path.
And if you don't get admitted to Stanford, just enjoy what you're doing, and do it well, and enjoy the moment.
I think much more important than any school, in my opinion.