So here's what we're going to do.
It turns out that it's sort of
complicated to keep track of where all
the max's and
the differences are in absolutes.
So we're going to make
a simplifying assumption, which is,
that the largest value in
our f function is bigger or
equal to the largest
value in our g function.
And I'm going to say we're going to
assume that without loss of generality.
Why is that okay?
>> Because if it weren't true,
we'd just swap f and g around.
>> Yeah, that's all.
I mean, we'll just call f.
Of the two functions
that we're comparing.
Call f the one that has the larger
max or larger or equal.
I guess, if they were equal.
If the maxes on the two were equal,
then it doesn't matter.
But we want f to have
the larger of the two.
What's that's going to do is going to
simplify some of our thinking with
the absolute value symbols.
Because otherwise,
the case analysis get's really tedious.
>> Hm, we can't have that.
Okay, I can't wait to
see where this goes.
>> All right, so ultimately,
we're going to be trying to compare
this quantity to this quantity.
So let's start off writing
this quantity on the left.
And then we're going to reduce it
step by step until we get
the quantity on the right.
So here's where we start.
What can we do with this?
Well given that we know that the max
of f(a) is bigger than the max of g(a),
because that's we were assuming
when we named f and g.
We can get rid of the absolute
value signs, yay.
>> Mm.
>> Now, because we're finally going
to come clean on this issue that
you were talking about before, which is
that these are kind of different a's.
And it would be good,
if we gave them different names.
So let's actually do that.
Let's actually say that,
a1 is argmax f(a) and a2 is argmax g(a).
>> Mm-hm.
>> So now we can rewrite this different,
max a f(a) minus max a g(a),
much more simply.
And it's just the difference between the
corresponding values in the function.
>> Sure.
>> All right, so
if you let me get away with that,
now you're in trouble,
because the next step is going to
follow pretty easily from this.
But it's going to take us
into a whole new realm.
So now, we said that this quantity
is equal to the difference
at a1 of the f function and
the value at a2 of the g function.
So since this a2 was chosen
to maximize the g function,
then any other a that we
could substitute in here,
let's just say a1, can only make this
smaller, or it can make it no bigger.
>> Right.
>> All right, so the g(a2) versus g(a1),
g(a1) is going to be smaller than or
equal to g(a2).
>> Yeah.
>> But since we're negating that in this
equation, that means it can only make
this quantity smaller than or
equal to the previous quantity.
>> That's That's kind of amazing.
That's a neat trick.
>> Right?
But
intuitively, does this piece
feel okay intuitively now?
Essentially what we're doing is, we're
taking the place where f is maximized at
a1, and
the place where g is maximized at a2.
And we're just sliding over to a number
that's- Well here, think of it this way.
So I find this little piece helpful.
So because of our, without loss of
generality statement, if we think of
this as a number line, we have the f
value at a1 is the largest thing of all.
[LAUGH] It is the king.
>> Mm-hm.
>> The g value of a2 is
>> Some other large value, but
not as large as f(a1).
So if we switch from g(a2) to g(a1),
we have to be going down or
at least not up.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And so if we look at
the difference between these two
quantities,
>> And the difference between
these two quantities, the difference
can only have gotten larger.
And that's what this
equation is showing,
that the difference can only have gotten
larger when we substituted in the a1.
>> Well that's not true.
It could stay the same.
So f(a1), g(a2), and
g(a1) could all be the same number.
But g(a2) cannot be bigger than f(a1),
and g(a1) cannot be bigger than g(a2).
>> Good.
>> No.
That's really clever.
This is cute.
This gets you a way of going from two
completely different variables to
one variable.
>> Right.
>> That's awesome.