So those are our discreet gradients, but now we said we wanted an operator.
Right, we want to mask our kernel that can implement these gradients.
So here's an example of an operator H.
And I'm going to use three rows, and I'll tell you why in just a minute.
For now we only have these two columns.
So the question is, is this a good operator?
>> No. >> No, it's not a good operator.
Why is it not a good operator?
Well there's a couple reasons.
One of which is there is no middle pixel.
So it's hard for me to say that this pixels value because the question is
what's special about the right.
It's should be, I could also be able to go to the left.
So, if I wanted to do that what might I do?
Well, I might do an operation that looks like that.
I'm going to go to the right here, and the left there.
Now, you might ask yourself why is it a plus a half and minus a half.
>> Why is it?
>> No, ask yourself, don't ask me.
Well, okay, here's why.
It's the average of the right derivative and the left derivative.
And what I mean by that is, the right derivative would be a plus one here, and
a minus one there, okay.
The left derivative would be a plus one here, and a minus one there.
If I wanted to average them, I would add them and divide by two.
So, I add them I get minus 1, 0, 1, and then when I divide by 2.
I get minus one-half and plus one-half, with a 0 in the middle.
So that's why this thing that goes plus a half to the right minus a half to
the left is the average of the left and right derivatives.
Get it?
Cool.