How does first order logic work?
What does it do?
Well, like propositional logic,
we start with a model.
In propositional logic, a model was
a value for each propositional symbol.
So, we might say that the symbol, P,
was true and the symbol, Q, was false.
And that would be a model that
corresponds to what's going on in
a possible world.
In first order logic
the models are more complex.
We start off with a set of objects.
Here, I've shown four objects,
these four tiles.
But we can have more objects than that.
We could say, for example,
that the numbers 1, 2, and
3 were also objects in our model.
So we have a set of objects,
we can also have a set of constants
that refer to those objects.
So I could use the constant names, A,
B C, D, 1, 2, 3.
But I don't have to have a one-to-one
correspondence between constants and
objects.
I could have two different constant
names that refer to the same object.
So I could also have, say, the name CEE,
that refers to this object.
Or I could have some of the objects
that don't have any names at all.
But, I've got a set of constants and
I also have a set of functions.
And a function is defined as
a mapping from objects to objects.
And so, for example,
I might have the number of function that
maps from a tile to
the number on that tile.
And that function, then, would be
defined by the mapping from A to 1, and
B to 3, and C to 3 and
D to 2, and
I could have other functions as well.
And, in addition to function,
I can have relations.
So, for example, I could have
the above relation, and I could say
in this model of the world, the above
relation is a set of two pulls.
Say, A is above B, and C is above D.
So that was a binary relation
holding between two objects,
say, one block is above another block.
We can have other types of relations.
For example,
here's a unary relation, vowel.
And, if we want to say the relation
vowel is true only of the object
that we call A, then that's a set of
tuples of length 1 that contains just A.
We can even have relations
over no objects.
So, say we wanted to have the relation
rainy, which doesn't refer to any
objects at all,
it just refers to the current situation.
Then, since it's not rainy today,
we'd represent that as the empty set,
there's no tuples corresponding
to that relation.
Or, if it was raining, we can say that
it's represented by a singleton set.
And since there's
the arity of rainy is zero,
there'd be zero elements in
each one of those tuples.
So that's what a model in
first order logic looks like.