Okay, now we're going to
look at another example.
We are going to build an email
spam detection classifier.
And how do we do it?
We do it by looking at previous data.
The previous data is 100 emails
that we've already looked that.
Out of these 100 emails, we have
manually flagged 25 of them as spam,
and 75 of them as non-spam.
Now let's try to think of features that
a spam email may be likely to display
and analyze its features.
One feature can be for
example containing the word cheap.
It seems reasonable to think that
an e-mail that contains the word cheap
is likely to be spam.
So, let's analyze this claim.
We look for the word cheap in at least
100 emails and find that 20 out of
the 25 spam ones and five out of the 75
non-spam ones contained the word.
So, we forget about
the rest of the emails and
focus only on the ones that
contained the word cheap.
Okay, so time for a quiz.
Here is the question.
Based on our data,
if an email contains the word cheap,
what is the probability
of this email being spam?
Is it 40%, 60%, or 80%?
Submit your answer below.