Let me go ahead and
show you my implementation for
this exercise, although your code
may be a little bit different.
Let's start with the /restaurants route.
If I'm receiving a get
request from the client,
I should return all of the restaurants
currently stored in my database.
I can do that by making a query
with SQL alchemy like so.
And then serializing and
jsoning the results.
Now, if I'm receiving a post request,
I will want to extract information from
the url parameters in order
to find a new restaurant.
So I retrieve my location and
mealType in the code here.
Next, I will call findARestaurant
on the mealType and location and
start in a variable
called restaurant_info.
So long as restaurant_info isn’t empty,
I can create a new restaurant row in my
database with the restaurant_info
object and commit my changes.
If I find a restaurant did
not come up with any results,
I can return a json message like
this one indicating the error.
Now for my /restaurants/id route.
For all of these requests,
I'm going to want to find the restaurant
with the matching id number of my route.
So I will execute that query here first.
If I received a get request,
I will simply return the restaurant
in a serialized json object.
If I received a put request, there
should be some parameters to update
the information about this restaurant.
I will grab these parameters
from the URL here.
I will only update
the restaurant if there was
actually a parameter
provided in the URL.
So I'll check first and then update.
Finally, I return
an updated JSON object,
once I've committed these changes.
And finally, I add the functionality for
the delete request.
I delete the restaurant,
commit the change, and
return that the restaurant has
been successfully deleted.
Running my tester.py, I see that
all of my tests run successfully.
The solution code for this activity
is provided in the instructor notes.
Please make sure you are able to get
your own version of this web application
running and understand the code
written thus far before continuing on.
Don't hesitate to ask for help in
the forums if you have any questions.