All right look, that was not rocket science, that seemed reasonable.
But the important question to ask, really important question to ask is,
why was that solution intuitive for you?
Why did you say, you know what,
I'm going to take a little average in order to get rid of some of the noise?
What assumptions are you making about pictures, and
by the way, about noise, in coming up with that answer.
All right, so a little thought we come up with,
you're making a couple of key assumptions.
The first assumption is that the real value of
a pixel is probably similar to the values nearby.
Okay.
Otherwise, why would I use the pixels nearby in order to try to
figure out what my real value was?
So okay that was assumption number one.
The other thing that you're assuming.
And for those of you who know a little,
just a little about that problem, though the math etc.
You're basically assuming that each noise that's been added to each pixel is
independent of the noise that's been added to all the other pixels.
And so what that means is if I take the average of the noise,
that's going to tend to, I'm going to assume zero.
That is that sometimes it'll be up, and sometimes it'll be down, and
if I take the average around them, that that will be zero.
So if I have pixels nearby having about the same value are related and
the noise is independent, then the average is the right thing to do.