We are now on to
the last major part of the solution which is Filtering and Emitting.
In part two of the written instructions, I hope you changed the number of
words to keep by changing the integer value TopN.
And now we're on to part three, adding a filter using
a skip words list to the ParseTweetBolt to skip undesirable words.
We first navigate to the ParseTweetBolt.
And at the class level, I created a private string array called skipwords.
Don't forget your new import statement to bring in arrays.
Next, if you followed my hint, you can use your top end visualization to
choose the words to skip that will be Twitter specific.
After doing this multiple times,
notice that I've skipped words like http, https, retweet, follow.
And we do this by scrolling down to the execute method and simply add in
the logic that we emit if the ray does not contain the skip words in the token.
And lastly, we only emit tokens if they have a length greater than three.
And finally, we have our word cloud, and notice this is one of the first times
we can show word cloud without blurring out a lot of nasty words.
In part 4, we complete the trivial step to emit hashtags instead of
words; remembering that hashtags begin with the pound character.
And we can do this simply with the logic.
If token starts with a pound sign, then we emit.
We can make this more efficient by keeping the code flexible for
this example, led to this simple solution.
Once we see that your word cloud is emitting only hash tags,
we can move on to part five and visualize the TopN equals 10 hashtags.
Remember, that's in your topN TweetTopology file.
Change your count to ten.
Once your visualization is running, remember to hit refresh periodically.
What's happening is your D3 array is collecting a number of topN hashtags.
And finally, if you like, you can do forward slash basic and
navigate to that page, and you'll see a simpler visualization that I
created that you can also as a jumping off point for your final project.
Congratulations on tackling and
completing one of the more complex assignments of this course.
And take a screen shot, post to the forum, comment on two others.
And if you like, tweet your image to your followers.
Remember that you compare you solution to lesson three, stage five.
If you continue to have any questions.
Great job.