I want to prove a point that
websites are made up of boxes.
This is an example from D3.JS
Which is a popular, and powerful library
for creating graphics on the web.
This Chord Diagram doesn't even
look remotely box like, yet
I promise you can find boxes.
I've opened up the elements
panel in dev tools,
and by hovering over different elements,
I can see them highlighted on the page.
Do you notice anything interesting?
Yep they're all boxes but take a look
at this a tag this one right here.
It doesn't take up
the whole with of the page.
While this H2 tag does.
Well sort of.
It takes up as much space as it can.
The white space you see on
the edges is actually padding
from the parent element.
In the web dev world we say
that these elements have
different display properties
the two major options for
the display properties are display
block and display inline.
There are others but
they all relate back to these.
Mastered these two, and
you'll pick up the others, no problem.
Okay, so here I have a block element and
an inline element and
I've given both of them borders.
At a high level we say that block
elements take up as much width as
possible while inline elements
are only as wide as needed.
We'll cover this in more detail later.
So check this out.
This is a div.
It stands for division, and
is the most generic block on the web.
Divs are all-purpose block elements
that you'll find pretty helpful.
But what is this?
This is it's box model.