The simplest feature you can get from
images consists of raw color values.
For instance, here is an image of a car.
Let's say you want to find out whether
some region of a new test image
contains a car or not.
What do you do?
Well, using your known car image as is,
you can simply find the image difference
between the car image, and the test
region and see the difference is small.
This basically means subtracting
the corresponding color values,
aggregating the differences and
comparing it with the threshold.
Alternatively, you could compute the
correlation between the car image and
test region and check if that is high.
Either way, this general approach
is known as template matching.
Your known image is the template or
model and you try to match it
with regions of the test image.
Template matching does work in limited
circumstances but isn't very helpful for
our case.
Can you guess why?