We're now going to look at The Kullback-Liebler Divergence or Information.
It's a general method to compare two probability density functions.
Now let's assume we have two models, a model f which is given by a pdf and
a model g, which is given by another pdf.
We can calculate the information of the Kullback-Liebler Divergence
between the model f and g using the following formula.
Here we have taken the logarithm with the natural base of the ratio of f and g.
The model g, can be estimated even by some parameter theta, and
it could be the model that best estimates the model f.
We can use this K-L information or K-L Divergence to
measure the distance or difference between two models as well.
We can think of the K-L Divergence as the information lost when g
is used to approximate f.
Sometimes the K-L Divergence is described as a distance.
However, it's not strictly a distance, since the K-L Divergence between f and
g is not the same as the K-L Divergence between g and f.
So it is more of a directed distance.
This function recognized that it's not symmetric.
In statistical information theory, the K-L
distance is considered one of the most fundamental of all information measures,
in the sense of being derived from minimal of assumptions.
In fact, you have seen the K-L distance before as
relative entropy between two measurements in lesson two.
We will not go into any more details of how we use the K-L Divergence or
similar metrics.
This subject is vast and we invite you to look into
the reference material in the instructor's notes and discuss this in our forum.
We'll now move on to estimating the kernel densities, for
the various bandwidth we have introduced before.
Take a look at the function called getAllKDE in the IPython note book.
This function is used to generate various kernel density estimates.
We use the Silverman's rule as well as various factors of Scott's Rule.
We plot all of them together in the same plot.
Once we have run the code above, we are going to use that function with our
variable x to draw all of the kernel density estimated plots.
Let's run this piece of code.
In general, we have used various different bandwidths to
make different kernel density estimates for variable x.
The actual PDF, has been put in the red dashed lines using a histogram.
In each of these cases,
we have used the Gaussian kernel to do our density estimation.
Now with a kernel density estimate,
we have a general parameter free model of our data.
We can now ask questions about probability.
For example, we know values close to 0 are cases when medicare paid
the health care provider the same, or close to the same amount that was charged.
The rising peak here, to the right,
shows that claims made by most providers, the faction of the total number of
providers is given by the integral under this curve are denied by Medicare.
So now we have formed a single variable kernel density estimate.
We have looked at various ways to compare our estimates and
make sure the values we are getting are optimal.
We have also validated our univariate kernel density estimation model.
We introduced mean integrated square error,
as well as K-L Divergences to look for differences in PDFs.