Let's make our text view
logger more useful by
persisting its state between activity
tear downs using onSaveInstanceState.
onSaveInstanceState takes
a bundle as its parameter.
This bundle is a key value
storage mechanism that we use to
store the data we want to be saved.
Now it can't quite store any data.
Bundles need to be passed between
processes or serialized to a file.
So they support a limited set of types.
That being said,
you can add complex types to a bundle
by having them implement
the parcelable interface.
The parcelable effectively contains the
instructions for how to output an object
to a stream of data, and then
recreate the object from that stream.
We're just going to save off the string
contents of the text view by keying
into the bundle.
We begin by creating our
key string as a constant,
then we override onSaveInstanceState.
First, we'll have it
call it super class.
Then, we'll also log and
append this state.
We'll get the text from our
mLifecycleDisplay text view,
and we'll store it in our bundle.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Finally, in onCreate we check to see if
the savedInstanceState bundle is null.
And if it isn't, we get our
lifecycle callbacks texts by key.
And then call set text on
mLifecycleDisplay with the saved text.