Most editors launch in less
than four our five seconds.
So you'll be making the launch,
at most, a half second faster.
But chances are, you're only
starting your editor once per day.
So to get back that hour that you put
in, you probably have to start and
stop your editor for 20 years or so.
Even though it takes a day to implement,
testing your
app manually on mobile devices is
a much more time-intensive and
cumbersome process that
really doesn't scale well.
So that day is well-invested.
As a front end developer,
you'll be writing lots and lots of HTML.
And most HTML tags need to be closed.
Even though it seems like
a micro-optimization,
this time that you save will
accumulate really, really quickly.
Generating multi-resolution imagery
is a perfect job for go tool.
Even if it takes you have a day to set
up a costumer script, it'll be worth it.