The way we do that for what's called key point localization and,
and key point and interest points are used similarly, key point was
the term used by David Lowe and Sift, we'll talk about that in a minute.
Here is the general idea.
We want to find robust extremus so
maximums, by the way, you can also find minimum, so if you remember for
the the Laplacian, it goes through zero, goes positive to negative.
So we've took the absolute value of that,
say the square, the value that's zero is a good point.
Anyway you want to find robust maxima and minima in both space and scale.
So that's what's drawn here.
We haven't talked a lot about scale space.
But the idea is, you know, I have an image, and
then I could filter that image again and I could filter it some more and
you can think of it as a coarser and coarser scale.
And, I have some point.
And you can think of that point as having neighbors to the left and right.
And you can also think of that point as having neighbors up and
down in scale, and that's referred to as scale space.
A specific way of using that scale space was suggested by David Lowe in
the SIFT paper, but at that point there was specific suggestion of.
Do this difference of gallium pyramid?
What I mean by that is you do it at different scales and over space and
find maximum values in all of those.
Now, sometimes you might long, land along edges.
Okay. So your on a maximum value but it's really just a maximum along an edge.
So what you have to do is you have to eliminate the edge points.
In fact, if you recall we first introduced Laplacian or
Gaussian to find edge points.
Right? Even though it was a circular symmetric operator you're able to
find these edges.
So from way back, from the Harris who said well edges aren't so good for
finding you know, specific locations we want it to be more like a corner.
So basically what you would want to do is, you would want to find points that
have these extreme values, then make sure that, you know, the thresholded, that
they were ex, extreme enough, if you will, and then make sure they're not edges.
So here is a particular method by which it was done and
I, I show you this so you can take a look at the results in a minute.
Basically what was done, was you take your image and
you deal with it an octave at a time, and an octave is a doubling.
So what you do is you make it blurrier and blurrier and blurrier and
blurrier, then you take half, then you reduce that down to half the size, and
make it blurrier and blurrier and blurrier and blurrier, and
what you do is you subtract these off to get your difference of Gaussian images.
Then, within each one of these Gaussian images, you're going to compare a pixel
and in fact, if I go back to this picture here, I'm going to compare this
pixel to each of its eight neighbors and each are in the same plane, and
there are nine neighbors above it and nine neighbors below it.
And if you're a maximum of that, you're going to say aha, I'm an extrema.