In an image, perspective is
the phenomenon where an object appears
smaller the farther away it is from
a viewpoint like a camera, and
parallel lines appear
to converge to a point.
It's seen in everything
from camera images to art.
Many artist use perspective to give the
right impression of an object's size,
depth, and position when viewed
from a particular point.
And let's look at perspective
in this image of the road.
As you can see,
the lane looks smaller and
smaller the farther away it gets from
the camera, and the background scenery
also appears smaller than the trees
closer to the camera in the foreground.
Mathematically, we can characterize
perspective by saying that,
in real world coordinates x, y, and z,
the greater the magnitude of
an objects z coordinate, or
distance from the camera, the smaller
it will appear in a 2D image.
A perspective transform uses this
information to transform an image.
It essentially transforms the apparent
z coordinate of the object points,
which in turn changes that
object's 2D image representation.
A perspective transform warps the image
and effectively drags points towards or
pushes them away from the camera to
change the apparent perspective.
For example, to change this into
a bird's eye view scene, we can
apply a perspective transform that
zooms in on the farther away objects.
This is really useful, because some
tasks, like finding the curvature of
a lane, are easier to perform on
a bird's eye view of an image.
Take this image of a road.
If we just looked at these lane edges,
the left line looks like it's
leaning and curving a little to
the right, but the right lane line
looks like it's leaning to
the left without much of a curve.
By doing a perspective transform and
viewing this same image from above, we
can see that the lanes are parallel and
both curve about the same
amount to the right.
So, a perspective transform
lets us change our perspective
to view the same scene from
different viewpoints and angles.
This could be viewing a scene
from the side of a camera,
from below the camera, or
looking down on the road from above.
Doing a bird's-eye view transform
is especially helpful for
road images because it will also allow
us to match a car's location directly
with a map, since map's display roads
and scenery from a top down view.
The process of applying
a perspective transform
will be kind of similar to
how we applied undistortion.
But this time,
instead of mapping object points to
image points, we want to map the points
in a given image to different desired
image points with a new perspective.
And again, this perspective can be done
for all kinds of different viewpoints,
whether that's from above like with
a map or from different camera angles.
Next, I'll go through how to
apply a perspective transform to
view traffic signs from
different angles using open CV.