Here's a little warm-up exercise to get
you thinking about Parallel Algorithms
on Trees.
Consider the following tree.
By the way, you can store this
tree in an array pool style,
just as you did with linked lists.
In particular,
let's start by numbering the nodes.
Then let's store the tree by storing
the parent of each node in an array.
As a mnemonic device,
I've converted these formerly
undirected edges to directed edges.
Later in this lesson,
you'll see other representations.
Now this array of parents is named P,
and it has one entry per node.
For example,
node two points to node three,
that corresponds to an entry of three
at position two of the parents array.
Let me fill in the rest for you.
Now let's say you want to
find the root of this tree.
Here's an easy Sequential Algorithm.
Start by picking any node.
For the sake of example,
let's pick node one.
Then follow the parent pointers
until you reach the root.
The root will be a node with no parent.
Let's quickly trace this
algorithm's execution.
First, you'll look up the parent of one,
which is eight.
Since eight is not equal to null or
zero, you'll move up the tree.
Then repeat.
In this case, the algorithm stops when
it hits three, which has no parent.
Now the running time of this algorithm
is linear in the number of nodes.
Why?
In the worst case,
you might have a very unbalanced tree.
One might be a the leaf and
you'd have to march up the entire
tree in order to get to root.
So, how do you do this in parallel?
Well, you could explore
all nodes simultaneously.
That is, for
every node, change it's parent, to point
to it's grandparent, if one exists.
Does this process sound familiar?
[SOUND] I'm back.
In these example, nodes one, five, six,
seven, and four all have grandparents.
For example the grandparents of
seven and four are both one.
So according to this idea,
you would visit seven and
four in parallel at the same time and
you would rewrite their parent
pointers to point to the grandparent.
Now if a node has no grandparent then
it must be pointing to the root, so
you'd leave it alone.
Here, neither nodes two or
node eight have grandparents.
So you would repeat this test and jump
process on all nodes yielding this tree.
Notice that after step one nodes one,
two, five and
eight all point to the root
which is node three.
Since the remaining nodes
still have grandparents,
you'd need to repeat this process.
And by the way,
you may be asking yourself,
why can't I just terminate
the search right away?
Why indeed?
Anyway, if you keep going, eventually
every node will point to its own route.
Here's some pseudo code
summarizing this procedure.
The pseudo code will use
two auxiliary routines.
The first one is called hasGrandparent.
HasGrandparent test whether
a given node, K, has a grandparent
give the set of all grandparents P and
it returns a true or false value.
Take a minute to parse the condition.
The second helper routine is adopt.
Adopt sweeps over the nodes in parallel.
If a given node has a grandparent,
then it records the grandparent's ID
otherwise, he records
just the parents ID.
Adopt essentially implements
this pointer jumping step.
Now giving these helper routines,
the algorithm is very concise to state.
It double buffers the parents array.
It's outer loop is sequential and
taking it over all the possible levels.
The maximum number, which is log n.
Now think about that last statement.
Does it make sense why?
At each level it performs
this adoption procedure.
Then before moving on to the next level,
the algorithm just needs
to update current by next.
Now in a practical implementation
you would probably just swap
these rather than copying them.
The final values are the roots and
that's what's returned in R.