Now, that we've created the contract and
the database, we should be
ready to add and retrieve data.
Let's start by implementing a query,
that will retrieve all our guests and
display them in the UI.
But how will we retrieve anything,
when we haven't even added any
guests to the database yet.
Well that's why provided
you with some code,
that will insert fake data
directly into the database.
This way you can test your own query,
and
check if your code works as expected.
Soon afterwards,
we will be implementing adding and
removing guests to complete our app.
>> This exercise we'll be using
the project titled exercise get
all the data.
To retrieve all the data in a database,
we need to run an SQL query that will
select everything in the waitlist table.
And to be able to run SQL
queries in Android, we will be
using the DB helper clause, that we
created in the previous exercise.
So, the first thing to
do is in main activity.
So the first thing to do,
in main activity is to declare
a variable of type SQL like database.
This will be our reference to the actual
SQL database linked into this App.
And then, inside the main activities
onCreate method declare and
initialize a dbHelper object from
the waitlistDbHelper class and
pass in this as the context.
Then, set the NDB database to
dbHelper.getWritetable database.
If we weren't inserting any data but
just interested in reading data,
we could use a getReadableDatabase
instead of getWritableDatabase here.
But because in a minute, we'll be
filling the database with fake data
We actually need
a WritableDatabase reference.
To fill a database with fake data, we've
provided you with a TestUtil clause.
Inside, there's a method
called insert fake data.
That just takes a database
reference as an input, and
it will automatically add
five guests to the database.
Awesome, now let's create a new
method called get all guests
that will actually return
everything in the database.
Our method get all guests, returns
the result in a type called cursor.
An cursor is what any SQL query
result will be stored in.
The cursor clause allows you to iterate,
over the query result in a very easy and
simple way, as we'll see soon.
So, now it's time to create and
run the actual SQL query.
To do that, we called the query method
in the database instance was created
earlier MDB.
This method can take quite
a number of parameters.
Here are only sitting the first and
the last one.
The first being the table name,
and the last being the order by
column that we're interested in.
And we can get both of those from
the contract constance that we declared
before.
Notice that we're ordering
by the time stamp column,
because that's the order that we
want to display the guests with.
The second parameter here,
is something called a projection array.
Here you can specify
an array of columns,
that you're interested in
returning in your query.
But because we're interested
in everything in the table,
we'll just passing a null.
The same goes for
the rest of the parameters.
If you want to know more,
if you're interested,
check out the intro documentation for
SQLite Database query method.
So now our all guests function is ready.
Since we just returned
the results of that query.
So let's go back and call it right
after we insert our fake data, and
so we can install the results and
cursor variables.
But to test the all guest work,
we need to update the adapter to
accept an integer representing the count
of guest is in the returned cursor.
This will reflect in the recycle view
showing a list of guests that is as long
as the count specify So let's open
our guest list adapter and modify it.
First thing, declare an integer
called mCount, that will store and
remember the count that's
passed in to the adapter.
Then update the adapter, to accept
this integer as a new argument.
And inside the adapter,
make sure you set this local
member to the past mCount.
And then finally, scroll down and
make sure you update the getItemCount
method to return the actual count
rather than just 0, perfect.
Now, let's go back to our main activity,
and make sure that
we're passing the cursor.getCount
as another input to our adapter.
This way depending on
the result in the cursor,
the adapter would let the RecyclerView
display a list that's that long.
When you run the application,
it does show five guests in the list.
But it only shows the default name and
the party size.
That's because we're only passing
in the count to the adapter,
not the actual names or the party sizes.
However, there seems to be
only five of them in the list,
which is exactly what we expected.
Cool, looks like we're
getting at least closer now.
Next, we'll see how to fix this default
text and show the actual names and
party sizes.
But before that, just make sure you've
tried what we've done yourself, and
see if you can get the same
results when you run it.