Hi.
>> Welcome to the next generation
of Android fundamentals.
Getting started on Android is more
straightforward than ever before.
>> Android Studio has become
a powerful development ally.
>> We're going to teach
you how Android works,
solid Android development patterns,
and best practices.
>> And you'll get to apply
them into a real Android app.
Our course is deeply rooted in code but
this isn't a copy paste code lab.
We'll help you navigate online
resources, sample code, and
documentation so
you'll be much more prepared to be
a professional Android developer.
>> This course assumes that you
have a programming background and
that you're pretty proficient in Java.
>> If you need a bit more help I
encourage you to check out our Android
basics courses.
>> Getting started is easy,
building something great is harder.
That's why so many of are here and
you'll even more of us along the way.
>> We'll work right along side you.
By the end of the course, you'll be able
to turn your app vision into reality.
And you'll build it the right way.
[MUSIC]