So the first one is a process can fail.
What do you do with it?
Because you're about to make crash for certain reason, that you're not aware of.
Or even machines can fail.
So which means, there's no notion of availability.
Because real time means, we are continuously making the data available.
All the network is available.
So these are two important stuff, right?
And because of that computations is lost and your real time liveliness is lost.
Right?
So these are the first set of problems.
So now how do you survey process failures?
So one simple way to do it is run multiple instances and
load balance across them.
So that even when you have got this down, you can go all the way back.
And they are doing essentially the same thing.
And similarly, you can do that.
Java/Python Backend SL2.
And they are just doing a redundant computation continuously.
But any given,
assuming that they are going on the consuming data at the same rate.
You should be able to [INAUDIBLE] takes from one of them at least.
Right?
And the second option is you can duplicate the web server,
because web servers are stateless.
On the other hand, you don't have to replicate the Java/Python program to do
the same work across multiple nations.
Instead, you can by do a MySQL on a Postgres database,
that's a key-value store kind of equal length.
And whenever the web server requests the data,
then you can pick it up from there, MySQL Postgres.
So those are very simple things that he can do to make it
more make our solution more sturdy.
And again, part of the issue is with this solution.
I think you guys,
one of you already told that scalability is one of the biggest problems.
Yes, as you can see you can't process data at scale.
So the whole idea is like you get a large amount of data.
So we get around totally like around 600 to 700 million tweets every day and
how you can keep up with it.
Because you have to look all the tweets in order to
figure whether those URLs are data or not, right?
Let say for example, your input data rate is 10,000 tweets per second.
Your Java back, Python backend is capable of doing only like say,
1,000 tweets per second, that is a processing rate.
Now, so like it takes ten seconds to even process one second worth of tweets.
So which means like you will be,
by at the end of 10 seconds, 90,000 tweets are going to be backing up already.
So which means its kind of, because you were processing rate much lower than
the input data rate and they going to keep back up always.
So you will never catch up with the input data rate.
Right?
That is an issue.
And if you look at this simple example.
So there are two cases you are to consider.
One is your input data rate is less than processing rate.
[SOUND] The next one is when the input data rate is greater than
the processing rate.
And so when the input data rate is less than the processing rate.
Yes, the Java/Python back end solution will work previously,
because I'm able to control it.
And when it goes beyond that, that's where the problems occur.
And this is a simple exercise, but
I think this is pretty straightforward for you guys to do it.
And so if your input rate is 500,000 tweets per second and your processing
rate is 10,000 tweets per second, how many seconds does it take to process?
One second of input.
So how many tweet, tweets will be waiting in the queue at the end of processing?
Any ideas?