[Thrun] So in Laplacian smoothing we look at the relative counts.
We know there is 1 instance of rain at time 0.
Normally it would be 1.
But we add 1 to the numerator and 2 to the denominator, and we get 2/3.
Let's look at these numbers again.
The count that we have is 1 out of 1 is rain and 1 out of 1 would give us 1
under the maximum likelihood estimator.
But because we're smoothing, we're adding a pseudocount,
which is 1 rainy day and 1 sunny day,
and we have to compensate for the 2 additional counts with a 2 over here
and therefore we get 2/3.
So our probability under the Laplacian smoother is 2/3 for the rainy day to be the first day,
which is really different from 1.
Applying the same logic over here, we transition 3 times out of a sunny state--
1, 2, 3--and each time it's a sunny state.
So maximum likelihood would say 3 times out of 3 it's sunny into sunny.
We add a pseudo observation of 1, and then there's 2 possible outcomes;
hence, we have to count 2 over here.
So it's 4/5.
And the missing 1/5 shows up over here.
We can do the same math as before.
Zero with 3 transitions from a sunny day resulted in a rainy day.
In fact, they were all sunny.
But we add 1 pseudo observation over here and 2 of the normalizer, 1/5.
These 2 things surely add up to 1.
The last one is analogous.
We have 1 transition of a rainy state and it led to a sunny state, so 1/1,
but we add 1 over here and 2 on the denominator so you get 2/3.
And if you do the math over here, you get 1/3.
I really want you to remember Laplacian smoothing.
It's applicable to many estimation problems,
and it will be important going forward in this class.
Here we applied it to the estimation of a Markov chain.
Please take a moment and study the logic so you'll be able to apply those things again.