So as we just saw, when you're done
with those code modifications,
the app will look like this.
But what exactly is this
mysterious block of code doing?
Well, if we take a look, it's actually
creating and accessing a database.
So let's break it apart and
see what we can understand from it.
So first,
let's focus on these two lines of code.
Now this first line here constructs
an instance of our PetDbHelper class,
the one that we just created.
And the second line here,
will either open a connection to
a database or create a database.
So you can think of it really similarly
to our .open command that we used in
the terminal.
So remember when we typed
in .open_shelter.db?
So to help you better understand
how these classes and instances
are interacting with each other, let's
jump out of Android Studio for a bit.
Now let me show you a quick diagram
overview of what's happening.
So here are our two UI classes, our
EditorActivity and our CatalogActivity,
and they'll both need to
interact with the database.
So so
far we have created a PetContract class
which has our contents available to us,
and it can be used by all the classes.
So when we call our PetDbHelper
class with this line of code,
we're creating a new instance
of our PetDbHelper class.
And that instance is called mDbHelper.
So when our activity,
say our EditorActivity,
wants a readable database,
we'll need to call this line of code.
So here we're creating
an SQLiteDatabase object.
And setting it's value to
this getReadableDatabase.
So here is asking our mDbHelper
which was our instance of our
PetDbHelper for a database.
So mDBHelper will check to see
if a database exist already.
So for database doesn't already exist.
Our instance of PetDbHelper will make
a database using the onCreate code.
So in this case we made
our shelter database.
And then following that we'll make
an instance of an SQLiteDatabase object,
and it will return this object to
the activity that ask for the database.
Now in the alternative situation
where our database already exists,
our instance of PetDb helper
won't call on create.
Instead, they'll make an instance of
our SQLiteDatabase object coupled with
existing database and return that object
to the activity they requested it.
So at the end of the statement,
we're creating SQLiteDatabase object,
the EditorActivity,
we'll have an SQLiteDatabase object
that's connected to shelter database.
And you can use this
object to communicate
SQLite instructions to
our shelter database.