Now, the magnitude of that Gaussian
noise we just added we said was
controlled by sigma.
Ran then generated random noise
with the unit variance and
we scaled it by this value of sigma.
Now, we looked at it by adding
the noise to an image and
just looking at the resulting image.
We could have looked at the noise
just as because it's a function,
we can display it as anything else.
But before I do, a few of you should
be screaming out there because
if you know anything about the Gaussian
distribution or the normal distribution,
it's got a piece like this and
a piece like this.
It's got parts that are positive and
parts that are negative.
It's zero mean.
So the noise is going to have values
that are positive and that're negative.
So how are we going to
display that as an image?
Well, remember what I said before,
it was only from computer science bad
training that you think that images go
from 0 to 255, 0 black, 255 is white.
We can make whatever we
want be black and be white.
So for example, we can make anything
less than negative 20 black,
anything more than positive 20 white and
nice grey scale in the middle, and
in fact,
what value do you think 0 will be?
It would be grey.
So that's how I'm going to display
the noise images directly.
So here you can see the effects of
sigma on the Gaussian noise, and
I'm going to be clear,
this is the sigma of the noise.
Because in a lecture or two, we're
going to have sigma of a filter and
it's going to be a Gaussian filter and
big sigmas will make noise go away, here
big sigmas make noise show up and you'll
just have to learn to deal with that.
So here,
I'm showing you some simple examples of
noise images where we have
a different value of sigma.
Okay, and you can see in the top left,
it's a very small sigma and
it looks like almost a perfectly
uniform grey background.
And as sigma goes up, goes 8, 32, 64,
okay, you can see if it looks more and
more textured, the noise gets bigger
which is just like you would expect.
What do you think
the underlying ranges here are?
See, I haven't really told you so
imagine if I had an image that
just went from 0 to 1, right,
so black was 0, white was 1.
If I had a sigma of 20 or a sigma of 8,
right, that noise would totally swamp
out the image, right, there a signal
of 0.2 or 0.02 might make more sense.
All right, so here I'm displaying it
as if I was thinking about let's say 0
being black, or let's say minus 128
being black and plus 127 being white.
So you have to worry about
the relative scale of the noise
to the overall range of the image.