The fact that you authenticate
malware infection,
malware finds a way to get onto
your device and it's running there.
So who authenticated,
it really doesn't matter.
So that first option is not
the correct option here.
The correct option is
actually the second one.
One threat with these personal
devices is that they can be stolen,
misplaced and things like that.
And if the device is in
the possession of somebody else,
the only protection you have is that
they authenticate themselves as you.
So your PIN or pattern that you have for
unlocking your phone,
sort of protects in case the device
gets into the hands in the wrong person.
So authentication that really is
addressing the thread that the device
may be in the hands of a person
who's not authorized to access it.