[Thrun] So the correct answer is tricky in this case.
It is no, no, no, and yes.
The first one is straightforward.
C and E are conditionally independent based on D,
and knowledge of A doesn't change anything.
B and D are conditionally independent through A,
and knowledge of C or E doesn't change that.
A and C is interesting.
A and C is independent. But if you know D, they become dependent.
It turns out if you know E, you can know something about D,
and as a result, A and C become dependent through the explain away effect.
That doesn't apply if you know B.
Even though B tells you something about E,
it tells you nothing about D because B and D are independent.
Therefore, knowing B tells you nothing about D,
and the explain away effect does not occur between A and C.
The answer here is yes.