In the case when the time
slice is one millisecond,
every one millisecond either we will
be preempting the CPU bound task or
the I/O bound tasks on
their own will be stopping
because they need to perform an I
operation every one millisecond.
So that means for
every one millisecond of useful work,
we have total of one
millisecond of the useful work,
plus 0.1 millisecond of
the context switching overhead.
So, total useful CPU utilization is 91%.
For the case when we have a round
robin scheduler with a 10 millisecond
timeslice, as we're going through the 10
I/O bound tasks, every single one of
them will run just for one millisecond
and then we will have to stop because of
issuing an I/O request, so we'll have
them context switch in that case.
So we will perform for
the I/O bound tasks, 10 times 1
millisecond of useful work, and
10 times 1 millisecond plus 10 times
0.1 millisecond for the context switch.
So this is the total, amount of
total work that has been performed.
And then finally the CPU bound tasks
will be scheduled and that one will run
for full 10 milliseconds because
the timeslice value is 10 milliseconds.
So that will complete 10 milliseconds of
useful work and then it will complete
total of 10 milliseconds plus
a context switch time of a total time.
If we compute this,
this comes out too close to 95%.
So, what this example shows us is
that from the CPU's perspective,
from the CPU utilization perspective,
having a large timeslice that favors
the CPU bound task is better.
We didn't ask the question of
what is the I/O utilization for
both of these cases.
Likely if we work out the math for
that case, we will see that from
the perspective of the I/O device, it
is better to have a smaller timeslice.
And that will be because the I/O device
really cannot do anything during this
entire period,
when the CPU bound tasks is running for
10 milliseconds with
the long time slice.