Let's look at how to
transpose data in Alteryx.
When we look at the data,
we can see that sales are shown
in six different fields by month.
We're going to take these six fields,
and put them all into one sales field.
To do this, we drag in the transpose
tool from the transform category.
Notice how the tool image itself
is showing you the before and
after of the data.
We're going to go from wide to long.
The key field which is the field
that is not going to be transposed,
is the product field.
While all the rest of the fields
remain checked in the data fields.
When we run the workflow, we can see
that 3 records turn into 18 records.
There were three records initially.
With six fields of data.
So when we transpose the data
this becomes 18 records of data.
Each initial record is now
represented by six records.
One for each month.
So when we transpose the data,
it creates two fields.
One is name or the name of
the field the data came from.
And value, which is the sales value.
We can use the select tool to change
the field called value to sales.
And then the field called name to date.