All right.
So let's talk through the analysis of
this algorithm in determine its MDPs.
I'm going to call the algorithm RMAX
because anything we don't know we assume
is RMAX.
It's not a great name, I guess, but
it is the name that it was given by
Brafman and Tennenholtz when they
first proposed and analyzed it.
I guess it had another name, too.
>> RMIN?
>> [LAUGH] No.
because the algorithm actually
is directly related to
an algorithm that Andrew Moore proposed
but didn't have an analysis for it.
>> So it could've been RMOORE?
>> [LAUGH]
I see.
RMAX.
And even more than that is RMOORE.
>> Mm-hm.
>> All right.
So let's just go with that.
So here's the algorithm.
I just copied it from
the previous slide.
And there's some things that we can
figure out about this, like once
we've actually visited all the state
action pairs in a deterministic MDP.
Then this algorithm is
going to be perfect.
It's never going to make any
more mistakes after that.
Right?
Do you see that?
Because in step three,
it solves the MDP which
is in this case now the actual optimal
policy and then any action that it takes
from that policy thereafter is going
to be an optimal action not a mistake.
So this is great.
If it's the case that we eventually
visit all of the edges in the MDP,
then we will no more
mistakes after that point.
>> How do you count mistakes, though?
Do you count mistakes
on a per state basis?
>> Yeah, a mistake in this case means
I'm in a state, I take an action,
and that action wasn't near
optimal from that state.
>> From that state, right.
>> All right, but we need
a couple more things here, right?
So it could be that we never
actually know the whole MDP.
>> That's possible.
For example,
if you're in Windows trap states.
>> What happens if you stop
visiting unknown states, right?
So what would that mean?
In the case of a deterministic MDP, it
would mean that we were following some
policy that is taking us on
edges that we know about.
So nothing new ever happens.
Nothing new is ever learned.
But there could be other unknown
edges elsewhere in the MDP
that we are not visiting.
So could we be making a mistake as
we go around this loop over and
over and over again.
>> If we can get to that state from any
of those states, then we would end up
going to that state, because we assume
its the best thing that we could do.
>> Not necessarily.