So take a moment now to get the SHA1
fingerprint from your debug certificate.
Remember, you're going to have to
find your .android directory for
your platform.
And then you're going to
run the keytool command.
And the keytool command is run
with the following parameters.
-list, -v, -keystore, with the location
of your keystore that you found.
It may change based on
your operating system.
You saw how I did it for the Mac.
-Alias android debug key -storepass
android,-keypass android.
Once you've run this,
take a look at your SHA1 key and
make sure you make a copy of it or
leave your terminal window open.
When you're done, check this box.