So you may have heard the term memory
when we're referring to computers.
Well, what does this term really mean?
Now your phone can be thought of as
basically a miniature mobile computer.
And computers have two kinds of storage,
temporary storage and permanent storage.
So the difference between temporary and
permanent storage can be thought of
similarly to short-term memory and
long-term memories that humans have.
Now in the temporary memory example,
say you're going to a restaurant and
you look up the restaurant's address
as you're driving along the street.
So you'll probably
remember this address for
as long as it took you to
get to the restaurant.
Then after a few hours when
you have left the restaurant,
you have completely
forgotten the address.
Now on the other hand
with permanent memory,
say you remember something
like your home address.
And you will probably remember that for
years and years and years.
So temporary storage is
similar to short-term memory.
And that means information that's
important for the task at hand but
then quickly forgotten when
it's no longer needed.
Whereas permanent storage is
similar to long-term memory.
So that means information that sticks
around in your brain for years and
years, such as the name
of your father or
mother or
even the lyrics to your favorite song.
So if we look at each of these
in more detail, on a computer,
temporary storage is short-term storage.
Used for things such as calculations and
displaying things onto the screen.
So it's quick and easy to access,
but the downside of this,
is that the information doesn't stick
around forever, it's short-term use.
So when we refer to a computer memory,
we're referring to this
type of temporary storage.
So if you've ever heard the acronym RAM,
such as someone saying, well,
my computer has 4 gigs of RAM, well,
they're referring to
the temporary computer memory.
RAM stands for random access memory.
Permanent storage comes in
the form of your hard disks, or
any of those flash drives you
have lying around the house.
So these permanent storage locations
are the places you want to save off
all the files that you want around for
a long time.
Now note that this type of storage can
be more time consuming to save off and
access.
So is this important as to why temporary
storage can be useful in some cases.
For the purpose of this lesson,
we'll be exploring permanent storage.
And if you'd like to learn more about
either kinds of these storage options, I
suggest checking out the links provided
in the instructor's notes below.