This is the hint portion of the video.
In this portion,
I'll write some pseudocode describing
how I structure the algorithm.
Then, I'll fill in some of the details
in the second portion of the video.
If you just want to see
the pseudocode as a hint,
watch up until the timestamp listed
in the instructor notes on this page.
Let's assume the system is
already in triangular form,
in order to compute our RREF.
We work from the bottom equation
up dividing through each equation
by the coefficient of
its leading variable and
then clearing that lead variable
from all the equations above.
Let's call M the number of equations,
and then let's make a for
loop iterating upward through the rows.
First, let's check if there are any
non-zero coefficients in our given row.
For example In these
rows zero equals blank.
There is no variable to solve for.
So we need to move up to the next row.
So, if there are no non-zero
coefficients in row I
we continue to the next row.
Let J be the index of the variable.
That's the pivot on row I.
Luckily, there's a function already
included in the linear system class
that finds this for us.
Then we need to make the coefficient
of the variable j in row i equal one.
So let's scale row i to
make this coefficient one.
Finally, we need to clear all terms
with variable j in rows above i.
There's still a bit of work to be done
in filling in what these last two steps
mean, but
that's the sketch of the algorithm.
Next in the full solution,
I'll show my python code for
this pseudocode and also my code for
the last two steps of the for loop.
This is the end of the hint
portion of this video.
The full solution will now follow.
Here's the function compute RREF.
Now in proper Python syntax.
Although it was given in the code
stuff I showed earlier, it's worth
pointing out that the variable tf refers
to the triangular form of the system.
And then, all the rref operations
are performed on this triangular form.
I'd also like to note that
to compute pivot indices
which is a list giving the index of
the leading variable on each row.
I use the preexisting function
indices_of_first_nonzero_terms_in_each_-
row.
Since we followed the pseudocode,
more or
less the only thing left to do
is to fill in the two functions
scale_row_to_make_coefficient_equal_one
and clear_coefficients_above.
multiplies the given row through
by the reciprocal, of the coefficient,
of the specified variable,
in the specified row.
Nothing too special going on here.
And clear_coefficients_above is
almost identical to the function
clear_coefficients_below that we
used in computing triangular form.
The difference is that the range
of equations I loop through
is in reverse order.
Also, since I know that the coefficient
of the pivot variable is one.
I can simplify my
arithmetic a little bit.
Otherwise, it's exactly the same logic.