The answer actually is true,
because remember we have write up root.
You can write at your or higher level.
So unclassified user is down here,
classified secret,
top secret, you can write at any level.
Write up rule is the star
property that we have.
The answer here is true.
Again, if you think something is not
right here, think about the BLP models,
focus is on confidentiality or
disclosure of information.
An unclassified user has no
sensitive information and
gets written at whatever level.
They may want to choose to call
it top secret perhaps, but
that is not going to disclose
any sensitive information
to somebody who should
not have access to it.
So, the write up rule is
the reason why the answer to
this quiz question is true.