Let me show you an example of
the Lytro Light Field camera.
Here, basically, if you see,
you know, I can focus by
clicking on different regions.
In essence, what this camera does,
it captures a stack of images
at different focal lengths.
And interactively, you can choose which
focal plane you want to visualize.
So, in essence, what it does is actually
to some extent it's learned photography.
Here you can even see parallax, right?
I'm just moving it, and you can see
a little bit of depth going on.
Again, is happening between the uv,
and the sd planes.
Again, by using the microlens length
arrays, they were able to capture a lot
of images, and now this is basically
interpolating between all of them to
give you both depth parallax issues,
and also focal planes.
Again, when we talked about
the photography we look at this whole
concept, right?
A photography said, find a bunch of
images that are just different by a bit,
and now, we can actually bring those
images to create a representation.
In this case,
they're using it to create a light field
by putting in a smaller micro-cameras
with a bigger camera system.
More information,
we capture it each and every pixel.
Then, of course,
we can actually generate more newer
forms of pixels after their captured.
So, that, in a sense,
is the idea of doing all of this.