If images are just functions then we can
do things like arithmetic operations on
functions so for example we could
just add two images together, why?
because you know you could add just two
functions as long as they're defined
over the same range.
So we're going to introduce
this notion of mathematics
on functions that we're going to use
noise as a way of doing that and
you'll see why because it in a minute.
It talks about how things combined
images so noise is just another
function that, if you combine it with
the original function, what do you get?
Well, you just get out, guess what?
A new function.
So here what I wrote was I prime of
(x,y) is just I of (x,.y) plus, and
this little Greek letter, eta of (x,y),
that's meant to be a noise term.
Okay.
Now you notice I've written them as
vectors because I didn't say whether was
color or black and white but the idea
is that I've added a noise term to
every vector element and
it is only a single one.
The single element in i at every
location x and y, all right?
So what do you think it would look
like when we add noise to an image.
Well you're right it looks noisy, okay?
So let's be more precise about
that colleague of mine Steve Sites
put together a nice says slides that
shows a couple different types of noise.
So here's one, okay?
This is what's called salt and pepper
noise, and for the culinarily challenged
among you, I'll let you figure out
why it's called salt and pepper.
Basically, you take your original image.
There, you see it on the left,
nice and clean, and
you add, occasionally, white spots.
Salt and black spots, and that's called
salt and pepper noise, all right?
Another kind of noise happens when
things just kind of glint, etc., or
whatever, and
that's called impulse noise.
Impulse noise, only salt, all right?
So, we just add lots of little
white spots, all right?
These noises happen, but they're
less common for us to think about.
Much more common for us is what
we think of as Gaussian noise,
Gaussian noise which we
are going to make a lot of.
Use of it going forward is
where we have the noise
in the variation in tense is drawn
from a Gaussian a normal distribution.
Now I'm hoping that most of you remember
your Gaussian normal distribution we're
going to talk more about
that a little bit.
But if you have to go turn off the video
and go run your book to look it up.
Okay go ahead do that.
Okay now you're back.
All right so here you can see what
Gaussian noise looks like and
you can see that all the little
pixel seem perturbed a bit and
they seem to be perturbed differently
one next to the other and
some are perturbed a lot and
some are perturbed a little.
We can look at this more carefully and
MATLAB makes that really easy.