In the previous sample,
you saw how to sign in with Google
using the sign-in button control.
Now this had basic theming, but you may
have noticed it used the Google+ logos.
If you want to have a sign-in button
that follows the standard Google
sign-in, you can do so with some very
simple modifications to your app.
First, there's some standard
graphics that you should use, and
they adhere to the design guidelines.
You can find the design
guidelines at this URL.
As well as the design guidelines,
that page also has buttons that you can
download and these are the standard
buttons in small, medium and long size.
Once you've read and
understand the guidelines, go ahead and
download the buttons.
You'll be taking a look
at them in the next app.