So Jake,
have you got notifications appearing?
>> Yep, I mean they're useless,
but they are appearing.
Here's how I did it.
First off,
if the controller is falsely, I bail.
The user already has the latest
version if it wasn't loaded via
a service worker.
If there's a worker waiting,
I trigger the notification and return.
If there's a worker installing,
I want to listen to its state changes.
I'm going to call another method
to do that, trackInstalling.
You'll see why shortly.
In trackInstalling,
I'm going to take the worker,
and I'm going to listen
to it state change event.
When that fires,
I'm going to look at the state, and
if it's installed,
I'm going to notify the user.
If there isn't an installing worker,
I'm going to listen for updates.
Once there's an update,
I'm going to call trackInstalling again.
You can see now why I
factored that code out.
Now I'm going to make a random
change to the service worker and
then refresh the page.
And there we have a notification.
If we were to deploy this change, we'd
bump the version number of our static
cache, so the old and new version
wouldn't step on each other's toes.
But this isn't really
worth deploying yet.
I mean,
the notification is kind of useless.
But this is an important step.
In the next lesson,
we'll let the user opt into the update.