So, what we want to do is, we want to figure out,
we want to model how this error function changes for small shifts.
So we're not going to move you of 97 pixels.
No we're going to move, maybe even just a fraction of a pixel or a,
or a small shift.
Right near u and v being zero zero, that is around no shift at all.
And of course what we'd like to see is that we get a significant change even for
a small shift that would tell us no matter how we move in u and v,
and that would tell us that this image is going to change as I move around, and
maybe it's corner-like.
So how do you predict the value of a function for small shifts?
Do you remember this?
Oh yeah, calculus.
Taylor expansions?
All right.
We're going to do a second order Taylor expansion of E of u v.
That's our function here.
Around u and v being zero zero.
And this second order means it's going to be a small, a quadratic approximation.
All right, so strap in, because we're going to go through the math of
doing that, and it'll get us to a point where it's very easy to
compute whether the neighborhood around a point feels corner like.
All right, so you may not remember everything you need to know about Taylor
expansions, so I'm going to write this out.
So back when you first took calculus, this was the equation of a Taylor
approximation, where we say that the value of a function of some small delta
near zero can be approximated the value at zero times the first derivative
times delta x times the second derivative of delta squared x half of that.
That was the Taylor approximation.
I'm sure you all have that tattooed somewhere on your body.
All right.
So it gets a little uglier when we do things in two dimensions.
Remember it's u and v.
Okay?
And we're going to write that out for
this expression, this error of u v function, this way.
You ready?
Okay, don't panic.
What we're saying is, that the error function u v for some small uv's near zero,
can be approximated by the value at zero zero.
The first derivative times the u v, so
that's like this d f of x times delta x, except now we got it in two dimensions.
So we've got the gradient and
the u dimensions, plus the gradient of the v dimension.
Plus, we have this quadratic term and
in vector notation for two dimensions, that quadratic term is written like this.
So these are our second derivatives.
Uu vv, this is uv uv, and we just matrix multiply times the uv vector.
Hopefully this is somewhat familiar to you from your vector calculus if not,
it's just true