Now to solve an MDP,
we're trying to find a policy--pi of S--
that's going to be our answer.
The pi that we want--the optimal policy--
is the one that's going to maximize
the discounted, total Reward.
So what we mean is:
we want to take the sum over all Times
into the future of the Reward
that you get from starting out
in the state that you're in, in time T--
and then applying the policy to that state,
and arriving at a new state, at time T plus 1.
And so we want to maximize that sum--
but the sum might be infinite
and so, what we do is
we take this value, Gamma,
and raise it to the T power, saying
we're going to count future Rewards less than
current Rewards--and that way,
we'll make sure that the sum total is bounded.
So we want the policy that maximizes that result.
If we figure out the utility of the state
by solving the Markov Decision Process,
then we have: the utility of any state, S,
is equal to the maximum over all
possible actions that we could take in S
of the expected value of taking that action.
And what's the expected value?
Well, it's just the sum over all resulting states
of the transition model--
the probability that we get to that state,
given from the start state, we take an action
specified by the optimal policy
times the utility of that resulting state.
So--look at all possible actions;
choose the best one--
according to the expected, in terms of probability utility.