The virtual file system supports
supports several key extractions.
First, there's obviously
the file extraction.
These are the elements on which
the virtual operating system operates.
The OS represents files
via file descriptors.
A file descriptor is created
when the file is first opened,
and there are a number of operation
that can be supported on files by
using the file descriptor to
identify the specific file.
These include read, write, lock a file,
send file, also close a file,
ultimately.
For each file VFS maintains a persistent
data structure called an inode.
One of the information that's
maintaining those inode is the list of
all the data blocks that
correspond to this file.
This is how the inode derives it's name,
it's like an index node for that file.
The inode also contains other pieces
of information for that file like
permissions, the size of the file,
whether the file is locked, et cetera.
The inode is a standard data structure
in Unix-based systems, and again
it's important because the file does not
need to be stored contiguously on disk.
Its blocks may be all over
the storage media, and therefore,
it's important to maintain this index.
Now, we know that files
are organized in directories.
But, from the virtual file systems
perspective and in general from unique
space systems perspective, a directory
is really just a file, except,
its contents include information
about files and their inodes.
So that we can find where the data
blocks for these files and so
the virtual file system will interpret
the contents of the directory
a little bit differently.
To help with certain
operations on directories
Linux maintains a data structure called
dentry, stands for directory entry.
And each dentry object corresponds
to a single path component
that's being traversed as we
are trying to reach a particular file.
For instance, if we're trying to
reach a file that's in my directory,
in the directory named ada.
We would have to traverse
this path /users/ada.
In the process, the virtual file system
will create a dentry element for
every path component.
Forward slash for /users.
That's the second
directory in this path.
And then finally, for the third
directory in this path, /users/ada.
Now this first slash,
that corresponds to the root directory
in the file system structure.
The reason that this is useful is that
when we need to find another file
that's also stored in
this directory ada,
we don't have to go through
the entire path and try to reread.
The files that correspond to all of
these directories in order to get to
the directory ada, and
then ultimately to find the file,
the next file that we are searching.
So the file system will maintain a cache
of all of the directory entries that
have been visited, and
we call that the dentry cache.
Note that this is soft-state,
\there isn't some persistent on-disk
representation of the dentry objects.
This is only in memory maintained
by the operating system.
Finally, there is
the superblock abstraction
that's required by
the virtual file system, so
that it can provide some information
about how a particular file system.
It's laid out on some storage device.
This is like a map that the file system
maintains so that it can figure out
how has it organized on disk
the various persistent data elements,
like the inodes or the data blocks
that belong to the print files.
Each file system also maintains
some additional metadata
in the superblock structure that
helps to during its operation.
Exactly what information will
be stored in a superblock, and
how it will be stored
differs among file systems.
So that's why we say it's file
system specific information.