Alright, lets add one more type of
preference, an edit text preference.
Users will use this preference
to set the size of the shapes.
Our angle would be to let
the user control how big or
small the shapes look by multiplying the
size with a value larger than zero, and
smaller than three.
For now, we'll just create this
edit text preference without any
error checking for
the range of the values.
This isn't significantly different
from creating a check box, or
a list preference.
I've linked the documentation below,
so you're welcome to check out
the branch which is also linked
below and try it out on your own.
However if you want to follow along,
just keep watching.
All right, so let's start by
adding the edit preference tag.
It should have a default value,
a key and a title.
And I'm trying to use
the string resources now.
So in the strings.xml,
just simply create those three strings.
One for the label, one for
the key, and one for the default.
And remember to set the translatable
default for those two.
In the visualizer activity,
I'll create this new method called
loadSizeFromSharedPreferences.
Which gets the preference as an imput,
converts it to a float, and
then called the set minimum size
scale on my visualizer view.
And then I can call this load side
from share preferences method and
this set up shared preferences,
which is called in the onCreate, and
also call it on
the onSharedPreferenceChanged.
However, I only want to call this when
this preference actually changes,
so I'll add this else if check.
Now back in the SettingsFragment
the summary will need to be
updated to support edit texts.
What I'll do here is in the set
preference summary, check if it's
an edit text preference, then simply set
the summary to whatever value is given.
Cool, let's try it out.
So, if we run the app now ad
then move to the settings,
we can see that there's
size multipliers there.
Let's change it to 0.5 and
then head back and
you can see that the shapes got smaller,
cool.