The best way to get used to the shell is
to try a bunch of things out in it and
see what happens.
So here's a bunch of things to try.
In each case, run the command and
see what you get.
And then in your own words,
write down what you believe it's doing.
Something to notice is that while
some commands are just one word,
others have more information
that follows the command name.
These are called Command Line Arguments.
And they're input that you provide
to a particular command or
program when you run it.
The command name is just
the first word like expr or host.
And the arguments make up
the rest of the command line.
So now, try each one of these
commands in your shell.
And in the box underneath each command,
write what that command
seems to be doing.