What I want to talk to you today is about what's called SIFT feature detection.
SIFT stands for Scale Invariant Feature Transform.
The motivation for the development of the, of the SIFT transform.
And this was done by David Lowe back 99 is really when the,
when the community first saw it and then early 2000s.
The Harris operator was not invariant to scale, now we've fixed that later,
and we talked about how to do scale stuff.
And correlation was not invariant to rotation.
So what David wanted to do, is he want to to do better matching, and
he wanted to develop a, two things, one was an interest operator,
a detector, that was invariant to scale and rotation.
And we talked about the SIFT detector last time, right.
We talked about these finding the maxima of the difference of Gaussians both in
scale and in space, and that by doing that you
could determine the natural scale, or I should say, the right scale.
But the other part of SIFT,
was building a descriptor, that is the description of the neighborhood that was
robust with respect to variations corresponding to viewing conditions.
So, as you scale the neighborhood where you found the right scale, if you
changed the brightness a little bit as you're rotating those kinds of things,
to build a descriptor that would be, robust under those transformations.
And just inserting opinion here, for these days for
SIFT and things like SIFT, the descriptor is the part that's used most.
Okay.
That's the part that the idea of building these local descriptors was really
significant and continues to be used today