Now you can insert data
into you task database, but
you have no way of retrieving that data
to display it all in the main activity.
So the next method we need is query,
which lets us ask for rows of data so
that you can display them in the UI.
>From our description of
the content provider methods,
you know that the query
function takes in a URI and
these other inputs to select
data from a database.
And then it should return a cursor
that contains the desired data.
The most important parameter is this
URI which should point to our tasks
directory because we will want to
display all of the tasks we've made.
In our task content provider class,
we'll start our query method similar
to how we started our intent method.
First by gaining access to
our underlying database.
This time with a call to
getreadabledatabase since we're
just reading from it and
not changing it.
Then using our URI matcher to get a
match number that identifies the passed
in URI.
Then we know it will be returning
the cursor and we can write a switch
statement to manage data
correctly in the cases we want.
And for now, we'll start with one case,
the case for
all tasks since that's what we'll
want to display in our app.
And in any other case,
we'll throw an exception.
And this starting code will look pretty
similar for all of our CRUD functions.
Now let's write the query for
our tasks case, which should return all
the rows in our database as a cursor.
To query the underlying database, you
just call db.query and pass in the table
name, and projection and selection
arguments that you've seen before.
This will return a cursor that you
can store in our retCursor variable.
Then you'll set another notification,
but
this time it tells the cursor what
content URI it was created for.
This way, if anything changes in
the URI, the cursor will know.
And finally, you'll want to
delete this last exception and
return the cursor that you queried for.
And that completes the query method.
Next let's hook this up to our UI so
that all the tasks in this cursor can
be displayed in the main recycler view.