Searching is one of the most fundamental
methods of solving problems in AI.
We've now seen depth-first search,
breadth-first search,
uniform cost search in a star.
In the book, we've read about iterative
deepening and bidirectional search and
the space and time advantages of
these different search methods.
Remember Sally from the Carter Center?
Let's use the knowledge from the section
to look at the problem more thoroughly.
Depth-first search is non-viable here.
If we were unlucky,
we might cross a country several
times in just our first branch.
Breadth-first search, or
our uniform cost search would work, but
we'd have to do three searches,
one from Little 5 Points to Scottdale,
one from Scottdale to Buckhead, and
one from Buckhead to Little 5 Points.
We would then determine the shortest
two of the three paths.
And so, the pulling station that
is common between those two paths
is a second pulling
station we would visit.
We could then start at either
of the other two cities.
The problem is that this method revisits
some nodes repeatedly in the three
searches, and the search would range
much farther than is necessary.
A bi-directional search
would help considerably.
Instead of each of the three
searches requiring B to the D nodes,
it would be done in B to
the D over two nodes.
But we would still revisit a lot of the
nodes in the triangle between the three
cities.
Instead, what if we start up the search
at all the locations simultaneously?
Growing them out until the first
two connect, and then continuing
all until the third location connects
somewhere with the first two.
That would avoid
the repeated node visits.
The question is, can we modify this
uninformed tridirectional search
into a tridirectional a star search?
The key is figuring out an admissible
heuristic that takes into account
two potential goals at the same time.
Give it some thought,
see if you can come up with one