What did you come up with?
>> So, based on the description we
were given, there is a filter, and
its associated receptacle that
holds the filter in place.
>> So, I guess I should have
clarified that by hardware here,
I meant electronic hardware.
>> Okay.
>> Okay?
The things that the software for
the controlling system
have to deal with.
>> Okay, so I do have a couple
of those elements as well.
So there is a brew button, and all
the connected, I guess, circuitry for
the brew button.
And maybe any other widgets
that might be on this.
But assume the brew button
was the only one described.
>> Okay.
>> And then a plate
that will warm the coffee pot, it has
to be told to be turned off and on.
>> We have to have that warming plate.
We also have to boil the water.
There's a heater for the-
>> Right.
Okay.
>> It's a water heater as well.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Okay, and
then there have to be some sensors.
because recall we had to be able to
determine whether there was coffee in
the pot.
Okay.
And we had to know whether
all the water was gone.
That is, had been heated for boiling.
So we needed a sensor there.
And safety is always a concern, so
we better have a pressure relief valve.
Which wasn't mentioned
in the requirements, but
it's another example of coming up
with requirements during the course
of thinking about the system
rather than all in advance.
And it's for reducing the pressure in
the boiler in case something goes wrong.