I'll start with a first one,
which in fact does cause
a forCED synchronous layout.
Take a look here at window.scrollY.
This is one of those properties that,
when accessed, will cause layout.
So, you're causing layout and
then you're updating styles.
This is putting the browser in a bad
read/write cycle between recalculate
styles and layout.
So, this is a forced synchronous layout.
The second option also causes
a forced synchronous layout.
Once again, accessing offset height
causes the browser to run layout, and
then bam, here comes a style change.
This option is definitely bad for
performance.
This means that the third one does not
cause a forced synchronous layout.
Notice our accessing offset width
is happening outside of the loop.
That's a good strategy.
Layout runs once and then you batch
update the styles afterwards.
Very nice.
So the question is then,
how do you fix these two options?
You'll have to check out
the next quiz to find out.