The answer to the question is that we look at the parents.
We find that the Sprinkler variable is negative,
so we're looking at this part of the table.
And the Rain variable is positive, so we're looking at this part.
So, it would be these 2 rows that we would consider,
and thus, we'd find there's a 0.9 probability for w, the grass being wet,
and only 0.1 for it being negative,
so the positive is more likely.
And once we've done that, then we generated a complete sample,
and we can write down the sample here.
We had +c, -s, +r.
And assuming we got a probability of 0.9 came out in favor of the +w,
that would be the end of the sample.
Then we could throw all this information out and start over again
by having another 50/50 choice for cloudy and then working our way through the network.