In the introductory lecture on processes
and process management, we discussed,
briefly, a few basic mechanisms
related to Memory Management.
The goal of this lesson is to
complete our discussion with a more
detailed description of
OS-level Memory Management components.
Let's remind ourselves one of the roles
of the operating system is to manage
the physical resources.
In this case,
the physical memory (DRAM).
On behalf of one or
more executing processes.
In order not to post any
limits on the size and
the layout of an address space based
on the amount of physical memory or
how it shared with other processes, we
said that we will decouple the notion of
Physical memory from the Virtual
memory that used by the address space.
In fact, pretty much everything
uses virtual addresses, and
these are translated to the actual,
physical addresses where
the particular state is stored.
The range of the virtual addresses,
from V0 to Vmax here,
establishes the amount of virtual
memory that's visible in the system.
And this can be much larger than
the actual amount of physical memory.
In order to manage the physical memory,
the operating system must then be able
to allocate Physical memory and
also arbitrate how it's being accessed.
Allocation requires that the operating
system incorporates certain mechanisms
or an algorithm as well as data
structures so that it can track
how Physical memory is used and also
what is free among the Physical memory.
In addition is the Physical memory
smaller than this Virtual memory.
It is likely that some of
the contents that are needed
in the virtual address space
are not present in Physical memory.
They may be stored on some
secondary storage like on disk.
So, the operating system must
have mechanisms to decide
how to basically replace the contents
that are currently in Physical memory.
With needed content that's
on some temporary storage.
So, there is basically some dynamic
component to the memory management
process that determines when content
should be brought in from disk and
then which contents from memory
should be stored on disk,
depending on the kinds of
processes that are running.
The second task,
Arbitration, requires that the operating
system is quickly able to.
Interpret and
verify a process memory axis.
That means that, when looking
at a virtual address, the OS
should quickly be able to translate that
virtual address into a physical address.
And to validate it, to verify that
that is, indeed, a legal axis.
For this current operating systems rely
on a combination of hardware support as
well as smartly designed data structures
that are used in the process of
address translation and validation.
The figure here illustrates that the
virtual address space is subdivided into
fixed sized segments
that are called pages.
The Virtual memory not
to scale these two.
Is divided into page
frames of the same size.
In terms of allocation then the role
of the operating system is to map
pages from the Virtual memory into
page frames of the Physical memory.
In this type of Page-based
memory management
system the arbitration of
the axis is done via page tables.
Paging is not the only way to decouple
the Virtual and the Physical memories.
Another approach is segmentations, so
that would be a Segment-based
memory management approach.
With segmentation, the allocation
process doesn't use thick-sized pages.
Instead it uses more flexibly-sized
segments that can then be mapped to some
regions in Physical memory as well as
swapped in and out of Physical memory.
Arbitration of accesses in
order to either translate or
validate the appropriate access
uses segment registers that are
typically supported on modern hardware.
Paging is the dominant method used
in current operating systems and
we'll primarily focus our discussion
on Page-based memory management.
That will mention segments a little
bit more later in this lesson again.
As I already hinted memory management
isn't purely done by the operating
system alone.
In order to make these tasks efficient
over the last decades the hardware
has evolved to integrate a number of
mechanism that make it easier, faster,
or more reliable to
perform allocation and
arbitration tasks regarding
the memory management.
First every CPU package is equipped
with a Memory Management Unit.
The CPU issues virtual addresses
to the Memory Management Unit, and
it's responsible for translating them
into the appropriate physical address.
Or potentially the MMU
can generate a fault.
The faults are an exception or
signal that's generated by the MMU,
that can indicate one of several things.
For instance, it can say that
the access is illegal, like for
instance that the memory address that's
requested hasn't been allocated at all.
Or it can indicate that there
inadequate permissions to perform
a particular access.
For instance, the memory reference
may be part of a store instruction,
so the process is trying to override
a particular memory location.
However, it doesn't have a right
permissions for that particular access.
That page is what we
call right protected.
Or another type of fault may be
an indication that the particular.
Page that's being referenced
isn't present in memory and
must be fetched from disk.
Another way hardware
supports memory management
is by using designated registers during
the address translation process.
For instance in a Page-based system
there are registers that are used to
point to the currently active
page table or in a segment based
memory management the registers that
are used to indicate the base address of
the segment potentially its limit,
so its overall size of the segment.
Maybe the total number of segments and
similar information.
Since the memory address translation
happens on pretty much every memory
reference, most memory
management units would integrate
a small cache of valid virtual to
physical address translations.
This is called the translation
lookaside buffer or TLB.
The presence of a TLB will make the
entire translation process much faster.
Since if this translation is present
in this cache then there's no
need to perform any additional
operations to access the page table or
the segment and to interpret.
the validity of the axis.
And finally, the actual generation of
the physical address from the virtual
address, so the translation process,
that's done by the hardware.
The operating system will maintain
certain data structures such as the page
table, to maintain certain information
that's necessary for the translation
process, however, the actual
translation, the hardware performs it.
This also implies that
the hardware will dictate what
type of memory management
modes are supported.
Can you support paging?
Can you support segmentation or both?
So basically, are there any
kinds of registers of this sort?
It will also potentially imply
what kinds of pages can there be.
What is the virtual address
format as well as the physical
address format since the hardware
needs to understand both of these?
There are other aspects of memory
management that are more flexible in
terms of their design since
they are performed in software.
For instance, the actual allocation
basically determining which portions of
the Main Memory will be used by which
process that's done by software or
the replacement.
Policies that determine which portions
of state will be in main memory versus
on disk.
So we will focus our discussion on those
software aspects of memory management,
since that's more relevant from
an operating systems course perspective.