The last method that every provider
requires is called Get Type.
It returns a string that
tells you the MIME type
of the data that's being accessed.
Now a MIME type is just a standard
way to define a data type.
Similar to file types like JPEG or
plain text.
For our purposes,
it's okay to leave this method blank
because we won't actually
be using it in our app.
It only becomes useful when MIME
types are used to organize data or
to validate data.
For example, an app might call getType
to distinguish between movie and
image types or to check data type before
doing something like a file conversion.
For our task data, the MIME types
we care about are, an item for
a single row of data, and
a directory for multiple rows of data.
If you want more information
about getType and how it might
look in the to-do list code, take
a look at the instructor notes below.
But right now,
you already have a completed app.
So take some time to
congratulate yourself for
learning all of these new methods and go
ahead and enjoy your new to-do list app.