One other thing I want
to point out here.
This is kind of cool and this is maybe
why potential functions are helpful and
why it can help speed up learning.
Eric Rewaref showed that the series
of updates that you get by running
Q learning with some potential
function is actually exactly the same.
As what you get by running Q learning
without a potential function, but
with the Q-function initialized to what
the potential function would have been.
>> So you get the same, in the sense
that, you get the same answer or
you get the same in the sense that,
it takes the same amount of time?
>> It goes through the same
series of action choices.
So it's going to do
the same things forever.
But yeah, the actual q functions that
you get are different in the two cases.
>> Okay, well I meant the same
thing in terms of policy,
which I guess had to be true.
>> Yeah, but
not only does it converge to the same
policy which we knew was true, but
it's actually going to have the same
policy at every step door in learning.
>> Right.
So that makes sense, okay cool.
>> Oh sure,
because psi is just a constant,
really, with respect to any given state.
>> Right, that's right,
which is having an impact,
this shift impact on what the Q
values are converging toward, yeah.
>> So that's kind of neat.
>> Yeah, it's neat, and
it's a cute proof technique as well.
So, I guess, one way of
interpreting this is yeah you know,
potentials they're really cool.
It's just like initialization.
Another way to interpret this is,
who needs potentials?
You can always get the same effect
by Q function initialization.
>> Well, I think,
it says something else too.
It says that whenever you randomly
initialize your Q function.
You are, in fact,
asserting a particular potential which
just cannot be the right thing to do.
>> Mm-hm.
Wait, so what do you mean by that?
>> Well, this argues that random,
because sometimes,
what are you going to do?
You gotta start out somewhere.
So you just randomly
initialize Q functions.
You put random values
in every Q function.
But that's like saying that, since
that's equivalent to having a potential
function, you're saying that where you
randomly choose to put high values
versus low values.
And you're saying those
are places you ought to be, or
places you ought to start
out trying to be anyway.
So, that would argue against
random initialization.
>> Because it matters, and so
if it matters, why be random?
I mean, one reason to be
random even though it matters,
is because you don't know [LAUGH]
If you always say give it 0, or
if you always give it plus 1000 or
something like that,
you're biasing it as well in a very
consistent way that's easy to fake out.
Right?
It's easy to make up an example MVP
where that's going to
be the wrong thing.
Whereas, if it's random,
you know, maybe it'll work.
>> My guess is though that the you know,
if you integrated over
all the ones that were wrong versus
all the ones that were right for
any given random thing,
for any given fixed MVP,
if you didn't know what it was,
that number's going to be big.
>> But I think it argues for
you shouldn't be randomly
initializing Q functions.
>> All right,
that's not an unreasonable thing to say.
I mean, because basically,
you're injecting knowledge.
And you should not inject noise.
[LAUGH] You should inject knowledge.
>> Right,
actually that's exact the way we put it.
Knowledge and
noise don't both start within.
>> Mm.
>> Only noise does.
>> [LAUGH]
>> That feels like a saying.
Knowledge and noise both sound the same,
but knowledge starts with k, like okay.
And noise starts with no, like N-O.
>> Oh, I did not know that.
Which is the beginning of knowledge.
Okay, all right.
I fear that we are off track.
So, the punchline of this was,
that well, your punchline was,
you don't want to randomly
initialize your Q functions.
My punchline was just that you
can actually inject various
kinds of knowledge in here, and it
could have an impact on learning time.
This doesn't actually show
that it has an impact, but
empirically it often does.
There are some results that actually
show that if you initialize
your Q function optimistically,
but not too optimistically.
You actually bound what the learning
kind is going to be in terms of that.
But that's kind of a story for
another time.
I think, at this point,
we've said what we're going to
say about messing with rewards.
So, maybe we should do
a what have we learned.
>> Okay, I'm a big fan of that.