Let me comment on the idea of a lens.
A fundamental limitation of a pinhole camera
is that only very few rays of light hit the plane of the imager.
So suppose we have an object over here
and the object emits light in all directions.
Then most beams get absorbed by the area outside the pinhole
and a very small number of beam makes it through the pinhole.
Now this is misfortunate because the total amount of light that hits the camera chip
is small and its support is only applicable for very, very bright scenes.
And further, as you make this gap smaller and smaller to increase your focus
on the image plane, you will eventually run into what's called "Light Defraction,"
which puts a limit on how small you can make this pinhole over here.
Now if you use a lens, then all rays will make it to the same point in the image plane.
So an example--a ray over here gets projected like this,
and a ray over here might make it like this.
So any ray in a good lens will eventually meet at the same point over here.
The lens collects all the light that hits it, and projects it back to 1 point.
Now this specific situation is characterized by only a small plane over here,
for which everything is in complete focus.
If you move your object back to over here,
then what you find is the resulting projections don't match up.
Therefore, when you have a camera with a large lens or a large aperture,
you have to focus the camera to make sure that the distance between the image plane,
the lens itself, and the opposite object are in tune.
There is an equation that governs all of this,
and it looks about as follows:
1 over the focal length, f, for the lens.
This would be the sum over the extrinsic distance.
Plus 1 over the intrinsic distance, lower cap z.
I won't revise this equation,
but this is the fundamental equation that governs when things are in focus, for a lens.