Angular's concept of two-way data
binding is one of its claims to fame.
It's a very cool feature but
the power of it can get a little lost
if you don't see it for yourself.
I want you to try it out and
see how easily it turns a static
site into an interactive one.
Here's an app that helps
create awesome name tags.
But typing in my name
doesn't do anything.
To complete this quiz, add this code
right here to the H1 in main.name HTML.
Then go back to the browser and
add your name to the page.
Change the text to orange.
And add a strikethrough to the text.
While you're exploring the app,
pay attention to how quickly and
easily you can change
the page's content.
The link to the starter code for
this project is in the instructor notes.
When you finish building the template,
the feedback extension
will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.