Let's get started by
declaring some variables.
We now to create a variable on Swift, we
need to use something like the following
syntax, var then,
the name of the variable = a value.
For example, this creates or
declares a variable with the name
petsAge with the value of 12.
When we write this code, the Swift
compiler works behind the scenes to make
an intelligent guess about
the type of petsAge.
And, it would determine that
this is an int variable.
When Swift automatically
infers the type of a variable,
we call this inferred typing.
But, what about this variable?
In this case, the swift compiler would
infer that this variable is a string.
However, what if we wanted this variable
to only represent a single letter,
like the character type?
Can we help the compiler out?
Well, yeah, we can.
This is a slightly different
syntax than we saw before.
This syntax is for when we need
to explicitly specify a type.
So returning to our previous statement,
we can specify that
myMiddleInitial should be
a Character instead of a string.
And, this works because our string,
which is the letter A,
is just a single character.
In general, Swift does a great job
inferring the types of a variables, so
in practice,
the syntax without the explicit type,
the syntax here at the top
is usually okay to use.
But as the developer,
you have the freedom to choose.