to help us with this lesson we're
excited to welcome drew gray who's
leading the self-driving car team at
auto which is now part of uber thanks
for joining us through
you're welcome so drew can you tell us a
little bit more about how you use deep
learning for self-driving cars at auto
pressure ppl networks have been a big
focus on my work at auto we're exploring
whether we can get a car to drive itself
using only deep neural networks and
nothing else
sometimes we call that behavioral
cloning because you're training the
network the cloned human driving
behavior or sometimes it's called end
and learning because the network is
learning to predict the correct steering
wheel angle and speed using only the
inputs from the sensors so as i
understand it deep learning isn't the
only approach to building a self-driving
car for a number of years people been
working on a more traditional sort of
Robotics approach so why do with deep
learning over a robotics approach right
my PhD is actually in control theory and
artificial intelligence so spend a lot
of time working on both approaches in
fact engineers auto are working on both
deep learning and the standard robotics
approach i'm working on deep learning
because i think it has the potential to
fundamentally change how we develop
self-driving cars
cool can you explain a little bit more
about the difference between the deep
learning approach versus of Robotics
approach the robotics approach to
building self-driving cars involves a
lot of detailed knowledge about sensors
controls and planning with a deep
learning approach we don't have to
program all that detail knowledge into
the vehicle we simply feed all the
information we have into the network and
then we let the network figure out its
own what's important also deep learning
allows us to build a feedback loop for
the more we derive the more data we can
collect which in turn allows us to learn
how to drive even better
so what you're doing sounds pretty
similar to what students will be doing
in their final project at the end of
this module only they'll be implementing
behavioral cloning and simulator well
simulator it certainly makes things
easier but the overarching principles
are the same whether in a simulator or a
real vehicle
yeah but can you actually drive a real
vehicle with just a deep neural network
you can we actually recently drove 20
miles down the highway in San Francisco
to the airport and back without touching
the steering wheel once wow so it really
works well then let's get started
building a deep neural network
let's do it