Let's look at the same video clip.
This video clip has ninety frames,
captured 130th of seconds,
so basically this is a,
you know, a three second video.
And, you know, this will play on for
three seconds and stop as it did.
So let's try to visualize what
these 90 frames look like.
Here's my x and y, and of course by
now you know I have a time axis.
Here are each and
every one of these frames.
I've basically stacked them.
I've just offset them a little bit, but
you can see the animation as it unfolds,
right?
That's my 90 frames of video.
And I label them just f1 to f90.
This is my first frame.
So, how about I do
something interesting?
What I do is I compute
how similar frame 1, f1,
is to all of the other frames,
including f1 itself.
Of course,
it's the most similar graph font.
It's the same thing, right.
So if I just compare f1 to f1,
the most similar is f1.
So in this video volume,
there should be some other frames
that might be similar also.
Again, I know I've kept the example
simple, all black pixels,
that's where the, for
our flame is itself.
And I can now actually figure out from
them which are the most similar ones and
the most dissimilar ones.
So in essence what I now need is
some sort of a distance metric.
We want to be able to do this for
all of them.
I want do this from f1 for
all of the other 90 frames.
And then I want to do this for
f2 and all of the other 90 frames.
And I want to do this for f3 and
I want to do this for all 90 of them.
So I want to find out, basically,
a kind of met, you know,
matrix which compares f1
to all of the other frames.
F1 to 90, f2 to all of the other frames,
including f2 itself,
f3 to all of the other 90.
And do that across the board for
each and every image itself.