So listening on a port is a very
simple sort of being a server.
A program that listens on
a TCP port is waiting for
another program to connect to that port.
Once that happens, the two programs
can send data back and forth.
Here's a quick and easy demonstration.
Open up a couple of SSH
sessions to your Linux box.
In one of them,
run nc -l for listen, 3456.
Okay, that doesn't do very much yet.
Now in the other one,
run nc localhost 3456.
Still not very much, but
what if we type some stuff?
Hey, check it out.
Whatever we type in here
comes out over there.
Switch back and forth.
Whatever we put in on one side comes out
over on the other side and vice versa.
In this case there's no HTTP involved.
This isn't a web server.
It's one layer below that,
it's a plain TCP server.
The nc in this terminal is talking to
the nc over in this other terminal,
just over plain TCP,
with no other layer between it and
the network, and
both sides can send to each other.
A TCP session is like a two-way road.
Although it's hard for me to show here
because I only have the one keyboard,
it's possible for both ends of a TCP
session to be sending at the same time.
Now you try it.
With two terminals SSH'ed into
your Linux box, on one of them,
set an nc process listening on a port.
You can pick whatever
port number you want.
You don't have to use 3456.
And then in another terminal,
connect to it with nc localhost 3456.
Try typing into each one.
And then when you're done,
figure out how to disconnect them
without just closing the SSH session.