Now it's time to actually write
the adapter portion of our recycler view
pattern that we just talked about.
I'm starting with our GreenAdapter
class, which also contains the code for
our view holder as an inner class.
This adapter won't be backed by
any sort of special data source.
It will just create views that hold
the string representation of a number.
We first need to specify how many
views the adapter will hold.
And we'll do this with a private int
member variable named mNumberItems.
Then we need to populate that
variable in the constructor.
So let's create the constructor for
GreenAdapter that accepts the number of
items to display and
sets our member variable to that value.
Next we'll have our GreenAdapter
extend RecyclerView.Adapter,
taking in the type parameter of
GreenAdapter.NumberViewHolder.
This way we know that we're working
with the right kind of ViewHolder.
Type safety is great to have.
Then Android Studio gives us an error,
because now we'll need to override some
of the functions that adapters require.
Let's start with overriding
the onCreateViewHolder method.
The onCreateViewHolder method
will return a view holder object.
And in here we inflate our item
view using a LayoutInflater.
LayoutInflater is a bit
of a new concept for you.
Its inflate method takes in
the ID of a layout in XML.
In our case,
this is the number list item layout.
Then it inflates or converts this
into a collection of view groups and
views that represent it in Java code.
The last parameter this inflate method
takes in is set to false, so that
the inflated layout isn't immediately
attached to its parent view group.
And this is the setting
you generally want to use.
So the inflater takes in our
layout XML and returns a view.
Then we'll pass this view into
the constructor of our NumberViewHolder.
And finally,
we'll return that new view holder.
Next, we'll override onBindViewHolder.
And since we added the bind function
to our NumberViewHolder itself,
we can just call this bind
method in onBindViewHolder.
So in onBindViewHolder, we just call
our view holder's bind method and
pass in the int position as a parameter.
And last but certainly not least,
we need to override getItemCount.
In this method, we'll just return
the mNumberItems variable.
And that completes the basic code for
this adapter.