It's easier with ACL, because your
traverse find the ACE for the user for
whom you want to remove the access
right and update that ACE or actually
remove that ACE from the list if
the user has no more access rights left.
So we, you know, we know what
resource we're talking about for
which accesses are being revoked.
We have the ACL for that resource,
which has all the ACEs in one place, we
find this user's ACE, take care of it.
C-lists, we said, you know, capabilities
are in the user's catalogues and
things like that, but you need to be
able to remove capabilities from certain
places, which is harder to do, so
revocation is easier with ACLs.