To address this Agarwala et al basically
kind of went back to an approach
that I'd also talked about before, which
is what we're interested in doing is
we want to be able to find cuts not
just blending from one to the other.
So here example, basically is
something I'll show you here.
This is something again from
an effort by Quatra et al,
where we basically rather than actually
just frame by frame do boundary matches.
We find a surface between the two
of them that actually lets you find
a better match.
In essence of that basically means is I
have an input video and output video,
I find a patch like this.
And this again, we had seen before was
when we actually had videos like this.
If we just did a simple video texture,
you found blurring and
kind of mixing of things going on.
But if you actually did this kind of
approach, where you found the cut,
you found a much better video sequence,
because the blending was much
better from one frame to the other.
Again, showcasing in this
video example of a waterfall.
If we just did graph cut textures again
found the boundaries, you can see a much
cleaner version much defined transitions
and actually much better quality video.
So, in essence, we can use the same kind
of thing here for us to help us do this.
And in essence,
that's what Agarwal et al did.
So this was of course, just finding
the continuous diagonal slice.
And between boundaries of all of this
to generate this new video volume.
Well, with this,
just it is rather than do this,
find cuts between different one of them.
You still get a continuous video
volume here, that's shown by this.
But now rather than having simple cuts
like this, you find different regions.
And again, they use a min cut
algorithm very similar to the graph,
cut algorithm to optimize
on the cost to get this.
Please look at the paper for
more details,
but you kind of see that this kind
of way of generating a video volume,
allows us to of course have a much
better way of looking at the results.
And here let's look at
the same example again.
Here basically is the video and
now with coherent fragments,
much better no more sharing going on.
And actually get much cleaner
transitions between each and
every one of the frames to generate
a much better video texture.