Now that we've walked through solving
our original problem together,
here's a new problem for
you to solve on your own.
This will let you practice a bit more
with building MDPs in Burlap and
let you self-assess your understanding.
In this MDP we will
again begin in state S0.
From state S0 we will have a choice of
two actions, action a and action b.
Action a will have two
possible outcomes.
With probability p1, we will loop back
into State S0 and obtain a reward of -1.
With probability 1-p1, we will enter
state S1 and obtain a reward of +3.
If we take action b from S0,
we will deterministically enter state
S2 and we will obtain the reward +1.
S2 has a single action that
deterministically takes us
to state S1 with zero reward.
At state S1 we have
another choice of actions.
Action c will be stochastic and
action d will be deterministic.
With probability p2,
action c from S1 will take us to
the terminal state S5, with zero reward.
And with probability 1-p2,
action c will take us into state S3 and
we'll obtain a reward of +1.
From S3 our only option is to
deterministically reenter S1
with zero reward.
If we take action d,
we enter S4 with probability 1,
obtaining the reward +2.
The only action available at state S4
is to deterministically enter
the terminal state S5 with zero reward.
Your problem will be to determine,
based on the parameters p1 and p2 and
the discount factor gamma, the optimal
actions to take at states S0 and S1.
Using the provided class SecondMDP,
fill in the constructor method and
the method bestActions.
Please feel free to add whatever
fields and helper methods or
classes you need to solve the problem.
And as always,
the Burlap javadocs will be your friend.
Good luck.