In order to complete this first
challenge, I must first import
the classes I used to execute my
CRUD operations from lesson one.
I will import Base, Restaurant, and
MenuItem from my database_setup file,
as well as create_engine and
sessionmaker from my sqlalchemy and
sqlalchemy.orm libraries.
Along with my imports,
I must also add these four lines
of code to connect to my database.
Once again,
just copying code written in Lesson One.
Now I will add another if statement to
my do_GET method such that landing on
/restaurants lists out all of
the restaurants in my database.
Let's look at this new if statement,
where I once looked for /hello or
/hola, I'm now looking for
the /restaurants path.
I then execute a query to get all
of the restaurants in the database.
My response codes are the same as with
my previous do_GET if statements.
But here I execute a for loop and that
all of the restaurant menu items to my
output string separated with brake
lines and enclose in my HTML body tags.
I write the output to my wfile and
send it off to the client.
When I save and restart my web
server I get an output like this.
When I visit local host
port 8080/restaurants,
it lists out all of
the restaurants in my database.
Objective one complete.
See the instructor notes if you'd like
to see my code for objective one.