Estimating the intensity of an algorithm
can tell you whether you need to work
harder to come up with a better one.
Just don't over do it.
Consider non matrix matrix multiply.
Let's say you were to implement it
with the conventional three nested
loops algorithm.
It essentially loops
over the elements of C.
For each value of C, it computes
the dot product between a row of A and
a column of B.
Now suppose you run this algorithm on
a machine with a two level memory of
size Z.
And let's make some
simplifying assumptions.
First, let's suppose the transfer
size is equal to one word,
this way you don't have to worry
about stuff like alignment.
With respect to Z, let's suppose that
it's big enough to hold two vectors
plus a little bit of extra space.
Now let's transform the three nested
loops into something IO aware.
I've inserted some comments to indicate
where you might load pieces of A,
B and C.
So, at the beginning of the body of
the i loop is a good place to load
row i of A.
And at the beginning of the body of the
j loop is a good place to load both C i,
j and column j of B.
Finally since we're done
computing C ij after the K loop
we can store it immediately afterwards.
Notice these loads and
stores respect our assumption two that
Z holds two vectors plus a little bit.
Here's my question.
What is the asymptotic
intensity of this algorithm?
Enter your answer symbolically
in terms of N and Z in this box.