So the simplest way to do
planning is really the exact same
way that we did it in problem solving.
That we start off in initial state, so
P1 was at SFO, say,
and cargo C1 was also at SFO.
And all the other things that
were in that initial state, and
then we start branching
on the possible actions.
So say one possible action would be to
load the cargo C1 onto
the plane P1 at SFO.
And then that would bring
us to another state,
which would have a different
set of state variable set.
And we'd continue branching out
like that until we hit a state
which satisfied the goal predicate.
So that we call that forward or
progression state space search,
and that we're searching through
the space of exact states.
Each of these is
an individual world state.
And if the actions are deterministic,
then it's the same
thing as we had before.
But because we have this representation,
there are other possibilities that
weren't available to us before.