As you learned back in
the first lesson and
as you rediscovered in the last lesson,
not all style changes are equal.
Some will trigger layout,
paint and composite.
Some will trigger paint and composite.
And some will just trigger composite.
>> In this lesson you'll learn how
to optimize the last two stages
of the pipeline.
Painting and compositing.
If you want a full break down of how
styles affect the rendering pipeline,
check out Paul's awesome website,
csstriggers.com,
and you can find a link to
it in the instructor notes.
So when you're wondering if the thing
that you want to animate is going to
trigger a layout, paint, or
composite, check out csstriggers.com
because it's got you covered.
Cool.
All right,
let's see what we've got in our tool kit
for getting our heads around painting.
Paint is normally one of the fastest
ways to kill your friends per second.
And let's face it, that's exactly
what we're trying to avoid here.