Sharing and accessing application
data is great for developers.
In using a content provider,
it's a piece of cake to have your app
grab data, or write data to
a user's contacts, documents or
calendar, with only a few lines of code.
For example, let's say you're making
a new business card reader app.
The goal is to have the user take
a picture of their business card with
their phone, and the app will
interpret the business card and
automatically add the contact
information to your phone's contacts.
Then the user can lose
the business card, but
they'll still have that hard
won networking information.
In order to make this app seamless for
users, you need to store the new contact
information in the same data source
the user's already using to store
their phone's contact data.
This is because this is where your
phone's default contact app looks for
contact information to display.
Now usually data sources
like a SQLite database
are private to the app
which created them.
This is done for security reasons.
So how do two totally
different apps easily read and
write for the same data source?
This is where content providers come in.
In short, a content provider is a class
that sits between an application and
its data source, and
its job is to provide easily managed
access to the underlying data source.