Now you're ready to have
your preferences effect what
is actually shown in sunshine.
The sunshine preferences class shown
here is a utility class with constants
and methods to help look up and
return preferences.
To complete this exercise
you'll start here.
Number one you need to complete the code
for the methods in sunshine preferences.
Namely getPreferredWeatherLocation and
isMetric.
Second, you'll head over
to your MainActivity class.
And here you'll implement
an OnSharedPreferenceChangeListener.
The purpose of this listener is
to set a static boolean to true,
if the preferences have changed.
Third, because you've actually
implemented this listener now,
in onCreate you should be
registering the listener.
And in the corresponding
onDestroy method,
you should be unregistering
the listener to avoid memory leaks.
So, you just created a boolean
in main activity, which,
when the preferences change,
will update to true.
Next, you'll need to override the
onStart method and check whether that
Boolean has changed to true, meaning
that you must reload the preferences.
And you do that by
restarting the loader.
Finally, you should make sure
that the openLocationInMap method
actually opens the location that
was set in preferences, and
not this default location.
Once you've completed these steps,
when you make a change in your settings
activity, it should reload
all of the data in your UI,
taking into account the new location and
metric settings the user just changed.
Okay, good luck!