We just saw Jake serving a gif
in response to everything.
Instead, let's only serve it in
response to a particular request.
If you want to get your code into
the same state as Jake's, in the project
folder run git reset --hard to
remove any local changes you have.
Then, git checkout gif-responses to get
the project into a state where it's
responding to everything with a gif.
Take a look at the code
in public/js/sw/index.js.
As you can see your task is to
only respond with a gif if
the request URL ends with dot jpg.
How you determine that is up to you, but
remember Event.request gives you
information about the request.
Write the code and refresh the page
to confirm your changes have worked.
Remember to have DevTools open and
use force update on reload so
you'll only need to refresh
once to see changes.
Once you've got it working,
head over to the settings page and
type gif-response into the test
field and press enter.
This will double check if
everything is working.