now we'll combine the data from all the
regions using the Union tool since all
the data streams are the same no
configuration is needed of the Union
tool
let's run the workflow and take a look
at the output looking at the output of
the Union tool we can see that we have
the control treatment pairs
however we need to add the store
attribute information from the store
information data to perform the analysis
so let's try to join two on the canvas
and join the output from the in tool
with the store information data stream
will join the treatment field from the
Union tool to the store field for the
store data and then we'll remove the
right store filled because we don't need
the store information twice so let's run
the workflow and see what our output
looks like now we now have a data set
that can be used to perform analysis a
list of control and treatment pairs with
the region and associated test group so
let's drag an output two on the canvas
and save the data file for later use
we're now ready to perform analysis and
summarize the results of the test