So what do we mean by
a linear dynamics model?
Well, it's pretty straight forward.
A linear dynamics model says
that our state at time t will be
distributed according to
a normal distribution whose mean
is just the linear function
of the previous belief, okay?
So D here is a it's either a scalar or
a matrix,
depending upon whether x is a scalar or
a vector.
And then we take that and
we put some Gaussian noise around it,
some covariance.
And by the way, you'll notice this
little t here on these Ds, okay?
What that says is, it could be that
our dynamics model changes over time.
That is the actual multiplication
that we do, might change.
But we assume we know it.
So I'll tell you the vast majority of
Kalman filters, those Ds are constant.
So that the, the transformation and
this thing here,
which is referred to as
the process noise, is constant.
All that's absolutely required is
that it's known for every time t.
So that's the linear dynamics model.
We're going to do an example
of that in just a minute.
We also assume a linear
measurement model.
And that looks stunningly similar,
right?
What that says is that the measurement
we'll get will be some Gaussian
normal distribution that's
about some linear, m,
here is a measurement matrix,
that linearly multiplies the state.
And that the measurement noise.
Is also a Gaussian, and
again, it's subscripted by t,
because it could vary with time,
but we assume that it's not.
So, what I haven't mentioned is that
this x, both on this slide, and
on this slide, those x's are unknown.
We don't, remember,
it's the hidden state.
We don't actually know
what this state is.
What we're saying is that this is
how our linear dynamics model works.