When you're thinking about
using the orderBy methods,
you should always take a look
at your data structure.
Here under the root node,
I have activeLists.
And in activeLists,
there's a bunch of shopping lists.
Now the shopping lists
are what we are sorting.
And because of that,
the location that you're interested
in is the location activeLists.
It is the parent of all
these shopping lists.
So you'll make a Firebase
reference location here.
And then you'll use
the orderBy methods on it.
And the question is for
each of our three sorting options,
sort by list name, sort by owner and
sort by publish time,
which of these ordering
options should we be using?
So my thought for order by name and
order by email is that we
should use orderByChild.
That's because for each list, and
you can see a full list expanded out
here, there's a owner property and
a listName property, and
that's what we want to sort by.
It is the child of the list objects that
you're looking at that you want to sort
all these lists by.
And depending on which property
you actually want to sort on,
you should put that property in
as the argument that you pass in.
Okay, so that's looking good for
those two.
Let's talk about publish time.
Okay, so orderByChild is
a good choice for these two.
orderByKey doesn't make a lot of
sense for sorting by listName or
owner because here the keys
are listName and owner.
And you're not actually taking the value
into any account if you tell it to sort
by key.
orderByValue would be used if these
top level lists here weren't objects.
Now we know they're objects because
they're composed of a bunch
of different properties.
But if there's a single value, like
this push ID just had a single number or
single string associated with it,
then you could use orderByValue.
But it doesn't, it has children and
so you need to be using orderByChild.
And you wouldn't choose orderByPriority
in this case because that
method is deprecated just in general.
Now ordering by publish time
is a little bit different.
While you could choose
to order by child,
a better answer is to order by the key.
So how does ordering by
key work in this case?
Well, the keys for
all these lists are the push IDs.
And if you remember,
push IDs have a special property.
Push IDs are created, in part, using
the time that they were actually made.
And when you sort a bunch of
push IDs lexigraphically,
they are sorted by the time
that they were created.
So because the push IDs,
which are the keys, have this property,
you can use orderByKey.
And because for each of these
objects there's only one key,
you don't have to pass
any arguments in here.
It's very clear what we're sorting by.
Okay, so to summarize for
sorting by listName and
owner you can use orderByChild.
And for sorting by the time
created you can use orderByKey.