The correct answer is that
likely the event-driven
model will consume least resources.
Recall that in the other models,
we had a separate thread for
each of the requests or for
each of the pipeline stages.
In the event-driven model,
we have handlers which are just
procedures in that address space, and
the helper threads only occur for
blocking I operations.
For the event-driven model,
extra memory is required only for
the helper threads that are associated
with concurrent blocking I/O calls.
In the boss-worker model,
extra memory will be required for
threads for all concurrent requests, and
similarly, even in the pipeline model,
concurrent requests will demand multiple
threads to be available in a stage of
the pipeline if the level of concurrency
is beyond the number of pipeline stages.
As a result,
the event-driven model will likely
have the smallest memory footprint.