Here's a geometric interpretation that may help you understand a little better what's going on.
Here we've gone back to the two-finger Morra game.
Now, remember we looked at the two possibilities of E going first
and revealing a strategy of playing one with probability P and two with probability of 1 - P.
Now O has a choice of what to do, and O wants to minimize.
If O chooses one, he'll be somewhere along this line
corresponding to this strategy for different values of P.
This graph here is showing the utility to E for different values of P
that P chose in P's strategy.
Now since O can achieve the minimum
since O gets to chose the strategy of doing one or two,
O can be anywhere on this frontier.
It makes sense to E to push that up at high as possible since H is the maximizer.
E will choose this point here, which turns out to be at P = 7/12.
The same argument going on this side.
Here O has gone first and chosen the strategy, q:one and (1 - q):two.
Now E has a choice of what to do. E can either choose two and be along this line,
depending on what the value of q is,
or can chose one, which will be along this line.
It would make sense for O, who is trying to minimize,
to get this frontier down as low as possible.
O would choose the value of q that puts us right here at this point.
It turns out that that also is q = 7/12.
We see that each side is trying to maximize or minimize,
and we end up at a distinguished point that's the intersection of their two strategies.