Let's think about the algorithm for
binary search.
Suppose you're given a sorted array
A containing n unique elements.
Now let's say you're
given a target value, v.
Here's your computational goal.
You want to find the largest
index i such that A of
i is less than or equal to v.
Just to be clear, consider this example.
You're given this sorted
array of keys and
you want to find f's
position in the array.
The standard binary search algorithm
starts with the median element of A,
comparing v to it.
It then repeats this
process on the left or
right half depending on whether is v is
less than or greater than the median.
Suppose A resides
entirely in slow memory.
My question is this.
How many asymptotic transfers
might this algorithm incur?
You can make the usual
simplifying assumptions.
Namely, L divides n, A is aligned and
all these quantities L and
z are powers of 2.