And this a picture taken out of from David Forsyth's text.
Let's suppose, that we have a sharp change in albedo, and
albedo's going to be row.
So the log of that, is also going to have sharp changes, okay?
By the way, why is it negative?
The reason it is negative is albedo is always some percentage, of the light so
it is a number less than one but greater than zero.
So the log of something less than one is going to be negative, so
that's why it is negative.
If you take the derivative of this, all right what you
see is that you'll just have this spikes where the thing goes up.
Another spike, another spike, another spike, right.
So the, the derivative of this staircase function is this set of spikes.
So remember that L is going to be the product of some slowly, varying intensity.
So this is a slowly varying intensity, and
then this is the logarithm of it, okay.
So it actually went up higher and that's the log.
And when I take the derivative of the log, I get this low kind of things.
Now, if L is the product of row times I, then the log is just the sum.
So it's just, this is just this plus this equals that.
And because derivative is a linear operator, it's the sum of this plus that.
This, is what the derivative, of the log of the image looks like.
This is in this one d case.
Okay?
So, remember what we want to reconstruct is this and so
far what we have ts that.
All right so here I've just copied over, what we had before.
Right? This is the derivative, of the log of, of L.
Well.
That's a, image that we can essentially threshold.
Imagine thresholding it by its absolute value.
If you threshold by its absolute value, you would get this, okay?
And then if you integrate that, I'd see you come along, you go up,
go up a little, go down.
All right?
That's the albedo.
Now of course, there's a constant of integration that we can't know,
because we only had the derivative, so we can't know the absolute brightness.
Which makes sense, right?
Because if I crank up the e by a factor of,
you know, if I add in a constant to it.
I can't tell, that it's an e or that it's in the reflect.
So there's this constant mitigation problem but
that's okay the idea is that you've recovered the reflectance