As we've described it so
far I would say not exactly.
To see why, consider the following
three way partition of a graph.
Each partition is balanced in the sense
of having two vertices each and,
as it happens, no other partitioning
of this graph will have
fewer than the 9 edges you see cut here.
Now this partition corresponds to
a splitting of the rows of the sparse
matrix.
Notice the 1 partition
has 10 non-zeroes,
while the others have 7 each.
In other words, the vertex counts
per partition are the same, but
the work is not.
In fact, there's actually a partition
that both minimizes edge cuts and
exactly balances
the number of non-zeroes.
Can you find it?
Alternatively, how can you augment the
graph partitioning problem in order to
model the balancing of work?