Since lines in a image can be in different lengths and orientations.
You cannot come up with a single template to find them.
Although you can use a bunch of templates at different orientations to
find parts of lines.
There are much better options for this purpose.
Template matching is in general not suitable for finding arbitrary lines.
The case for finding faces is arguable.
Again, due to the possible size differences,
you cannot come up with a single template.
Moreover faces can be front-facing or
side-facing or rotated at any arbitrary angle.
Either answer is correct, although as we will see,
there are much better ways of doing this as well.
Finding and recognzing icons on a computer screen is a fairly predictable task.
This is because icons are usually shown upright and
their size is from a limited set.
Therefore, template matching is suitable in this case.
Cracks and fissures hardly have a predictable shape.
Therefore, they cannot be detected by template matching.
Are there any other good uses you can think of?
Or cases where you are sure that template matching is bound to fail?
Share with your peers on the forum.