Sometimes it's really obvious that code
has a bug because the bug makes the code
crash.
And when it crashes it usually
gives some kind of error message.
Error messages can be confusing, but
they do give some kind of information
besides just, it didn't work,
try something different.
Specifically, when Python code crashes,
the message it gives
is called a Traceback.
The Traceback tells you what line it
crashed on, what file it was running,
and how it got there.
The information the Traceback gives you,
especially the line number and
function name,
can focus your attention on the part
of the code that might be going wrong.
Even if the root of that problem
isn't on that exact line,
it's somewhere upstream of that line.
In this case, line number 5 is
doing something that doesn't work,
trying to add a number and a string.
And we can look up the error message
to find out what to do about it.
In this case, if we look up
unsupported operand type(s) for
+: int, str, how about you try it.
Look this error message up on
your favorite search engine, and
see if you can find a solution.