Right on cue we have a mike hurtling
towards us food into the pipes.
Mike.
And the one for the student to do.
>> You guessed it.
Here we go.
To make things easier, some of
the methods have been stalled out.
And comments have been added to show or
code is missing.
To get those, you need to go to the
project directory in the command line
and run git reset hard to remove
any local changes you have.
Then, git check out task update reload.
First, let's take a look.
In public/JS/main/indexcontroller.JS
_updateReady is being called whenever
there's an update ready to show.
We implemented that in the last task.
But we're now passing the new
worker into the method.
In _updateReady the new
version message is shown.
And we hit this line,
the to do if the user hits refresh.
Here, you need to send a message
to the new service worker
to tell it to take over
control of pages immediately.
You'll need to handle this
message in the service worker.
Over in public/js/index.js at
the bottom there's a TODO.
Here's where you can listen for
the message to take over page control.
Back in public/JS/main/indexcontroller,
there's a to do in
_registerserviceworker.
You need to listen for the pages
controlling service worker changing and
using that as a signal
to reload the page.
Once you've coded it up,
you'll need to get those changes
picked up by the browser.
And once again,
this is a little awkward.
Thankfully, this is
the last time it's awkward.
The easiest way is to delete the service
worker, and then refresh the page.
This will re-fetch and
cache your JavaScript.
Now, make a change to your
service worker, adding or
changing a comment will suffice,
and then refresh the page.
If your code's working,
you'll see the notification as before.
And pressing refresh
will reload the page.
Once you've got it working,
you can test it on the settings page.
The testing is a little different
here to the previous tests.
First make a change to your service
worker, and refresh the page so
you have an update notification.
Now in the settings page,
type update reload into
the test field and press enter.
Then you have eight seconds to hit
the refresh button in your notification.
This will confirm it's all working.