Thank you for taking the time to
reflect on what you've done so far.
Being able to teach others about what
you've built feels rewarding, but
it's also a core skill in being able to
communicate with teammates that you may
work with on a software project.
With that in mind,
let's keep moving forward so
you can go back to those people soon and
share your progress.
So far the functionality of the quantity
picker in our app is working well.
So now we can spend a little bit of
time making it look a little better,
a little sexier.
We want to move closer
towards our end goal.
This is what we have now,
and this is what we want.
The buttons in our app currently work,
but they're not in the ideal layout.
This layout leads to
a better user experience,
because we're going to be adding more
fields to the order form in Lesson 3.
With this layout of the buttons,
it's easier to scan through the list
of fields in the order form quickly.
In the current layout, if you want
to scan through the form quickly,
you would read quantity plus
two minus price and so on.
So it's faster to scan through the form
if the buttons are laid out like this.
This updated layout also takes advantage
of more of the horizontal space on
the screen, instead of squishing
everything into a very narrow,
vertical column.
The challenge becomes identifying
the gap between what we have now and
what we want.
Can we repurpose the views that
are already on screen and move them into
the new position for the new layout, or
do we have to add views or remove views?
Before we get lost in
the details of changing the XML,
I want you to first plan out how you're
going to approach building this layout.
In your own words, describe your
thoughts on each step that we've taught
you for how to build layouts.
You don't need to write
XML at this point.
You can just plan out your strategy.
These notes are going to help you
actually write the code at each step, so
be as detailed as you want.
The first step is to select the views.
Which views are you going to need
in terms of text view, image view,
button, et cetera?
The second step is to
position the views.
Can you describe how these views
are positioned on the screen?
Which view groups are relevant
to building this layout?
Step 3 is to style the views.
Is there anything we need to do
to change the visual look and
feel of each of these views?