Now that we know a little bit
about data persistence on Android,
it's clear that shared preferences is
a promising option for saving data.
This is because shared preferences
saves data between app restarts.
And even when something drastic happens,
like the device loses power.
We can save information,
like my shapes should be RED,
in primitive key value pairs.
The key being something like shape_color
and the value being a string like RED.
In fact, shared preferences were built
with saving app preferences in mind.
That's why they're called
shared preferences.
Because shared preferences
are usually used for app settings,
they work hand-in-hand with another
part of the Android framework.
Which was meant for creating a user
interface for settings activities.
This framework class is
called PreferenceFragment.
Before I get into how
PreferenceFragment works,
I want to talk a little bit about
what a fragment is in general.
A fragment is a class that
represents a modular and
reusable piece of an activity.
For example, sometimes in your app,
you might want the ability to split up
portions of the activity
UI into fragments.
This is so that you can reuse those
portions of the UI on different screens.
A common use case for this is if
you want to provide a phone and
a tablet layout for your app.
For example,
you might have an app which,
on the phone,
shows a list of book recommendations.
When you click on a recommendation,
it then shows you a detail
screen about the book.
In the tablet version though,
because you have quite a but more room,
you might want to actually have both
of these UIs on the same screen.
You can only have one activity, though.
So instead of duplicating the code,
you can put the list in a fragment and
the detail view in a fragment.
Then you could reuse
both of these fragments.
In the app for the phone, you'd show
them each on a separate screen.
And in the tablet version,
you'd show the fragments side-by-side.
Now looking back at setting screens,
you'll usually have an activity,
that can contain one or more subclasses
of fragments, called PreferenceFragment.
The PreferenceFragment subclass
is specifically built for
displaying preferences.
There's also a class called
PreferenceActivity which I don't
want you to confuse things with.
Since Honeycomb,
it's been deprecated in favor of
the more flexible fragment version.
Since we want to stick to best
practices in this course,
we'll be using a PreferenceFragment.
PreferenceFragments populate themselves
with preferences defined in XML.
This is much like how our activity
layouts are also created in XML.
The XML is used to generate
UI widgets in the fragment.
When the user changes these values in
the widgets, this automagically updates
associated key value pairs in
the shared preferences file.
Then when you need to actually
know the value of the preference,
you can then read from the shared
preferences file in your app.
To start, we're going to create a new
activity called SettingsActivity.
And we'll open it when you
click on a menu item for
the main visualizer activity.
Second, we'll add a PreferenceFragment
to that settings activity.
Along with the PreferenceFragment,
we'll create an XML file that defines
what preferences are in the fragment.
We'll pick what the preference names
are, the keys that are used in
the shared preferences file,
and their default values.
Then third, we'll talk on what happens
after your user sets the preference.
You will see how to load up preference
from that file when your app first
opens.
And how you can be triggered whenever
that preference actually changes.
Finally, we'll spruce our
PreferenceFragment with a UI component
known as the preference summary,
which shows the current
state of the preference.
Okay, those are the four steps,
so let's get started.