Let's start by talking about how
Android Wear deals with notifications.
When an Android handheld and
Android Wear device are connected,
the handheld automatically pushes
notifications to the wearable.
On the wearable,
each notification appears as
a new card in the context stream.
Notifications are shown on
the Android Wear device automatically
with no extra work
required by the developer.
If you want to give the best
wearable experience to your users,
you can add wearable specific extensions
with just a few extra lines of code.
Let's start off by showing how regular
Android notifications work on a phone
by loading and running a sample.
We'll use the sample basic
notifications for this.
We'll use the same sample later
on in the Android auto messaging
lesson as well.
Go to File > Import Sample,
and search for notification.
You'll see there's basic
notifications here.
Click on that, and then Next.
You can leave everything
as the default values.
Click Finish and it'll create
a new project on your machine
based on the basic notifications sample.
Now let's build and run the sample.
By clicking the green Play button here,
it runs the assemble debug task to
compile it and
then it asks where to run it.
So we select our phone,
which is already connected,
and then we hit OK to begin
the installation and start running it.
You can see the sample
has started on the phone.
We'll walk through the code shortly.
We click do it to generate
the notification and
you can see it appear here
in the notification shade.
When you click on it,
you'll see it launch a web browser and
open up a URL for
the notification documentation, which is
what the sample was configured to do.
Now lets go back and click Do It again.
This will regenerate a new notification.
And if we look at our
Android wear devices,
you'll see both of them show
a notification from the application.
This all happens automatically.
We can make the intent trigger by
clicking Open on the phone and
you'll see it appear here
just like it did before.
The nice thing is that Android wear
takes care of all of this for us.
So now I want you to
replicate the same steps.
Run the sample in a phone or emulator
and check that you can get it to work.