Scope can be a tricky subject,
especially when you're balancing
between global and function scope.
One of the gotcha scope can result in is
called scope overriding or shadowing.
To show you how this works and
how you can avoid it, let's take a look
at the the following code example.
Here we have the same variable
bookTitle being assigned values in
two different scopes.
The bookTitle in the global scope is
assigned the value Le Petit Prince, and
the bookTitle in this function scope is
assigned the value The Little Prince.
If we print out the value of bookTitle
at each part of this program, you'll see
that in the final console.log statement,
that The Little Prince is printed out.
However, at this point in the code,
we're no longer in the function scope
of the display book English function.
So why is the bookTitle Le Petit Prince
not being printed instead?
Well, this is a classic case of
scope overriding or shadowing.
When we reach the fifth
line of this code,
the bookTitle variable from the global
scope is actually being reassigned with
the value The Little Prince.
So the bookTitle here is being
reassigned by the bookTitle here.
That means when we finally reach
the last console.log in this code,
bookTitle in the global
scope has been changed,
even though we'd exited
the function scope.
To prevent this from happening, we're
going to simply declare a new variable
inside the display
book English function.
So instead of just
reassigning bookTitle,
we're going to create
a different variable.
So now, we've got a variable
inside displayBookEnglish
that is relative to this function scope.
And our bookTitle that's declared in
the global scope will remain unchanged.
And that way, when we'll reach the tenth
line in our code, and we print it out
for the third time, it's going to print
out what we expect, Le Petit Prince.