[Narrator] Naive Bayes can also be applied to
the problem of hand written digits recognition.
This is a sample of hand-written digits taken
from a U.S. postal data set
where hand written zip codes on letters are
being scanned and automatically classified.
The machine-learning problem here is
taken a symbol just like this.
What is the corresponding number?
Here it's obviously 0.
Here it's obviously 1.
Here it's obviously 2, 1.
For the one down here,
it's a little bit harder to tell.
Now when you apply Naive Bayes,
the input vector
could be the pixel values
of each individual pixel so we have
a 16 x 16 input resolution.
You would get 256 different values
corresponding to the brightness of each pixel.
Now obviously given sufficiently made
training example, you might hope
to recognize digits,
but one of the deficiencies of this approach is
it is not particularly shifted range.
So for example a pattern like this
will look fundamentally different
from a pattern like this.
Even though the pattern on the right is obtained
by shifting the pattern on the left
by 1 to the right.
There's many different solutions, but a common one could be
to use smoothing in a different way from
the way we discussed it before.
Instead of just counting 1 pixel value's count,
you could mix it with counts of the
neighboring pixel values so if
all pixels are slightly shifted,
we get about the same statistics
as the pixel itself.
Such a method is called input smoothing.
You can what's technically called convolve
the input vector equals pixel value variable, and
you might get better results than if you
do Naive Bayes on the raw pixels.
Now to tell you the truth for
digit recognition of this type,
Naive Bayes is not a good choice.
The conditional independence assumption
of each pixel, given the class,
is too strong an assumption in this case,
but it's fun to talk about image recognition
in the context of Naive Bayes regardless.