To understand what's required from
a scheduler in a simultaneous multi
threading system,
let's make some assumptions first.
Since we will base our discussions on
Federova's paper, we will use the same
assumptions that she has made, and the
figures that we will use to illustrate
those assumptions will be reproductions
from her paper and her presentation.
The first assumption that we will
make is that a thread can issue
an instruction on every single cycle.
So that means that a CPU bound thread,
a thread that just issues instructions
that need to run on the CPU, will be
able to achieve a maximum metric in
terms of instructions per cycle.
And that would be instructions
per cycle equal one.
Given that we have just one CPU,
we cannot have a IPC
that is greater than one.
The second assumption that we
will make is that a memory access
takes four cycles.
What this means is that a memory-bound
thread will experience some
idle cycles while it's waiting for
the memory access to return.
We will also assume that the time
it takes to contact switch among
the different hardware
threads is instantaneous, so
we won't take any overheads
over that into consideration.
And also let's to start with for
the sake of our discussion,
let's assume that we have a SNT
with two hardware threads.
let's take a look first at what would
happen if we chose to co-schedule
on the two hardware contacts.
Two threads that are both compute-bound,
so compute intensive, or CPU bound.
What that means is both of the threads
are ready to issue a CPU instruction on
every single cycle.
However given that there is only
one CPU pipeline, so one CPU fetch
decode issue ALU logic, only one of them
can execute at any given point of time.
As a result these two threads
will interfere with each other.
They will be contending for
the CPU pipeline resources.
And best case, every one of them
will basically spend one cycle
idling while the other thread
issues its instruction.
As a result, for each of the threads,
its performance will
degrade by a factor of two.
Furthermore, looking at the entire
platform, we will notice that in this
particular case our memory component,
the memory controller, they're idle.
There's nothing that's scheduled that
performs any kinds of memory accesses.
Well that's not good either.
Well another option is to
co-schedule to memory-bound threads.
In this case we see however,
that we end up with some
idle cycles because both of the threads
end up issuing co-memory operation.
And then they need to wait
four cycles until it returns.
Therefore, we have two of
the cycles that are unused.
So, the strategy then to co-schedule
memory bound threads leads to
wasted CPU cycles.
So then our final option is to
consider mixing some CPU and memory
intensive threads, and then if we see,
we end up with the desired schedule.
It's a bingo.
We end up fully utilizing each
processor cycle, and then,
whenever there is a thread that
needs to perform a memory reference,
we context switch to
that thread in hardware.
The thread issues the memory reference,
and
then we context switch back
to the CP-intensive thread.
Until the memory reference completes.
Scheduling, a mix of CPU and
memory-intensive threads,
allows us to avoid or at least limit the
contention on the processor pipeline.
And then also, all of the components,
both the CPU and
the memory will be well utilized.
Note that this still will
lead to some level of
degradation due to the interference
between these two threads.
For instance, the compute
bound thread can only execute
three out of every four cycles,
compared to when it ran alone.
However, this level of
the degradation will be minimal given
the properties of the particular system