Enough about letters. Now let's use all the tools at our disposal and tackle a new task--
the task of classification into semantic classes.
Say we're given a sequence of phrases and want to classify them
into one of several categories.
Here I've chosen just three--people, places, and drugs,
and I have some examples of each.
What would you use to do that?
Well, you have a number of things at your disposal.
One, you could memorize some common parts.
So "Steve" and "Bill" are very common as that first word in a phrase which represents people.
"San" and "New" are common in places.
"City" is common at the end of places.
But not all these techniques will be unambiguous or 100% accurate.
So for example, if you have a phrase where the last word is "grove"
and the first word seems like part of a name,
that could be a place, but it could also be a person's name.
With drugs, it looks like maybe the letter-based approach is better than the word-based approach.
They seem to have a much higher frequency of starting with "z" or ending in "x", for example,
but you can imagine a classifier using the techniques that we've seen in machine learning
that takes all these features.
What's the first word? What's the second word?
What's the first letter? What's the last letter or the last two letters?
Throw all those features in and build a classifier.