Now, it's time to setup your Development
Environment, which is to say,
The Tools You'll Need for this course.
There are four things you'll need to
use Google App Engine with Python.
First, you'll need a text editor.
Anything with syntax highlighting
will work just fine.
You can use whatever you're
comfortable with, but
I'll use sublime text when
showing you code examples.
Second, you'll need a working
installation of Python 2.7,
Python 3 will not work.
To check which version
of Python you have,
just run Python dash dash version or
Python dash big V from the terminal.
You'll need git.
Version control in general is a must
have for any project, but we're hosting
the project files on GitHub, so it's
pretty much the right tool for the job.
And you'll also need the Google App
Engine Software Development Kit or SDK.
You can download the SDK from
the URL in the Instructor Notes.
For Windows and Mac,
it will come with a nice GUI
tool called App Engine Launcher.
If you're running Linux,
you'll use command line tools
devappserver.py and appconfig.py.
There's a link in the Instruction Notes
with more details on those.
Another option is the Google Cloud
command line tool, G Cloud.
This includes tools for App Engine as
well as other Google Cloud services.
However, G Cloud is a bit harder
to setup for basic purposes.
So, I'll be using the basic SDK and
App Engine Launcher for
the examples you'll see in this course.
Now go ahead and make sure your
system is setup for development.
Check off the steps you've completed and
continue when you're done.