To figure out why option C was
the best on the last quiz,
let's review the actual syntax rules
in Jjava for defining a method.
This is also known as
the method signature.
This is the method signature for
the calculate price method
that we saw earlier.
You might be wondering why the order
of the words are a certain way.
Well, they follow a specific format,
and it looks something like this.
I know this looks really overwhelming,
but don't worry.
We're going to go through each one,
one at at time.
The first part in this method
signature is the word private.
This is known as the JAVA
access modifier.
It determines who has access to
this method, calculatePrice.
The most common access modifiers that
you'll see are public or private.
This method is marked as private,
that means that calculatePrice
can only be called within other
methods of the main activity.
Outside of the main activity,
like another activities,
you won't be able to call this method.
It's private to the main activity.
On the other hand,
if you mark this as a public method,
then anyone could call this method,
whether you're inside the main activity,
or you're in other activities.
It's kind of like this analogy.
If you're celebrity and public,
then everyone knows about you.
If your private and
you live inside your house all the time,
then only a couple people know you.
So for the calculate price method,
we are going to keep it private, so
it is only used within
the main activity.
Next we have "int" which
is the return data type.
Do you remember our
diagram from earlier?
Where we said that when you call
a method you pass it inputs and
you get an output back?
Well the return data type is a type of
data that is returned in the output.
And the data types we've learned
about so far are Int and
String from the last lesson.
This can also return
an object data type, and
we'll learn more about
objects later in the lesson.
In our case, this calculatePrice method
is returning the total price of
the order, which is an integer.
In a social media app, if I had a method
to get the number of friends I have on
Facebook, it could return an integer,
which is the number of friends.
Next we have the method name,
which is calculatePrice in this case.
Just like how we can refer to variables
with their name, we can refer to methods
with their name so that we can execute
the instructions in this method.
In the same documentation about defining
method, we can scroll to the bottom and
see a section about naming methods.
You can read about this in more detail
later, but basically it says that method
names should begin with a verb like
run or get, or compare or set.
It starts with a lowercase letter and
then use camel case if
there's multiple words.
After the method name we
have the list of inputs
which are denoted within the opening and
closing parenthesis.
You can have as many inputs as you want.
If you don't want any inputs, you just
have an empty set of parentheses.
If you have one input,
it looks like this.
If you have multiple inputs,
you just separate them with
commas in between each input.
Let's look at the case
where we have one input,
which is also known as
an input parameter.
We define an input parameter by
specifying its data type and
a variable name that we choose for it.
So from the diagram of inputs and
output, this is going to be
the first input to the method.
Within this method, then you can
refer to the quantity variable.
And it's just like any other variable,
where it already has
a value inside of it.
The value comes from when you
initially call the method and
you pass that input in.
If we want to modify the method
signature to add a second input param,
we have to specify the data type and
the variable name for
that second input param.
Then within this method we
can refer to the quantity or
price of one cup variables just
like the regular variables.
When you call this method
you have to remember to pass
the right number of inputs to
the method that it's expecting, and
the inputs must be of the right
data type and in the right order.
You can't flip the order of these.
Otherwise, the method is going
to interpret them incorrectly.
After you list out your inputs,
add a closing parentheses and
then an opening brace.
This starts the list of all
the instructions within your method.
After all of that,
then just add a closing brace,
to mark the end of your method.
Going back to our documentation,
now this method declaration
will make a lot more sense.
First we have the access modifier.
Then we have a return data type.
The method name,
followed by the list of all the inputs.
In this case there are four
different input parameters.
And they each have a data type and
a variable name.
And then we have an opening brace.
The list of all
the instructions inside of it.
And then a closing brace.
And this is a method declaration.
In this quiz you'll have a chance to
practice identifying the different parts
of method declaration.
We're going to provide some code
to you in instructor notes.
The code contains a bunch of methods
that could appear in any app.
For each case,
can you tell me what is the method name?
The list of input parameters?
And the return data type.
Let's do the sample together.
Here's an example method.
The goal is to create a custom greeting
message based on the given name.
The return value is going to be
a greeting in the form of some text.
Now let's ignore the comment for now.
First we have the method name,
which is in camelCase here, and
it says createCustonGreeting.
Next we have the list of inputs.
This is the first input parameter.
The data type is String and
the variable name is firstName.
Next we have the second input parameter.
This is the data type, and
this is the variable name.
And the two inputs are separated
by a single comma, and
they're enclosed within the opening and
closing parenthesis.
Then we have the output here.
The data type of the return
value is String,
because we want to return a greeting,
which is a string,
and this is what it looks
like filled into the table.
Now, go ahead and fill in the blanks for
the remaining three methods.