As you just read, code coverage is
an important tool but easily misused.
Code coverage is tricky because it
cannot test for faults of omission.
Here might be all of your team's code
and here's the code that's been tested.
A fault of omission is something
that you forgot to write and
there's no way that code
coverage tools can catch this.
A coverage tool tells you how much of
the code you'd written was run by tests,
but it can't point out when you're
missing coder statements entirely.
It also can't tell you if you've
actually tested your code sensibly.
A test that simply runs some code and
doesn't have any sort of assertions
about that code is pointless, but
it will come up as having tested more
code in your code coverage tool.
This can lead to a sort of
false sense of security.
Striving for high code coverage can
actually incentivize writing bad tests.
For example,
developers can write bad tests
simply to try to get some sort
of high code coverage score.
Lower percentage of code coverage
isn't necessarily terrible.
Merit differentiates between high,
medium and low risk areas of code.
High risk areas of code involve code
which if written wrong could lose your
company money, affect a large number of
users or even seriously injure someone.
And since time is a finite resource,
it's infinitely more important to focus
on the testing code that's high risk.
So how could code coverage be useful?
When code coverage is used as
an expectation and not as a requirement,
it's more useful.
For example, you can have two
similar code coverage situations
that should be dealt with
in very different ways.
Code coverage allows you to detect
a generally weak test suite.
If your devs are not gaming the system,
these weaknesses in the test suite can
be used to make decisions about where
you should go to fix high risk code.
For example, code coverage metrics can
identify what are known as black holes.
Black holes in your testing
suite are things like complete
features which you've forgotten to test.
In the end, code coverage tools are just
what their name implies, they're tools.
And helpfulness is based
primarily on who is using the tool
rather than the tool itself.
You might be wondering when to
actually employ code coverage.
You generally want to run code coverage
right after running unit tests.
There are plenty of code
coverage tools out there and
they usually depend on
your target language.
I've gone ahead and included an overview
of some common tools in the notes.
[BLANK_AUDIO]