Basically, what I am going to talk about is not just about illumination, but
a novel camera.
So now, let's replace this passive photocell with a camera.
We can do some similar interesting things.
Remember in our generalized novel camera, we had an aperture in front of it.
So again, the same modulating aperture we can actually put a similar modulating
aperture, which basically we can put in front of the camera.
Both of them can be coded and controlled differently.
So of course I can modulate it by opening the apertures here, and
of course that illuminates the scene.
Of course that goes into and the camera captures this