We're going to do one more quiz
question before we move on.
And this has to do with, we did talk
about responsible disclosure and
the dilemma you face if you do or
if you don't.
So in this case US-CERT,
this is the computer
emergency response entity
that we have in the US.
And there are similar CERTs in
other places, other countries.
So it follows what they say
a responsible disclosure process for
vulnerabilities.
If you find a vulnerability
you can report it to US-CERT.
And US-CERT has, we talked early on
about a database of vulnerabilities.
There's the National
Vulnerability Database and so on.
So, you can report it and
then it'll inform everybody by
adding it to one of those databases.
So, you find a vulnerability.
You report it to US-CERT.
What does US-CERT do,
or what should it do?
What is responsible
disclosure in this case?
Make the vulnerability information
available to everyone.
It doesn't know who are affected, so
basically that amounts to make it
public immediately is the first option.
The second option is provide
a certain amount of time.
An argument for that is that if you
inform the vendor and provide a certain
amount of time, maybe they have
a patch to fix the vulnerability.
So before it's public including the bad
guys come to learn about it, well,
we at least have a way deal with it.
So that's the second option.
So think about what you would
consider responsible disclosure.
Actually, US-CERT uses one of these,
I'm asking you which one
you think is the right one.