Now that all of our code is
running fast and awesome, let's
talk a bit more about memory and how it
affects the performance in our system.
Many programming languages that are
known for being close to the hardware,
or rather, high performance,
like C, C++,
and Fortran, usually programmers
to manage memory themselves.
Effectively programmers
are responsible for
allocating a block of memory and then
sometime in the future de-allocating
it when they're actually done using it.
Since you define when and how much
memory to allocate in free, the entire
quality of managing memory depends
on your skills and effectiveness.
That's a lot of responsibility.
And the reality programmers aren't
always the best at keeping track of
all those bits and pieces of memory.
I mean think about it,
product development is a muddy and
crazy process and often memory ends
up not getting freed properly.
These un-liberated blocks of memory, are
called memory leaks and they just sit
around hogging resources, that you
could use better or somewhere else.
To reduce this chaos, stress,
and sometimes big money losses,
caused by memory leaks,
managed memory languages were created.
The run times of these languages
track memory allocations and
release memory back to the system
when it's no longer being needed by
the application itself, all without
any intervention from the programmer.
This art, or rather science,
of reclaiming memory in a managed memory
environment is known as garbage
collection, this concept was created by
John McCarthy in 1959 to solve problems
in the lisp programming language.
The basic principles of garbage
collection are as follows, number one,
find data objects in a program that
cannot be accessed in the future for
example, any memory that is no
longer referenced by the code.
And number two, reclaim
the resources used by those objects.
Simple concept in theory, but
it gets pretty complex once you've
got 2 million lines of code and
four gigs worth of allocations.
Now think about it, garbage collection
can be really gnarly, I mean,
if you've got some 20,000 allocations
in your program right now.
Which ones aren't being needed anymore?
Or better yet, when should you
execute a garbage collection event
to free up memory that isn't used?
These are actually very
difficult questions, and
thankfully we've had about 50 years
worth of innovation to improve them,
which is why the garbage
collector in Android's Runtime,
is quite a bit more sophisticated
than McCarthy's original proposal.
It's been built to be as fast and
non-intrusive as possible.
Effectively the memory heaps in androids
runtimes are segmented into spaces,
based on the type of allocation and
how best the system can organize
allocations for future GC events.
As a new object is allocated,
these characteristics are taken into
account to best fit what spaces should
be placed into depending what version
of the android runtime you're using.
And here's the important part.
Each space has a set size,
as objects are allocated, we keep
track of the combined sizes, and,
as a space starts to grow, the system
will need to execute a garbage
collection event in an attempt to free
up memory for future allocations.
Now it's worth putting out that
GC events will behave differently
depending on what Android
runtime you're using.
For example, in Dalvik many GC events
are stop the world events, meaning
that any managed code that is running
will stop until the operation completes.
Which can get very problematic, when
these GCs take longer than normal or
there's a ton of them happening at once,
since it's going to significantly
eat into your frame time.
>> And to be clear,
the Android engineers have spent a lot
of time making sure that these events
are as fast as possible to reduce
interruptions, that being said,
they can still cause some application
performance problems in your code.
Firstly, understand that the more time
your app is spending doing GCs in
a given frame, the less time it's got
for the rest of the logic needed to keep
you under the 16 millisecond
rendering barrier.
So if you got a lot of GCs or some long
ones that are occurring right after
each other, it might put your frame
processing time over the 16 millisecond
rendering barrier, which will cause
visible hitching or jank for your users.
Secondly, understand that your code
flow may be doing the kinds of work that
force GCs to occur more often, or making
them last longer than normal duration.
For example, if you're allocating a
hoard of objects in the inner most part
of a loop that runs for a long time,
then you're going to be polluting your
memory heap with a lot of objects and
you'll end up kicking off a lot of GCs
quickly, due to this
additional memory pressure.
And even though we're in
a managed memory environment,
memory leaks can still happen.
Although they're not as easy to
create as the other languages.
These leaks can pollute your heat
with objects that won't get freed
during a GC event, effectively reducing
the amount of usable space you have and
forcing more GC events to be kicked off,
in a regular fashion as a result.
So that's the deal, I mean,
if you want to reduce the amount of GC
events that happen in a given frame,
then you need to focus on
optimizing your apps memory usage.
From a code perspective, it might be
difficult to track down where problems
like these are coming from, but
thankfully, the Android SDK has a set
of powerful tools at your disposal.
Let's take a look.