onConnectionFailed is pretty complex and
in many ways is the workhorse
of your application.
So in it you've just got to be
careful to manage all your states.
First of all,
you're going to use an intent, so
create an intent on the activity and
call it mSignInIntent.
Also create an integer that
you call mSignInInteger.
So when you create
the onConnectionFailed,
be sure to override it and it takes
a connection result called result.
Then you're going to need to
check your sign in progress, and
if its not STATE_IN_PROGRESS,
then set the intent that you've
created to result.getResolution().
If it is STATE_SIGN_IN, then you'll
just want to call resolveSignInError(),
which you will be writing shortly.
Otherwise, you're going to
call onSignedOut(),
because you're actually signed out.
Implement this functionality, including
the onConnectionFailed override and
check this box when you're done.
OnConnectionFailed is pretty complex and
in many ways is the workhorse
of your application.
So in it you just gotta be careful
to manage all your states.
First of all,
you're going to use an intent, so
create an intent on the activity,
and call it mSignInIntent.
Also create an integer that
you call mSignInInteger.
So when you create
the onConnectionFailed,
be sure to override it, and it takes
a ConnectionResult called result.
Then you're going to need to
check your sign in progress.
And if it's not STATE_IN_PROGRESS,
then set the intent that you've
created to result.getResolution().
If it is STATE_SIGN_IN, then you'll
just want to call resolveSignInError(),
which you'll be writing shortly.
Otherwise you're going to call
onSignedOut() because you're
actually signed out.
Implement this functionality, including
the onConnectionFailed override, and
check this box when you're done.