I have a confession,
picking a mapping and
counting edges to compute congestion
can make you more than a little crazy.
Eep.
Let me help you out.
Here's a shortcut to estimate
a lower bound on congestion.
Consider two hypothetical networks,
a logical and a physical one.
Now suppose you find a bisection
in the physical network.
By the definition of bisection width
this bisection will divide the network
into two pieces of
roughly the same size.
Here I am using V1 to represent
the nodes of one half.
And V2 to represent
the nodes of the other half.
Now the bisection cut will also
go through a bunch of links.
The number of such links
is the bisection width.
Let's call that B sub X.
Now bisecting the physical
network implies a cut
of the logical network as well.
So schematically,
it might look like this.
Now the cut in the logical network
will go through some number of edges.
Let's call the number of such edges
on the logical network capital L.
So in other words, what we're saying
is that there are at least L,
logical edges that map to B sub X,
physical edges.
So the congestion of the mapping
has to be at least L divided by B.
We can say more.
The minimum possible value that L
could have is the bisection width of
the logical network.
That's because the size of the cut that
splits the network in two has to be at
least the bisection width.
Again, that follows from
the definition of bisection width,
therefore a lower bound on the
congestion is the ratio of the logical
bisection width to
the physical bisection width.
Neat!
Let's see if this works.
Lets go back to the 1-D ring and
2-D taurus example.
So let's say we start
with a logical 2-D torus.
And suppose we map that
to a physical 1-D ring.
Do you remember the bisection
widths of these two networks?
They are 2 edges for the ring and
approximately 2 root P for the Torus.
Let's plug these in.
What you'll get is square root of P.
Now the true value of the congestion of
this mapping is square root of P + 2.
So you can see the lower bound
in this case is pretty good.
Here's what knowing
the congestion allows you to do.
You can estimate how much worse
the cost of your algorithm might be,
if you run a physical network,
that has less bisection capacity,
than your logical network.