So, let's look at this in our app.
If I click on Banner Ad now,
you can see onAdLoaded
is shown on the screen at the same
time the test banner is loaded.
If I click on the test banner,
you can see onAdOpened and
onAdLeftApplications are being
displayed, because the ad was opened and
we left our app to display the ad.
I can now go back to our app, and
you see, onAdClosed is called.
Let's see what happens if I turn
the phone into flight mode.
So I go over here to Settings,
turn the phone into airplane mode,
go back to our app.
Now if I click on the banner ad,
You can see onAd failed to load with
Network Element being displayed.
So all our callbacks are working fine.