So no matter where you are, that is, no
matter what your shell's current working
directory is, you can give a file's
path as either an absolute path
from the root, or you can use a relative
path from the current working directory.
For this quiz, let's say you're
currently in /home/otter.
Here are five pairs of cd commands.
For each pair,
figure out whether the two commands
will change the same working directory.
This first pair is an example.
If you're in /home/otter and
you do a cd That will
take you to the current working
directory's parent which is /home.
That's the same result as cd /home.
So yes, this first pair matches.
Try the next row on your own.
Remember, in each case your initial
working directory is /home/otter,
right here.