So AT&T collects data about you, and
it doesn't tell you how long
they're going to keep it.
So it doesn't disclose
its retention policy.
Actually we talked with Google,
it didn't do that either but
we'll get to that.
So they get a lower score because they
don't disclose their retention policy.
They do use industry best
practices to protect the data.
So this is the information security,
the data they collect,
how do they secure it from attacks
that can come from bad guys?
So they do best-practices.
But other reason they lose points is
because they're not transparent about
what data government demands.
Okay, so
law enforcement department comes to them
to get information they have collected.
And being transparent means
you tell what kind of
requests they get from
the government and
what kind of data they supply
in response to those requests.
And this transparency is not there, and
because of that, they lose another star,
and that's how they end
up with very low scores.
So, both of these,
if you don't do these things,
should count against you
in a privacy score, yes?
That's what,
and this is not true in this particular
case that we're talking about.