All right, so the next thing we said we
would do is consider adding a scalar.
So again, I wrote the Bellman Equation
for sum reward function R.
So this is the target behavior if
we use R as our reward function.
And now we're going to replace R
with a new reward function, R prime,
which is the old reward
function plus this constant C.
So now on every step,
we get an additional C reward that we
wouldn't have in the original thing.
So what does that do to our Q function?
What's our new Q function as a function
of the old Q function and this value C?
>> It'll be different from Q(s,a).
Are you going to tell me the answer?
>> I will, but
only after we do this as a quiz.
>> Okay.
Fair enough.
All right so,
it's just like what we did before
except now we're adding a constant.
So I suspect we ought to be
able to use similar reasoning
to get to the right answer.