All right.
One more thing.
In order for all of this to work, we need a pr-,.
a, a property called shift invariance.
And shift invariance is basically that your operator behaves
everywhere the same way.
So I have a couple of pixels over here on the left and I apply my operator.
If I had the same pixels over here on the right.
Oh, this is my left,
my right, your right, turn around, okay, or, look, never mind.
If I have them up and down, right.
If I have a couple pixels up here, and I apply a filter I get the same values if
I have a couple pixels down here and I apply a filter.
That means that I can shift things around and
do the addition, and get my entire image back.
As we said, because convolution or correlation are built on multiplication and
addition, these are linear operators,
making the whole notion of filtering a linear operation.
And this means that convolution has some very useful properties.
For example, it's commutative.
All right. So, f convolved with g is the same as g convolved with f.
Remember that whole idea about which is the impulse and which is the filter?
It's also associative.
So that here we, we wrote the associative property of convolution.
We're going to take advantage of that in just a minute.
It has an, a, a unit impulse.
It's the identity.
So that's what we talk about,
that if you convolve any function with the identity you get back that function.
And then here's a cool one.
Differentiation of course is just the limit of subtraction and then a division,
and a division is same as multiplication it's 1 over in that, in that case.
So differentiation is a linear operator.
Now you may have remembered that from calculus, right, so the derivative of
a times f, where a is a constant, was just a times the derivative of f.
And the derivative of f plus g was the derivative of f plus the derivative of g.
So, differentiation is also a linear operator.
And because of associativity we get this cool property here.
That the derivative of a convolution is the same as taking
the derivative of one of the elements and then convolving it with the second.
And we're going to make use of that when we do edge detection and
gradient finding in a little bit.