Burrell recognizes that this can be a common situation in
multithreaded environments.
And argues for a new construct, a condition variable.
He says that such condition variables should be used in
conjunction with Mutexes to control the behavior of concurrent threads.
In this modified version of the producer consumer code.
The consumer locks the mutex and checks and if the list is not full,
it then suspends itself and waits for the list to become full.
The producers on the other hand, once they insert an element into the list,
they check to see whether that insertion resulted in the list becoming full.
And only if that is the case,
if the list actually is full will they signal that the list is full.
This signal operation is clearly intended for whomever is
waiting on this particular list_full notification, in this case, the consumers.
Not that while the consumer is waiting,
the only way that this predicate that its waiting on can change, so
the only way that the list can become full, is if a producer thread
actually obtains the mutex and inserts an element onto the list.
What that means, is that, the semantics of the wait operation must be
such that this mutex that was acquired when we got to this point,
has to be automatically released when we go into the wait statement.
And then automatically reacquired once we come out of the wait statement.
Because we see, after we come out of the wait statement,
we actually need to modify the list and this mutex m was protecting our list.
So when a consumer sees that it must wait
it specifies the condition variable that it must wait on.
And the wait operation takes its parameters,
both the condition variables as well as this mutex.
Internally the implementation of the weight must ensure the proper semantics.
It must ensure that the mutex is released.
And then, when we're actually removed from the wait operation,
when this notification is received, we have to reacquire the mutex.
At that point, the consumer, so it has the mutex, it's
allowed to modify the list, so to print its contents and remove its contents.
And then the consumer will reach this curly bracket, this unlock operation, and
at that point the mutex will indeed be released