one of the best parts of this module is
that you'll be learning from experts in
academia and industry in a regular
classroom it would have been next to
impossible to bring together all these
people in the same place but online at
Udacity we can do that first you'll
learn about the foundations of machine
learning from professors Charles is
ballot Georgia Tech and michael wittmann
at Brown University afterwards you'll
tackle deep learning with Vincent van
hook principal scientist with Google's
deep learning infrastructure team along
the way drew gray who leads the
self-driving car team at auto which is
now part of uber will teach you
step-by-step how to use the same
frameworks that he uses to build deep
neural networks to drive cars finally
Brian Catanzaro the vice president of
applied deep learning research nvidia
will help you dive into how to use some
of the most famous deep neural network
architectures is a starting point for
your own work
great let's get started