>> To answer this question,
let's start by clearing our database.
Then, we'll open up the app,
press the plus button, enter a name, and
then press the create button.
Looks like it flashes green for the list
name node and yellow for the root node.
It flashed green here because
you're adding the list name value.
The route node flashes yellow
because it is the parent of
a node which has changed.
When you made additional
changes to the list name,
you'll notice it no longer flashes
green and, instead, both flash yellow.
In this case, the list name is
being overwritten and not created.
Now that you know
a little more about data,
Lila will show you how to
read from the JSON database.