Let's look at the pipeline of how we're going to compute Gaussians
and Laplacians.
I start off with my first Gaussian at the first level.
We know how to compute that using things like reduce.
Of course, now I can also compute a expanded version of the same image.
So in essence that is, in looking at the blur function a little bit.
And of course, I can compute a Laplacian, which is the subtraction of these two.
Then I can, of course, sub sample to get a smaller version of the image.
Which is where we go in for the pyramids and Gaussians here.
So this is Gaussian pyramid, this would be G0, and
this would be the expanded version of the same.
And of course, the Laplacian.
So notice that we can actually create and compute both the Gaussian and
the Laplacian pyramid for each and every image that we want.
So, here, I'm just basically showing you a Laplacian pyramid and
also a Gaussian pyramid.