All of the security features discussed
in the previous video are important, but
the implementation details
are different for each one.
Some have to be implemented on the
client machine, using the browser and
JavaScript, and others need to
be implemented on the server.
And sometimes,
security features must be implemented
on both endpoints to properly function.
As a full-step web developer,
it's your job to make sure security is
properly implemented in the right place.
Look at the following
security features below.
Decide if they should be implemented on
the client side, server side, or both.
If you're unsure, check out some of
the resources in the instructor notes.