The fourth category of connector is a little bit different than the other.
This is linkage connectors.
And they're responsible for describing the structure of the system.
That term linkage here, you can think in terms of link editors,
if you've ever heard of those ways of organizing or constructing or
putting together the pieces of a system.
Linkage connectors are responsible for
establishing the ducts and enforcing the interaction semantics.
Hence, they provide a facilitation service.
Because they're responsible for putting the system together but not for
actually running the system, they may disappear after setup is complete.
The unit of linkage might be a module, might be a file might be an object.
And related to this are tools like configuration management tools and
the make command for actually building a system.
There are semantic issues with respect to the granularity of the pieces and
the semantics that is the, what are the protocols among the pieces.
Among the variants that are involved with linkage connectors are whether they're
implicit or explicit.
For example, implicit might be something like make where you
merely state a overall target that you're trying to build and
the other building steps are done, done for you.
The granularity that is what, what unit is being put together.
Could it be variables, procedures, functions, and, and so on?
And then of course, the semantics, the cardinality in terms of defines and
uses provides and
requires, and a key one is binding, that is when does all this happen?
It might be at compile time, it might be at run time, or
might even be before compile time if, well,
part of your construction process involves things like templating or generics.