By now you've got a pretty good feature
list for each of your app ideas.
And you might be tempted to include all
of the features in your app, don't.
Seriously.
It's much better to implement one or
two ideas really well than to
implement all of them poorly.
To help whittle down your list of
features you can use the following
ranking system.
Now, required features are those
that have to be included.
Your app would not function
well without them.
Reasonable features are those
that you can implement, and
you know that you want to.
Ambitious features are then
you're nice to haves.
They would be cool to include in
the app, but you're either not sure
of your ability to implement them or you
have absolutely no idea where to start.
So now go ahead, go through
each of your feature lists and
mark each item as required,
reasonable, or ambitious.
If you'd like, share your list
with your fellow classmates and
see how they've ranked their features.
Check this box when
you're ready to continue.