Some forecasting methods are very
simple and occasionally effective.
But they do have their faults.
Let's take a look at Sam,
the simple forecaster,
who previously worked in your
position at Bates Hotel and
how he used simple forecasting
methods to forecast bookings.
When Sam was first tasked with
forecasting bookings for Bates Hotel,
he didn't know how to use
a sophisticated predictive model to add
early forecast results.
Nor did Sam want to
take the time to learn.
Instead, Sam used simple
forecasting methods so
he could hit the slopes before
they closed at the end of the day.
Sam's first attempt at forecasting
was to use an average method.
Here, the forecast of all future values
are equal to the average
of historical data.
The average model assumes that the best
predictor of what will happen tomorrow
is the average of everything
that has happened up until now.
For Sam and Bates Hotel management,
this was not the case.
Using our Sam the simple forecaster CSV,
we can calculate what Sam
forecasted using this method.
As you can see, Sam missed his
mark by over 9,000 bookings.
Yikes.
&gt;&gt; The next month,
Sam used the moving average method.
This method uses the average of
a time series over a defined number
of time periods.
Sam figured that the last 12 months of
bookings would be a good moving average
to base his next forecast.
Again, Sam was wrong,
missing by almost 3,000 bookings.
Management is starting to become
frustrated with the results.
Sam decided to give another method a try
since he's been unsuccessful with his
previous two forecasts.
This time he tried the naive method.
In this method all forecasts are simply
set to be the value of the last
observation.
Sam is getting closer yet
still off by over 1,000 bookings.
Naive methods are commonly used
when starting a time series.
If there is not enough data
to create a predictive model,
the naive method can supplement
forecasts for the near future.
It is also a theoretical basis for
sophisticated modeling.
For Bates Hotel though, they have lost
potential revenue using this method.
Sam was given one more chance to
forecast bookings for the next month.
Without any luck on
his previous methods,
he wants again to change his approach.
This time using a seasonal naive
method..Unbeknownst to Sam,
management outsourced the bookings
forecast to a consulting firm.
They believed using a sophisticated
exponential smoothing model
that they can beat Sam's forecast for
this next month.
Poor Sam.
Unfortunately for Sam, they were right.
Using the seasonal naive method,
Sam was once again off by
more than 1,000 bookings
with the consultants narrowly missing
their forecast by only a few hundred.
Had Sam known that the Seasonal
Naive Method will assume that
the magnitude of the seasonal
pattern will remain constant,
he would have made a better
choice selecting his method.
Needless to say, Sam was let go.
Don't be like Sam.