We've taken a look at correspondence done in a simple fashion.
And in fact that simple fashion is what you guys are going to do on
your problem set.
I want to take a look at a couple of slightly more sophisticated methods that
are actually closer to the state of the art in stereo.
There are a couple of ways we do that.
There's a bunch of stereo pairs out there for
which there is known ground truth of depth.
So here's one from the University of Tsukuba.
It's a well known scene, and the image on the right is the actual depth.
And these things can be generated in a variety of ways.
You use a laser scanner.
Some other method of being very precise and doing the matching.
But the idea is, if you're developing a stereo algorithm or
you're doing a paper or something, you have a scene for
which you can say, I know what the actual value should be.
So, the types of methods I was showing you before,
which are Window based matching,
on the left here we have sort of the best result of a Window based match.
And on the right is the Ground truth.
And we're using a false color image here.
It makes it a lot easier to see mistakes.
If everything was just gray values and
disparities, it's harder to see how things have changed.
And you'll notice that it does an okay job.
You know the, the mannequin head is in front of other things, but
it really does a pretty crummy job around the edges.
This movie camera in the back, whoops bad color, this camera in
the back is sort of all eaten up here, never mind what's going on over here.
So it has some general difficulties, and what we'd like to do is to see if we
can get a lot closer to that ground truth solution.
So better solutions do something more than
just individual correspondence estimates, all right?
Essentially what they want to do is they want to optimize the set of
disparity assignments, in some sense, jointly, meaning that I don't just
assign this pixel to somewhere and then this pixel independently.
I want to think of all of the assignments together in some way.
Come up with an optimal solution.
And this can be done in two different at, at least two different ways.
One is to do a scanline at a time.
So we're still going to do a line at a time.
But for all of the pixels in that line,
we're going to think about how we want to do the assignment.
And then we do that for each scanline.
And then even more modern methods, the ones that are,
that get even more improvement, they actually do it on a full 2D grid.
So we're not thinking just across the scanline but vertically as well.
So let's talk about the scanline methods.
So here I have, that's Kuva University picture again, and
we have two intensity profiles, the left and the right, all right?
So just to be very precise about it,
we have a 1D signal here, and a 1D signal here, and
we have to match every pixel here to some pixel somewhere over here, all right?
But what what we want to find is we want to find the best overall match,
that is the whole set of matches, we want the best set.