The answers are, the first sentence has erroneous syntax. We're using an and
here between two terms, but you can't do that. An, and can only be used between
sentences or predicates in first order logic.
The second sentence does correctly encode the
English sentence, Paris and Nice are both
in France. Similarly, the third sentence does correctly
encode, there's a country that borders Iran
and Syria. But the fourth one incorrectly encodes
it. Here, we have an x essential. There exists a C, and then an implication.
And that's usually the wrong thing. The problem here is not if C represents a
country, but what if C represents something that's
not a country, say my dog. My dog
is not a country, so there does exist a C, which is my dog, such that this
implication is true because whenever the antecedent of
an application is false, my dog is not a
country then the whole thing is true. But
the final sentence in English, no two bordering countries
can have the same map color. Both of
these are correct encodings. The first one seems more
obvious and the second one, we've just manipulated things a little bit. We know
that a implies b is the same thing as saying not a or b. So here, we've
just taken the left hand side and negated it, and then put those all together
with an or. So those, these two sentences
represent the same thing, and they're both correct.