Now that we've talked a little bit
about what machine learning is,
let's talk about how it can be used.
Machine learning can be applied
to nearly every domain.
In trading, for example,
machine learning is starting to be used
to predict what stocks will perform
well over the next months or years, so
we can make more sound investments.
In education, it's being used to
identify what students might be at risk
for not graduating, or not completing
a class pretty early in their studies.
So we can intervene, and help them along
earlier, and maximize their chance for
success.
In health care,
it's being used similarly.
We're using machine learning to try and
identify patients who have certain
illnesses, or are at risk for
certain diseases, long before
we've been able to otherwise.
Long before symptoms even appear,
so we can improve their treatment,
improve their prognosis.
I actually have trouble thinking
about any real field that can
not be addressed by machine learning.
So let's actually try that out.
Go to Google, and
Google machine learning,
along with some field that
you're interested in.
It could be a sport, it could be
a science, it could be a hobby of yours.
Just Google machine learning along
with something that you like, and
see if anything comes up.
And then in the box that we'll give you,
write down what you Googled, and
write down whether or
not you found out something that
machine learning is doing in that area.