Well, you might think, and
I'll go back to here, that it's because they're horizontal that we
know that they're parallel image planes.
But, actually, parallel image planes mean that the line,
the epipolar lines are all going to be parallel.
The only reason they're horizontal is because I happen to be holding the camera
in such a way, the, the pair of cameras, that the baseline between them
is horizontal with respect to the vertical in the image.
Right?
So basically if I had held things this way or rotated my one camera that way
ins, I would still have parallel epipolar lines because the epipolar
lines are defined by the geometry of the camera center and the point.
That is the plane, they just have to be in a plane.
But I can shift them up and down, I can rotate them.
And that will rotate or my parallel lines so it's not the horizontal epipolar
lines that tell you that the coplanar, but the fact that they're parallel.