That ends this lesson on SIFT descriptors.
As I mentioned, getting SIFT to work can be painful, and that's why those of you
who are taking the OMS version of this and working on a problem set using it,
we'll be giving you some libraries for computing the descriptors.
You're going to be on your own, for finding the points, finding the interest
points, and figuring out maybe the scale or maybe we'll just fix the scale but
the idea is that then you can use the library to do the descriptor.
Then, you're going to have to do all this matching.
Okay?
Now, you know, matching, if you think about that, suppose you've got a thousand
descriptors here and a thousand descriptors there, right.
That's a million combinations, if you're just trying to
compare this one to every each point here to every point there.
If you've got 10,000 that's 100 million, that might not
be really a very good idea, so you might want to do something smarter.
And, what would it be to do smarter?
What would be really smart would be to watch the next lesson, so
you can learn how to amaze your friends doing this.