All right, in this lesson,
we're going to add Cast Support
to the Universal Media Player.
We'll start with the version of UAMP
that's missing a few key pieces
like the Cast button, and
we'll add them back in one by one.
Specifically, we've removed the CCL,
the Cast button,
as well as the logic to play media.
But most of the functionality to handle
playback state has been left intact.
For this lesson,
you're welcome to download and
follow along in code if you like, or you
can just watch to get the gist of it.
I just downloaded the zip from
the link in the instructor notes.
This will be a great point to ensure
that your Android device is connected to
the same WiFi network
as your cast device.
Notice there are a couple
of layers in this project.
That's because UAMP uses
the CCL to make things easier.
So the first thing we'll need
to do is download and build it.
We're going to build the CCL as
a standalone library that we'll
include as an application dependency.
First, we need to clone the CCL
from the main GitHub repository.
To do so, open up a terminal and
use the command shown here.
Next, we need to build the library,
and we use Gradle to do so.
First to make sure that
your Android Home and
Java Home environmental
variables are set.
You can see how they look on my MAC
using the Echo Command and take a look
at the instructor notes to see what
to do if they're not set on yours.
Now go ahead and
build gradle using the command.
You'll see a whole bunch of output and
at the end you'll see BUILD SUCCESSFUL
if everything ran okay.
Here I've cleared the screen
to get rid of some noise.
And if you have a look at
the build output's AAR directory
you'll see the debug and a release
version of the CastCompanionLibrary.
The next step is to copy these
over to our UAMP source trees, so
we can link them to our application.
The directory you want to
copy them to is mobile/Libs.
Now if we go back to Android Studio,
we'll see them appear in our project.
The next step is to open up build.gradle
and add the CCL as a dependency.
Here I've copied and
pasted this line, and
notice that we're including
the debugged version for now.
In the future you can
include the release version.
Now go ahead and re-sync the project.
And if you run into a re-sync error
like I have, just make sure that
the CastCompanionLibrary is actually
named the way you included it.
Here we are inside UAMPApplication.java.
The CCL uses a singleton object
to manage it's internal state.
Let's go ahead and initialize it.
Notice also that while we initialize
it we can enable some features.
For instance, automatic reconnection.
Now UAMP does this inside
its application class, but
I'd actually recommend doing so
inside one of your activities.
The reason is that objects you
initialize within your application class
are actually global.
And so if you're creating things that
you don't necessarily need here later in
you application you're wasting memory.
Lazy initialization
is usually preferred.
Notice also that we've enabled
the debugging feature.
And for this lesson,
we're using an already registered styled
media receiver that's hosted by Google.
Here I am in our menu main.xml.
One of the user experience principles
is making sure the cast button
is always visible to the users.
They can control playback.
Its good practice to add the cast button
to every activity in your application.
To do so we need to add a media route
action provider item in the menu for
each activity and we'll do that
by editing the menumain.xml file.
I'll just scroll over so
you can see the whole thing.
This step assumes of course that your
activity is a sub class of of action
bar activity.
Now lets head over to
ActionBarCastActivity and
lets take a look at
the on create method.
Now that the CCL is all set up,
any activity can call
VideoCastManager.getInstance.
This instance provides all the
capabilities we need to manage the life
cycle of CAST in our app.
It's good practice to first make sure
that Google Play Services is set up
and enabled.
If not, the VideoCastManager
will prompt the user to do so.
And, when our activity starts up,
we check to see if we can reconnect
to an existing Cast session.
Next add the following line
the on create options menu.
You'll want to do this in
all your activities and
it will use the cast manager
to add the cast button for us.
CCL keeps track of how many
UI activities are running and
if at least one is active it will look
for cast devices on the local network.
Inside on resume of your activity,
add the following snippet to
tell CCL that you're active.
Likewise, inside on pause, add this
snippet to decrement the UI counter so
CCL doesn't waste energy looking for
cast devices when your
activities aren't running.
At this point, if you run your app,
you'll see the cast button appear.
The next step is to create a callback so
we can update RUI when
the receiver state changes.
For example, when it starts or
stops playing media.
CCL provides a wide variety of
callbacks you can use to be informed of
lifecycle events.
As you can see here,
there's a ton of them.
To make our lives easier,
CCL provides the VideoCastConsumerImpl.
This is a simple no-op
implementation of all the callbacks.
So you can extend it and just override
the ones you're interested in.
Here you can see we've implemented
a method that's triggered when
a cast device is discovered
on the local network.
We've also added logic to show
a first time usage screen to the user.
We need to register our callback when
the activity becomes active, and
likewise remove it when we're inactive.
At this point we've set up
the CCL to inform us about
any events that are coming
from the cast session.
Now let's see how to actually
trigger the playback of some media.
To see how that's done, let's head
over to the CastPlayback class.
This is an implementation of a simple
interface that contains playback logic
for different devices.
Inside the play method,
the first thing we'll have our sender
do is tell the receiver to load media.
The CCL uses the media info class to
hold meta data about the media to play.
For example, its title and its URL.
Next we use the CastManager LoadMedia
method to start playback
on the receiver.
Since we've already added a callback,
we'll be informed of the events returned
from the CCL,
when the receiver state changes.
And here's where we are informed of
that state change inside the video
cast consumer.
That's adding Cast
support in a nutshell.
As an exercise, you can continue to play
with adding Cast support to UAMP or you
can check out one of the many examples
on the Cast Developers homepage.