So that ends the lesson on stereo matching.
In fact, that ends all of our lessons on stereo.
You're going to implement the simple correspondence method.
By the way, for a more advanced version of this class, we ask to do the energy
minimization by either implementing or using the library for graph cuts.
If you're so disposed, you might find that a really cool thing to do.
When you go to implement this simple version,
hopefully you're going to be impressed by two things.
One is, doesn't work nearly, as well as I implied it work.
And I even, didn't even imply that it would work well at all, so
that's really going to be.
However, your computer will be seeing in 3D.
You're going to give it two pictures, we provide the pictures and
your computer will recover the depth.
You know, up until not that long ago, that was considered magic done by
human being's brains that was un, not understood.
And now you can do it on your iPhone, if you had two cameras.
Anyway, I hope you'll find it cool that you can recover that depth.
That ends for stereo.
Talk to you soon.