So I've talked about the possibility
axioms and the successor state axioms.
That's most of what's in
Situation Calculus and
that's used to describe an entire domain
in like the airport cargo domain.
And now, we describe a particular
problem within that domain
by describing the initial state.
And typically, we call that S0.
The initial situation and in S0,
we can make various types of insertions
of different types of predicates.
So we could say that plane P1 is at
airport JFK and S0, so
just a simple predicate and
we could also make larger sentences.
So we could say for
all C, if C is Cargo,
then that c is add to
JFK In situation S0.
So we have much more flexibility
in Situation Calculus
to say almost anything we want.
Anything that's a valid
sentence in first order logic
can be asserted about the initial state.
The goal state is similar.
We could have a goal of saying,
there exists some goal state s,
such that for all c.
If c is cargo, then we want
that cargo to be at SFO
in state s, so this initial state and
this goal says, move all the cargo.
I don't care how much
there is from JFK to SFO.
Now, the great thing about
Situation Calculus is,
that once we've described this in the
ordinary language of first order logic.
We don't need any special program
to manipulate it to come up with
a solution.
Because we already have
theorem provers for
first order logic and
we can just state this as a problem.
Apply the normal theorem prover that
we already had for other uses, and
it can come up with an answer of
a path that satisfies this goal.
A situation which corresponds
to a path which satisfies this,
given the initial state, and
given the descriptions of the actions.
So the advantage of
Situation Calculus is,
that we have the full power
of first order logic.
We can represent anything we want.
Much more flexibility than in problem
solving or classical planning.
So all together now, we've seen
several ways of dealing with planning.
We started in deterministic,
fully observable environments.
And we moved into Stochastic and
partially observable environments.
We were able to distinguish
between plans that can or
cannot solve a problem.
But, we had one weakness in all
these different approaches, is that
we weren't able to distinguish between
probable and improbable solutions.
And that will be the subject
of the next unit.