Of course if you're a photographer you already know terms like dodge and burn.
Dodge and burn are basically techniques that
actually are inherited from traditional photography done in the dark room.
Dodge of course builds on the screen mode concept we just covered and
is much more aimed at lightening an image.
While burn basically builds on the multiply and
is much more aimed at darkening an image.
And actually, in the good old traditional photography mode,
it's something equivalent to burning a negative before it's been processed.
Again, I'm just giving you a simple set of examples of these types of modes.
There are numerous other examples and variations linear dodge, linear burn that
are actually not [INAUDIBLE] completely driven by screen or multiply.
There are many different variations again, if you remember, that all we're
really trying to do is come up with the equation f of top layer and bottom.
Any processing I can do on a and
b can actually allow me to generate a new blend function.
And that's the strength of this approach by just getting the pixel values and
getting every one of them, you can come up with various ways of
blending pixel values from one to the other.
And that creates a foundation for
a whole lot of stuff that we will be looking at.