An interview is a conversation between
two people who want the same thing, for
you to get hired.
Here are some tips.
Don't think of the interview as
a test or exam, because it's not.
You're not supposed to show up and
repeat rehearsed answers.
Don't be afraid to ask questions.
If you encounter something you
don't understand, ask questions and
communicate what you do know.
That really helped me for
my Udacity interview.
I was speaking with a product
manager about reviews which
I was really unfamiliar with.
I finally said, I'm unclear on what
reviews is, could you explain?
After he did, I asked a lot of questions
and I was able to demonstrate what I
did know about education and
learning in general.
This showed that while I wasn't
an expert at the time on reviews,
I was a quick learner with a lot
of other related knowledge and
I could become an expert.
Don't be afraid to change the topic.
Of course,
you need to answer the question.
However, if the employer says something
interesting, you can ask about it and
dive deeper into it, which also is
another way to show off what you know.
Last, do be confident.
My job at Udacity is my first
job in the tech industry.
In the interview I was asked about a lot
of things I was really unfamiliar with.
I very easily could have
had a horrible interview.
However, I was confident and
I knew myself.
For every question that I
didn't know how to answer,
I approached it as research for
a problem I wanted to solve.
Being a problem solver is
the most important characteristic
an employee could have.
It's definitely something you need
to demonstrate in an interview.
Up next, we'll go over the STAR method,
a strategy for problem solving.