Lets put together what we've
learned to draw a smiley face.
We'll use ShapeRenderer to draw
the circles and arcs, and we'll also use
an orthographic camera and
an ExtendViewPort to frame the scene.
The tricky part is going
to be drawing the mouth.
Since we can't draw lines thicker
than a single pixel without
Open GL monkey business that doesn't
work everywhere, making a thick line for
the mouth is going to be hard.
The trick is to draw two arcs.
First, draw a black arc, and then you
can draw a slightly smaller yellow arc.
The portion of the black arc that
isn't covered by the yellow arc
becomes the mouth.
All right, check out the course
code to give it a try.