Let's take a quiz now in which we will compare the performance of some of
the multithreading patterns that we saw.
For this quiz we will look at an extremely simplified performance
calculation for the toy order application.
And we will compare two solutions.
One, which is implemented via the boss-workers pattern.
And then the second one that's implemented via the pipeline pattern.
For both solutions, we will use six threads.
We'll assume, also, that in the boss-workers solution,
a worker takes 120 milliseconds to process a toy.
For the pipeline solution, we will assume that each of the six stages,
where a stage is a step from this application, take 20 milliseconds.
The question then is,
how long will it take for each of these solutions to complete ten toy orders?
You should ignore any time that's spent waiting in the shared queues in
order to pass orders from the boss to the workers or across the pipeline stages.
And assume infinite processing resources, like tools or work areas.
Then, you should answer, what if there were 11 toy orders?
How long will it take each of these solutions to process the 11 orders?
You should write your answers below, expressed in milliseconds.