I can't think of anything right now, but it, I think, it's going to be along,
along the lines of it's going to be hard to extend it,
functionality later on at this point.
>> You're getting there.
And, and, you mentioned something about this this earlier on.
One hint to all this, is we have designed three classes that
satisfy the requirements of the coffee maker spec, but they, as yet,
don't depend on the specifics of the Mark 4.
If when we added the methods, we were explicitly include calls to the API, then
we couldn't reuse those classes when next years version, the Mark 5, comes out.
A better approach is to use a technique called dependency inversion.
Let's see how that works.