So here's this error that we've received
from running our filterPlayground query.
We've gotten this 503
Internal Server Error.
That's not very informative.
We go over to the Developer's Consule,
though, and look under monitoring and
logs, we can see a request to
ConferenceApi.filterPlayground returning
an error.
And if we take a look into that error,
we'll see it says here,
raised NeedIndexError (no
matching index found.
The suggested index for this query is,
and then it has kind: Conference,
properties: city,
month, topics and name.
So normally when test
the app on localHost,
indexes get autogenerated, and
they land in a file called index.yaml
which shows up in your source directory.
As you can see,
there's a previous index from
a simpler version of this query here.
But you can also specifically
define composite indexes for
all queries that you will run.
So knowing what you now
know about indexes,
which of the following
statements are true?
How can you make
sure that you will have all of
the indexes that your queries will need?
Could you manually edit
the index configuration?
Run every multi-property query on
localhost before you deploy to appspot?
Mark all properties you need
indexed with index equals True.
Or for single property indexes,
you don't need to do anything.