First things first.
There are too many fields and
a lot of them are completely irrelevant.
Why is this form asking for
a middle initial?
First off, not everyone has one.
And secondly,
it's just not necessary for a checkout.
Same thing with age and gender.
This is a checkout form not a census.
And still, why is age a drop down?
Isn't that a number?
Anyway, there's Confirm Email Address
which just annoys me,
like I don't know how to
type it the first time?
Don't put these on your forms.
I could keep going.
There are a lot of examples of
totally irrelevant information here.
And the layout isn't that great either.
The form doesn't try to help you out.
There's no indication of progress, and
nothing is being validated whatsoever.
So, it looks like you'll
have your work cut out for
you at the end of this
lesson when you fix this.