So you saw in theory how
the process works, but
now I'm going to show you a way that
you can actually witness the peDbHelper
class creating a database by exploring
your device's file system and
then watching the .db file appear when
the database is actually created.
So as a note,
the method I'm about to show you,
I highly suggest you
run on your emulator.
And this is because if you're
using a physical device,
that device needs to be rooted.
Also, all the steps that
we've seen in this video,
I'll be showing as text below.
So be sure to check that out
after you watch this video.
So in the CatalogActivity of our
project, I'm going to start by
commenting out the call to this method,
our displayDatabaseInfo method.
So we can actually, pretty much,
ignore this method right now.
And instead, I want to execute
the first line that it was calling
which was this one, creating
an instance of a PetDbHelper class.
Next, I'm going to go into my device and
clear out the data and
the cache as well.
Here's how that's done.
So you need to head over into settings,
go down to apps,
go to the app that we're interested in,
so
the pet's app, head over to Storage and
then clear cache as well as clear data.
So the instructions for what I just
did there will also be listed below.
So what happened clearing
out the data and the cache,
it erases any pre-existing
SQLite database for the app.
And so this should mean that, going
back to the app, nothing should appear.
So as expected,
our CatalogActivity isn't calling
displayDatabaseInfo anymore.
So, at this point no database has
been created because we didn't call
any getWritableDatabase method or
any getReadableDatabase method,
which we had done in our
displayDatabaseInfo method down here.
So to confirm this, I'm going to show
you how you can check up the data that's
on our device, and show you that
there's no database in it juts yet.
And, as a reminder, the method will
require you running it on an emulator
instead of the physical device,
unless you do have a rooted device.
So start off by heading to the Android
Device Monitor, this button right here.
So from here,
with our emulator selected,
head over to the File Explorer, and
this feature allows us to
explore a device's file system.
So what I'm interested
in is this data folder.
If we click into that, scroll down just
a bit, we find another data folder, and
scrolling into it, I want to find
the package that we're interested in
which is com.example.android.pet,
and that should be right here.
So if you click that open,
you can see the data that's
associated with this application.
So if we click through it, we see
there's some files associated with this
app already but none of them
are database files so no .db files.
And remember,
that's because this line of code,
our getReadableDatabase method
hasn't even been called yet.
So we've skipped it because we're
skipping over our displayDatabaseInfo
method here.
So instead, I want to copy and paste it
up into this onCreate method up here.
So now I'm going to rerun the app and
see what happens.
So if you have not
initiated Instant Run yet,
be sure to do that if
it's the first time.
So tools &gt; Android and
Enable ADB Integration.
I'm going to click run again,
all right, so the updated code ran.
And let's see what happens
in our data package.
So back in the emulator,
File Explorer, back into data &gt;
data again, and then down into
the package that we're interested in.
So notice that a new folder
called databases is created.
If we open that up, perfect.
So as expected we have
a shelter database file now.
So we just saw that adding the method
call, getReadableDatabase,
actually created
something on our device.
So if I decide to run the app again,
no new file will appear
because the getReadableDatabase method
will simply be providing a connection
to this existing database,
instead of re-creating it.
So if I want to see the contents of
our shelter.db file, I can download it
through our DDMS, which is our
Dalvik Device Monitoring Service,
or which is what we're seeing here,
by pressing this button here.
So what this does, is that it
pulls the file from the device.
So I want to call it shelter.db, and
let's save it off to our desktop.
So that file name looks really
similar to what we worked with
when we were in the terminal.
And that's exactly what we're
going to do right now, so
head over to the terminal.
So one quick way to see that is
actually through Android Studio.
Clicking this button here takes us to
the terminal on our computer already.
So remember, the keyword to get into
the SQLite 3 program was sqlite3,
followed by, actually remember that
I saved it off onto my desktop.
So I'm going to make sure I
head over to the desktop,
I'm going to cd into my desktop.
And then from here,
I'm going to open up sqlite3 program and
the shelter database file that's on it.
So from here I can use
my .tables command.
So I see that there are two tables.
So the first one here,
android_metadata is one that's
created by the android system.
And the second one pets was created by
us in onCreate method of petDdHelper.
Now, I can use
the PRAGMA TABLE_INFO command
to see the columns in my database,
so let's use that.
And, remember,
because this is an SQL command,
I'm going to end it with a semi-column.
So, this shows all
the columns in my table.
Remember, we can use .scheme command
to show SQL statement that I use
on my code to make the table.
Now downloading the database from your
device can be kind of laborious, but
it is one useful way that allows
you to debug your SQL code.
So if you're trying this out and
your table doesn't look like this,
then something probably went wrong
with the creation statement here.
So you can erase the database
by uninstalling the app and
then fix the code and
then reinstall the app again.
So when the database is matched and
it's working correctly,
you can move on to the next step.