Next, we will use the content
resolver to call this method query.
This query method is
part of a set of four,
mapping to the four CRUD
methods mentioned earlier.
Just like with a SQL live database,
there are four basic things that you
can do with the content provider.
You can read from the data,
add a row or rows to the data,
update the data, or delete a row or
rows from the data.
These actions amount
to four basic methods.
Query, insert, update, and delete.
So basically, you specify what you want
to do, by calling contentresolver dot,
and then one of those methods.
Then the content resolver tells your
content provider to perform that action.
You want to read data from the content
provider, not change anything.
So, you'll be calling the query method.