[Thrun] So we're now ready to define Bayes networks in a more general way.
Bayes networks define probability distributions over graphs or random variables.
Here is an example graph of 5 variables,
and this Bayes network defines the distribution over those 5 random variables.
Instead of enumerating all possibilities of combinations of these 5 random variables,
the Bayes network is defined by probability distributions
that are inherent to each individual node.
For node A and B, we just have a distribution P of A and P of B
because A and B have no incoming arcs.
C is a conditional distribution conditioned on A and B.
D and E are conditioned on C.
The joint probability represented by a Bayes network
is the product of various Bayes network probabilities
that are defined over individual nodes
where each node's probability is only conditioned on the incoming arcs.
So A has no incoming arc; therefore, we just want it P of A.
C has 2 incoming arcs, so we define the probability of C conditioned on A and B.
And D and E have 1 incoming arc that's shown over here.
The definition of this joint distribution by using the following factors
has one really big advantage.
Whereas the joint distribution over any 5 variables requires 2 to the 5 minus 1,
which is 31 probability values,
the Bayes network over here only requires 10 such values.
P of A is one value, for which we can derive P of not A.
Same for P of B.
P of C given A B is derived by a distribution over C
conditioned on any combination of A and B, of which there are 4 of A and B as binary.
P of D given C is 2 parameters for P of D given C and P of D given not C.
And the same is true for P of E given C.
So if you add those up, you get 10 parameters in total.
So the compactness of the Bayes network
leads to a representation that scales significantly better to large networks
than the common natorial approach which goes through all combinations of variable values.
That is a key advantage of Bayes networks,
and that is the reason why Bayes networks are being used so extensively
for all kinds of problems.
So here is a quiz.
How many probability values are required to specify this Bayes network?
Please put your answer in the following box.