I don't know about you but I can see
five things that are wrong here.
Number one the text fields in the header
don't stretch all the way horizontally.
And if you can't see them just go
to Canvas, then Layout Rectangles.
So this way you can see
the text fields and
they don't take all
the space like they should.
Number two, there's no space
between the stack views and
we should turn this back on.
And see,
no space between the stack views.
The text field doesn't take
enough vertical space.
The buttons here are distributed
in a kind of funky way and
they take up way too
much vertical space.
This vertical space should
belong to the text field.
So I suggest you pause the video now and
think of what you would do
to fix these five issues.
Okay, let's continue so
let's fix number one,
the header is a vertical stack view.
So we just need to change
the alignment property to Fill,
and now it takes all
the available space.
If you want to see the text fields
just go back here, see there they are.
The second one,
the lack of space between the stack
views it's also easy to fix.
Select the root Stack View,
and by the way when you have
many stack views it's a good
idea to give names to them.
So, let's do it right way,
this is going to be the Root one,
then we have the Header,
inside the Header we have First Name and
Last Name, and we have the Footer.
Okay so lets select the Root Stack View
and add some spacing.
I like 8, that's the standard value by
the way, the one recommended by Apple.
Now the distribution of the footer is
Fill, this algorithm has two features.
Number one, it doesn't care about
the intrinsic content size of the views,
that's why it changed them all.
And number two it favors the first view,
that's why the first button is
much bigger than the other ones.
We can fix this by changing the
distribution and we have a few options.
Actually we have three, Fill Equally,
Equal Spacing, or Equal Centering.
I prefer, Fill Equally and
then put some spacing, let's give it 20.
The last two issues
are actually the same thing.
Text view and footer are fighting for
vertical space and
we want the text view to win this fight.
How can we do that?
We can do it by lowering its
Content Hugging, and we're almost there.
There's just one minor problem
that you can see if you remove
the rectangles, and it's here.
There is no space between
the caption and the text field, and
also there is no space between these
two rows, these two stack views.
We know how to fix that, so
we'll add some spacing to
the First Name Stack View.
Again, I'll use 8, that's the standard
and same thing for the Last Name.
And if we want to add some spacing here
we need to select the Header Stack View
which is vertical and add some spacing.
Again, I'll use 8, and
check this out the first one is now
much narrower than the second one.
Why?
Because of the distribution algorithm,
it's Fill and
Fill always shrinks or
expands the first one.
So, let's use Fill Equally and
it looks much better.
So make sure you understand everything
that went wrong and how we fixed it.
By understanding this you will soon
realize there's a logic to auto layout
in a bizarre kind of way.
So stick to your commandments and
principles and don't panic.