So far,
we've talked about all to one reduce.
Start with a set of nodes
on a linear network.
Initially, each node
has a vector of data.
Performing a reduce produces
the combined data on one of the nodes.
This node that stores
the result is called the root.
Now a reduce has a natural partner.
It's called a one-to-all broadcast,
or just broadcast.
In a broadcast, one processor
has all the data initially.
It wants to send a copy of this
data to all other processes.
So it's basically one process
shouting in a room to all others.
So in principal if you
know an algorithm for
reduction, then you also know
an algorithm for broadcast.
You basically run
the reduction in reverse.
Because of this relationship
between Reduce and Broadcast,
I'll refer to them as
Duals of one another.
Here's another useful
collective operation.
It's called a Scatter.
In a Scatter,
one process starts with a data.
It then sends a piece of its data
to each of the other processes.
A scatter also has a natural dual.
The dual is called a Gather.
In a Gather, everyone has a piece
of data, and one node collects it.
How do you like my
primitive cheese people?
Another useful primitive
is an All-gather.
Initially each process
has a little bit of data.
After the All-gather, all processes
have a copy of all of the data.
And All-gather also has a natural
dual called a Reduce-scatter.
In a reduce-scatter, initially all
processes contain a vector of data.
They then globally reduce this data
using some kind of combining operator
like a vector addition or
vector element-wise multiplication.
The result is distributed
to all processes.
By contrast,
recall that a normal reduction,
an all to one reduction, leaves all
of the results on just one process.
I'll show you some techniques for
implementing all of these
collective operations efficiently.
I learned these techniques from a fellow
by the name of Robert van de Geijn.
Once you've learned those methods,
you can then simply invoke them
as collective operations in your
algorithms whenever you need them.