Let's have a quick checkpoint
of what we've done so far.
You've done a lot.
So, first of all, you were able
to get the geoFencing Event.
And then you were able to determine
what the transition was from that event,
whether you were exiting or
leaving the geoFence.
You then got the list of geoFences
that were triggered during that event.
Remember, more than one can be
triggered if they're overlapping.
You created a string out of this list.
And then you created a notification
helper that generated
a notification from that string.
So now, all you have left to do is to
call the method, the send notification
method that sends the notification for
us, and add that to your onHandleIntent.