Remember our shortcut for
constructing a graph laplacian.
Along the diagonal, we'll fill in
the degrees of all the vertices.
So for instance,
vertex 5 has a degree of 3.
As for the off diagonals,
they'll just mark all the edges.
For instance,
5 is connected to 2, 4, and 8.
So if you look at a graph laplacian,
you'll see -1 entries at 2, 4, and 8.
By the way, as you'd expect,
the motion of the system is wavy.
[MUSIC]
Whoa, groovy, baby.
I like to dream.
Yes, yes,
right between my sound machine.
On a cloud of sound,
I drift in the night.
Any place it goes is right.
Goes far, flies near,
to the stars away from here.
Well, you don't know what we can find.
Why don't you come with me,
little girl, on a magic carpet ride?
Oh, you don't know what we can see.