Laying out the sub views
is the first step.
And having some input from a designer or
an engineer with designer skills
is extremely useful here.
There are three different but
equivalent ways of doing this.
Let's check them out.
The first one is code.
So, let's first create
a UIViewControlller, and
see how we can lay out the views,
just using code.
You must overwrite the loadView
method of UIViewController and then
create and position the views by code.
This way provides the most
configurability but
you have to lay out visual elements
in the code which can be difficult.
It is usually done out of necessity
in huge teams where storyboards or
XIB files cause many conflicts in GIT.
Unless you enjoy shading with a machete,
this is probably something
you'll never have to do.
The next method is by using XIB files.
XIB files are similar to storyboards but
simpler.
They only include one scene.
This was a standard before storyboards.
Unlike the code option, this is
something you will likely have to
use at some point while developing apps,
either while reusing a view
controller or when working on a team.
In order to create a XIB file
just create a view controller and
check also create XIB file.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Here you have the single scene of the
XIB file and you would setup your layout
just by dragging components just
as you would do with a storyboard.
The last way of laying our your
sub views is by using storyboards.
This is the latest set and the currently
standard way of designing interfaces.
Storyboards allow developers to
graphically lay out multiple scenes and
views in a single file.
All of these methods have one thing
in common, they're all static.
There's no information about
how the UI should adapt
if the size of the screen changes.
That's where auto layout comes in.