But there's one other pair that I, I need you to know about.
And again we're not going to derive this but it's important.
And that is the notion of a pulse train or a set of impulses, okay.
And so this is refered to as a pulse train, you can see that here.
And the Fourier transform of pulse train is another impulse train.
And the thing that you need to realize is that, and remember the scaling theorem
give us this and a bunch of things give us this, right?
As the pulses in space get further apart,
the pulses in frequency get closer together.
And this is a hand-wavy way of thinking about this.
Imagine that our pulses got very, very far apart, okay?
So far apart that I have an impulse in the middle and
the next one is infinitely far away.
Well, that would be just like having sort of a single impulse.
That's the hand-wavy part.
Well, what is the Fourier transform of a single impulse?
Well, we said it was a 1 because an impulse gives you back the,
when you can involve it, it gives you back the entire image.
So therefore the frequency has to keep all the frequencies.
So the hand wavy way of thinking about this is,
as I stretch out my impulses in space, I have to shove all these impulses and
frequency in time infinitely close together to make a solid bar.
Okay, and that's one way of thinking about how the Fourier transform of
an impulse train is another impulse train, and
as they get bigger in space they get closer in frequency.