Before we go any further,
I need to jump in here.
We already mentioned that the refresh
button is for debugging only, but
let's look at why.
In real life, you should always
seek to eliminate the refresh
button from your app or
at least make it unnecessary.
A good app should work
like a good butler,
giving you what you want before
you even have to ask for it.
Much like the save button, it's a relic
from a bygone age, that's at best,
a reassuring safety blanket for those
of us who grew up with floppy disks.
With the ability to run background tasks
or send messages directly from your
server to your app, there's no reason
to force your users to hit refresh.
That the app is up to date and
synced with a cloud should be a given.
Also, this means it's not desirable to
use async task and activity to do this,
because we're coupling what
should be a background operation,
fetching data from the Internet, with
a foreground component, the activity.
We'll cover storing data in databases
and scheduling background tasks in
future lessons, both of which are
critical for making great Android apps.
But like we said this is for
debugging, so
like logging statements, it's
acceptable for this particular purpose.