In this quiz you're going to practice
creating a text view object and
then call methods on it.
Since this is just for practice,
we're going to do this in a new Android
app outside of the JustJava app.
That way we don't mess
up the JustJava app.
Open up the project wizard in Android
Studio by going to File &gt; New Project.
Then you can accept the defaults for
all of these.
Make sure you have blank activity
template selected, then click Finish.
Once your project gets created go
ahead and run your app on your device.
The default behavior should be to see
the words Hello World show up here.
But now we're going to do
something a little different.
In the main activity class, we're
going to modify the on create method.
Instead of calling set content view
on this activity main XML layout,
we're going to create our own
text view and set that here.
On the Android Developers site,
there’s a Training section where it
talks about building your first app.
Specifically, I’m looking at the Display
the Message part of the tutorial.
It tells you that in
the activity onCreate method,
we can create a TextView.
And here's the code we recognize
from earlier in this lesson.
We're creating a new TextView and
we're storing it in
a variable called textView.
This constructor requires
a context as an input parameter.
And passing (this) as
an input parameter,
because (this) refers to
the current activity.
And an activity is also a context,
so this so
this will correctly create
a TextView object for us.
Then we can call methods
on this TextView object.
Remember that this is a textView
variable name, not a TextView class.
That's why t is lower-case here.
We can call textView.setTextSize and
textView.setText as an example.
When you scroll down it says
to call setContentView and
pass in this textView
as an input parameter.
If you scroll down further
it actually shows you
a code sample of the onCreate method.
We don't need this part.
We're just focused on this part
where we're creating a textView and
then we're setting that as
the contentView of the activity layout.
Back in Android Studio in
the MainActivity class,
I'm going to modify the onCreate method.
I'm going to insert
some blank lines here.
First I'm going to create a new
TextView object using the constructor.
I'm going to give it a variable
name of TextView, but
feel free to call it something else as
long as it's appropriately descriptive
of what this is.
The text you constructed
requires a context, so
I'm going to pass in this
to refer to this activity.
And then on the next line of code,
I'm going to call a method
on the textView object.
As soon as I hit dot, it's going to show
me all the possible methods that I could
call on this textView object.
If I start to type then it will filter
down these auto complete options.
You can see the options have narrowed.
I'm going to choose setText so I can
hit enter to use this auto complete.
Then I can put in a string
as an input argument.
And the last step is to change
the set content view line.
So instead of using this XML layout file
I'm going to just paste in textView.
I'm going to save this and
then run this on the device.
What I expect to happen now is that the
screen will show a new text view that
says Wow on it instead of hello world.
And it does.
It's a little underwhelming though.
So I want you to make it
a little more interesting.
I want you to call other methods,
on this textView object,
like try to change the color,
or the text size.
If you're even more adventurous,
you can try calling up other
methods on the textView object.
Look at the online documentation for
textView.
In order to figure out what
the other possible methods are.
When you're done,
check these boxes to continue.