Okay, we made a variable but
nothing about the functionality
of the app has changed yet.
The next thing that I want
you to do is to make it so
that when you click the +3 POINTS
button, the score goes up by 3.
Meaning that if I click this
multiple times, it should be adding.
These other buttons
don't have to work yet.
It's fine.
Now again, I want to stress planning.
So, before you actually go ahead and
write this in Java,
you're going to write it in English.
Or at least you're going to write it in
a special kind of English that Katherine
talked about in the lesson
called Pseudocode.
So, let's say your goal is that when
the +3 POINTS button is clicked
you want two things to happen.
And I'm making this kind of
a multiple choice problem.
So the things that you can
have happen during Step 1 are,
you could display scoreTeamA.
You could change the value
of scoreTeamA to 3,
or another way of saying that
is set the scoreTeamA to 3.
You could display the scoreTeamA plus 3.
Or you could increase
the scoreTeamA by 3.
And then for Step 2,
you have these same options.
So just randomly,
if you want your two instructions to be,
Display the scoreTeamA, Set the
scoreTeamA to 3, you would select A to
first Display the scoreTeamA, and
then B, set the scoreTeamA to 3.
Okay, you tell me,
what do you think the two steps are?