Data is sacred.
Every hour of every day a new
sensor is connected to the web.
Every trip, every memory,
every creation,
every discovery joins the ever-growing
web we're building together
amidst a world of ever-growing
skepticism and falsehood, data is truth.
It's transparent, provable.
Most of it is unstructured streams of
raw numbers being amassed at dizzying
rates but by applying intelligence
to it, we can find the patterns and
connections that matter.
We can find the meaning
hidden in the numbers.
The economists says, more for
you is less for me, but
the lover knows, more for
you is more for me too.
And when we visualize the right data.
It gives us that most precious feeling
at the intersection of art and science.
Wonder.
&gt;&gt; Hello world!
It's Raj.
And today, we're going to learn
how to preprocess a data set.
Yes!
Preparing data is one of
the most important yet
most overlooked parts of
the Bashan Waning Pipeline.
A lot of introductory tutorials just
have you import a pre processed version
of a data set like
handwritten characters or
movie ratings in just
a single line of code.
Real world is not that easy.
Once you've decided what problem you're
trying to solve or you have a question
that you want the answer to,
it's time to find the right dataset.
&gt;&gt; I want to know what happened
to the plans they sent you.
&gt;&gt; I stored them on Microsoft Azure.
&gt;&gt; The predictions your deep net makes
are only as good as the data you give
it.
Garbage in, garbage out.
So you want to make sure your
data is relevant to your problem,
there are tons of resources to find
publically available data sets and
I linked to some in the description.
The defacto standard format for
data is CSV, most software packages out
there deal with data in that format and
you can convert your data into
CSV format just as easily.
There is so much we could
potentially do to our data but
there are three key
preprocessing steps for
every dataset we'll cover, cleaning,
transformation, and reduction.
We're going to look at three different
datasets and go through these steps for
each one to get them ready to
be [INAUDIBLE] into a model.
So let's start with our first, the first
dataset we'll use is music based.
This data was collected from
a game called Tag A Tune.
In the game,
two players listen to a song and
tag it with songs or instruments
that they think are relevant.
When the song is over, the player who
had the most correct tags gets a point.
&gt;&gt; So, I would win every time.
&gt;&gt; Our dataset has 25,000 songs
with the correctly labelled tags.
We want to train a model on this data so
that given a new song it'll
correctly classify its genre.
We'll import pandas to help
us parse this dataset,
then the read CSV function
will let us store the data
in the two-dimensional pandas data
structure known as a data frame.
Data frames are easily modifiable and
we'll call our variable new data.
Let's explore this data first, shall we?
We'll display the first five rows
using the head function with five as
the parameter.
So, basically, each row is numbered.
Has an id and then either a one or zero
next to a tag to indicate whether or
not the given MP3 has that tag.
Seems simple enough.
We can use the info function
to get some more data.
Only 38 megs.
So for our cleaning step,
is there anything we need to do?
Not really.
Each label has a simple binary tag.
It's consistent and luckily our
data does not have empty values.
&gt;&gt; But my soul does.
We can move right on to
the transformation step.
What are some modifications we can
make to this data that will make it
easier for our model to understand?
Well, notice how a lot of the tags
are pretty similar sounding.
Like female singing, female vocals,
we can generalize these features
into one feature called, female.
Let's create a two-dimensional list
of synonyms that we find in our data
then we can merge them and drop all the
other columns, except for the first one.
For each synonym list in our matrix,
let's get the max values from each of
the features and add them all to our.
For synonym in our data object,
which will effectively merge
the values into one column.
Then we'll drop the rest of
the features from the data frame.
Now, we've got more
generalized features.
Next, for
the reduction step, what can we remove
from this data that's not necessary.
Everything seems pretty solid, so
let's go ahead and foot it into
training validation and testing sites
that we can feed into our model.
Notice how in this example, I'm not
thinking which features to use and
which not to.
Before deep learning we had to pick the
right features to use to fit our model.
But deep learn high level features
from whatever features we give it.
It decides for itself what is relevant
to the problem from a dataset?
Architecture engineering is
the new feature engineering.
The second dataset we'll use is
a collection of network connections,
either labeled normal or abnormal.
The abnormal connections
are intruders trying to break in.
We want to be able to classify
a connection given the set of
other features.
When we look at this data,
it seems pretty dense.
No missing values,
nothing really jumps out as an outlier.
So, let's skip the cleaning step and
move right on to transforming it.
Our numerical features are all
operating on different scales, so
we should normalize them to insure each
feature is treated equally by our model.
After storing our data into
a Pandas DataFrame, scikit-learn has
a handy submodule called StandardScaler,
which will import, than initialize.
After that, we're ready to
move on to our reduction step.
We got a lot of features, and
there are probably a lot
that are highly correlated.
We can use a technique called
dimensionality reduction to
reduce the number of features we have.
This will also let us visualize
our data in 2D or 3D space.
This doesn't mean that our model
will be more accurate, necessarily.
Just that our data is easier to read.
One method of doing this is
called PCA which stands for
Porsche Club of America.
Wait, wrong definition,
Principal Component Analysis.
[MUSIC]
My data got's so many features.
I'll squash into three
like little creatures.
First I'll normalize, then I'll
correlation matrixize [INAUDIBLE] infect
[MUSIC]
So, let me summarize this process again.
Let's say we had four features and
we wanted to them to just two using PCA.
There are five steps to this.
The first is to normalize the data
once we have it stored in a variable.
Then we want to compute a covariance
matrix, to construct this we compute
the covariance between each
feature with every other feature.
So we subtract the mean from the feature
matrix, calculate the transpose and
multiply it by the feature
matrix minus the mean.
Then, we take that whole value and
divide it by the number
of features minus one.
This gives us our covariance matrix.
Next, we'll perform Eigen Decompostion
on it to get the Eigen vectors and
Eigen values.
&gt;&gt; Eigen,
isn't it such a fun word to say?
&gt;&gt; Eigen vectors are the principle
components of a data set.
They give us the directions along
which our transformation acts.
The Eigen values give us
the magnitude of each.
We'll sort both in descending order,
then create a matrix out of them.
We'll use this matrix to transform
our orignal feature matrix
via the dot product.
We could then plot our
data in 2D space and
use these principal components
to replace our many features.
Let's look at one more data set,
this time for airline prices for
flights between New York and Paris.
We want to predict the ticket price
from just the departure date.
We've got departure and
arrival dates, Airport and
flight prices up to 120
days before departure.
Notice how we've got quite a few
missing values in our data.
So for our cleaning set, we could remove
these values, fill them with zeros,
fill them with the average
price across all the days, or
try to predict them using
a learning algorithm.
Let's go ahead and calculate the average
price for each row across all days.
Using the mean function, and
they will iterate through the data and
if it's null,
we'll replace it with the mean price.
Then we can smooth our data.
That means finding outliers
in it that we can remove.
To find these, we could run
clustering or regression algorithms
on certain values to find
the outliers and then remove them.
Or just remove them by eye.
Since our dataset is small,
let's do the latter.
No need to reduce our data.
This seems like a good set.
Lets break it down.
There are three sets to
preprocessing a dataset.
Cleaning, transformation and reduction.
Deep learning learns the relevant
features from our data so,
architecture engineering is
the new feature engineering.
And principal component analysis
is a popular dimensionality
reduction technique that can be
implemented with scikit-learn.
The winner of the coding challenge from
the last video is Charles-David Blot.
Charles-David used just NumPy to
build a three layer neural net
capable of predicting an earthquake.
And he used the random search strategy
to find the optimal hyper parameters for
his model.
Wizard of the week.
And the runner up is Siby-Jack Grove.
He used TensorFlow for
his prediction using just three inputs.
The coding challenge for
this video is to use a dating data set
to predict if someone gets a match
based on their personality traits.
Details are in the readme.
Post your GitHub link in the comments,
and I'll announce the winner next video.
Please subscribe if you want to
see more videos like this.
Check out this related video.
And for now, I gotta predict if
roses really smell like poo poo poo,
so, thanks for watching.