If you've taken Udacity's course
on configuring Linux web servers,
you set up an Apache web server
on your development machine.
Otherwise, you might have experimented
with setting up a web app on your
own computer or another computer.
Then, you probably found yourself typing
an IP address into your browser, so
you could access your app.
But real web sites have to domain names.
You don't type any Udacity's IP address
when you want to watch this course.
By setting up a domain,
you make it easier to show off
the web apps that you create.
Plus, domain names cost money, so
this is a totally optional exercise.
If you register a new dot com domain
name with Google, as of today,
it'll cost you US$12 per year.
Other domains and
other registrars have different pricing.
If you don't feel like paying that,
just skip this exercise.
That's totally okay.
Unfortunately, I can't make
domain registration free.
But if you're up for it, you can
get some live experience in another
aspect of running a real
service on the network.
If you'd like to do this,
just go to domains.google.com, and
follow the instructions there
to set up a DNS domain.
Or you can use any other DNS registrar.
Google works just fine though,
so that's what I'll use.
They're not paying me to tell you that,
by the way.
So, here's me setting up
a domain with Google.
First, I have to pick a domain name.
I want one that's actually new and
available, not one that somebody wants
to sell me for a few thousand bucks.
Here we go.
My new website is going to
be greenspaceghost.com.
Okay, I've got to fill out this
form with my name and address.
But I'm going to set this option of
make my info private, so my name and
address and phone number and
all aren't publicly listed.
I don't want any more email from Google.
Now, it's asking me if I really
want to buy greenspaceghost.com, and
I'll say yes.
Now, I'm in my domain and
I select configure DNS.
And then,
go down to custom resource records.
I'm going to put in a record for www,
and put my IPv4 address in there,
which is going to be this,
and add that record.
It says successfully saved.
And now,
if I go to www.greenspaceghost.com,
I get my website.
So, here's the exercise and
again, this is totally optional.
Go to domains.google.com or
any other DNS registrar, and
register a new domain, then add an A
record pointing at the IPv4 address for
your development server.
If you do, put your A record's
name here, and we'll check it out.
If you don't want to,
just mark this box instead.
Again, this might cost you about US$12.
If it costs much more than that,
try a different domain.