The security association specifies
a two-way security arrangement between
the sender and the receiver.
This is false,
because a security association
only specifies a one-way arrangement
between a sender and a receiver.
Second, SPI is used to help receiver
identify the SA to
un-process the IPSec packet.
This is true.
Third, if the sequence number in the
IPSec header is greater than the largest
number of the current anti-replay
window the packet is rejected.
This is false, because in this
case the packet is accepted and
the window is at advantage to
discover this new sequence number.
Fourth, if the sequence number
in the IPSec header is smaller
than the smallest number of
the current anti-replay window,
the packet is rejected.
This is true.