[Thrun] The answer is 0.55.
The way to compute this is by the theorem of total probability.
Probability of X2 equals heads.
There's 2 ways I can get to this outcome.
One is via this path over here, and one is via this path over here.
Let me just write both of them down.
So first of all, it could be the probability of X2 equals heads
given that and I will assume X1 was head already.
Now I have to add the complementary event.
Suppose X1 came up tails.
Then I can ask the question, what is the probability that X2 comes up heads regardless,
even though X1 was tails?
Plugging in the numbers gives us the following.
This one over here is 0.9 times a half.
The probability of tails is 0.8,
thereby my head probability becomes 1 minus 0.8, which is 0.2.
Adding all of this together gives me 0.45 plus 0.1,
which is exactly 0.55.