The Carter Center in
Atlanta is famous for
monitoring elections to
make sure they are fair.
This year, they decide to have their
interns practice on local elections.
Sally, a Georgia Tech
computer scientist,
turned activist, needs to visit these
three polling stations on election day.
The night before,
she plans to stay at a hotel close
to one of the polling stations.
After checking the voting
machines at the first station,
she will visit each of
the other two in turn.
Sally is on her bicycle, so she wants
to minimize her travel distance, and
she is willing to go the wrong way
down one way streets to do it.
Fortunately, Sally took
the artificial intelligence course, so
she knows how to write a program
that tells her where to start and
the optimal streets to use to
get to each polling station.
Proud of being a nerd,
Sally wrote her program such that it had
minimal runtime and memory overhead.
How did she do it?
Choose the best answer.
Remember, these challenge questions
are designed to give a preview of
the lesson to come.
We do not expect you to know
how to do the answer yet.