The last implicit intent we'll
cover is the share intent.
When I click
the Share Text Content button,
a chooser dialog appears from
the bottom of the screen
showing all the apps on the device that
are able to handle this type of intent.
When you want to share data there's
a lot more you need to think about
than if you're just
starting a new activity.
Depending on where you want to send the
data you have to think about what type
of data it is, the number of files,
and other things.
To save you from all those concerns
Android had a special helper class
called ShareCompat.
ShareCompat and
it's inner class IntentBuilder abstract
away all of these decisions so
you can chain together the bits that you
need and ignore those that you don't.
Before we construct the share intent,
let's talk a little bit more about
how to specify the data inside it.