So what is the right error function?
Well, we refer to this error function as the geometric error, and
it works as follows.
Let's suppose I have some points in the world capital Xi, and
here they are shown in yellow.
And furthermore, let's suppose I have an image and
I know where those points are in the image.
And those are the, the red Xi's here and these are these little red points here.
Now, when I specify a camera projection, some sort of an m.
Right? What I'm saying is I know where those capital Xi's,
the real points, are supposed to project to the image plane.
And what I want to do is I want to find the M that gives me the smallest
distance between the predicted X size and the ones that I actually found.
And that's what this equation here says.
What it says is we have an error function that is
the sum of the distances between the observed points, those are the red Xi's.
And the predicted image locations, the white Xi's here of, of where the,
the particular M predicts that the points in the world would land in the image.
And what I want to do is I want to find the M that minimizes that value.
And now what's kind of cool is, I might have a more complicated mapping
from points in the world to my 2D points that include things like,
modeling radial distortion, but fix for me the focal length.
The idea is I'd have some great big nonlinear function that does
the full projection.
And what I want to do is I want to minimize this error function by min,
by manipulating the parameters of that big nonlinear function.
And you might do that using your favorite Levenberg–Marquardt or
some other way of doing nonlinear minimization.
So if you read about this in a book and the, it says, the Gold Standard.
Well, the Gold Standard of this type of work is the book on
Multi-View Geometry by Hartley and Zisserman.
What they refer to as the Gold Standard of calibration is,
Given some number of points, more than, greater than or equal to, but
should be greater than 6, where you have 3D to 2D point correspondences.
The way to find, they refer to it as the Maximum Likelihood Estimate.
We could talk about why that's the case later, I'll tell you right now.
You're assuming that your the place that you located the points in
the image was perturbed by a little bit of Gaussian noise.
So you maximize the likelihood by making that as small as possible, and
you want to minimize the square error, if it's a Gaussian error.
So the way you do that is as follows.
You first compute a linear solution.
Now Hartley and Zisserman talk a little bit and, and this is for
those of you who are going to be more involved in doing some of this.
What you might want to do is, you know, if you're measuring your points out
here in meters, you might have some big numbers or
small numbers depending upon your coordinate system.
Your size of your image, you, you may have different pixel values.
They do a normalization, so that everything sort of goes between zero and
one to try to get numerical stability.
So when they do that, they, they create new vert, new external world points and
new image points.
You can do that or not.
Then what you do is you solve the thing I showed you before.
The direct linear transformation using, typically, the eigenvector approach.
That gives you a starting point for the M matrix,
which gives you a starting point for your nonlinear function.
And then what you can do is you can try, u, u,
using the M, you project the points.
And then you can minimize that total distance that's what's written down
below using, like I said, your favorite nonlinear method.
After you've done all that, if you've done the normalization, you have to
denormalize or, or, or translate back from the, the normalized methods.
So that's how you get out your M.
And that's what they refer to as the Gold Standard alg, of, of calibration.
We only use bronze, which is why in your problem set,
you're going to use just the direct linear method.
And you're going to see that even without, I, I will tell you this,
that the first time we did this we had people do the normalization and
it turns out the normalization by just some, but not a lot.
When we do it this time, you can use the normalization or not.