In the previous module, you learned
how to use Google Authentication
to sign into your Android app.
It gave you a very basic access to
the users details using the plus APIs.
You might remember that we spoke
a little bit about scope., and
the scope that we used gave access
to this profile information.
But your users may not want to
give you that much information.
They might just want you to know who
they are based on their email address,
for example.
So in this module, you'll learn
how to handle that scenario.
The user only allows you to
get their email address and
that's all that you'll get.
Now you'll probably also notice that
the button you got on your app when
you were signing in was
the red Google+ one.
You may not want to offer
that to your users, and
just give them a basic sign
in with Google button.
So in our first example,
you'll see exactly how to do that.