Okay. So where are you guys now, with your respect to your project?
>> So we wanted to do, to try to sort tweets on Ebola into certain buckets.
The ones we came up with were based on certain words,
whether we think they sound like misinformation, that's was >> Mm-hm.
>> An idea you sort of prompted us with.
Another one that we came up with was sort of panic mongering words.
>> Uh-huh. >> Coz that there's a lot of that.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And it maybe is an offshoot of that coz before we came in
here we were starting to think of if there's correlation of especially these
panic mongering words with political words.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Coz it's becoming more and more of a political issue.
>> So that's the rough, sort of,
structure, I think, of what we're trying to do is.
>> So what are the buckets that you're applying
to do that one is misinformation, and political tones, and.
>> And maybe one was just critical information.
>> Okay.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And the basis for
that was there are some Twitter handles that are being trusted more, with ,.
Been coming from trusted sources.
So, we could use those as references.
>> Oh, okay.
So, for example, cities might have a Twitter account.
>> Right. >> And that might be verified by Twitter so,
that is an authentic account.
>> Exactly. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> And in terms of the technology.
So, basically, we're going to follow.
We connect the spots as, to the [CROSS-TALK].
>> Mm-hm. Hm.
>> originally, we were planning to do some, lo, location,
v, visualization, but since we know only a small part of the,
the Twitter we have visual location data >> Mm-hm.
>> And, we don't want to, e, e, e, exclude that all those other things, so.
Well we, we probably got an inquiry audit where it's just for those of us-
>> Okay. >> That's and the part.
Later we can figure out if we want to add location visualization or not.
>> Okay.
I think like even this playing the bucket and
coming up with some kind of score-able Percentage of misinformation versus.
>> Right. >> Political tones, or even panic mongering and all, right?
That itself is a good fate of how much, you can measure it.
As long as you can measure it and
give me the count, or give me the percentage, how much is going on, right?
>> Yeah. >> That itself is a, a good thing to have.
It's a very practical application.