So now we can start to talk about sampling and aliasing.
So before we do that, we have to talk about the notion of sampling at all and
the notion, and, and the idea of reconstruction.
So here we have a the idea of some nice smooth scene illuminated by
a light source and then we have an imaging system that
captures the intensity at a bunch of discrete places.
And of course, what we'd like to do, is we'd like to take the captures from
these discrete places, and be able to reconstruct this nice, smooth signal.
That is to know what that signal is.
Let's talk a little bit about sampling.
Sampling arises when we come up with this notion of,
how do you store a continuous signal in a computer, right?
So here we have a continuous signal, and this is in 1D, and
we're going to do a lot of our stuff in 1D today because it's easier to draw.
And so the obvious way of representing that, it's actually not
the only way because you can imagine different clever basis kinds of things,
but sort of a, a normal way of thinking about that is by samples.
That is, you just take the samples at each different location and
you write down what the value is.
And once you have that set of samples later what you want to do
is reconstruct what the original signal was, right?
And why do you want to do this?
Well, maybe you actually want to use the signal, you want to play it.
If this is audio, you want to play it through a speaker.
And I don't need samples, I need a continuous voltage.
Or maybe I want to do some sort of analysis or
a mathematical processing in terms of thinking about what this signal is.
So essentially, what you have to do is you have to
guess what's going on between each of the samples.
That's all you can do.
You have the samples at discrete places but
you need to connect the dots if you will.
You need to fill in what's going on.
And a lot of what we're going to be talking about today has to do with
what's actually going on, when you think about taking a set of samples and
then trying to guess what's in between.
So to illustrate most of these points we're going to use a 1B signal, so
you think of this like audio, all right?
So here's an interesting audio signal.
You see this signal?
This, so this is time, okay, it goes this way.
And it starts off with a low frequency and it gets higher and higher and
higher and higher, higher, higher and stops.
All right, if you were to play that sound, you would hear what's called a chirp.
Okay, it's actually what it's called,
it's called a chirp, it comes from radar, et cetera, whatever.
It's something that has power in lots of different frequencies so
when you send a chirp out, no matter what the frequency response of
the thing you might be hitting is, you'll get something back.
It also, it, it's also a nice way being able to localize it.
There are lots of good reasons to use what's called a chirp.
But here's a chirp that has higher and higher frequencies.
But it's a good signal to think about looking at aliasing.