Hello and welcome back.
In module five, we have covered
a lot of interesting topics,
starting off with image transformations,
where we learned about how to warp and
transform images, applied them for
image morphing, then we learned about
image panoramas and HDR, and
a few other things, like stereo.
Now I want to introduce to you a series
of lectures recorded by my very good
friend Aaron Bobick, for the Computer
Vision class on camera calibration.
When we talked about HDR and panoramas,
we talked about the fact that we wanted
to be able to take images and actually
take the pixels from those images and
model them to the environment.
And of course, that meant the geometry
of the scene, and also the radiometric,
the color information in the scene.
Now, what we want to do here is
talk about calibration in a general
framework.
In those lectures,
I talked about relative information.
That is, to take a series of images, and
the pixels from that could be used to
model relative information in a scene.
Now we want to be able to do this
in a much more general framework.
What I'm referring to here is a series
of three lectures by Aaron Bobick.
Aaron and I have known each other for
a very long time,
he's been teaching
computer division here.
He is much more funnier than I am and
of course his interesting lectures
will actually keep you engaged.
This is optional material and
I just want you to watch them, and
it'll give you guidance of what happens
when you want to actually start getting
into things like the photosynth
application that we've looked at
that actually gets 3D
points from scenes.