The word test may bring
back memories of school.
I remember staying up much too late
the night before a final exam,
trying to cram in as much
information as I could.
These were stressful high pressure
situations because I wanted to
perform well.
There was a lot riding on the results.
Namely passing the class.
In these situations, I sometimes felt
as if the teacher was testing me.
But here's a different
way to think about it.
What if the teacher was
actually testing themselves.
I'll come back to this example
in a moment, but first,
let's discuss another kind of test.
A test that cannot be passed because
the test only gives results when
the subject fails.