So the first step was made really easy.
All you need to do is
uncomment these lines here.
For the second step, I had to change
the user profile creation code so
that user.nickname is used for the
display name and user.email is used for
the main email value and that's it.
If you set up the web client ID
correctly and configured the consent
screen correctly, you should now be
able to log in to your app on appspot.
If instead of getting a consent screen
here, you're getting an error message or
forbidden error, check to make sure
you've entered the URL correctly and
that the email and project name
are set in the consent screen.
You can also check the instructor
notes for some help.