So ACTION_DETAIL is the action for when
a user views the details of a product,
so that's basically anytime they
go to the view product page,
or they select the product in a list.
And you're going to be doing that
with the dinners in a minute.
When the user purchases the product,
the action is somewhat
unsurprisingly ACTION_PURCHASE.
When the user removes the product from
the cart, the action is ACTION_REMOVE.
Okay, I'm guessing this is
going to be ACTION_CHECKOUT.
And in fact, it is.
So all of these, I think,
are very intuitive.
The one that's perhaps not quite so
obvious is ACTION_DETAIL, which is
basically what you use whenever a user
views the product or views the details.
So maybe it should be ACTION_VIEW.
But, no, it's not, it's ACTION_DETAIL.
I just need to remind you that
these actions are purely for
information to send to Analytics.
You'll still need to write the code
to actually add the product to
the cart, etc.