Now let's look at a one-d signal and start thinking about how would we
actually reconstruct a signal based on the information that's available to us.
Here is a signal that's basically in one dimension and it's a repeating
impulse function, which basically means that this function is zero and
all of a sudden there's a peak.
It comes down.
Peak.
Comes down.
Peak. Comes down.
So, in the four times it repeats.
So this is, you know, four different periods.
Whenever it hits point one, two, three, and
four, it repeats and hits a magnut a magnitude.
A one.
So that's why it's referred to as a repeating impulse function.
What we're interested in is, if this is my target signal,
how would I go ahead and reconstruct it if I knew anything about the signal?
To help us do this, let's create a building block.
The simple building block we want to actually use here is this function.
Which is a cosine where A is the amplitude and omega here is a frequency.
So, just by varying the omega and the times of omega, for a specific A,
I want to be able to generate a function, f, and I want to be able to see if I
can actually use this to start creating a recreating a signal like this.
So we're interested in forces using a function like this,
where we can vary the n, omega,
the frequency, time is of course the variable that goes on this axis.
And of course, you want to be able to go,
in this case, an amplitude of A which is 1 and generate a signal like this.
Any thoughts on how we would do this?
Well let's get into it.
So if you just remember some of your earlier math
concept that you may have studied in past what we want to do
is now create a repeating signal that goes and has four periods.
And it goes from, in this case, 1 to minus 1, back to 1, minus 1,
back to 1 and basically, it's repeating.
And of course, this is an output of this cosine function,
where t varies from 0 to 4 here, and we're changing omega.
Now of course, if you know any things about sines and cosines, you know that if
this term here is going to be a specific value, the value of this one will be 1.
So of course that basically means in a repeating circle like this,
we're basically changing the angles.
And of course sines and
cosines of these angles have been computed and plotted on this thing.
So let's look at a variety of these things.
F1 was when we basically just replaced it and we basically have this value.
Now in this case I'd claim n was 1, what happens if I make the n 2.
So replacing the f n value to be 2.
With the same omega and t.
We now basically are getting twice as many repetitions for the same period.
So now, of course, this is higher frequency information.
We're getting more signals, and peaks and signals coming in than we did before.
Here is basically now I've basically gone for the n value of 3, and
repeated the signal again, so the more frequencies are coming in.
Here of course f4.
Again, higher frequency.
So in essence what we've done is we've gone from low frequency information to
high frequency information here, now let's look at all of them together.
This is the f1, f2, f3, f4.
before we go on further, let's actually introduce a way for
you to play around with the similar kind of concept on your own,
on the browser, or on MatLab, or in OpenCV.