All right, so
do you see what to do here?
>> No.
>> Okay, all right, so
here's my suggestion.
So remember this B thing is
just a bit of notation here.
And what the notation is saying is that
whatever value function you give it,
you can replace this whole thing with
a value function defined like this.
>> Right.
>> All right, and so imagine what
happens if you actually plug all that
in, if you actually take this BQ* and
replace it with the definition according
to this operator definition above.
>> That says that Q*
is actually equal to,
well that's the definition of Q star.
>> Do we have a name for that?
>> Q star?
>> Sure, we have a name for Q star,
but the equation that defines Q star.
>> Well it's the Bellman Equation.
>> Yay!
>> That was easy.
Okay.
>> And you don't have to put the
exclamation mark to get the full credit
for that one.
>> Oh, I don't know.
I think you should require they
put the exclamation mark or
they don't get full credit.
>> No, I think it's okay.
>> All right.
>> In fact,
anything that has Bellman
in it should be fine.
>> Anything that has Bellman in it?
>> Yeah, like the Bellman Identity.
Or, the [LAUGH] I don't know.
I was trying to think of
other sequels that have.
>> The Bellman Ultimatum.
>> Yes, Bellman reloaded.
All right, so, good.
So with that kind of thought process
in mind can you do the next one?
So we have some Q function,
we apply the Bellman Operator to it and
we get some new Q function.
>> Bellman update?
>> Yeah, it is a bellman update.
But this now you can
think of as an algorithm.
It's going to actually generate a whole
sequence of value functions one from
the next.
>> PV?
>> [SOUND] No.
>> No.
>> Well then I don't know
because I'm trying to, oh, wait.
This is value iteration.
>> Whoo!
>> Yeah, I think I need extra
exclamation marks with that.
That makes perfect sense.
>> Yeah.
So
value iteration is this big algorithm,
and it probably takes a page of code or
whatever to write, but
in this operator notation, boom.
You start off,
probably to be more precise,
you want to say something like Q0 = 0
value function or something like that.
You need to initialize
the value function.
But then after that,
you're just generating value
functions from other value functions.
That's exactly how
value iteration works.
>> Yeah.
And it would work even
if Q0 weren't last to 0.
>> That's true.
Yeah, but if we want it to be
a complete algorithm we'd have to say
where it starts and then how we
generate new things from old things.
>> It just starts with whatever
happened to be in memory at the time.
>> I see.
[LAUGH] Yeah.
That could run you into trouble,
but probably shouldn't.
As long as the types are correct.
>> Yeah, well it doesn't matter,
they're just bits.
They're ones and zeros.
>> Yeah but
they'd better be interpreted
as floating point numbers.
Because if you interpret
them as imaginary numbers or
something like that it could make
the Bellman equation act strangely.
>> It doesn't matter,
the operators will do the right thing,
they'll just interpret them as numbers,
or doubles.
>> Perfect.
Okay, well then we're all happy.
So I guess what I was hoping
to do with this example is,
you know convince you to
develop an appreciation for
this particular notation,
this Bellman Operator notation,
because we can write stuff that we
care about really, really syncly.
>> Yeah, yeah okay I'll buy that, and
it means that you'll be able to
fit everything in on a slide.
>> [LAUGH] Which will be good,
and look at how less,
I'm messing around with subscripts,
it's very nice.
>> I like your subscripts.