Before you begin, let's go over what
you'll be working on the first week.
To start with, you'll be introduced to
machine learning through regression
models using Scikit-Learn.
The concepts you'll learn here
apply to deep-learning as well, so
while regression isn't as flashy,
it's important to understand.
Next, you'll get an introduction
to neural networks.
We'll cover basic perceptrons,
the building blocks of neural networks.
Then have a train networks using
gradient descent and back propagation.
Finally, we have a short
project prepared for
you where you'll build your first
neural network using only Numpy.
TensorFlow hides a lot of details.
And it's important to understand how
neural networks make predictions and
how they are trained.
All right, let's get started.