Now let me show you, perhaps,
the most exciting example of
controllable light sources or
a projector camera system, where both
a camera and a projector are used to
generate light that's controlled enough
to actually become a headlight on a car.
This is what going on at CMU, and I'm
going to let them describe it to you.
[MUSIC]
>> Automotive headlights have been
on the road for nearly 135 years.
But surprisingly, driving at
night is still very dangerous.
Today's headlights are bright,
energy efficient, and
even adaptively illuminate the road.
But even the best ones are not generally
for performing multiple tasks,
and they typically
require mechanical parts.
We have developed a headlight with
a single hardware configuration
that can be programmed to
adapt to any road environment.
The key component of our design
is a spatial light modulator,
such as a DMD chip,
commonly found in DLP projectors.
The benefit of using
a spatial light modulator,
is that a single beam from a light
source can be divided into a million
smaller beams, each of which can be
controlled to react to the environment.
The spatial light modulator is optically
co-located with a camera that senses and
captures images in front of the view.
The images are analyzed with a processor
that also controls the spatial
light modulator to appropriately
illuminate the road environment.
In order to be useful at highway speeds,
we determined that the headlight needs
to react within two milliseconds
of acquiring an image.
A high speed spatial light modulator was
built by combining a custom DMD board
and the chip with the optics and
the light source of an off
the shelf DLP projector.
The result is a spatial light
modulator capable of display rates
of over 1,000 hertz.
The prototype is a little bulky,
so suction cups are used to
mount the prototype on the hood of
a pickup truck for road testing.
We demonstrate the versatility of
the headlight by first addressing
one of the biggest problems while
driving on the road, the glare problem.
The solution to this problem is
straightforward due to the high
spatio-temporal resolution
of our prototype.
After detecting oncoming
vehicles by their headlights,
only the light rays directed
toward other drivers are disabled.
This works for any number of vehicles
in any number of lanes on the road.
This should look familiar to anyone
that has been blinded by headlights.
The anti-glare feature of
this prototype is disabled
to emulate the glare typically
seen from standard headlights.
When our system's anti-glare
function is enabled,
the difference is very dramatic.
The oncoming driver is no longer
blinded, and the vehicle and
the road environment
become more visible.
Now how does it look to the driver
equipped with the headlight prototype?
Because the prototype has unprecedented
resolution over space and
time, there is little perceptible
difference to the driver
even with three oncoming
vehicles in the other lane.
So with the programmable headlight,
drivers can use the brightest headlights
available, or always keep their high
beams on without losing too much light.
This is a stark contrast to
LED-based anti-glare headlights.
Another problem that our headlight can
address is poor visibility in the snow.
Driving at night during
a snowstorm is a nightmare.
Snowflakes appear as bright flickering
streaks and are very distracting.
The problem is mainly caused by light
from our own headlights reflecting off
the snowflakes and back to our eye.
The solution to this problem is
very simple with our headlight
by avoiding illumination
of the snowflakes.
In other words streaming light
in between the snowflakes
the visibility of
the snowflakes will be reduced.
This might seem like a crazy idea, but
preliminary experiments with artificial
snow demonstrate that it is technically
feasible, while significantly improving
visibility, with little loss in light.
The current prototype is ten times
faster than our previous prototype with
much better performance, bringing
this technology closer to reality.
>> So, hopefully you will agree.
This is pretty impressive,
what they are trying to propose here.
Again, if we really think through it,
this is a system where
there is a camera.
There is a controllable light source.
And both of them are in tandem, working
to be able to illuminate the scenes, or
turn off the illumination where there
are objects that we want to prevent
being illuminated.
So pretty much like the last instance
we looked at, where we basically turned
on the projection,
where there was person, occluding it.
So we actually turned off the projection
where the person was occluding it,
not get to the screen.
Now in this case, we basically have
a light source that flickers out, for
example, where there
is another car coming.
So we can turn off the lights there, or
where there small flakes would be, and
we can turn it off, or
rain and stuff like that.
Very impressive, and again,
you saw a little bit of the description
of what we have talked about before.
That is how we can actually create
modulated light sources and
how we can actually compute all
of the information within it.
Pretty exciting.
Again, I encourage you to look at
the details of this on your own
from the website down here, and
also the video that I have also linked.