>> But how does color blindness come from cones.
>> So, actually before we talk about color blindness, I think it makes sense to
talk a little bit about color.
>> I think that's a great idea, because what exactly is color.
>> So, remember how we talked about how sound is a wave. >> Yeah.
>> light's actually a wave too. >> Oh, really?
>> And so, what that means is that, well, remember the properties of waves. Do you
remember which property corresponded to pitch?
>> Yeah, that was frequency.
>> Exactly. And so, what would a, for example, high frequency wave look like?
>> It would look like this.
>> And what about a low frequency wave?
>> Excellent. That's perfect. So, high frequency, lots of fast oscillations; low
frequency, fewer waves per second, slower oscillations.
>> So, what does frequency have to do with light waves?
>> Well, Lauren, with light, we actually usually talk about wavelength, which is
the distance between let's say, here and here.
>> And light waves can have all sorts of wavelengths, but we can only see certain
wavelengths.
>> Which wavelengths can we see?
>> The smallest we can see is 400 nanometers, and the largest is about 750.
>> But, what's a nanometer?
>> right, well, 1 nanometer is actually equal to 1 billionth of a meter.
>> Well, what's the difference between the big ones and the small ones?
>> Well, that's how we see color. Let me show you something.