I asked about what is interesting for
him in iOS development basically,
again, to find
if he's passionate about this, if it's
not something that he chose at random.
Well what pays more?
Android or iOS developer?
Then I'll just choose this one.
No.
I want to make sure
that he's passionate about mobile
development and iOS in specific.
You don't want someone who's
coming to this market or
ecosystem for mostly or exclusively for
reasons that exclude passion.
He must be interested
in what he's using.
He must own an iOS device.
He must be a user of
what he's going to code.
So maybe I should have asked,
do you own an iPhone and
if he pulls an Android, you're fired,
this obviously not the right candidate.
He did well he did definitely well.
And again I think he's
passionate about this.