Now there's a convention in situation
calculus that predicates like at,
we said plane p was at
airport x in situation s.
These types of predicates that can vary
from one situation to another are called
fluents, from the word fluent having to
do with fluidity, or change over time.
And the convention is that they
refer to a specific situation and
we always put that situation argument
as the last in the predicate.
Now, the trickiest part about situation
calculus is describing what changes and
what doesn't change as
a result of an action.
Remember in classical planning
we had action schemas,
where we described one action at a time,
and said what changed.
For situation calculus, it turns out to
be easier to do it the other way around.
Instead of writing one action,
or one schema, or one axiom for
each action, we do one for each fluent,
for each predicate that can change.
And we use a convention called
Successor-State Axioms and
these are used to describe what happens
in the state that's a successor
of executing an action.
And in general, a Successor-State Axiom
will have the form of saying for
all actions and states, if it's possible
to execute action a in state s,
then, and I'll show in general what they
look like here, then the fluent is true,
if and only if action a made it true or
action a didn't undo it.
So that is either it wasn't true
before and a made it be true.
Or it was true before and a didn't
do something to stop it being true.
For example, I'll show you
the Successor- State Axiom for
the in predicate.
And just to make it a little bit
simpler, I'll leave out all the for
all quantifiers.
So wherever you see a variable without
a quantifier, assume that there's a for
all.
And what we'll say is it's possible
to execute a in situation s.
If that's true, then the in
predicate holds some cargo c and
some plane in the state which is the
result of executing action a in state s.
So that end predicate will hold if and
only if either a was a load action.
So if we load the cargo into the plane,
then the result
of executing that action a,
is that the cargo is in the plane.
Or it might be that it was already true
that the cargo was in the plane in
situation s, and a,
is not equal to an unload action.
So, for all a and s for which it's
possible to execute a in situation s,
the inpredicate holds if and only if
the action was a load or the inpredicate
used to hold in the previous state and
the action is not an unload.