If you read through the hybrid DSM
implementation section you will see that
it mentions several examples of DSM
systems and specifically describes
what are the software tasks that
those hybrid implementations support.
And for
every one of those examples prefetching
is listed as one of the software tasks.
It makes sense that prefetching is a
good task to be implemented in software.
Whether or not prefetching is useful
is going to depend on a particular
application, on the kind of
access pattern that it exhibits.
At the same time, address translation or
triggering invalidations
are more concretely defined.
And it's easier to implement
them with hardware support.
For these reasons,
prefetching pages is the only
correct answer to this question.