I hope you found the basics of Storm's multi-language capabilities interesting
and potentially useful to your topology design process.
I'll walk through my approach here, but as always, feel free to skip ahead to
the next section if you didn't encounter any problems.
In step zero, after adding your credentials to the tweet topology file,
end of step one-creating a resources directory and
making sure it's in your Storm folder.
We've registered this folder location in the palm.xml file by copying and
pasting the Maven module.
So we copy, navigate to the palm.xml file, paste and finally uncomment.
See that the structure directory that we created is source/jvm/udacity/storm.
Which corresponds to the source jvm Udacity Storm file structure we have.
Make sure you don't list the resources directory here.
This ensures that the resources folder will be a folder in
the jar file as required by the storm.python module.
In step three,
you could follow the link below, or navigate from storm.apace.org.
Click on any programming language.
And click on adapters in Python.
Not example topology, which takes you to Nathan Marse's older code.
Once in the adapters in Python page, click on Storm > Storm starter, and
finally, multilangresources.
Finally, in step four, we copy this storm.py and splitsentence.py files.
Remember that these files go in the resources directory and
create storm.py and splitsentence.py.
Finally, copy and paste the storm.py and splitsentence.py files.
In Step 5,
after reviewing the usage of Python bolts, and my hint in Step 6 that shows
the inner class SplitSentence extends ShellBolt implements IRichBolt is needed.
In Step 7 we create a new file in the storm folder,
making sure it's not the resources folder, named splitsentence.java.
After copying and pasting the interclass splitsentance.java into your new
java file and the required import statements,
remember that your package structure needs to be updated.
Remember, package.udacity.storm is udacity.storm.
We imported all of the import statements from the prior file, but for
sure we know we don't need the random sentence spout, we can comment this out.
Finally, in step eight,
we remove the static statement since we're now defining a class.
And in step 9, we update the Topology to use the SplitSentence bolt.
We navigate to the tweetToplogy file.
And scrolling down to the Topology section,
we comment out the old ParseTweetBolt and entering our new SplitSentenceBolt.
I've given this a component ID of python-split-sentence,.
And finally the implementation question, we need a shuffle grouping.
And finally we connect this to the tweetSpout.
Once we've made the connection between the tweetSpout to
the python-split-sentence bolt, we need to
complete the connection to the count bolt by changing our field grouping.
First we change the component ID parse-tweet-bolt to python-split-sentence.
And next we update the fields from tweet-word to
the field declared in SplitSentence.
To find this we navigate to SplitSentence and
scroll down to the declareOutputFields.
And see our new field declared is word.
Notice that the splitsentence.java bolt is declaring the output field word and
not our python splitsentence.py file.
Now that we know the field word, we navigate back to our tweet topology and
update the new fields tweet-word to word.
And now we're done with our topology connecting the tweet-spout to
our python-split-sentence bolt,
from our python-split-sentence bolt to the count-bolt.
And using the existing connection from the count-bolt to the report-bolt.
Also in step zero, remember to install the Python Beautiful Soup package,
making sure you have a built success.
Finally in step 10, package and run your topology.
Again, it's Maven package.
And once you have a build success, we submit our project Storm jar
target Udacity with dependencies, Udacity.storm.tweet Topology.
And as we see our tweet stream in the background we see that the visualization
begins to update.
This is using the word splitter bolt in Python.
And finally, remember that your code will now match Lesson 3, Stage 2.
Now that we've covered the basics of using Python in Storm,
lets move on to something a bit more interesting.