When we created the main
restaurant's page,
we executed a query to get all of
the restaurants in the database.
I will use the ID number
of each restaurant entry
in order to find a specific
restaurant to update.
Let's go ahead and replace that hash tag
with the ID number and then a slash and
the word edit to indicate a new path
where we will edit our menu entries.
I will now create another if statement
that looks for slash edit in the URL.
Since i chose to edit
restaurants by their ID,
I need to find a way to grab
that ID number out of the URL.
The split command in Python
comes in handy here and
returns an array of strings
separated by a slash.
I figured out the third value of
this array contains my ID number.
So with this two here,
I'm grabbing the third element
of this zero indexed array.
I then do a restaurant query
to grab the restaurant entry
equal to the ID in the URL.
If I find that query then I generate
a response and begin to render the page.
I create a form with one field for
the new restaurant name.
Let's create a POST method and
pass in the path for
the /restaurants/id/edit, passing in
the id of the restaurant I want to edit.
I also prefilled this field with
the current name of the restaurant.
I close all my tags, and
add this output string to the wfile.
Now let's write up the post response for
our edit form.
Some of this code might be
starting to look pretty familiar.
After making another if statement,
we grab the input from our form again.
Then we perform the query to find
the object with the matching ID.
We reset the name field to
the entry we created in the form,
then add to the session and commit.
I then added a redirect to bring
us back to our restaurants page
after the code has been executed.
This was a lot of code to write,
so let's save and
rerun our server again
to see if it worked.
If I renamed Panda Garden to
The New Panda Garden look,
it's been updated in the database and
on our restaurant's page.
The source code for objective four is
also available in the instructor notes.