The solution to the system is x equals
one y equals negative three and
z equals two.
I'll run through the steps of Gaussian
elimination on the system, so
you can see how I solved it.
First, I want to clear the x terms in
the equations below the top equation.
To do this, I add one times the first
equation to the second equation.
The second equation now reads negative
three y plus five z equals nineteen.
And then I add seven times the first
equation to the third equation,
which becomes two y minus four
z equals negative fourteen,
having cleared the x terms in
the second and third equations.
I now want to clear the y
term in third question,
since this will put the system
in triangular form.
To do this, I add two-thirds times the
second equation to the third equation,
which becomes negative two-thirds
z equals negative four-thirds.
Now that the system is in triangular
form, I will work backwards to solve for
the variables.
First, I multiply the third
equation by negative three halves.
This gives me that z equals two.
Next, I subtract five times the third
equation from the second equation.
Which gives me negative
three y equals nine.
And then I subtract the third equation
from the first equation to get
negative x plus y equals negative
four in the first equation.
Now to solve for y, I multiply
the second equation through by negative
one-third, and
that shows me that y is negative three.
Next, I subtract the second
equation from the first,
giving me negative x
equals negative one, and
I multiply the first equation through by
negative one, which yields x equals one.
This completes the procedure, and
gives me the unique intersection point,
one, negative three, two.