The dimensionality reduction looks a little bit silly when you go
from 2 dimensions to 1 dimension.
But in truly high-dimensional space it has a very strong utility.
Here's an example that goes back to MIT several decades ago
on something called eigenfaces.
These are all well-aligned faces.
The objective in eigenface research has been to find
simple ways to describe different people in a parameter space,
in which we can easily identify the same person again.
Images like these are very high-dimensional statistics.
If each image is 50 by 50 pixels,
each image itself becomes a data point in a 2500 dimensional feature space.
Now obviously, we don't have random images.
We don't fill the space of 2500 dimensions with all face images.
Instead, it is reasonable to assume that all the faces live on a small subspace in that space.
Obviously, you as a human can easily distinguish what is a valid image of a face
and what is a valid image of a non face, like a car or a cloud or the sky.
Therefore, there are many, many images that you can
represent with 2500 pixels that are not faces.
So research on eigenfaces has applied
principle component analysis and eigenvalues to the space of faces.
Here is a database in which faces are aligned.
A researcher at Santiago Serrano extracted from it
the average face after alignment on the right side.
The truly interesting phenomenon occurs when you look at the eigenvalues.
The face on the top left, over here, is the average face,
and these are the variations,
the eigenvectors that correspond to the largest eigenvalues over here.
This is the strongest variation.
You see a certain amount of different regions in and around the head shape
and the hair that gets excited.
That's the 2nd strongest one, where the shirt gets more excited.
As you go down,
you find more and more interesting variations that can be used to reconstruct faces.
Typically a dozen or so will suffice to make a face completely reconstructable,
which means you've just mapped a 2500 dimensional feature space
into a, perhaps, 12 dimensional feature space
on which we can now learn much, much easier.