For step 8, you're going to
implement the resolveSignInError( ).
Now we've seen this function
a couple of times already.
We put it behind
the Signing In button and
we also put it on
the On Connection Failed.
But what should this function do?
It's a pretty complex function.
So give it a try anyway.
If you get stuck,
the source code is available for you.
But ultimately, what we want it to do is
say, if we don't already have a sign in
intent, then we want to
start an intent server for
our mSignInIntent that
we created earlier.
This start intent server will use
a request code of RC_SIGN_IN.
Now, if you remember earlier on when we
tried to sign in, we had to do things
like selecting the count or
accepting the permission screen.
That's what this intent will do for you.
Try and implement this function and
check this box when you're done.