So that concludes this lesson, and
we've looked up a lot of
pretty complicated code.
And been able to digest it and
understand what's going on.
&gt;&gt; And trust us, a lot of the problems
you're going to face in programming for
VR are problems you
can't solve on your own.
Being able to go out on the web, find
some code that you've never seen before,
and put them as yours so
your solution is critical.
So, you've a bit of
experience doing that now and
I hope it makes it a lot
easier in the future.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so, definitely feel
free to look at Google or
the Unity documentation for example
code that you can use in your project.
And good job going through this lesson.