This was a pretty tricky group
of features to pull off,
it actually had three parts.
The first was to make sure that you
were correctly writing item objects to
the Firebase database.
The second was to then get those objects
and make them display in the app.
And finally, you had to make
sure to fix your cleanup so
that when you removed a list,
it also removed the list of items.
All right, let's start with the first
step, which is just making sure that we
add items to the right
place in the back end.
So I'm going to go to
the AddListItemDialogueFragment class.
Okay, I'm going to scroll down until
I'm here in the do list edit method.
Now this method is basically
going to do two things.
It's first going to construct
an item object POJO
with the input that the user gave.
And, then it's going to send that
POJO over to the correct location in
the Firebase database.
Here's where you make the POJO,
it's pretty straightforward.
Right now, I'm just passing
in this mItemName variable.
That's equal to the value that you could
get from the edit text in the dialogue.
Saving it to the correct place is
a little bit more complicated.
I get the reference for
where items should be saved
in the shopping list, here.
Let's see what this URL here is.
So this is a combination of the base
FIREBASE_URL and the FIREBASE_LOCATION
for SHOPPING_LIST_ITEMS,
which is the string shoppingListItems.
Okay, so we have that base URL and
then we go to the child
that's equal to the ListId.
You have to make sure that you're
setting mListId correctly,
it should be the push ID of the shopping
list that you're adding this item to.
Okay so
now that we have this itemsReference,
where do we want to actually want to
store this particular item, and
what methods are we
going to use to store it?
You still need a unique ID.
Remember when we were
mapping this all out and
we didn't quite know what ID we
were going to use for the items?
Well there's no reason
not to use a push ID.
Again, it's a unique ID, so it's handy
for the same reason that using it for
the shopping list was handy.
Basically, it makes sure that each of
your shopping list items are definitely
unique, separate items.
Okay, so I do that here,
I take my items ref and
I get a push ID which makes a new
Firebase ref for me with that push ID.
And I go ahead and
I save that push ID here in the item ID.
Now hopefully you remembered that you
have to update the time stamp last
changed whenever anything about
the shopping list updates.
So that I could bundle the whole
update together in one fell swoop,
I decided to use update
children instead of set value.
This allows me to update something
in the shopping list object
as well as to create a new item
elsewhere in the database.
You can't use POJOs
with update children so
I used an object mapper class to get
a hash map version of my object.
And then I put both
the updated time stamp and
the new item into a hash map and
push that all with update children.
Okay, so let's see what that does.
Okay, so I'm going to go into
movies snacks and add some popcorn.
Okay, and we can see here that it
actually made a shoppingListItems node.
And here's the push ID of the shopping
list that I was adding to,
you see that these two match.
And here's the push ID for the item,
so it's the shopping list push ID,
the item push ID and
then here's the actual item itself.
Okay, so it looks like we're adding
items to the back end just fine,
so that's great.
To get the items to appear here, as you
can see in this sort of finished version
of this step, you also need to
add a Firebase list adapter.
You might have noticed that
there's a ActiveListItemAdapter
meant specifically for this purpose.
Within this class you should
overwrite the populate view method.
The code down here is for
the little delete icon that you see.
Right now it just calls this method
remove item which doesn't do
anything yet.
Okay, so that's the populate view method
inside the actual adapter, but then in
the active list details activity class,
you actually need to set up the adapter.
So I'm going to scroll down and
here's where I set up the adapter.
It's pretty straightforward and it
matches how you set up the adapter for
the shopping lists.
Okay, so
at this point you've done two things.
You've both successfully written
data to the Firebase database and
you're also reading out those
items into this list adapter here.
But there's one more thing that you
needed to do in this code step and
that was to update removing
the shopping list.
So I'm going to go to the remove list
dialogue fragment, scrolling down.
Here's where I remove the list.
Now I could've used remove value
twice instead of update children, but
this would make two calls to the server.
Using remove value is the same as
using set value at the same location,
and passing null.
Similarly you can pass null to
update children to remove a value.
So I'll use update children, and
pass null to these two locations here,
the location of the actual list and
the location of all the list's items.
The mListId is all I need to specify
which shopping list I'm talking about.
And because I used update children,
I don't have to make two
different calls to the server.
Whew, well, that was a bit tricky.
It's also an accumulation of everything
you've learned in this version of
the app, so really great work for
sticking it out.