Now that we have the data ready,
sometimes it's useful and
interesting to visualize the raw data.
Tableau makes this easy to do.
Just select the data
prep file you just saved.
You will see under the measures
there is a latitude and longitude.
To place them in the workbook,
just double-click both of them.
Then, go to Analysis and
turn off Aggregate Measures.
The store locations should
now appear on the map.
If you want to see how the data lines
up visually with what we'd expect,
you can select something like Snow Feb
and drag it to the size marks.
We can see that as expected,
there's a lot more snow in the Northeast
US in February than anywhere else.
Feel free to explore more by taking
off one of the variables and
adding another back in.