This leads me to the concept
of Photo Tourism or
sometimes also referred to as
photosynthesis or Photo Synth.
Now this a widely used method
in computer vision, and
computational photography,
started off by Noah Snavely,
Seitz, Szeliski and they referred to it
as Photo Tourism and their goal was to
explore photo collections in
3D in reference to each other.
I will be showing you more
details of this in a bit.
This was a paper that
was published in 2006.
It's a very interesting idea, and
I'm going to tell you
more about it in a bit.
Of course, this was taken
into a complete technology
preview that's available online for
you to even play around with
called Photo Synth developed by
Microsoft following this work.
So, during this lecture, I'm going to
tell you more about both these two
different technologies, again something
the foundational work in 2006,
which has been evolved into
a available package online since 2008,
and of course,
has just been recently updated.
But of course, there are other similar
solutions also available, that I'm going
to introduce you to, and my assumption,
and hope is that you are actually going
to play around with them, because they
are going to tell you more about what we
can do with a collection of photographs
and how to use them to showcase space?