Another important design point in
distributed shared memory systems
is to understand what are the types
of access algorithms that
need to be supported on
top of that DSM solution?
In other words, to understand what are
the kinds of applications that will be
running on top of the DSM layer.
The simplest example is
single reader/single writer.
For these kinds of applications,
the main role of the DSM layer
is to provide additional memory,
to provide the application with
the ability to access remote memory.
In this case,
there really aren't any consistency or
sharing related challenges that need
to be supported at the DSM layer.
The more complex examples are of
an application support either multiple
readers and single writer, or both
multiple readers and multiple writers.
In those cases,
it's not just about how to read or
write to the correct physical memory
location in the distributed system, but
it's also about how to make sure that
the reads return the correctly written,
the most recently written value of
a particular memory location, and
also that all of the writes that
are performed are correctly ordered.
This is necessary so as to present the
consistent view of the distributed state
of the distributed shared memory
to all of the nodes in the system.
Multiple reader,
single writer, is a special,
simpler case of the multiple reader,
multiple writer problem.
And so, in our discussion in this
lesson, we will focus on DSM support for
multiple readers, multiple writers.