Moving from top to bottom, what CSS
property is used to italicize text?
For this one,
I'll bring up Mozilla CSS reference and
see what they have on italicizing text.
If I search for the word italicize,
the first result font-style reads
italic specifies that font face is an
italicized version of the normal font.
That certainly sounds like
what I'm looking for.
If I follow the link, scroll down.
I can see that font-style's in fact, the
property I should use to italicize text.
So the answer for
the first one is font-style.
The next question asks, what CSS
property is used to underline text?
This time,
I'll search CSS-Tricks CSS almanac.
If I go to their page and search
text underline, I get a result for
the property text-decoration.
And if I click the link,
the top of the page reads,
the text-decoration property adds
an underline, overline, line through, or
a combination of lines
to the selected text.
That's what I want.
And check this out.
Further down the page, CSS-Tricks even
has a demo of the property in action.
That's awesome.
So text-decoration is the answer for
number 2.
For number 3, what CSS property's
used to uppercase text?
Let's try a good old Google search and
see what we can find.
I'll simply type what CSS property
is used to uppercase text.
And look at that, our first result
reads the text-transform property
is used to specify uppercase and
lowercase letters in text.
Sure enough,
that's the answer for number 3.
Finally, what CSS property
is used to bold text?
Since you've seen some examples for
how to use CSS references,
I'll just write this one in.
To bold text,
use the font-weight property.
Remember, CSS references are great tools
and you should reference them often.
If you ever get stuck
during development,
you can always refer back to them