We know that 3-DOF tracking allows VR
hardware to sense your head rotation.
But how does that happen?
It's pretty incredible how quickly and
accurately VR headsets detect rotation.
How do they do it?
Well the answer is these headsets are
using a really cool electronic device
called an IMU.
Or Inertial Measurement Unit.
An Inertial Measurement Unit is
a tiny sensor that is really good at
quickly and
accurately detecting rotations.
It does this by combining the data
from an on board accelerometer,
magnetometer, and gyroscope.
Basically, it's using gravity and
the Earth's magnetic field to constantly
infer which way it's pointed, and using
some fancy math an IMU is able to do
a surprisingly good job at detecting
the direction it's facing.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So that's how 3-DOF works.
Sometimes an IMU is embedded
inside your VR headset.
And sometimes the IMU inside
your phone is used instead, but
no matter what, all modern 3-DOF
tracking uses some kind of IMU.
Pretty neat right?