(Peter) Welcome to office hours. You guys are doing a great job.
And some really interesting questions this week, so let's get right to them.
First one's from Jonathan in New York. He says, "Some websites represent a Captcha to type text that us blurred
"or otherwise obscured, to let you in and make sure you're not a computer robot. Could you comment on this as an A.I. challenge?"
So I think you're right, Jonathan, that that is a real A.I. challenge, and in fact,
(Chander) Malik, one of my old colleagues at Berkeley who wrote some of the computer vision chapter in the textbook,
did this with his student, Greg Mori. So it's a great challenge.
They were able to do pretty well. They somewhere between 30 and 90% accuracy, depending on exactly what test you want to give them.
And of course, even 30% is enough to foil these tests, because they allow you to try two or three or four times.
So you could always get it right. But it does provide a lot of insight into what's difficult and kind of pushes things forward,
and there's a never-ending battle to try to improve.
(Sebastian) Yeah, and some of these Captchas are easily solved, really easy to decode, and some are really hard.
My friend, Louis Menand, who runs a company in this space, used words from the New York Times archives as Captcha words,
and specifically those that OCR--optical character recognition--failed to decode.
And as a result, he not only solves the Captcha problem, with really hard examples that are really hard to solve,
but also transcribes the old annals of the New York Times, which is really cool.
So if you can solve this, let us know. Don't tell anybody else. I'd love to see a solution for the general Captcha problem,
it would be quite amazing.
The next question: "What do you think of OpenCV or other existing libraries as frameworks for doing (practical) computer vision?"
By J&amp;M from Romania. I think it's a great idea. My good friend, Gary Bradski, of course, wrote OpenCV
with the intent that everybody can use it. It's been a very powerful library. It's very fast, very efficient.
Reasonably easy to program. There's multiple generations of interfaces, but once you get beyond, this is actually really useful,
and it's really state of the art computer vision algorithms. I highly recommend using it in computer vision.
It's an exercise in learning value to code stuff yourself, but when you do something practical, use it.
There's other libraries as well. My favorite is actually MATLAB.
Even though it's not meant for practical use in a highly efficient work environment, it's really amazing for rapid prototyping
and the algorithms are really really well-coded.
(Peter) "So in the lecture for stereo cameras, you discussed two cameras displaced in the horizontal plane.
"Why not three cameras?" This comes from Johnny Boates in Philips, Maine. So is three better than two?
(Sebastian) Why don't we have three eyes? You have two eyes, I have two eyes. Seems to me something magic about two eyes.
The answer is it's actually useful to have three cameras. It turns out three cameras fail in horizontal lines.
Now, nature isn't full of that many horizontal lines that really matter. Vertical lines are much more prevalent, like trees and so on.
You can run into them. But that's probably the reason why nature didn't give us three eyes.
In reality, there's a field called triocular vision, where people use three or more cameras,
and they're arranged usually in an L shape, so they can see depth, and this continues in different directions,
and they tend to be superior, but they take more processing power, so they're not very frequently used.
(Peter) Yeah, and I should say in audio processing it is common to use a large array of microphones,
and then you can zero in on exactly where a sound source is coming from, and from a crowded room you can pick out
the one person that's talking and eliminate all the crowd noise.
(Sebastian) And honestly, this is still a research problem. If you're able to make a microphone array that can localize
a person and cut that out in a crowded room, then let me know, it's going to be really amazing, and it's going to be really useful.
(Peter) So next question is from Nagwater in Los Angeles.
"We learned about depth from sets of images, but what about using a single image?"
(Sebastian) That's a wonderful question. It's a way under-researched field even though it's relatively old.
Actually, single images have depth cues, like perspective, for example, (unintelligible) gets smaller at distance.
Known objects, like you know how big people are, that really helps you understand how far things are away.
And we all know that people can do this. We can look at a photograph and we can recover depth quite well.
This is a beautiful field. Only two recent projects that I know of that deal with this, one at Carnegie Mellon, one at Stanford.
But there's much more opportunity. So if you want to apply interesting A.I. technology, this is a great field to be in.
A second though is even in human vision, we use stereo at near range because that's where the displacement works really well,
but if you look really far away, like 12 feet or four meters, for my international friends, there's no stereo vision left.
So we do all the depth recovery at a range, from motion cues, from parallax, move our head around.
And of course, single images, we understand how big things are in the world.
(Peter) "Running dynamic programming to find the optimal alignment is highly dependent on the cost of occlusion.
"And bad correspondence pixels. How can we estimate the penalties for occlusion and bad correspondence?"
(Sebastian) Well, that's a machine learning question, and it's a beautiful question because it's a really easy answer,
but it's surprising, the simplicity of the answer: Which is, go and take images where you manually label the correct correspondence
as good as you can. And then write a computer program that has costs assumed for occlusion and costs of the type we talked about here.
And run it and see how well it does, and score how well it does. So every time it gets it right, add plus one,
and if it gets it wrong, add minus one. And now I have a computer I would search in the space of these parameters,
like your correspondence costs and so on, and propose new parameters, run the software again, and see if the score goes up or down.
If it goes up, you've done a good twiddle of your parameter, and if it goes down, you've done a bad twiddle.
This algorithm works like a charm, and all my students, I can tell you, are using it.
We call it Twiddle in my lab. It tweaks individual parameters, one after another, and just looks at the outcome,
how well the score (unintelligible) data, and if the score goes up, it keeps tweaking those.
In fact, that's what humans also do when they tune their software, but you can automate this with a couple of label examples.
Wonderful machine learning opportunity.
(Peter) And we call it cross-validation rather than twiddling or tweaking to make it sound more official, but--
(Sebastian) Yeah, you can have a theory on it and come up with theoretical bounds if you wish,
or just implement it and run it.
Okay. "So past content, would it be possible to provide us with a particle filter algorithm," in the ten lines of C code that I mentioned?
By (Dee Dee) in New Jersey. And the answer is I was probably slightly inaccurate when I said ten lines,
unless you have very long lines of C code. And the reason is the essence of the particle filter is ten lines long,
which is the ten lines I gave you. But when you plug in things like the measurement model, those can be very complicated.
They can be as complicated as computer vision is. Or if you have laser range finders in our robots, they are non-trivial.
And can buy my book and find them described there, if you can spare the money to buy my book, Probability Robotics.
In the robotics class, I will go through examples of using particle filters for localization.
And there we work step by step through a particle filter with a very simple sensor model, and a simple motion model,
but it can see each little step again. I hope that will help you understand the particle filter algorithm.