I'm in main.js, and
I want to find setInterval.
So I'll do it the easy
way by using Cmd+F.
It looks like setInterval is repeating
on a four millisecond timer,
which is actually a little ridiculous.
In fact, I noticed that as I was
filming, Chrome crashed once or
twice, and I think this
actually might be the culprit.
But I'm actually just guessing there.
I'm not sure.
Either way, I will go ahead and
remove that and
replace setInterval with
requestAnimationFrame.
Okay, now, that's simple enough but
remember, the function itself also
needs to call requestAnimationFrame.
Here's the function captureFrame
which is running the animation.
And inside, I will make another call
to requestAnimationFrame to the same
function.
I'll save it, and
let's see what it looks like.
Inside the app's directory,
I'll run gulp serve.
It looks like this site has finished
building, so I'll click Allow.
All right, and
it looks like it's working.
Let me take a look at the timeline.
It looks like that, yes,
in fact, animation frame fired
is being called over and over.
So it looks like the job here is done.
All right, well,
now it's on to the Web Worker.