Now it's time for you to practice
decomposing a game on your own.
As your subject, you'll take one
of the first games ever, Pong.
If you haven't played it,
go play it now.
There's a link down in the instructor
notes where you can find a version you
can play online for free.
Once you've played it,
it's a pretty simple game, right?
Well, do the following.
First, write out a couple paragraphs
describing as precisely as you can
how the game of Pong proceeds.
Then go through your paragraph and
underline all the nouns you can find.
From that list of nouns,
come up with a list of classes that you
think you'd need in order to represent
the state of the game of Pong.
Then go through your paragraph again,
underlining all the verbs this time.
And from those verbs,
come up with a list of methods that your
classes would need to have in
order to actually play the game.
When you're done, write in this box
the number of classes you came up with.
And then write down the number of
total methods on those classes.
Now because this is such a subjective
exercise and I have no idea
what description you wrote down,
this isn't actually going to be graded.
I'm just curious what you come up with.