So we've asked a lot of you in this course.
We asked you to think about who the end user is
and their use cases. We asked you to take into consideration
the mobile user and their constraints and now we're asking you
to build context aware applications. You might be thinking that sounds
really difficult. I would really love to make an application that
senses whether my user is asleep or awake, but how would
I even go about doing that? Are there APIs for that?
>> Well, yes there is, and those APIs
are called Google Play services. They're an awesome
set of APIs that you can use today to make your applications context aware by,
for example, sensing of the users walking,
sleeping, running, and so on. Remember that Chromecast
example from Netflix? You can even cast
two Chromecast using this API. So there's a
whole host of things you can do that
can make your applications really awesome on Android.
>> So, let's bring it back to Dorm Room Debbie. Go to
Google Play Services documentation and research it. Explore around a little bit.
See if you can find a really awesome API, that you could use to plus 1, Dorm
Room Debbie's Pizza application. Come up with a
really great idea, and post it to the Forum.