So far we have seen that the variables f1 and f2 are linearly correlated.
In this case, we decided to use f0 and
f1 as the variables of interest for building our model.
Now we want to form a general model that involves f0 and f1.
What are our choices?
We could build a parametric model we could build a non-parametric model which
would both be statistical models or we could build some mathematical model.
We could also try to build some.
Machine learning models we using clustering and so on.
In our case, we'll choose the simple non-parametric model.
We will use the method of kernal density estimates to
build a non-parametric model.
We choose this because in a lot of statistics classes,
you would have probably seen parametric.
Models already.
Since we are going to introduce kernel density estimates here we are going to
stick to single variable approach.
To do so we are going to use a derived feature.
The derived feature we will use will be defined as x,
which is the absolute value of the difference between f naught and f1.
Divided by the value of f naught.
This feature by itself is scaled to the values of f naught.
Thus we expect the range of the variable x to be between zero and one.