I want to use a few words of terminology.
This, again, is a Bayes network, of which the hidden variable C
causes the still stochastic test outcomes T1 and T2.
And what is really important is that we assume not just
that T1 and T2 are identically distributed.
We use the same 0.9 for test 1 as we use for test 2,
but we also assume that they are conditionally independent.
We assumed that if God told us whether we actually had cancer or not,
if we knew with absolute certainty the value of the variable C,
that knowing anything about T1 would not help us make a statement about T2.
Put differently, we assumed that the probability of T2 given C and T1
is the same as the probability of T2 given C.
This is called conditional independence, which is given the value of the cancer variable C.
If you knew this for a fact, then T2 would be independent of T1.
It's conditionally independent because the independence only holds true
if we actually know C, and it comes out of this diagram over here.
If we look at this diagram, if you knew the variable C over here,
then C separately causes T1 and T2.
So, as a result, if you know C, whatever counted over here
is kind of cut off causally from what happens over here.
That causes these 2 variables to be conditionally independent.
So, conditional independence is a really big thing in Bayes networks.
Here's a Bayes network where A causes B and C,
and for a Bayes network of this structure, we know that given A,
B and C are independent.
It's written as B conditionally independent of C given A.
So, here's a question.
Suppose we have conditional independence between B and C given A.
Would that imply--and there's my question--that B and C are independent?
So, suppose we don't know A.
We don't know whether we have cancer, for example.
What that means is that the test results individually are still independent of each other
even if we don't know about the cancer situation.
Please answer yes or no.