So let's look at the two
options we have here.
First one says, file permissions
can change after an open call.
Remember checking was done
when an open was formed.
This call was made, this call complete,
that's when we down to the IO table or
the file meta-data table,
setup the open file table entry, return
an index, all the checking got done.
Well at that time, this user lets
Alice was able to read the file.
Later on, Bob who owns the file comes
and turns read permission off for Alice.
But Alice's process is still running.
And Alice's process to actually read
the open before Bob was able to
revoke this permission.
And Alice's process hasn't
closed the file yet.
Will Alice be able to
continue to read this file?
Yes, because we're not
performing any more checks.
The checks were done at the time
when we opened the file, okay?
So it was separated from the use.
So the check was during an open( ) call,
okay?
So sequence here is Alice did open,
sometime after that Bob comes and
removes the permission, and
sometime after that Alice is
trying to read this file.
Alice is doing read not open now,
so there's no check happening.
So if file permissions change after
an open ( ) call, it completes, but
before it's closed, Alice has the file
open, hasn't closed it, because if she
closes it, and then it has to be
opened again, we'll check again.
And when we check again, Bob's
change might be seen by the system.
So if permissions change
between the time we check and
the time we use, well,
that actually is the reason for
this vulnerability talked to
vulnerability that we're talking about.
And the second option is saying,
the file permissions only change when
the file is currently not opened by any
program, then this
vulnerability will not arise.