The matrix view gives you an easy
to think about distributing a BFS.
Suppose you have P = 3 processes.
You can do a 1-D partitioning of
the matrix by, let's say, columns.
That is, group these three
columns together on one process,
these three columns on the next, and
these three columns on the last.
This column partitioning corresponds
to a partitioning of the vertices.
So, what does this partitioning suggest?
Well, it assigns vertices 0, 1,
and 2 to one process, 3, 4, and
5 to the next, and 6,
7, and 8 to the last.
Note that the column partitioning
also implies a partitioning of u.
That's u the vector, not you the viewer.
What about the frontier vector?
This partitioning suggests that you'll
need to replicate the frontier vector on
each process so that the process
can do its local update.
Schematically that looks
something like this.
Now what happens if you replicate?
Well, when you create the next frontier
by analyzing the local updates,
you're going to need to
re-replicate the frontier vertices.
Put another way, here's what happens
when you create the next frontier.
You use the local update vector
to update the local frontier.
You then need to do an all-to-all
to exchange the local frontiers.
Okay, that was a bunch of steps.
So let's summarize
the distributed 1-D algorithm.
First, divide the columns of A and
the entries of u.
Then, do a matrix-vector product
to determine which vertices
may need distance updates.
Then, update the local distances.
Then, determine which of the local
vertices need to be a part of
the next frontier.
Finally, do an all-to-all exchange so
that everybody knows what
the full frontier looks like.
Notice that the all-to-all exchange
is the only communication step.
So, what does that cost?
Unfortunately, it's actually hard to
write down an exact communication cost
because it depends on
the structure of the graph.
Despite that, we can say
something concrete about its form.
Because of the all-to-all,
you should expect some term that is
linear in the number of processes, P.
There's a paper linked to
in the instructor's notes.
It has more analysis.
And I'd encourage you to download it and
take a look.