In the analysis of the algorithm for
polynomial identity verification,
I avoided the word probability because
we haven't defined what it means yet.
We'll do that now and
use the algorithm to illustrate
the meaning of the abstract
mathematical terms.
A discrete probability space consists of
a sample space omega, that is finite,
or accountability infinite.
This represents the set
of possible outcomes for
whatever random process we are modeling.
In the case of the previous algorithm,
this is the value x that is chosen.
A discreet probability space
also has a probability function
with these three properties.
It must be from the set of subsets
of the sample space to the reals.
Typically, we call a subset of
the sample space an event, say E.
For every event, the probability
must be at least 0 and at most 1.
The probability of the whole
sample space must be 1, and for
any pairwise disjoint collection
of events, the probability
of the union of the events must
be the sum of the probabilities.
To illustrate this idea
with a polyequal example,
let's define the event Fi to be the set
consisting of the single element i.
This corresponds to i being
chosen as the value at which we
test the polynomials.
And we define the probability
of Fi as one over omega,
the size of our sample space or
one over 100d.
Now these Fi aren't
the only possible events.
They're just the single element
subsets of the sample space.
We need to define our
function over all subsets.
But actually we've done some implicitly
already because of this property here.
For any subset s of the sample space,
we have that this subset is
the union of some Fi, the individual
elements of the sample space.
These are all disjoined, so
the probability of the union is the sum
of these individual probabilities.
And so the result is that the overall
probability is the size of the set,
s, divided by the size of the sample
space, as we would expect.
Let's now confirm that this function
meets all of the criteria for
the definition.
This third property holds because
the size of a disjoint union
is the sum of the sizes
of the individual set.
Clearly the probability of the whole
sample space is one, as we see from this
ratio here and the probability of
any event is between zero and one.
So this example here is in fact
a discrete probability space.
By the way, this probability
function is called uniform,
because the probability of
every single element event,
that is to say the Fi here,
they're all the same.
Not all probability
functions are like that.