We can visualize the balance
of risk versus return
in a scatter plot that looks like this.
So along our horizontal axis here,
we plot risk,
vertical axis is return and
we'll calculate those values for
each of the stocks or
other assets that we're considering.
And we can plot them using
a scatter plot on this chart, and
we can compare them directly.
So, we compute the standard deviation
of daily returns for each stock, and
that gives us where it
falls on this risk line.
And the average daily return,
tells us where it is on the return line.
So for instance,
if we have These two stocks.
This one up here let's
say this is our XYZ
is riskier but
also has provided a greater return.
And this one over here might be our ABC
and it's less risky but lower return.
And typically we have multiple stocks
that are part of our portfolio
that we're considering.
It's usually the case that if we make
one of these plots for a lot of stocks,
we'll see that they form a sort
of trend going up into the right.
Meaning that the higher return
stocks are higher risk, and
the lower risk stocks are the ones
that are lower return.
Now a portfolio is a weighted
blend of these different assets.
So essentially we have a weight for
each of these assets that
are part of our portfolio.
And you would expect that the risk and
return for portfolio is
going to be some approximate
average of these different assets.
But if you're careful about things and
you use a portfolio optimizer which
we're going to talk more about, you're
actually able to create a portfolio
that has a lower risk than any of
the individual equities by themself.
And sometimes it can be
at the very high end
of the returns of all the assets
that make up the portfolio, okay?
Let's now take a look at how we can
create a visualization
like this in code.