All right, now it's your turn.
Implement AppBar scrolling into
the forecast fragment layout
when in phone portrait mode.
First, we're going to add the design
support library into app dependencies.
And then we do all the rest of
the work inside of fragment_main.xml.
We begin by converting the base
view to a frame layout.
You might be able to use
Cordinarily out here, but
I ran into life cycle
problems when I tried that.
Wrap the toolbar in RecyclerView
with a Parent Coordinator Layout and
then wrap just a toolbar
with a Parent AppBar layout.
Add the scrolling view
behavior to the RecyclerView.
There is a string defined for
this in the design's support library.
Add the scroll flags to the toolbar.
I chose scroll or with Enter Always
to get the behavior I wanted.
Finally, we anchored the empty
view to the RecyclerView,
taking advantage of the frame layout
type properties of Cordinarily Layout.
I also set Anchor Gravity to fill,
so the empty view fills the space.