What happens if we start looking at the Fourier spectra, for real images?
So here of course, bricks.
In the previous case I showed you simple examples of just stripe patterns,
here of course has some structure like this, this is of course a rooftop,
also has a nice structure, and of course, much more natural scene like grass,
this of course, are human made of samples, this is,
of course, purely natural, this spectrum of this one, if you notice,
does have two dominant directions, one, of course, in this direction,
the other one also because there are repetitions in this axis too, so you
could see a dominant two axis here, shown by of course, these two variations.
What would be your guess for this image here?
If you notice, yes, there is a dominant direction because this way, but
if you were to look carefully, there is repetition going on in this axis too,
and therefore you see, this axis here.
See the domain, the axis are visible here and
this way, and this one's because primarily there is a,
dominant direction repeating this way, in addition to one of course this way.
And you can see that or hopefully clearly in this one.
For this one, there's no dominant direction but
actually some may claim that frequency repeats on equally in all directions if
you were to look at it, and that's showcased very well by,
this frequency transform here, it's distributed equally in all directions.
Of course, so far,
we haven't talked about the magnitude, we'll get to that also.