Now I've gone ahead and
made the changes required for this quiz.
So let's talk through them.
So starting off in our catalog activity,
I'll need to add code to start up
a new activity whenever the user
clicks on an item in the list view.
So I've done that here In the onCreate
method I've added this block of code.
And what this does is it sets up an item
click listener that opens up the editor
activity whenever the user clicks
on a pet in the list view.
So notice the code here to set
up an onItemClickListener.
It is just our typical code to make an
intent and then pass it to the activity.
Now prior to starting the activity
I actually need to make a URI so
that I can add it to the intent
that's sent to the next activity.
So to make our URI,
I'm going to use this line here,
contentUris.withAppendedId.
So what this method does is it forms
the content URI that represents
the specific pet that was clicked on,
specifically appending the id onto it.
So for example, we're passing in
a content URI, which is this one here.
And then depending on which
item the user clicks on,
it appends the id of that specific item.
So once I have this URI,
I can call setData and
pass in the URI that
was created up here.
Now all this should be done before
the activity is started down here.
So once this information is passed
through the intent to the next activity,
then we can go on to
the receiving end of the message.
So the editor activity is what's
receiving our message intent.
Now in the onCreate method
of the editor activity,
I'm going to get the intent here.
Also I'll get the data
from the intent and
remember our data was the URI
that we attached to it.
So now we're kind of
at a fork in the road.
because remember, there are two ways
that this editor activity can be opened.
So the first way is if the pet is
clicked on in the list view, and
the second way is if the user clicks on
the floating action button, or the FAB.
Now if the FAB were to be clicked on,
then we wouldn't actually receive
a URI through the intent.
So that means we need to check whether
there is or is not a URI passed in.
Now this if else block here
helps us take care of that.
So that means if there is no
URI passed in with intent,
then I know we're coming from
the FAB button being pressed.
So I should set my title to Add a Pet.
However, if there is a URI
passed in with intent,
I know I'm coming from clicking
a pet in the Listview.
And that means, I need to
change the title to Edit a Pet.
So if we expand on
this by clicking on it,
notice that the title
should be a string.
And the string here is a new one that
I've added into my string resource file.
So let's see where that's set up.
I'm going to right click,
head to Go To, and go to Declaration.
So my strings XML file, I added this
new line, which is the title for
the activity to edit an existing pet.
And lastly,
in order to accommodate this,
remember that in our Android manifest
file, we setup the activity.
For our editor activity we've
given it a label for new_pet.
But because it can be a variable name
now, either edit pet or add a pet.
I'm going to go ahead and delete this.
And this way the title of
the editor activity is dependent on
what URI is passed in.
So whether a URI was passed in or not.
So now let's check whether this worked.
I'm going to go ahead and
run it on my emulator.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So first let's click on the FAB.
So this opens up the activity.
And the editor says Add a Pet,
which looks good.
Now let's head back.
And now let's insert our dummy pet.
So from here, let's try editing
this pet and see what the title is.
So clicking on a pet from the list view,
I pull up the editor activity, but
now the title of it is Edit Pet instead.
So it looks like it all works.