In terms of the first benefit in proving reusability. Well,
cohesion does that by making each of the modules that you have,
have a single purpose which you can then identify and reuse that module if you
have that particular need. The second benefit is enabling maximum variability,
and that's what orthogonality is intended to support. A third one,
in terms of raising the level of abstraction,
is what information hiding does by preventing access to details and
implementations and finally, the fourth factor is requiring more code reading
and that one is coupling if you have highly coupled systems and
then you change one of them you may have recode in many other modules