In this scenario, you're working
on an app called Health Check, and
what HealthCheck is is basically
an app that administers a quiz, and
that quiz can tell the person who's
using it how healthily they're living.
The questions appear in this box here,
and the user can answer either Yes,
Sometimes, or No, and let's say there's
about 100 different questions, and
they range from things like, do you
exercise more than three times a week?
Do you drink less than two
caffeinated drinks a day?
Or, do you have a supportive
social network?
Now, the questions are phrased in such
a way that when you say Yes, that always
means you're more healthy and when you
say No, it means you're less healthy.
Sometimes is sort of
an inconclusive answer.
And what the app is doing is
really keeping track of a score.
When you hit Yes,
it adds 1 to the health level.
When you answer Sometimes,
it remains unchanged, and
when you answer No,
it subtracts 1 from the health level.
Also, once you've selected
one of these options,
it'll show you a summary of
what you just answered and
what your current health level is
before giving you the next question.
We're just going to look at
the interaction between clicking one of
these buttons and showing the summary
of where you're at right here.
Let's look at the code.
Okay, so here's the code, and I've also
provided it in the instructor notes,
if you want to take a look at
the sort of text version of this.
Again, it's not the complete code.
These little ellipses here mean
that there's code before and
after the methods that
you're shown here.
So how does this work?
Well,.when you hit the Yes button,
the yes method is called.
This increases the healthLevel, makes a
message, and then displays that message.
Similarly, when you hit the Sometimes
button, the sometimes method is called.
The only difference here is that
instead of adding 1, you add 0,
which means that the variable
value doesn't really change.
And the format is similar
when you hit the No button.
The no message is called,
1 is subtracted from the healthLevel and
a message is printed.
Okay, we have two variables in this
program, healthLevel and message.
Let's look at message first.
So my first question to you is,
from the code that you see here,
is message a local or global variable?