The first one is very easy.
Octave and
Matlab make it really trivial to specify
indices repeating at a given step.
In this case, we would like to start
with row 1, step 2, and til the end.
Exactly the same for columns.
This selects rows and
columns 1, 3, 5 and so on.
Okay, now for blurring.
Remember how we used imfilter?
Pass in an image and a filter, defined
here using the fspecial function.
As mentioned,
we want a Gaussian of size 5 by 5.
All right, so
this is our filtered image.
We simply used the same
indexing as before.
Make sense?
Let's see what it looks like.
All right,
here's the result of only down-sampling.
And this is with blurring and
down-sampling.
This appears to be a more natural
blurred version of the original image,
whereas the former has
ugly aliasing effects.
Note that the result is being affected
by how the resize function works.
You can control how it functions,
using a third parameter.
Here, passing in nearest
means no interpolation.
As you can see, this is a much more
accurate representation of what
the pixels in the one eighth
size image look like.
By the way,
this is the downsampled image.
Compare this with the blurred and
downsampled version.
It still wins.
You can also use linear or
bicubic which is the default.
Try these out,
we will be using downsampling
to build Gaussian pyramids next.