Another consideration is what's going to happen next.
If you're building a system and you've done a good job and
that system is successful, you're customers are going to want more.
Fact of life.
They're going to want enhancements and
you can't really anticipate very well in advance what those enhancements are.
Okay?
If you could, then you could build your system in the first place so
that it already had the enhancements in there, okay?
So as another little quiz here see if you can list three
ways in which this particular quick indexing tools might be improved.
Three, three kinds of enhancements that you can imagine the customers wanting.