So had like an architecture question.
I struggled a bit.
I still don't think I understand the right, the best practice for
if I want to look at a trend over time.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Do I store that in the bolts?
Do I store that in Redis and, and then how do you?
You know where does it?
Where do I persist say, you know, the last 10 minutes of data as
I'm [CROSSTALK] a, a, a histogram of, of Tweets, say.
>> Okay, so if you are doing Window-based computations,
typically the idea is to keep that in a Bolt or whatever it is, right?
So bo, and the bolt is computing the or moving into aggregate online.
What do you call it?
The time [INAUDIBLE] bits of [INAUDIBLE].
>> So all bolts check the clock and
then they decide now I'm going to basically report in my aggregated data.
>> Yes. >> And push it out.
>> Push it out.
So now the venue, before that.
So, the time window that remains [INAUDIBLE] right?
So now once you designed the time window then at the end of
the time window you can emit this or this time window.
This is my percent of analytics.
>> Okay. >> Alright so that gets told into the particle persistence store.
>> I see.
>> That should be stored in the partition so, so that you can go and
look back much longer.
Right? >> Okay.
>> Because then if you are doing a refinement at interval.
Then if you wanted to go back to five days ago, or ten days ago, or
twenty days ago, yes, then you can go back to the para,
para, persistent tour and see those values.
Right? >> Okay.
>> Whatever it is, right?
Another like if it's a moving aggregate, then for
a eh, every change in that time.
For example the last 10 or five minute of [INAUDIBLE] then every one minute
elapses then everyone [INAUDIBLE] moving out the gate.
[INAUDIBLE] right?
>> I see.
>> But, so on the other hand if it is a time window then
every five minutes [INAUDIBLE] persistently and a moving window of one minutes.
Moving window over five minutes.
And every minute you write that.
>> Yes. >> Persistently.
Then you can get the moving aggregate or be [INAUDIBLE] time.
>> Okay. And then, and then, aggregating into a database versus Redis was, was,
I guess Redis is more just instantaneous for
collecting the output of many bolts.
>> Yes.
No, I mean that's all, I mean this is just something [CROSSTALK] that's.
>> It's just an aggregator, basically?
>> Yes. >> Okay.
>> I mean it is,
I mean as long as if you don't worry about the output of that outtakes.
It doesn't have to be persistent, I just need it for
some look up on whatever it is.
And after a certain time then it's, cannot, I don't need it.
Means, then you can do what it is.
But on the other hand if you need that an outtakes early,
then you can store it in a e-Value store