Before moving onto the main program,
you should take some time to set up your
development environment and fill in
any gaps you might have with Python.
We'll be making heavy use of NumPy,
Matplotlib, and Pandas.
Libraries that are staples
of the Python data toolkit.
If you haven't worked with these before,
I suggest taking our Intro
to Data Analysis course.
Anaconda is a popular package and
environment manager built
specifically for data science.
It's the easiest way to install and
manage all the libraries you'll need for
this program.
And finally, a lot of the work here
will be done using Jupyter notebooks.
Notebooks are documents that live in
your browser, and combine text, code and
images all in one place.
These are by far my favorite tools
when working on data projects.
And you should take time to learn
how to use them effectively.