The surprising data point I wanted
to investigate was the student
who had the maximum number of minutes.
First, I needed to find that student.
First, I initialized the student
with the max minutes to be none and
the maximum minutes spent to be zero.
Then I looped over each student and
the number of minutes they spent in
the total minutes by account dictionary.
If the total number of minutes was
greater than the maximum I had found so
far, then I reset both
the maximum number of minutes and
the maximum student to be this
number of minutes and this student.
Then I output the maximum number of
minutes I'd found to make sure it was
the same, and it looks like it worked.
Next, I wanted to print each
engagement record for that student.
So I looped over the engagement records,
and
if the engagement record's account key
was equal to this student's account key,
then I printed the record, and
these are the records I found.
The first thing I noticed is that there
are way more than seven entries here,
which shouldn't be the case since
this is within the paid engagement
only in the first week dictionary.
This should only include
one week's worth of data.
The data points aren't falling
within a one week time span either.
You can see here the first
data is January 7th and
then scrolling to the bottom,
the last date is April 26th.
This makes me suspect that something
might be wrong with my within one
week function.
In this function, I'm checking that the
engagement date came at most seven days
after the join date.
I'm not checking that the engagement
date actually came after the join date.
So for students who enroll once,
then cancel, then enroll again later,
everything from the first enrollment
will count as their first week.
To fix this, I checked that at least
zero days had passed from the join date
to the engagement date.
That way, I'm only considering data from
the most recent enrollment which was
my intention.
Then I reran this cell,
as well as all the cells after it.
Now the maximum time spent in the first
week comes out to about 3,500 minutes,
which is roughly 60 hours.
That's a lot of time to spend
studying in one week but, at least,
it's possible.
Now, even though this number sounds
reasonable, there could still be
a mistake, so it's a good idea to rerun
the same check that I did before.
I'll go ahead and do that.
This time, I'm seeing exactly seven
entries within the first week,
which sounds perfect.