Hi, my name is Fernando.
You may remember me from such courses
as Grand Central Dispatch or Core Data.
Today we will tackle one of the most
feared technologies of the Apple stack,
auto layout.
Auto layout allows you to specify
how your UI should behave
when the size of the screen or
the containing view changes.
However, under this simple description
lays a very complex system.
You've probably already tried
using it and ran away in fear, and
with good reason.
Auto Layout can be intimidating, and its
behaviors seems impossible to predict.
Put all your worries aside.
By the end of this course you
will have tamed this beast, and
will feel confident creating UIs for
any Apple device.