As a Nanodegree student,
you can leverage your career development
projects by completing the resume
review and getting personalized and
detailed feedback.
We offer you three options for resume
review related to your work experience,
entry level, career change,
and prior industry experience.
Entry level job candidates have zero
to three years of work experience, and
are trying to prove that they're
ready for the workforce.
You may or
may not have a college degree.
I had an entry level resume when
I applied my first job at 19.
And I had an entry level resume when
I applied to my first job after
graduating from college years later.
Job candidates who are undergoing
a career change want to showcase their
previous experiences, even if
unrelated to the job they now want.
They also have to show that they're
serious about their new career
direction, and that they have
the relevant skills for the job.
A person who may fit this
profile is a restaurant manager
with five years experience,
who wants to become a web developer.
Another person may be a lawyer
with ten years experience,
who wants to become a data analyst.
Likewise, someone who has worked in IT,
the hardware side of computers,
would be undergoing a career change if
they wanted to be a software engineer.
All three of these people will be
pursuing different roles at different
levels, but their resume order and
structure should be the same.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Those with prior industry experience
also have a different resume format.
For example, a web developer who also
wants to learn mobile app development,
or a statistician who wants to
shift toward machine learning.
It's okay if you don't think you fit
perfectly into one of these categories.
Try out the different guidelines for
each, and see what works for you.
Remember that you are in charge
of your career development.