Take a look at the site at this
URL which you can find a link
to in the instructor notes.
When you scroll up and
down it looks okay but
it actually could be a lot better.
There's quite a bit of
painting happening here.
Paint problems can be way worse than
virtually any other performance
bottleneck you're likely to hit.
So I'm going to pop open dev tools and
see what's going on here.
Once you're in dev tools if you hit
the Esc key you'll get this menu
which includes Rendering.
Rendering has some especially cool
options which are going to be
really useful and you'll be exploring
in this quiz and the next couple.
For this quiz you're going to
be using Show paint rectangles.
If you're ever worried about painting.
This is your go-to move to
check out what's happening.
It'll show you when and
where painting is happening on the page.
You're going to be looking at
this site for the quiz, so
I'm going to show you an example
using my Twitter page.
When I scroll up and down, you can see
that the scroll bar is showing up in
green, and
that means it's being repainted.
This fine video here is
totally in green and
that's because every
frame has to be painted.
Look for the green flashes and
you'll see where painting is happening.
So for this quiz, I want you to go back
to the parallax site, which you can find
in the instructor's notes, and
click on Show Paint Rectangles.
Scroll around a bit, and try to figure
out, where is the painting happening?
Is it the whole page, the top left,
the top right, the bottom left,
the bottom right, or the bottom half?
Pick one of these answers.