All right, so.
Presumably you kind of took a stab
at validating our theory that
words are predictive of labels.
So now I'm going to show you how
I would attack this problem, and
then we can kind of compare notes.
This learning style,
I really, really like.
Because I think that
it's most beneficial for
people to sort of attack a problem in
their head first and really realize what
their kind of go-to set of tools is, and
then see how another person might do it.
I find that to be a really fulfilling
and educational way to go about things
and to really know where you're at,
as far as, how you tackle a problem
like you would in the real world,
when you're not in the classroom.
And then compare that to how
someone else might do it.
So yeah, let's tackle this problem.
So I've got a couple of go-to tools I
always like to use from collections,
import Counter.
So we're going to be counting words.
And I find that the counter
object is just so fast and so
much easier than using dictionaries.
And I'll show you how to use it.
And then numpy for
whenever we do numerical calculations.
So the first thing that we're going
to do is we're going to just count
sort of words that
show up positively and
words that show up
negatively in various views.
So for i range((len(reviews)), I-E-W-S.
Gotta create our counter.
So positive counts equals counter.
This is how the counter objects work.
So you create an empty counter and
it acts a little bit like a dictionary.
And we'll just do total_counts so
it's cached.
You could use the other
ones to create it, okay.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So they act like a dictionary, but
you don't have to actually
create the original keys.
You can just start incrementing them as
if you had every key that you put
in as you're in a position to.
You'll see what I mean here in a second.
So for i in range(len(reviews)).
So for every review and label,
if(labels[i) is a POSITIVE label,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Then we're going to basically count all
the words that are in that review and
add them to our positive counts.
So for word in reviews[i].split,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And positive_counts[word] += 1,
total_counts(word) += 1.
else:
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We'll do the same thing here.
Just we're going to add it to
negative_counts and total_counts.
Okay, let's check that out.
So we run that.
Takes a second to run because
we have 25,000 reviews.
Next thing we're going to do is
just sort of take a look at it.
So the counter gives you this
nice little convenient function.
So I can say positive counts,
most common, and there you go.
So all right,
whenever you count any words at all,
the most frequent ones you get here.
This doesn't really tell me if these are
indicative of things that are positive.
These are just telling me whether
they're frequent words or not.
So what we need to do is something
that's called normalization.
So we're not really interested in
what's the most frequent positive word.
We're interested in the word
that is most frequently
positive versus negative, right?
because if I look at negative counts,
[LAUGH] it's the same words, right?
So we want to kind of come up with some
sort of ratio that is more comparative
between these two lists as opposed to
just these two lists by themselves.
So to speed things up a little bit, I'm
going to show you how I would calculate
this ratio,
which I also put into a counter.
And if we look at positive and
negative ratios, so
words with a positive ratio
looks kind of like this.
So starting to see
a little bit of signal.
These are mostly names, so
what I'm going to guess is that
these are movie reviews, right?
So people have some favorite actors, and
they like to talk about them positively.
So I guess it's probably good
if your last name is Caruso or
Gino or something like that, right?
I'm going to guess there are not
very well favored actors.
But I'm also guessing that my
theory about work relation's right.
So maybe this isn't true,
but actors names happen.
If this actor's name was only mentioned
once, or I guess at least ten times,
then if it was just in one positive
review, it might show up here.
When we're looking for correlation,
we kind of want things
that happen very frequently and
have an affinity somewhere.
Somebody that's just mentioned once,
100% of them will be positive, but
it's not really indicative
of being a positive feature.
So let's up this to 50 and check it out.
See a bunch of names, ooh, excellently.
Interesting, okay.
So we the name delightfully, okay.
Well, let's up this a little bit more.
As you can see,
I'm investigating the data.
I'm taking a look and
looking for patterns and
refining how I'm looking and just trying
to get a feel what the day is like.
Wow, so now I'm really seeing stuff.
I see a few names, I see flawless,
superbly, perfection, astaire, captures,
wonderful.
Okay, so now I'm really seeing words
that I would expect to be positive
words, being positively
indicative of these labels.
Let's see if I look for
negative, how's that look?
Pointless, atrocious,
drivel, laughable, awful.
Okay, great.
So at this point, I'm feeling
pretty good about the theory.
It's clear that the words that
I would expect to be predictive
seem to be predictive, or
at least correlative with the kind
of the labels that I think they
should be correlated with.
So in the kind of the next section,
we're going to be talking about how we
can leverage this predictive theory
to create an input and output data so
our network can sort of refine this
correlative power into a classifier,
right?
So stay tuned kind of for the next
section, and I'll see you there.