For this quiz, I'm going to list some decisions and
you tell me what architectural style it might apply to. Don't worry,
it's a fairly commonly used architectural style. For this particular kind of
system, we're going to have software components that are physically separated,
that means on different machines. Some of the components are there to
request services from other components that provide those services. By so
doing, this allows for scaling. In the situation where the number of requests
grows over time. We're going to have that the service providers are unaware of
the identities of the service requesters unless those,
service requesters provide that identity information. We're going to in this
particular architectural style it isolates the requesters from each other.
They're aware of the service provider or providers but not each other and
we're even going to allow for multiple service providers the number of
which may grow dynamically depending upon the demand for
the services that are there. Can you name this particular architectural style?