Let's look at some more details of this.
What we looked at in the last one, example, was basically an error
function between the expanded minus the original version of the image, and
we called that a error image, and of course, it's referred to as a Laplacian.
Here, of course, we will refer to as L1 for the first level.
Of course, using this same method we could computer L2.
The expansion is in essence done by doing this equation here.
We expand from one level to the other one.
And then, of course, subtract it from the original to get a Laplacian.
So that's how we computed L1,
we can generalize this to computer L2, L3, L4, and so on.
In essence, what these Ls or these Laplacian images are, again a pyramid.
Because again, they can be stacked on each other and
of course, they encode in different frequencies.
But there are series of error images that form a Laplacian pyramid.
And in essence, what they are doing is computing the difference between two
levels of a Gaussian pyramid.
At one level I got the Gaussian value and
I got it at the other level because of, of how I computed it.
And now I can difference it and
actually starts giving me, what was the error between all of them?
So now let's think about how we can use this information.