Well, we know that the Operating System
keeps track of applications or
processes that we have on the system.
Because it has to make various resources
available for this processes or
applications.
So, in addition to if knows on whose
behalf a given application is running.
And when I say that I really mean.
So the user would launched
this application.
So the answer to this actually is,
first one,
processes are going to run on
behalf of users and that users have
to login to the system and launch
this application or these processes.
System, the trusted computing base as
the responsible for complete mediation,
is going to keep track of these
processes as we said before.
So when a process is going to make
a request, and I keep saying process, or
application interchangeably,
an application essentially
runs as a process.
So when the process makes a request,
the system knows on whose behalf that
process is running and the user on
whose behalf it's running is somebody
who must have logged in previously.
And after logged in, we had
launched its process for that user.
The resource that is
target of this request,
we have to keep track of who
all are able to access it.
But when we get to Access Control
we'll discuss how that is done.