>> Dun, duh, dun, dun, duh, dun, dun, dun. Dun, duh, dun, dun, duh, dun, dun,
dun. Dun, duh, dun, dun, duh, dun, dun,
dun. Dun, duh, dun, dun, duh, dun, dun, dun.
>> Hi, I'm Michael Litman and welcome to
clustering and expectation maximization. I dunno, I feel
a little drama might help kind of wake us
up this morning. How are you doing Charles?
>> I'm doing fine. I just had a lot of ice cream.
>> [LAUGH] Dude, you really shouldn't eat
ice cream first thing in the morning.
>> It wasn't first thing in the morning. That was after I had
a muffin, and a breakfast burrito. So it was third thing in the morning.
>> You frighten me. As you may recall, the
mini course that we are doing now is on
unsupervised learning and we haven't really kind of set
down and, and introduced these concepts. So, I, I thought
it maybe worth taking a step back, even though
we are going to talk about some particular algorithms today,
to talk more generally about what unsupervised learning is.
So up to this point in the first mini course
we talked about supervised learning. Supervised learning,
in supervised learning we use labeled training
data to generalize labels to new instances.
And what unsupervised learning is is making
sense out of unlabeled data. So when I wrote these down I started to
think boy, they're more different than you'd
expect just by sticking an un in front.
>> How so?
>> Well they don't seem to really, the definitions don't seem to
have all the much in common. You know, it's not like this
one uses labeled training data to generalize labels to new
instances, and this one uses unlabeled training data to generalize labels
to new instances. Like I would think that you'd have the
definition of one. You just stick an extra un in there.
>> Well, that's kind of true, right? So you, if you,
if you do some data description and make sense out of
unlabeled data. And then I give you a new piece of
data. Somehow, using that description, you would know how to describe it.
>> Maybe. I mean there's definitely some,
some unsupervised learning algorithms that do some amount of generalization.
>> Mm-hm.
>> But but it's, it's not as, it's not as
unified. I think, in some sense the concern here is that
unsupervised learning is just not as unified a problem, or
as well defined, or crisply defined a problem as supervised learning.
>> Oh, I think that's definitely true.
>> So just as labels, and I think we talked about this in the
intro to the whole course. That supervised
learning, we can sometimes think of as function
approximation, which is learning how to match inputs
to outputs. Whereas, unsupervised learning is data description. It's
about taking the data you've got, and finding
some kind of more compact way of describing it.
>> Sure, I buy that. And it makes a lot of sense.