Lets now look at some of the interplay between threads and
the way signals need to be handled.
In the selerious threads implementation as described in
the papers there's a signal mask that's associated with each user level done.
And that's part of the user level process.
It's visible at the user level library level.
There is also signal mask that's associated with the kernel level thread or
rather the likely process that it's attached to and
that kernel level mask is only visible at the kernel level.
Now in when a user level thread wants to disable a signal it clears
the appropriate bit in the signal mask and this is happening at user level.
This mask is not visible to the kernel.
Now when a signal occurs,
the kernel needs to know what should it do with the signal.
It is possible that the kernel visible signal mask has that bit still
set at one, so the kernel thinks that the signal is enabled as
far as this particular process, this particular thread is concerned.
If we don't want to have to make a system call and
cross from user into kernel level each time a user-level thread
modifies the signal mask, then we need to come up with some kind of policy.
The SunOS paper that describes the lightweight user-level threading
library proposes a solution of how to handle this situation.