Hey, my name is Rason Mohan and
I run a website called Fusion Ed
to teach people about VR.
I'm super excited to be teaching this
Udacity course and we're currently in
mixed reality, which is one of
the best ways to show your friends and
family what it's like to be within VR.
We're currently in this apartment scene,
but with the click of a button,
we can transition into
this beautiful island and
you do this too using
the audacity VR app.
All you need is Google Cardboard,
and just smart phone.
Just put it in here and
boom.I'm viewing VR within VR.
How meta is that?
Seeing really is believing, so let's
get you into your first VR experience.