The answer is that it yields nothing.
The actual maximum independent set
will have size of V minus size C
star vertices in it.
While the compliment of
the vertex cover that we find
will have size of V minus
size of C vertices in it.
But, if C star happens to be the number
of vertices over 2, well then the size
of C could be equal to V, and then this
ratio becomes entirely meaningless.
We've now seen the potential
trade-off between time and
accuracy in the context of
the vertex cover problem.
There is an exact exponential algorithm,
and there's a polynomial
factor to approximation.
What if a factor to approximation
isn't what I really want however?
What if I'd be happy with a factor ten
approximation if it were fast enough?
What if I really need to be within 1% of
the optimum, and I'm willing to wait for
an answer as long as it takes?
It would be very convenient if there
was some way to easily trade off
speed versus accuracy in this way.
For vertex cover it turns out that
this is highly unlikely but for
other problems there are schemes that
allow us to trade off speed versus
accuracy with precise guarantees.
We'll illustrate this
possibility with the example.