Here is seems to be a problem of not enough data and not a very good smoothing algorithm.
Now the problem was even though I had 4 billion words from which I trained by probabilistic model,
I had never seen the word "ginormous"--not once in those 4 billion.
Yet, I should be able to deal with it even if I haven't seen the word before.
So having more data might mean that I would've seen "ginormous"
and I could have some probability for it rather than just making the Laplace smoothing assumption.
And having better smoothing could also help--
maybe something more sophisticated than Laplace,
maybe something that looks more carefully at the content of the word.
So it might have a letter model to say these letters look common,
ending in "ous"--that's a common ending in English--so this looks more like a word,
even if I haven't seen it before, than some other combination of letters.