So for this exercise,
I won't tell you exactly how to fix it.
Less hand-holding,
like Katherine wanted.
This will be a chance for you to
figure out what the problem is and
what the potential solution is.
I'd like you to examine the code and
answer these questions.
First, what's wrong with
the PhraseActivity and
why do you think that's happening?
Go ahead and write your answer here.
Second, describe how we should modify
our code to fix that problem, so
that our app looks like this for the
numbers activity and looks like this for
the phrases activity.
There's no need to write
the actual code here.
Just describe your approach but
be as specific as you can so
that you can easily translate those
ideas into code in the next step.
If you need some hints,
check out the notes below the quiz.
Don't worry about the spacing and
visual appearance of the app for now.
We'll take care of
those in a later step.