We want the stack view to take the whole
width in every single device and
orientation.
You probably already found how to
do it by yourself but here it goes.
We need to add a new constraint to
the stack view that makes it stick
to the right hand side.
This will force it to stretch.
Hold your horses.
Don't add it just now,
before you do, think,
what do you expect to happen to
the views inside the stack view?
Will they both stretch?
Now go ahead and add it.
Well, that was anticlimactic.
Nothing happened at all.
This is because the right
hand side constraint
is telling the stack view to remain
at this distance from the border.
Let's change it so
it is the same as the left one.
Now it makes sense.
Notice that the stack view chose
to stretch the text field and
leave alone the label.
Can you tell why it did that?
Why was the text field
stretched instead of the label?
While we think about it, add some space
between the label and the text field.
Who's shrinking?
In the next video we'll
learn what happened.