We need an API client,
but how do we design it?
A good place to start is thinking about
the API methods that we want to make and
what they might return.
So what methods or
function calls do we need to make?
If we list the API
interactions that we need,
then we can write convenient
API methods for each one.
The interactions we need are getting
a request token, getting a session ID,
getting the user's ID,
searching movies by search string,
getting a user's favorite movies, adding
and removing favorite movies, getting
a user's watchlist movies, and finally,
adding or removing watchlist movies.
For this exercise, I want you to think
of an intuitive function name for
each requirement and
what these functions might return.
There are no perfect answers for
this exercise,
but some answers are better than others.
Typically, we want to go with simple,
intuitive function names with return
types that are convenient and expected.
Using something simple and
intuitive may be like, for
this one, get request token,
is a property of good reusable APIs, and
you should assume that others want to
use your API client in their projects.
So take this approach with each of your
function names that you write here and
then write the return types here.