Well that was easy.
The next method is
a little more complicated.
Self erode at index path is
the method that the table view
uses to get cell objects one at a time.
There's a challenge in
the implementation of this method.
It isn't so difficult but
sometimes it trips people up.
This challenge comes from
an optimization that tables need.
Consider how fast we like to be
able to scroll through tables.
iPhone users want to be able to swipe
along a list in a split second.
It's an interesting technical
challenge each row is
a fairly complex view object.
If we have to swipe through a few
hundred rows that's a lot of
objects to allocate.
Too many objects as it turns out.
If every cell had to be allocated
as it appears on the screen
the scrolling would get choppy.
So Apple's worked out a caching
scheme to reuse these cell objects
over and over.
Kind of like stairs on an escalator,
when cell objects scroll off the screen
they get reused on the other side.
Anything that is shared across
cells gets reused, cell border,
image placement,
recurring control elements,
recurring labels,
the structure of the cells data.
This means these shared elements
don't need to be re-specified
when a cell comes onto the screen.
Only the data needs to be re-specified.
At any given time, there will be a few
TableViewCell objects that are off
the screen in a queue waiting to
come back on screen with new data.
Because of this, we never need
to construct cells ourselves.
The queue is kept inside the table
view so whenever we need a cell
we dq one from the table view, populate
it with data and we're good to go.
Some tables combine more
than one type of cell.
To accommodate that cells are tagged
with string reuse identifies
to keep them separate.
In those cases the tables keep
separate queues for each type of cell.
Our favorite things table
only needs one kind of cell.
But we'll still need to give
the cells a reuseIdentifier.
All right, let's figure out
what the code should look like.