Recall that we started
the whole conversation around
computational photography by looking at
how we're going to capture 3D world with
all of the illumination associated with
it into an image through a sensor and
a set of optics.
The sensor basically gave us,
among other things,
an image representation
in terms of pixels.
That's what we looked at, and
here is example of the image
we'd looked at before.
We're just going to look at a black and
white image of this.
And we basically said that, in essence,
this image has a certain width and
height, and that helps us look at
concepts of what a megapixel image is.
So a digital image in that time,
and we discussed it,
was basically a numeric representation
in both dimensions, in x and y.
And this is the coordinate
frame we looked at.
And we basically looked at the whole
concept of how we can access any part of
this image by just traversing through
basically the rows and columns in x and
y for continuous form,
and is and js, basically,
again, looking at each and
every pixel in discrete form.
This allowed us to look at
concepts of image resolution.
We basically looked at image resolution
as width times height of an image.
And we made claims that each element,
or each pixel, picture element,
contains light intensities for each
value of x and y for the whole image.
And that's how we accessed it.
Of course,
we learn how to do filtering and
everything associated with that later.