I'll be going through the initial
camera calibration steps
in this Jupyter notebook.
The first step will be to read in
calibration images of a chessboard.
it's recommended to use at least 20
images to get a reliable calibration.
And for this example,
we have a lot of images in this
calibration images folder.
They are all images of a chessboard,
taken at different angles and distances.
And there's also a test image
I'll eventually want to test my
camera calibration and undistortion on.
Each chessboard here has eight
by six corners to detect.
I'll go through
the calibration steps for
the first calibration image in detail.
First, you can see that I've
already done my numpy open cv and
plotting imports.
Then I'll read in the first image
calibration1.jpg, and I'll display it.
So here's our calibration image.
I'll map the coordinates of
the corners in this 2D image,
which I'll call it's image points
to the 3D coordinates of the real,
undistorted chessboard corners,
which I'll call object points.
So, I'll set up two empty arrays to
hold these points, object points and
image points.
The object points will all be the same.
Just the known object coordinates
of the chessboard corners for
an eight by six board.
These points will be 3D coordinates,
x, y and z from the top left corner,
0, 0, 0, to the bottom right, 7, 5, 0.
The z coordinate will be zero for
every point, since the board
is on a flat image plane.
And x and y will be all
the coordinates of the corners.
So I'll prepare these object points,
first by creating six by
eight points in an array.
Each with three columns for the x,
y, and z coordinates of each corner.
I'll initialize these all as zeros
using numpy's zero function.
The z coordinate will stay zero so
I'll leave that as it is but for
our first two columns, X and
Y, I'll use numpy's M grade function to
generate the coordinates that I want.
M grade returns the coordinate
values for a given grid size and
I'll shape those coordinates back into
two columns, one for x and one for y.
Next, to create the image points,
I want to look
at the distorted calibration image and
detect the corners of the board.
Open CV gives us an easy way to detect
chessboard corners with a function
called findChessboardCorners
that returns the corners
found in a grayscale image.
So I'll convert this
image to grey scale and
then I'll pass that into the fine
chessboard corners function.
This takes in our grey scale image along
with the dimensions of the chessboard
corners.
In this case, eight by six and
the last parameter is for any flags.
And there are none in this example.
If this function detects corners,
I'll append those points
to the image points array.
I'll also add our
prepared object points,
objp, to the object points array.
And these object points
will be the same for
all of the calibration images,
since they represent a real chessboard.
Next, I'll also draw
the detected corners,
with a call to drawChessboardCorners,
that takes in our image,
corner dimensions and corner points.
And I'll display these corners so
that we can see what was detected
in an interactive window.
So let's run this code.
Here's what our detected
corners look like.
And if I zoom in, it looks like the
corners were detected pretty accurately.
The next step will be to do this for
all the calibration images.
I can read in all the calibration
images by importing the glob API,
which helps read in images
with a consistent file name,
like calibration one,
two, three, and so on.
Then, I'll iterate through each
image file, detecting corners and
appending points to the object and
image points arrays.
Then later, we'll be able to
use the object points and
image points to calibrate this camera.
I'll show you the open cv functions
you'll need to calibrate the camera and
finally, undistort images.
To calibrate a camera, open cv gives
us the calibrate camera function.
This takes in our object points,
our image points, and
the shape of the image.
And using these inputs,
it calculates and
returns the distortion coefficients and
to the camera matrix that we need
to transform 3D object
points to 2D image points.
It also returns the position of
the camera in the world, with values for
rotation and translation vectors.
The next function you'll
need is undistort.
This takes in a distorted image,
our camera matrix, and
distortion coefficients.
And it returns an undistorted,
often called destination image.
In the next quiz, you'll need to apply
what you've learned to calibrate
the camera and correct for
image distortion.
Good luck.