If we had a basis set for images, and we'll talk a minute about what that means,
that could be probably useful for analysis, especially for
linear systems because we could consider each basis component independently.
Why is that true?
because you remember, in linear systems things just sum.
So if I could say how some operator applies to each element of the basis set,
and then I just have to scale it and
sum it, then I'd know how this operator applies to the entire image.
And that's part of the reason that we're going to go through this whole
basis set decomposition, is because most of our operations are going to be,
that we'll be considering, are going to be linear operations.
And when I was talking about things from a long time ago and
filter theory, et cetera, those are all based on linear, types of operations.
To consider basis sets of images, what we're going to do is, we're going to
think for now, of an image as just being a single point in a very large space.
So if I have a space that's, N by N image, right, so
let's suppose it's 100 by 100.
So 100 by 100, that's 10,000, okay, so you can think of
the entire image as just a 10,000 dimensional vector if you wanted.
That would be fine.
Okay, so what would be a basis set for a 10,000 dimensional vector space?
Well, one particular basis set is just our usual one, right?
We do zeros except we have a 1 in one of the elements that's like x and y and
z and p and q and r and you run out of letters before you get to 10,000.
But, but basically you have a 1 in every place.
Now are these independent?
Yep. Because if I sum up a whole bunch of them, the only way I
can get to a zero vector is if I have a zero multiple of each of them,
because they're independent, they don't effect one another.
But, it's really not a very helpful basis set because each one of these ba,
basis vectors, that one, that's just a single pixel.
So telling me what, about, sorry, how it behaves in respect to a single pixel,
that's not a particularly helpful basis set.
Instead, we're going to look at a different kind of basis set.
And it's a basis set that considers this image, or
any image in terms of how quickly it varies in different directions.
So here you see an image that is just, you know, no variant stalls.
You can think of that as just a constant intensity.
And as you move to the right, it starts to wiggle faster and faster and faster.
As you move down, it wiggles faster and faster and
faster, but this time horizontally, and
then if you combine them you would get these different orientations.
And by the way the two different pictures of the blue and the green are sort of,
you know, you can think of these as like, kind of like sine and
cosines, kind of off set.
Now this particular basis set has a name, okay, and
it's referred to as the Fourier basis, or Fourier decomposition.
And it's named after this dude, John Baptiste Joseph Fourier, okay.
So he had a crazy idea, a crazy idea in 1807, that any periodic function,
that's a function that repeats, could be rewritten as a weighted sum.
Try to say that quickly, rewritten as a weighted sum of sines and
cosines of different frequencies.
In other words you could make any repeated pattern, doesn't matter what it
looks like, as long as it eventually repeats, using sines and cosines.
So don't believe it?
Well you wouldn't be alone.
Back at the time there were some other folks you may have heard of like
Laplace or Poisson and other mathematician types.
They didn't believe it either, lot of controversy.
This question about whether Fourier's proof was correct it turns out his
result was correct and in fact it was so controversial it
wasn't even translated into English until 40 some odd years after his death.
But like we said it is true, and the series now, now that he's dead and
famous, we call this the Fourier Series, all right.
We're going to get from Fourier series to Fourier transform to discrete Fourier
transform, just so you know where we're headed.