>> Oh Matt, you brought Spud today. Can I hold him?
>> Of course.
>> Hi puppy, you're so cute. How old is he?
>> Well, my little canine friend here is about two years old, so that's about 14
in human years.
>> Oh, and how old are you my human friend?
>> well actually I just celebrated my 30th birthday.
>> Happy Birthday.
>> Thanks, but why do you ask? How old are you?
>> About 200,000 years old.
>> 200 what, you look good for your age.
>> Thank you. What could I say?
>> But that's not possible, you can't be that old.
>> Well, I know. I'm not 200,000 years old, but modern humans are. You should know
that, you're a genetics expert here at Udacity.
>> Yeah, yeah I knew that. Yeah, modern humans, homo sapiens have been around for
about 200,000 years, but we're not the only kind of humans that's existed on
our home planet.
>> That's true. Homo habilis was around for 2.5 million years.
>> That's right, homo habilis, one of the first primitive forms of human lived
almost 2.5 million years ago before going extinct after a million years. In
total, they lived almost five times as long as modern humans have been alive
today. Actually, let's go look at the timeline and learn a bit more about human
evolution.
>> I'll go with you, I'm just going to go put Spud down.
>> Okay.