To summarize,
in this lesson we look at virtual and
physical memory management
mechanisms in operating systems.
You should now understand what are the
data structures, the mechanisms, and
the hardware level support.
That the operating system relies on when
it tries to map the process' address
space that uses virtual memory onto
the underlying physical memory.
We talked about pages and
segmentation, address translation,
page allocation,
page replacement algorithms.
We also looked at how these
memory management mechanisms,
that are part of the operating system,
can be used by some higher level
services, like checkpointing.