Alright so we should have copied and
pasted this code snippet from the gist
into your Pet Provider class.
And this is the code for
how you should have added the two
URI patterns to your URI matcher.
So first we call sUriMatcher.addURI and
pass in the pet content authority and
the pets path.
So this Uri pattern will be
assigned integer code pets,
which maps to the value 100.
And so, if the URI matches this pattern,
we know that we need to act
on the entire Pets table.
So, for the second URI,
we also call sUriMatcher.addURI,
and pass in the pet content authority,
as well as the pets path which
has slash pound appended to it,
which refers the ID of the specific
row were interested in.
Now this URI pattern will be assigned
to the integer code PETS_ID,
which maps to the value 101.
So in Editor Studio, this is what
the pet provider class will look like.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now, to double check that our codes
still works, I'll compile and
run the app.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So there are no visible changes
in the UIs expected, but
there's still a bit more left to do,
so let's keep working on the provider.