great job so far in this lesson you've
used image analysis techniques like
candy edge detection and hot transforms
to find lane lines in images these are
the exact same techniques that you're
going to need for the first project so
Ryan what will students be doing for the
first project
well your goal in this first project is
to write a software pipeline to identify
and track the position of the lane lines
in a video stream that might sound
complicated but don't worry you can do
it a video is really just a series of
images so you already have the tools you
need to do this project
awesome this project is your first step
toward becoming a real self driving car
engineer and in fact this was one of my
first projects when I was wanting to
become a self-driving car engineer so
let's get to it