Next we'll take a look at the JavaScript.
In Andy's JavaScript file,
one of the first things we see is the hideAllCats function.
As you can see, he's going over all of the cats and
hiding every single one of them.
The first two things we see are var cats and var buttons.
These are variables, and in them is stored a J
query collection of the cat class objects, and the button class objects.
And the next thing we see is the hide all cats function.
What Andy is doing here is looping over all of the cats, and
hiding each one of them.
Now this isn't the best way to do things.
If you have many, many views for a single area instead of one.
A bug in your code could easily make multiple cats show up simultaneously,
breaking the layout.
And as we saw before in our HTML, each cat does have it's own view.
So that's kind of bad news.
But in terms of classifying what these things are, they all seem view-like.
This represents the cat views.
This represents the buttons and then this function here is the function that
hides all of the cats, effectively changing the rendering of the page.
So, all three of these things seem very view-like.
If we continue looking at the file,
we'll find two more functions, bindButtonToCat and bindCounterToCat.
And you'll also see that these two functions will get called here in for
loops where we go over all of the buttons and
all of the cats, and run this for the buttons and this for each of the cats.
So what do these two functions effectively do?
They effectively add event handlers to our buttons and to our cat images.
In this one, when you click on a button, it hides all the cats using our
function, then it grabs the cat with the ID of cat 1 or cat 2, and shows it.
In bindCounterToCat, it's saying, whenever you click on the cat,
do the following, get the click count from the DOM, parse it into a number, and
then re-update the DOM with the new counter.
So, now, where do you think Andy's model effectively lives?
Where is he storing his data?