Using route calculation
within apps is essential for
store locators, taxi hailing apps,
and other everyday applications.
It's also really applicable for
delivery services
doing route optimization to
hundreds of locations a day.
See if you can take directions API
to the next level by mapping a route
from Florence to Milan,
stopping at Genoa, Bologna,
and Venice in an optimized order.
Map out a route from Florence to Milan,
stopping at Genoa, Bologna, and Venice.
Use the cities as waypoints,
and get the optimized route.
Take note of the order of
the cities you should stop at.
For some starter code,
reference the sample linked below.
Arrivederci!
Number the cities in the optimized
order you will visit them.