So I'm actually going to go ahead and
check the first one as
the correct answer.
Clearly whether it is to
do with theft of data,
identify theft, or
theft of intellectual property,
somebody invading your privacy,
we need laws against those.
Those people shouldn't be able to do
it without any sort of a consequence.
So criminal sanctions against
those kind of activities,
in particular those cyber-crime laws,
are necessary and we have them.
If you're going to pick the second
option, we will actually talk about
a number of challenges that you have
to deal with when you have laws.
And you perhaps can take
the position that no really laws,
this notion of what is right or
wrong, we can debate that.
Sometimes, while they're overarching and
things like that, but
this is more about
having legal deterrents,
that their consequences intend on doing
harm to others, their consequence.
I'm going to go over this one