There are many ways to solve this quiz,
but this is what I came up with.
I'm using an array to store up the
different sections of the template and
then join them together to become
the body of the constructor function.
First I set up my delimiters and
some variables.
This section here updates the default
delimiters with any custom ones
that are passed in.
Here I split on every occurrence
of the starting delimiter.
Then i loop over each segment,
find where the closing delimiter is.
I grab what's in the middle,
which will become the variable.
And then I add the remaining stuff
after the closing delimiter.
Then I join each of the different
segments back together and
add a loop to log the template once for
each time.
Then I create the function.
Then I join each of
the segments back together and
add a loop to log the template once for
each time.
Then I create the constructor function.
One tricky part is that the body of
the function has to be a string, but
those quotes are removed when
inserted into a constructor function.
So for something to be a string
inside of a constructor function,
you have to wrap them
in two sets of quotes.
That's what these wrapInQuotes
function calls are doing.