If you've marked all of these as correct
answers, then you're correct, and
I'll explain why.
First, at the lowest level,
we said that the virtual machine monitor
must provide guest VMs with
a virtual platform interface
to all of the hardware resources,
the CPU, the memory, the devices.
So this clearly is a requirement.
Obviously, the virtual machine
monitor will have to isolate guest
VMs from one another.
And this actually can be
pretty easily achieved
using the similar kinds of mechanisms
that are used by operating systems
to provide isolation
across the guest VMs.
So, the hypervisor will use techniques
or the virtual machine monitor
will use techniques like preemption,
will take advantage of hardware support
in the memory management unit so
that it can perform validations and
translations of memory
references pretty quickly.
So, there are opportunities
to achieve this requirement
efficiently using the existing methods
and the existing hardware support.
Also, within the virtual machine
at the topmost level of the stack,
the virtualization solution must
continue to provide the ability to
protect the guest operating system
from faulty or malicious applications.
We don't want a single application,
when it crashes,
to take the entire guest OS down.
What this means is that somehow we have
to have separate protection levels for
the applications and for the guest OS.
So these expectations that exist
when the guest OS is executing
natively on the physical platform,
they must continue to be valid
in the virtualized environment.
At the same time, the virtualization
solution has to have mechanisms
to protect the virtual machine monitor
from the guest operating systems.
We don't want a single faulty or
malicious guest OS to bring down
the hypervisor in the entire machine.
What this means is that we cannot have
a solution in which the guest operating
system and the virtual machine monitor
run at the same protection level.
They have to be separated.