When you don't have a clear plan for
debugging your issues,
you can waste a ton of time wandering
aimlessly through your code.
I've been there before, and it sucks
the joy right out of programming.
But it doesn't have to be this way.
A better approach to debugging is
having a consistent debugging process.
First, you want to
reproduce the problem.
The more complex the problem is,
the more important this step becomes.
Being able to reproduce the problem
ensures that you understand
the reasons which led to it.
And sometimes it's as easy as clicking
a button for your program to crash, but
other times it may take
running your app for
thirty minutes before
the problem occurs.
The point is, you can't reproduce a
problem if you don't understand it, and
if you don't understand it,
then you can't fix it.
Which leads to the second step,
gathering debug information.
Now this is crucial.
But you may be wondering what type of
information are you looking for exactly?
Well it depends on the problem,
but typically you want to start by
examining the program state or logs.
Now the program state is all the stored
information that you have at a given
point in your program's execution.
For instance, when the error occurred,
what is the value of a variable?
What kind of error are we looking at?
Maybe it's in EXC, BAD_ACCESS,
maybe it's a off by one problem,
it could be anything.
What line of code caused the error?
Or what functions or
methods led to the error?
This is the information that you'll
want to know when you're debugging,
and ExcCode reveals this
to us through its tools.
And thankfully there are a bunch of
tools, and they're really easy to use.
Now the hope is, of course, is that with
all the information that you gather,
you can form a strong hypothesis
about what went wrong.
But as you may already know,
having an hypothesis and
actually testing that hypothesis,
are two entirely different tasks.
If you're certain about what went wrong,
then you can go ahead and try to fix it.
But if you're unsure at all,
then you should probably go back and
gather more information
before trying your fix.
In some cases however,
trying a fix that you're not 100%
sure about isn't a bad thing.
Even if it doesn't fix the problem,
it could reveal more information
about why and what is happening.
The trick is to make sure that
you maximize the amount of
information you gain
per fix that you try.
If you find yourself making small
changes and your program keeps crashing,
or it doesn't behave like you expect,
then stop for a moment, pause,
collect your thoughts, and make sure
that you really understand the problem.
Once you do,
you can make a more informed fix and
try to reproduce the problem again.
And if your fix works,
then when you try to reproduce
the problem it won't happen.
But if the problem still occurs
then you'll have to go back and
start in the same debug spin cycle.
Now this can be tough,
but it's expected.
It often takes multiple iterations
of this full debugging process to
ultimately figure out
what your problem is.
So let's review.
The debugging process is as follows.
First, reproduce the problem.
Then gather any debugging information
you can about the problem.
Once you have enough information,
form a hypothesis about what went wrong.
Then determine an implement affix.
Last, test the fix by trying to
reproduce the problem again.
If you stay true to this method, and
you know which tools are available,
then debugging isn't so
much of a headache anymore.
It's almost like solving
a code mystery each time.
If you treat it that way then it can
be a much more pleasant experience
when you're programming.