So first, I'll modify
the activity_numbers.xml file,
to contain a GridView xml element.
So that means changing this
ListView to a GridView.
Right now I'll need to add a new
attribute called android numbers column,
and here you can specify how many
columns the grid will have, and for
this example I'll choose 2.
So notice in the Preview pane,
Android Studio tries to show a preview
of what this might look like.
And again, it doesn't show
real data from our app, and
it's not the real list item
layout that we're using.
But the point here is just to show
us that there will be two columns in
the grid, and that looks good.
All right, so let's go back to
the NumbersActivity.java, and
I see that there's an error now.
So the error message says that there's
an unexpected cast to the ListView
because the tag in the layout
file says GridView.
Well, since we switched to a GridView,
when we find the view in the layout, we
need to cast it to a GridView and store
it in a variable with type GridView.
So let's make that change now.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
All right, so now there's no
more errors and all the code and
activity looks fine.
So we can create an array list as usual,
and
we can create an ArrayAdapter
from that words list.
And then we can set
the adapter onto the GridView.
Let's build the app and run it on
our device and see what happens.
Now tapping to the Numbers activity,
sure enough we see
the two columns of words.
So each item is using
the same layout as before.
So we have a vertical linear layout,
with the Miwok word on top and
the English word on the bottom.
Now the only difference is that instead
of each item taking up the whole width
of the screen, each item now only
gets half the width of the screen.
because as we said,
we wanted a grid with two columns.
As we see, the logic of
the ArrayAdapter can stay the same,
whether it's attached to a ListView or
a GridView.
The adapter can produce item views with
the right content from the words list,
and a ListView or GridView slots
them into the screen accordingly.
Hopefully that exercise was helpful
to better understand adapter views.
Now I'm going to undo my GridView
changes and go back to using a ListView.