Since we don't have any robotic dolphins
that we could be doing testing and
training on, let's think through
an example of doing reinforcement
learning to try to teach a robot
soccer player to score a goal.
So, this is supposed to be
kind of a robot soccer pitch.
This is the goal in blue.
This is the ball in yellow.
And this is the robot in black.
And what we really want it
to do is score in the goal.
And that's worth a hundred.
Again, just like in the dolphin case,
it's very unlikely that the robot is
going to spontaneously drive around,
drive around, hit the ball into the
goal, experience the 100 and then say,
okay, cool,
that's what I'm supposed to be doing.
So, what are some things
we can do shaping-wise?
How can we modify this
reward function so
that it might encourage something in
the direction of scoring the goal?
>> I think, there are a couple
of things one might do.
I'll try not to over-think this.
Well, in order to kick the ball,
the circle with its circle feet,
it has to get near the ball, so
I could imagine putting some reward for
being near the ball,
wherever the ball is.
>> Cool.
So, you think like plus one
is enough for that or maybe?
>> I don't know, but
let's start with plus one.
>> All right.
How do we define near the ball?
There's going to be some kind
of epsilon ball around the ball?
>> [LAUGH] Yeah, that makes sense.
Or, you could go all the way around and
think about the distance you
are to the ball is inversely
proportional to the reward that you get.
>> Good point.
All right, let's look at your
way of thinking about it first.
So, if we're getting a reward,
the agent is getting a reward by
virtue of being close to the ball.
What's a good policy?
A good policy might be
to just sit in place or
sit a little bit closer to the ball and
just rack up the points.
>> Sure, so
then you'd need something else,
like hitting the ball
is worth some points.
>> Aha, okay,
that seems plausible, right.
So, if the robot is getting additional
points, additional pleasure for
getting closer to the ball, and
then actually hitting the ball, yay,
that was really awesome.
But, of course, by hitting the ball
it pushes the ball away which
is going to cause the near to
the ball score to go down.
So, it's going actually kind
of be sad that it did that.
>> Sure.
But then,
you would want to give it something for
getting the ball near to the goal.
So, just like being near to the ball
is worth something proportional,
inversely proportional distance,
you want the distance of the ball to
the goal to also be inversely
proportionally related to distance.
>> Yeah, that makes some sense!
So, now, we want to be careful that the
amount of bonus that the robot gets for
pushing the ball toward the goal
is going to be an improvement over
the fact that it's now no
longer itself near the ball.
>> Right, so I don't know.
Two times, or something.
I don't know.
I mean, I don't know exactly what
the right numbers are, but there you go,
something like that.
>> So, it seems like we could
play with these numbers for
a long time trying to get
the behavior that we want.
And there are a couple of really
interesting failure modes.
So, for example, if we have hitting
the ball being defined as making
contact between the player and the ball.
And you get, let's say +10 for
that each time,
ignoring these other factors for
a moment.
Then, once thing [LAUGH] that you often
see when you ask reinforcement learners
to learn in that kind of setting,
as you'll see,
robot walks over to the ball,
touches the ball, gets its plus ten.
And it turns out,
if you want to get that plus ten again,
the best thing to do is just back
off from the ball a little bit and
then make contact with it again and
in fact really what you want to do is
go up to the ball, and just shiver.
Right, just like vibrate back and
forth, [SOUND] so
that you just keep getting plus
tens over and over and over again.
You can make a lot of money that way.
A lot more than you can
make by scoring the goal.
Because you can do this, you know 30 or
40 times a second if you're
a good wiggler, and so this ends up
actually even though this additional
shaping information that we're
defining is giving good hints,
it's also creating
spurious optimal policies.
>> Right.
Well, it makes sense, right.
People have been making money for
thousands of years by wiggling.
>> [LAUGH] I guess that's sort of true.
But in this particular case,
what we have to do is somehow make it so
that you can't have a money pump.
You can't do arbitrage.
You can't, by doing the good thing,
undoing it and then doing it again,
get double credit.
>> I see.
>> So, a natural idea is
to actually say, all right,
if you're going to get plus ten for
hitting the ball, then letting go
of the ball should be a minus ten.
Right?
You should not be able to make a profit
by repeatedly bumping into the ball.
Does that make some sense?
>> It does.
My favorite part about that is how
you called it an actual idea which,
as opposed,
makes what I said not an actual idea.
But yeah, okay.
>> Oh,
I did not mean to imply that or even-
>> That's fine.
>> Say it.
>> It's fine.
It's fine.
I see what kind of rewards
shaping your doing.
It's okay.
[LAUGH] In any case what I guess is
happening, so that makes sense.
So, you don't want to get into a place
where you can get into a suboptimal
positive loop.
So, you're going to say,
getting to the ball is good.
Getting away from the ball is not good.
>> So, you're going to learn to get to
the ball and have to do something else,
that will get you even more reward,
make it worthwhile backing
away from the ball.
>> Right, good.
And I like the thing that you said about
not wanting to create a suboptimal loop.
>> A suboptimal positive loop.
>> [SOUND] Because a suboptimal
positive loop is actually going to
cause this spurious behavior to happen.
If there is a way that you can
do a sequence of actions and
generate profit where there really
shouldn't have been in the environment,
then it's distracting, right.
The agent is going to end up doing
things that you didn't wanted to do.
So, we have to avoid creating
these suboptimal positive loops.
And so a natural idea from,
I'm going to say physics.
And you can tell I'm
an expert in physics,
because I understand Bellman's equation,
Einstein's Bellman equation.
That is that the idea
of potential functions.
What I am going to do is define
potential functions and then show how we
can use them to do shaping without
actually messing up the optimal policy.
>> I look forward to it.