As you know, Android Wear devices
come in different shapes and sizes.
You'll need to consider both round and
square faces,
as well as different resolutions.
Some concepts work better in a certain
format, but a little planning will allow
users to enjoy your watch
face on every type of screen.
Ideally the visual design of the watch
face works for both round and
square formats.
In this example,
the design is flexible enough to work
well in both cases without any changes.
However, other concepts might require
different designs for square and
round screens.
When you need to do separate layouts for
round and square,
try using a common set of colors,
line weights, shading and other design
elements to draw a visual connection
between your square and round versions.
By using similar colors, and consistent
visual elements, you can customize
different square and round designs
that still feel visually similar.
Some of your concepts will naturally
take the shape of an analog clock.
Like a center dial with hour and
minute hands.
In this case, consider the corner areas
that are exposed when translating to
a square format.
Try extending and
exploring this extra space.
Now it's time for a quiz.
Which are the better watch
face designs from here?
The first one is a square watch
with an analog watch face drawn
inside of the circle.
The second one is a square watch with
the analog watch face extended to
the edges.
Third one is a watch face with the whole
week's weather drawn around the edges.
And the fourth one is a watch face
with just the current weather.