Why did you choose iOS development,
what do you find interesting or
fascinating about iOS?
So what brings you to
iOS develop instead of,
maybe, backend develop or anything else?
>> When I started writing
code it was with C and C++.
And I was writing small apps that
would run from the command line, but
I never really got the opportunity to
write something that could quickly go
into somebody's hands.
So when I wrote my first app,
the thing I was hoping for
by writing apps was being able to
build something that I could give to
my brother or my friends and
see what their reactions were, and
build apps that were more tailored for
users as opposed to other developers.
>> And do you have a GitHub profile?
Do you have any side project
that you work on on your own?
>> Yeah, I have a GitHub link,
I can share that with you later.
But right now one thing that I'm
working on, I'm a big gamer and
I grew up playing the Nintendo and
the Gameboy, and things like that.
I was a big fan of Pokemon, which is
a little top down adventure game,
and I'm trying to recreate that
using Strike-It, just for fun.
So, take a game with the mechanics that
I know, that I've played before and
then I can simulate
them on a Gameboy and
try to replicate those using iOS',
or Apple's frameworks.
>> Okay, and you're doing this
on your own, on your free time?
>> Yeah, just on the weekends, or
sometimes during the week I'll plug
around with that and
other side projects.
>> Okay, thank you.