So your style should
look something like this.
We have a bluish color in red-green-blue
notation, and a bold style.
Now one thing that you might want to
notice is over here in the column,
it shows you a small preview
of what the color is.
So if we go over to our design view,
we can see that the text has
changed to a bolder blue color.
Styles and
themes bring the unique character of
your company's product to your app.
We will do a formal deep dive
in lesson three when we discuss,
Bold graphic design.
In the meantime, you can take a look
at some open-source apps like
the 2014 Google IO Scheduler app or
this list on Wikipedia
of open-source Android apps
to see what others have done.
Now, be advised that not all of these
apps use material design principles,
you might see some old UIs in there.