Here's a 'Structure from Motion' type problem,
that is similar to what I asked you on a homework assignment.
Assume there is a world of 3 point features,
that will be named; 1, 2, 3, but I won't tell you which one is which.
There are 4 pinhole cameras; A, B, C, and D.
And they all have a left, center, and right side.
Left, center, and right side.
And you should observe,
that the perceived order of features in the scene,
by virtue of using a pinhole,
will be inverted inside the pinhole camera.
So camera 'A', sees in the left position,
feature '1',
on the center position, feature '2',
on the right position, feature '3'.
I would like to know,
for which of the other camera's,
is it the case that feature '3'
will appear in the leftmost position?
So the leftmost position is 'L' over here,
'L' over here, 'L' over here.
Assuming the optical centers, shown over here.
Please check any or all of the following;
Camera B,
Camera C,
Camera D,
or None of them.