The Android rendering pipeline is broken
up into two key sections, the CPU and
the GPU, which both work together in
order to draw images on the screen.
Each one has some specific processes
that are defined by it and
need to obey specific operating
rules in order to be performant.
Now on the CPU side, the most common
performance problems come from
unnecessary layouts and
invalidation's that is
part of your view hierarchy having to
be measured, torn down, and rebuilt.
This generally comes in two problematic
flavors, either the display lists
are being rebuilt too many times
during a frame or you're spending too
much time invalidating too much of your
view hierarchy and needlessly redrawing.
Both cause taxing CPU overhead
in refreshing display lists and
other related cache GPU resources.
Now the second major problem is on
the GPU side, involving an inefficiency
called overdraw, which is effectively
when we waste GPU processing time
coloring in pixels that end up getting
colored in later, by something else.
Now, in this lesson, we're going to talk
more about invalidation's, layouts, and
overdraw, and how you can use
the tools available in the SDK
to find out if they're hurting
the performance of your application.
And don't worry about all the crazy
diagrams you've seen so far, once we've
covered the theory, Chris is here to
walk you through the code samples that
will teach you how to fix these exact
kind of problems in your applications.
So, let's get started with
something easy, overdraw.