>> Sure. We could do this intuitively or
we could be a little bit more, systematic about it.
And one way of getting a hint on things is to actually look at the constraints.
And you'll notice that for the constraints that we had the answers that
Jerrod gave were also already on the left hand side of the equations. In fact,
they were the in the context part of the constraint, they were the class that
that came first. So that's a hit you can use to try to
decide who's responsible for maintaining them. Now, in actual practice,
any component could be responsible, okay? Or we could introduce a new
component to be responsible. In fact that's what were going with this
how do we manage the indirect constraints that are more than one class?
Will that means some kind of interaction among the classes or components, and
who's responsible for managing that. That turns out to be a tricky part of this.
And we want to handle that in a systematic way as well.