Your next task is to understand how
to implement a graph algorithm in
the language of linear algebra.
Once you've got the hang of that,
you'll be ready to go distributed.
Go distributed!
Yay!
Let's start with a level
synchronous variant of BFS.
BFS, not an acronym for
best friends sometimes.
Recall the setup.
We're given a graph G of vertices and
edges.
And you're also given a start or
source vertex S.
What you want to compute is the minimum
distance of every vertex from S.
For example, suppose S equal zero.
Initially S is a distance
of 0 away from itself.
So I've labeled S with
its starting distance and
I've put an entry in
the distance vector.
All the other vertices which
are unvisited start infinitely far away.
The level-synchronous algorithm
processes one level at a time
starting at level 0.
Now for any given l, there's a frontier.
The frontier consists of all unvisited
vertices which are a distance
l away from the source.
In this case, level 0 contains
just the source vertex 0.
Processing the level means visiting all
of the frontiers unvisited neighbors,
in this case the neighbors are 1 and 5.
We can update their distances
with the current distance plus 1.
These previously unvisited neighbors now
become the frontier at the next level.
You've just lathered and
rinsed, so now repeat.
Look at all the unvisited neighbors
of 1 and 5, which are 2 and 6.
Update their distances to 1 plus 1 or 2.
Now 2 and 6 become the new frontier.
Update the next set of unvisited
neighbors which are 3, 7 and 8.
Then they become the new frontier and,
in this example, just once more.
So, what's the cost of this procedure?
Let's consider just the sequential case.
Suppose there are n vertices and
m edges.
Then the sequential running time will
turn out to be big O of m plus n.
That's because you might, in the worst
case, visit every edge once or
every node at least once.