The first answer is correct, yes.
Flash has the helper processes, so
it can handle I operations
without blocking.
The second answer really makes no sense.
Both processes continue receiving
the same number of requests
in these experiments.
The third answer is correct as well.
At 100 megabytes, the workload,
it's size increases.
It cannot fit in the cache
as much as before, and so
it becomes more I/O bound.
There are more I/O requests that
are needed beyond this point.
For a SPED, at this point, once the
workload starts becoming more O/I bound
the problem is that a single blocking i
operation will block the entire process.
None of the other requests
can make progress, and
that's why its performance
significantly drops at that point.
And finally, the last answer,
that flash can handle more files.
That's really not correct.
SPED and
Flash have comparable memory footprints.
And so,
it is not that one can handle more files
than the other in the memory cache.
If anything, Flash has the helper
processing so if those are created,
they are going to interfere with
the other available memory, and
will impact the number of available
cache in the negative sense.
So if anything,
it will have less available memory for
caching files than SPED, so this is not
an answer that explains why the Flash
performance is better than
the SPED performance.