I Michael Charles how's it going it's
going quite well how's it going with you
good good good good so today I thought
we would talk a little bit about the
philosophy of machinery who hate
philosophy I don't like it much either
although I'm a Doctor of Philosophy oh
that's very impressive aren't you dr.
philosophy to have its kind of imprint
of his kind of impressive
so what we wanted to kind of get across
the day is a little bit about why we the
class structure the way it is what the
different parts are and maybe go a
little bit of back and forth about what
we think you should be getting out of
course it seemed reasonable
sure ok so first off by the way before
we get started I want to thank you for
coming down to atlanta and join me in
these beautiful studios but it's it's
very nice to be here thank you for
inviting me
no no thank you for coming Michael thank
you for asking me to do the course this
has been a lot of fun
oh the whole point was built of course
with you want we like each other and
that's one of the things that we want
you to get want to get across this class
because we like machine learning a lot
of stuff in common but i'm not sure we
completely agree on the most important
parts of machine learning and why we do
the things that we do
alright so i think people now sarwar
Michael would claim that you're more
theoretical than i am and carry in
theory and I'm more practical than you
are practically at least in practice and
hopefully some potential to come out in
the class but I think in order to see
why that tension works that way you have
to understand what machine learning is
so Michael right what's machine learning
it's about proving games
no I would not say it's about proving
there's although proving theorems is
often important machine i agree with
that
ok so we're on the same page we're
partially on the same page what is
machine 1 what is machine learning the
right definition so it is computational
statistics
how's that for definition that is a
definition it is wrong on so many levels
however a lot of people would agree with
that statement they would say that
machine learning is really just applied
statistics applied statistics
computational statistics computationally
about statistics i don't like that
definition i think that it's a bit too
narrow I think the machine learning
about this broader notion of building
artifacts computational artifacts
typically that learn over time based on
experience
and in particular it's not just the
active building these artifacts that
matter it's the math behind it it's the
science behind it it's engineering
behind it and it's the computing behind
it's everything that goes into building
intelligent artifacts that almost by
necessity have to learn over time by
that
yeah so you have data and you do an
ounce of the date and try to glean
things from the data and use various
kinds of computational structure to do
that so computational statistic
I don't think that's computational
system