So if you've updated it correctly, your
view should look something like this.
Here's my four TextViews
with all of their details.
Now notice that I've named
them accordingly, so
I have a latitude label that
I called latitude_label.
I have the latitude text where I'm
going to write whatever the latitude of
the device is, and I called it
latitude_text, and ditto for longitude.
Here's the label and
you can see, here's the text.
Now, one thing to note is that I am hard
coding the text in the labels as you can
see here, longitude goes here.
Now best practice would be to
put that in a string resource.
And if you haven't learned
how to do that yet,
Go to the Android Fundamental's course,
follow the link below to learn how.
It does make it much easier to maintain
your app, as well as of course,
doing things like localization.
So if I touch on Design, now this is
what our user interface will look like.
Before we go to the code,
we'll need to go through the rest of the
steps as discussed in the last session.
You'll do that next.