So now, let's talk about Stereo Vision.
A specific form, and again,
driven by many biological systems.
Humans of course, have two eyes.
Many other animals also have two eyes.
And our interest with this is,
can we actually infer depth from images
that are captured at the same time?
But from more than one viewpoint,
two different viewpoints.
So here's simply an example that
actually showcases this, right.
I have two eyes, and inside is
just kind of showing the brain.
This eye is basically seeing
a viewpoint which is kind of,
you know, this view point here, and
this eye is seeing another viewpoint
which is shown by this cone.
Both of them are different, right?
One of them is seeing from this side,
the other one is from this see,
seeing it from this side.
So just look at these cones.
You can basically see that this eye is
actually seeing, this viewpoint and
actually, you're actually going to see
things a little bit from this side also.
Right?
You can actually see the other pins
of this bowling pins from this side.
'Kay, what happens from the right side?
Of course, the right side sees
the right sides of these pins.
The left is seeing the left
sides of these pins.
Actually, this is interesting so by
fusing these two images one, of course,
you're getting a little
bit of sense of depth.
Two, you're actually going to see
more information about the scene.
This is going to actually be
the way we actually see 3D scenes.