As human beings, we recall and
use information from our own
experiences to solve problems.
The same is true when we're programming.
We must also recall and use information
or data in order to build applications.
As developers,we can do
this by using variables.
Consider the following example.
Let's say I'm cooking tomato soup, and I
have a recipe that makes four servings,
but I want to make more soup than that.
I can define variables that will
calculate the amount of each ingredient
I should use.
For example, this line of code creates
a variable called servingsFactor.
If you read this moving
from left to right,
it says that the servingsFactor is
determined by dividing the desired
number of servings by the number
of servings for the recipe.
Each of the names, or identifiers, used
in this expression like servingsFactor
and desired number of
servings are variables.
And we can associate values with
them that help us solve problems.
And that's exactly what we've done here.
The number of servings for
the recipe is 4,
and the desired number of servings is 8.
Let's say the recipe normally calls for
2 pounds of tomatoes.
If we want to calculate how many
pounds of tomatoes we'll need for
our desired number of servings,
which is 8, we can use this calculation.
We'll take the normal amount of
tomatoes needed for the recipe and
multiply it by the servings factor
that we calculated earlier.
If we print this out we can see that
we'll need 4 pounds of tomatoes to make
8 servings.
Now of course,
this is pretty simple math and
we could probably do it in our head.
But a nice benefit of variables is that
they enable use to reuse expressions and
formulas, for example,
to calculate the amount needed for
multiple ingredients or
on multiple occasions.
Let's say I have my entire family
coming over for dinner, and
instead of 8 servings, now I want to
make 16 servings of tomato soup.
And we rerun our code with
this small alteration for
the desired number of servings,
we can see that we need to use 8 pounds
of tomatoes to make 16
servings of tomato soup.
[BLANK_AUDIO]