And here's an example of it being run in a color image.
What you should see here is that there's this color board in a dark shadow.
Okay? And here's the same color board in bright sunlight.
Right?
And the idea is that in the image, if you actually measured the intensity coming
off of this white square, and the intensity coming off of that black square,
you would actually see the values of 119 in both places.
So objectively, those two are the same value.
But of course, you and I both say that this is white and
this is black, even though they have the same value coming to our eye.
Because clearly what's going on is we're saying, oh that's in shadows, so
I, I recalibrate that.
Well when you run that retinex algorithm that I just showed you,
and by the way, running it in two dimensions is a little bit trickier than
running it in one dimension.
That it says that this thing has a value of some random number 126.
This thing has a value of 175, so it is figured out, that the white square is
brighter than the black square, even though in the darkness, the light square's
going to have the same amount of light as the black square in the sunlight.
Another way of thinking about this is if you take a piece of coal, black coal,
outdoors in the sunlight, and
you look at it, more light is going to be hitting your eye,
coming from that black coal than a white piece of paper, inside your classroom.
Okay?
And yet the white piece of paper looks white and the black coal looks black.
And that's because your brain is computing for
all the stuff that's going on around it.
And this, this constancy, and lightness constancy,
we'll talk about it in just a second, is it's just remarkable.