Congratulations on making it this far.
Think about how many new tools you
have in your developer toolbox for
building better apps.
You've learned how to add
maps to your application and
configure them for
lots of different map types.
You've also learned about how you can
add value to those maps,by understanding
how to move to different places,
add markers to locations of interest,
customize those markers and
draw on the surface of the map.
Using lines and shapes and circles.
You're well on your way
to mastering mapping.
For the next section, you're going
to go even deeper than a map.
And take the user right
down to street level,
using Google street view technology.
So, let's buckle up and go.