A platform which terminates apps on its
own is a pretty radical departure for
anyone like me who cut their
teeth in desktop development.
You start with the onCreate method,
where you build and wire up your UI.
Once that's done,
your activity has been created.
It likely won't be a surprise to
you that there are also methods
when the activity becomes visible,
onStart, and another for
when it gains focus and becomes
the active foreground app, onResume.
That same sequence then
happens in reverse.
OnPause indicates
the activity has lost focus,
followed by onStop when
the app is no longer visible.
Finally, there's an onDestroy method,
indicating the end of
the app life cycle.
When your app is first launched,
it quickly moves through
these three states.
Create, start, and resume,
one after the other.
Within the full application lifetime,
from when onCreate is first called,
until the app is terminated,
it will move to through the active and
visible life cycles many times.
Let's look at those in
a little more detail.