Here's what the finished app
looks like on an emulator.
The main activity uses a RecyclerView
and adapter to display a list of tasks
that have some description and
a priority number, one through three.
Initially, this activity
won't display anything,
because the database will be empty.
But for this example,
I've added a couple of tasks just so
you can see what they look like.
Adding task data will be done
through a separate activity,
which is launched by this plus button.
You may have seen buttons
like this before.
They're called floating action buttons,
since they kind of float above a layout
and perform some action
when they're clicked.
When you click this one, it opens
another activity that lets a user
input a task with some
selected priority.
There's also a color associated
with each priority, red for
the highest, then orange and yellow.
So let's add a new task.
I'll type finish learning Android.
And I'll give it a medium priority,
since it's below say, breathing.
And then I'll click this add button.
This returns to the main screen, and
you can see that the task has been added
to the list and sorted by priority.
So this lands right between breathing,
which is priority one, and
grocery shopping,
which is the lowest priority, three.
Now, you won't start with
all this functionality.
Instead, you'll be given starter code
that includes only the basic UI and
an empty task database and
content provider structure.
And throughout this lesson, we'll be
building off that starter code so
that we can insert and
display tasks like in this finished app.
So let's do a quick walk
through of the starter code.
The todolist data package
has three classes.
First, there's the shell of
the TaskContentProvider class,
which we'll be completing
throughout the lesson.
Then also TaskContract and
TaskDbHelper classes.
And you've seen the likes of these
before in the SQLite lesson.
The TaskDbHelper creates
the databasethat stores our task data,
which you can see here in onCreate.
And the TaskContract class keeps track
of any constants that help us access
the underlying data.
As you can see, right now it contains
the name of our table and its columns.
Outside of this data folder, our
starter code also includes UI code for
AddTaskActivity and
Adapter and our MainActivity.
The MainActivity is going to
set up our main layout code.
And all the layout code can be found
in our resources layout folder.
But let's poke around our main activity.
Inside the onCreate function,
we set up the RecyclerView and
adapter, which are responsible for
displaying the task data.
Lower down, you see that there's
a click listener attached to our
floating action button,
our FAB button for short.
The FAB has an attached onClick
listener so that when it's clicked,
it can launch an AddTaskActivity.
And the add task activity is where
you'll have to write code to
accept user input and
create new task data.
At the bottom of our main activity code,
you'll find the LoaderCallbacks.
And you'll be responsible for
implementing these to retrieve
data on a background thread.
And if any of this code looks
unfamiliar, please take a look back at
Lessons three and four, which go over
RecyclerViews and AsyncTaskLoaders.
So a lot of the UI code is
provided in the starter code.
But if you run it, it won't do much.
Let's try it out.
Here's the starting state of our app.
Nothing will be displayed,
and you can't add tasks yet.
To display tasks and make the add
buttons work with our SQLite database,
we'll be building a content provider and
hooking it up to this UI.
For now, I encourage you to look
around this incomplete code,
look at the XML layouts, and read any
of the comments if you want more detail
about what a class or function is for.
Next, let's see the structure
of our task data so
that we can start building
a provider to access it.