So to help us kind of situate this,
let's actually think of a simple quiz
on, how we can calibrate a projector?
So here basically,
I have a screen that I'm actually
putting a projector in front of.
And of course when I project on a screen
of course the shape of the image would
be dependent on what orientation the
screen is with respect to the projector.
So for example here, the projector might
be a little closer on, on the side here,
of course that's why it's basically
showing you a little deformed image.
Of course our interest is, how can we
automatically get a perfect rectangular
image to display on this projection or
projection screen,
and has the same, and exact aspect
ratio of the original image?
So simply put,
we want to be able to figure out,
how we can actually project this image
that actually shows perfectly same
aspect ratio to fill the entire screen?
Of course, one way to do this would be,
is to move the screen so
it's completely perpendicular
to projection of the projector.
Another approach would be to
actually move the projector, right?
I can just move the projector right
here, perpendicular to this scene here,
and that would actually
create a very good image.
I can move it up and
down a little bit or
a third option that is, how about we
just use a camera to capture the image?
And then use that to
analyze the image and
then transform the image on
the display of the projector
to warp it to the exact dimensions
of the projection screen.
So of course,
choose the right answer here.