So, let's assume we have some sort of a surface normal, okay?
So, here we have our surface normal drawn and it is on a surface, okay?
If we have a point on a surface, we can define two tangents, all right?
One is, if I take a step just in the x direction, there's a question of,
how does z change?
So, if I step in the x direction, no change in y.
Then my change in z will just be the partial z with respect to x.
And so that's negative p.
So tangent in the x direction.
So it's on the surface, let's draw ourselves a little surface here.
Put a point here.
And this is one tangent vector, okay?
Well the other tangent vector we can have is we just take a step headed in
the y direction then there's how the z changes as a function of y.
And that's negative q.
And so that would be another tangent.
So if I want to find the surface normal, that's easy to do.
I just take the cross product of those two directions.
By the way, these vectors they're not,
I haven't made them unit vectors or anything.
They're just taking one, a step that goes 1 in the x direction and
changes however much it does in z, same thing for the y.
So if I want a unit normal, what I have to do is I have take tx cross ty.
So I, remember, the cross product of two,
two vectors is perpendicular to that right?
So I take tx cross ty.
And if I want it to be a unit vector, I have to normalize it by the magnitude.
Okay?
And so, when you take tx cross ty, you get pq1.
And the magnitude of that,
of cour, course, is the square root of p squared plus q squared plus 1.
By the way, so the reason I used the minus partial respect to z.
Respect to x and y.
Is, that allows my normal to be p,q, 1.
If I do it the other way, it would be minus p, minus q, 1.
So, same difference.
So that's the algebraic description of p and q.
And that's important, because we're going to use it.
But it's also important to understand the geometric interpretation.
Because when we reason about multiple constraints,
it'll be easier to think about that.
To do that, I have to introduce something called the Gaussian Sphere.