Let's move now to the kernel level data structures.
First for each process we maintain information about that process.
What are all the kernel level threads that execute within that
process address space?
So what are the mappings that are valid between the virtual and physical memory?
What are the user credentials?
For instance, if this process is trying to access a file,
we have to make sure that that particular user has access to that file.
And then, information like, what are the signal handlers that are valid for
this process.
We'll talk about this a little bit later, but for
now, know that this is information about how to respond to
certain events that can occur in the operating system.
Next, we have the lightweight process data structure and
this contains information for a sub subset of the process.
For instance, it can have information that's relevant to one or
more of the user level threads that are executing in the context of the process.
And keep track of their user-level registers and the system call arguments.
The information that's maintained in a light-weight process data structure is
in some ways similar to what we maintain at the user level in
the user-level thread data structure.
But this is what's visible to the kernel, so when the OS-level schedulers need
to make scheduling decisions they can see this information and act upon it.
Also note that we track resource usage information in this data structure.
At the operating system level,
the kernel tracks resource uses on a per kernel thread basis.
And this is maintained in the data structure for
the lightweight process that corresponds to that kernel level thread.
So if we want to find out the aggregate resource usage for
the entire process, we need to basically walk through all of
the lightweight processes that are associated with it.
The kernel level data structure includes the kernel level information,
like registers, stack pointers, scheduling class.
And it also has pointers to the various data structures that are associated with
this kernel.
So what is the lightweight process?
What is the actual address space?
What is the CPU where this is running?
One thing to note about these two data structures is that the kernel-level
thread structure, it has information about a kernel-level thread,
about an execution context, that is always needed.
They're operating system level services that
need to access some information even when a thread is not active.
Like, for instance, scheduling information if they need to
decide whether they need to activate that thread.
So this information is basically not swappable.
It always has to be present in memory.
Whereas in contrast the light weight process data structure, the information
that it maintains does not always have to be present in memory so.
If we're running under memory pressure, it is possible to swap out this content.
This also potentially allows the system to support larger number of
threads in a smaller memory footprint than what
would've been the case if everything needed to be constantly memory.
Next is the CPU data structure.
It has information like the current thread that's currently scheduled,
list of the other kernel level threads that ran there.
Some information how to actually execute the procedure for dispatching a thread,
or how to respond to various interrupts on the referral devices.
Note that if we have information about the CP and
a given CPU once we know the current thread through it we
can find that information about all of the different data structures that
are needed to rebuild the entire process state.
On the SPARC architecture that is used in the Solaris papers,
there are extra registers, so there are lots of registers.
And the implementation is such that there is one dedicated register that is
used to point to the current thread at any given point of time.
So you're in context which this register is updated.
But what it implies is that it's easy to just access that register and
then immediately be able to start tracking through these pointers to
find the right information.
That's in contrast to perhaps having to access memory to read the CPU
structure to then read the current thread information, et cetera.
Here's how the Eykholt paper on multithreading the SunOS kernel
describes the relationship between all of these data structures.
This is figure two in this paper.
A process data structure has information about the user, for instance
the address space, and then points to a list of kernel-level thread structures.
Each of the kernel-level thread structures points to the likely process that it
corresponds to, to it's stack, and to other information.
The lightweight processing stack.
This portion of the state is actually swappable.
What's not shown in this figure that was showed in the previous image is
any information about the CPU.
And there is some other information,
some other pointers that are not shown here so as not to clutter everything,
like from the thread going back to the process, et cetera.