A couple of quizzes ago,
you used data returned from a route, and
marked it up with HTML and
Handlebars expressions.
This is what the app
looked like at the end.
Here's the store template that I ended
up with after completing that quiz.
For this quiz, you need to create
a Lego brick component that replaces
the content here in this inner loop.
So the code in the inner loop needs
to be replaced with a new Lego brick
component.
With a new component make sure that
the resulting HTML structure looks
like this.
Each color has a section and a heading.
Each brick component has its own
container div with the necessary
classes.
The component then
displays the bricks info.
The on sale class that's used might be
a little tricky when converting this to
a component, check the instructor
notes for some helpful links.
The link to the starter code for
this project is in the instructor notes.
When you've finished, the feedback
extension will give you a code,
enter that code on the next page.
Ember uses the queue
unit testing framework.
And I created a number of tests
that you need to satisfy.
These tests help guide you through
completing the assignment.
Once all the tests have passed, the
feedback extension will give you a code,
enter that code on the next page.
You can find a link to this project's
test page in the projects read me file.