I should mention that, there've been other attempts at not,
the other pieces of work on finding corners.
In fact, Shi-Tomasi did this nice work on, cornerness, and
it, it did something different looking at the lambdas,
instead of using that r, and found local maximums.
And, I will tell you, if any of you who use OpenCV,
they have something called OpenCV Good Features to Track, it's a function, it
finds you points in the image, that are good features to, good points to track.
How does it work?
I'm pretty sure that's the Shi and Tomasi version of this.
It's still based upon the same moment matrix,
it's just a different use of the eigenvalues.
And, there's reports that maybe it's a slightly better way for
things that are undergoing certain kinds of deformations.
There was another one 2005 Brown, Szeliski and
Winder, and I write this one because I've stolen so many of these pictures from
Rick Szeliski's book, I feel like I have to put this in there.
It again looked at eigenvectors in another slightly different way, and
there are other, types of, of corner detectors.