First.
The longer the system is in use, the
more it learns about network activity.
This statement's true, because anomaly
detection involves first learning or
profiling what is normal.
The longer the system is in use,
the better it can learn what is normal.
Second, if malicious activity looks
like normal traffic to the system,
it will not detect an attack.
This is true, because anomaly detection,
detects what looks not like normal.
Therefore, if an attack
managed to look like normal,
then the anomaly detection system will
not be able to detect this attack.
The third statement,
false positive can become a problem,
normal usage can be mistaken for
an attack.
This is true.
Because the definition of
false positive is that,
a normal activity is
mistaken as an attack.
At the minimum, false positives
can waste systems time, because
the system needs to investigate whether
there's truly an intrusion or not.