Okay.
So we've got matching covered.
Let's talk about how to
write the actual rule.
The rule determines whether the actual
match vacation can be read from or
written to.
Each match contains a rule or rules, and
a rule will always start
with the key word allow.
After allow, there are three requests
methods, read, write and read, write.
Allow read will allow anyone
at this location to read.
Same goes for write and for read, write.
Now a rule could be
followed by condition,
such as this condition right here.
And the condition will only activate
the rule if the condition is true.
You're probably wondering
about these conditions.
So we're going to go
into that more next.