You can download the data set
that represents a possible
clustering solution for
our store by climate analysis, by using
the links in the instructor notes.
It's a file called data with cluster ID.
It is basically the data file
of the original data, but
now with the cluster numbers assigned
to each store in a CSV format.
I brought that data into Tableau, which
will make it easy to build out some
visualizations to see whether our
solution seems to make sense.
The first thing I want to do is convert
the cluster over to a dimension,
because it really is a dimension and
not a measure.
Since we are dealing with climate and
weather, the first thing that could make
sense would be to see if the clusters
look different when
looking at them on a map.
We can make use of the latitude,
longitude values by selecting them for
column and row dimensions.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Make sure you select the actual
latitude and longitude values and
not the ones generated by Tableau.
Also remember to uncheck
the aggregate measures.
Now we want to add in the clusters and
let Tableau assign a random color,
to each one so we can visually see the
distinction and where they are located.
We do this by dragging the cluster
ID into the color mark.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
This gives us a really nice
visualization of where the clusters
are located geographically, so
that we can see that cluster one
is primarily in Southern Florida,
and cluster five is mostly in the
Northeast section of the United States.
If you're familiar at all with weather
patterns in the US, just looking at this
map might indicate that the cluster
solution we've created seems reasonable.