Recall the initial sorting phase, or
Phase 1 of the external
memory merge sort scheme.
You first partition the chunks,
and then for each chunk,
you read it into fast memory,
sort it, and write out the result.
In this quiz, I want you to count
the number of asymptotic transfers and
comparisons incurred at each step.
That is, in each of these boxes,
I want you to enter the number
of slow fast memory transfers or
the number of comparisons
aggregated over all iterations.
Enter them symbolically
in the big O sense.
Enter your answer in terms of n, z and L
and maybe other numerical constants, but
ignore f.
F was just some fudge constant to make
sure that the size of the input buffers
fit into fast memory along with any
extra working space we might need.
And just to repeat,
enter your answer as totals taken
over all n over Z iterations.
For simplicity, you can assume that
everything divides everything else.
Or to be more precise, the L divides
f times z, and f times z divides n.
Lastly, assume that the local sort
is an optimal comparison-based sort.