In order to write the reverse_names
function, I'm going to start off
by writing a function that
reverses only a single name.
First I'll split the name on a space,
which should give
me a list containing the first name and
the last name separately.
Then I'll extract the first name and
the last name using split_name at 0 and
split_name at 1.
And finally I'll return the last name,
followed by a comma and
a space, followed by the first name.
Now before trying to apply my
reverse_name function to the entire
series, I'll test it
out on a single value.
I'll use the iloc attribute to get
the name at position zero, and
then reverse that name.
And sure enough, the name Andre Agassi
has been transformed to Agassi, Andre.
Now I can reverse all the names
using the apply function.
Specifically, I'll return names
that apply and all passes and
argument the reverse name function.
And when I call reverse names I
get each of the names reversed and
collected in a panned series.