This was the description of Projective Transformations for 2D coordinates.
It's 3 by 3 applied to the homogeneous.
So xyw gets mapped to w prime x prime, w prime y prime, w prime.
And to go to non homogeneous or inhomogeneous, you divide through by the, the w.
So now I'm going to do just a little bit of the projective geometry that
relates to the homogenous coordinates we've been talking about, and
we'll do that a lot more in the next lesson.
So what is the geometric intuition behind using homogeneous coordinates?
The bottom line is that a point in the image can be thought of
as a ray in projective space.
So what I mean by that is so every point x, y, on the image plane.
Let's change the color here so you can these.
So here we have this point and we're talking about x, y.
Can be thought of as on this ray,
intersecting an image plane that set a value of z equal to 1.
By the way, and I stole this slide from someone, I can't re,
somebody was very clever here.
They wanted positive z to go along the direction of the camera.
So you notice they have x this way.
This is negative y.
So it means positive y is down, and if x to the right and
positive y is down, x to y, means z goes that way.
It was a way of keeping a right handed coordinate system.
Don't worry, you will screw this up.
That's okay.
I ju, in case somebody saw the picture and
wondering why it said that, that's what it is.
Back to our regularly scheduled program.
All right.
So if this point on the image x,y,1 is
just this ray intersecting the image plane.
That means that any point along that ray is on that,
it projects to the same point of the image plane.
And the points along that ray are the scaled sx, sy, and
s, if you multiply by scale.
And remember in homogenous coordinates, sx, sy, and s,
you divide by the s to get out the new x, the new y.
That's the relationship between that homogeneous transformation dividing out by
the third coordinate.
And this notion that a point on an image is essentially equivalent to a ray in
space, coming from the center of projection and intersecting the image plane.
We're going to make way more use of that in our conversation next time.
We're only going to use it a little bit this time.