To get started, let's create a new
C# script called Audio Picker.
And C# will create something that's
extremely similar to a list,
called an array.
Unity also has support for
a type called List but for
the purposes of this video we'll
be using the built-in array.
To declare one for
audio clips we type in
PublicAudioClip [soundfiles].
Just like other variables we've used,
this enables us to assign our sound
files from the Unity interface.
The key difference here
is that these brackets
allow us to assign multiple
audio clips in an array.
While we're here let's create another
variable for an audio source.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now that we've defined our array and
audio component,
all we need to do is
populate the properties.
To do that, we need to define the size
of our array, and then just drag and
drop all of the audio
clips that we want to use.
We also need to drag
in our audio source.
And with that set up, the next thing we
have to do is just pick a random song