From the code example in the
documentation you'll notice that the
DownloadFilesTask class extends async
task, the name is followed by additional
class games in brackets
remember that the brackets indicate that
there are three generic parameters for
the async task. We first learned about
generics when we were building the Miwok
app we created an ArrayList of
vocabulary words and displayed them
using a custom ArrayAdapter the
ArrayList and ArrayAdapter classes
except generic type parameters. The E and T
are placeholders for the specific object
data types that we want to use. By using
generics we can rely on the Java
language to ensure that the right type
of data is being passed into and out of
methods. For example,
whatever data type E represents, it will be
the required data type for input to the
ArrayList add method to add another
element to the list.
If you call the get method at a certain
index an object of type E will be
returned,
this is called type safety, the Java
language enforces type safety by
showing errors if you're passing on the
wrong data type, or if you store the
return value of method in the wrong data
type.
You won't be able to run your app until
you fix these errors. When we use this
generic class, we swapped the generic E
placeholder for a specific data type
like the string class to have an ArrayList
of strings we replace every where
there used to be an E with a string. As a
result we can only add objects of the
string data type to the list.
If we request an item at a specific
index, the ArrayList will return a string
data type. in the MeWork app
we wanted to use a custom data type that
was a little more complex than the
string object. Recall that we created a
custom word class to hold the English
and Miwok translations for a word to
form a list we specified the generic E
parameter to be a word object so we
would have an ArrayList of words,
then when we added to retrieve an entry
from the ArrayList we could ensure
that it was a word object, then we could
call a specific method
on the word object to extract out
English for Miwok translations that
would not be possible if the get method
return a string or a different object
data type.
Similarly, in the Miwok app we use
generics to create a custom ArrayAdapter
of words, we could expect each item in
the adapters data set to be a word
object.
Now that we've reviewed generics, let's
go back to the async task documentation.