Here's how you create a new
project in Android Studio.
First, open up Android Studio.
Then click Start a new
Android Studio project.
As we mentioned in the quiz,
set the App name to be Just Java,
and the Company Domain to
be android.example.com.
This way your code will match our code.
This automatically sets the Package
name to be com.example.android.justjava.
This will uniquely identify our app.
For the project location, feel free to
select any spot on your computer to save
this app, then hit Next.
For the minimum SDK,
we can set it to be Ice Cream Sandwich,
which is API level 15.
This means that our app will run on
Android devices running
Ice Cream Sandwich release or later.
This will target 90% of the devices
that are active on Google Play.
Cool.
So this looks good so let's hit next.
These are the different templates for
creating a new activity.
Let's just choose blank
activity template and continue.
Here we have an option of changing the
default names for our main activity and
our layout and our menu, but
these defaults are fine, so
let's just hit finish.
And now we wait while our
project is being created.
If you run into a rendering problem
here regarding the action bar,
you can simply change
this setting to be 21.
So that the device preview here
will be using API level 21
This is just a temporary fix
until the bug here is fixed.
Then, when you ready,
you can hit the screen play button
to install your app on the device.
I had my Nexus Six device connected so
I can choose to run it on this device.
And, I also click use same device for
future launches so
this dialogue doesn't keep popping up,
then hit OK.
And, this is what it looks
like running on the device.
It says Just Java across
the top in the app bar, and
it says Hello world!, down here.