Another problem is that it could be very hard to do debugging from the test case.
These are very large and or nonsensical,
and so what I mean here is that random test case that triggers a failure in some software under test
might be many bytes long, and it may have no usable human interpretation.
In any of those cases debugging software under test can be really hard and there's the solution for this.
There's is a pretty good solution for this problem but I'll talk about it a little bit later.
A final disadvantage of random testing is that every fuzzer
and the final disadvantage of random testing is that people experience is
that every time you write a new fuzzer, it finds different bugs.
And what this basically means is little incidental design decisions in the random test case generator
explores suddenly different parts of the system under test input to many
and that results in finding different bugs, and this shouldn't be a surprise given the
extreme difficulty of the testing problem, but it's still a little demoralizing
when you spent a lot of time writing a fuzzer.
It finds a lot of bug and you think the system is getting pretty robust.
and then somebody else writes a little simple fuzzer and then it finds a whole bunch of bugs
that you can find and this is very common for that to actually happen.
That's the longest of drawbacks. Any drawbacks are real.
Let's go back and look at the other side of trails.
In the advantage side random testing has less tester bias,
means the testing is less influenced by what I know about the systems implementation
and random testing also has weaker hypothesis about where bugs are.
Maybe that's just another way to say the same thing.
Besides this issue of bias and hypothesis, perhaps the real killer
advantage of random testing is once you implement a random tester
and once you automate the testing process the human task of random testing is basically zero,
and this is surely been the case with the C compiler fuzzing effort that I have mentioned several times
where we really spend a long time developing this random tester.
We worked really hard on it, but since we more or less finished it up a couple of years ago
its been finding on average a bug that too are weak in real compilers would almost no efforts from us.
The machine sitting in dark room somewhere, it's doing random testing but it's running by itself.
It needs almost no oversight, all we have to do is look at the results and write up some bug reports
and this process of turning random test into a bug report
is something that will come back to you a little bit later.
An extremely interesting when your talking about random testers is they often surprise us.
I have the personal experience of being surprise by random testers many times.
And also, in the course of reporting 450 compiler bugs,
I found the compiler developers are often really quite surprised about the behavior of their tool.
Random testing sort of consistently has this ability
to tell us something we didn't know and that's extremely valuable.
And another advantage is that every fuzzer finds different bugs
and so of course, I included that under disadvantage as well.
This is sort of depressing at some variable but on the other hand, this is really cool.
What it means is, we have several fuzz tools,
might as well just bought a couple of course in each of them and more of them likely
because now your going to be that over lap when the bugs are found by the different random tester.
And finally due perhaps to some combination of this other advantages
are at least find random tester to be really fun.
It's fun to have self-automated. It's fun to be surprised about the system.
It's fun to have shortcomings and a logic pointed out
by a process that doesn't have a human involved.
It's just really interesting to have this happen and it's just really interesting that this kind of staff happens.