So if Label L then dominates Label L2,
this is because either
the level is higher.
So, for example, this could be top
secret and this could be secret.
If that's the case, then D1 would
contain more sensitive data than D2.
Okay.
So this actually is correct.
When D2 is dominated by D1,
which is the case here,
because L2 is less than L1,
or L2 is dominated by L1.
It cannot contain more sensitive data,
so the second option is not correct.
The third option says the data
contained in D2 has a narrower scope
as defined by its compartment.
So what exactly does
narrower scope mean?
Remember, categories define what
the more categories the data, at least
the way we define a label comparison, so
that one set contains another set means
this information is about more topics or
more areas or something like that.
So, since L1 dominates L2,
the compartment of L1 has more
elements in the compartment of L2.
Okay, remember L1 compartment,
if I use this notation,
is a superset of L2 compartment.
So in this case,
we know that the categories
that we associate with the data
that's in D2 are going to be fewer.
So that's a narrower scope and
we can say this is true.