A concrete example of
this type of applications
is distributed shared memory.
Distributed shared memory is a service
that manages the memory across multiple
nodes so that applications that
are running on top will have an illusion
that they're running on a shared
memory machine, like a SMP processor.
Each note in the system owns some
portion of the physical memory,
so owns some state, and
it also provides the operations in
that state, the reads and writes.
They may be originating from any
of the other notes in the system.
Also, each note has to be involved
in some consistency protocol, so
as to make sure that the shared accesses
to the state have meaningful semantics.
For instance, when nodes read and write
shared memory locations, these reads and
writes have to be ordered and
observed by the remaining nodes in
the system in some meaningful way.
Ideally, in the exact same way that they
would have been perceived if this was
indeed, a shared memory machine.
In this lesson, using distributed
shared memory as an example, we will
illustrate some of the issues that come
up with distributed state management,
beyond just caching, that we already saw
in the distributed file system lecture.
We will also discuss some meaningful
consistency protocols that
are useful in these kinds of scenarios.
Distributed shared memory mechanisms are
important to study because they permit
scaling beyond the limitations of
how much memory we can include
in a single machine.
If you have a multi-thread application
or in general an application that was
developed with the expectation
of shared memory underneath and
all of the sudden you need to support
work loads that require more state,
you have to add more
memory to that system.
Now, if you look at how the cost
of computer systems is affected by
the amount of memory they're configured
with, you will see that beyond a certain
limit, the cost starts increasing
rapidly, and machines with very large
amounts of memory can be in the order
of half million dollar range.
Instead with distributed shared memory
we can simply add additional nodes and
achieve shared memory
at a much lower cost.
Yes, access in remote memory will be
slower than access in the local memory.
However, if you're smart about how
data is placed in the first place in
the system, how it's migrated across
the different nodes, and what
kind of sharing semantics are enforced
whenever something gets updated,
we may hide those access difference
from the applications so we may
not even perceive there is any kind of
slowdown because they're executing and
distributed in that environment.
One goal of this lecture is to teach you
what are some of the opportunities to
hide these access differences.
Distributed shared memory is becoming
more relevant today, because commodity
interconnect technologies offer really
low latency among nodes in a system.
For instance, these are interconnect
technologies that connect the servers in
a data center and
they offer these RDMA based interfaces,
where RDMA stands for
Remote Direct Memory Access.
That provide a really low latency when
accessing the remote memories and
that really helps address
this particular challenge,
the fact that accessing
remote memory is slower.
Using these advanced
interconnection technologies
makes these remote accesses
significantly better than what they were
before such interconnection
opportunities existed.
Because of that,
distributed shared memory based
solutions are becoming more sustainable.