Firebase Notifications is a tool to
send targeted notifications in your app.
Built on Firebase Cloud Messaging,
Firebase Notifications lets you
send notifications to your users.
As you'll soon see, configuring
Firebase Notifications requires
very little code to get started.
And you'll primarily use the Firebase
console to actually handle sending
messages.
There you have a lot of control.
You can send a notification to
all users, groups of users, or
even just a single user.
You can even use analytics to determine,
which groups of users should
be sent notifications.
For example, you may want to target
just users, who made an in-app purchase.
Perhaps you want to send them
a notification about a special offer.
In order to encourage them to
make more in-app purchases and
have more user engagement.
After sending this notification,
you can then check back in
the analytics console to see your data.
And you can use that data to actually
determine how the notification affected
user engagement.
Analytics automatically records, when
a notification is in the foreground.
When it's received, when it is open,
and when it's been dismissed.
Which provides you in depth engagement
data on notifications sent to users.
So, as you can see
Firebase Notifications and
analytics go hand in hand to
boost your user engagement