[Thrun] This question is about naive Bayes and Laplacian smoothing.
Our training data is a set of movie titles: A Perfect World,
My Perfect Woman, and Pretty Woman.
We also have a song class of song titles: A Perfect Day, Electric Storm,
Another Rainy Day.
Suppose we get a new title, the query Perfect Storm,
and we wish to know whether Perfect Storm is more likely a movie or a song.
Compute for me the following model probabilities:
the probability for movie class and song class,
the probability of the word "perfect" conditioned on the movie class,
the probability of the word "perfect" conditioned on the song class,
and the same for the word "storm."
Please use Laplacian smoothing for this with K equals 1.
Don't compute the maximum likelihood estimate.