Let's take another look at the whole frequency spectrum and
see how we can manipulate it and do different types of things with.
So of course one way we could do is now actually basically can say is,
find me all frequencies in this frequency spectrum that's inside this circle,
and that would be actually some way of looking at what we want to start doing.
Filtering, either, could be low-pass or anything above it.
So, of course, I can now, using this threshold on this spectrum,
look at just the frequencies that are above or below this.
I can create bounds.
So I can only look for high-pass or, in there, just information within it,
or just look for information in the spectrum, just in this band here.
So that allows me to play around with just using the amplitudes and figuring out
which parts of the signal I want to actually be paying more attention to.
Of course we can take the same kinds of things for
phase radiations, and create bands.
And now I in fact just look for information of these kinds of orientations,
the image that are just within this or that.
And now allows me to kind of customize how I do processing,
on which frequency bands or
which orientation bands I want to be actually extracting information out of.
So that allows us to basically change the spectrum and
also reconstruct this on the kinds of information we're specifically looking at.
And again, one of the things we want to look at is,
which sometimes in a signal I may want to pay attention only to core signal.
Sometimes I may be interested looking at the finer signal.
And of course using that,
I can customize my processing to get the right kinds of information out.