Here is my pair of images again,
and my scan line, and I'm extracting from it a very small little window
that is the local image of the specific feature over here
which happens to have a strong vertical structure,
which is nice of localization.
Now I'm comparing this little patch with my little patches in the right image,
and I'm drawing a sum of square difference error,
which is minimized when these two patches look alike.
I'll tell you in a second how this looks like mathematically,
but intuitively we have to pick the place along the random measured search space
that has the smallest sum of square difference error,
which is the one where these two patches just look mostly alike.
This is a space of the scan line in which I search,
often called disparity, and for one location this is actually being minimized right over here.
Here's the basic algorithm for SSD minimization.
We take two patches--one from the left image, one from the right image.
We normalize, so the average brightness is zero.
We then take the normalized image and take the difference.
Then we square the difference. That gives us a sum-of-square image.
Then we can sum up all the pixels to get a single value.
This is our SSD value, our sum-of-square difference value.
All of these operations are easily implemented using the material you already know.
The smaller the SSD value, the closer these two images correspond.
This is a very common technique for comparing what's called image templates,
where your left image is a template,
and you're searching the left image for the optimal template.
As you vary the location of the right image, you can find different SSDs.
You tend to get graphs for the right image.
With an image template, it gives you certain errors.
Sometimes you get a very small disparate error.
That's the place you'll pick for the best, mostly likely alignment.