You've been thinking about scans.
So you should suspect that
you can use a scan somehow,
in order to address this parallel
partitioning problem for quick sort.
Can you see how?
Here's an idea.
Suppose this is our input and the pivot
value is, I don't know, this three.
First, why don't you compare
every element to the pivot?
If you have some auxiliary storage,
you can do all of these comparisons and
record the results entirely in parallel.
For the results, you'll get a 1
if the element is less than or
equal to the pivot and a 0 otherwise.
Now, here, I've written the Boolean
results as 0, 1 integers.
Here's why.
Suppose you do a scan on
this array of 0, 1 values.
What would you get?
Here is the result.
Now, I want you to notice some
things about this output.
First, the last element of the scan
is the total number of elements that
are less than or equal to the pivot.
This is especially convenient,
because it would allow us to, say,
allocate an output array
of the appropriate size.
Here's something else to notice.
In this output sequence, you get
a little bump everywhere you encounter
a new element that is less than or
equal to the pivot.
That's really neat.
It means, for example,
that the elements you want are easy
to spot just by looking at the scan.
You look at a value,
compare it to it's previous value, and
you can see right away, oh, I must
have encountered a new value here.
So just by inspecting the outputs,
we can find the elements we want.
Now, there's a much
cooler thing to notice.
These scan output values that I've
highlighted are both unique and
consecutive.
So what does that mean?
It means, you can use these values
as indicies into the output array.
Think about that for a second.
You can use these scan values to do a
fully parallel right with no conflicts.
So for every element that I want,
there is a corresponding unique integer.
The integers are consecutive and
they range from 1 to 5 which
is the length of the output.
And there is a 1 to 1 correspondence
between the value I want and
its output index.
So let's go ahead and
write those all out in parallel.
Yes!
Let's summarize your scanned based
approach to partitioning with
some pseudo code shown here.
Here, we compute the flags.
Here, we do a scan to get the indices.
And finally, and we do this in parallel,
we inspect the flags.
And if a flag is set,
then we can safely do this output.
And luckily for us, k provides these
unique, consecutive integer addresses.
I hope it's easy to see that this
procedure has both linear work and
logarithmic span.
If it isn't, do not pass go until it is.
Now, this procedure of doing a flag
scan followed by a write is an extremely
handy primitive.
So let's refactor these lines of codes
into a tool that becomes a part of our
algorithmic toolbox.
So I've taken these lines
of code that were here and
I've extracted them into a general
procedure called gather If.
Gather If, as you can see,
takes an input array a of length
n along with a flag array.
Then, it does the scan and finally,
the parallel outputs using
the flags as a guard.
You can now insert this new primitive.
And in fact, I want to introduce
one additional notational shortcut.
Rather than having to write gatherIf,
if you give me an array and
an array of flags then a sub
f will do the gatherIf.
With this new primitive, the original
quick sort algorithm we had been
talking about becomes easy to
write in a very compact fashion.
Let's take a look.
Here's the original quick sort,
and here's the partition step.
Let's replace these
with our new notation.
So here,
I'm computing the flags on the fly.
And then I'm using them as indices
into the original array to extract
just the elements that I want.
Cool beans!