The answer to this question is the it
depends answer that's common in many
systems questions.
Here is why.
We mentioned that in message passing
multiple copies of the data must be made
between the processes that
communicate and the kernel.
That leads to overhead, clearly.
For shared memory IPC, there are a lot
of costs that are associated with
the kernel establishing valid mappings
among the processes' address spaces and
the shared memory pages.
Again, these are overheads.
So there are drawbacks,
basically, on the both sides.
And the correct answer will be,
it depends.
In the next video, we will explain
the trade-offs that exists among
these two types of IPC mechanisms.