This one was a tricky question.
There were two parts to the solution.
One was identifying that the skills
feature is a categorical variable,
and it needs to be broken down
into multiple dummy variables.
That part, Lorenzo did very well.
In fact, I was impressed by his answer.
He said that you only need two dummy
variables to represent three levels.
That was a good catch.
The other part of the solution was that
there are two numeric features
which have different ranges.
And so one of them might
overshadow the other when
fed into a machine learning algorithm.
Lorenzo started on the right track
in terms of standardizing or
normalizing these values.
But the ideal answer I was looking for,
was subtracting the mean and
then dividing by the standard deviation
off the corresponding feature.
That would normalize the values
into a standard range.
Now there are other ways of doing this,
as well.
For instance, taking the min and
max of each feature and
scaling that down to zero and one.
These have their own pros and cons.
So I'm okay with the answer
that Lorenzo gave.
He could have developed his
answer a little bit further.