[Thrun] And the answer is yes, F is independent of A.
What we find for our rules of D-separation is that F is dependent on D
and A is dependent on D.
But if you don't know D, you can't govern any dependence between A and F at all.
If you do know D, then F and A become dependent.
And the reason is B and E are dependent given D,
and we can transform this back into dependence of A and F
because B and A are dependent and E and F are dependent.
There is an active path between A and F which goes across here and here
because D is known.
If we know G, the same thing is true because G gives us knowledge about D,
and D can be applied back to this path over here.
However, if you know H, that's not the case.
So H might tell us something about G,
but it doesn't tell us anything about D,
and therefore, we have no reason to close the path between A and F.
The path between A and F is still passive, even though we have knowledge of H.