For loops are the most common
type of loop in JavaScript.
What makes them different than
the earlier while loop is that for
loops forced you to specifically
define the starting point and
stopping point of your loop.
As well as how your loop is going
to proceed to the next step.
Now you might be saying to yourself, how
is that any different from a while loop?
In a while loop, I had to specify
all of those same things.
Well, the difference is in a for
loop, you have to define all that
upfront in the for statement.
In this example, I have a for loop that
prints out the value zero through five.
Let's look at how it's set up.
For a standard four loop, it requires
the same three pieces of information as
before and each of these pieces
are separated by semicolon.
The first piece is your starting point.
For this example, we have
a variable i that is set to zero.
The second piece is your stopping point.
This is going to tell us when
we want our loop to stop.
In this case, we want the loop to
stop executing once our variable i
is no longer less than six.
If i can no longer satisfy that
condition, then our loop will exit.
The third and final piece of our for
loop is how our loop should
proceed to the next step.
In this example,
we say that each time our loop runs,
we want to increase
the value of i by one.
All right, so that's the setup.
For this next part, I'm going to walk
you though each iteration of our for
loop.
Normally, you don't really
think about or notice how
each iteration of a loop runs,
because your code executes so fast.
So what I'm doing here,
sort of slowing it down for you, so
you can see how the code is going to
be interpreted, as it's being ran.
I've also added this table, so
you can see the value of i
throughout the lifetime of the loop.
If you're ever writing loops and
your loop isn't behaving exactly how
you might expect, doing an exercise
like this can be really helpful.
At the end,
I'll paste this code into the console so
you can see it running at full speed.
Okay, so when our loop starts,
i is set to zero.
Then we check the condition
to see if i is less than six.
If that condition is true,
then we go into our loop.
So, in this statement we're just
going to print out the value of i.
So printing out i equals 0.
Awesome.
So we just finished our
first step of the loop and
now, we need to go look and see how
we've defined to get to the next step.
So, our code jumps back up and
it looks and it says,
okay, we're going to increment i by one,
so i is now one.
Let's check our condition again to make
sure that we want to jump into the loop.
And If i is less than six, which it is
again, it's going to evaluate the true
and we're going to jump back into
the loop or run the statement again.
And now, we got printing out i equals 1.
And we're just going to continue
this process until the condition
i is less than six is no longer true.
So look, we'll increment i by one.
Now it's two.
We'll look at our condition.
It evaluates to true again,
and we print out the value.
So I can just keep running through this,
and eventually, we will get to
the very end where i is going to be six,
and six is not less than six.
So, here we go.
We're at four.
Now, we're moving to five.
The condition's still true.
We print out the value.
Okay, we get to the end.
Now we increment the value
one more time, now it's six.
And when we go to check our condition,
it evaluates to false.
And we jump out of the loop.
Now just to show you our for
loop running in full speed,
here I've got it pasted in the console.
And when I hit enter, boom, we've got
printing out zero, one, two, three,
four, five.
And once we get to six,
the condition doesn't hold true and
we jump out of the loop.