There's actually sort of a problem with vertical least squares.
And the reason I called it vertical least squares is
we're actually minimizing the error in a particular direction, right?
Vertically, with the y.
So for example, that's not even rotation in variance.
So if I get lines that are kind of horizontal, that works okay because,
you know, the points.
But I got lines that are very steep, then as I move off the line a little bit,
I end up with this huge error, which is not really right.
I just moved off the line a little bit.
And that's because I'm using this particular direction.
And of course, it fails totally for vertical lines.
So it's really not a good model, it's not a good noise model for
what we're doing.
So let's develop a slightly better model.
We're going to refer to this as total least squares and
this you've, you've also seen.
So now what we want to do is we want to minimize the distance between the point
xi, y and some line ax plus by equals d, where a and b are this unit normal.
Right? So, it's actually the unit normal in the direction towards the line.
So when you take the dot product of the point, xi, yi and a, b,
that would give you this here.
Okay?
That should equal d,
which is the distance of the point, of the origin to the line.
That's this distance here, as it's drawn there.
And it, to the extent to which that point does not lie on that line,
that perpendicular distance, as drawn here is just ax plus by minus d.
Right? It's supposed to equal these, so
if you subtract d, that's the dot product and that's the perpendicular distance.
At the end of the day, what that does?
Is this gives us this new error function, E.
Pretty straight-forward.
And what we're going to do is we're minimize that error function now instead of
our previous error function.
How do we do that?
Pretty straightforward.
Same thing, we start with out E.
All right?
We're minim, doing a minimization.
We take the derivative with respect to the parameter d,
that's the first one we're going to do.
That generates this equation for us.
We can use that to solve for d and d is just this beautiful ax bar,
x bar is the average of the x's plus by bar.
That's, that's what these terms here are.
Okay. So this, now I've got an expression for d in terms of a and b.
So I can substitute that back in and
I get this kind of ugly expression that we'll make beautiful in a minute.
So I've now plug these in, so there's no more ds in there and look at that.
That now looks very similar to the expression we had before,
except now we've got this these means subtracted.
So if I stack up all my x's, x minus x bars here and y's minus y bar there.
And I'm actually going to call that matrix U because I do.
I can write this whole thing as
Transpose Where h now is just this parameter a, b.
Remember, we got rid of d.
We solved for d in terms of a, b and now we just have to solve for a and b.
Okay. So now that we have an expression for E in terms of U, which is a,
which are known from the x's and y's and h which is our parameter vector.
In order to solve for h, what do we do?
Same thing, we take the derivative of E with respect to h.
Repeat that equation, set that equal to zero and
that should start to look vaguely annoyingly familiar, right?
We have this matrix here, U transpose U,
which is just made up of the x minus x bars stacked up,
y minus y bars stacked up, transpose whatever, times my parameter equals zero.
Remember, what equations equal to zero are?
Those were homogenous equations.
Uh-huh.
All right.
So the solution to U transpose h equals zero.
Well, the dumb solution is set h equal to zero.
We said that wasn't going to work.
Remember, when we did the essential matrix and when we did calibration and
all that stuff.
We said no, since we have everything okay up to the scale factor
what we're going to do is we're going to set the magnitude of h equal to 1.
Now in this particular case, we were going to do that eventually anyway,
because you remember a and b, which was the h is here,
where the components of the unit direction of that line.
So a and b have to be a unit vector, so
we might as well just set the magnitude of h equal to 1.
And so remember, how you can solve that?
You can do that whole SVD eigenvector thing again, so given you transpose U,
you can find the eigenvector with the smallest eigenvalue and
that's your solution to for h.
I'm showing you this as a way of talking about that the right thing to do is
perpendicularly squares.
Here's how you do perpendicularly squares and now the question that you really
should be asking is, why is perpendicularly squares the right thing to do?
Well, it's because we have in mind a particular model of noise.