Now, we're trying to build an artificial intelligence
that can solve problems like this all on its own.
You can see that the search algorithms do a great job
of finding solutions to problems like this.
But, you might complain that in order for the search algorithms to work,
we had to provide it with a heurstic function.
A heurstic function came from the outside.
You might think that coming up with a good heurstic function is really where all the intelligence is.
So, a problem solver that uses an heurstic function given to it
really isn't intelligent at all.
So let's think about where the intelligence could come from
and can we automatically come up with good heurstic functions.
I'm going to sketch a description of
a program that can automatically come up with good heurstics
given a description of a problem.
Suppose this program is given a description of the sliding blocks puzzle
where we say that a block can move from square A to square B
if A is adjacent to B and B is blank.
Now, imagine that we try to loosen this restriction.
We cross out "B is blank,"
and then we get the rule
"a block can move from A to B if A is adjacent to B,"
and that's equal to our heurstic h2
because a block can move anywhere to an adjacent state.
Now, we could also cross out the other part of the rule,
and we now get "a block can move from any square A
to any square B regardless of any condition.
That gives us heurstic h1.
So we see that both of our heurstics can be derived
from a simple mechanical manipulation
of the formal description of the problem.
Once we've generated automatically these candidate heuristics,
another way to come up with a good heurstic is to say
that a new heurstic, h,
is equal to the maximum of h1 and h2,
and that's guaranteed to be admissible as long as
h1 and h2 are admissible
because it still never overestimates,
and it's guaranteed to be better because its getting closer to the true value.
The only problem with combining multiple heuristics like this
is that there is some cause to compute the heuristic
and it could take longer to compute
even if we end up expanding pure paths.
Crossing out parts of the rules like this
is called "generating a relaxed problem."
What we've done is we've taken the original problem,
where it's hard to move squares around,
and made it easier by relaxing one of the constraints.
You can see that as adding new links in the state space,
so if we have a state space in which there are only particular links,
by relaxing the problem it's as if we are adding new operators
that traverse the state in new ways.
So adding new operators only makes the problem easier,
and thus never overestimates, and thus is admissible.