Before we do a quiz,
can we talk about why we care about this
topics, why would our student use them?
>> Oops,
I really shouldintroduce Shelly.
Hi, Shelly.
>> Hi, Dan.
>> Shelly, is going to be
helping teach the class and
providing you quizzes along the way.
Doing these problems is try
the best way to learn the material.
So Shelly, let's talk about problem
solving in game playing and
provide some context for this lesson.
Hopefully, you all are like me and love
to play strategy games, like checkers,
or isolation, or Othello, or chess.
Amazingly, we can use
the same algorithms,
even the same code,
to make the computer player for
a game that's as simple as tic-tac-toe,
or as complex as chess.
In principle,
the only thing that is different
between these games is the code for
generating all the next possible moves,
as well as the user interface.
Minimax is our primary algorithm
to figure out what is
the best move at every turn.
Alpha beta pruning helps
optimize this algorithm,
making the agent play quicker.
>> I see, so tic-tac-toe and chess
are both deterministic games, right?
So the outcome of each move is known.
Can we also use Minimax for
games that have an element
of chance like Backgammon?
>> That's a good question.
For those types of games,
we use a modification of
Minimax called Expectimax.
It considers all the possible outcomes,
and
chooses the one with
the maximum expected return.
This is assuming the opponent is
making the best moves available.
Again, once we have it, this expected
max algorithm can be used for
many different games.
>> Okay, great.
I think I see where we're going now.
>> Good.
Let's get back to that
challenge question.