So we've come to the end of this lesson, and before we move forward,
let's pause and reflect on the things that we have learned together.
I want you to write down everything you've learned in the course thus far.
But, this time, as a blog.
There are many free websites that will let you do that.
Blogger is a popular one, and a link to it is available in the instructor notes.
Here are suggestions on the topic for this blog.
It can be about ideas you've learned in this course.
Or you can write a blog about any one of the how would you
do blank in Swift topics that we have put together.
These topics are also listed in the instructor notes.
Once you're done, you should share your blog with us on the next screen.