Well if you have, you'll notice that this is a panorama.
It's referred to as a planar rect,
rectilinear panorama, where all the lines are still straight.
This is a rotational, spherical, or a cylindrical panorama.
As you notice, it seems to be like if you were at one point,
the whole panorama is rotating around it.
This is referred to as a path, route or a multiview panorama, and
this is somebody driving in a car and actually now stitching slices together.
And of course, it looks like something you'll have best views as
a move from one place to the other.
This is a vertical panorama.
In this case, the panorama is moved up and down, or at least the camera is
moved up and down to capture height of something much larger.
This is not a panorama, it’s a single shot.