As we hinted already with
the discussion of the syntax data type,
XDR specifies both the syntax,
the interface definition language.
So how our data type's described,
and also it specifies the encoding.
So what is the binary representation
of data when it's on the wire?
As we handled already in the discussion
of the string data type,
XDR that corresponds both to
the interface definition language,
essentially that's the syntax.
How we are describing data types.
And also it specifies the encoding.
That's the binary representation of
how is data represented when it's
being transmitted between the client and
the server on the wire.
Here's some encoding rules.
All data types are encoded
in multiples of 4 bytes so
transmitting a single byte argument
would include a single byte for
the data and 3 bytes of padding in
order to make that up to 4 bytes.
This is to help with alignment when
moving data to and from memory and
the network packets and
the network card.
Big endian is used as
the transmission standard.
What this means is that regardless of
the endian in this type, of the client
or the server machine, every type of
communication will require the data
is first translated into big endian
representation and then if necessary,
translated into the appropriate endian
in this for the target machine.
In some cases, this may be pure
overhead just because the client and
the server machine are both,
let's say little endian machines.
But, in principle, it's easier to have
this type of standard agreement so
that there's never any
kind of ambiguity,
what is the encoding that's
being used on-the-wire.
And how to interpret the bytes that
are coming into the network packets.
Other rules include things like,
two's compliment is used
to represent integers.
And the IEEE is used for
floating point numbers, so other roles.
Let's explain this a little
bit better using an example.
So, let's say that in the .x file,
we have a definition of a data type
that is a variable length
array of a size up to 10.
And let's say we have an argument,
hello,
that needs to be passed from
the client to the server.
In the client or
the server address space,
if these are C processes,
this variable will take 6 bytes.
5 bytes for each of the characters and
then the last 6 bytes for
the null terminating character.
However, for transmission, this variable
will be encoded to take 12 bytes.
The first 4 bytes will be used for
the length.
In this particular case,
the length is 5, it's 5 characters.
The next 5 bytes will be used for
those characters, H-E-L-L-O.
Notice we're not going to be
transmitting the null terminated
character.
And then, at the very end, we will
have 3 characters use the padding,
because XDR specifies that everything
needs to be on 4 by boundaries.