We can make sure everything is running
correctly by loading the SpecRunner,
HTML file in our browser.
If we review this page,
called the SpecRunner, we can see some
stuff is already happening by default.
It says the Player should
be able to play a Song, or,
when song has been paused.
These lines are also styled differently.
These are black and these are green and
indented a little more.
Since this is just an HTML page, let's
load this file into our text editor, and
try to figure out exactly
what SpecRunner is doing?
So we see this is just
a normal HTML file.
We're including some
jasmine library files here.
And there's a section called
include source files here.
And another that says
include spec files here.
The source files are all of
your application's files.
And the spec files are our tests.
Let's look at PlayerSpec.js.
Here we go.
Some of these lines should
look pretty familiar to you.
Look at this line,
expect(player.currentlyPlayingSong).toE-
qual(song);.
This looks very similar to the test
you wrote in the previous lesson, but
these lines are wrapped
up in parent functions.
We see this it function here,
it should be able to play a Song.
And if we go higher,
we even see another, describe Player.
Hey, these terms look familiar.
We saw these on
the SpecRunner page as well.