Hope this wasn't too difficult.
Yes, the code is 007.
Now let's see how we got that.
First, convert the images from color to grayscale.
And then use the edge function to compute the edges individually for each image.
Note that I've explicitly passed in canny.
The default is I think sobel, which doesn't work as well.
Canny accepts additional arguments, the hysteresis values and smoothing sigma.
Feel free to play with them.
Here are frizzy's edges.
This is almost perfect.
Note that around the mouth and
nose, where we had thick outlines, we have double edges.
This is expected.
And here's froomer's edges, also pretty good.
Okay. Now what?
Note that edge images are binary images.
Which means you can and them together to find common edge pixels.
And there you go.
You never know what's hiding in an image or two.