The correct answer is the second one.
Both P1 and P2 can have the exact same virtual address space range
from 0 to 64,000 in this case.
The operating system underneath will map P1's virtual addresses to
some physical locations, and P2's virtual addresses to other physical locations.
The fact that we have decoupled the virtual addresses that are used by
the processes from the physical addresses where data actually is makes it
possible for different processes to have the exact same address space range and
to use the exact same addresses.
The OS will make sure that they point to distinct physical memory locations if
that's what's required.