Unit tests are probably
the most well-known test
used by software developers.
They are very useful to test
the low-level functionality
of separate components,
like classes and methods.
They're fairly easy and straightforward
to write, maintain, and run.
So they usually form the largest
part of the overall test body.
In the Agile development process, unit
tests are usually the responsibility of
developers, but this does mean that
the product team has to plan time and
prioritize reading tests, enough so
that the developers are actually
empowered to write them.
If developers are working
under tight deadlines and
are rewarded by feature releases, it's
unreasonable to expect that they will
instead write tests just because
it's a good thing to do.
So while developers are responsible for
writing and maintaining tests,
the whole team is responsible for
giving them the time to do that.
In general, there are three
approaches to writing unit tests.
The first is to write
tests after the code.
Another approach is to write
tests before the code,
which is also called
test driven development.
Option three would be to write no tests,
I guess, but actually scratch that,
that's a very bad idea.
As far as when unit tests get run,
they're still fairly fast.
So they're the next type of test
that runs after smoke tests.
They can also be run on
the development machines,
giving developers very quick
feedback on their code.
This however is only possible
if the tests are written and
committed at the same time
that new code is committed.