At this point, we've covered the basics
of probability theory, so we'll be able
to turn our focus on the algorithms
themselves and their analysis.
Up first is the classic
randomized Quicksort algorithm.
In case you don't recall randomized
Quicksort from a previous algorithms
course, here's the pseudo code.
To keep things simple we'll assume that
the elements to be sorted are distinct.
This is a recursive algorithm with
the base case being a list of 0 or
1 elements,
where the list can simply be returned.
For longer lists we choose a pivot,
uniformly at random
from the elements of the list, and
then split the list into two pieces.
One, with those elements
less than the pivot.
And one with those elements
larger than the pivot.
Then, we recursively
sort these shorter lists,
and then join them back together
in sorted order like so.
The efficience of the algorithm depends
greatly on the choices of these pivots.
I'm going to visualize a run of the
algorithm by drawing out the recursion
tree over here.
I'll write out the list in sorted order,
so
that we can see better what's going on,
though the algorithm itself will likely
have these elements in
some unsorted order.
The ideal choice of pivot is always
the middle value in the list.
This splits the list into two equal
sized sublists, one consisting of
the larger elements, the other
consisting of the smaller elements.
Then in recursive calls we split
these lists into two pieces
until we get down to the base case
of the list of length one or zero.
Because the size of the lists
get cut in half with each call,
there are only login levels to the tree,
and
every level gets compared with
a pivot in a call to Quicksort.
So there are order n
comparisons at each level, for
a total of n log n comparisons overall.
That's if we're lucky and
pick the middle element every time.
How about if we're unlucky?
Suppose we pick the largest
element in every iteration.
Then the size of the list only
decreases one in each iteration.
So they are n levels.
The first level requires
n minus 1 comparisons.
The second n minus 2, and so forth.
So that the total number of
comparisons is an arithmetic series.
And therefore is order n squared.
This is as bad as a naive
algorithm like insertion sort.
The natural question to ask then is,
how does Quicksort behave on average.
Is it like the best case where we pick
the pivot in the middle of each list?
Or is it like the worst
case that we have here,
where we're always picking
the largest element in the list?
Or is it somewhere in between?