A time series that exhibits a repeating
pattern at fixed intervals of time
within a one year period is said to
have a seasonal pattern or seasonality.
Seasonality is a common pattern seen
across many different kinds of time
series.
For example, if you live in a climate
with cold Winters and warm Summers
your home's air conditioning costs
probably rise in the summer and
fall in the winter.
You would reasonably expect
the seasonality of your air conditioning
costs to recur every year.
Likewise, a company that sells heavy
coats would see sales jump in the Winter
but drop in the Summer.
Companies that understand the seasonal
patterns of their business can time
inventories, staffing, and
other decisions that coincide with
the expected change in business.
The US postal service hiring temporary
drivers and workers during the holiday
season shows how a company adapts to
meet a change caused by seasonal demand.