So those of you that are old enough will remember, and
especially if you're from the United States.
You'll remember that for
a while there was this whole bunch of books out there called Where's Waldo.
And they would give you a scene that looked like this on the left, and
your goal was to find.
Here's Waldo right here, kind of blurred out,
hard to see, that would be my template maybe.
And I want to find Waldo.
And if you take a look at this, can every body see where Waldo is?
Well, he's right there, okay.
We go back there, okay, you can see him.
There he is, all right?
So, the question is, how could you do this doing the template matching?
Well, we would do the same thing before.
We take our image, we take our little template, and
maybe you can see over here on this Correlation map, all right?
There's that bright spot right there.
And you'll notice, that everywhere else it's hardly bright at all.
But right there, that's that bright spot.