As stated in the question, there
are actually multiple correct answers
because of a harmless
ambiguity in the algorithm.
Let me give you one possible answer.
It's the vertices c, d, and e.
Let's see how I got that and
where an ambiguity arises.
Initially, the queue F contains
just the source vertex S.
So the first time you test whether F is
non-empty, F will contain the vertex S.
Now after extracting S,
we visit the neighbors.
In this case,
the neighbors are just B, C, D and E.
Notice that they're all unvisited.
So the algorithm will update their
distances and then insert them into F.
The ambiguity is the order in which
the vertices are updated and inserted.
That will affect the order in
which we later extract them.
Now from a correctness point of
view that doesn't actually matter,
this ordering.
Now let's just walk through an example.
Suppose we really did update and insert
the vertices in the order shown, b, c,
d and e.
And assuming F is a FIFO,
first in first out queue,
then the next extraction
will first pull out b.
Now the vertex b has just
one outgoing neighbor d.
D has already been visited so
in this iteration of the while
loop nothing else will happen.
That brings us to the third
execution of the while condition.
In that case F contains c, d, and e.
Okay so that assumes that we
inserted them as b, c, d, and e and
extracted b first.
What if we had instead
extracted c rather than b?
Then you should be able to convince
yourself that the contents would be
this instead.
It's the vertices b, d, e and a.
As it turns out,
this ambiguity is a feature, not a bug.
We'll, in fact, exploit this ambiguity
in designing a parallel algorithm,
which is the reason for this quiz.
That is,
the quiz is not designed to torture you.
It's actually designed
to teach you something.
Imagine that.