So can you think this through?
>> I think I can think this through.
So when we did the last one,
you did a kind of derivation.
I didn't really talk about how I came
up with the answer that I came up with.
But I did it basically just by
substituting a few things in my head and
seeing if it worked out.
So when we did the multiplying
one I said, well,
all you're doing is
multiplying R of sa times c.
And since the sum of all those T
of s of a, s prime times the max
of a primes of those Q's, is really can
be unrolled as a series of rewards.
That means all you're doing is
multiplying all of those rewards by this
constant C,
and so I could take it out and that's
how I ended up c times Q of s of a.
I think there's a similar argument here.
See if this argument makes sense to you.
If we took the equation up top and we
said, what's Q prime s of a, equal to?
Well, it's equal to R of s, a plus c.
>> Right.
>> All we're doing is adding a c.
And then inside that sum, if we
unroll the Q's it's just going to be
a series of all the rewards that we see.
Each time adding up a c.
And so we can sort of separate out
the adding of the c each time.
And the problem with that, is that each
time it's being multiplied by gamma.
So what we're seeing is a bunch of Cs
added over and over and over again.
I mean, an infinite number of times,
potentially.
But each time, multiplied by gamma.
Then gamma squared, then gamma cubed.
But that's okay, because we
actually have a formula for that.
>> Good.
>> It's the geometric series.
>> Yes.
>> And that's just 1 over 1 minus gamma.
>> The sum of the gammas is that.
>> And then you multiply by c.
>> There we go.
All right, so you're saying that
the new Q function should be essentially
the same as the old Q function,
which is already kind of gathered
up all the rewards, the R rewards.
But we need to modify it by
this infinite sequence of Cs.
Which is C over one minus gamma.
>> That is what I'm saying.
>> Awesome.
>> Is that right?
>> Yes.
So, let's do the proof.
So again, the trick is going to to be,
we are going to to write out the Bellman
Equation for Q prime, substituting in,
our guess for Q prime and our definition
of R prime and then see if it works.
All right, this is the thing
that we need to be true.
If the rest of it is true.
That is to say,
if it's the case that the new Q function
is just the old Q function, then
shifted by this c over one minus gamma.
Then we need this equation to be true.
So this is true, if and only if what?
Well we have this c over 1 minus gamma,
inside the max,
getting added to this Q,
s prime, a prime.
How does that influence the max?
>> It doesn't effect it at
all as long as c is positive.
>> Even if c is negative, actually.
>> Oh you're right.
>> Because it doesn't depend on a,
at all.
>> It's a constant.
>> It's a constant so,
we're adding this constant to all
the different pieces of the max.
So then the actual max we get into
the end of that is going to be
whatever the max was before,
plus the same constant.
So we come out of the max, but
we're still inside the sum with
the transition probabilities.
So what happens to the transition
probabilities here,
is this gets multiplied by this,
just before.
Plus, it's also getting multiplied
by this, but this is a constant,
it doesn't depend on this prime or
anything like that.
And the sum that we're taking
is a bunch of coefficients and
all of that up to one.
So really, this whole piece here is
going to get promoted all the way out
of the parenthesis.
With the only difference that it's
going to get multiplied by a gamma.
So, what we really got
here is a c plus c gamma
over one minus gamma on this side, and
a c over one minus gamma on this side.
So in fact, here, let's do this,
as a step, this is true if, and only if,
this is true, which I got by subtracting
from both sides the solution to
the original Bellman Equation.
>> Right.
We've got this Q,
we got the R, we got this thing here.
And all that's left are these c things.
So is this true?
>> Yeah.
It is.
>> And why is that?
>> because you multiply
everything times one minus gamma.
Oh, good idea.
[LAUGH] So this is true if,
and only if, this is true,
where we've multiplied
through by 1 minus gamma.
And this is true.
>> Right, because?
>> Because we've got
this c on both sides, and
we've got c minus gamma and
a c plus gamma.
No, sorry, a negative c gamma and
a positive c gamma that cancel.
>> Right, so c=c.