Okay so there are different
answers to this question
depending on how you solve the problem.
Let me show you my solution first, and
then I'll talk through how you may
have come to a different conclusion.
I'm iterating through the URLs and
adding two .thens for each URL.
The first gets the JSON data and then
the second creates the planet thumbnail.
As for each iterates through
the array of planet data urls,
the sequence gets longer
by two thens each time.
Each .then will need to wait for
the promise before it to
resolve before it can execute.
There's some good news and
some bad news.
The good news is that the planet
thumbnail show up in the right order.
The bad news is that
it's happening in series.
You can pretty clearly see that each
request depends on the one before it
finishing, but you might have seen that
all the thumbnails show up and found
that it was in parallel, and if so, I
bet your code looks something like this.
Notice that this time I'm not actually
adding to the sequence, rather,
I'm simply adding two
thens which quickly get
overwritten by the next
iteration through the loop.
Luckily, these two thens stay
attached to one another, and so
they continue to execute.
If your code looked like this,
then you probably saw
the request come in like so.
They're in parallel and
the problem is that there's
no guarantee about the order.
And to be honest for many
applications this is completely fine.
You can handle ordering in
other ways with your front end.
But if the order that promises
resolve is important to your app,
this kind of code could easily become
a subtle source of bugs later.
Browsers can request many
resources simultaneously so
it makes a lot of sense to run
code like this in parallel.
But if you want to do so,
you probably should where it's really,
really obvious that your requests
are happening in parallel.
In fact,
you'll be doing that in the next quiz.