So, you might say, woah, didn't we already do this?
We did the ideal perspective projection, where we said that some value
u was just going to be the focal length times x divided by z, and v was,
was y divided by z multiplied by f, as well.
So you might ask, aren't we done?
Well, no, because that would be in some idealized world.
The first problem going back to here is, f might be in, you know,
millimeters, so we might have a ten millimeter lens, or a 50 millimeter lens,
but the pixels, the screen pixels, they're in some arbitrary coordinate, right?
That depends upon exactly how many pixels we get per millimeter in the sensor.
So the first thing that happens is that we introduce an alpha that's just
going to scale that value, because we don't really know what f is.
Now sometimes people will give you an f,
a focal length, in pixels, which is kind of a weird thing.
But what they're actually doing is,
they're giving you this combined value that is sort of the conversion from
millimeters to pixels times millimeters, just given to you, and pixels.
But basically, because they may be in some arbitrary units,
we have a scale factor alpha.
So that's one degree of freedom.
But, who said the pixels are square?
Megan, did you say pixels are square?
No.
Now, it turns out pixels are more square now than they used to be.
They used to be cool and now they're, nah, never mind.
Anyway, pixels are more square now than they used to be.
The used to be, back in television, more of television days,
pixels had the same aspect ratio as actually a television.
So a pixel was wider than it was tall, and
some other things, they were taller than they were wide.
They weren't necessarily fixed.
In fact, even some CCD arrays that I calibrated once,
it turned out that well, it was almost square.
It was like 95% of the height was equal to the width, all right?
So because they're not exactly square, you might have a separate scaling factor
between the u direction and the v direction.
And so now we've introduced beta.
So now we have two degrees of freedom.
But we're not done.
Next, well you remember we put the center of projection,
when we were doing the ideal projection.
We put the center projection right at the camera coordinates system.
As if the image was taken so that zero, zero was right in the middle.
But of course, we don't have any guarantee of this, right?
The image may have been cropped out of a a section of the window.
Or the, the location of the image actual sensor might need,
might not be lined up with the optical axis of the camera.
So we have two offsets, a u and a v offset, u0, v0.
So now we're up to one, two, three, four degrees of freedom.
Two scale factors and two offsets.
Are we done yet?
But wait, there's more.
Here comes the really ugly one.
We're assuming that the u direction and
the v direction are actually perpendicular.
What if there's actually a little bit of a skew?
So u and v went out drinking one night, and
they came back just off a little bit, all right?
So that's what's shown in this figure here.
The idea is that the ideal u and v are this way, okay?
But maybe the sensors actually sampled that way and that way.
That is, that the, the actual sampling of u,
v is not perpen, are not perpendicular, and they're off by some angle theta.
So that's what these equations are showing you here.
They're showing you the relationship between the v-prime which is measured and
the actual v, the u-prime and the actual u.
And so, when you substitute those into those equations we just had,
you get this sort of ugliness, okay?
So this is the really ugly extrins, sorry, intrinsic parameter representation.
And now we have, how many?
Well we've got an alpha and a beta, the two scale factors.
That's two degrees of freedom.
A u0 and v0 for the two offsets.
Plus theta, which is the skew