No I'll show you something else that's really cool. Since we know that the
sample statistics often aren't exactly what the population parameters are, we
might want a confidence interval for the true correlation. In other words, a
range of likely values for the population correlation coefficient rho. I used
the statistical program R to calculate confidence intervals for Pearson's r,
using this data. For the correlation between age and time you arrive at a
party, the 95% confidence interval went from negative 0.3995, to positive
0.0914. And for age and number of pets, this ranged from 0.1369 to 0.5733.
Based on these Confidence Intervals, what could you logically conclude? What
would be your statistical decision for each?