So we know that the Phrases
activity screen broke
with the most recent code changes.
So let's go back and
review what we just did.
In the WordAdapter class,
we added this block of code to display
the correct image in a list item.
So it's probably acting weird when we
called the setImageResource because
phrases don't have an image.
So here's the answer
to the first question.
The problem with the Phrases activity
is that the screen is blank.
The WordAdapter assumes that
the word has an image, but
phrases don't have images.
So, moving on to the second question.
There are several possible
solutions on how we could describe
the way we should modify or
code to fix the problem.
We could have written a specific adapter
called PhraseAdapter that would know
exactly how to create list item views
that contain just two text views and
no ImageView.
So the PhraseAdapter would have been
just used in the PhrasesActivity.
Whereas the WordAdapter could have been
used in the other three activities.
However, this solution involves a lot
of duplicate logic in both adapters.
We would have the same logic to handle
displaying both the English and
Miwok translations.
So, why don't we just stick with
the single WordAdapter class.
So we can modify the WordAdapter
class just slightly so
they can create list items both
without an image and with an image.
And then we can use the single
adapter in all other activities.
So you'll notice that the
PhrasesActivity has the same layout for
list items as the other
three activities,
except that there's no ImageView.
So the text just shifts
slightly over to the left.
I also gave you a hint in the quiz
that said that you can hide or
show a view in Android
while the app is running.
So knowing that, does that mean that we
can show an ImageView in a list item in
some cases, and
hide the ImageView in other cases?
Here I am in Android for
All documentation looking
at the if/else statements.
Now, if you remember from lesson
three in the last course,
we learned that our code can
behave in different ways
using something called
control flow statements.
This means that we can go
down different paths of code,
depicted here as the train tracks,
based on certain test conditions, so
depicted here as the switches.
Now for the number, family and
color words, we can go down one path.
But for the phrases,
we can go down another path.
More specifically, how does that
translate to our code or for
the number family and color words?
We want to execute this block
of code that's used for
setting the correct
image on an ImageView.
But for phrases, we want to go ahead and
just skip this logic and
instead hide the ImageView so
it doesn't show anything at all.
So let's write that answer into
the second question on our quiz.
So asked to describe how to modify
our code to fix this problem.
We can modify the WordAdapter so that we
only assign an image to the ImageView
for number, color, and family words.
But for
phrases we can just hide the ImageView.
Well, I don't know about you but I'm
not too happy with this answer just yet
it's still really hard
to translate into code.
We need to think more about how we can
determine which category a word is in.
Now, if we go ahead and
take a look at the word class, one way
to go about this is that we could add
a new variable that keeps track
of the category for each word.
But ultimately,
we just need to know whether or
not we should hide this ImageView.
Now, remember in the word class
we already have a field for
the image resource ID.
And when I say field,
that's just another word for
global variable of a class.
So in order to determine whether we
should hide or show the ImageView in
a list item, we can check whether or not
the constructor has set this ImageView.
So I'm going to go back and
update my answer to this quiz question.
So instead,
we can modify the WordAdapter so
we use and if/else statement.
If there is an image associated with
the word object, show the ImageView.
Otherwise, hide the ImageView.
And there we go.
That's a lot more helpful
when we need to write
the code to make this change.
So the previous answer
was just too vague.
All right, so knowing this,
let's move on to the next step now.