Here's the movie manager.
Let's take a look at what it can do.
This first screen should look familiar.
It's like the login screen from last
lesson, however in this lesson we're
going to use a new auth flow
that's similar to OAuth.
OAuth's an authentication
standard that focuses on.
Our apps not having to collect
usernames and passwords.
And you can see here there's no
username or password field anymore.
Using this off-flow is going to
be great exposure for us,
because it's like OAuth.
And OAuth is so
commonly used by other APIs.
If we tap the button then this web use
display, and we can either allow or
deny the app access to our user data.
In some cases you may not see this
screen first because you have to log in
through the website so
you may be presented with a username and
a password except this
time it's in a web view.
In either case,
once we get here we'll tap allow so
that we can actually access the app.
Once we're in,
we have another tab view controller.
And you can see here at the bottom we
have a movies tab, a watchlist tab, and
a favorites tab.
On the movie tab, we can search for
movies by name so
I'll start searching for one of my
favorite movies, the school of rock and
as I'm typing, you can see that
the table view updates automatically.
This is really slick.
And then when we tap it,
we're presented with this detail view.
On the detail view you've
seen this button before,
this is the favorites button and
then this button here will allow you
to add the movie to your watch list.
So I'll go ahead and add school of rock
to my favorites and to my watch list.
And then rather intuitively I can
go back to the watch list tab and
school of rock's been
added here at the bottom.
And then if you look
at the favorites tab,
it's also been added to the bottom here.
And that's the app.
Let's go build it.