For approach one, where we have a single reference in a student course.
The problem is that using this scheme a student can only take one course.
So for the second approach a vector of references to students in each course,
this solves the first problem.
But it makes it hard to find the courses taken by a student.
That is you have pointers from courses back to students but
you don't have pointers from students to courses.
And the third option was to have an association class.
And the disadvantage here, as I indicated a moment ago,
was that there's an extra step involved in doing any kind of traversal,
which might have a performance hit.
And finally, the symmetric Vector approach in which there are vectors in
each instance of the student class and each instance of the course class is
perfectly general, but it may lead to referential integrity problems.
That is when a student drops a course, we have to make sure that you remove
that particular reference in the student class but also in the course class.