So the correct answers are the hypercube
and the fully connected network.
First remember that we're assuming P=n.
So for this example picture
there are 16 processes.
Notice that the first eight
processes have to exchange data
with the second eight.
Therefore you need a network with
a linear or better bisection width.
In this case,
a hypercube and fully-connected
networks are really your only options.
In fact, a fully connected
network is probably overkill,
because it has many more
links than you actually need.
A hypercube, on the other hand,
is a pretty good fit.
Can you see why?
Just think about how you
build hypercubes, and
how that compares with
the basic pattern of exchange.
By the way, there's another kind of
network topology called a butterfly
topology.
The butterfly network is
exactly this picture.
Butterfly networks remind me of
an old joke about Europeans comparing
the word butterfly in their
various native tongues.
What is wrong with Schmetterling?