Here's what I calculated.
The calculation, itself,
is not very interesting.
It's basically just plugging and
chugging numbers.
In this case, n is 2^50 bytes divided
by 2^8bytes per item or records.
So, that's a total of 2^42 items or
records.
Similarly z is 2 to the 28th records and
l is two to the seventh records,
so plug those values in,
round to three significant figures and
you should get these numbers.
The more interesting bits
are the numerical improvements
relative to the baseline of n
login equals 185 terra ops.
One big improvement comes
from reducing n to n over l.
This factor is really about ensuring
that, when you make a pass over the data
you do so in L size transactions,
as much as possible.
The other big improvement comes
from going from log base 2,
to log base z over l.
Now, when you calculated this you may
have used the following handy fact
about converting logs.
Log base z over L of x is
log base two of x divided by
log base two of z over L.
This improvement involves
the capacity of fast memory, z.
So this win comes from ensuring that
your algorithm utilizes the fast memory
capacity, z,
to the greatest extent possible.
Okay, one last remark.
Now these speedups, are notional.
When we do algorithm analysis we usually
do it in an asymptotic sense, and so
there's always some
other hidden constants.
The main point is to build your
intuition about how performance changes
as you change the algorithm to
improve with respect to L and Z