looking at a grayscale image i see
breakpoints dark points and all the gray
in between rapid changes in brightness
are where we find the edges are image is
just a mathematical function of x and y
so we can perform mathematical
operations on it just like any other
function for example we can take its
derivative which is just a measure of
change of this function a small
derivative means small change derivative
big change images are two-dimensional so
it makes sense to take the derivative
with respect to X & Y simultaneously
this is called the gradient and in
computing it
we're measuring how fast pixel values
are changing at each point in an image
and in which direction they're changing
most rapidly computing the gradient
gives us thick edges with the candy
algorithm we will thin out these edges
to find just the individual pixels that
follow the strongest gradients well then
extend those strong edges to include
pixels all the way down to a lower
threshold that we defined when calling
the candy function