As your user progresses through
the steps in the checkout process,
your app needs to send
an analytics hit for each step.
However, you only need one checkout hit.
So subsequent steps in the checkout
process, send checkout option hits.
So that you don't over report
the number of checkouts.
And use the setCheckoutStep
method to set the step number.
And you can set the number
to whatever you want, but
it only shows up in the checkout
behavior analysis report in
the google analytics dashboard
if you set a funnel step for it.
If i set the step in the code to 99, but
I've only labeled 4 checkouts steps in
the admin console, I will never see
the 99th step in the dashboard, so
that's just not a good idea.
That's better.
So go ahead and add a second step to
the checkout process for the dinner app.
For that you're going to
need a payment button.
So add another button to the order
dinner screen labelled payment.
And in the order dinner activity,
add the method to get the payment info.
Then send a step two hit to analytics.
Make sure to set the action
to an ACTION_CHECKOUT_OPTION.
Show the payment button
only when relevant and
hide the other buttons when
the payment button appears.
Test your app and try it out.
And in the analytics dashboard,
look for the realtime activity.
And in the realtime activity,
check for the events.
See, here's the Get payment step.
It might take a good amount of time
after you see the realtime hits for
the checkout behavior
analysis page to update.
But when it does,
you should see your new payment step.
Oh, something went wrong.
I got a hit for getting the address,
but not forgetting the payment details.
That's not what I wanted.
Okay that happened because step
one is starting checkout and
step two is getting the address.
Step three is getting
the payment details.
That's easy to fix for now.
Go to Admin > Ecommerce, and
I'm just going to remove
the Get address final step.
Yep, I'll delete this rule.
And submit, and go back to Reporting,
and look at that.
The get address step is gone,
and I've got my payment details.
And I know that that is correct,
in this case.
An alternative would be to change
the step number to three in the code.
But then we would be
skipping over step two.
So we would have values here,
nothing here, values here.
So when you set your check out step in
the code, you need to make sure that it
mapped the correct final step
in the analytic dashboard.
So make sure step two is in fact
the payment step, and if not, fix it.
So go ahead and do these steps and
check the boxes when you're done.