So far, our shiny new application
class does absolutely nothing.
Let's fix that.
We can give it a method
called StartTracking
to activate analytics tracking.
You can use the Google Analytics class
to get a Google Analytics instance,
like this.
When you've got the GoogleAnalytics
instance, you can create a new tracker
by calling newTracker in
the config file for the tracker.
It'll look like this.
If you call your tracker config file
something else, other than track_app,
then be sure to use the name of
your tracker config file here.
And you can see here that I used
mTracker as the global variable
to store the newTracker.
Next, you're going to need to
initiate auto tracking and
you do that by calling
enableAutoActivityReports.
It's your turn now.
Try out a couple of methods in
your new application class.
First, define the global
variable mTracker, and
then implement startTracking.
You're going to need to check if
the tracker already exists and
if it doesn't, then you can create it.
While to implement the method getTracker
to return the tracker, be sure to check
that the tracker exists and has been
activated before returning it, and
check the boxes when you
are done doing these things.