So for our last question,
I was hoping we could do
another simple Python method.
Let's say I give you
an array full of integers.
And I give you a number.
Let's call it k.
I want you to tell me if any two
numbers in the array add up to k.
Cool, okay, so
this is like an algorithms problem.
It's probably going to be a little
bit trickier than the last one.
>> Yep, this one's trickier.
>> Okay, so we have this list or
array and it has, I guess,
do we know anything
about how large it is?
I guess not really.
>> Just that it has n elements.
>> Okay, cool, that's okay.
And it returns, I guess,
the indexes of the two
elements that may or may not?
>> Sure, sure.
>> So let's think.
>> Or if it's simpler,
we can just start with saying,
does it have two numbers that up to k?
>> Okay, so to start with,
just as brainstorming,
I'll think about the different
potential ways to tackle this problem.
So you know the obvious solution is
to do like a nested for-loop thing,
where we compare every element to every
other element, and we do that for
every element so that you're looking at
every single combination of things and
to see if they add up to k.
>> How many combinations are there?
>> I guess that is n times n, n squared?
>> Mm-hm, it's o of n squared.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, cool.
>> So usually when you
come up with an algorithm
that involves something like that, it's
probably not the best way to do things.
So I want to put my thinking cap now and
see what else I can come up with.
>> Okay, cool.
>> Let's see.
So, I'm trying to see if we
can make a simpler problem,
so we can come to a dynamic
programming solution or
a recursive of like a subproblem
I can solve that's easier.
Let's see, hm.
So I guess one thing you could do
that's maybe less space-efficient.
Hm, let's see, yeah, okay, so, I'm going
to, is it safe to assume that I have
a library of good data structures
like a hash table or set I can use?
>> Yep, yep, definitely.
>> Okay, so
I guess what I could do is I'll
kind of sketch out the more
abstract idea before I code it.
So I could kind of iterate
through the array in order.
And as I go I can kind
of record what number would go
with this number to make it work.
For instance, I'll do an example.
Let's say our list is 2,
4, 7, 3 and k = 9.
So if I iterated through
this array in order,
I could say we've seen the number 2, so
if we see an eight, then we're done.
So I'll put that into my set, or I could
have like a hash map or something.
>> If we see an eight, we're done?
Yeah, so, I'd put this into a set,
so I know I've seen the 2 so
that means if we, sorry, I mean seven.
So if I, so if we later on encounter
a seven, then we can stop there.
>> Okay.
>> So I'll put into my set a seven.
And then we'll move on to the next
digit, or the next item in the list.
Let's use our happy bracket syntax so
we know what we're talking about.
So I come up to a 4.
I can do a little subtraction to say,
okay,
if we see a five down the road,
then we know that that's our other pair.
So I'll put my five into the set.
>> And at the same time we're
checking that 4 is for 7 or 9.
>> Yeah, so we'll do like
a membership test like when this set.
>> Okay.
>> And then we can,
good catch, by the way.
And so then we continue our iteration
because 4 wasn't a member of the set.
And so we get to 7, and so
we first do our membership check.
Then we see that there is a 7 here,
so we know 7.
We can return 7 and we can get
the other number in reverse, but
it's like k minus seven is two.
So that's our second pair.
So yeah,
that's the outline of the solution.
>> So tell me the runtime now.
>> Okay, so
there's a few moving parts here.
So of the outer level, there's this
iteration through the list of n items.
So it's o(n).
>> Next up,
in each step we are doing an insertion
to the set which involves hashing it.
>> Okay.
>> Which,
I should have studied ahead of time.
Let's see, inserting into a set.
What's the runtime?
>> So, quick question,
is this just a list or
is this a hash map that you're doing?
>> It's a hash map.
>> Okay.
Yeah.
Yeah, because I'm pretty sure I remember
that they were testing for membership in
like a list or an array would be an o of
n time, but we can do it faster here.
Like I think it's log of n.
So I think insertions and checks are
both log of n, if I remember correctly.
>> It's o of one.
>> Really?
Well that's even better.
That's why I went to the set, obviously.
[LAUGH]
>> [LAUGH]
>> And so we
have this o(n) cycling through
plus the set operations.
We have the checking
if it's a membership.
And so that is some o(1) at each step.
So that's times n.
So, I guess, altogether,
the entire thing is o(n).
>> Okay, and can you tell me
how much space we're using up?
>> So the original list is n elements
long, the set, I guess, is also n big.
So, I guess, the size of
the whole thing is order of n.
>> Okay, all right, great.
Let's start writing up how
this would be in Python.
>> Okay, cool.
Let's see, I'm going to work over here.
So, I guess this function is called,
we'll just call this,
it's really abstract,
I'll just call it func.
And it takes in two inputs.
It takes in the list named l.
And it takes in k,
which is our sum we hope to find.
>> Okay.
>> So first I'll make this set.
Let's see, do you want this to be
strict Python or can I do like?
because I don't know the actual
the how to create a set.
I think-
>> It's a dictionary.
You said wanted it to be a hash map,
right?
>> Okay, yeah, well,
I guess Python has two.
It has it's dictionary type,
and also has a set type.
>> Let's use dictionary.
>> Okay, cool.
So, first we'll make our set.
We'll call it set, and
we'll just make it empty dictionary.
And then we can get into
the meat of our solution.
So, let's do this for-loop.
So it will do for n in l.
That's an l.
I should use distinct characters,
I guess.
So for each element in this list of
integers, we will do two things.
We will say if it's in set, then
there's, we need some text for that.
So, wait, no, let's see.
So we want to see if this number is the
complement of a previously seen number.
Remember that step?
So, if-
>> K minus.
>> Yeah, if k- n, that's in set,
then we can return,
then we return k- n, and then,
and we'll turn those into tuple.
So return n, k- n.
So if it's not in the set,
we insert it into the set.
So, in that case, we just put, or
we don't put insert into the set,
we insert its complement, like we said.
So, So,
else, we'll do, let's see.
These are, should be square brackets.
And just to mark that as a member of
the set, we'll set this equal to true.
>> Okay.
>> And I guess if we reach
the end of the function and,
I guess we need to do the check.
Let's see.
So we see if it's in the set,
if not, we put it in the set and
then we continue on.
So I guess if we make it through
to the end of the array and
we haven't come up with anything,
there is no paired return so
we'll just return none,
which is the default to that behavior.
>> Okay, all right, perfect.
So now can we dive a little bit deeper
into how a hash map is working?
So this is a dictionary.
So, how do we match a key
to a value in a hash map?
How does that whole process work?
>> So
that process relies on a hash function.
So, a hash table,
I'm going to erase our previous work
now that we've got it concretified.
Okay, so a hash map is,
I guess, or dictionary or
whatever you want to call it.
You can diagram it like this, where
you have keys and values of k and v.
And so the idea is when we
insert something, like a value,
like k of n, that's an integer.
So we run that through
the hash function.
And the idea of the hash function
is it can take any kind of input,
like any value, and
it maps that into some other value.
And the idea is of all
the inputs can take,
it makes an even distribution of
values so that when you do look it up,
there's just hopefully this
one thing in this bucket.
So, say k of n was equal
to this 2 example.
Let's see, so
2 gets hashed into some string,
some hash value like so [INAUDIBLE].
And that corresponds to
a bucket in this thing, so
let's say our hash value was 72.
And that would be our value true here,
yeah.
>> Okay and so,
what happened when you're looking up 2?
>> So when you're looking up 2, you run
it through the hash function again.
That gives you the hash value.
And this is basically like an array.
So we go to, and looking up a thing
in array, if you know the index,
is like an o of one operation.
So you go to, for instance,
the 72nd element in this array, and
here's our value.
>> Okay.
>> So
this is a simplification obviously.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah, clearly.
So, can you explain to me why, maybe
as far as a developer is concerned,
were you able to get constant time out
of this in look-ups and insertions?.
Yeah, so the hash function
itself is an o of one thing.
So the process of looking up
a thing in this array is o of one.
The process of hashing
a value is o of one.
So that's why you can
look up in this time.
And it's kind of the reverse for
insertions.
You just hash the value.
You go into the table.
And there's complications
if there's a collision.
I don't know how much detail
you want to get into today.
So for insertion it's like
you hash it in o of one,
then you insert elements
into this array.
And that's, writing is also o of one.
because you don't have to iterate
through it or anything like that.
>> Okay?
Yeah.
>> All right,
last follow-up on this question.
And your answer is great, but
let's say we're in a super memory
constraint environment and
I don't want you to use a set at all.
>> Okay
>> How would you solve it now?
>> Okay, man,
[LAUGH] okay let's see now,
my default style is to use these-
>> All you get is l.
You can modify l as you wish.
I don't want you to create a new
data structure, let's say.
Okay, that's interesting.
So when you say that I can modify the l,
that leads me down the path of
thinking dynamic programming,
like I can use the array to,
kind of like to record my progress.
So let's see, let's go back to
thinking simple solutions and
we can work from there.
Let's see, soo, So,
the initial naive solution of the nested
for-loops, the o of n squared thing that
works in this constrained
environment you just described?
>> Right.
That works.
>> But I have a feeling you're going for
something a bit more sophisticated.
So let's see.
So that's why I was thinking the dynamic
programming sort of angle on this.
Let's see.
>> So what was the fundamental reason
you were using a set in the first place?
>> I guess I wanted to, I needed to keep
a record of values that I had seen so
that I would be able to recognize future
ones that corresponded to those values.
>> So you had a really fast
way of searching for a value.
>> Yeah.
>> Can we replicate that behavior,
maybe not at the same speed,
but without using any data structure?
Yeah, let me see.
So, my first thought when you're going
down this path is that maybe you could
use the indexes of the different spots
in the array in an intelligent way.
But the tricky thing is if
you are re-using this array,
you don't want to overwrite parts
of it you haven't seen yet.
So that's an inherent constraint
to this problem that I'm seeing.
Let's see, so yeah, let's see.
>> So if you were in your
double for-loop solution,
what you were doing was, for
each element, you go and search for
the next element that matches it,
or that's the converse, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Is there any way we could speed up
that search bit?
Is there some modification we can make?
>> So I guess, initially, this list
is like a random list of integers.
>> So we could do an in-place sort
on that, so we have an ordered list.
>> Okay, how long does that take?
>> That's a n login for
any good algorithm.
So let's assume reason
Python's built-in.
So we got that,
we have a good n login sort.
And then, I guess, and
then how do we use a sorted list?
Okay, so
we still need numbers that add up to k.
So I guess what we could do is,
this might not be the best,
but my initial idea to use a sorted list
is you look at the first element, and
you say, for instance, it's a one and
we're trying to add up to seven, so
we need to find a six in this list.
So I determine if there's
a six in the list.
So we can do like a binary
search on this list.
So start in the middle and
binary search until we find a six or
find that there is no six.
>> Okay, how long does that take?
>> That takes a login.
>> Okay.
>> So I guess the, and
then you'd have to do that search for,
if it wasn't the first one,
you'd have to go into the next one.
You'd have to do a bunch of these login
searches and login to these searches,
conceivably.
So that entire solution,
this vague idea of a solution, I guess,
comes down to an n login sort of thing.
>> That's the time?
Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> And the space?
>> And the space, because we're
using the array itself, it's size n.
We're sorting it in place, which is
hunky dory, so we're still a size n.
And I guess there's some constant
size but basically size n.
>> Okay, cool.
So, we're not adding any new data,
and we're adding a login extra.
All right, cool, perfect.
>> All right,
that was really interesting.
Thanks for the guidance along the way.
>> No problem, you got it.
>> because it was fun.