[Thrun] As usual, we can resolve this using Bayes' rule.
Probability of Perfect Storm given movie times P of movie
divided by the same expression plus this expression for the opposite class, song.
Here I simply write 3 dots for the text Perfect Storm.
Plugging in the values over here and assuming conditional independence,
as is the case when I use Bayes, we get the probably of "perfect" given movie,
which is 3/19 and "storm" given movie, 1/19, times the prior over half,
and we divide this by the same number plus probability of "perfect" given song,
which is 2/19, and the probability of "storm" given song, which is 2/19 times the prior of half.
Now, all the enumerators fall out, and we get 3 over 3 plus 2, which is 3 over 7.