Before we go on, let's look at again the Traditional concept of how a film or
a digital camera work and
what’s different with respect to it in computational photography.
Now to some extent I would argue that computational photography now encompasses
even traditional in film photography, because it provides a little bit more for
general framework for all of it.
We looked at this whole concept of a Novel Camera which basically is
generalized optics, sensor, and processing.
Let's think about this in a little bit of a general form.
In essence, a Lens is used to focus light onto a sensor.
This could again be film or digital Sensor, you know like CMOS or CCD.
We'll discuss of course in detail what both of those are in a future lecture.
But as Lens focuses this on Sensor, basically what we do is we use that to
convert it into pixels to create an image.
Now this is the same pipeline that exists for
any kind of photography in general, not just the computational.
Can take the same pipeline, and now actually come up with a general concept.
Here, we have you know,
a Generalized Set of Optics, not just one Optics lens itself that moves around.
But perhaps a controlled set of Optics.
So the light goes through and now it's controlled and bent into a different way.
This is not traditional Sensor either, but
a Generalized Sensor, which does a lot more.
Can sample arrays again.
Remember the examples we looked at in the previous lecture by controlling how or
what kinds of light would go through by controlling an aperture by
a modulated aperture array.
Using this we can actually now generate a novel form of
a computation pipeline to process the input that's coming in.
And from there on, generate a novel image, light field array, we'll talk about
light fields a little bit, or other types of newer images that may be possible.
Same process, same pipeline, just more allowed in terms of
what can computation do at each and every aspect to generate novel images.