Let's go through them, all in turn. So the first one, is pretty close but it
produces one extra string. And that extra string it produces is the empty
string. So that's not equivalent to this set. It has one extra string in it. The
second one is a equivalent. It produces as least one Z, and then from the Z star
zero or more Z's in addition to that which will produce this whole set. The next
one is also equivalent. It produces Zero more zs from here, either zero or one z
from here, and at least one z. So the sum of that is at least one plus zero or
one plus one or more, which is one plus any number of extra zs. Exactly the same
as this set. The next one is not equivalent. For example, it can't produce the
single z string. It only produces strings with an even number of zs. This last
one is equivalent. It must produce at least one, because of the z at the
beginning. Then it can produce any number of even number of zs from this zz star
expression. But then from the z question mark, it can add one to that or not add
one to that. That produces all strings in the set of one or more zs.