Because the save for later feature will
have its own page where customers can
view items they've saved for later, a
new entry in the router will be needed.
The save for later check box will
be added to the item template but
the page that lists all items that have
been saved will need its own template.
So a new template will
need to be created.
I'll come back to services
in just a minute.
Just like the template the items
controller will have a new property to
track if it's been saved for
later or not.
But the save for
later page will need a controller.
The save for later information will be
used by several templates, the product
page, an individual item page, and
the save for later page itself.
Since all of these need access
to the same information,
we need a service to
keep track of everything.
Then we'll let each template's
controller have access to that service.
Our app is already housed
inside of a module, so
we'll just add our new feature
to the existing module.
So this feature used almost all of
the concepts we'll be looking at
in this course.
As you're learning each new concept keep
in mind what it should be used for and
how they all fit together.