Requiring users to use strong passwords
can be implemented in different ways.
You can check for it only the client
side with JavaScript, but
that would be very insecure.
As the client could work around it if
they figured out a way to mimic the HTTP
request sent from the browser.
If we make sure that an insecure
password cannot be saved in the server,
then we effectively prevent our
user from making weak passwords.
But they won't figure that out until
the server responds with an error.
We could implement a solution
that is user friendly and
secure, however, by doing both.
Informing the user on the client side
if their password is strong or not.
And then preventing weak passwords from
being stored on the server site as well.
Securely storing passwords has to
implemented on a sever site in
the database where the passwords reside.
And protection from man in the middle
attacks has to implemented on
both sides.
Since sensitive information can
be coming from both the client
and the server.
Let's see in the next video how
using third party authentication
simplifies implementing
these concerns for us.