The answers are that speech recognition
can be handled quite well by supervised learning.
That is, we have input/output pairs;
the input is the speech signal,
and the output is the words that they correspond to.
Analyzing the spectral emissions of stars
is an example of unsupervised clustering
where we're taking the input data--
we have data for each star, but we don't have any label associated with it.
Rather, we're trying to make up labels
by clustering them together,
giving them to scientists,
and then letting the scientists see:
Do these clusters make any sense?
Lever pressing is a classic example of reinforcement learning.
In fact, the term "reinforcement learning"
was used for a long time in animal psychology,
before it was used in computer science.
And elevator controllers is another area
that has been investigated,
using reinforcement learning
and, in fact, very good algorithms--
better than the previous state of the art--
have been made, using reinforcement learning techniques.
So the input, again, is a set of state/action transitions;
and then the reinforcement is--
in this case, it's always a negative number
because there's always a wait time.
And so that's the penalty--we're trying to minimize that penalty,
but all we get is the amount of wait time that we're trying to minimize.