We just talked about
texture filtering and
how that lets you draw textures
at whatever size you want.
However check out these buttons
in your operating system.
No matter how big they are, they always
have these nice rounded corners and
the same smooth gradient on the sides.
If we created these buttons by
simply drawing the same texture
at different sizes,
they would look stretched out and
the corners wouldn't
maintain their nice curves.
The way buttons are drawn and
actually this entire window is
using what's called a NinePatch.
So if you look at this window, there are
four corners that don't stretch at all
and then there's four edges that do
stretch, but only in one direction.
Finally, there's the middle or
the contents which we'll have
to stretch in both directions.
Four corners, plus four edges,
plus the middle equals nine patches.
So, to make a nine patch you
take a stretchable image,
like this one we're going to use for
GigaGal's platforms.
And then you draw four
lines across it like so.
Now we've got our nine sections, the
four corners that don't stretch at all,
the four edges that only
stretch from one direction, and
then the middle that
stretches in both directions.
Now we can draw this nine patch at
whatever size we want and the edges and
corners will never distort.