Another interesting case when we have multi CPU systems and threading
support at the user and the kernel level is related to synchronization.
Consider the following situation.
We have one user level thread T1 running on
top of one kernel level thread on one CPU.
And this thread currently has a mutex.
A number of user level threads may be blocked, but
then on another CPU, currently a user level thread T4 is scheduled.
Let's say this thread T4 actually needs to log the same mutex that's
currently held by T1.
Now the normal behavior would be to place T4
in that case on the queue that's associated with this mutex.
That's what we saw during our earlier discussion about threads and concurrency.
However, on a multi-CPU system, it's possible to have this situation.
The owner of the mutex,
the one that's currently executing the critical section, is running on one CPU.
And when we request that same mutex from the other CPU,
it is possible that by the time we take this thread, T4, and
context switch it and place it on the queue that's associated with this mutex.
In that amount of cycles maybe the critical section here is very short and
T1 will actually complete its execution.
If that is the case if the critical section is short then we
are better off if the thread that needs the mutex.
Actually just ends up spinning on this CPU.
Just burning a few cycles,
waiting a little bit until T1 actually releases the mutex.
If it takes less time for T1 to release the mutex.
Were better off spinning than actually picking a thread, context switching it,
and queueing it up on a mutex queue.
Super short critical sections don't block spin.
For long critical sections we will have the default behavior where a thread is
actually properly blocked placed on
a queue that's associated with a mutex until the mutex is freed.
We call these kinds of mutexes which sometimes result in the thread to spin and
other times it result in the thread to block adaptive mutexes.
Clearly these only make sense on multi-CPU systems, since whether or
not we spin is going to depend on whether the owner of the mutex,
like in this case, is actually running on the other CPU.
In a single CPU system, that definitely won't be the case,
so then it doesn't make sence to consider the use of adaptive mutexes.
Early on, when we first introduced mutexes, we said that it is useful to
maintain some information about the owner of the mutex.
These adaptive mutexes are one example of how such information can be useful.
When we try to lock a mutex.
If the mutex is currently busy, we can look quickly who the owner of the mutex
is, and then verify whether that other thread is running on another cpu.
That will tell us whether or not we should spin or block.
Clearly we'll also need to have some idea about the kinds of
critical sections that are used with this mutex, so as to determine whether it's
likely that the owner of the mutex will release it quickly so
we can spin, or not, and in that case we need to block.
And at the end, I want to make some final points about destroying threads.
Once a thread is no longer needed, so once it actually exits,
it should be destroyed and its data structure, stack, etc.,
should be freed.
However, since thread creation takes some time,
like data structures need to be created and initialized, it makes sense to
reuse these data structures, essentially as if we're reusing the actual threads.
The way this is done is when a thread exits it's not immediately destroyed,
the data structures are not immediately freed.
Instead the thread is marked as it's on a death row.
And periodically a special reaper thread will perform garbage
collection which means that it will actually go ahead and free up all of
the data structures that are associated with the threads on the death row.
If a request for a thread comes in before the thread has been properly destroyed
from the death row then its data structure and stack can be reused.
And this will lead to performance gains since we don't have to wait for
all the allocations.