So, my background is in particle physics-
>> Mm-hm.
>> Which are characterized by like,
huge streams of data that we have to be like, sort a grocking as they come in.
And one of the realities of that situation is that basically,
we're producing much more data that we can actually write to disk.
>> Mm-hm. >> So, in real time, we have to decide whether to write an event, or
to like throw it away and wait for the next one to come in,
because we can take like, a fraction of a percent of our data.
So, we have to have these like dedicated setup like hardware software systems,
that can do like super like, low latency,-
>> Wow. >> Decision making-
>> Mm-hm. >> To try and decide, whether we're going to write it down or not.
We call it a trigger, but that's one of the reasons I'm so
excited about this, I was like, oh, it's a trigger for like, real stuff.
>> Oh, yeah. >> [LAUGH] Not just particle physics.
Yeah, so we use this, we use this all the time.
This is like our bread and butter.
>> How much data did you produce?
I mean in terabytes or in petabytes-
>> Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, we do, we write, we produce 40 million a second.
>> Mm-hm. >> Right, a 100 a second and I think each event is tens of megabytes.
>> Oh wow.
That's a lot data.
>> So, yeah. It's huge amounts of data.
>> Mm-hm, mm-hm. >> Yeah, yeah.
So, we have, we're cheating a little bit because we have dedicated hardware and
sensor systems.
>> Mm-hm. >> Set-up to be super super fast.
>> Mm-hm.
>> But that is a >> [INAUDIBLE] much more flexible.
>> Yeah but but with those sensors, the sensors as tools.
Fixed the data somehow.
Because they're just tapping into all those instruments and
all the various things.
Once you tap the data.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Then, you run through some kind of data time pipeline.
Something like a storm or probably our dedicated systems.
>> Yeah, I mean the other this is,
is that it's a big complicated thing and things break.
>> Mm-hm. >> So, you also need to be running analytics on the machine because
there's a sensor that might go down and you need to detect that right away.
>> Mm-hm. >> because it can shut down the whole machine.
So, that's another sort of side project [INAUDIBLE].
>> Like monitoring those sensors itself.
>> Exactly. Exactly.
>> Yeah, mm-hm.
So, that's pretty cool.
>> Yeah.
>> So, anybody else encounter any new real-time systems or.
>> Well, [INAUDIBLE] we do front detection.
>> Fraud detection.
>> Wow, okay. >> So, we do see malicious behavior online, in real time.
And, as soon as somebody's doing something suspicious or
no, anomalous, we should stop that from happening.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So, that's kind of like in the seconds, milliseconds domain.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah, that, that's super-cool.
I mean, I do [INAUDIBLE] kind of a location information also,
location history also, of where people buy things.
Right, so, if there a pattern is beyond that, whatever the history that you
have seen, then immediately you would figure something, whether to, so do,
go to the latency of, whether you in the, loving the courage card to go through,
or it's just only for the red [INAUDIBLE].
>> So, it's not just necessarily credit cards.
>> Mm-hm. >> But also wired money out to a different person.
>> Mm-hm. >> That could be stopped.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Day or two to clear the money.
>> Mm-hm. >> And there's plenty [INAUDIBLE].
>> But, you can. >> We start to this wire or you know, to, to, to [INAUDIBLE].
>> Okay.
Yeah, that's pretty interesting, definitely.
>> Yeah.