Well, a Shell Command and
a Python Function have a lot in common.
They're both units of code,
they both have a name,
and they can both take arguments.
But, they exist in pretty
different contexts.
Most commands that you run in
the Shell are actually whole programs
that are started up as separate
processes on your computer.
>> Like Carl says, running a Shell
command in your terminal is a lot like
calling a function in a program.
But the two techniques
are used in different ways.
Functions are used to organize a program
while Shell Commands are used to
run programs.
Since Shell Commands output their
results in text, it's easy to read and
understand what's going on.
You can run a command,
see what the result is, and
then decide what to do next.