Remember our concepts of using kernels, to help us do this.
In this case, let's actually build two kernels, one in the ver,
vertical direction and the other one in the horizontal direction, and just for
the sake of the completeness, here actually basically given you the values
where a and the one fourth, number here, one fourth minus a over 2,
in both directions, again, symmetry, in v and symmetry in h, using this,
of course, we basically now should be able to compute this, this is a concept
laid out in Berton Adelson, and I refer you to that paper for more details.
In this case, a values basically are computed to be the following,
by Berton Adelson, and of course, now using these, horizontal and
vertical kernels we can actually create an h which would be
the kernel we want to use to doing any kind of processing, and
this is what was used, as an h function to compute all of this.