First, web server can be attacked
by any web site that it visits.
This is true.
As we have discussed, we can not
authenticate all websites, and
even if a website is authenticated,
it may still have vulnerabilities.
Second, even if
a browser is compromised,
the rest of the computer
is still secure.
This is false,
because if a browser is compromised,
it can lead to malware
installation on the computer.
Third, web servers can be compromised
because of exploits on web applications.
This is true.
The security vulnerabilities of web
applications can lead to attacks
that deface websites or the backend
servers can be compromised as well.
For example, credit card information
can be stolen from the backend servers.