So now we have this 128 vector.
And also remember we've been smoothing by these Gaussians so
the middle has more weight.
In fact, and I mentioned this before in order to make these things work,
we ensured smoothness.
In fact I think in, in Davy Lowe's work,
they originally talked about sort of trilinear interpolation.
What they meant, was that.
Points get smooth and they contribute not only to bins they,
they actually overlap the histogram bins a little bit.
And that way each pixel corresponds multiple times, is, is used multiple times.
In different gradients and also they, they vote in to adjacent orientations.
The details don't matter, so much.
But what it means is, is that if you get a small shift in where
this neighborhood of eight by eight, or 16 by 16 pixels lands.
You don't get, a large change in the scriptor.
And that's really important,
because when you re-localize a point from one image to the next,
you're not going to land, you may not land in exactly the same spot.
So the smoothness allows you to get a very slow change,
in the descriptor as you move just a little bit.
And that's really important.
This also is why I said it takes effort to make these SIFT libraries function.
One of the things you don't want to do is remember.
The magnitude, of the gradient.
I mean I'm not sure I said this.
That the, that it's weighted by the,
the gradient, it's actually a weighted magnitude gets used in the histogram.
Well, a problem with that is, if something has very high magnitude.
It's going to dominate the votes, or
it's going to dominate the descriptor in a way you might not like.
And so, one of the things that they advocate doing is after you
rotate your normalize the rotation,
clip the magnitude of the gradient to some maximum, okay?
So you don't let it get more than a certain amount.
Talks here about point two, the which one you use is a function of
your know imagery but the idea is that it gets clipped.
The second thing that you do in order to prevent any sort of illumination change
from really, harming you is that you take this 128 long vector and
you normalize it to be magnitude 1.
And that way if, if more gradient vectors show up because you scale everything.
Essentially things are better behaved,
because you're going to be comparing these descriptors one to another.
And you want them to be, sort of a similar magnitude.
So by normalizing to one, they're all exactly the same magnitude.
And it's just the distribution within that vector that gets used to,
to compare them.
I suspect that has function of exactly how you do the comparison.
If you were doing dot product kinds of things,
the magnitude normalization might matter a little bit less.