For the majority of Android
developers out there,
the concept of performance is
the last thing on their minds.
Most app development is a mad
sprint towards getting features in,
making the UI look perfect, and figuring
out a viable monetization strategy, or
a lack thereof if you're
in Silicon Valley.
But application performance is a lot
like the plumbing in your house.
When it's working great, no one
really notices or thinks about it.
But when something goes wrong,
suddenly, it's everyone's problem.
You see, users notice bad performance
before any other features in your app.
Before your social widgets,
awesome image filters, and
how one of your supported
languages is Klingon.
And guess what users unhappy with
performance give bad reviews
at a higher percentage than any
other problems in your app.
This is why we like to
say that perf matters.
It's easy little side of performance
as you're developing your app.
But frankly perf is involved
in everything you do.
Users feel bad performance.
They complain about bad performance.
They uninstall your app, and
then vengefully give you a bad
review all because of performance.
When you think of it this way,
performance sounds more like
a feature that you should focus on,
rather then a burden that
you have to put up with.
But in honesty, improving performance
is a really tough thing to do.
Fixing these problems means knowing why
it's slow, which means knowing how to
use the right tools in the right
ways to get insight into that data.
>> But don't worry.
Everything in this Udacity course has
been specifically built around helping
you know the tools,
see how problems manifest in them,
and understanding what they
mean from a theory prospective.
Basically, it's everything that you
need to become a performance ninja.
I'm Colt, this is Chris,
let's get started.