When it comes to 6-DOF tracking,
things aren't simple.
There isn't some standard sensor that
we can use to quickly figure out where
things are located.
In fact,
it's an area of ongoing research and
it's something that I personally
find very fascinating.
Almost every high end VR
headset uses a different
kind of optical tracking system.
But there are all kinds of other
approaches that can also be used.
There are tracking systems
using magnetism and acoustics,
that are also very variable.
And even among the optical tracking
systems, there is a lot of variations.
In short, there is a lot of
work being done to improve our
ability to quickly and accurately detect
the positions of objects in 3D space.
Let's talk about how the major
6-DOF tracking systems work.