All right.
So let's go through the solution.
So here I've written as if I only had two points, point 1 and
point n with a whole bunch of points in the middle.
Okay.
So I've got the matrix A times m equals 0.
How big is the matrix A?
Well, it's 12 across.
Right? Because there are 12 ms and how many rows does it have?
Well, it has 2 times n, where n is the number of points.
So it's a 2n by 12 matrix.
M is just and m by 1 vector and here's the 0 vector of length 2n.
Okay?
So now let's talk about solving that.
One step at a time here.
All right. So here's our goal, right?
We said, we want a unit vector that minimizes Am.
A unit vector for m that minimizes Am.
So let's do what's called the singular value decomposition and
I'm going to assume that you've seen that before, at least some place.
But the idea is that any matrix can be decomposed in
to this UDV transpose format where V is a real orthogonal matrix.
So in our case, it would probably be a 12 by 12.
U is going to be a much bigger matrix.
It says, orthogonal, but I should, can be more precise.
Each column's orthogonal to each other, so
that would be, in this case a 2n by 12.
And most importantly, D is a diagonal matrix.
So it only has values in the diagonal and
it is customary to write it in decreasing order of absolute value.
So from the biggest D to the smallest, all right?
So we're going to write A is equal to UDV transposed.
So minimizing Am is the same as minimizing UDV transpose m.
Got it?
So far nothing significant other than you have to
use your singular value decomposition code from Matlab.
Here comes the first little bit tricky part, that is that the magnitude
of UDV transpose m is equal to the magnitude of just DV transpose m.
Why?
Well, these are just unit vectors.
Right? The U's and V also for
that matter are made up of orthogonal unit vectors.
So multiplying them doesn't change the magnitude of the matrix and
that's why these magnitudes are the same.
And it's also why the magnitude of m
is equal to the magnitude of the transposed M.
For those of you who think about such things,
V in this particular case is a orthogonal.
In this case, 12 by 12 matrix.
You can think of it as like a rotation matrix.
So when you rotate a vector, you don't change its magnitude.
So the magnitude of m is the same as the magnitude of V transpose m.
So that means instead of minimizing UDV transpose m,
we can just minimize DV transpose m, subject to,
instead of being subject to m equals 1, subject to V transpose m equals 1.
Got it?