So let's talk about
security in Firebase.
Taking a step back,
when we say security, we can divide
this up into three subcategories.
Authentication, authorization and
validation.
We discussed authentication
in version 0.3 of
the app when we added the ability
to log in using Firebase.
Authorization is about controlling
access to your data by specifying
who has read write permission and
to what objects in your database.
Authorization is often used in
conjunction with authentication.
This is a fancy way of saying
you can have somebody log in and
then only allow them to look at
information related to them,
such as limiting the list of
shopping lists they can access.
The final form of security, validation,
is used to check that the data conforms
to some expected standard for
the structure of the data.
For example, validation rules
can specify exactly what
properties a shopping list
object can contain, or
verify that an e-mail address
contains an at symbol.
Lyla was worried about either herself or
somebody else adding these unnecessary.
And in some cases malformed feels
to shopping less plus plus.
Given that, which of these three topics
should we start talking about to
solve that issue.