Forcing all processes to see the exact
same order on all updates may be
an overkill.
For instance, P3 and P4 here may
perform completely different in
independent computations
with the values m1 and m2.
And furthermore, the update to m2 had
nothing to do with the value of m1,
they were also completely independent.
However, if we take a look at
the second example, before the value
m2 was written, the value of
the memory location m1 was read.
This means that there is potentially
some relationship between the memory
location m2, this particular update
to the memory location m2 and
this update to the memory location m1.
Given that this read operation that was
performed at P2, just before this write.
Return the value of this write operation
that happened on processor one.
There is clearly some flow of
information, some potential dependence
between these two updates that
happened on two different processors.
Based on this observation,
clearly it is not okay for
these two operations,
this m2 update to y and
the update of memory location m1 to x to
be perceived in this different order.
It would be very incorrect for
somebody like P4 in this case to observe
that the value of m2 was updated to y
before the value of m1 was updated to x.
P4 here thinks that m1 is still zero and
then it finds out that m2 became y.
But there is dependence between
the fact that y was written to m2 and
the fact that x was
already written to m1.
So clearly,
this is not a reasonable execution.
It will be very difficult for software
to understand what is exactly happening
with the memory if it cannot reason
about dependencies like this.
However, in this case,
with such dependence did not exist.
It will probably be okay for
us to tolerate this kind of reordering.
The consistency model that provides
exactly this kind of behavior is
called causal consistency.
Causal consistency models guarantee that
they will detect the possible causal
relationship between updates.
And if updates are causally related,
then the memory will guarantee that
those rights, those update operations
will be correctly ordered.
What that would mean is that in this
situation where the two updates
are in fact correctly ordered,
we have to make sure that every
processor observes that the update
of x to the memory location m1
happened before the update of
y to the memory location m2.
So we have to make sure that on P4,
this first read of the value of
the memory location m1 returned an x.
In this case, this execution will
be causally consistent given this
particular relationship
between the updates.
For writes that are not causally related
or they're referred to in causal
consistency as concurrent writes,
there are no guarantees.
Causal consistency doesn't guarantee
anything about such updates and they may
perfectly legally appear in arbitrary
orders on different processors.
Just like before, causal consistency
also makes sure that the writes that
are performed on the same processor will
be visible in the exact same order on
other processors.
Again, it would be too much of
a challenge to understand how to really
reason about a system if the updates
from a single processor can be
arbitrarily reordered.