Okay, so in that last video
you made a new task here.
The ACTION_CHARGING_REMINDER task.
And that task increments
the charging reminder.
And then sets up that notification.
And you also made
WaterReminderFirebaseJobService.
Which often the main
thread executes that task.
And also cleans itself up effectively.
The next thing that you now have to
do is actually schedule that job.
So to do that I have actually made
this class called ReminderUtilities
which I'll open up now.
And the whole point of this
ReminderUtilities class
is to hold a method
which schedules my job.
Before I get into the nitty gritty
of that I'm going to add a couple of
constants at the top.
The first constant I have here
is REMINDER_INTERVAL_MINUTES.
Which is the number of minutes I want
the job to wait before it starts.
Next, I have this
REMINDER_INTERVAL_SECONDS.
Which uses the timeUnit class to
convert the minutes to seconds.
Finally, I have a constant
called SYNC_FLEXTIME_SECONDS.
Which is the number of seconds of leeway
you want to give your execution window.
And finally, I'm going to add one
more constant, REMINDER_JOB_TAG.
Which is the unique tag that's
going to identify my job.
And I'm also going to make one variable.
Which is going to be
a private static variable.
And also, I'm going to make one variable
which is a private static boolean
called sInitialized.
And the point of sInitialized is just to
keep track of whether the job is started
or not.
Okay, now I'm going to write the method
of this class that actually starts
the job.
And that's going to be called
scheduleChargingReminder.
This method is going to be synchronized.
And that's because we never want
this method to execute more
than once at a time.
Inside of this method,
the very first thing I'll
do is check if the job
has already been set up.
And if it has I am going to return.
Otherwise am going to make a driver
which is equal to a new Google Play
driver.
Then I'm going to make
a FirebaseJobDispatcher object.
And I just need to pass in that driver.
So now let's actually schedule this
job with all of the constraints.
So we're going to make a new job
called constraintRemainderJob.
And we're going to set it equal to
something that the dispatcher builds.
First I'm going to set the service
to my job service that I just made.
Next, I'm going to set the tag
to the tag that I just created.
After this I am going to start setting
the constraints of my job service.
I'll then set the constraints so
that the job service only occurs
if the device is charging.
And because I want the job to
execute basically forever.
Even if the device restarts.
And because I want the job to
execute basically forever.
Even between reboots.
I'm going to set the lifetime
to lifetime forever.
And I'm also going to
tell the job to recur.
Okay, now I need to define how
often this job is going to be run.
So I'm going to use
the settrigger method and
basically make a window of execution.
And that window's going to be
between REMINDER_INTERVAL_SECONDS.
And REMINDER_INTERVAL_SECONDS plus
those FLEXTIME_SECONDS that I defined.
So this will wait at least 15 minutes.
And then the job has about
50 minutes of wiggle room.
And then finally,
I'm going to set ReplaceCurrent to true.
Which means that if
the job is ever remade.
We're going to replace the old
job with the new one.
And then finally I'm
going to build the job.
Okay there.
I have a job, and then I just take
my dispatcher and I schedule it.
And then finally so
that this sInitialized variable
is actually doing something.
I am going to set it to true.
Okay, so now this method will have
everything to set up reoccurring jobs.
Almost done.
I just need to actually
call this method.
I'll do that in MainActivity.
Scrolling down into On Create.
I will go ahead and
set up my repeating job here.
By calling the ReminderUtilities
class that I just finished.
And the method scheduleChargingReminder.
And I'll pass in this as the context.
Whew, okay.
So now, I will run my app.
Okay, so, I'm charging, and
I'm going to wait about 15 minutes.
Huzzah, a notification.
Now, if you prefer not to sit
around waiting for 15 minutes.
You could always change this
to a smaller time interval.
I do that for
testing purposes only though.
And as clean up,
I also want to remove things like
this test notification method.
And our test button that we
had on the screen before.
Because all of that was before we had
our nice scheduled notifications.
Okay, now it's your turn.
Give it a go.