Using the same analysis now,
we can actually even create signals that have characteristics like a box filter.
I will leave this up to you folks to kind of play around with.
But in essence, taking infinite or a large number of samples where and
could be as large as infinity starting with one,
we'd actually now take this sine function and
using this we can actually generate an approximation to a box filter.
For that specific case, the amplitude and
the frequency axis which show this characteristic.
Starting at one and as we go down one the whole spectrum will
reduce as we go from again, you know, different frequencies.
So in essence, in the limit, as I go for
large number of samples, we would basically be able to generate a filter
response that would actually have that box filter representation.
This is shown by, as I said, you know, in the limit.
As we increase N the frequency increases, the amplitude also goes down.