[Thrun] So here is our algorithm particle filter.
It sets as an input a set of particles with associated important weights,
a control, and a measurement vector,
and it constructs a new particle set as prime
and in doing so it also has an auxiliary variable, eta.
Here is the algorithm.
Initially we go through all new particles of which there are n
and we sample in index j according to the distribution
defined by the importance weights associated with the particle set over here.
Put differently, we have a set of particles over here
and we have associated importance factors which we will construct a little bit later on,
and now we pick one of these particles with replacement
where the probability of picking this particle is exactly the importance weight, w.
For this particle we now sample a possible successor state
according to the state transition probability using our controls
and that specific particle as an input. We call it sj over here.
We also compute an importance weight, which is the measurement probability
for that specific particle over here.
This gives us a new particle, and this gives us a new non-normalized importance weight.
For now we just add them into our new particle set as prime and we reiterate.
The only thing missing now is at the very end we have to normalize all the weights.
For this we keep our running counter, eta,
and we have a For loop in which we take all the weights in the set over here
and just normalize them accordingly.
This is the entire algorithm.
We feed in over here particles with associated important weights
and a control and a measurement,
and then we construct the new set of particles by picking particles from our previous set
at random with replacement but in accordance to the importance weights,
so important particles are picked more frequently.
We guess for this particle this will be a state.
We guess what a new state might be by just sampling it,
and we attach it an importance weight which we later normalize
that is proportional to the measurement probability for this thing over here.
So you're going to upweigh the particles that look consistent with the measurements
and downweigh the ones that are non-consistent.
We add all of these things back to our particle sets and reiterate.
I promised you it would be an easy algorithm.
You can look at this, and you could actually implement this really easily.
Just remember how much difficulty we introduced
with talking about Bayes networks and hidden Markov models and all that stuff.
This is all there is to implement particle filters.