Now, to control our animations when
we're actually in our apartment,
we need to use a script.
Scripting is a fairly complex subject,
in fact the next course is
dedicated entirely descripting.
So for now, let's take a small dip into
scripting by learning how to use one
without coding If you navigate
to the scripts folder,
you'll find a script
called TriggerAnimation.
With our clock handle second
game object selected,
we can drag out TriggerAnimation script
into the inspector of this game object.
This script will allow us to switch
the rotation of our clock hand by
clicking on the screen.
To use it, we need to provide
the script with some information.
First is the animation name property.
This is the name of our
trigger that we created.
So let's type in its name,
we called it Reverse.
Second is access to our
animation controller,
which is also on our clock
hand seconds game object.
Let's click on it and
drag it into that property.
And with that, we've used our first
script to dynamically control our clock.
So if we hit run now, we'll be able
to transition between our animations
anytime by clicking on the screen.
When we put our apartment in VR in
the next lesson, we'll be able to use
the trigger on the cardboard to control
the rotation of the clock as well.