Hey everyone, it's me, Jared. I'm filling
in for rod right now and I'd like to
show you the app we're going to create
in this course called Pitch Perfect.
Pitch Perfect allows you to record your
voice and play it back with various
sound effects, including changes to speed
pitch and even reverb and echo.
I'm running it here in the iOS simulator,
so that I can show you. The first screen
simply prompts you to record your voice.
Here at Udacity, we believe that asking
questions is one of the best ways to learn.
Judge a man by his questions
rather than by his answers. Now you can
see that Pitch Perfect has moved us to
the playback view. We can choose to play
back my voice using a variety of
different sound effects.
Let's try listening to my voice played
back really fast.
“Judge a man by his questions rather than by his answers”
Or we can play back my voice at a really low
pitch and I'll sound like Darth Vader.
This app is a lot of fun to play with.
But more importantly, as you build this app,
you'll learn key iOS development
concepts along the way.