My application has a ListView in it.
And I've notice as I start
scrolling things just
tend to not become very smooth.
I notice that I'm scrolling along and
like it's just taking a while or
it gets stuck.
Like all these things happen
where it just feels quite janky.
You see that quite a bit.
What are some things I could do
to start to debug those issues?
Where are some possible causes for that?
>> One cause could be that the data is
just not loading into your ListView
fast enough as you're swiping.
>> So
that's certainly a possible reason, but
let's suppose I have
all the data in memory.
So it's just a bunch of text fields or
something.
I have the data in memory.
What else could cause the issue?
>> Well, you say you have it in memory.
But if you're loading up all those
ListViews at once, it may not
necessarily populate all those-
>> Well the model I have in memory.
>> Okay, so let me think, your ListView.
Yeah, it seem that you are, I mean,
are you loading any sort of
memory intensive or like images or
high resolution images or
anything like in ListView that
would normally take a long time to?
>> I guess I could.
I mean, let's say it does.
I guess where you're getting at
is that I could have an image.
And then somehow, loading those images
is taking time and could cause a delay.
Yeah, that's certainly possible.
But, let's say,
that's not happening in this case.
>> I think another possibility is that
your views are just not
getting reused fast enough.
You can't load everything all at once.
Typically, you would want to load
an item above and an item below, and
then the items on the screen,
and then reuse those.
>> So that's a common pattern that
you would use with like a ListView.
What is that commonly referred to as?
>> I know it as RecyclerView.
>> Yeah, so I mean I think that's
why RecyclerView has that name is
because it forces you to recycle views.
>> Right.
>> In ListView before it wasn't
enforced by the system and so
you just had to implement yourself.
That's something that people missed.
So yeah, that's perfect and
I think that's a lot of
cases where you'd have that.
Suppose for instance I'm recycling my
views, images are loading off the UI
thread, like the model seems to be
consuming a reasonable amount of memory,
do you have any other
ideas what could cause it?
>> So if you're using RecyclerView,
I know, RecyclerView is really good for
a lot of things and a lot of transitions
and things like that and unique things.
But one thing it's not good
at is views that are too
customized or things that are too high,
like images that are too high quality.
It can't process them very fast it's
doing other stuff in the background and
that makes it hang up
a little bit longer.
>> So think of your hinting at is that
I could have a very complex layout
that just takes a long time
to actually layout and draw.
So yeah that could be an issue possibly
the other thing you're thinking with
images could be that they're occupying
a larger memory footprint and
there's process of that has to be done.
So suppose for
instance I have a crop type.
I'm saying to center crop or
do whatever.
If the image is too large, then yeah
that could also take some time.
So yeah.
Those are all very good reasons.