So I'm going to claim this is the last
relationship that we have to build
to prove that there all equivalent.
We'll pull that altogether at the end.
But this is going to be the hardest one.
This ones says that if we
have an algorithm that
does well on average per step,
right, it's nearly optimal per step.
Then we can use that to build
an algorithm that actually identifies
an arm that is nearly optimal.
And so this is what we're imagining.
We imagine we have an algorithm,
we were calling it C I think.
That gets within epsilon per step of
optimal after some number of pulls
with high probability.
So after this tau k epsilon delta pulls,
then the average reward that we've
gotten is close to the average
reward that you get if you were
pulling the optimal arm on every step.
What we want is algorithm A,
which, after some number of pulls,
returns an arm that is
epsilon prime optimal.
So someone has to tell us K,
the number of arms.
Epsilon prime and delta prime.
Oh and this holds with probably
one minus delta prime.
Then what we get to do is set up this
other algorithm C, however we want.
And run it for how long it runs.
And at the end of that, somehow use
the information that was gathered
to pick an arm that is nearly the best.
>> Right, and I just realized something.
I think was obvious, but I actually
wasn't thinking much about it.
So I should say it out loud, which is,
we're going to take the epsilon prime,
the delta prime, and we're going to
create some epsilons and deltas.
That has to be polynomial.
>> Yeah, because if we did 2
to the 1 over epsilon prime or
something like that, then we've
actually made things really bad.
>> Right, right.
So it has to be polynomial.
Okay, let's worth remembering.
>> And that was true in the other
two examples that we did, and
it's going to be true in this one too.
>> Right, sure, sure.
It just occurred to me that you
could cheat if you could just do any
arbitrary epsilon, epsilon prime.
>> [LAUGH] Yes.
Just set epsilon to zero and.
>> [LAUGH], Yeah.
Okay, cool.
All right, so I.
>> I think I have half an answer here.
So maybe half the answer will
help towards the full answer.
So here's the half the answer.
If I've run algorithm c and
I've got a per step,
near optimal payoff,
then one thing I know is that
if I were to keep following whatever
distribution of pulls, of sort of bandit
arm pulls that I'd done before, I would
still have the same per step average.
>> So here's what we're going to do.
We're going to introduce
an additional epsilon looking thing.
We're going to call it e sub i,
and that is the sub optimality for
the error of the plurality
arm chosen by algorithm c.
So there's going to be some arm that
gets chosen more than the other arms.
Or as much as the other arm, but
no less than any of the other arms, and
we will call that arm I and
EI is the subabnormality of that arm.
So, what do we know?
We know that this arm is
chosen 1 over K of the time,
so the total per step error Epsilon
has to be at least as big
as ei times 1 over K.
>> Right.
>> Yeah?
Right.
Okay, so if we rewrite this in
terms of a constraint on ei,
ei has to be less than or
equal to epsilon times K.
But we want to set epsilon so
that the suboptimality
of the plurality arm is less than or
equal to epsilon prime, right?
So that's the constraint
that we're given.
We need to figure out
a way of running things so
that the plurality arm is
epsilon prime optimal.
So we want this plurality arm to be
less than or equal to epsilon prime.
So if we set epsilon equal to epsilon
prime over k, then everything holds.
Over here, epsilon over k greater
than or equal to this implies that
epsilon is greater than or equal to e
sub I, which is exactly what we wanted.
So this implies the rate thing.
>> Right, and in fact, you could get
the epsilon equals epsilon prime over k
just by doing algebra, right?
You got e sub i less than or
equal to epsilon prime, and
we know that e sub i is also
less than epsilon times k, so
we want epsilon times k to be less
than or equal to epsilon prime.
Therefore, epsilon is equal to
epsilon prime divided by k.
>> Good.
So if we set that epsilon and
then we run algorithm c for
tau steps, then the arm that
we get at the end of that run,
that's chosen most often
has to be nearly optimal.
Right, because if it wasn't
nearly optimal then we would have
actually accrued a lot
more per step error.
So that actually does it.
We actually can,
just the fact we can do arbitrarily well
means we can find something
arbitrarily close to the best arm.
>> Wow, so that's brilliant.
So whoever came up with that
proof is one smart, handsome guy.