Here's how we going to do.
The idea is that we're going to classify our image points
based upon computing those, that Harris matrix, and
looking at some measure that's a function of its eigenvalues.
And the idea is that in a flat area,
both of those eigenvalues will be very small.
In fact if it was perfectly flat,
everything would be zero because the gradients were zero everywhere.
And that would mean no matter how I moved, nothing changes, so
it's a terrible corner.
Likewise if I have just one of the eigenvalues large,
that means there's some direction that changes quickly so
if I move in that direction, I know things have changed.
But if it's zero in the other direction I can move as much as I want.
Remember that's what happened along an edge, so when one eigenvalue is much,
much bigger than the other then you're along an edge up here.
And when is it a corner?
Well, when both of the eigenvalues are large.
And we'll say that.
It says here that they're approximately the same magnitude.
Just that they're both big enough, and
that the ratio between them should not be terrible, all right?
If you're, even if they were both large but
the ratio between them was 10 million, then probably your code was wrong.
If they're moderately large and your ratio between them is still pretty big,
then you have to worry because it means one gradient is much much more dominant
than the other, and maybe the noise is affecting the finding of the corner.
So you want them to be approximately the same magnitude.
So you might think great,
that means all I have to do is find the eigenvector, and the eigenvalues, right?
Right.
Guess what?
You don't even have to do that.
This is what was so good about the Harris thing.