So how does linting help your code?
The first one here is correct.
Having a linting configuration for
your project helps with code sharing and
development with multiple team members.
Linting certainly does help
with all these and more.
Some dead code is easily forgotten and
can mess up your app
in many obscure ways.
And linting will help find
many of these patterns.
Linting does not help
identify slow functions.
Linting works purely by analyzing
the actual source code.
In order to find out how long
a function takes to execute,
it needs to run in the browser.
A linter also doesn't
help with this last one.
Given the dynamic nature of JavaScript,
often the type information is not known.