So what exactly was happening
with shopping list plus, plus,
why everything is so tricky?
>> Well, I can explain what the data
structure look like and then,
maybe you can explain
what the larger issue is.
Here, give me the tablet.
So this is what our final
data schema looked like.
The developers were swan enough
to make sure that all of our
data was denormalized.
Here you see we separated out shopping
list items from the actual lists.
And we did this because when we list
the shopping lists on the shopping list
fragment page, we knew that we didn't
also want to download all of the items.
And you can see that relationship here.
In the same way, we move shopping
list out from under users.
And instead, put them in their
separate denormalized node.
To know who has access to them,
we store the owner as well as
the users that list was shared with.
Now, the issue that users were
experiencing was loading up the shopping
list fragments screen
here was super slow.
This screen here combines a list
that the users both shared on
with lists that they own.
For each user, this only amounted
to about ten or 20 shopping lists.
But it was sluggish to load up
even these ten or 20 items.
If you're wondering why, Walter,
well, I think our developer can
explain a little bit more about
what might have been going on.