So I actually got this survey a few
months ago from my university's alumni
association.
It was awful.
There were hundreds of radio buttons and
every question seemed
basically the same.
I had no idea when it would end.
I know it was probably important for
them, but
I just kind of gave up halfway through.
I just didn't want to spend 20
minutes clicking little radio buttons.
So if you're watching this and
you're from my school, sorry.
But anyway, that's one question.
How much more is there?
Most of us have places to go,
people to see.
And you know I started the survey so
that probably means that I cared
enough that I wanted to finish it.
But then I started weighing my options.
I could keep going and lose an unknown
amount of time, or I could just quit and
be done with it.
Neither option seemed that great.
So I wondered if I could save
my progress and come back later.
Would it even be safe
to close my laptop?
I wasn't sure, so
that's my second question.
Can I finish this form later?
This is especially important for
e-commerce,
where people may start shopping now,
but actually purchase later.
I take the train home almost every day.
My laptop doesn't have Internet
on the train, but my phone does.
I'm always looking for
work I can do to keep myself occupied
on the hour of my journey home.
So that leads to my next question.
Can I finish this form
on a different device?
Giving your users the option
to easily finish later
only makes it more likely
that they'll actually finish.
These all seem like really
reasonable questions to me.
In the next video you'll watch the next
part of the interview with Luke.
He'll describe the ways he empathizes
with users when testing new forms.