So here's the algorithm sort of simply described for circles.
Just like before, for every edge pixel, for each possible radius, right, so
we don't know the radius, and then, either for every possible edge gradient,
if we vote for the cone, or if we use the estimated gradient,
then we compute a and b and we increment for a, b, and r,
all right, and then that would just vote you in your Hough space.
In general, even though 3D is only 50% more D than 2D,
you'll find that voting in 3D is way more than 50% harder than 2D.
And that's because, just one way of thinking about this is,
let's suppose you had 100 buckets in each dimension.
Okay.
So, how many would that be if you had one dimension, Megan?
>> 100?
>> And if you had two?
>> 10,000.
>> And what if you had three?
All right, that's a million, right, ten to the sixth.
The number of cells that you have to consider is exponential in
the number of dimensions, and that's a challenge with using the Hough transform.