Here's a quiz for you on the behavioral diagrams. Once again,
I'd like you to match between the diagram type and its definition. As far as
diagram types are concerned there on the left, there's the Activity Diagram,
the Sequence Diagram, Communication Diagram, Interaction Overview Diagram,
Timing Diagram, Use Case Diagram, and State Diagram. Definitions, number 1,
system functionality provided to external actors. Possibility 2, dynamic
behavior in response to stimuli. 3 is flow of control from activity to activity.
4, synthesis of lower-level Activity Diagrams. 5, interaction of
classes in terms of message exchanges. The next one is object interaction in
terms of numbered messages. And the last one is a rotated sequence diagram.