Okay, so let's go back to the zoo
with the gorillas and llamas.
Remember these tables?
In this one, we have animals' names,
species and birthdates.
In this other one, we have species and
the foods that they eat.
Suppose that we wanted to find out,
how many individual animals eat fish.
Well, that's a how many question.
So we'd need a count aggregation,
but, what are we aggregating?
The animals table doesn't
talk about food and
the food table doesn't say how
many of each species we have.
But suppose that we could get
a table that added the food column,
to the animals table.
Then we would have something
that we could count up.
We saw earlier that we can derive a new
result table from existing tables by
doing a join between those tables.
That will give us something like this.
Select animals.name, animals.species,
diet.food from animals join diet,
on animals.species equals diet.species.
But we just want
the animals that eat fish.
We saw earlier, that we can
ask the database for just rows
matching a particular criterion,
with a row restriction like this one.
The same query, but now it ends with,
where food equals fish.
So to answer the question,
how many individual animals eat fish?
Our query will have to do three things.
First, it will join animals with diet,
using species as the match.
Then, it will do a restriction,
selecting only rows
where food equals fish.
And finally, we'll do
an aggregation to count the rows,
something to think about, how many
rows will be in each of these tables?
Just as the tables are related to each
other, so too are the row counts.
Let's imagine that we have
100 animals in the zoo and
that the final answer that we get from
our query, is that 20 of them eat fish.
Remember that every result we get back
from a database query, is a table.
That includes the result
of this count aggregation.
The count table has just one row and one
column and it contains the number 20.
Well that means that the result of
filtering for food equals fish.
Must have had 20 rows.
Now we don't actually know how many rows
this join has, but it's got to be at
least 100 rows, since each animal,
eats at least one kind of food.
But some animals eat more than one,
like bears which eat fish, and
meat, and fruit, too.
And we don't know how many rows
the diet table has, but it'll be at
least as many as the number of
distinct species in the animals table.
Again, that's because each species,
eats at least one kind of food.