Now to add an image to
the list item layout,
I'm going to open up the list
item dot XML layout file.
We see here that it already
has two text views.
One that holds Miwok word and
another for the English translation.
So let's go ahead and
insert an image view here.
I'm going to sign a view ID called image
because we were for to this in the Java
code reader, in order to make
changes to the image source and
as a note we don't need to do that
in this coding task particular, but
we will in the future one.
Next let's set the layout width and
height to be both wrapped content.
And lastly let's set the Android
source attribute to use
the app icon as the placeholder
image like we mention of the quiz.
So we refer to the app icon using
the syntax @mipmap/ic_launcher.
All right, that looks good so
let's test it by running our device now.
So with our device running let's
tap into the numbers activity.
All right cool so it's running and
we have the image on our screen.
However the icon and the spacing doesn't
look quite like we wanted to just yet.
So from the quiz we saw that we
want the image on the left and
our text on the right.
So we'll need to make a few
adjustments to our layout.
So to modify this list item layout,
first I can see that we can build this
list item with the horizontal
linear layout.
So the first child is the image and
the second child is all
the text on the right.
So we can do this with the horizontal
linear layout with two child views.
We also notice that the second
child is made up of two text views
that are vertically stacked.
So this can be created with
a vertical linear layout.
So here we see that we have
a vertical linear layout
nested within the horizontal
linear layout.
This is a concept called
nested view groups.
So view groups contained
within other view groups.
And remember that we learned this topic
back in lesson two of the last course.
Now back in Android studio, let's make
those changes to our listItem layout.
First I'm going to modify a linear
layout to change it orientation from
vertical to horizontal.
And then next I'm going to wrap
our two text views inside a new
vertical LinearLayout and
then add the closing tag.
Notice here in the new
LinearLayout I just added
that there is some
padding on the left here.
So 16 dbs of space between the text and
the image.
Now lets preview to see
what that looks like so
click the preview button over here.
So from the preview pane I can see
that the layout looks a lot better.
So we have the best icon on the left and
our two text views on our right.
Now let's go ahead and run the app on
our device and see what it looks like.
So first I want to close up
the preview pane and run our app.
So here's the current version of
the app running on our device now I'm
going to tap into the NumbersActivity perfect.
So it looks like a screenshot from the
quiz with our basket icon on the left
and showing for each list item.
Now, things aren't exactly looking
the same as our design marks but
we can worry about these little
details such as font size, colors, and
padding at the end of this lesson.