Consider this directed graph and
its adjacent matrix.
Suppose we treat the matrix
as a boolean matrix.
That is every one value is true,
and all zeros or blanks are false.
Let's call this matrix
capital B as in buzz.
Now suppose you want the undirected
version of this graph.
How do you compute the boolean adjacency
matrix of the undirected graph,
given the directed adjacency matrix B.
Assume you have the following logical
explanations to help you out.
Not of x takes a boolean matrix x and
converts every true entry to false and
every false entry to true.
And takes two boolean matrices x and
y and
computes the element y's logical and
of the entries.
X and y, of course,
have to have the same size.
Or does the same thing as and
except with a logical or
in place of logical and.
Lastly, trans of x takes the matrix
x and computes its transpose.
Type your solution in this box.