For this question,
the answer is data items.
In the same application main activity
Java file we just looked at,
it's contained in the data
item generator class.
In this case,
you'll find it's data items as well in
the same main activity dot-Java file.
The difference is that it actually
uses assets inside the data items
to send the images
which are quite large.
For this question,
the answer is messages.
Go to the wearable project, and
open up data layer listener service.
And then find the on
data changed method.
This is called whenever
data items arrived.
If you looked at the code,
you'll see that it uses send
message to send the replies back.