Are here are four.
First off is associations.
Associations are everywhere inside the OOA diagrams, but
object-oriented programming languages don't have associations.
It's going to be up to you to decide during object-oriented design how you're
going to implement those associations.
Related is the question of aggregation.
We know in our diagrams that various,
the diamond is used to represent aggregations.
You will have some choices at programming time as to how you are going to
represent what programming language futures you are going to use to represent
those aggregations, and during O-design you have to make those decisions.
Third off, is invariants, so
in your OCL you may have to express certain invariants.
And it's up to you in your program to enforce those invariants.
That is, make sure that it's always the case that the invariant holds.
During OOD design, you have to come up with some strategy whereby those
invariants are going to be maintained.
And finally with StateCharts,
OO programming languages don't have state machines.
And as we seen, the state charts that are produced during OOA can be complex, so
you will need some kind of approach in your OOD for
how you're going to deal with that complexity.