So before we go to Storm oh, in terms of what Real Time analytic's and
what are the batch analytic's?
I want to just give a perspective of what analytic's means.
I mean why do you have to do it?
So according to Wikipedia there are two aspects analytic's and
the first is discovery.
I mean in the sense like, you have lots of data that is being accumulated or
repeated after time, and somehow you are to find some kind of
patterns in the data, that is what we call discovery.
The second aspect of the analytic's is communicating.
So if your analytic's is not able to be communicated very well to the.
Either the upper level management or the appropriate group that is going to
make the decision is not going to be very useful.
So, there are two aspects of analytic's that are going to
affect the company in general.
One is to increase the sales which is contributing to the bottomline.
The second aspect is to make the company more efficient in terms of
cost savings.
Or in terms of people savings.
So those are the kind of things that analytic's makes you
help you make those decisions.
So, and then there are several different type of analytic's.
The first one is what we call is a cube analytic's.
I'm not I'm not sure how many of your heard about the cube analytic's, but.
So it's, it's mostly what we call is a variant of business intelligent, or
probably business intelligent analytic's.
And where most of your analytic's are either you take a larger amount of data,
you do some kind of filtering, and do some aggregations either based on.
Some kind of dimensions.
So typically your data will have a notion of dimensions.
For example, let us take the retail data that you have
purchased this product at this store at this time of the day.
So, this data has three dimensions.
One is the product itself,
and the second one is the time, and the third one is the store.
So, so when you have these multidimensional data modeling all you
can there are a lot of analytic's that he can do with this data.
One is, so what he can do is like slice and dice these dimensions.
And the data might not only have three dimensions.
It can out in a number of dimensions.
And you can slice and dice this data across this dimension.
So that you can know how much product were from this,
sold in this area during this quarter.
So those kind of analytics.
That is what typically characterizes a business in intelligent analytic's.
The second type of analytic's is Predictive Analytic's.
So this essentially means like we take a mode of data mining and
statistics, and apply to a.
Large amount of data.
And this was pioneered after the business intelligence came into being.
And then a lot of Internet companies, like Google, Yahoo, Facebook, and
all piggybacked on this because it gives you.
Lot of information about the user behavior, and
how to model user behavior, those kind of stat analytics.
And this analytic's inten, engine tend to apply a lot of statistics.
And broadly they're into what is called linear regression.
And some kind of data clustering to identify how the similarity of
data is there or not, and there's some identifying outliers in the data,
then some kind of associations too.
For example in the retail same example,
you can figure out whether two products are being bought together.
For example.
People tend to buy beer and chips together,
because when you are having beer you want to have some kind of snacks, right?
So what is that type of snacks?
So if you wanted to find those kind of association,
this is what the predictive analytic's can do.
And, moving on, there is, different dimensions of analytic's, so
there are broadly two different dimensions, and one is real time,
so where you are able to analyze the data instantly, I'll go into more
detail about the real time analytic's, what it means, on the following slides.
The first is the Real Time, and followed by batch.
And batch typically takes a few hours and days to even get required.
And there is the two broad sort of analytic's.
So you have any questions and answers.
Cool.