If authentication asks,
are you the person you claim to be,
authorization deals with the issue of,
do you have the right to the resource
you are trying to access?
When you're trying to gain access
to an exclusive or restricted area,
having the right kind of authorization
is what will get you past the door.
Even if you can effectively verify
you are who you claim to be,
sometimes that just isn't enough
if you aren't on the VIP list.
So being authorized means that you have
been granted the right to do something.
But in the context of user login
systems, authorization can
also be used to authorize some third
party to do things in your name or
have access to some part of your data.
And this is what happens when you use
third party auth providers like Google+
or Facebook.
The first time you log in, they will ask
if you want to grant the initial website
access to some of your data,
like a unique ID or email address.
The same principle
applies to mobile apps.
When you install them, they ask for
permission to use certain phone
functions, and you can then either allow
the installation to proceed or not.
Another example of authorization is the
access control in an operating system.
Even after you are authenticated and
logged in, you cannot do everything.
There are certain things that require
passing additional authorization checks.
Authorization is what can allow
users into an application,
while still protecting
its most valuable assets.