Now that you've seen how a basic
notification app can be turned into
an Android Auto app, you're now ready
to explore a more complicated example.
We have a sample called Messaging
Service that is a much more complete
example, that you should
really have a look at.
So let's create a new
project that uses this.
We can find the sample by going to find,
import sample.
So we type messaging service,
we click on it, hit Next, and
then we can hit Finish
with the defaults.
Now that the sample's loaded,
let's expand the list of Java
files that are included.
So you can see here,
we have a much more detailed example.
Let's run this on the simulator and
see what happens as well.
So with the sample running,
click these buttons to generate
different kinds of conversations.
So click this button here,
you can see we have some debug output
which shows you the kind of
message that was generated.
Let's go to the messaging simulator and
see what it looks like.
>> New message from Jane Doe.
Did you finish the messaging app yet?
>> So, now that you've seen
it work in the simulator,
you can play around with the sample and
get more familiar with it.
So what you should do now is you should
review the messaging service sample, and
try it out for yourself.
Build and install it to the emulator,
and then try it with
the messaging simulator.
This is a great starting point
that shows all the capabilities
of Android Auto-Messaging.
Check off each box,
once you've completed each task.