Let's try a programming quiz
where we'll use GDX app
to figure out what platform we're
running on and then log the result.
Since this is the first programming quiz
in this class, I'll walk you through
the workflow you'll be following for
the rest of the class.
First, below the video,
you should see a link containing the URL
of the starter code for this quiz.
In this case it's 2.1.02
exercise log application type.
All right, we've loaded up the exercise.
So now the first thing to note
is that the root of this folder
contains a readme.
It actually has a detailed description
of everything we've covered so
far in the course along with
instructions of how we're
going to complete this exercise.
So this says to open up the TODO pane
to find what we're suppose to do.
Looks like there's four TODO's and
two different files.
If we open up one of these folders.
That's actually this TODO
in the README itself.
If we open up this one,
this looks like what we're suppose to
be accomplishing in this exercise.
Let's open it up.
All right, first thing,
we're supposed to give our
application listener a log tag.
Well, we want the tag to be public,
static, and final.
It's a string named tag and it's value
is logging demo, class, getname.
All right,
that's one to-do accomplished.
Let's look at the next.
All right, the next few to-do's are us
Gdx.app to find out what application
type we're running, and
then use Gdx.app to log the result.
Well, I think I can actually
do those together in one line.
We'll start with Gdx.app log,
passed in the tag,
provide some description of
what we're talking about, then,
to get the application type,
we can just use Gdx.app getType.
Now, if we run this application
we get the nice log message
we're running on desktop.
All right, give this a try yourself.
And also try running it on
Android to see of Gdx.app
is accurately reporting
its application type.
Remember to follow the Todos
in the starter code and
take a look at the solution
code if you run into trouble