So, it's time to write
your very own AsyncTask.
Once again, you want to open
a project in Android Studio.
Lesson two part five AsyncTask.
The Todo manager is once again
a great help in instructing us in
how to proceed.
And not surprisingly,
the first to-do is to make an AsyncTask
inside of our MainActivity.
We'll call this GithubQueryTask.
The Todo also gives us a pretty big hint
to use the types URL, Void and String.
So our execute and
doInBackground method will take URLs.
We won't make use of published progress,
and
we'll return a string containing
the contents of the query.
Pretty cool.
And not surprisingly, that's what
the next two to-dos tell us to do.
First, override doInBackground,
and have it take the URL.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Pass it into
NetworkUtils.getResponseFromHttpUrl and
return the response.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Then override onPostExecute to set the
results into our SearchResultsTextView.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Of course, we still need to start our
AsyncTask, so our last to-do has us
returning to our old friend
makeGitHubSearchQuery, and replace
the networking code with instantiating
and executing our GitHubQueryTask.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now it's your turn.
Create the GithubQueryTask as
an inner class of MainActivity,
with the types URL, Void, and String.
Then, override the doinBackground
to query Github using our
NetworkUtils.getResponseFromHttpUrl
method.
Override onPostExecute to set our
text view to the returned string.
Finally, we instantiate our
GithubQueryTask in the existing
makeGithubSearchQuery function
replacing the existing networking code.