So on your browser you should have a window which allows you to do
simple calculations.
Here we are going to play around with Octave.
Which is, again, very similar to what you will find and
be able to interact with on MATLAB also.
Let's start off giving it a few sets of things.
And then, we'll actually see what we can actually do to
run different types of things here.
Here the goal for us is to play around with different cosines.
We're basically going to look for four periods, n is equal to 4.
And I'm going to create a variable vector here, t,
which basically is going to vary from 0 to 4.
But also, what we're going to do is, since we're going to
play around with sines and cosines, we're going to look for degrees.
And here I'm just going to use 90.
And of course here, we're just giving it an amplitude of two.
All right, just to get us started.
This was f1, where basically we have amplitude times cosine.
Goes from of course our n in this case is or
at least the num, the a, n value that we had was one.
Of course, times 2 pi.
And of course, multiplied by t.
That was the equation we looked at.
Let's just plot this and see what happens.
Of course, here you get a simple response to the cosine function.
Remember our amplitude this time around as opposed to in the previous case that
I've showed you on the slide as two.
It goes from minus two to two.
Starts with of course a value of two.
That's the max amplitude.
At half comes to negative two and of course it
just varies from two to minus two and we have four different cycles.
Of course looking at this plot you can see that we
can actually now generate other plots like this.
So for example, this would be an f2.
Again, the only thing I've changed is the multiplier here.
Is now replaced by 2.
So this is a simple way of now looking at it.
We can plot this.
And actually, let's just go ahead and
actually generating more of these f values from f1 to f4.
So, here, of course, I've just added f3.
And this here is f4.
And of course, we can plot all of them.
So let's go ahead and
run this and see if we can actually plot all four of these things.
So this is f1, amplitude of two, f2, amplitude of two, and
if you notice the frequency's increasing if we hit f3 and then f4.
So we have all four of them.
So now the question for you all is,
what happens if we just take all of the f1, f2, f3, f4 and add them together.
Here is just me now plotting for
the t value, all of the different f1, f2, f3, and f4.
This is the amplitude we get.
The amplitude has gone up, but
if you notice an interesting pattern is showing up.
There is an impulse function, repeats again here, repeats again here.
There is, of course, some changes in values between these impulse functions.
But an interesting trend is visible.
Well, let's take that idea to the next level.