One thing I'm trying to understand is like at what point do we decide that we
need, say, another layer of bolts.
For instance there could be a single bolt that could calculate the values along
information and credibility dimensions, a single bolt.
>> Mm-hm. >> Then we wouldn't need this.
>> Yeah, definitely yes.
Because the thing is like the advantage of this one is this is more relaxed.
>> Great. >> To make the logical, clear,
what you call panic versus misinformation credibility is more [INAUDIBLE].
And it kind of all on their own.
>> Okay.
>> On the other hand, if you can put all of them into three.
You can do that too.
There's nothing, like, stopping you from doing that you can do all of them,
except the fact that your competition is going to up.
>> That's right.
>> Competition is going to go up but number of instance will be probably some of
the number of instances of each one of the model, >> Mm-hm.
>> Involved with here.
>> Hm. Right. >> Right.
Yes, yes there's nothing that prevents you from doing that except you are your
competition would change a little bit, and this avoids that, this thing.
When you avoid this stage, then you are avoiding the network
traffic that's going in from the one stage to another.
And the cost of putting the data into a network, which is called serialization.
>> Right.
>> And the cost of reading back from the network, reserialization.
>> Yeah, makes sense. >> And the moving the network data and
the network, that also costs.
So you are avoiding that so which means you could be less latency.
>> Okay.
>> then, Oh, okay, so
that one, in this case, like this is more of a, what do you call?
Fun grouping?