All right.
So, just to review a little bit, we talked about sort of
practical application about how to make a mosaic or a panorama.
We said you take a bunch of pictures from the same center of projection,
same camera position.
You compute the transformation between each of the images.
Say the first and second, right?
What's that transformation going to be?
Well.
Same center projection.
It's going to be homography.
You then use that homography to transform, say,
the first image to align with the second.
There'll be some overlap, so
you'll have to blend them, and then you can continue to do that.
So, that was for the, the cool application.
But the theory, and this is really important part,
is that homographies map from planes to planes.
And this allows us to compute what a different image plane would look like from
the same center of projection.
So we can build mosaics by projecting a set of
images that are all taken from the, the same camera center.
And in, in general, what we're doing is we're going to be,
we're working more in this projective relationship between image planes.
So that ends the lesson on homographics and mosaics.
That was kind of the cool part with a very gentle introduction to
projective geometry.
Now we're going to do a little bit more serious, or next lesson I'd say, we're
going to do a little more serious conversation about projected geometry and
the duality between points and lines.
How often do you get to use the word duality in a, at a party?
I mean, seriously.
We're going to talk about the duality between points and
lines, and that will help us get to relationship between sort of
arbitrary cameras that you might, I don't know,
want to do stereo matching between, or some other alignment between those views.