Let's look at a variety of light fields.
Of course, if you notice we basically
started off by looking at this,
function here,
which of course has seven parameters.
So this is a seven
dimensional light field.
Has seven different dimensions,
again, we know what these are by now.
It captures the entire scene.
And, in essence, this would be the best
way to represent a holographic video.
Right?
At any point we can see all 3D,
as we move our viewpoint we can
actually see different types of 3D.
And this is the concept really
behind holographic video.
Something you may recall
from an old movie
we saw Princess Leia
show up in complete 3D.
I'm not going to go into a lot of
details about holography here, but
I encourage you to look
at this kinds of stuff.
Of course this has been one of those
bigger efforts of trying to understand
imaging and being able to generate
imaging out of nowhere into ten space,
like in this case here.
We can also, of course,
create a five dimensional light field.
Well if you notice basically it's there
ignoring the time and wavelength.
So we're basically kind of not paying
attention to the video aspect,
temporal aspect, the dynamic aspect.
And also we're kind of saying it's okay,
let's not worry about too many
different types of colors.
Let's simplify it as much as possible.
It's really more aimed at
capturing the viewpoint and
the direction of the information.
And you've seen this kind of
stuff at very simple holograms.
Like this one that you most
probably have on your credit card.
I point this out because one of
the people I had privilege working with,
Steve Benton, was one of
the people who has invented these.
And actually was always involved with a
whole lot of holographic video research
when I was a graduate student.