You might already be
familiar with Gradle,
as the magic that happens when
you hit run in Android Studio.
>> Or you might be familiar
with other build tools and
are just looking to ramp up on Gradle.
These days it takes a lot of work
to turn a pile of source code and
resources into a shipped,
tested and functioning app.
>> In this class, we'll learn to use
Gradle to automate these processes,
which makes software development so much
more fun and so much more productive.
>> Anyone serious about making
a business in Android or
Java development should understand
the complexities that development will
kill you if you don't automate.
Welcome to Gradle and Android for Java.
I'm Mark, a Core Engineer at Gradle.
>> And I'm Jeremy,
a Course Developer at Udacity.
>> In this course we'll be focusing
specifically on how to build your app.
And we'll assume you're familiar
with writing simple Java and
Android applications.
>> If you're just starting on your
Android journey, Udacity also has
a developing Android apps course, which
you might want to take before this one.
>> This course is divided
into four lessons.
First we'll learn the basics of
Gradle and Gradle build scripts.
>> Then in lesson two, we'll learn to
use Gradle to build Java projects.
>> In lesson three, we'll learn how
Gradle interacts with Android Studio,
and how to create app with free and
paid flavors.
>> Finally, we'll learn how to use
Gradle to automate a whole raft of
useful Android tasks, like dependency
management, unit testing and sign-in.
It will be a bit of a whirlwind tour but
we'll do our best to call out any
topics where you can dig in deeper.
There's nothing magic about
the App Build process but
it can get pretty complicated at times.
>> All right.
I'm ready.
Let's build something.
>> Sounds good Jeremy.
Let's dig into the Java and
Android build process.
>> Yeah.