Now, what I've just shown you is called a gradient image.
The gradient image in the horizontal direction
is the image convolved with this kernel over here.
And the gradient image in the vertical direction
is the original image convolved with this kernel over here.
This notation should now make sense
since we practiced it a number of times.
This is called, again, the convolution of the image.
Now, if we wish to find edges in any direction,
a really easy way to do this is to combine both of these gradient images
into a single edge image, and here's how it goes.
We take our gradient image in direction x, and we square it.
The same with y,
and we take the square root.
And this response over here tells us
in any of the 2 directions how strong the gradient response is.
Here is just that gradient image.
Compare this to the original image,
and you can see that wherever there is a strong transition
between a bright and dark color,
the gradient [mack] into the image I just calculated has an edge.
It has an edge vertically and an edge horizontally.
And again, it's made of these 2 components,
vertical edges and horizontal edges.
By combining both of them, we get a gradient [s/l magnet?] image,
and we have our very first feature detector,
which is a feature detector of any edge in the image.