So now that we've got our
pets.db database file open,
let's learn how to add
a table to that database.
So first off,
here are the different columns that
we decided would be in our table.
In order to make a table we need to
identify what the table would be called
and what each of the columns
would be called, and
lastly, we need to determine
what type each column should be.
Now, types work a little bit differently
in SQLite than they do in Java.
The names or the types are slightly
different but the idea is the same.
So let's take a deeper look.
So SQLite uses a more
general typing system and
to better understand what this means,
let's take a look at an example.
So for integers, there are many
distinct type of integers.
And in fact there are over
six different data types that
could represent different
sizes of integers.
So for example, we can have
a 1-byte integer, a 3-byte integer,
or maybe a 6-byte integer.
And translating that into SQLite,
these ad types
can be grouped into a single category or
what's called a storage class in SQLite.
And these are grouped into
the INTEGER storage class.
So you can use both
the generalized storage class
as well as the more specific data
types as different types as SQLite.
But I don't want you to get caught up
in the technical details of different
memory sizes.
So we'll be using the main storage
classes in this lesson and throughout
the course I'll be using the words types
and storage classes interchangeably.
But if you're interested in learning
more about the distinctions
between these two,
I've linked below a documentation to
the SQLite data type information.
So with that said, here's a list
of the general storage classes or
different types.
A single value and a SQLite can have.
So first off, we have null,
meaning that the value is a null value.
Next is integer, so this is
a signed integer thing such as one,
two, or three.
Pointing that we have reals.
And this means the value
is a floating point.
So for example 7.8.
And next we have text.
And those are things that are strings.
And lastly, here, we'll see blobs.
So this means that the data is
stored exactly as we input it.
An examples of these are images or
binaries.
So from this list,
you'll notice that our standard
data type of Booleans is missing.
Now, SQLite doesn't have
a separate type for Boolean.
Instead, a more efficient way to store
Booleans is just store them as integers.
What does this look like?
Well, for example, you can associate the
number 0 with the Boolean value false,
or the number 1 with
the Boolean value true.
In fact, integers are a great
way to store information for
columns, where there are only a few
options that could be in that column.
So let's take a look at an example where
we're associating integers with values.
Looking at our headphones
example from before.
Well, one of the attributes for
headphones was style.
And let's say there are four different
styles that the headphones could have.
So it could be ear buds, over ear,
on ear or bone conduction.
And one way we could have
stored all these values
is by storing them as texts.
Now, a simpler way would just be
associate a number with each of these.
And storing that number
in the styles attribute.
So first of all, storing a single
digit takes up way less space
than an entire word,
like phone conduction.
And secondly, a long string
of text can be less precise.
For example, if we imagine
people typing in, On Ear or
Over Ear, it's possible they
could misspell that entry.
Now, let's take a step back and discuss
how we could choose a data type for
each of the attributes
of our headphones.
So remember first off, we had name and
that could be stored just as a text.
Next, we have the price
of the headphones.
And we can see we want to
store that as an integer.
So it's often easier to store
prices as integers representing
just the total number of cents and then
dividing it by 100 to get the dollars.
So doing so
ensures that you never get a nonsensical
number such as 33 dollars and 787 cents.
And next we have style.
Remember the different styles
we had could be inner ear,
over ear or bunk conduction.
Well, in this case,
we can store as an integer and associate
an integer value with the style.
So say zero for earbuds, one for
on ear, and so on and so on.
Next up we have in stock.
And we want to store this as an integer.
So in stock is essentially a bullion,
meaning that we can store zero for
not in stock or one for in stock.
And lastly, we have the description.
And this can be simply stored as text.
So here's your chance
to practice this out.
I've listed the column names in
the pets table and I like you to choose
which of these storage types would be
a best fit for each of these attributes.
So the couple of things to note here.
First off, for weight,
we're going to simplify things and
not be including the decimal point.
Next, for gender, we're going to
have three gender options.
So male, female and unknown and
lastly for breeds, as
soon that there'd be lots of breeds with
pets of new breeds coming in everyday.
I notice in our storage class options,
I've removed NULL because
there is no situation where you'll have
a column that only has NULL values.
Much like you never have a variable
in Java with a NULL type.
Now, the rest are possible answers and
go ahead and pick the storage class that
you think is the best match for
each of these attributes.