Well, since we're talking about
the DMCA with you know it's about
protecting digital objects.
And circumvention of techniques
that are used to, to protect them.
First option was the case
Professor Felten at Princeton
actually was threatened.
He was doing research.
So this was sort of a,
a, a competition where
you would be given an audio sample
that had a watermark in it and
you had to remove the watermark without
affecting the quality of the audio.
That was protected by this watermark.
So Professor Felten's group
actually was able to do that and
there were more details to
this particular case but
they wanted to publish a paper
on how this is this can be done.
What sort of techniques that were used
and they were threatened with a lawsuit.
And became sort of
a really big deal thing.
Eventually they were able to,
to publish it, but
the idea is that circumvention of
watermark which is used to protect this
music object that we're talking about.
That is covered by the DMCA.
The second option I would not choose
here because this is actually in a,
as we said, finding vulnerabilities and
based on those vulnerabilities you
can say defrauding the Transit Authority
because somebody who learns those,
finds out about those vulnerabilities
doesn't have to pay the transit fare.
And if that's obviously not good
in that case the Transit Authority
is defrauded in this case.
So the second one actually was covered
by, or the, the students were threatened
with that they'll be taken to court
under the CFAA, the Computer Fraud and
Reviews Act provisions.
This also idea is that it's research
that you want to publish it and
this is comes again and again.
While if you do that won't bad
guys be able to then use that to,
to successfully craft attacks?
Now who knows if the bad guys
going to do it just because of this?
They may already know it and
things like that.
So again this was somewhat
controversial and, and
I think the students were able
to talk about what they did or
their methodology and
what they found at some conference.
So the second one clearly is sort of a
CFAA type and the first one is the DMCA.
So how this could be applied is,
is what we wanted to to
explore with this question.