Machine learning is a very large field
with many different methods
and many different applications.
I will now define some of the very basic terminology
that is being used to distinguish
different machine learning methods.
Let's start with the what.
What is being learned?
You can learn parameters
like the probabilities of a Bayes Network.
You can learn structure
like the arc structure of a Bayes Network.
And you might even discover hidden concepts.
For example
you might find that certain training example
form a hidden group.
For example Netflix
you might find that there's different types of customers
some that care about classic movies
some of them care about modern movies
and those might form hidden concepts
whose discovery can really help you
make better sense of the data.
Next is what from?
Every machine learning method
is driven by some sort of target information
that you care about.
In supervised learning
which is the subject of today's class
we're given specific target labels
and I give you examples just in a second.
We also talk about unsupervised learning
where target labels are missing
and we use replacement principles
to find, for example
hidden concepts.
Later there will be a class in reinforcement learning
when an agent learns from feedback with the physical environment
by interacting and trying actions
and receiving some sort of evaluation
from the environment
like "Well done" or "That works."
Again, we will talk about those in detail later.
There's different things you could try to do
with machine learning technique.
You might care about prediction.
For example you might want to care about what's going to happen with the future
in the stockmarket for example.
You might care to diagnose something
which is you get data and you wish to explain it
and you use machine learning for that.
Sometimes your objective is to summarize something.
For example if you read a long article
your machine learning method might aim to
produce a short article that summarizes the long article.
And there's many, many, many more different things.
You can talk about the how to learn.
We use the word passive
if your learning agent is just an observer
and has no impact on the data itself.
Otherwise, you call it active.
Sometimes learning occurs online
which means while the data is being generated
and some of it is offline
which means learning occurs
after the data has been generated.
There's different types of outputs
of a machine learning algorithm.
Today we'll talk about classification
versus regression.
In classification the output is binary
or a fixed number of classes
for example something is either a chair or not.
Regression is continuous.
The temperature might be 66.5 degrees
in our prediction.
And there's tons of internal details
we will talk about.
Just to name one.
We will distinguish generative
from discriminative.
Generative seeks to model the data
as generally as possible
versus discriminative methods
seek to distinguish data
and this might sound like a superficial distinction
but it has enormous ramification
on the learning algorithm.
Now to tell you the truth
it took me many years
to fully learn all these words here
and I don't expect you to pick them all up
in one class
but you should as well know that they exist.
And as they come up
I'll emphasize them
so you can resort any learning method
I tell you back into the specific taxonomy over here.