Can you explain what
a notification is and
when you would use it instead
of a delegate for example.
>> Sure, so notifications or
I like to think,
are kind of like a radio broadcast, it's
something that can be broadcasted and
then any object that chooses
to observe a notification.
Can observe it and
then call an action to do something.
So there are certain cases, for
instance, within the UI kit,
like when you use a keyboard.
Where Apple's chosen not to expose
certain functionality of the keyboard
like when it comes up and
when a value has changed when
you're typing into a text field.
And you can listen in for notifications
such as when the keyboard is shown and
then do something.
And when the keyboard should hide and
do something as well.
Just little bit different than
a delegate where there's more of like
a tight coupled relationship between
who's going to be handling and
response to something happening.
Or when you delegate something
to oppose a specific object it
has to implement the delegate protocol
so you can guarantee that it's going to
provide certain functionality, whereas
with a notification it's more of,
are there are no guarantees necessarily
to who might be listening for
a particular notification.
Okay, very good.
>> So what about if you have one
object that needs to send information
about something that just happened
to one other object, and you
have another case when you need to send
this information to several objects?
What would you choose in each case?
Notification.
Delegate.
Why?
>> For the one to one I
would choose the delegate.
And then for the one to many
objects the notification.
That's because the notification
is essentially like a broadcast.
And anyone can tune in
who needs to tune in.
And behave a certain way.
So it seems to kind of go
nicely with that use case.
>> Okay so, can an object
have more than one delegate?
>> It can.
I mean, an object can have
more than one delegate and
objects can be the delegate, I'm trying
to think how you'd word the relationship
here, somebody can take on
the responsibilities from a delegater.
Let's say multiple delegaters.
If you wanted to.
>> But in that case you
would use notifications.
>> If there needs to be many objects or
notifies.
>> Yeah, that's what I would use.
>> Okay, so that makes sense.