As Colt just talked about,
there are certain tasks you can delegate
to the system because the system will
have a better idea of when to schedule
those tasks in order to save battery.
Now as a developer, the key is
to identify which tasks in your
app should be delegated to Android's job
scheduler using the job schedule API.
For example,
this is non user facing work.
Tasks that can wait for
the device to be plugged in or
connected to WiFi or just general
situations where a bunch of tasks
can be batched to run at the same time.
All of these are good candidates for
the job scheduler.
So let's see how we can modify
our sample app code to use it.
To follow along, check out
the branch 3.22_wakelocks_optimized.
Now when you check out
this optimized branch,
you'll notice that your
activity's been updated.
You have a new button within your
freeway clock activity called pulse
modder bees modder and it's going to
go ahead and execute our improved code.
So, let's go ahead and
see what this code actually does.
All right, so
here we are back in Android studio and
I want to call out a few new
additions to our project here.
Namely, a new file
called my job service.
We'll quickly learn what we're
going to do with this file.
Let's go ahead and focus back on the
main source for this way clock activity.
Now in order to use the job scheduler,
you're going to need to
create a service endpoint.
This is what the system will call when
it's appropriate to run your job.
And this is exactly where our
job service source comes in.
All right, so here we're extending the
framework provided job service class and
then all we need to do is implement
the onStartJob and onStopJob callbacks.
So let's look at them.
Now, in our onStartJob method, we can
implement the logic to retrieve our new
updates from the network
in the background.
As you can see, this is similar
lines to what you've seen before.
We're calling our simple download task
and executing it in the background.
Now, you should already be familiar
with this code from before.
You check to see if the device
is connected to a network.
And then if so, we go ahead and
execute our simple download
task in the background.
And we don't do anything major in
the on stop job callback in this
mock situation.
But this method is invoked if your job
must be stopped prematurely, i.e.,
before your code calls job finished.
Now, this might happen if the
requirements for your job aren't met.
For example,
if your device loses connection to WiFi.
Now, if you are shipping in an app, make
sure to add code here that would be able
to prevent your app from misbehaving
due to your job being halted.
And when you're finished
with your work,.
It's important that you call
the job finished method.
This lets the system know when
you're done with your work so
it can release the wake lock that
it's been holding on your behalf.
Now since the majority of our work
occurs in the simple download task,
it would make logical sense
to come down here and
call job finished during
our onPostExecute method.
So now that we know what will happen
when our job is actually called upon by
the system to run.
But how do I actually do
submission to the job scheduler?
Let's take a look.
So I want to go over here and launch
our FreeTheWakelockActivity again.
So let's go ahead and modify what
this pollServer function does.
Again this method pollServer is actually
called when we press this button
Poll Smarter, Be Smarter.
As you can see, it's scheduling jobs.
Okay, so here we are within
the pollServer method.
Now the first thing we do is we get
a reference to the job scheduler itself
using a call to get system service.
The next thing we do
is the important part.
We're going to go ahead and create what
the framework calls a job info instance.
And this is a basically an encapsulation
for the requirements for
a particular task you'd like to defer
to the system to do on your behalf.
Now the way we generate
a job info object is we
use this builder class
with the job info.
And it's got a set of handy helper
methods within it to basically help
specify the constraints for
our particular job.
In this case, we call setMinimumLatency,
which means that
the system should wait at least five
seconds before running this job.
We then set an override
deadline of 60 seconds.
That means if this job hasn't been
executed within a minute, go ahead and
execute it.
The next thing we do is we set
a required network type to be any.
So, we allow this job to run on WiFi and
any data connections.
Finally, we finish it by calling
.build which generates our job info.
Now, once we've encapsulated our entire
job constraints within the job info
object, all we need to do is
call scheduler.schedule and
pass in the job info instance
that we just created.
Pretty cool, huh?