So here, if you leave off the endAt,
what happens?
Well, we still have the same startAt,
so we're not going to take Dan's
shopping lists or dinner requests,
because they start before do.
Without endAt,
there's nothing to stop us from
selecting everything else in this list.
All of these lists come
after the string do.
So selecting all these is
the correct answer here.
Now, in this case, we still have
the same startAt, so again,
we're not going to include Dan's
shopping list or dinner requests.
But we end at doZ.
Because I don't know the ASCII
alphabet off the top of my head,
let's take a look at a web page.
Here I've loaded up
the Wikipedia web page.
I'm going to scroll down
to the ASCII table.
All right, and
here's an ASCII printable code chart.
So reading, this we have space
comes before exclamation
point comes before quotes, and you can
see the decimal values increasing here.
So we have all these characters, notably
numbers here, some more punctuation,
and then after that, we have all
of the capital characters, and
then only after that do we have
all of the lowercase characters.
So the capital Z comes before
Meaning that anything
that starts with do and
then a lowercase character is not
going to fall within the range.
The one thing to note is that the space
character here does come before
the capital Z.
What this means for example is that do
lowercase n is not going to be included,
as are none of these other ones,
but do space will be.
So that's what I think
the answer is to these two.
Okay, you're almost ready to
add this feature to the app.
One caveat.
Let's say you search for
users whose emails start with d.
When we eventually have thousands
of users, this could be 50 users,
100 users,
maybe 1,000 emails that start with d.
We need some way to limit
the number of responses returned.
JP said he'd tell you
about limit queries, so
I'll send you to talk to him.