That's all the physics we're going to do.
We've talked about how we, model the light, and
we talked about surface property, so the albedo of the mat reflectance, and
sort of the specular component, and
we've talked about how the shape, the surface normals, interacts with that.
So in computer vision, there are these fundamental questions of,
well, when I look at a, a scene, can I figure out, say the shape, or
the albedo or both, just from an image that I'm, that I'm looking at.
And so fundamentally, this is an ill-posed problem, right,
because it's an interaction between both the shape and the whatever's painted,
or the texture on the surface, and yet our brain does it all the time, which
means that we, as computer vision scientists, we'd like to try to do it, too.
So over the next couple of lessons, we'll be talking, sort of,
the computer vision approach to recovering those elements.