Actually well it's d.
We, we took the associative and the differentiation is linear and
associative can be applied and that's what allowed us to take the derivative of
the operator and apply that to the whole image.
We'll talk a little bit, I guess next time,
why that's a good thing to do sometimes.
But its simplest explanation, let's suppose my image is 1,000 by 1,000.
And pose my derivative, my, my smoother is 31 by 31.
I could take the derivative of a 31 by 31,
which is small, and then apply that to my 1,000 by 1,000.
Or, I could apply my 31 by 31 to my 1,000 by 1,000 and
then take a derivative of the whole 1,000 by 1,000 which would be a lot
bigger operation than taking the derivative of a smaller filter to begin with.
That's one of the reasons why, we do that.