Let's look at the same problem again,
and let me just draw the two scan lines--
the left scan line and the right scan line.
As before, we get to see red pixels, black pixels,
and the occlusive blue pixels as indicated over here.
Now we'll try to match the entire scan line on the top to the entire scan line on the bottom.
so we can figure out what the exact correspondence is.
We do this by minimizing the cost function.
The cost comes in two different flavors.
There is the cost of bad matches.
Let's assume if the color matches perfect, we pay zero,
but if the color matches very poor, we pay 20.
There is also the cost of occlusion.
If in the process of matching these lines we have to assume a pixel is occluded,
we're just going to pay 10.
The question now is optimal alignment of the top to the bottom under this cost function?
Let's just go through this. Let me look at two different possible alignments.
Here is one. We align those black pixels, and we align the red pixels.
If we did this, what is the cost of the total match. Please put the answer over here.