One thing that's important to
explain is what exactly happens with
cache coherence when atomic
instructions are used.
Recall that the purpose of atomic
instructions is to deal with issues that
are related to the arbiter intereleaving
of threads that are sharing the CPU,
as well as threads that are concurrently
executing across multiple CPUs.
Let's consider the following situation.
We have two CPUs.
On both of these CPUs we'll need to
perform some atomic instruction that
involves the memory location of x.
And this x has been cached
in both of the CPUs.
The problem, then, is how to prevent
multiple threads on these different CPUs
to concurrently access
the cashed values of x.
If we allow the atomic constructions
to read and update the cash value of
the memory reference, that's the the
target of the atomic construction.
There can be multiple problems.
We have multiple CPUs with caches and
we don't know where that
value has been cached.
We have write update versus
write invalidate protocols,
we have latency on the chip.
Given all these issues,
it's really challenging
if a particular atomic is
applied to the cache on one CPU.
To know whether or
not on another CPU another atomic
is attempted against
the cash value in that CPU.
For that reason,
atomic operations bypass the caches, and
they always directly
access the memory location
where the particular
target variable is stored.
By forcing all atomics to go directly to
the memory controller, this is going to
create a central entry point where all
of these references can be ordered and
synchronized in a unique matter.
So none of the rates conditions
that could have occurred if
we allowed atomics to access the cache,
that just won't occur in this situation.
This will solve the correctness problem,
but it will raise another issue.
Atomics will take longer than
other types of instructions.
We will always have to access memory and
they will also content on memory.
In addition in order to
guarantee atomic behavior,
we have to generate the coherence
traffic and either update or
invalidate all of the cached
copies of this memory reference.
Even if the value of this memory
location doesn't change with the atomic
operation.
We still have to perform this step
on enforcing coherence traffic, so
either invalidating or forcing the same
value to be reapplied to the cache,
regardless of whether or
not this location changes.
This is necessary in order to
stay on the side of safety and
to be able to guarantee correctness
of the atomic operations.
In summary, atomic instructions on SMP
systems are more expensive compared
to on a single CPU system, because
there will be some contention for
the shared bus or
the shared interconnect.
In addition,
atomics in general are more expensive,
because they will bypass the cache,
in these kinds of environments.
And they will trigger all the coherence
traffic, regardless to what happens
with the memory allocation that's
the target of the atomic instruction