We are basically done with
implementing sign in,
there's just one tiny bug
that I want you to fix.
When our app first starts, and no one's
signed in yet, we're sent to the sign in
screen created by FirebaseUI,
you can see that right here.
When you press the back button from this
screen, it just opens up FirebaseUI's
sign in activity again, that's fairly
annoying, how do I get out of the app?
Unfortunately, it's also the expected
way that our code works right now.
The code's off state listener
will always pop this up,
when you press the back button, you're
trying to go back to the main activity,
but the main activity automatically
triggers this log in flow to appear if
you're not signed in,
creating an infinite loop of sorts.
Now the app should just let us exit
if we just press the back button, so,
let's figure out how to do that.
Let's go back to the FirebaseUI diagram,
which shows the sign in flow.
We started the FirebaseUI flow from
within a startActivityForResult call,
the result will come back in to
the onActivityResult method.
The result code will
also be returned with it,
to indicate whether a sign
in happened successfully.
FirebaseUI uses the standard RESULT_OK
and RESULT_CANCELLED result codes,
RESULT_OK means that the sign in
process completed successfully, and
RESULT_CANCELLED means that the sign in
process wasn't completed successfully,
like when the back button is pressed.
In our app, we attach
the AuthStateListener in onResume,
what's helpful about this is that
onActivityResult gets called
before onResume, so you can see what
was returned in onActivityResult before
all that AuthStateListener stuff happens
that causes that endless loop with
the login flow appearing.
And if you see that in fact
the sign in was cancelled,
you can just exit the app, okay,
let's add that to the code.
In the main activity,
right below my onCreate method,
I am going to override onActivityResult.
Now I get to use that RC_SIGN_IN
constant that I made before,
so what I can do is see if
the requestCode is equal to RC_SIGN_IN,
this means that if the activity that's
being returned from was our login flow,
we'll execute this code.
Then I can see whether the result was
okay or not, by checking the resultCode.
If the user signed in, I'll go ahead and
show a Toast, otherwise, if the user
cancelled the request, in which case
the resultCode will be RESULT_CANCELLED,
I'll make another Toast which shows
the cancelled result, which says Sign in
canceled and I'll finish the activity,
let's build this and run it.
Okay, and now the moment of truth,
let's try pressing the back button, and
it exits friendly chat.
And when we do want to sign in,
I'm signed into the chat and
I can start typing messages as myself.