Before we chat about ways
to implement collectives,
I want you to think about what
our cost goals should be.
For example, let's take reduce.
We described a tree-based scheme.
Is this good or bad?
You showed that the cost
was essentially this.
Basically, the time to send
a message of size n times log P.
So put another way,
you're sending log P messages and
you're sending a copy of
the array log P times.
So is that good or bad?
Let's first think about the fact that
we're paying for log P messages.
That's alpha times log P.
Can we do better than that?
At least on a linear network
the answer is probably not.
Let's see why.
Remember that any process can
only perform one send and
one simultaneous receive during
any round of communication.
So this process can send and
receive simultaneously.
If this process wanted to
perform a second send,
it's not allowed to do that.
The second send has to
wait until the next round.
So in the very best case,
you can pair sends and
receives, no matter how you choose
to arrange the computation.
And if you're pairing you'll need at
least log P rounds of communication.
Since the alpha terms essentially
measures the number of rounds,
then this says that
log P rounds is good.
So what about the beta term?
Is beta times n times log P good or bad?
Let's start with an intuitive and
somewhat trivial lower bound.
Each process has n words of data.
So, at some point in time,
every process except the root
is going to have to send
its n words somewhere.
So, in the very best case, you'd need to
send a total volume of n (P-1) words.
Since there are (P-1)
of these processes.
If all (P-1) processes could
send their data simultaneously,
wouldn't that be great?
The time we would pay,
would be proportional to,
the total volume divided by (P-1).
So we need to pay to
send this many words.
And the speed of communication
is one over beta.
Therefore a lower bound on time
with respect to beta would be just
n times beta.
Looks like our tree-based scheme
might be sending too much
data by a factor of log P.
Now you can apply a similar line
of reasoning essentially to
all the other collectives.
So for
all the collectives we've discussed,
the lower bound on
communication is this.
For collectives like scatter and gather
remember that we use the symbol m,
m denoted the local problem size.
So in this lower bound,
this size n is really the combined size.