Both of these commands do the same
thing, so this one is true.
The new command does not have an alias,
so running this command will not work.
These two also do the same thing,
so this is true.
The generate command does have an alias,
but it's not gen, so this is also wrong.
Generates alias is just the letter G.
We'll be using it often
to build our app.
Professionals try to do as little
work as possible while achieving
the same outcome.
Why work hard when you don't have to?
We'll be generating a lot of files and
typing out the letter G is a lot faster
than typing out the word generate.
Ember gives you these shortcuts for
free, so use them.