Welcome to lesson five. This may be shocking to hear,
but thus far, all of the data that we've used in
this course has been relatively manageable. What do I mean by
that? Well, we can fit it onto one machine pretty easily,
we can load it into memory and we can run all
of our analysis in a serial fashion. But imagine that we
are working with some very large data set. I'm not talking
hundreds of gigabytes here, I mean terabytes, or maybe even petabytes.
At this point, it would make sense to introduce something
like the MapReduce programming model, which allows us to take
our data, distribute it across many different machines, and run
our computations in parallel. If you spent any amount of time
around data science circles, you've probably heard tons of crazy
terms like hadoop or hive. Or a MapReduce or distributed file
systems. More generically, you've probably heard a lot about big
data. During this lesson, we'll discuss how to use the MapReduce
programming models to solve some very
simple problems. We'll also discuss other big
data tools like Hive at a high level. That way, next time when
you find yourself at a data science cocktail party, you'll be able to
keep up with the conversation. Alright, well why don't we get started then.