We do have a major problem with concurrency. The
lock makes essentially the whole body of the code critical,
while the digitizer is doing his work, the mutex
lock will prevent the tracker from doing his work and
similarly, while the tracker is doing his work, the
lock will prevent the digitizer from doing his work. All
parallelism is lost. Okay, okay. So we put too much
code in the critical section. Remember, that our original problem
arose when both threads were trying to modify bufavail. If we're
able to stop that, then we achieve mutual exclusion on the
buf frame array. Let's just try putting the lock around our
changing and accessing of the bufavail variable. What's wrong with this program?