Let's see if these changes
are effected in our app.
We can go straight to
the phone to test the app.
There are no code changes to deploy.
Not connected to Android Studio.
Okay.
Here's the app.
I'll show the daily special,
and there it is,
gingerbread noodles with orange sauce.
Now let's see what happens when
I switch my language to French.
I want you to pay close attention to
the symbol next to Language & Input, and
remember it.
It's kind of a globe-y thing.
And then Language is the top item
in the Language & Input list.
The reason I want you to notice those
things is it can be very frustrating if
you're messing around with
a language you don't understand, and
then you want to switch back
to your own language, and
you can't remember which of
these options is Language.
So pay attention to it.
I'm actually going to try French now.
There it is.
See what happens in my app.
And I've got the French.
Now let's see what happens
if I choose Spanish.
I'll start my app up, show the daily
special, and see we have no value.
That's because we have rules
when the language is English or
French, but no catch-all for
other languages.
Let's go back to Tag Manager.
So in the daily-special-en variable,
add back the Always trigger.
We need to add exceptions for
the languages that we're explicitly
handling, in which case this is French,
save the variable and
publish the changes.
Now over here on the phone,
we'll start the app again,
show the daily special and
it should come up in English
because we've defined English to always
fire unless the language is French.
Feel free to add variables and triggers
for whatever languages you like.
What languages did you try?
Go ahead and enter them here.