The answer here is false.
You cannot do the sharing by sharing the
file descriptor numbers because those
descriptors point into a per
process table we're talking about.
Descriptor five value FD
being five means the fifth
entry in process one's open
file table points to something.
Okay, but process P2s open file
tables is entirely separate.
So fifth entry in there may
be pointing to nothing or
may be pointing to
altogether different file.
So if you try to use the descriptor,
it won't take you to the right place,
in particular the file that process
P one is trying to share it.
Well it has the operating system data
structure set up to get to it, and
these are per process, so the same thing
as done for P2, it's not meaningful
to share file descriptors in Unix based
systems, so the answer here is false.