While optimizing your
work is generally good,
you can definitely go overboard and
over-optimize.
Before we teach you some
good ways to optimize for
the web, let's see if you can identify
which optimizations are beneficial.
Which of the following optimizations are
worth doing considering both the time
and risk?
A 10% speed up in launching your editor,
that takes one hour.
A post-process that tests
your app on a mobile screen
that takes a day to implement.
An editor plugin that autocloses
your HTML tags that takes 30
minutes to implement.
Or a script that generates images for
hi-res devices and takes four hours.
Check your answers here.