So, in this case, there's no dominant strategy,
so we'll have to go to a mixed strategy.
And we'll start by looking at max and saying
he has a mixed strategy with a probability P
of playing 1, so then if min chooses 1,
then we'll have the outcome 3P + 5(1 - P).
And we want to set that equal to the outcome
if min plays 2, which is 6P + 4(1 - P).
And we solve that, and that works out to P = 1/4.
So, P, that was a probability of max playing 1.
That should be 1/4, which leaves 3/4 over here.
And now we go at it from min's direction,
and if min has a probability of Q
of playing 1, then we want to set 3Q + 6 (1 - Q)
equals 5Q + 4 (1 - Q).
And you solve that, and you get Q = 1/2.
So, 1/2 and 1/2.
And then the utility of the game is the expected value,
so we look at all the outcomes and the probability of each outcome.
So, 3 times 1/8, because it's 1/4 times 1/2
would be the probability, so 3 times 1/8
+ 6 times 1/8 + 5 times 3/8
+ 4 times 3/8, and that works out to 4.5.