Layers are a common concept in
image manipulation software.
For instance, at Udacity we use a piece
of software called SketchBook Pro to
make drawings like
the ones you see here.
And we use layers to make
it easy to separate and
edit different parts of our drawings.
Here let me show you.
These are the menu options I
get when I'm using SketchBook.
And this one here gives me
control over the layers.
For instance, I can hide the background.
I can hide the sidebar for the stories.
In fact, I will select this story, and
I can move it around the page without
affecting any of the other
layers which is pretty cool.
Here, let me undo that.
Being able to control separate
parts of this image individually
makes it much easier to put
together something complex.
Photoshop uses layers too,
as does pretty much every other piece
of visual media creation software.
Our video production team, for example,
uses Adobe Premier to composite all
the videos that you watch on Udacity.
In fact, these tablet style
videos have two main layers.
We create one layer by doing
a screen recording on the tablet.
And then we create a second layer with
a camera above the tablet pointed
down at our hands.
When the two are composited it together,
we put the tablet on top of the hand so
that no matter where the hand is on the
screen, you can always read the text.
Pretty cool?
If you want to learn about the story
about how we came up with this
technique, check out
the instructor notes.
For this quiz, I want you to think
about the layers of this mobile app.
This menu, which is currently
shown on the side of the page,
will slide in when somebody
clicks on the hamburger icon.
The nav bar at the top is
going to be stuck at the top, so
if the user scrolls up and
down, it's not going to move.
And then the stories can
obviously slide up and and down.
So, knowing what you know about how
elements that stick and move together
should be in the same layer, how would
you organize the layers in this app?
For elements that you want to be on the
same layer, give them the same number.
So for instance,
if you think the nav bar in the title
here, Watch This Cute Puppy Code!,
should be in the same layer,
put the same number in these two boxes.
But if you think they
should be different layers,
then put different numbers
in these two boxes.
It doesn't matter exactly
what the numbers are,
it just matters if they're the same or
different.
The elements that I want you to
identify are the div that says world,
the entire menu that slides in,
the top nav bar.
The heading for this article,
the video for this article, and
then this entire article.
Put numbers into all these boxes.
And then one last hint,
there should be a total of three
layers when you composite this page.