So this one is probably bugging you just a little bit, so
lets just go through them, all right.
Let's talk about a.
All right. Well, of course, a has got to be true.
The direction of the lines in the world,
of course the talk we just showed, the maps shows that,
you know, where they intersect in the image comes from there.
And then it says whether the world lines are on the ground plane.
Well, all world lines that are on the ground plane,
all intersect, parallel lines, they all intersect at what?
They intersect at that horizon.
But, now here's where it was a trick question.
I said, what determines at what point, in the image parallel lines intersect?
I didn't say what line, I said at what point, so that's why b is not true.
Now c is the orientation of the camera, so you can think about this two ways.
One, everybody knows that where a point lands on your image has something to do
with where you point the camera.
Watch Meghan's nose move.
Okay. Yeah, as I move the camera of course things move.
The right way of thinking about this is remember the a, b,
c which is the direction of the the lines in the world.
But that's in some coordinate system, and
that coordinate system is defined by our camera's center of projection.
That's the x y z center of our universe there.
And we're defining all of our points in that coordinate system.
And that's why it's a and c.