We see that every page table entry will
have the physical page frame number and
that it will also have
at least a valid bit.
This is also called the present bit
since it indicates whether the contents
of the virtual memory are actually
present in physical memory or not.
There are a number of other fields
that are part of each page table entry
that the operating system uses
during memory management operations,
and also that the hardware understands
and knows how to interpret.
For instance,
most hardware supports a dirty bit,
which gets set whenever
a page is written to.
This is useful, for
instance, in file systems,
where files are cached in memory.
And then we can detect using this dirty
bit which files have been written to and
need to be updated on disk.
Also useful is to keep
track of an accessed bit.
This can keep track of in general
whether the page has been accessed,
period, for read or for write.
Other useful information that can
be maintained as part of the page
table entry also would include
certain protection bits.
Whether a page can be only read or
also written to, or
maybe some other
operation is permissible.
So that was a generic discussion
of a page table entry.
Here is the specifics of
the Pentium x86 page table entry.
The flags present, dirty, and accessed,
have identical meaning as in the generic
page table entry we just discussed.
The bit read/write, it's a single
bit that indicates permission.
If its value's 0, that means that,
that particular page can be accessed for
read only, whereas if it's 1,
that means that both read and
write accesses are permissible.
U/S is another type of
permission bit which
indicates whether the page can
be accessed from user mode or
only from supervisor mode, from when
you're in the kernel, basically.
Some of the other flags here dictate
some things regarding the behavior of
the caching subsystem
that the hardware has.
So, for instance, you can specify things
like whether or not caching is disabled.
That's an operation that's
supported on modern architectures.
And also there are some parts and bits
in the page table entry that are unused,
and hopefully in the future we'll have
good uses for these bits as well.
The MMU uses the page table entries not
just to perform the address translation,
but also relies on these bits to
establish the validity of the access.
If the hardware determines that
a physical memory access cannot be
performed, it causes a page fault.
If this happens,
then the CPU will place an error code
on the stack of the kernel, and then it
will generate a trap into the OS kernel.
That will in turn generate
a page fault handler.
And the page fault handler,
it will determine what is
the action that needs to be taken
depending on the error code as well
as the address that caused the fault.
Key pieces of information in this
error code will include whether or
not the fault was caused because
the page was not present,
it needs to be brought in from disk.
Or because there is some sort of
permission protection that was violated,
and that's why the page
access is forbidden.
On x86 platforms, the error code
information is generated from some of
the flags in the page table entry.
And the faulting address that's also
needed during the page fault handler,
that one is stored in a register, CR2.