[Thrun] For my next example, I will study a different type of a Bayes network.
Before, we've seen networks of the following type,
where a single hidden cause caused 2 different measurements.
I now want to study a network that looks just like the opposite.
We have 2 independent hidden causes,
but they get confounded within a single observational variable.
I would like to use the example of happiness.
Suppose I can be happy or unhappy.
What makes me happy is when the weather is sunny or if I get a raise in my job,
which means I make more money.
So let's call this sunny, let's call this a raise, and call this happiness.
Perhaps the probability of it being sunny is 0.7,
probability of a raise is 0.01.
And I will tell you that the probability of being happy is governed as follows.
The probability of being happy given that both of these things occur--
I got a raise and it is sunny--is 1.
The probability of being happy given that it is not sunny and I still got a raise is 0.9.
The probability of being happy given that it's sunny but I didn't get a raise is 0.7.
And the probability of being happy given that it is neither sunny nor did I get a raise is 0.1.
This is a perfectly fine specification of a probability distribution
where 2 causes affect the variable down here, the happiness.
So I'd like you to calculate for me the following questions.
Probability of a raise given that it is sunny, according to this model.
Please enter your answer over here.