Hey Leila, so what app are we
going to be building in this lesson?
The business card camera optical
character recognition one?
Seems a little involved for
a sample project.
>> Yeah, you're right and in this lesson
we're actually going to be building off
of an app called DroidTermsExample.
Now unlike the other app,
which was storing contact information,
DroidTermsExample stores word
definitions for use in a glossary.
But both of those apps
use content providers.
Now instructions for
downloading the app are below,
why don't we take a look at it.
DroidTermsExample is
pretty straightforward.
It's an app for
keeping track of all these Android
terms you've been learning.
Ever wanted to have
the definition of adapters and
what happens in on pause on hand?
>> Yeah, all the time.
>> Well Suzanne, in DroidTermsExample
which I have opened here,
you can view Android glossary
terms with their definitions.
And then when you come across a new
word, you can add a definition for
it, save it.
And it will appear here
on the main screen.
DroidTermsExample is storing all of this
information, including the words and
the definitions on the phone itself,
using a content provider.
Now what's actually going on under
the hood is that there's a SQLite
database, and
the content provider is just providing
managed access to that database.
But from a developer's point of view,
who's using the DroidTermsExamples
content provider,
you don't actually need to know that
the SQLite database even exists.
Because you don't have
the permission to and
you never will be accessing
the SQLite database directly.
Okay, so
we've looked at DroidTermsExample.
Now, imagine like you want to make an
app that quizzes users on the definition
of the Android words
in DroidTermsExample.
DroidTermsExample has all of this
word and definition data already, but
how can you actually access it?
Well, since whoever made
DroidTermsExample used a content
provider, you can easily access
all this data in your own app.
So DroidTermsExample has
already been made, and
what you're actually going to be doing
is making an app called QuizExample.
It shows the first word that is stored
in DroidTermsExample's data, but
with no definition.
You can then click show definition to
reveal what the definition is, and
the next word to go onto the next word.
By creating QuizExample,
you'll learn how to access data
using a content provider, and
this will work for any content
provider that's publicly accessible.
You'll also learn how to take
the data from a content provider and
display it in a UI.
Follow along with the next
tutorial to get started.