When we put it all together,
non-seasonal ARIMA models
are displayed as ARIMA p, d, q.
The p, d, and q values represent
the amount of periods to lag for
in our ARIMA calculation.
Basically, that means
that we said p = 2.
We'll be using the two previous periods
of our time series in the autoregressive
portion of the calculation.
This helps adjust the line
fitted to forecast the series.
Purely AR models will look
like a linear regression where
the predictive variables are a certain
number of previous periods
which is represented by p.
The differencing term refers to
the process we use to transform a time
series into a stationary one.
That is a series without trend or
seasonality.
This process is called differencing and
the d refers to the number of
transformations used in the process.
And, the moving average term refers
to the lag of the error component.
As a quick reminder, the error component
refers to the part of the time series
not explained by trend or seasonality.
MA models look like linear regression
models where the predictive variables
are the previous q periods of errors.