The virtual file system data
structures are software entities.
And they're created and
maintained by the operating
system file system component.
But other than the entries,
the remaining components will
actually correspond to blocks
that are present on disk.
The files, of course, are written out to
disk, and they will occupy some blocks.
And here we have two files,
the green file and the blue file.
And they occupy multiple blocks
that don't have to be contiguous.
The inodes, we said, will track all of
the blocks that correspond to a file.
And they do have to be
persistent data structures.
So they will live somewhere in disk.
So let's say these two blocks
here correspond to the inodes for
these two different files,
for simplicity.
To make sense of all of this and
to be able to tell what is an inode,
what is a data block, what is a free
block, the super block maintains
an overall map of all of
the disks on a particular device.
This is used for allocation,
when we need to find some free blocks to
allocate to a new file creation
request or file write request.
And it is also used for
lookup when we need to find the
particular portion of a particular file.