All things start with a route in Ember.
But we already have our routes,
so there's nothing to generate.
We need to take all of this data and
move it to a JSON file.
Here's the file that I created.
Notice that it's an array of objects
with one object for each type of cookie.
I put this file in the public
folder inside of store directory.
Now that we have data that can be
retrieved we need to update the cookies
route to get this file.
Remember that a model hook is
where we fetch data for route.
I'll use jQuery to get the JSON
file which then gets returned.
And that's actually all we
need to do in this file.
Pretty simple?
Now that the cookies template is
being given the data we can replace
all of this with the dynamic content.
Since the data is stored in
an array we can use an each
block to loop over the data.
Since we're looping we only
need one of these containers.
Each time through the loop, the cookie
will be stored in this cookie variable.
So I just need to replace these hard
coded values with an expression.
There we go.
We've removed over half of this file
by cutting down on duplication and
instead, looping over the provided data.
Typically you won't retrieve
your data from a local file.
You'll usually fetch it from a database,
API, or third party website.
But the steps are pretty much the same.
You fetch the data in the model hook,
you return it, and
then you consume that
data in the template.
Ember makes all of this pretty
seamless and easy to use.