Let me show you just more example just to highly a particular little problem.
So here we have a nice man-made scene of a some beautiful bridge
somewhere in Europe.
And you'll notice that there is this strong vertical here.
And a vertical if you think about coming down this way and
coming that, is a step edge horizontally.
Okay. You remember, dots like this are sinusoids that,
that vary as you go up and down.
And you remember that if you have a step edge,
remember we had a square wave, okay?
It had all the frequencies, just in decreasing power.
And what you're seeing is a whole bunch of frequencies in
decreasing power coming down.
So the question is,
where is the strong horizontal edge that's suggested by that vertical line?
Remember a vertical line is all of these frequencies, which means that it's got
a horizontal sharp edge, and the answer is a little tricky.
Basically, if you think about how the sinusoid goes in the image,
it's essentially as if it assumes the image just kept wrapping around, okay?
Remember we talked about the Fourier series,
assuming that everything just kind of repeats?
So here what we're essentially doing when we do this sum from minus n over
2 to n over 2, is we're assuming that the thing continues, that it's periodic.
Which would mean that the thing over here should be the same as the thing
over there.
And if it's not, that would represent a significant change.
And, this edge down here, is really different than that edge down there.
So when you wrap it around, you get a big step.
And that's what cor, causing that sort of weirdness in the Fourier transform.
Do you remember when we talked about doing filtering in MATLAB?
There was, there was a wrap option.
To head out off the edges instead of replicate or reflect.
You could take the stuff from the top and put it back down on the bottom.
And I said that won't make any sense to you at all until we get to
Fourier analysis.
Well, that's as if you had a periodic signal.
Because if you don't have that, you get this funny sort of sharp edge.
One way to eliminate that when you're doing Fourier analysis is you'll take
you're image, and you'll multiply the whole image by a Gaussian that tapers off
towards zero by the edges, and then everything becomes nice and smooth.
When in doubt, fix your life with a Gaussian.