Companies come to us for
three different reasons to host
machine learning competitions.
The first is they have a really
challenging use case and
they want to put some of the best
minds of the world on the problem and
to attack the use case in
a very competitive setting.
So this looks like are R&D development
or IP development, and for
the companies that are falling into that
basket at the end of the competition
they get access to the top three to
five winning solutions as well as
contact with teams that won them.
And then in many cases they go on to
either hire the teams that won them or
continue on in a consulting
engagement with the teams that won.
There's two other reasons that companies
host competitions with us as well.
The first is marketing, either their own
brand or they have a tool that they want
to promote encouraged asked scientists
to use or things along those lines.
So, and then the second is recruiting
where they're looking to hire
the scientists to solve problems
internally some of which can be framed
in the machinery learning competition.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Yes, absolutely.
Kaggle is a really great distribution
platform for innovative techniques
because whenever someone sees
the first person on the leaderboard
in a competition that they
participated and competed heavily and
they spent many hours in, they really
really want to know what beat them and
how did that winning person win.
So that means if there's a technique
that tends to do well in
a SQL competition we have 1,000 or
10,000 participants
pouring over the details of that
technique and how it works.
And that makes Kaggle a really
effective grounds both for
proving out that this technique
on a problem really works as well
as growing a large-scale
adoption of that.
One example of that is a library called
XGboost which is a quick and efficient
implementation of Gradientboosting
machines that is super easy to use and
is also enormously flexible.
It was released a couple years ago.
It started doing really well in
competitions about a year and
a half ago.
Over the past year and a half we've
now seen over 50% of the Kaggle
competitions have used XGboost as
a key part of that winning solution.