Okay, so here's where we left off
with the app in the last exercise.
It's interactive, but barely.
Partially because it's not
really saving any information.
Sounds like we're going to need
a variable, or variables, and
I want you to help me plan what
variables that you'll need.
Now in this simple version of the app,
there's no ability to reset, and
we're only talking about one team,
Team A.
Given that we know that when you
click a button we want the score
to increase here.
Can you tell me what variable,
or variables,
that you think we need to create for
this app to work?
I've given you a number of
options to select from,
check which of these you
think we need a variable for.
Do we need a variable to keep
track of the number of points for
a 3 point shot, or
a 2 point shot, or a free throw?
Do we need a variable for the number
of shots attempted, a variable for
the number of fouls,
and/or a variable for the score?