So, you've seen two or three different
error messages from the shell by now.
Let's try a command that actually works.
Well, here is probably one of the best
known Unix shell commands, ls.
ls is an abbreviation for list, and
it gives you a list of items
in your current directory.
We'll talk more about files and
directories later on in the course,
but for now, you can think of this
as listing the files in the folder that
the shell is currently looking at.
Except, since we just logged
into a freshly installed system,
there aren't any files in
the current directory.
It's pretty common for
commands that don't have anything to
do to just exit with no message at all.
There are no files because
this is a brand new server and
you haven't put any on it yet.
Let's fix that.
See if you can guess what
this command will do.
Will it send all of
your money to Karl so
he can buy more of these silly t-shirts?
Will it curl your hair.,
put stuff in it, and snag in the zipper?
Or will download a file from the web?