If you've ever painted a room or
a house, you know that it takes a lot of
work to color in those walls, and if
you need to end up repainting it again,
you've wasted a ton of work
doing it the first time.
This same concept of wasting
effort to paint something
can also contribute to performance
problems in your applications.
See, at the intersection
of performance and
design lies a common
performance problem.
Overdraw.
Overdraw is a term used to describe how
many times a pixel on the screen has
been redrawn in a single frame for
example if we have a bunch of stacked
UI cards, all of the cards that are on
the top part of the stack closer to
the user will hide large portions of
the cards that are hidden underneath.
Meaning that we'll spend time drawing
those cards which are mostly invisible.
This is actually a large problem because
each time we're rendering pixels that
don't contribute to the final scene,
we're wasting GP performance.
And with modern layouts, it's easy to
fall into a trap where we're stacking
and layering views to give us this
beautiful, transcendent design.
But also creating the same
overdraw problem.
To maximize performance
in your application,
you'll want to minimize overdraw.
Fortunately, it's easy to see the amount
of overdraw in your applications
right on your Android device.
Simply go into developer mode, and
then turn on the Show GPU overdraw flag.
Now, don't panic while your phone turns
into some sort of visual awesomeness.
This is completely normal.
Android is using different colors to
highlight areas of overdraw occurring
on your screen.
If you've only rendered
a pixel one time,
you should see it in its
true color with no tint.
However, as the overdraw increases,
so do the colors.
A one x overdraw, for
example, is tinted blue,
meaning that you've now redrawn
this pixel one extra time.
And, of course, two x, three x, and
four x follow the same pattern.
So when you're tuning your
app's user interface,
you'll want to reduce as
much overdraw as possible,
reducing all of those areas of
red in favor of the nice blues.
To accomplish this goal, there's two
main ways you can remove overdraw.
Now firstly, you'll want to
eliminate unneeded backgrounds and
drawables from views that won't
contribute to the final rendered image.
Remember, this is wasted performance.
Secondly, you can define areas
of your screen that you know
will hide portions of your view, which
can help reduce CPU and GPU overhead.
So let's get started at the top and
join Chris as he's going to take us and
help us look at overdraw.