So the general idea is that there's two types of kind of emotions,
one from emoticons and one from emojis.
And so the emoticons would be like, you know, smiley face or stuff like that and
there were five different classes that we had.
One was, you know, like happy, medium happy, neutral, being sad and
you know, unhappy and then the other ones were emojis and
they were based on Unicode characters that I found online.
You know there was this kind of a list of all the Twitter emojis.
Yeah, I think this might be it here with the Unicode.
Oh, no here's the list.
Here's the happy list.
So, as we see here, here's your happy list and
the various Unicode characters associated with them.
And so here's happy, mediumHappy, neutral, mediumUnhappy and
unhappy, and these were just, you know, based from my own feelings of what
constituted happy versus mediumHappy, which is a little arbitrary, I suppose.
>> Great. How do you think the approach in general worked?
>> I think it was okay.
I think next time, perhaps we should get rid of these mediumHappy and
mediumUnhappy, kind of category,
because I think that added a little bit more to the noise.
It was a little bit arbitrary in terms of well, is this happy or
kind of medium happy?
So it was a little more difficult.
>> And then how do these map onto the colors for the D3?
>> Oh yeah, so, this is, happy is the darkest yellow.
This one's a light yellow.
This one is the pale green.
MediumUnhappy is a light blue, and unhappy is a dark blue.
>> So, happy is yellow like a happy face?
>> Yeah, exactly.
So, happy is, you know, the yellow happy face, and
unhappy is like I'm feeling blue.
So, that's why it was blue.