All right,
we just learned a lot about methods.
Now it's the time for
you to take a break.
You can do some jumping jacks,
you can go take a walk outside,
you can even go to a new browser tab.
When you're ready,
you can come back here and
then we're going to look into
the display message method,
one of my favorite methods.
In the next coding task,
you're going to modify the app so
that instead of saying price here,
it's going to say order summary.
This is a better name because if you
change the quantity and then hit order,
then the summary does show up here,
it's more than just the price.
This is a small UI change,
but in the process,
you're going to be modifying
the display message method,
which we gave you in Lesson 2 without
explaining what it really does.
In the coming videos, we'll start to
understand more about all the different
parts that are going
on inside this method.
You'll begin by experimenting with
changing some of these values and
seeing what happens.
When you make the change it will cause
an error in the displayPrice method, so
you can actually delete this method now.
You even get a warning now that says
that this method is never used.
So, go ahead and delete it.
The overall goal is to
change the price section
to be called the order summary section.
There's a couple of additional
changes we'll be making along the way.
In the activity_main layout file,
go ahead and
change the price header to say,
ORDER SUMMARY.
Then find the TextView for
the price value, not the header, but
the actual value.
Change that view to have an ID of this.
The view ID used to be something
like price_text_view, but
now that we've changed it into
an order summary section,
we're going to update the ID as well.
Then, in the main activity file in
the displayMessage method, go ahead and
change the variable name from
priceTextView to orderSummaryTextView.
And lastly, go ahead and change
the reference to R.id.price_text_view
to R.id.order_summary_text_view,
with the underscores here.
When you're done check these boxes.
Then take a moment to step back and
make any observation about what's
happening in the displayMessage method.
Do you have any guesses
about what's going on or
what the connect is between
xml layout and the Java file?