Now, let's try to see what will
happen if we're considering two I/O
bound tasks.
And again, we'll think of two tasks that
have execution time of ten seconds, and
in a system that has a context
switch overhead of 0.1 second.
And let's also assume that the nature in
which these I/O calls are performed is
that a task issues an I/O
operation every one second.
And also let's assume that
every single one of those I/O
operations complete in
exactly half a second.
If we look at the timeline, it looks
identical as what we saw in the case for
the CPU-bound jobs with
a time slice of one second.
This makes sense, because exactly after
one second, the tasks are, in this case,
not exactly preempted.
They actually end up issuing an I/O
operation, so yielding voluntarily,
regardless of the fact
that the time slice is 1.
So if we look at the performance
metric for this case,
they will be identical to the previous
case in the case of the CPU bound tasks.
Now if we look at the second case that
has a time slice value of five seconds,
we see that the timelines, the schedules
of the two tasks, are identical to
the case when we had a much smaller
time slice value of one second.
Similarly, obviously, if we compute the
matrix, they will be identical, it's for
two identical schedules.
The reason for
this is that at this particular moment,
we're not exactly time slicing.
We're not interrupting the tasks
in either one of these cases.
The I/O operation, again,
is issued every one second.
So regardless of the fact
that in this scenario,
the time slice value is much longer,
we still end up issuing an I/O operation
at the end of the first second.
And therefore, the CPU is at
this point released from T1,
T1 yields, and T2 is free to be
scheduled and to start executing.
So one conclusion that you can
make from this is that for
I/O bound tasks, the value of the time
slice is not really relevant.
Well, let's not draw that
conclusion that fast.
Let's look first at a scenario
where only T2 is an I/O bound task.
T1 is a CPU bound task,
as what we saw in the previous morsel.
In that case, the execution for
the two tasks T1 and
T2 when the timeslice is
1 will look the same.
The one difference is that in the event
of T1, we preempted after one second,
where as in the case of T2,
the I/O bound task, after one second,
it voluntarily yields since it has
to go and wait for an I/O operation.
In the case of five seconds,
the execution of T1 and
T2 will look something as follows.
T1 will run for five seconds, and at
that point, its time slice will expire,
so it will be preempted.
T2 will be scheduled, and
as an I/O bound task,
T2 will yield after one second because
of reading on an I/O operation.
At that point,
T1 will be scheduled again.
Now, at this point, T1 is actually
complete, so T2 is the only runnable
task in the system, and that's why we
have this illustrated in this manner.
If we work out the performance
metrics for this last case,
the numbers will look as follows.
And again, for all of these,
the calculations are posted
in the instructor notes.
We see that both with respect to
throughput and the average wait time,
the use of a smaller time slice
results in better performance.
The only reason why, in this case, the
average completion time is so low, then,
if you look at the calculations,
there is a huge variance between
the completion time of T1, which is at
11, and then T2, which is way later.
We see from this that for
I/O bound tasks,
using a smaller time slice is better.
The I/O bound task with a smaller time
slice has a chance to run more quickly,
to issue an I/O request,
or to respond to a user.
And with a smaller time slice,
we're able to keep both the CPU
as well as the I/O devices busy,
which makes, obviously,
the system operator quite happy.