Let's go download the code for
this course.
It lives on github.com.
So first we need to open up a browser.
The address is github.com/udacity/ud405.
So here we are,
code supporting the free Udacity class
2D Game Development with LibGDX.
Looks like we're in the right spot.
Looks like there's a bunch of
folders that are numbered and
labelled either Demo,
Exercise, Solution.
Okay, cool.
If we scroll down here, we find a nice
little ReadMe that says you can download
this code using the grey
download zip button on the right.
If we actually scroll up a little
bit to find that, here we go.
Download zip.
All right, while that's downloading,
let's have a look around.
Looks like the ReadMe also says
that instructions for importing and
running these projects can
be found in this directory.
All right, let's have a look.
If we check out the ReadMe down in
this directory by scrolling down.
Let's see, we have instructions for
importing and
running your first LibGDX project,
description of the app architecture,
instructions on installing
Android Studio, and
instructions on running the desktop and
Android versions of the game.
This seems suspiciously like what
the rest of this lesson is about.
Well really, you can think of the course
code as being the textbook for
this course.
People learn best in different sorts
of ways, so if you want to listen to me
talk about LibGDX,
that's a great way to take this course.
But if you'd rather just read
instructions and play around with code,
well, you could actually get pretty
much everything I have to teach
out of this course,
just by looking at the course code.
So that's an option for you.
Looks like our download is finished, so
let's go extract that somewhere useful.
So here we are in our downloads folder.
We have the UD405 master zip,
that's what we just downloaded.
Lets move that to the desktop.
And we'll go ahead and extract it.
And you should see that same directory
structure that you saw back on GitHub,
just a bunch of numbered and
labeled folders.
All right that now that you've
seen me do it, it's time for
you to download the course code.
Navigate to github.com/audicity/ud405 or
follow the link in the instructors note.
Download as a zip.
Or if you know what you're
doing with Git and GitHub,
you can just fork and clone it.
Extract it somewhere useful,
I recommend on the desktop.
And when you finally see the contents,
check off this box here too.