There's a really cool thing
you can do about this, and
it's something called a dolly zoom.
And this was an effect that I think,
at least I've been told,
was invented by Alfred Hitchcock.
Basically, if you move closer and
closer to something, but you widen
out the lens at the same time,
you'll cause the object and
subject in the middle to stay about
the same size and to be stationary.
But it's going to be very weird, because
what's going to happen is that all
the stuff from the outside is
going to look like it grows.
[MUSIC]
And in the slides and study guide on
YouTube is a link to the original.
And there's also another link put
out by somebody who wanted to
just demonstrate this effect.
And they did it for even a longer time,
and you can get to see that.
[SOUND]