So in David Lowe's work in doing the sift work, he had a pretty clever idea, and
this is the idea.
Take your first-nearest neighbor, so you do the best match.
See what its score is.
Now we already said setting a threshold just on that is challenging.
But here's what he's going to do.
Take a look at the next-best match.
So I now have the first nearest neighbor and
what's called the second nearest neighbor.
And, take a look at the ratio of the best to the second best.
Now if you think about this, [COUGH] before we get to the plot.
When you're a correct match, the best is really good and it's the best one.
And the next best one, well.
You know, presumably it won't be it, we know it not going to be as good, and
how, however much it falls off will depend upon sort of where in the image there
happens to be another point that just happens to look like this one.
So, you're going to get that ratio, all right?
But now consider a point that is not the right one.
So it's sort of randomly, maybe its real match was occluded.
It's not actually in the picture.
So it randomly went and picked some point, and it happened to be its best match.
Its second best match, is going to be some other random point in the picture.
So those are going to be more similar in value than in the correct case.
And that's exactly what this graph shows.
This is the ratio of the best to the next best, okay.
And what you're seeing here is for
the correct matches the distribution is over here, okay.
So, that ratio of error, okay?
Is, you know, a lot of this stuff is over here.
Right, so like this 0.1 would mean that the best match SSD is sum of
square differences which you want to be low, is 10% of the next best match.
So that's, that's really a big difference, here it's 20%,
30% for the incorrect method matches.
Remember it's randomly selecting them you hardly get any
that have such an extreme ratio.
And in fact you don't start seeing them show up until you get to
this much higher value.
So setting a threshold here, you could set a threshold, you know,
right about there.
And almost all of your matches, your best matches would have been correct ones.
And very few of them would have been incorrect.
Now you might ask, but
wait a minute, you're going to throw out some correct matches that way.
Isn't that a problem?
There's no way Megan's going to be able to remember that entire question.
So you might just say, well, aren't you going to throw out these here,
that are the correct matches, but the ratio didn't pass your test?
Yep.
So you're going to be throwing away some correct matches, but
our assumption is that we've got plenty of correct matches and
we just have to figure out which ones are there.
Okay, so that's this cool method of doing this
selection by comparing the best to the nearest best.
Cool?
Good.