After copying over the assets, updating
the launcher icon in the Android
manifest, and adding the helper
methods to the utility class,
we need to modify to detail fragment and
forecast it after classes.
In the detail fragment
onload finished method,
we read the weather condition
code from the cursor.
Then we pass this into the utility
helper method to get the resource ID for
the colored icon in order to
set it on the image view.
The ForecasterAdapter change is a little
trickier because we want to use
a colored icon for the today layout and
we want to use a gray icon for
the other days.
In order to distinguish between the two,
we call getItemViewType given
the current cursor position.
If the view type is today.
Then we get the weather
condition code from the cursor.
Then we get the resource ID for the
colored image from the helper method.
And then we set that
on to the image view.
If the view type is for
a future day, then we read the weather
condition code from the cursor.
Then we pass it into the helper
method to get the resource ID for
the gray icon and
then we set that on to the image view.
If you previously hard coded
an image into the layout,
then you should remove that value now.
Otherwise on app launch, it will
load up the placeholder image and
then flash to the actual icon.
Now that the wire frame
implementation for
the phone UI is pretty much complete,
let's look at the tablet UI.