The trace for the site is looking
actually pretty close to 60 frames per
second, but it's not quite there.
All the big purple bars are a pretty
good indication that there's probably
too much layout happening.
Just like before,
I want to find the cause of the jank, so
I'll zoom into the beginning of
the trace to see what started this mess.
When I zoomed in it becomes pretty
apparent that there's something wrong
with these layouts.
These red triangles definitely
look like warning signs to me.
I've clicked on one, and then inside
the Details pane I see a warning.
The warning says that,
Forced synchronous layout is
a possible performance bottleneck.
Well, this seems like a pretty useful
message, and where's it happening?
Right here,
a function called totesLayingOutYo.
What?
Paul come on,
why would you name it that?
Well, anyways, it's coming in
at the quiet script on line 190.
I think this might be the culprit.
Just to make sure, I've clicked on
the function that led to this force
synchronous layout, and it's pointing
me to the quiet script, too.
And there it is, there's Paul's
weird function, totesLayingOutYo.
On line 190, he's setting offset
width which is forcing layout.
And there you have it,
there's the source of the jank.
This time the jank wasn't caused
by the function that started it.
But, in fact,
it's a function that's being called
every time a new frame has to be run.
This time the jank isn't caused by
a function running at the beginning
of the script,
it's a function that's being called
every frame by requestAnimationFrame.
This means the correct
answer is totesLayingOutYo.
By the way, Paul and I will come back
to this example later on in the course.
You'll learn just a little bit more
about what you're seeing here and
what this performance issue is.