So now we didn't have M.
Now we know, that M encodes all the parameters, the extrinsic parameters and
the intrinsics.
So we should be able to find things about the camera from M.
For example, the focal length which should be an intrinsic.
Or, how about the camera center?
In order to be able to do the projection,
the camera center, remember the translation vector that translates from
the world coordinate to the camera center.
That, if we just knew that translational value, that would
tell us the location of the camera center in the world coordinate frame.
So we should be able to get that directly from the end matrix.
So I'm going to tell you about two ways of doing that.
Sort of the pure way,which is beautiful, and then the easy way.
So we'll start with the pure way.
Here's a slight change in notation just to pull out our parts.
Okay.
So we have our matrix M, and I'm just going to assume that M, which is a 3 by 4.
Is going to be made up of this 3 by 3, which I'll call Q and
b is just this 3 by 1, it's just a, a vector.
Okay, so we've got Q and b.
I'm going to claim that the center, C, which is a point,
which I'm going to represent as a vector, is in the null space.
Of the projection matrix.
And what that means is that if you multiply M times C, it equals zero.
And if you found such a C, that would be the camera center.
And you should just trust me.
Okay, maybe you don't trust me.
Let me show you why that's true.
All right? It's really pretty simple.
Except drawing it is painful, all right?
Let's suppose I have some camera center C.
And I've got some plane.
And I have some point P that's out here.
So I have a ray that goes from P to C.
And I'm going to have a point X that's somewhere on that ray.
Okay, so that's where X is.
All right? So that's all that this equation says.
That X is equal to something that's a blend between p and c.
Alright, lambda times P, one minus lambda, times C.
So given some M, that's the camera, the projection.
All right?
Of X is just MX and just by linear algebra,
that projection is just lambda MP plus 1 minus lambda MC.
Now for any point, P, all the points on that ray have to land at the image of P.
So, any point P, all the points on this ray,
have to land at the same point on the image, okay?
So, any point X along here will land at that same point,
no matter what lambda is.
Well, if this equation has to be true, no matter what lambda is.
And it has to land at MP because lambda might be one.
That means that this value, MC, has to be equal to zero.
So if C is the center, MC equals zero.
And that's why, I could,
I said before that the center C can just be found by finding the null space.
Of the projection matrix M.
That wasn't too painful.