Bucket sort is a really neat idea but
it has one big problem.
It's this assumption about a uniform
distribution of input values.
If that doesn't hold,
then you won't get nearly equal
numbers of elements in each bucket.
By the way, for some really fascinating
examples of non uniform distributions
that somewhat mysteriously arise in real
life, please go look up Benford's Law.
So to build a robust linear-time
sorting algorithm for
the distributed setting,
you'll need a better idea.
Blam-o!
That better idea is sampling.
Not that kind of sampling,
though my inner grad student does
enjoy the occasional freebie.
Indeed, all of the state of the art
sorting algorithms that run at scale use
some form of the following idea,
which is really easy to state.
Basically, you'll still do
a distributed bucket sort.
But instead of equal width intervals,
let the interval widths
vary according to the data.
To decide those widths,
you'll use sampling.
Here's the algorithm on an example with
3 processors and 24 input elements.
First, let's assume the elements
are initially equally distributed among
the three processes.
Then, each process will
sort its elements locally.
So after the local sort,
you'll get this.
Next, each process will pick
a sample of P-1 of its elements.
It should choose these elements to be
equally spaced from the sorted lists.
So for example, we might choose these.
Each of these subsets
are the local samples.
Next, let's gather all the local
samples onto some root process.
Then, let's have the root
process sort the samples.
From the sorted sample, let's choose
a final sample of P-1 elements.
I don't know,
let's pick these two for example.
These become what
are called the splitters.
The splitters define
the global bucket boundaries.
For instance, using these splitters,
we might assign the first process
to the 0 elements, the second,
to elements 1 through 3, and
the third, from 4 to the end.
Now having chosen the splitters,
we need to broadcast the splitters so
everybody knows who owns which range.
Now each node can partition it's
local elements using the splitters.
Now all the nodes can exchange values.
Every node now only has
elements in its bucket.
Finally, each node can sort its local
bucket, thus completing the algorithm.
Now a good exercise is to go back and
compare this result to what you would
have gotten if you had assumed
a uniform distribution of values.
That is, divide the intervals 0
through 9 among three buckets,
two of which have three elements
each and the last having four.
You should find that the sample
sort result is better balanced,
at least by a little.