Now tcpdump can look at a lot more
than just pings in DNS requests.
For instance, we can use it to look
at the packets that your machine
uses to talk to a web server.
And we can use that to get a little
better sense of what's going on in TCP.
So, for instance,
there's a web server at example.net
that serves an example web page.
And we can use nc in our secret
knowledge of HTTP headers to
send it a request while we have
a tcpdump watching port 80.
Hey, look.
We have some things.
What are these things?
Well, I'm going to stop tcpdump with
Ctrl+C and we can look at them.
If we look here, looks a lot similar
to what we just saw with DNS.
We see a timestamp, we see IP address
of the web server and of our machine.
And then what's all this?
Flags, ack, win, options, nop, nob.
We're going to need to
look closer at this.
In total, there are ten records
of output here from tcpdump, and
each one of them, just as with ping,
represents a single packet.
In case you weren't able to get this
to work, I've put a copy of the tcpdump
output that I got into a file
that you can download.
The timestamps, addresses, and some of
these fiddly details will be different.
But the structure should be the same.
I'm going to copy this tcpdump
data into a file right now.
Now something to notice
right away is that
no place here do we see the contents
of the network traffic,
that HTTP HEAD request
isn't anywhere here.
What we're seeing is data from
the headers of the packets.
The metadata.
Next up, we'll be looking in
detail at what's going on here.
What actually happens at the TCP
level when a client requests
a web resource from a server.
But first, give it a try yourself.
Run tcpdump in one window and
netcat in the other, and copy and
save the results to a file so
we can analyze them.
Or, if that doesn't work, download
the saved version from when I ran it.