I know that you have quit filling out
a massive form like this one before.
I know you've groaned when you've come
across some huge form with a million
pages and tons of little radio buttons,
because nobody likes to click these for
hours on end.
So, with that in mind,
I want you to brainstorm some
questions that people ask when they
come across big forms like this one.
The reason why is that one of
the most important skills for
any developer is empathy.
Empathy is the ability to see the world
through somebody else's perspective.
Any one who creates any thing for
any other people needs
a strong sense of empathy.
And that includes web developers.
Remember, you're building a website for
your users, not for yourself.
So this questions is going to
be a free response question.
See this long form?
Ask yourself,
what are you thinking when you see it?
What do you want to
know before you start?
What kind of knowledge
would help you finish it?
Type your answer into this box, and
in the solution video,
I'll show you what I think.
Share your answer in the forums,
too, because maybe one of you will
catch something that I didn't.