Now that we've found a way to
clean up all those nasty leaks,
we run into an even larger
problem called, memory churn.
>> Remember that each heap space has
a finite size that limits the number of
objects that it can accommodate, and
as the size of the heap gets too big,
a GC event is kicked off to eliminate
unneeded objects to free up memory.
>> Now, memory churn is a term used
to describe the process of allocating
lots of objects in a very
short amount of time.
For example, if you're allocating a load
of temporary objects in the middle of
a for loop, or you're allocating a bunch
of objects in your on draw function.
>> This is effectively the same
problem as an inner loop,
any time the screen needs to be
redrawn or an animation is occurring,
you'll end up with calls to
these functions every frame,
which can quickly add up,
adding pressure to your heaps.
>> In both cases, we've created
a scenario where a high volume of
objects can be created in
a very short period of time.
And depending on how many of
these objects are created, or
their size per object,
you can end up quickly consuming
all of the available memory in the young
generation, forcing a GC to kick off.
And as more of these are kicked off,
the more of your precious frame time
is going to be eaten up by them.
As such, it makes sense that for
a high performance application,
you would want to identify and
move allocations out of inner loops or
any code that's going to
be executed repeatedly.
To make finding these
allocations easier,
Android Studio has a handy tool
built just for this problem.