Have you ever had that experience
where you fix one bug,
and it just creates, well, more bugs?
You might of noticed that we lost
some functionality from the app.
You can actually no longer click
on items to open up detail views.
This is because we've removed
the layout we were clicking on, and
destroyed the on click listener.
Let's think about this as an opportunity
to rethink how we actually open
our details list activity.
Okay, I'm here in
ActiveListDetailsActivity.
If I scroll down to the onCreate method
I make a new Firebase reference here and
I attach a ValueEventListener
to that Firebase reference.
This is the URL that
we're listening on and
it's statically attached to
whatever's stored in ACTIVE_LIST.
Now that we've got a lot of lists, we're
going to need to change this URL so
that it's referring to the specific
list that the user just clicked on.
Which means if I go over to
ShoppingListsFragment here,
in this onClick listener here
in ShoppingListsFragment that's
attached to the ListView,
I probably want to pass on
some information about the list
item that I just clicked.
And we can easily do that with a intent
extra, so what you should be asking
yourself is what extra data do
you actually need to send over so
that you can make that specific URL to
the list that you're interested in.
So should we send over the push ID,
the shopping list name, or
the Firebase reference object pointing
to the specific shopping list?