First, let's looks at the users table.
A person's full name isn't unique, but
the user name on the form should be.
So that can serve as a primary key.
Next, the posts table.
Each post has a unique id,
and that's the primary key.
And author here, seems to refer to
the users tables, username column.
So that's a foreign key.
Lastly, there's the votes table.
Post_id here seems to refer
to the id column in posts,
which would make that a foreign key.
In the voter column, refers to
the username in the user's column.
So that's also a foreign key.
But one more thing,
since each user should only be
allowed to vote once on each post.
The pair of columns post id
comma voter in the votes table,
should also be a primary key.
It talks about, for instance, user
Prince Utena's vote on post_id number 2.