Now, there is a convention in situation
calculus that predicates like At.
We said plane p was at
airport x in situation s.
These types of predicates that can vary
from one situation to another are called
fluents, from the word fluent having to
do with fluidity or change over time.
And the convention is that they
refer to a specific situation.
And we always put that situation
argument that's the last
in the predicate.
Now, the trickiest part about situation
calculus is describing what changes and
what doesn't change,
as a result of an action.
Now remember, in classical planning,
we had action schemas,
where we described one action at a time,
and said what changed.
For situation calculus, it turns out to
be easier to do it the other way around.
Instead of writing one action, or one
schema, or one axiom for each action,
we do one for each fluent, for
each predicate that can change.
And we use a convention called
successor state axioms, and
these are used to describe what happens
in the state that's a successor
of executing an action.
And in general, a successor state
axiom will have the form of saying for
all actions and
states If it's possible to execute
action a instead s then I will show
in general what they look like here.
Then the fluent is true if and
only if action
a made it true or action a Then undo it.
So that is either, it wasn't true
before and a made it be true.
Or if it was true before, and a didn't
do something to stop it being true.
For example, I'll show you
the successor's state axiom for
the end predicate.
And just to make it a little bit
simpler, I'll leave out all of the for
all quantifiers.
So wherever you see a variable without
a quantifier, assume there is a for all.
And what we'll say is, it's possible
to execute a in situation s.
If that's true, then then the in
predicate holds between some cargo C and
some plane in the state
which is the result
of executing action A in state has.
So that in predicate will hold, if and
only if, either A was a load action.
So if we load the cargo into the plane,
and then that results,
the result of executing that action
A is that the cargo is in the plane.
Or it might that
it was already true that the cargo
is in the plane in situation s.
And a is not equal to an on load action.
So, for all a and s for which it's
possible to execute a in situation s
the in predicate holds If and
only if the action was a load or the end
predicate used to hold in the previous
state and the action is not an unload.