Now we want to make a script
that changes the scene.
But to do it,
we're going to need to use methods.
Methods are a block of code you
can run whenever you want to.
And in our case, we're going to
write the code that gets executed
when the vacation block is clicked.
Let's get started by adding a script to
our vacation block, which will program
to change the scene when the user looks
at it and clicks the cardboard button.
With the vacation block selected,
go to the Inspector and
scroll down to Add Component.
Now type Change Scene.
And the only option you
should have is New Script.
Go ahead and click on that.
And then it'll automatically
have Change Scene for
your name, and
then click Create and Add.
We now have an empty
script called Change Scene
which is attached to our vacation block.
And the script itself is saved in the
root of the Assets folder, right here.
Go ahead and double click on the script,
and open it up.
In MonoDevelop,
you'll see Start and Update.
Go ahead and delete both of these.
We don't need to do anything on start or
every frame.
Instead, we're going to create our
own method that changes the scene.
Now type public void
GoToScene and
then open brace and close brace.
And if you don't know where
the brace keys are in your keyboard,
on a standard US keyboard,
you can type them by holding Shift and
then they're right beside the P key.
So in this case,
public means that other scripts in our
system can see our method and call it.
This includes the event system.
It needs to be public or
it won't show up to other scripts.
Void allows us to execute this block
of code without having to return
any specific data type.
Don't really worry about
this too much right now,
just know that this is the way that
we're going to build this method.
GoToScene is the name of our method and
then inside the braces is what's going
to happen when this method is called.
For now, we just want to test that
our click method is working properly.
So inside the GoToScene method,
type debug.log.
And then type something
like my method was called.
When this method is called,
we'll see a little debug output at
the bottom left with our message.
But nothing is calling our method yet.
So let's fix that.
All right, let's go back to Unity and
call our method.
Navigate back to the vacation box and
then scroll down to the event trigger.
Now this might seem a little strange,
but
we're going to go to the hierarchy and
click on the vacation box.
And drag it all the way over
to that little slot for
an object in the event
trigger right here.
What that's doing is saying,
when somebody clicks on a vacation box,
it's going to call a method
that's on this object.
And in this case,
we want to call the GoToScene method
in the change scene script right here.
So click on the drop down
box that says no function.
And then Change Scene.
And then go to a scene.
All right, that's it.
Let's test it, for
now we should get a debug message
when we click on the vacation block.
So, run the scene in Unity and
try to clicking on the block.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
All right, so I'm going to click on it.
And there you go.
Down at the bottom left,
it says my method was called.
All right, that's great.
Okay, so technically we're already
interacting with VR objects now.
But why don't we do something
a bit more satisfying,
like actually going on vacation [LAUGH].
Next up, let's modify our method to
change our scene when it's called.