We can copy the source code for D3.js
and paste it directly into the console.
This code over here is
the latest version of D3,
and notice that this code
is minified and uglified.
Minified means that all the white space
characters have been removed from this
code, including ending lines and tabs.
Uglified means that a lot of the
variable names have been shortened, and
oftentimes replaced with either one or
two characters.
Now, this JavaScript code is
definitely less readable, but
it still functions as
the original programmer intended.
So, I can copy all of this code, and
paste it directly into my JavaScript
console, and hitting the Enter or Return
key I get true returned as the result.
This means D3 is now loaded into my
web browser and we can see that there
are some functions that come
with D3 that are now available,
things like D3 select and selectAll,
which we'll learn about very soon.
Another way to load D3 onto the page is
to add the D3 library into a script tag.
We can create a variable called
script that will hold that tag and
then we can set the type
to text/javascript.
We'll set the source to
the source code of D3,
which you can find here on the website.
And then finally we'll add
the script to the head over document
inserted into the web page.
Now, we can also check in our
elements tab if that actually was
added to the page.
So, if we click on the head,
we can scroll down and
sure enough,
we see the script type there.
Now, we didn't actually need to this for
this particular web page,
because it turns out that this web
page actually loads D3 on its own and
it's included in the body.
But if you're ever wondering
how to add D3 to a web page,
this is definitely a sure way to go.
Now, one last thing to keep in
mind is that if we refresh or
reload a web page in your browser and
the page doesn't come with D3,
then you're no longer have access
to any of the variables or
the methods that are defined with
D3 in the JavaScript console.
Now it won't work for this web page,
because again D3 is already defined.
So, if I do refresh and type D3, I still
see that I have some of those methods
available like select and selectAll.
So let's just check this for
a web page that doesn't load D3.
For example,
udacity.com definitely doesn't load D3.
So if we open up the JavaScript console,
and if we type in d3., we notice that we
don't get the methods that are usually
there, this means D3 isn't defined.
Typically your application or
file will reference this D3 script,
so that way you can make use
of it in your application.
Often times the D3 script is also
surfing a content delivery network or
CDN and this just gives you
quick access to the script, so
that way your client can download it and
make it available for the application.
To get started learning
D3.js we'll change some
HTML elements on this web page and
then we'll go and recreate a portion of
Hans Rosling's famous Gapminder chart.
We're going to recreate this graphic and
we're going to recreate
the dot that represents China.
So, we'll need to be able to plot the
life expectancy, the income per person
and the total population which
is the size of the circle.
When it comes to remaking this
one dot only to learn about axis,
scales and proportion when it comes
to circles and how to size them.
All right let's get started.