So, that was a really
informative talk we just heard.
>> Yeah, it sounds like there's
a lot of data in the shelter,
and there could be better ways
to capture it and access it.
>> Yeah, I totally agree, and you know
what, this seems like the type of
problem that mobile would be perfect for
helping solve.
In this course, the students will get
to learn a powerful way to structure
the data, build an app that leverages
the structure to allow users, so
our staff in this case, to easily get
the information that you need for
each pet and be able to act on it.
>> Yes, so I think we can
go back to Udacity now and
try to build a prototype.
>> Yeah, great idea.
>> Okay, let's go, Jessica.
>> Just give me one second.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>> Jessica,
you're going to have to return Jacob.