Let's review just for a second.
This is called the minimax routine for evaluating a game tree.
Given a particular state we look and see is it a terminal state?
Is it a maximizing state? It is a minimum state?
In each case we look up the utility from the game.
We do the max value routine, or we do the min value routine, which is similar.
That gives us the value of each state.
Then the action that the agent would take would be just to take the action
that results in the maximum state--the state with the best value.
Now let's try to apply the minimax routine to this game tree.
This is a small game in which Max has three options for his moves,
and then Min has three options for its moves, and then the game is over.
Here are the terminal values for these states in terms of Max's score.
What I want you to do is use minimax to fill in the values of these intermediate states.
What are the values of these three states for Min to move,
and what is the value of this state for Max to move?