Just as in the Laplacian smoothing example before,
the value of k is a smoothing parameter.
It makes the function less scattered.
Here is an example of k=1
for a 2-class nearest neighbor problem.
You can see the separation boundary is what's called a Voronoi diagram
between the positive and negative class, and
in cases where there is noise between these class boundaries,
you'll find really funny, complex boundaries as indicated over here.
Particularly interesting is this guy over here where the class of this circle over here
protrudes way into the otherwise solid class.
Now, as you go to k=3, you get this graph over here,
which is smoother.
So if you are over here, your two nearest neighbors are of this type over there,
and you get a uniform class over here.
In this region over here, you get uniform classes as solid classes
as shown over here.
The more you drive up k, the more clean this decision boundary becomes,
but the more outliers are actually misclassified as well.
So if I go back to my k-nearest neighbor method,
we just learned that k is a regularizer.
It controls the complexity of the k-nearest neighbor algorithm.
and the larger k is, the smoother the output.
We can, once again, use cross-validation to find the optimal k
because there is an inherent trade off--between the complexity of what we want to fit
and the goodness of the fit.