If your app is accepting requests
from an authenticated user,
you want to be sure that it's actually
the user who came up with that request
and it isn't someone tricking
them into sending it.
Anti-forgery state tokens protect
the security of your users
by preventing anti-forgery
request attacks.
The first step to protecting
against this type of attack
is by creating a unique session token
that your client side code returns
alongside the Google
generated authorization code.
In later steps, you will verify this
unique session token with your server
when a request is made to verify that
the user is making the request and
not a malicious script.
Let's go ahead and open our
applications project.pie file and
add a few new lines in order to
generate our unique session tokens.
I first need to make a few imports
in order to add this functionality.
I already used the word session in this
code to refer to my database sessions
with SQLAlchemy.
So, let's go ahead and
import flask version of sessions and
name it login_session using
the as keyword in python.
This login_section object
works like a dictionary.
We can store values in it for
the longevity of a user's
session with our server.
I'm also going to import the random and
string python libraries,
which I'll use to create a pseudo-random
string that will identify each session.
Now let's create a new routing path and
call it /login.
I will then create a showLogin function
that creates a state variable.
State will be 32 characters long, and be
a mix of uppercase letters and digits.
Now, let's store state in
our login_session object
under the name state.
To see what our state looks like,
we can return the following string.
Now, if we save and visit our
/login page in our application,
we get something that looks like this.
Each time we refresh,
we're generating a new state variable
that we are passing on to the client.
For cross-site request forgery, the
attacker would essentially have to guess
this code in order to make
a request on the user's behalf.
Later on, we will check to make sure
the user and the login sessions still
have the same state value when
a user tries to authenticate.