Now what that suggests is the design for an exploration agent
that will be more proactive about exploring the world when it's uncertain,
and will fall back to exploiting the optimal policy--or whatever policy it has as close to optimal--
when it becomes more certain about the world.
And what we can do is go through this
normal cycle of TD learning--
like we always did.
But when we're looking for the estimate
of the utility of the state,
what we can do is say:
The utility of the state estimate will be
some large value, plus R--
say, plus 1--in the case of this example--
the largest reward we can expect to get.
In every case, when the number of visits to the state
is less than the sum threshold, E, the exploration threshold.
And when we've visited a state E times,
then we revert to the learned probabilities
or the learned utilities, rather.
So when we start out, we're going to explore from new states;
and once we have a good estimate of what the true utility of the state actually is,
then we stop exploring and we go with those utilities.