Given the requirements that we listed
in terms of what a cloud system has
to incorporate, several different
technologies come into play.
First, we already talked about
the need for virtualization.
This is required in order to address
this ability to provide fungible
resources that can be
dynamically repurposed.
Which application they serve and
then exactly how are they used,
what are the expectations?
You don't have to have
the exact same CPU or
the exact same type of device
based on the customer's needs.
Then you need some technologies to
enable the dynamic provisioning and
scheduling of
the infrastructure resources.
Certain platforms like Meso, or Yarn,
Hadoop's Yarn, that serve this role.
In order to address the customers' needs
for scale, cloud technologies need to
provide abilities to process and
store large amounts of data.
There are a number of big data
processing frameworks that
are out there.
Hadoop MapReduce is one.
Spark's another one that is popular.
Regarding the data storage layer,
cloud computing platforms include
things like distributed file systems.
These are file systems that typically
operate in some append only mode where
you're not arbitrarily rewriting data
and deleting data and modifying data.
And then there are other important
technologies that enable the storage,
access and
manipulation of data at scale.
These include a number
of NoSQL technologies,
which are a departure of traditional
relational SQL databases.
The ability to store data across
distributed memories, as opposed
to repeatedly perform disk accesses,
and a number of other enhancements.
Cloud computing customers,
they not only need to get
the right amount of resources.
However, they need to somehow
be isolated from each other so
that every one of them thinks that
they own their resource slots.
For that reason, cloud computing
technologies need to include some kind
of mechanism that enables these
software-defined slices of resources so
that costumers are provided with their
own software-defined data center or
subset of the storage that's controlled
and defined by the software or
the network resource, etc.
And then also, especially given
the complexity of these environments,
it's important for cloud computing
platforms to also use a certain
efficient monitoring technologies.
In real time to process logs, to detect
certain anomalies or failures, but
also to provide that as a service to
the users that may not just want some
batch access to potentially large data
but more of a real time, more of a maybe
interactive access to information that's
produced from their applications.
Some of the technologies that provide
this monitoring type functionality or
real-time log processing
include Flume and CloudWatch,
this is the Amazon service,
or LogInsight,
this is a product that's part
of the VMware portfolio.
Flume is Open Source,
and many, many others.