Okay, this is a messy one, that is
assuming I did something reasonable.
Blah.
I basically got the cube
root of a bunch of stuff.
Stuff in this case is
2 times W-D over PD.
The exact answer isn't as important
as how you get there, so if you got
something different or the grading
robots didn't give you credit for
an equivalent expression, don't worry.
Okay, here's what I did.
First, I used Brent's theorem.
This gives an upper bound on time given
that we've slowed down the cores but
we get to use more of them.
The first sigma models slowdown,
the second sigma cubed models
the increase in processor cores.
Then I thought to myself,
self, let's pick a sigma to
minimize the righthand side.
Let me give the righthand side a name.
G of sigma seems like a sufficiently
creative name for [INAUDIBLE] work, so
let's go with that.
To minimize g, let's return to
the dark recesses of Calc 101.
In particular, let's take the derivative
of g with respect to sigma.
We'll get something,
we'll set it to 0 and solve for sigma.
When you do that,
you basically get this mumbo jumbo.
You can also take a second derivative
of g just to verify that it's positive,
meaning that sigma is
really a minimizer.
The more interesting question is,
can you get a speed up?
And the answer depends
on the value of P.
But the short answer is, sometimes.
I'll leave figuring that out as
an additional exercise for you.