We just completed the lesson on
matched pair design experiments, and
the course on A/B testing.
Let's review what we've
covered in this lesson.
Building on what we learned in the last
lesson, we walked through a pricing
elasticity problem, and learned
about using discrete variables and
trends to help match treatment and
control units in an experiment.
We also demonstrated the ability
to perform two tests in parallel.
You've now completed
the course on A/B testing, and
know how to set up and conduct two types
of A/B testing experiments and analyze
the results to determine significance
to support your business decisions.
You're definitely ready to demonstrate
your understanding of A/B testing.
Excellent job.