So you have this great idea for an app.
It will sure become so popular, probably
the entire world will download it and
it will become a crucial technology
in every person's everyday life.
This thing is sure going to
bring you fame and fortune.
>> No, no, no, no, no.
Hold up.
Fame, yes.
But fortune, the money,
where's that going to come from?
>> Didn't think of that.
You're always raining on my parade.
Fame without fortune.
That will be terrible.
What are we going to do?
>> Take it easy.
That's why we are here
in the first place.
We're going to look at AdMob, where you
can get paid to show ads in your app.
>> Hm, that would be great.
How do we get started with that?
>> We'll kick it off by looking
at some monetization models.
But first, shouldn't you properly
introduce yourself to the audience,
our students?
>> What students?
That's right, I'm so sorry.
That was very rude of me.
[COUGH] Honored student,
welcome to the AdMob lesson.
This one, Is all about the money.