If we look at the information on the top
half of the screen, this equation in
orange right here is completely related to
everything over here on the left. We know
that instead of writing total money
earned, we can write a, like we have in
this bottom equation. So, we can cross
this out and put a. And since we've
figured out alternate expressions for
money earned from wipers and money earned
from nozzles, we can just substitute in
those new values in these slots. So, we
know that money from wipers is also seen
over here, and it equals 36w. So, we can
take 36w here, and put it here. We can do
the same thing with the money from the
nozzles. Money from nozzles is 22n. So, we
can put that in this spot. Of course, we
want to keep the operators that join these
quantities together since we're just
calling these quantities different names.
So, we still have an equal sign and a plus
sign. So, we should have a=36w, move the
plus sign down, plus 22n. So our answer
choice must be, well here is that exact
thing written down, 36w+22n.
The question is, are any of these other
answers right? Well, we can go through one
by one and eliminate ones we know are
wrong. This has a bunch of factors
multiplied together, so does this one.
This one has four different terms added
together, and that's not what we're
looking for since we only have two terms
up here. And all of the rest are at least
almost in the form that we're looking for.
2w has never popped up anywhere for us
before. This would mean that 36 people are
each paying Grant 2w dollars. We know that
in order to buy a set of wipers from
Grant, you only pay w dollars, and that 36
people bought wipers, so this answer is
not correct. We need something with just
36w in it. If we look at the remaining
answers, there are some incorrect
combinations of coefficients and
variables. We know that 36 goes with w,
not with n, so this answer can't be right,
or this one. And we know that the
coefficient of n needs to be 22. Since as
we figured out a couple of quizzes ago,
11*2n=22n.
And we want each of the 11 people who are
purchasing nozzles to buy two, so this
answer isn't right, either. So, now we're
left with just two answers. 36w+2n, which
we know is right, and 22n+36w.
Now, this expression is actually exactly
equivalent to this one. So, it's right as
well. In order to say that this is true,
we have to use something called the
Commutative Property of Addition. This is
really similar to the Commutative Property
of Multiplication that we've talked about
a lot already. Except that this time
instead of talking about switching order
when you multiply things, we're talking
about changing order when you add things
together. So, just like we know that
2+3=5, we also know that 3+2=5.
That means we know that 2+3=3+2.
In the same way, if you have not just
numbers but numbers and variables. Let's
say, an expression like 36w+2n, you can
rearrange the order of the terms that are
added together and get an equivalent
expression like 22n+36w.
So, that means that both of these answer
choices were correct.