One of the best things about Android's
Java language is that it's a managed
memory environment that is, you don't
have to be super careful about handling
when objects are created or destroyed.
While this is generally great,
there's some hidden performance problems
lurking under the surface here.
Now remember,
the memory heaps in Android's runtimes
are segmented into spaces,
based on the type of allocation and
how best the system can organize
allocations for future GC events.
And each space has its
own reserved memory size.
When the combined size of an object in
a space begins to approach its upper
limit, a garbage collection event
is kicked off to free up space and
remove unneeded objects.
These GC events aren't generally a
noticeable problem to your performance.
However, a lot of them recurring
over and over and over and
over again can quickly
eat up your frame time.
The more time you're spending doing GCs,
the less time you have to do other stuff
like rendering or streaming audio.
One common situation that developers
can fall into that cause a lot of
these GCs to occur is
known as memory leaks.
Memory leaks are objects which
the application is no longer using, but
the garbage collector fails
to recognize them as unused.
The result is that they
stay resident in your heap,
taking up valuable space that's
never freed up for other objects.
As you continue to leak memory,
the available space in your heap's
generation continues to get smaller and
smaller and smaller, which means that
more GCs will be executed more often
to try to free up space for
normal program execution.
Finding and
fixing leaks is tricky business.
Some leaks are really easy to create,
like making circular references to
objects which the program isn't using.
While other are not so simple,
like holding on handles to class loader
objects as they're being loaded.
In either case, a smooth running,
fast application needs to be aware and
sensitive to memory
leaks that may exist.
I mean, your code's going to be
running on a federation of devices and
different types, and
not all of them are going to have
the same memory footprints and sizes.
Thankfully, there's a simple tool that's
available to help us see where these
leaks might exist
inside the Android SDK.
Let's take a look.