Okay, so now you can log into
your Linux machine, awesome.
You've got a screen full of stuff, and
at the bottom you've got
a line with a $ at the end.
That last line is the shell prompt, and
it means that the system is waiting for
you to give it a command.
So just type something,
it doesn't matter what.
It can be anything.
Just type something in and press Enter.
Huh, you probably got an error saying,
no such command, or
that program isn't installed,
or something like that.
And after that,
you got another shell prompt.
So just type in some random junk,
see what happens.
See if you can find anything that
doesn't make the shell prompt come back.
And when you do find something
that makes the shell prompt not
come back when you press Enter,
describe what it is you did here.