Your app is now in the state that
the saveProfile method knows
that when it is called, it should be
passed data that conforms to the fields
defined ProfileMiniForm class.
Which in practical terms means that the
input data can include display name and
teeShirtSize.
If the input data includes any
other fields, they will be ignored.
Since we also want to store
the user's email address,
we'll do that by getting the email
address of the logged in user.
This of course means that
the user must be logged in.
You can check that by calling
endpoints.get_current_user.
If that does not return to user object,
the user is not logged in.
The endpoints system lets your
code handle this case by raising
an exception, which the front end
can handle by displaying an error or
redirecting to the log in screen.
So you don't have to change the
saveProfile method to get this behavior.
But instead work with
the getProfileFromUser method
where we used dummy data before.
Check out the TODO 2 comments.
Step 1,
make sure the user is authenticated.
If they're not, then we'll raise
the endpoints.UnauthorizedException.
Step 2, use the real data
from the logged in user
instead of the dummy data for
displayName and mainEmail.
Now there's one more thing to
change if you'd like to use
the app from the JavaScript based front
end, as well as from the APIs Explorer.
Take the same WEB_CLIENT_ID that
you used in settings.py and
put it in the JavaScript file app.js,
in place of this web-client-id here.
When you're done,
deploy your code on localhost and
test it, then deploy to appspot.
Check off each one of these boxes
as you finish that step and
then fill in your project ID down here.