Now, modern feature detectors extend Harris corners
into much more advanced features.
They are usually localizable, like corners are.
They also have unique signatures
that summarize the identity of a feature
that's typically invariant to lighting, orientation,
translation and size variance,
as you might find it in the image space.
So, common methods that people use are called HOG,
for histogram of oriented gradients,
or SIFT, for scale invariant feature transform.
All of these methods take corners
and reduce the various variants like rotational variants
by extracting statistics that are invariant to things like
rotation and scale and certain perspective transformation.
I took the liberty to apply SIFT features
to the bridge image,
and what you find here is a myriad of features
that are all very localizable.
There's features over here,
very large ones like the square over here,
which is, I guess, very visible, another square over here,
and very small, tiny features like the square over here and the square over here
that all have a unique signature and can easily be matched across images.
This is called a SIFT feature extractor,
and it's one of the state-of-the-art methods that are very commonly used.
So, if you wish to extract features from an image,
I recommend checking out HOG or SIFT.
You can download software from the web.
They are somewhat involved, and you can learn about them
in advanced computer vision classes.