Things I will cover basically,
I'll introduce to you the concept
of video stabilization.
We'll learn about how we can
estimate the camera emotion
just by analyzing the video given to us.
We'll talk about how we can smooth
the camera paths to be able to then
synthesize a new camera view that
actually is much more smooth, stable.
And how we can render
those stabilized videos.
In addition to that, I will actually
introduce to you the problems associated
with something that is called
the rolling shutter artifact.
That actually is predominantly
visible in lower-end CMOS sensors.
Again, remember,
we've talked about CMOS sensors.
We'll talk about them again a little
bit here, and how we can actually
get rid of those in the case of video,
because again, this will actually
increase the amount of shaking during
a video because of the rolling shutter.