It turns out that that works fine when you actually have Gaussian noise.
Turns out it doesn't work so great when you don't.
When you have some various, shall we say, non-Gaussian noise.
Okay?
So, here in this picture I've got a bunch of red points.
And fitting the line through those points, okay, not very exciting.
Actually, I probably should have had those points spread out.
That's the problem when you steal some other people's slides.
You say, you know I should have spread out those lines a little bit,
but even with all of those points sitting right on the line,
okay, I'm going to add one more point.
All right. Just one.
And it's not going to be a nice point, it's going to be a.
Not a, if it were Gaussian point, it would be very hard to get far away.
Let's suppose my points actually are made up of a bunch of
points that are perturbed by the Gaussian off the line,
plus evil Megan came in and sprinkled a few just nasty points.
What would happen?
Well, here's just one nasty point, bang.
This one point, out here, makes this line the,
quote, best solution for all of those points.
Now, many of you've seen this before for robust fitting.
Bear with me.
That point is one of our outliers.
It doesn't come from the model that we have.
And our model is actually made up of two parts.
Our model is that there's a line and that there's a little bit of Gaussian noise
added, not, there's Gaussian noise added to the points off the line.
This model is the evil Megan model.
And we don't even know about that.
But we would like to sort of be immune to the evil Megan model.
So the question is, how can we do that?
And you know, why is the evil Megan model so annoying to us?
Well the real problem is that squared error, right?
So the bigger the error gets, you square its effect.
That heavily penalizes outliers.
So outliers can have much more of an effect on our
model fitting than we really want them to have.
So the question is how to deal with that.