All right, let's do this in code.
Write a function to down sample
an image to half its size.
You can do this by picking
alternate rows and columns.
Now write another function, this time
blur and then down sample the image.
Here is a test image.
I wonder how long you can
sit on that at a time.
Ok, to relieve that guy of his misery,
let's down sample the image.
This should be half the original size
that is half width, half height.
Once more, and a third time.
Let's do the same with the blur and
down sample function.
All right.
Now we have two images one
eighth the original size.
Let's view the down sampled image.
Magnify to the original size.
And let's compare that
with the other image.
Implement the two functions and
compare the results.
You know what they look like.