So currently when the app launches, we see both the microphone and
the stop buttons.
This if you think about it, isn't really good design.
When the app first appears to the users,
we should only see the microphone button.
This way, there is no confusion about what the user can actually do
on the screen, which is, record audio.
So to hide this stop button,
what we have to do is write code that looks somewhat similar to this.
And this code should execute when the app first launches or
first appears to the user.
So the question for us to answer is, where within our ViewController can we
write code that runs when our app first launches or appears to the user?
I want you to think about this question for a bit.
And see if you can do a Google search to come up with some insights.
Here is your question one more time.
Share your response with us on the discussion forum.
And check this box when you are done.