So far we've seen how there
must be an assignment
that satisfies at least seven-eighths
of the clauses in any 3-CNF formula.
And in fact, the same argument gives
us an algorithm that satisfies
seven-eighths on average.
Just pick a random assignment.
By itself however, this does not
guarantee that we'll actually find
an assignment that satisfies
seven-eighths of the clauses.
To obtain such a guarantee,
we're going to use a technique
called derandomization.
That will take the randomness
of our algorithm out and
give us a deterministic algorithm
with a guaranteed seven-eighths
factor approximation.
An important part of the algorithm
will be a subroutine that
assigns a value to a variable and
simplifies the causes.
We call this procedure instantiate.
Let's say that we want to
set a variable, x1, to true.
Then any clauses not involving
x1 are simply left alone.
And if a clause has an x1 in it,
then it gets set to true.
If a clause has a not x1 in it,
then we just eliminate that
literal from the clause.
If not x1 is the only
literal in the clause,
then we just set the clause to false.
Another important set routine will be
one that calculates the expected number
of clauses that will be satisfied if the
remaining variables are assigned true or
false uniformly at random.
Of course, if a clause is just true,
then it gets assigned a value 1.
And a clause that's just false
gets assigned a value 0.
A single literal gets
assigned a value one-half.
Two literals get assigned
a value of three-quarters.
And three literals gets
a value of seven-eighths.
Remember that there's just one way
to assign the relevant variables so
that the clause is false.
The E of Y procedure simply calculates
these values for every clause and
then sums them up,
using the linearity of expectations.
With these separate teams defined,
we can now write down our
derandomized algorithm as follows.
We start with an empty assignment for
the variables.
Then for each variable and term,
we consider the formula resulting from
the variable Xi being sent to true.
And the one resulting from
Xi being set to false,
between these two we pick the one
that gives a larger value for E of Y.
That is the one where the expected
number of satisfied clauses is greater,
assuming that the remaining
variables are set at random.
Note that we're using our knowledge
of how a random assignment
would behave here.
But we actually aren't
using any randomization.
Having picked a better way of
assigning the variable Xi,
we update the set of clauses and record
our assignment of the variable Xi.
The reason this algorithm works is
that it maintains the invariant
that the expected number of clauses of C
that would be satisfied if the remaining
variables were assigned uniformly
at random is at least 7m over 8.
This is true at the beginning,
just by our previous theorem.
But this expectation is just the average
of the expected number that would be
satisfied in Cp and the expected
number that would be satisfied in Cm.
So by picking C to be the one for
which this E of Y is greater,
the lavariant is maintained.
Of course, at the end of the algorithm,
all the variables have been assigned, so
this expectation is just counting
up the number of true clauses.
This technique is known as the method
of conditional expectation and
it has a number of clever applications.
Overall then we've shown that
there's the deterministic algorithm
which given any 3-CNF formula
finds an assignment that satisfies
at least 7/8 of the clauses.
Remarkably, it turns out that
this is the best we can do
assuming that P is not equal to NP.
For this argument we turn to the concept
of probabilistically checkable proofs.