So far, we've been working
in the Tag Manager UI, but
now it's time to code our app to
use the daily special variable.
So what we're going to do is
add the default container
to our Android Studio project.
And the default container is
the thing that you just downloaded.
So the default container contains the
initial values for the variables, but
we're going to want our code
to get the latest values.
So we'll add code to download
the latest container into our app, and
we'll do that in the onCreate
Method in the main activity.
It's important to save
a reference to the container so
that you can get hold of the container
from any other place in your app.
And then throughout your app,
wherever you need, you get the container
and you get what you want out of it
by retrieving the value
of the relevant key.
And that's a simple get call.
Now then,all of these tasks, adding
the default container to a project and
writing this code,
are one time only tasks.
After you've done these steps, the only
thing you need to do when the special of
the day changes is to update the value
in Tag Manager and publish the change.
So the first thing is to find the file
that you downloaded from Tag Manager.
It likely starts with GTM and it will
probably be in your downloaded folder.
You're going to have to rename it.
The name must only have
lowercase letters and
underscores, no hyphens allowed.
For some reason the downloaded file
has capital letters and hyphens so
you definitely have to rename it.
You need to copy a file
into the raw folder
in the res folder in Android Studio.
And you'll need to
create the raw folder.
So the file that's now in the raw folder
holds the initial default value for
everything in the Tag Manager container.
Usually, your app will
get what it needs from the latest
version of the container.
But it's required to
have a default container,
even if it's just an empty file.
Okay, go ahead and do these steps now.