So the numbers that I'm going to
give you here come from a report
in the first quarter of 2015.
The CVV or 3 digit code we have
credit cards actually goes for
$2, not very much.
Credit card information, actually
there's a range for it depending on what
kind of credit card you have, so
this could go anywhere from $5 to $45.
A PayPal or
Ebay account was going for $27.
And health information could be
obtained for $10 in the black market.
So the exact numbers are not as
important as something that's striking.
These values are not very high,
well that's okay because
they have millions of these.
So if you take these values and
you multiply the two, you can see that
this could be an attractive thing for
a criminal who's out to make some money.