There's another useful operation you can
do when you have two NumPy arrays of
the same length.
This time, the second NumPy array
needs to contain booleans, and
the first can contain any type,
not just numbers.
For example, suppose your first array,
a, contains the numbers 1, 2,
3, 4, and 5.
And your second array, b, contains
the booleans false, false, true,
true and true.
Then the code a[b]
would return a shorter
array containing only the elements 3,4,
and 5.
The second array is called
an index array, and
it tells you which elements
of the first array to keep.
So here we didn't keep 1
because that element was false.
We didn't keep 2 because that was false.
But we did keep 3, 4, and
5 because those were true.
When you combine this with the
vectorized operations you learned about
previously, this can be very powerful.
In this example,
I kept all the elements greater than 2.
So I could have created the boolean
array b with the code b = a > 2.
I could also have created this array
without using the variable b at all.
To do this I would use the code a [a>2],
and that would have the same result.
In my opinion,
this piece of code is a very concise and
clear way of saying keep all the
elements of a that are greater than two.
Right now it may take more effort to
understand this piece of code than it
would have taken you
to understand a loop.
First, you have to remember
that a is an array.
Then you have to remember that comparing
an array to a single number is
a vectorized operation that
returns an array of booleans, and
then you have to remember
about index arrays.
However once you're used to it this
can really speed up the process of
writing your code.
And as usual, this code will run faster
than the loop since all the operations
are implemented in C.
To give you some practice using index
arrays I'm going to take an example from
the previous lesson.
I want you to write a function
that takes in two NumPy arrays.
The first, time_spent,
contains the total time
each student spends in
the classroom in the first week.
The second, days_to_cancel,
contains contains the number of
days before that student cancelled.
I want you to calculate the mean
time spent in the first week
among only students who do not
cancel for at least 7 days.
As a hint, you'll first want to convert
days_to_cancel into an array of
booleans that you can
use as an index array.