In most situations in this game tree,
our computer player o wins.
But in a few situations,
the game ends with our opponent
x winning at level five.
If our computer player
makes a poor choice for
its first move,
x can win no matter what o does.
Clearly we never want our computer
player to make this bad first move.
To avoid that situation we could
keep a table of best first moves for
this board configuration.
This table is called an opening book.
Similar tables can be kept for
end games.
But how do we make discovering
these bad moves automatic?
Better yet, how do we discover the best
moves for our computer player?
The answer is the minimax algorithm,
a version of which we will see next.