Now that we have our Data Prep to be
used in a Clustering Process, and
we have an idea of which Variables and
Principle Components we might want to
incorporate, it's time to start looking
at the actual clustering process itself.
That's what we'll focus on
throughout this lesson.
Now, there are at least a few different
methods that have been developed in
recent years, that will divide a number
of objects into relatively homogeneous,
or similar segments or clusters.
They primarily fall into
two types of methods.
One is called a Hierarchical method, and
the other is called a K-Centroid method.
I will go over the high level
characteristics of both of these,
as well as some of the differences.
Later in the lesson, we will look in
detail at the K-Centroid method, for
our hands on exercise.