As an Andrew developer
looking at code for
an existing app is
a critical skill to develop.
If you join a team in the future,
it's likely that you would work on
an existing app instead of creating one
from scratch.
Some major projects may
have hundreds of files and
you may not have time to
read through all of them.
However, you can still get a high level
idea by looking at the filenames,
then looking closer at the files
related to the work you need to do.
So in this case,
we currently have a small project.
So, in the quiz we asked you
to look at each file and
let's do that now together.
So, I am going to start off by going
over here to the project changing list,
to the project view and when I look
at the code base for the first time,
I expand out the Java folder where
all the logic of the app is.
Then I had over and
expand up the resource folder
which has everything related
to the appearance of the app.
In the Java folder, we have one
Java file called main activity and
it turns out that main activity
is the main screen of our app.
Now we can move on to the app
resource files located in
the app/source/main/restdirectory.
These files control how the app
appears on different devices.
Resources can include xml files,
images, and other media files.
We could start by expanding
out the layout folder.
Here we have the activity_main.xml file.
This file defines the layout for
the main screen of our app, and
it contains a vertical linear
layout with four text views.
Then we have our mit mat folder,
which is a special folder just for
the app icon.
Other images in your app should
go in the drywall folder.
Then we have the values folder.
This contains the colors.xml file which
defines the colors of our app, the app
theme colors and the color associated
with each category of the words.
Next we have the dimensions.xml
file which contains dimensions
such as the width and
height values for our app.
It also contains the list item height
which we've here set to be 88 dp.
Moving down,
we have the strings.xml file.
These are all the text strings that
will appear to the user in the app and
we put them in a single file so
that we can easily translate
the app into other languages.
And lastly we have the styles.xml file.
Here we define the theme of the app and
specify the theme colors.
We also have the style for
how a category should look and
that's why each category on the main
screen of the app looks similar in
terms of height, padding,
font size and more.
So now let's move to
the third task of the quiz
which is to create a visual diagram
of the different parts of the app and
everyone's diagram will be different,
which is a good thing.
So here's one example that
represents the big picture
of the Miwok App code base.
After reading all those files,
maybe your takeaway was
there are a lot of resources the
determine the appearance of an app and
a single Java file for
the logic of that.
So here's another example of
a diagram you could have drawn.
We have an image of what the app looks
like with the four categories and
you label this as the main
activity.java file.
With an annotation that the layout for
this activity is defined in
the activity_main.xml layout file.
Then the theme of the app is
defined in the styles.xml file.
How a category item appears is also
determined by a style that is defined in
the styles.xml file.
The background color of the categories
is defined in the colors.xml file.
By the category names are defined
in the strings.xml file.
Lastly, the list item height is
defined of the dimensions.xml file.
So, regardless of how you chose
to create a diagram of the app,
you just thought like a professional
developer and as we start to add more
features having a mental map of the app
in our head will help us figure out what
parts of the app would need to modify to
make these new features work properly.
For example, if we receive a feature
request from our designer to change
the layout of the main screen,
we should head over to
the activity_main.xml layout file.
But the feature request is about
changing the name of the app.
We should head over to
the styles.xml file.
And if we need to change how the app
responds when you click on a view,
then we should look at the logic
in the MainActivity.java file.