at this point you've built and trained
deep neural networks from the ground up
congratulations this is an amazing set
of skills with a wide range of
applications however deep learning
engineers often don't actually start
with a blank slate when they're building
neural networks starting from scratch
can be time-consuming it's not just
architecting the network but also
experimenting with it
training it and adjusting it which can
take days or even weeks to accelerate
the process engineers often begin with a
pre train network and then modify it
fine-tuning an existing network is a
powerful technique because improving a
network takes much less effort than
creating one from scratch going even
further we can take an existing network
and repurpose it for related but
different task repurposing a network is
called transfer learning because you're
transferring the learning from an
existing network to anyone to learn more
about why transfer learning is so
important for building deep neural
networks we're going to get some advice
from brian Catanzaro a deep learning
expert in video