Unlike dispatch async, dispatch
sync won't return immediately and
run the closure sometime
in the near future.
It will wait until the closure
exits before exiting itself.
Take a closure look at the function
with big image that we wrote previously
to download a heavy image.
Would it be okay to replace the last
call to dispatch async by dispatch sync?
Would it be okay to call
dispatch sync in here?
Certainly yes,
after all once the handler is
finished there's nothing left to do.
Therefore, it doesn't matter
if you call dispatch sync or
dispatch async, it's pretty much
the same, or absolutely not.
What if this completion closure
does something stupid and blocks?
What do you think?