So when a new conference is created,
there might be a variety of
tasks that need to be executed,
such as starting the process to book
the venue, or creating the agenda,
organizing the catering, or sending
a confirmation email to the organizer.
You want to do all of these tasks in the
background, rather than try to complete
everything before the create
conference function returns.
In this exercise, you're going
to use the default task queue to
send the confirmation email when
someone creates a conference.
The learning goal is to understand
how to use task queues.
But you can imagine there are many
other tasks that need to be completed
when a new conference is created.
To execute a task in
the background using a task queue,
the first thing you need to do
is define the work to be done.
It's up to you to write
the code to execute the task.
This can be in a separate handler or
an endpoints method, or
anywhere else that can
be accessed by a URL.
We've provided the email sending code,
however, so
you can focus on thinking about queues.
An optional thing you might want to
do is configure queue in queue.yaml.
One exception is that if you're
using the default queue,
then you don't need to
do any configuration.
You'll use the default
queue in this case.
But you can check the documentation for
configuration options.
And then you'll need to write
code to add tasks to the queue.
Using the default task queue
in Python is pretty easy.
To end queue a task,
you'll call the taskqueue.add function.
In this simple case, you only need
to provide the URL to use and
additional parameters that
you want to pass to that URL.
In this case, you at least want
the user's email to send to,
and the conference information.
If you're going to use
the non-default queue,
you'd also pass in
the queue name as well.
You can also set other configuration
options such as the name of the task,
the HTTP method,
retry options and so forth.
Once you've implemented all this,
deployed to appspot and added a new
conference to kick off the process, you
can then go to the developer console and
look at the queues and
tasks and their status.
As well as delete tasks that
are currently in a queue, etc.
One thing to remember is that unless
you specified how many times to
retry a task,
if you specified an incorrect URL,
it will retry indefinitely so
test your queues carefully.
And now it's your turn to add
task queues to your application.
We've provided most of the code
in the additions folder,
under todo2,
you just have to put it all together.
See the TODO 2 comments
in the relevant files.
You'll need to modify app.yaml,
main.py, and conference.py.