I was happy with the way
the overall interview went.
I liked how Lorenzo began every problem
with a very structured approach,
noting down every piece of
information that I gave him.
And then he walked me
through his thought process.
That was very helpful and I was never
feeling lost or disconnected from him.
In some cases his answers
weren't fully developed and
he required a little bit of coaching or
guidance in order to get there.
But that was a good sign that he's
open to receiving feedback, and
probably a good indicator that he'll
be able to work well in teams.
His project was really impressive.
And it really demonstrated to
me how passionate he was for
machine learning as well as in music,
and how he was able to
bring those fields together to create
something that he really liked.
It is not necessary for you to always
come up with a perfect answer, or
get on the right track on
your very first attempt.
What is important, however, is for you
to communicate with your interviewer,
and explain to them how you're
thinking about the problem,
how you're breaking it down and so on.
Sometimes you might land on the exact
answer they're looking for, but
that's kind of rare.
So you often have to rely on other
aspects of your application,
of your profile.
For instance if you've worked on
a project that you're really passionate
about, talk about it, try and squeeze
it in somewhere in the interview.
That will really help you convey to
the interviewer how passionate you feel
about machine learning.