Let's get started with Tales from the Genome.
>> We're really excited that you've decided to join
us on our exploration of the human experience through biology.
>> We really hope that this going to
be an awesome learning odysee that just might
change the way you think about yourself and
others in a fundamental way. For example, whether
you know it or not, the objects in
these two images are intimately related. The image
on the right, I think you already know what that is. But the image on the left,
represents a DNA molecule, the substance that
makes up all of our genomes. All living
things including you, are created from their
genomes which are a set of genetic instructions.
>> That seems pretty mechanical to me.
>> Well it is, sort of, Biology is just Chemistry that crawls.
>> So you mean like chemistry that comes to life. Well yeah, what I mean
is that every physical aspect of who you are is deeply rooted in the chemical
engineering processes that interprets the information
within your genome. Together with environmental
influence, your genome and unique development,
the chemistry of you is what brought
you to where you are today. But, I am a psychology person. So
it's not just the physical aspects, right? What about our feeling and behaviors?
>> Well, your physical aspects. You size,
your metabolism. Even your behaviors and your interests.
>> So even the personality traits, too.
>> Exactly. These
are all deeply influenced by your genome's instructions. If you
were to zoom into your body. You would see that you
are made up of trillions of individual cells, all different,
because they read different parts of your genome's instructions. Some are
skin cells that use melanin to protect you from UV
rays from the sun. Some are stomach cells that help you
digest products that you eat and drink. Others are red
blood cells that carry oxygen to all parts of your body.
All of these cells and more. Use your genomes instructions
to build who you are. You are a giant conglomeration of
cells, all meticulously reading the book of instructions to keep you
alive and functioning. Forming the basis for all of your traits.
>> Now, this course will help you relate your traits to this book
of instruction. And show you some really amazing life stories along the way.