So we just saw how we can modify
the parameters of the query method in
order to return back the specific
cursor that we want.
Now what the heck is a cursor?
So in short,
a cursor is an object that represents
a bunch of rows in the database.
Now assuming our entire database looks
like this, if we use our query method
on this table on the database, we can
specify what values we want to return.
And then this information is returned
to us in the form of a cursor object.
Now remember that in
our previous example,
we'll use the parameters
of the query method
to get just the information we
want back from our cursor object.
So if our selection argument is select
all the pets from the pets table.
We'll get returned back a cursor object
that contains the rows of the database.
Now if we were to further specify that
we want to select from the pets table
only the pet whose name is Toto.
We would get back this cursor object
that contains all the rows where
the pet's name is Toto.
And we just have this one.
So erase that example and
let's start fresh with another one.
Say we want to select the name and
breed from the pets table.
So this means we narrow our table to
only return back these two columns.
And it's returned back to us as
a cursor object that contains the rows.
But only the details from the name and
breed column.
So all those cursor objects we just saw
are instances of Android's cursor class.
So this class contains methods
that allow us to access and
move through our cursor object.
So for
example, moving through the rows if
the cursor object is more than one row.
And we'll cover these
methods in more detail later.