As a whole, we refer to this process representation as an address space.
We said earlier that the potential range of addresses from
v0 to vmax represents the maximum size of the process address space.
And we call these addresses virtual addresses.
So these, between v0 and vmax are the addresses that
are used by the process to reference some of its state.
We call these addresses virtual, because they don't have to correspond to
actual locations in the physical memory.
Instead, the memory management hardware and
operating system components responsible for memory management, like page tables
maintain a mapping between the virtual addresses and the physical addresses.
By using this type of mapping, we decouple the layout of
the data in the virtual address space, which may be complex and
it may depend on the specifics of the application or the tools that we used,
like how the compiler chose to lay that data out.
That's completely decoupled with how that data is laid out in physical memory.
And that will allow us to maintain physical memory management simple and
not in any way dictate it by the data layout or processes that are executing.
For instance, the variable x may be at a location 03c5
in the virtual address space.
And this may correspond to a completely different address,
0f0f in physical memory.
The way this happens is when the process requests some
memory to be allocated to it at a particular virtual address.
The address of the physical memory that the operating system actually allocates
may be completely different, and instead of notifying the process about
the details of where exactly in memory that variable really is.
The operating system will create a mapping between this virtual address,
03c5, and the physical address, 0f0f, where x actually is.
So then whenever the process tries to access x, this mapping is referenced,
and in reality the exact physical location where x is will be accessed.
As long as the mapping between 03c5 and 0f0f is present in this mapping table,
this is a page table and this is a page table entry, any access of the process
to x will, in fact, access the correct physical location where x is stored.