Let's show an example of where
a backwards search makes sense.
I'm going to describe a world
in which there's one action,
the action of buying a book,
and the precondition is we
have to know which book it is and
let's identify them by ISBN number.
We can buy ISBN number b, and
the effect is that we own b,
and, probably, there should be
something about money, but we're
going to leave that out for
now, to make it simple.
Then, the goal would be to
own ISBN number 0136042597.
Now if we try to solve this problem
with forward search, we'd start
in the initial state and let's say the
initial state is we don't own anything,
and then we think about
what actions can we apply?
Well if there are 10 million different
books, 10 million ISBN numbers then
there's a branching factor of 10 million
coming out of this node and we'd have to
try them all in order until we happen
to hit upon one that was the right one.
Seems very inefficient.
If we go in a backward direction
then we start at the goal.
The goal is to own this number.
Then we look at our
available actions and
out of the 10 million actions,
there's only one action schema and
that action schema can match
the goal in exactly one way.
When b equals this number.
And therefore, we know the action
is to buy this number.
And we can connect the goal
to the initial state in
the backwards direction
in just one step.
So that's the advantage
of doing backwards or
regression search rather
than forward search.