The answer is that the number of states
is the crossproduct of the numbers of
all the variables,
since they're each independent and
any combination can occur.
So for the power,
we have three possible positions.
The camera has two,
the Brush Height has five.
The dirt has two for
each of the ten positions.
So that's 2 to the tenth, or 1,024.
And then the robot's position can be
any of those ten positions as well.
And that works out to 307,200
states in the state space.
And notice how a fairly trivial problem,
we're only modeling a few variables and
only ten positions works out to
a large number of state space.
And that's we need efficient algorithms
for searching through state spaces.
[BLANK_AUDIO]