In previous exercises,
we added in the JumpState
to determine when GigaGal is up
in the air versus on the ground.
We added the Facing state to determine
whether we should display the left or
the right facing sprite.
So, now let's add in WalkState to
determine when GigaGal is just standing
versus walking.
Then we'll make sure we're
updating the WalkState properly.
Then we'll add into our giant
if-else block in Render.
Then we'll add the walking sprites into
our giant if else block in Render.
I know this is getting pretty ugly and
you might be thinking,
shouldn't we be doing this
with switch statements?
Well, you can do it with three nested
switch statements if you really want to.
I think this is a little bit cleaner.
The result is a Gigagal that stands,
jumps, and walks.
Follow the to dos in the course code.
To load up the walking sprite,
create the walk state enumeration, and
display the proper sprites with Gigagal
is walking versus standing or jumping.