Welcome back to Introduction of Computer Vision.
Today we're going to wrap up our unit on essentially calibration and
stereo and we're going to talk about the fundamental matrix.
Last time, we developed the relationship between two views of two calibrated
cameras where I actually knew the rotation and translation between them.
And what was cool is we derived, we essentially went with what the geometric
constraint was that whole epi-polar constraint that we had shown very early on.
And we derived from the geometric constraint, an algebraic constraint.
And in particular we defined something called the essential matrix which related
between two views or I should say, world points of two calibrated cameras.
So the same point in the scene, the two different views of it,
what the relationship was between them.
But you might ask, suppose I don't have a calibrated camera.
All right, well look, let's think about the intuition.
If you gave me two images, and
you gave me enough points to tell me that this point is this one,
this one, this one, this one, gave me enough corresponding pairs.
It feels like you should be able to figure out,
say the epipolar lines, that is how the, how the lines map across and
what the, what the correspondence should be for all the other points.
When I say correspondence, where,
where they can be along the epipolar line depending upon their depth.
Well, today what we're going to do is we're going to make that intuition real.
We'll, we'll do the mathematics of this relationship between two
uncalibrated points.