Let's take a look at the file
structure for the webpage and
D3.js that's added to the project.
I'm going to open up sublime and
then I'm just going to drag and
drop the folder that I
downloaded into sublime.
Now I'm using sublime text as
my preferred editor here but
you could use any text editor
that you're comfortable with.
So opening up our DataViz demo project,
I can see I have two subfolders,
assets and lib.
And then I have a demo CSS file and
an HTML file.
The assets folder contains a lot
of images an svg for Facebook, and
then some other pngs that
will be images on the page.
And then there's also a lib folder
which contains Bootstrap, which is for
formatting different elements
on the page for design,
and then we have our D3 code, which
is minified and uglified, and then we
also have jQuery code, which will,
is very useful for manipulating the DOM.
The CSS file contains styles which
will style our web page, and
then we have our HTML demo code.
This is the DOM, or the HTML elements,
that make up the web page.
Now, whenever I encounter
a new technology or a library,
I always like to
interactively explore it.
And I might explore in a repple, in my
terminal or the console of a webpage.
I find that having immediate
feedback in the console and
having tools like auto complete makes
it really easy to use the browser and
increases the speed
at which I can learn.
So let's open up this HTML
file inside of a webpage.
So opening up our JavaScript console,
we have the html for
the webpage, we have the JavaScript
console itself, and then we have
the visual display of the webpage
which we would see in our browser.
The nice part about this environment
is that we can inspect the HTML,
the CSS, and the JavaScript,
all in one place.
If we'd like to review the raw source
file for the page, we can do that by
right-clicking on the page, and
then clicking on view page source.
This is the HTML file that
the browser receives, and
then parses to render the visual
display of the webpage.
And what looks like the HTML source
displayed in the right web console
over here is actually
the document-object model, or DOM.
It's a representation of the HTML
source file that you just saw.
And notice that as you hover
over different elements,
they get highlighted in the page.
Here's a container and
here's the footer.
All right, now that you have some basic
understanding of this webpage and
D3, let's hand you over to Jonathan for
a quick quiz.