Typically, web services really mean that you're conforming to
a certain alphabet soup of standards that are out there.
On the data side, it means you're using XML and possibly some some other
related protocols such as SOAP, RDF, OWL, JSON and so on.
On the services side, if you're doing full, full-blown web services.
You're probably using WSDL which is the Web Services Description Language.
Which gives a way of actually defining the service in such a way that
then code generation technology can build some of the,
the pieces that you need for managing it.
The third element of web services is UDDI which stands for
Universal Description Discovery and
Integration, and what that really means is "Yellow Pages".
Using UDDI you describe your service, it gets posted to some kind of server,
then that your potential clients can look up when they need a service,
and they form, in fact, provide that service.