Hey, welcome back.
So while you where taking
a break our designer provided us
updated designs of what what the app
should look like, and here they are.
We could leave the app as is, but
as it stands,
the audio feature is hard to discover.
Now we want to provide some
indication to the user
that the list items are clickable and
that by clicking it they can hear
the pronunciation of each word.
So our designer provided these designs.
And notice that each list item
now displays a play arrow icon
to indicate that the item is clickable.
So in this task,
you'll make your version of the Miwok
app look like these designs.
I'd like you to add
the play icon to the app.
Our designer also requested that
the icon be 24dps by 24dps,
have it be vertically centered
within the list item, and
also positioned 16dps from
the right edge of the screen.
Now as a heads up,
you might need to make some significant
changes to your layout in order
to make this new layout work.
[INAUDIBLE] icons, you can download
it from [INAUDIBLE] icons here.
So, this library was created by
the Google design team for you to use
in your own apps in order to comply
with the material design guidelines.
So, this is a valuable resource if you
want to go on to create other apps but
don't have a desire to create icons for
you.
Now if we scroll down
here to the AV section.
There's a play icon that we can use.
So click on it, and
it'll give you options for
how you can download the icon.
So, we want to choose
the 24dp version of the icon,
as requested by our designer.
Then I want to choose the white version,
as opposed to the black version.
And then download PNGs.
So the file's downloaded as
a ZIP file onto my desktop, and
then I unzipped it right here,
so let's open that up.
So we got different versions of the app.
So let's open up the Android folder.
So you organize these drawable folders
for the various density buckets.
Now inside this drawable-hdpi folder, we
have the hdpi version of the play arrow.
Now, I'd like you to go into
each of these folders and
copy over the image into your version
of the Miwok app in Android Studio.
So that means the HDPI icon goes
into the existing drawable-hdpi
folder in our app.
The drawable-npdi icon goes into the
drawable-ndpi folder in Android studio,
and so on, and so on.
And you can also rename the file as
well so that they have a shorter name.
So something like ic_play_arrow.
Remember where ic stands for icon.
Now remember that we should include all
versions of the assets in our app so
that the icon doesn't appear
blurry on certain devices.
And once you're done with this task, I'd
like you to check this box to continue.