Now why do we have to interweave
planning and execution?
Mostly because of properties of the
environment that make it difficult to
deal with.
The most important one is if
the environment is stochastic,
that is if we don't know for
sure what an action is going to do.
If we know what everything
is going to do,
we can plan it out right from the start.
But if we don't, we have to be able
to deal with contingencies of, say,
I tried to move forward and the wheel
slipped and I went someplace else.
Or the breaks might skid,
or, with our walking,
our feet don't go 100% straight.
Or consider the problem
of traffic lights.
If the traffic light is red,
then the result of the action of go
forward through the intersection
is bound to be different than
if the traffic light is green.
Another difficulty we have to deal
with is multiagent environments.
If there are other cars and
people that can get in their way,
we have to plan about what
they're going to do and
we have to react when they
do something unexpected.
And we can only know that at
execution time, not at planning time.
The other big problem is
with partial observability.
Suppose we've come up with a plan
to go from A to S to F to B,
that plan looks like it'll work.
But we know that at S the road
to F is sometimes closed and
there will be a sign there telling
us whether it's closed or not.
But when we start off we can't read that
sign, so that's partial observability.
Another way to look at it is, when we
start off we don't know what state we're
in, we know we're in A, but we don't
know if we're in A, in the state
where the road is closed, or if we're in
A in the state where the road is open.
And it's not until we get to S that we
discover what state we're actually in,
and then we know if we can
continue along that route or
if we have to take a detour south.
Now, in addition to these
properties of the environment,
we can also have difficulty because
of lack of knowledge on our own part.
So, if some model of the world
is unknown, that is for example,
we have map or
GPS software that's inaccurate or
incomplete, then we won't be able
to execute a straight line plan.
And similarly,
often we want to deal with a case where
the plans have to be hierarchical.
And certainly a plan like
this is at a very high level.
We can't really execute the action of
going from A to S when we're in a car.
All the actions that we can
actually execute are things like
turn the steering wheel
a little bit to the right,
press on the pedal a little bit more.
So those are the low level
steps of the plan, but
those aren't sketched out in detail.
When we start, we only have the high
level parts of the plan, and then it's
during execution that we schedule
the rest of low level parts of the plan.
Now, most of these difficulties can be
addressed by changing our point of view.
Instead of planning in
a space of world states,
we plan in a space of belief states.
To understand that,
let's look at a state.