Here's a code snippet illustrating thread creation.
Two threads are involved in this system.
The parent thread that's executing this code and
the child that gets created via this fork.
Both threads perform this operations safe_insert which manipulates some
shared list that's initially empty, let's say.
Let's assume initially the process begins with one parent thread,
T0 in this case.
At some point thread 0 calls fork and it creates a child T1.
Now, T1 will need to execute safe_insert with an argument 4.
As soon as T1 is created, the parent thread continues its execution and at some
point it will reach a point where it calls safe_insert of 6, in this case.
So it's trying to insert the element 6 into the list.
Because these threads are running concurrently, and are constantly being
switched when executing on the CPU, the order in which these
safe_insert operations on the parent and the child thread is not clear.
It is not guaranteed that when this fork operation
completes the execution will actually switch to T1 and
will allow T1 to perform its safe_insert before T0 does.
Or, if after the fork, although the thread is created,
T0 will continue and the safe_insert for
argument 6 that T0 performs will be the first one to be performed.
So as a result, both the list may have a state where the child
completes its safe_insert before the parent or the other way around,
the parent completes before the child does.
Both of these are possible executions.
Finally, the last operation in this code snippet is this join.
So we're calling join with T1.
If this join is called when T1 has actually completed,
it will return immediately.
If this join occurs while T1 is still executing, the parent thread
will be blocked here until T1 finishes the end of the safe_insert operation.
In this particular example,
the results of the child processing are available through this shared list.
So really the join isn't a necessary part of the code.
We will be able to access the results of the child thread regardless.