The answer is every kernel convolution is linear.
Each pixel becomes the linear sum of, in this case, 2 pixels
that are weighted by plus 1 and minus 1, but in terms of the original variables,
which is the original image, this resulting sum, minus the left pixel plus the right pixel,
is a linear equation in the original pixel values.
The same is true for the Gaussian kernel of size 5 by 5.
It is a linear kernel because it just adds up all these values
summed by the Gaussian kernel.
Absolute value is nonlinear.
The function that governs absolute value for input and output looks like this,
and there is a nonlinear kink over here.
The same is true for gradient magnitude.
There are squares in there, which are nonlinear,
and the square root makes it a nonlinear operation.
The absolute brightness is a linear operation.
It's just like a Gaussian kernel with a uniform mask.
It just adds up all the values and divides them by the number of pixels.
It is a linear function in all the input pixels.