Let's walk through the
PlaySoundsViewController+Audio class extension to
understand what exactly this code is doing.
As you master these concepts,
you'll be making great strides towards
becoming a skilled iOS developer.
Make sure you have the
PlaySoundsViewController+Audio.swift file
open, and navigate to the top.
The first thing you see is a struct of
alert messages. This is a convenient way
to have the alert messages in a single
place. If you have strings or other
static items that you want to use
throughout your app, this is a good
practice to follow. Below that, you can
see the PlayingState enumeration,
which will be used by the configureUI
function to set the button states
depending on if you're playing or not
playing any audio. Next up is the setupAudio
function which is where we try to
load the audio recording file past in
from the RecordSoundViewController.
If loading the audio file fails, we present
an alert message to the user.
By the way, did you notice these MARK
statements here in the comments?
These are to make it easier for you to
jump around your code. If you left-click
the last item in the editor toolbar, you
can see section headings in bold.
These section headings correspond to the MARK
statements we see in the comments. And if
you click a section header, the editor
will jump you to the right location.
So I’ll click Alerts and jumps me to the
Alerts. And I’ll click Audio Functions,
and it jumps me back to the Audio
Functions. The playSound function is
the main function in this extension.
As the name suggests, it carries out playing
back audio. This function has something
you probably haven't seen before, that is
optional parameters. See this code
=nil that comes after the rate parameter?
This indicates that rate is an optional
parameter to the function. That means if
you don't pass a rate into the function,
it will automatically be set to this
default value of nil. pitch, echo and
reverb are also optional parameters.
But for echo and reverb, if they are
not passed into the function, then
they're set to false. The first part of
this function is to grab the AVAudioEngine
and create a AVAudioPlayerNode.
Next we check if the rate or the
pitch parameters were passed in, since
they're optional. The way we do this
check may look a little weird at first,
as we're doing a value binding inside of
an if statement. See the line here,
“if let pitch = pitch”? you should really read
it as “if the pitch variable is not nil,
then execute this if statement,
otherwise we'll skip over this code and
go on to the next if statement. if the
rate variable is not nil, then we'll
execute this if statement,
otherwise we'll skip it and move on to
the next line of code. The concept of
value binding like we see here will be
covered in greater detail later in this program.
Next we create echo and reverb
nodes, but we'll only use them if the
echo or reverb parameters were passed in
and set to true. We can have either echo
and reverb, just echo just reverb or neither.
These if statements wire up the
connections correctly based on any of
the cases we just mentioned.
Lastly we tell the audio player to stop
playing any current audio and schedule
our recorded audio for playback.
This ensures that the recorded audio is
in memory and ready to be played.
This part here that looks like another
function is actually a trailing closure.
Closures are another concept that will
be covered later in the program. They're
essentially functions or chunks of code
that can be passed around just like
regular variables. The scheduleFile
function takes a closure that it runs
when the audio file is ready to start
playing. The code in this closure sets a
timer to fire when the audio is done
playing, that resets the buttons to the
notPlaying state. Now that everything is
setup, we try to start the audio engine
in the audio node playback. When the
execution reaches this point, the audio
would be playing. The stopAudio
function is in charge of stopping the audio.
Remember that timer we set back in
the playSound function? We don't want it
to fire as we're stopping the sound here.
So this if statement invalidates or
cancels that timer. Collectively the rest
of the lines of code stop the
audioPlayerNode and the audioEngine itself.
connectAudioNodes is a helper function
to connect a set of audio notes together
in the audioEngine. As with most helper
functions, this just cuts down on the
duplication of code in the playSound
function. Next we come to the UI
Functions, which are really just in
charge of enabling and disabling the
playback buttons and the stop button.
These are helper functions and they help
us by avoiding duplication of code. We
have one place to enable or disable the
buttons depending on if we are playing
or not playing audio. You can also see
that configureUI itself uses another
helper function to toggle the playback
buttons. If you pass in false, they all
get disabled. If you pass in true,
they'll all be enabled. Last up is the
showAlert function, which simply
displays an alert to the user using
UIAlertController if something goes wrong.
That's it. I take you through the class
extension that allows the audio to be
played back with various sound effects.
Remember there's no harm in playing
around with this code, you should feel
free to experiment changing settings and
more.