Now we'll write the second half of
the Gaussian elimination algorithm,
which brings a system into reduced
row-echelon form, or RREF for short.
Remember that this is the unique
triangular form in which the pivot or
leading variables each have
a coefficient of 1 and
are each in exactly one equation.
There are no terms above or
below that equation with that variable.
To really ensure uniqueness, we have
to add the technical condition that
if the system contains
equations of the form 0 = k for
non-zero k, then k must equal 1.
And all such equations must come before
any equations of the form 0 = 0.
But for our purposes,
it will be fine as long as you put
all equations of the form 0 = 0 and
0 = k at the end of the system.
And this will happen if you use
the triangular form algorithm
we computed last time.
I've added another function
called compute_rref to my module.
It will return a new system
in reduced row echelon form
that has the same solution
set as the original system.
Notice that I make sure the system is
in triangular form by first running
compute_triangular_form, which
we coded previously.
This gives me a copy of the system in
triangular form, which is helpful,
because I can then assume that
the system is in that form for
all my later operations.
Now go ahead and
finish coding compute_rref.
So you can check your work,
I'll provide some test cases for
you to run in the instructor notes
like we did for triangular form.
If you need a hint,
the first portion of the solution video
will contain pseudocode for
the main structure of the procedure.