Up until now, we've really been doing really mostly image processing where
you take an image in, sum of I of x,y and you apply some function to it and
you get out a new image what I'm labelling is I prime of x,y.
And that's great and there's whole courses, in fact, entire careers.
Hundreds of thousands of PhDs written on image processing.
But that's not why we're here.
We're here to talk about real computer vision.
In real vision you still take an image in, but what you get out is good stuff.
All right, the whole idea is that we're putting images in and
we're getting stuff out.
So what are some examples of stuff?
Well, maybe just a line.
So here we have an image on the left and
some edge description of it in the middle, and
you can see a whole bunch of lines that have been found within this image.
Or maybe you want to find circles.
Actually it's a little hard to see, but there's a bowling ball there.
And the way the bowling ball was found was find all the circles in the image.
Well guess what?
There's only one circle and that's the bowling ball.
Or, here's some more circles.
Just find the coins.
And in fact I'll tell you that this particular picture was put
together by a TI TA of mine a huge number of years ago.
He's now a pretty famous researcher doing stuff on at I can't say where.
But this was in order to show how to do a Hough transform on circles.
And you might even find a good stuff as like.
Find me this car.
So you see on the,
on the left here just some examples of where we might locate the car.
But actually, the car is found right in the middle.
Actually, this is a notion of an arbitrary shape.
And in fact, we're going to get to how to do finding an arbitrary shape.
Actually not this lecture, not this lesson, not the one after it.
But the one after that, where we talk about a generalized Hough transform.