As it turns out, the correct
answer is iterative deepening A*.
This problem is much
harder than it sounds,
simply due to the size
of the search space.
This table shows the number of nodes in
the search tree as a function of depth.
Clearly the problem becomes
intractable quickly.
However, in 1997,
Richard Korf published an approach
using iterative deepening A* search.
He had to search to
a median depth of 18 for
the random configurations he attempted.
The question is, what admissible
heuristic did Korf invent for
his A* search?
To find out, follow the link to
his paper in the instructor notes.
This problem continued to bother
computer science researchers.
In 2010, Thomas Rokiki and
Morley Davidson proved that the maximum
number of quarter turns needed
to solve the cube is 26,
using 29 CPU years of idle computer
time at the Ohio Super Computing Center.
Games have a long history of inspiring
rapid to nasty for AI researchers.
As Peter teaches us about search, keep
in mind interesting problems like these,
and look for clues as to how we might
use search techniques to solve them.