Recall the list ranking problem.
You're given a link list.
You want to compute
the ranks of every node.
The ranks you'll remember
are the distances of every node
from some endpoint, say the head.
Now one idea is to apply a scan or
a prefix sum to this problem.
How does that work?
You start by assigning a value of zero
to the head and ones every where else.
You then use parallel pointer jumping to
combine these values yielding the ranks.
This idea, by this way,
is due to this fellow,
I'm going to call him Wyllie,
because it makes me think of coyotes.
[SOUND] [SOUND] Now recall
the cost of this scheme.
Although it was very simple and elegant,
you will notice that
it's not work-optimal.
But there's at least one
trick to making it so.
You'll need this trick when
parallelizing tree algorithms.
So I want you to think
about it through this quiz.
Here's the trick.
Start by shrinking the list.
That is, let's say you start
with a list of size n.
Suppose you can magically compress this
list into an equivalent one which has m
less than n nodes.
Then run Wylie's algorithm,
but on this smaller list,
instead of the original one.
Since you're running
on the smaller list,
this would have a work cost of m log m.
Further suppose that it's possible to
take the results of this intermediate
step, and then extend to
a ranking of the full list.
At long last, here is my question.
The question is,
how should you choose m?
For the moment,
just ignore steps 1 and 3,
that is assume step 2
dominates the overall work.
Choose the best option for
m among this list.