You are looking at the final project.
Congratulations on making it this far.
You're going to need a copy of this
project on your local machine, so
check the instructor notes for
download information.
In this app, Paul has created
a performance nightmare.
This news aggregator uses
the Hacker News API to
pull up the current top stories.
It's pretty cool, but watch the frame
rate right here as I scroll.
That definitely didn't look good.
Now watch what happens when
stories slide in and out.
See how it drops?
And just try using this app on mobile.
It is totally unusable.
There's going to be a lot to improve.
In the instructor notes,
I'm going to leave a list of hints for
major areas that definitely need fixing.
But if you want a real performance
challenge, don't look.
Take some measurements and
see what you can find out on your own.
Try it yourself first, and
then use the hints as a fallback.
In the solution video,
you'll see me go over a few of the high
level problems that this app faces.
And I'll also show you
how I fixed those.
Keep in mind though,
that my solution is just one of many.
It is extremely likely that
your code will look very,
very different than mine.
I'll also post a link to my code,
which you'll be able to peruse and
compare to your own.
And for the completionists among you,
I will also be posting a list of
all the known bugs in the project.
If you've made it this far, you've got
all of the tools that you need to make
this app run at 60 frames per second.
So what are you waiting for?
Download the app,
start measuring and start improving!
When you are hitting
60 frames per second,
post a link to the live version of
your Performant app in the forums so
that we can see what
improvements you've made.
Good luck everybody!