In the last few lessons,
we learned all about persistence.
>> By persistence,
do you mean the determination that it
took our students to get through three
lessons without changing anything
about the way sunshine works?
>> Yes, but we also learned about
persisting data in databases and
reading and writing that data using
a content provider interface.
>> Lots and lots of code.
So it's time to put some of that
hard work to real use in sunshine?
>> Indeed, we've gotten the database and
content provider working against a test
framework, but now it's time to
connect it up to your application.
>> But we're not going to just do that.
We're going to use that content provider
and database to store information
that the app collects when
running in the background.
>> After all, the best kind of
application is one that has
critical information available,
even when you may not be on a network.