So we can look at this ellipse a little more carefully, okay.
Let's first consider the case, where the gradient at
every point in the image, is either horizontal or vertical.
Sorry, not in the image in the window.
So, at each point.
It could be horizontal or
it could be vertical, but it's not going to be slanted, okay?
So some places it'll be horizontal, some places it'll be vertical, but
it's never, the, both Ix and Iy are never non-zero at the same time.
Well, that would mean that these terms would always be 0, right.
Ix times Iy, all right.
So, that would look like this.
And I'm writing this as lambda one, lambda two, these are the diagonal terms.
The off diagonals would be 0.
Now, that's a nice full right matrix, right, lambda one, lambda two.
Except if one of those were 0, it would not be a very good full,
it would not be a full rank equation, right?
So for example, if the Iy squareds were all 0 and
that there was no gradient in the Y direction, only in the horizontal direction,
that would mean that my matrix would only have one of these values, and
probably, that's not really a good corner, right?
Because if I only have say gradient in this way and
not in that way, then I can slide up and down as much as I want.
So, something about these numbers tells us how good a corner,
the location in the image is.
Can you smell the algorithm that's coming?
It's not me, it's Megan.
In fact, I'll write it just this way.
If either of those lambdas were close to 0, this is not a corner.
So what we want is we want,
is we want to look for locations where both of those are large.
Now for those of you who remember from your calculus and and you're learning
algebra, of course, we can take this second order matrix, this ellipse,
and what we can do is we can diagonalize it through a rotation, and remember we
talked about singular value decomposition, well this is not exactly that but
it's quite related, where basically, what it says is we can think of M which is
that special matrix as being sort of rotated or unrotated by R.
Then it's a diagonal matrix and then it's re-rotated.
The axis lengths of those ellipses, okay how big those ellipses are,
that's determined by the eigenvalues these numbers.
Of that diagonalization, and
the orientation of the ellipse is determined by that rotation.
So here I'm drawing that, like this, so remember,
this is a particular ellipse of constant E, constant error.
So for places where, it's a very narrow ellipse.
That means that the E changes quickly.
I didn't have to move very far for the E to get to that value.
Whereas, the places where it goes very slowly, okay,
I have to move a farther distance, in order for that value to change.
And you see how it says it's one over the, the square root?
So, remember, if that lando were 0, okey?
That would mean I'd have to go an infinite direction,
that means it doesn't change at all as I move in that direction.
So what I'm telling you here is that the eigenvalues, of that M matrix,
are indicative of the cornerness of that matrix.
That's pretty cool.
So, it turns out, Harris figured this out and
they figured out a really simple way of thinking about this.