Now let's look at a few examples of how time, frequency, and
frequency spectra are combined together.
Let's imagine this is a signal I want to generate.
This signal was generated by simply doing an addition of two different signals.
This signal here, again, repeating.
And the next one was this one.
Let's look at them mathematically.
So this output target signal was basically a sine.
Twice of the frequency stuff here.
And then one-third of the sine of twice what the frequency is
also much higher, three times.
So in essence what you basically look at is this signal times one-third of
this signal is giving me this signal.
How we plot this in the frequency domain?
So again, now we're looking at amplitude and the frequency.
The variables here are f1 is f itself, f2 is twice f, f3 is 3 times f.
Remember that's, this is what three times f is.
So first value, of course, is 1 amplitude entirely of f itself and
then 3 times one-third signal.
So this is, that's why this is 0.13.
And this was about 1.
So this is basically the frequency spectra of this signal looks like.