For the billing address
input I just set the for
attribute on the label to
the same ID that the input has.
Easy enough, and then for
the telephone number I nested
the input inside the label.
I actually like doing it
this way a little bit more,
because nesting it makes it more obvious
that the input belongs to the label.
I still used a for attribute though, so
that my form would play
nice with screen readers.
And here's how it looks.
Doesn't look too different right now but
you'll notice that when
you click on the labels,
that their associated
inputs get put into focus.
Very nice.
Next stop, we'll be continuing our
interview with Luke Wroblewski.
Watch him as he describes how
he likes to design inputs.