That was the algebraic approach to the solution and it works nicely.
In fact that was the math that you would actually encode if
you were writing a computer program to do this.
But what it doesn't do is give you exactly the intuition of what's going on,
in photometric stereo.
So to do that, let's take a look at this in p q space.
So, let's suppose we have some light source, the first light source, p s one,
q s one, and so we'll say that, remember we know it's, it,
where it's located, and then if we measured it's intensity,
let's say it's 0.7, that some particular curve here.
So the other ones are dotted to remind you of them.
But the idea here is that the solution for
p and q, must lie somewhere on that curve.
All right, we don't know where yet, so what do we do?
Well, in the old shape up shading we did some funny sort of assumptions and
integration and stuff that just doesn't work.
Well, here all we do is we say let me put up another light source.
Here is a second light source, p q of 2 of s and
now it has to lie somewhere on this curve.
'Kay?
And you'll notice those curves intersect in more than one place.
Well that's troubling it intersects more than one place.
What do we do to make it come to one place?
Well, we just put down a third light source, all right.
And if everything is calibrated and
working correctly, then the orientation of that point.
And the albedo are recovered at being exactly that location.
So, that's the geometric, sort of, description of photometric stereo.