Here's a graph for
which I computed some mapping.
If you were to course on this
graph based on this matching,
here's what you get.
Now, suppose I use the Lipton and
Trajan result to identify some vertex
separator in this course graph.
Hey, that's not too shabby.
The two halves are pretty balanced.
The total vertex weight of the upper
half is eight as is the lower half.
To get the value of eight, remember that
each of the super vertices corresponds
to two vertices of the original graph.
So then counting up you'd get, say,
2 plus 2 plus 2 plus 2, that's 8.
And 2 plus 2 plus 2 plus 2.
Now, to make the mapping from the fine
graph to the coarse graph a little bit
easier to see,
let me highlight the matched edges and
their correspondents
in the coarse graph.
Here's what I want you to do.
Go back to this original graph.
I want you to click on
all the vertices and
edges associated with
the separator in the coarse graph.
Okay, so what does that mean?
For example, consider this
edge in the coarse separator.
In the original graph,
this super vertex corresponds to
these two vertices plus this edge,
so you'd mark them.
The other coarse vertex corresponds
to this vertex, so you'd mark it too.
Lastly, this edge maps to this edge.
Check.
In other words,
the first course graph separator
edge corresponds to this subgraph.
Okay, now I want you to try.
By the way,
what's the point of this exercise?
Well, I want you to discover by example,
a subtle detail about what partitions in
the course graph mean for
the fine graph.