Now I'm going to give you another chance
to practice using vectorized operations.
One question you'll often want
to answer in data analysis is,
how does a single data point compare
to the rest of the data points?
For example, I mentioned that I'm
interested in how the employment rate in
the U.S. compares the the employment
rate in other countries.
Is it higher or lower than the average,
and by how much?
The question isn't very well-defined,
but
one typical way that people use to
answer it, is to convert each data point
to a number of standard
deviations away from the mean.
This is called standardizing the data.
For example, let's consider
the employment data we have for 2007.
The mean employment rate was 58.6%,
the standard
deviation was 10.5%, and the employment
rate in the United States was 62.3%.
Then the difference between
the United States employment, and
the mean employment rate was 3.7%.
This is equal to about 0.35
standard deviations or
about a third of a standard deviation.
In Mexico on the other hand, the mean
employment rate in 2007 was 57.9%.
Thus for Mexico the difference
between the employment rate and
the mean employment rate was -0.7%.
Note that I use a negative difference to
indicate a value that's below the mean,
and a positive difference to indicate
a value that's above the mean.
This translates to about 0.067
standard deviations below the mean,
giving a standardized
score of negative 0.067.
On the next screen,
I'd like you to write a function that
takes a numpy array as an input.
And the array could contain
any type of numerical data,
such as employment data for example.
Then I want you to return
a standardized array,
where each data point has been replaced
by the standardized data point.