Now we see how to modify the Tree Search Function
to make it be a Graph Search Function
to avoid those repeated paths.
What we do, is we start off and initialize a set
called the explored set of states that we have already explored.
Then, when we consider a new path,
we add the new state to the set of already explored states,
and then when we are expanding the path
and adding in new states to the end of it,
we don’t add that in if we have already seen that new state
in either the frontier or the explored.
Now back to Breadth First Search.
Let’s assume we are using the Graph Search
so that we have eliminated the duplicate paths.
Arad is crossed off the list.
The path that goes from Arad to Sibiu
and back to Arad is removed,
and we are left with these one, two, three,
four, five possible paths.
Given these 5 paths,
show me which ones are candidates to be expanded next
by the Breadth First Search Algorithm.