Recall, in previous lecture we
talked about that in essence video
is nothing else, but images that are
stacked on top of each other in time.
And we looked at basically, how we can
access this by looking over x and y, and
looking at basically, how we can stack
these images over time like this.
And that allows us to look at digital
video basically in a similar manner,
as we did for images.
Basically, looking for x and
y stacked in time, and of course,
we can access any part of this
image by basically looking at
how we can access it in x and y, or
i and j for discreet ones in time.
We also discussed the concept of
video resolution extending from
concept of image resolution, and
looked at aspect ratios of videos, and
talked about where I
did a video formats.
Again, this is just to
kind of remind you,
what we've talked about
before in terms of image and
video representation, and
similarities and differences in each.