So Jake, have you got the service
worker serving the skeleton page?
>> Yes, and here's how i did it.
Over in the service worker instead of
cache the root page with the date in it.
I'm going to cache the skeleton.
I'm going to bump the cache version
number as well because we've
changed things.
Now I'm going to pause the request URL.
First, I check to see if
the request origin is the same as
the current origin.
Remember that the service worker
handles requests for other origins too.
In this case, we only want to intercept
route requests for the same origin.
Now I checked the path name,
if it's the route, I respond with
the skeleton straight from the cache.
I don't need to go to
the network as a fallback,
because I know skeleton is cached
is part of the install step.
So let's test this.
I refresh the page get
told about an update.
I click refresh and
now I'm running with the page show.
At this point,
we have a pretty viable product,
this is something we could launch.
Things haven't changed much
when the connection's perfect,
but perfect doesn't really exist.
On a slow connection we get to render
the top bar much quicker, we even get to
render content quicker purely because
our JavaScript is arriving sooner.
Li-Fi is still a bit crap really, but
at least something is on the screen.
With offline, we're now showing our own
error message using the branding of our
app, rather than the default browser
error message, which is something.
Even at this stage, we can massively
improve the user experience, but
now we need to cache those winter posts.
And to do that we're going to use
one of the web's most hated APIs.
[MUSIC]
Yes, but seriously,
we're going to tame this API and
learn how to use all the good bits
of IndexedDB without getting burned.
It might even be fun, maybe.