Here's the answer.
The first branch on the left is simple.
We pick the option where
player two has the best score.
On the middle branch, we'll start
with the first leaf node on the left.
Player two is only concerned with
maximizing their own score, so
we know they will choose a node where
they get greater than or equal to seven.
Because the scores add up to nine,
this restricts the other scores to
at most less than or equal to two.
However the next level up
is player one's move, and
they already have a better choice
from the left branch, three,
compared to less than or equal to two.
That means there's no way they
would choose this middle branch, so
we can actually prune
the remaining two nodes.
A similar situation
occurs on the right side.
We could prune the right-most node for
the same reason.