[Male narrator] Now, why doesn't the general tree search or graph search algorithm stop
when it adds a goal node to the frontier?
The reason is because it might not be the best path to the goal.
Now, here we found a path of length 2
and we added a path of length 3 that reached the goal.
The general graph search or tree search doesn't know
that there might be some other path that we could expand
that would have a distance of say, 2-1/2,
but there's an optimization that could be made.
If we know we're doing Breadth - First Search
and we know there's no possibility of a path of length 2-1/2.
Then we can change algorithm so that it checks states
as soon as they're added to the frontier
rather than waiting until they're expanded
and in that case, we can write a specific Breadth - First Search routine
that terminates early and gives us a result as soon as we add a goal state to the frontier.
Breadth - First Search will find this path
that ends up in Bucharest, and if we're looking for the shortest path
in terms of number of steps,
Breadth - First Search is guaranteed to find it,
But if we're looking for the shortest path in terms of total cost
by adding up the step costs, then it turns out
that this path is shorter than the path found by Breadth - First Search.
So let's look at how we could find that path.