So now, let's dive in and ask the question.
What are the basic elements of computational photography?
We start off with things like a 3-D scene.
Here, I'm basically showing a nice beach scene here, and
of course, what we're interested in is taking a picture of this nice 3-D scene.
So, of course, what makes this 3-D scene, is light is emitting from everywhere.
Right.
Rays of light.
Again that's what I've talked about.
And each one of them a different color, showing you the details and
all that kind of stuff.
Well, these rays of light are coming in.
Of course, they're illuminated by a source of light.
So for example, in this case, the sun is illuminating the whole scene.
The rays of light are illuminating this scene.
I have now the most basic element of the scene.
The word itself is illumination.
In essence what's happening is light transport.
Light from this thing is coming in, rays of light.
And now of course this is what we refer to as illumination of the scene.
Another part of it is, what we want to do with this is, we want to use optics.
To be able to now capture, assist in capturing the light transport,
the rays of light in the environment.
To actually capture the information in the digital world, we need a sensor.
So we need to have some sort of a digital sensor.
Of course in traditional photography the sensor was a chemical process by film.
Which captured the light and ordered the light, and fused the light with
chemistry to save it, the information, by doing some sort of photo uptake.
Our photo electric was actually changed into energy and saved.
In this case, of course, we do this with digital where light
sensors are basically saving the light information.
Then of course, what we can do is process the image.
This would actually be an optional step, but it is an important step also now
the current pipeline where all of the sensor information is now processed to
give it actually, much more of the information which creates an image.
And you can notice in the computational pipeline,
this could happen much more actively.
In a digital film pipeline, once you get the information, processing and
stuff happens later.
Another part of it is, after I processed it,
display is a general word here I use for sharing information.
That is, how do you kind of create an image or print or something like that.
So, it could be just a computer display, or it could be the printing medium.
So, now we have taken this 3-D scene,
taken it through all of these processes, to be able to share the output.
And, of course another important ingredient in all of this,
is the user, because the user wants to interact with.
It's not just a unidirectional when going user can actually do things like
share these images and perhaps also control of it.
Now, of course what you notice is.
The user is now much more closer to all of this.
Of course they were closer to it with darkroom photography and
stuff, but it was a passive process.
And this is more of an active process.
The bottom-line is, computation can be embedded in all aspects of
these elements to support photography.
I can use a computer here to illuminate the scene differently.
I can use a computer here to control the variety of
aspects what optics does to generate and capture light.
Of course computation is very close to the sensor, and
imagine I can put a multi-,
multi-array of sensors to capture things differently.
Processing, of course that's the more obvious one, right?
I can just do processing of the images in the computer.
Display, well, if this is a special type of an image,
I need to have a special way of displaying it.
So imagine, for example, concepts of augmented reality and, you know,
even holograms require you to have computation right here.
And the user, of course, is just to kind of there to use all of this.
To then of course, do things like share more images and stuff like that.
So these are the main elements that I will be referring to
throughout this class.
And we will talk about how we going to control, and
computationally impact each and every of them in this class.