Another core thing about transforms
is that they can be nested.
And so what means is that you'll often
have hierarchies and transforms.
One way to think about that is,
imagine you have a robot arm.
Something like, well like this.
Yeah, that'll do nicely.
All right, so you have this robot arm.
And right now he's just sort
of following me around, but
let's use him for
demonstration purposes.
So imagine that I just want to rotate
just the bottom part of the robot arm.
And you'll notice that as I
rotate it along, the middle and
the top rotate as well.
Okay, now if I rotate the middle,
only the top rotates along.
And if I rotate the top,
it rotates by itself.
That's how a transform hierarchy works.
So, let's figure out how
to do that inside of Unity.