Now we just walked you through
how to create an application
on Google app engine.
You might have ran into some issues.
If you don't have a working projet
at this time, no worries at all.
We're going to show you a short cut
that lets you create an app engine
application that you can use yourself.
We're back in Google
app engine launcher,
let's click on file,
then create new application.
What this is going to do is it's
going to set up all the folders and
files and
make sure everything works correctly.
We can call it whatever we want but
for now let's just use Engine App.
I'm going to select browse to
pick where I want this saved and
I'm just going to save
it on the desktop.
So I'm going to click the desktop,
click OK, and we're ready to go.
Let's click create,
now you can see another application
in the Google App Engine Launcher,
Engine App.
Let's go ahead and run it locally,
now that it's running, let's view it in
the browser by clicking browse and
look at that, it says hello world.
Okay, so
we're running our application locally.
Let's confirm that it
was actually created.
What I'm going to do is I'm
going to open up the desktop, and
as you can see,
the engine app folder was created.
Let's open it, and we have main.pie,
we have app.yamel and
a couple of other files that
Google App Engine created for us.
We only have to worry about main.pie,
and app.yamel for
now so let's open them up with Sublime.
I'm going to right click, select
Open With, and then choose Sublime.
And we're in Sublime,
let's scroll down and look at that.
All the contents from our
file are in here now.
Google App Engine created that for
you and made sure everything
was set up properly.
Now that we've confirmed that the
main.pi file is the same let's go check
out app.yaml.
Great so we're back in the project
folder, let's open up app.yaml and
confirm it has everything
we're looking for.
I'm going to right click on app.yaml,
select Open.
And it looks like Windows
can't open this file,
let's select a program from
a list of installed programs.
We're going to open it up with Sublime
so let's see if we can find it in there.
I'll click OK, and there's sublime.
Let's select it,
click OK and there we go.
So, we're in our app.yaml file and
it looks like that we've
got everything we need.
Google app engine added in a little
bit of additional information,
but really we need to focus on
the application ID right here.
Right now the application
ID is engine app.
But let's go ahead and paste in our
application ID we created before.
Now that we've pasted in our
application ID let's go ahead and
save this file and
now we want to deploy it.
Let's see if it actually works.
I'm going to go back to
Google App Engine Launcher.
I'm going to highlight our
application and click deploy.
Okay, let's take a look at our log and
yes,
it looks like our
deployment was successful.
Let's open it up in the browser, and
make sure everything worked out okay.
I'm going to go to our
application ID.appsot.com.
Let's reload the page and
see what happens.
And look at that, we have Hello world.
Everything worked great.