Let's revisit our weighted average.
Okay.
So, instead of just thinking about averaging the local pixels,
let's think of this as a set of weights, okay, and what we're going to do is
we're going to weight all of these pixels by some set of weights, and
we're going to combine them using those weights to come up with the new value.
Now when we were just doing the moving box, our weights were just,
let's say it was five long, they would be one fifth,
one fifth, one fifth, one fifth, one fifth, five of them, right?
So our weights was uniformly distributed, okay.
But wait a minute, does that make sense?
Remember our assumption that nearby pixels are related to my value?
And there's another related assumption to that.
The more nearby you are, the more related you are.
So that means that pixels that are closer to me
should contribute more to the average.
So let's change our moving average, so that that's true, okay?
Before, if you remember, we had these uniform weights.
One, one, one, one, one, all the way across, divided by five.
What if we wanted to use some nonuniform weights?
So, so here's a set.
One, four, six, four, one divided by sixteen.
And what I’m going to do is I’m going to change those weights from
being uniform to being nonuniform, and
I want you to watch what happens to this bottom picture.
So that’s the uniform weight,
and that’s the nonuniform, centered weighted, right.
Uniform.
Nonuniform.
And you'll notice that the nonuniform is a smoother rendition.
In fact, you know, take a look here.
You know, this area right there, we get a smoother range of, of what's going on.
And the nonuniform weights corresponds to
this assumption that the more nearby a pixel is, the more weight it should have.