Now that we've gotten a bit more
comfortable writing some simple code,
that's capable of doing pretty cool
things, let's spend some time to discuss
the term variables, in the context
of our rotate light script.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
At its core,
a variable is just a name we give to a
value stored in your computer's memory.
For example, the values zero, false or
Udasti rocks are all values that
can be stored within variables.
A C#, we can also give our variables
a type, which can be a float,
a bool or a string,
just to name a few basic ones.
But they can also be more complicated
things, like a vector or a quaternion.
To talk about some of the basic ones,
let's hop into the Unity animator.
Remember using triggers to
build your apartment scene?
At that time, we also discussed ints,
floats, and bools.
The reason the animator uses these
variable types is because they make up
the very fundamental building blocks for
all our complex VR worlds.
So let's dive into what they really are.
A bool is a variable type that can be
two different states, true or false.
It's a great way to keep track
of whether we've done an action,
like press the cardboard
trigger in our script.
An int is a variable that can
take on an integer value.
For example, you have 1,
-1, -1,000, or 1 million.
For the animator,
it's a great way to keep track of
different types of states for
our animations.
In the case of animating a character,
this could be the state of whether
it's sitting, standing or running.
Last, a float variable is a value
that can take on any decimal.
This value is really great for
blending between animations.
For example, if we want to blend a
walking and running animation, we could
provide a float value for the speed, and
Unity will automatically create a blend
between walking and running, based
on how fast the character is moving.
And these are just some of
the basic building blocks.
You can define these almost
anywhere within your scripts and
you've probably noticed that we've
defined some variables within methods
but also some at the top of our class.
This has to do with a complex
topic called scoping.
The best way to think about this
is that a variable can only be
used within its
surrounding curly braces.
So when we define variables
at the top of our script,
we're essentially letting
the whole script use it.
But for now, we really just want you
to be comfortable with the concept of
variables so that you can use them to
really make the most out of your data.
As an exercise,
why not create another variable for
the time parameter that we
give to the slurp method?