Now Street Views is of course captured
with a camera that's mounted on a car
that goes all over the country or
the world these days.
Of course, there have been other
types of examples of this type of
capturing system on a tricycle here.
And there have been sightings also
of much more mobile capture devices,
like this.
Again, this is an example of
more authoritative, you know,
a company like Google is walking
around to create these amazing maps.
So, I just caught a, captured a segment
from the about Street View site,
which basically shows at least a simple
pipeline of about how Street Views work.
Starts, of course starts
with collecting imagery.
In this case,
it's similar to the kind of imagery
we have looked at in a panorama.
Of course, use that align
all of the imagery together.
And then of course,
using that to generate a full panorama,
like the one in attaching it
to the maps on the street.
So this is in essence a simplistic
pipeline of how Street Views works.
Of course, there's a whole lot of
machinery in there that I cannot tell
you anything about, because most
of it might also be proprietary.
But in essence, what you see is they
actually can use images from the special
panoramic cameras, registered, aligned.
And then of course,
create images like this.
Of course, we also want to do this
kind of stuff with our own images.
So here is something, this morning, I,
before I was walking into my office and
I just used my iPhone to take
a bunch of different images.
And of course, they are interesting
in their own right, but
I just uploaded them to Photosynth and
here is the output.
And again, remember,
these are pictures I took.
Now just the walk through
here into my office.
Now, of course if you,
if I had office hours,
this is where you would come to see me.
My office here again.
If you're really interested,
you can zoom in here and
see the friends that we've seen in
a variety of different lectures already.
Sitting there in my office,
waiting for me.
Now, again,
this is giving you a sense of its 3Dness
of the environment is far from perfect.
Alignment is not there.
But remember,
this is just like 20 pictures that you
use to generate this walk-through.
Quite impressive, you can manipulate
it and visualize again, a photo tour.