Welcome to Udacity's Deep Learning
nano-degree foundation program.
I'm Siraj.
>> And I'm Matt.
>> And we're both so excited that you're
joining us in the rapidly expanding
community of deep learning enthusiasts.
Deep Learning is driving the current
revolution in computing.
It's the secret sauce behind
everything from self-driving cars,
to language translation,
even generated art.
>> In 2016 alone, these technologies
have made things possible
that sound like science fiction,
but are in fact very, very real.
For example, Helping Faces is an app
developed in India that uses facial
recognition to find missing children.
Reuniting them with their families.
>> Deep Learning is
saving real human lives.
IBM is using it to browse millions of
genetic profiles in a way no single
human could, to classify genetic
disorders in patients accurately.
>> And you've probably used or
heard about Amazon's Alexa,
which uses Deep Learning to recognize,
interpret and act on human speech.
>> So basically, it's going down,
you should be hyped.
>> Just by being here today, you're
officially part of this revolution,
at the start of the journey that
can lead you amazing places.
Because Deep Learning is
the cornerstone of so
many game changing technologies,
you have limitless paths open to you.
>> We're pumped to see
what you wizards create.