By now, you might have recognized what we're really building up is a Bayes network
where the parameters of the Bayes networks are estimated using supervised learning
by a maximum likelihood estimator based on training data.
The Bayes network has at its root an unobservable variable called spam,
which is binary, and it has as many children as there are words in a message,
where each word has an identical conditional distribution
of the word occurrence given the class spam or not spam.
If you write on our dictionary over here,
you might remember the dictionary had 12 different words,
so here is 5 of the 12, offer, is, secret, click and sports.
Then for the spam class, we found the probability of secret given spam is 1/3,
and we also found that the probability of secret given ham is 1/15,
so here's a quiz.
Assuming a vocabulary size of 12, or put differently,
the dictionary has 12 words, how many parameters
do we need to specify this Bayes network?