So a multi threaded Dag algorithm for
matrix multiply is easy enough
to write down as we did before.
What should you do for
a distributed memory machine?
Let's start with the case of
a linear network having P nodes.
For simplicity, let's also assume that
the matrixes are squared n by n objects
and that P divides n.
The first question is, how should
you distribute the matrix operands?
There are lots of potential choices.
I want you to start with
the following convention,
distribute the operands by block
row in an identical fashion.
That means you give each node n over P
consecutive rows of each matrix operand.
Let me draw a picture.
For each node,
I've assigned n over P consecutive rows.
Notice I've used the same
distribution for each matrix.
While it's not strictly
necessary to do so,
it simplifies the design of practical
interfaces to the matrix objects,
because essentially you can always
assume they have the same distribution.
Now consider some process,
what is the most work it can do
given this data distribution?
In the best case it could update
it's entire block row of C
using the entire block row of B and
one sub block of A.
It could not for
instance do anything with a sub block
of A that's say over here or over here.
Why not?
Well recall the definition
of matrix multiply.
To fully update this block row of C,
you need to multiply this little block
of A by this entire block row of B
and then this block A by this
entire block row of B, and so on.
So on.
But, given this distribution,
this process doesn't have access
to this block row labeled b0.
So to help the algorithm make progress,
you're going to need to
shuffle blocks around.
Now again, there are many choices.
One convention is in order
compute strategy in which you
keep the block of C in place.
You also keep A in place.
If you do that,
then you have to move B around.
Since we're on a linear network,
one strategy is to shift
the block rows of B.
For example,
if I were to shift B downwards,
then I would get the following result.
Now that this node has b0, it can do
a partial update with the block a0.
If you keep circularly shifting,
eventually,
every node will see all of B.
That's a total of P shifts,
which by the way,
leaves B in its original
distribution once you're done.
Very convenient.
Let's write down some pseudo
code to express the algorithm.
We'll let A hat, B hat, and
C hat represent the local parts of A,
B, and C.
Notice that they're of
size n over P by n.
Now to implement the shift we're
going to need to send the block that we
have and we're going to need some
space to receive a new block row of B.
So here I've declared another little
temporary storage matrix B twiddle.
These two variables compute
the neighbor below me, r next, and
the neighbor above me, r previous.
The loop iterates over circular shifts.
We can start by doing a local matrix
multiply on the data we have.
To keep the pseudo-code simple I've
used placeholders, where you would
compute the appropriate indices of
the local variables as a function of L.
Following the partial update
is the communication.
Step 1 is to send the local
buffer to the next processor.
Step 2 is to receive from
the previous processor.
Then we wait for these two
communication operations to complete.
So, that ends one
circular shift operation.
And, finally, before moving on to the
next round, we just swap the temporary
buffer used to receive with the current
local buffer used to compute.
Easy breezy.