First, a block cipher should use
substitution to achieve confusion.
This is correct.
Second, a block cipher should use
permutation to achieve diffusion.
This is correct.
Third, a block cipher
should use a few rounds,
each with a combination of
substitution and permutation.
This is correct.
These are the three high level
properties of block ciphers
that we have just discussed.
Fourth, a block cipher should
keep the algorithm secret.
This is false.
Because we should never
keep the algorithm secret.
We should only keep the key secret.
Many researchers have analyzed
a public or standard algorithm and
improved its security.
Therefore, a public or
standard algorithm can be more
secure than a secret algorithm.
Therefore, we should
use a public algorithm.