For our example,
we're going to use data in the
MatchedPairAnalysisExample Excel file.
This file contains the results of
our new candy product introduction
experiment.
The stores that were used for treatment
stores are in the Treatments tab.
The matched pairs of control and
treatment stores can be
found in the Pairs tab.
The data from the experiment
can be found in the Data tab.
Baltrex will not only perform the t-Test
and identify the significance of
the results but will also compare the
treatment and control stores to baseline
or past data to see the impact
during the treatment period.
In order to do this, you'll need to
feed the tool both the baseline data and
the data from the experiment.
The experiment was run from October
15th, 2011, and ended on March 17, 2012.
Each week, each store recorded
the average spend per customer.
So let's create a new Alteryx workflow,
and
use the input data tool
to bring in the data.
The control store information is located
in the Pairs tab of the spreadsheet.
So let's import that first.
Next, let's bring in the treatment
store data from the Treatments tab and
lastly, let's bring in
the historical performance
as well as the data from the experiment
located in the Data tab.
Now that we have the data,
we're ready to up the analysis.
Let's grab an AB analysis tool and
drag it onto the canvas.
Connect the data from the Pairs
tab to the C or Controls input.
Connect the data from the Treatments
tab to the T or Treatment input.
And the data from the Data tab should
go to the P, or Performance input.
Next, let's configure the tool.
On the Input Data tab,
let's set up our analysis as follows.
The control section of
the configuration window
relates to the control store data in
the Pairs tab, coming in on the C input.
The controls field is
the control unit identifier.
And the treatments field is
the treatment unit mapping field.
The treatment section uses the data
coming in from the T input.
And we're looking for the field
to match the treatment identifier
with the treatment identifier
from the controls field.
So we should use store ID
from the treatment stream
to match to the treatments
field of the control stream.
For the performance data, we'll use the
right store ID, the Week Ending date and
the Spend Customer fields to
finish our configuration.
Clicking on the Test Dates tab, we need
to enter the dates of our experiment.
The start date was October 15th, 2011.
And the end date was March 17th, 2012.
Next, let's add browse
tools by right-clicking
on the AB Analysis tool and
selecting Add All Browses.
Let's run the work flow and
take a look at the results.
[BLANK_AUDIO]