So this is actually an interesting idea
because that can allow us to start
creating a light field or
a plenoptic camera, something which
was introduced by Ng et al in 2005.
I have a subject, I have a main lens.
And what I can do now
is add a linticular or
a microlens array before the sensor.
And what that could do now is anytime it
goes through, it basically can also do
more analysis to figure out more
information about the light.
Just pretty much light what we saw,
by putting it in a series of pinholes.
So what does a lenticular or
microlens array do?
Here's a simple example.
This is a lenticular array.
By just placing these types of small
lenslets like this in front of a screen,
We can actually start seeing depth.
So, lenticular array is basically
putting in different lenses
that basically can be seen, in this
case, by the left eye or the right eye.
And basically,
allows you to generate a newer image
that will start encoding depth and being
able to see depth in images like this.
I mean, lenticular arrays are one
of the more popular arrays,
you may have seen them.
Also, we're showing 2D or
3D images in a 2D plane.
Or sometimes they could also be just
cylindrical lenses that could be used to
form lenticular arrays.
Again I encourage you to
look up this kind of stuff.
You may have seen a whole lot of
these types of things already.
But just in essence of this kind of
stuff, we can actually putting something
like this in front of it cylindical,
cylindrical lenses like this,
before a sensor, we can start actually
now capturing more information.
So now let me connect it to something
we have also looked at already.
Remember the UV and the ST planes?
UV was where the lens would be put,
the camera plane, and
the ST is where the image plane is.
And here, basically what I do, is I put
in a bunch of smaller micro-lens arrays.
And according to what we did previously,
that is, put in small pinholes.
If I put in this kind of stuff,
now I can actually create a light field.
Because what we have done now is use
this way to create an array of cameras,
and each camera is capturing
different types of things.
Once I have this kind of stuff, what I
can now do is traverse from u and v and
s and t To start creating not just
one image that was captured but
a seas of images.
And, of course,
interpolating between those,
I can actually start getting more
information than just one single image.
In essence,
I would've captured a light field and
generated pixels whenever
I want to add to the fact