Let me now demonstrate a bit of code to
do an affine transformation of an image.
The usual preamble of loading an image,
an out, open cv and
numpy, reading the image.
And here, rather than do other types of
things with transformations, we're going
to take much of a, approach where we can
identify the points of transformation.
So I basically now come up
with first user points.
And if you notice here, I'm giving it
three different points, in first image,
and three different points
in the second image.
Using these two points,
I can now create a, affine, basically
apply the affine transformation to
compute a transformation matrix.
And I'll, once we have the
transformation matrix, we can apply it
to the image that we already know all
the other information of like, for
example, width and height.
And after, of course, we have applied
it, we can display the image.
Just run this code here.
So, from those three points that we
used, we were able to compute an,
transformation matrix which
is actually printed out here.
This was my original image.
And this is the final output image after
the transformation matrix applied of
giving it an affine warp.
Now you can see the image have been
warped, but again, notice straight lines
are straddle straight lines as we
talked about earlier in the lecture.
It just basically has more of an affect
of being able to be, create a warp, or
a kind of a shear in two
different directions here.
All lines are still straight
as you can see here.
The straight line still remains
straight in this transformation.