The browse fragment is very powerful.
In this lesson,
we'll bring some of that power to life.
First, our UI is looking
a little bit drab, so
let's add some content to spice it up.
Inside the on activity created method,
uncomment setup UI elements.
Now, let's take a look
inside this method.
First off, notice that all these methods
are being called on the browse fragment
provided by the lean back library.
Most of this code is self-explanatory
except for setHeadersState and
setHeadersTransitionOnBackEnabled.
These indicate to the browse fragment
you want headers to be visible by
default and that we want the back button
to move the focus back to the headers
from a row, if it's pressed while
the user is scrolling through cards.
The browse fragment can display
either a badge or a title.
If you prefer a badge,
uncomment this line.
Let's run the project now and
see how it looks.
It looks a little bit better but
there's still not much going on.
That's going to change really soon.
Now it's time to add
content to our layout.
Return to onActivityCreated and
uncomment loadRows.
Here's the loadRows method.
There's still more than
a page of code here, so
we're going to comment some out
to make it easier to understand.
First, I'm going to comment
out all these lines except for
mRowsAdapter, which is an object
adapter that I'll explain later.
Next, I'm going to change this i to a 0.
Let's run the project to see what's up,
and
then I'll explain what
happened line by line.
Now we're getting somewhere.
One thing to notice is that we
have really smooth animations, and
it's easy to browse our
layout with the D-pad.
There's even sound if you
have speakers attached.
On the left, we see a category name.
Pretty soon we'll have many.
And on the right, we see a list
of three cards inside of a row.
We only added a few lines of code, so
where did all this
functionality come from?
Well, it turns out the browse fragment
goes way beyond helping with layout.
It also provides smooth animation,
easy D-pad navigation and
memory efficiency for displaying large
lists of media items behind the scenes.
When you use the browse fragment,
you get all this for free.
Here's the code that
created our category name.
The first parameter is unique ID for
the item.
The three cards we saw were
created by these lines.
Cards of course can get much fancier
than just a line of text, but for
now let's stick with this.
How are these cards created?
Well, that's the job of a presenter.
Recall that a presenter takes an object,
in this case a plain text string, and
returns a view that represents it.
Let's take a look inside this class and
see how it works.
And by the way,
in case the name confuses you,
we really could have called this class,
Textcard Presenter.
Inside, there are two important methods.
And at run time,
LeanBack will call both of these for us.
First stop is onCreateViewHolder.
This creates a view
that becomes our card.
A ViewHolder, by the way, is a simple
class that Android uses to improve
performance, by removing the need to
do a linear lookup for nested views.
It's not native to LeanBack.
Here, the view we create is
just a simple text view and
we set a couple of properties
to customize how it looks.
Next stop is onBindViewHolder.
This method receives the view that we
created earlier as well as an object
that should be bound to it.
Bound by the way, is a fancy way
of saying that we should populate
the fields of the view,
using properties of this item.
The parameter always
comes in as an object, so
we cast it to the appropriate type.
Here, we know that
this will be a string.
We also know the view we created
above is a text view, so
we make that cast, as well.
And now we can set the text to
match the string we passed in.
Now we have a presenter
that creates cards and
three strings that should become cards.
To tie these together, we use a LeanBack
class called an ObjectAdapter.
If you recall from our previous lesson,
an ObjectAdapter's job is to
connect the model with the view.
When we create our adapter, we give
it our presenter in the constructor.
Next we add objects to it.
At run time,
the ObjectAdapter will use our presenter
to create views for these objects.
Now we want our category name and
our three cards to be
displayed as a single row.
To do so, we'll use a list row class.
This is built into LeanBack, and it's
just a holder for a category name and
the ObjectAdapter that will
create cards for that category.
And remember at this point,
the object adapter contains
both the presenter to create cards and
the data that should become cards.
Now that we have a list row,
we'll need a presenter for it.
Scrolling up a bit, you can see
one that LeanBack provides for
us, called a ListRowPresenter.
Just like we used a presenter to create
views for strings, this presenter will
create a view that contains multiple
views and line them up in a row.
We need a second ObjectAdapter to hold
this presenter and we create it here.
We add our list row to that adapter and
then we set it as the main adapter for
the browse fragment.
That's the Model Presenter View
pattern in action.
Once you understand it,
you're well on your way to
understanding the LeanBack library.
Here's a quick quiz.
An ObjectAdapter uses a blank to
display objects from the blank.