Here's a new network that we'll use to investigate
how sampling can be used to do inference.
In this network, we have 4 variables. They're all boolean.
Cloudy tells us if it's cloudy or not outside,
and that can have an effect on whether the sprinklers are turned on,
and whether it's raining.
And those 2 variables in turn have an effect on whether the grass gets wet.
Now, to do inference over this network using sampling,
we start off with a variable where all the parents are defined.
In this case, there's only one such variable, Cloudy.
And it's conditional probability table tells us that the probability is 50% for Cloudy,
50% for not Cloudy, and so we sample from that.
We generate a random number, and let's say it comes up with positive for Cloudy.
Now that variable is defined, we can choose another variable.
In this case, let's choose Sprinkler, and we look at the rows in the table
for which Cloudy, the parent, is positive, and we see we should sample
with probability 10% to +s and 90% a -s.
And so let's say we do that sampling with a random number generator,
and it comes up negative for Sprinkler.
Now let's jump over here. Look at the Rain variable.
Again, the parent, Cloudy, is positive,
so we're looking at this part of the table.
We get a 0.8 probability for Rain being positive,
and a 0.2 probability for Rain being negative.
Let's say we sample that randomly, and it comes up Rain is positive.
And now we're ready to sample the final variable,
and what I want you to do is tell me which of the rows
of this table should we be considering and tell me what's more likely.
Is it more likely that we have a +w or a -w?