All right, let's start off, just to
confirm that we did everything right,
in the previous video, by hitting play.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
You should be able to see the vacation
block, but you can't click on it.
So, how do we make it interactive?
To interact with things
in our VR experiences,
we need to use the event
system in Unity.
This system listens for
things that are happening in the scene,
like clicks, hovering and more.
To use the event system,
let's go to Create,
UI, Event System, okay.
And if you already had an event
system in your hierarchy,
don't worry about that.
Unity will often create one for
you, when you create certain
types of UI objects, like, text.
This event system object controls which
type of events we're listening for, and,
you can see, it's already added
a couple of components here.
The stand alone input module is
the default input module for Unity, and
it listens to things like a typical game
would need, things like joystick input.
But we aren't making a typical game,
we're making VR.
So for us we want to remove this.
So click on the little gear icon,
and go down to Remove Component.
We instead want a new info module,
we want one that is going to
be configured for cardboard.
So go to Add Component and search for
gaze input module, gaze input module.
Okay, there it is and
then press Enter to select that.
The gaze input module is the module
that considers where you're looking at
with the viewer and
you're pressing the Viewer button.
It's the module for the gaze and click
way of interacting with an environment.
So you look at something and
you click the Viewer and the system will
register that the event occurred,
which we can use with the script.
Okay, so in order for
all of this to work,
your clickable objects must have
a collider attached to them.
This can be a sphere collider,
a box collider, a capsule collider, or
anything else.
But for our vacation box,
we're going to use a box collider.
So go ahead, click on your vacation
box over in the hierarchy.
Go to Add Component, and
then search for Box Collider.
Okay, great,
you'll notice that it is perfectly
sized to the size of the vacation box.
If you resize it you'll
see that it completely
snapped to the edges of this box.
So we have a collider
that is perfectly sized
to the size of the vacation box and
we are ready to go with that, okay.
So, now that we have a collider,
the next step is we have to get
something talking to this event system.
So, how do we do that?
Go ahead and
add a component called an event trigger.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Event trigger.
Once you do that,
you're going to see a new button
appear called, Add New Event Type.
Go ahead and click on that and
then you're going to see a whole bunch
of different event types pop up.
And you'll notice that
they're all mouse-oriented.
The GazeInputModule converts our VR
reticle into sort of a simulated mouse.
So for us, we want to be able
to click on this vacation box.
So go ahead and select PointerClick,
it's right here.
When you do that,
you're going to see a little plus
button appear down at the bottom.
And when you click that little
plus you'll see a new field appear
with an empty object holder.
Now we're going to talk more about
this in the next lesson, but for
now just now just know that this is
where we're going to wire in our method
that changes to our
beautiful island scene.
And we'll hook this up really soon.
Okay, so let's get working in our
next lesson on wiring up that script.