So let's say you're running
a web app on your own site and
some of your users are complaining
that they can't get to it anymore.
You want to figure out whether their
access is being blocked by a firewall or
a filter or
something between them and you.
Which of the following options do
you think might be useful to check?
First, can the user ping
your site by IP address?
Second, can the user access
a different domain on the same server?
Third, are you able to send them
email from your Gmail account?
Fourth, can they look up your
server's host name using DNS,
using a tool like host or dig?
And fifth,
are all of the users that report
the problem located in the same country?