We're going to talk about game theory,
which is the study of finding an optimal policy
when that policy can depend on the opponent's policy and vice versa.
And let's look at 1 of the most famous games of all,
a game called the "Prisoner's Dilemma."
And the story is that there are 2 criminals, Alice and Bob,
who have a working relationship, and they're both caught
at the scene of a crime, but the police don't quite have enough evidence
to put them away.
They offer each independently a deal saying
"If you testify against your cohort,
we'll give you a better deal and give you a reduced sentence time."
And Alice and Bob both understand what's going on.
They're both perfectly rational,
and to understand what the situation is,
we draw up a matrix in which we have possible outcomes
and possible strategies for each side.
For Alice, she has 2 strategies.
1 is to testify against Bob,
and the other is to refuse to testify.
And Bob has the same choices,
to testify against Alice or to refuse.
In general, different agents may have different actions available to them.
And now we show the payoff to each agent.
Sometimes those payoffs are opposite,
as in a game like chess where if 1 player gets a +1,
the other gets a -1.
In this game, the payoffs are not opposite,
so it's a non-zero-sum game.
And if they both refuse to testify against each other,
then neither can be convicted of the major crime,
but the police will get them for a lesser crime.
And let's say they each serve 1 year in jail,
so that's a -1 for each of them.
If Alice testifies and Bob refuses,
then the police are grateful to Alice,
and she gets off with nothing, and Bob gets
the book thrown at him and gets a -10 score.
Likewise, if the roles are reversed
and if both testify against each other, then they're both guilty,
and they split the penalty.
Now, the question that both Alice and Bob have to face
is what is the strategy going to be?
And the first concept we want to talk about
is the concept of a dominant strategy.
A dominant strategy is one for which a player
does better than any other strategy
no matter what the other player does.
And now the question is, does either Alice or Bob
have a dominant strategy?
If Alice has a dominant strategy,
I want you to check that off, either testify or refuse,
and similarly, if Bob has a dominant strategy,
check that off.