Now, 1 reason there's such a wide discrepancy in the outcomes
of these 2 versions of the game is that
we handicapped E and O so severely
that here E had to reveal his entire strategy,
whether he's going to play 1 or 2 all the time,
and the same thing for O over here.
What if we could think of a way where we didn't handicap them quite as much,
where they weren't giving away quite as much information?
Let's look at a way to do that.
Let's look at the situation where E goes first
and has to reveal the strategy,
but instead of having to reveal my strategy is
to play 1 or to play 2,
what if E says "Well, my strategy is
with probability P, I'm going to play 1."
"And with probability 1 - P, I'm going to play 2."
And that's called a mixed strategy.
So, E would announce that strategy for some number P.
And there could be an infinite number of possibilities,
so we should be drawing an infinite number of branches
out of this decision point for all the possibilities
for values of P that E would come up with.
But instead, I'm just going to sort of parameterize that
and just draw 1 line coming out.
And now O as the minimizing player
has to make a choice between 1 and 2, and what are the outcomes?
Well, if P was 1, then 1 + 1 is 2,
so with probability P, we get an outcome of 2.
That's 2P, but if we choose 2,
the probability 1 - P, then 2 + 1 is 3,
so with probability 1 - P, we get a -3.
So, 2P - 3 times 1 - P
would be the outcome for this day.
And then the outcome over here would be
-3P + 4 times 1 - P.
That's the parameterized outcome given the parameterized strategy.
And we could do the same thing on the other side.
What if O had to go first?
With probability Q, O plays 1,
and with probability 1 - Q plays 2.
Then even is the maximizer
and we get 2Q - 3(1 - Q)
and -3Q + 4(1 - Q).