Moving pages between physical memory and
secondary storage raises
some obvious questions.
When should pages be swapped out
of physical memory and onto disk?
And also, which particular
pages should be swapped out?
The first part is easier.
Periodically when the amount of occupied
memory reaches a particular threshold
the operating system will run some
page out daemon that will look for
pages that can be freed.
So something that would make sense as
an answer to this question would be that
the pages should be swapped out
when the memory usage in the system
reaches some level,
some high water mark.
And that this paging out should
be performed also when the CPU
usage is below a certain threshold so
as not to disrupt the execution
of some applications too much.
To answer the second question, one
obvious answer would be that the pages
that will not be used in the future
are the ones that should be swapped out.
The problem is,
how do we know which pages will
versus won't be used in the future?
To make some predictions
regarding the page usage,
operating systems use some
historic information.
For instance, one common set of
algorithms is to look at how recently or
how frequently has a page been used, and
use that to inform a prediction
regarding the page's future use.
The intuition here is that a page
that has been used most recently
is more likely to be needed in the
immediate future, whereas a page that
hasn't been accessed in a very long
time is less likely to be needed.
This policy is referred to as the LRU
policy, least recently used, and
it uses the access bit that's
available on modern hardware to
keep track of the information whether or
not the page is referenced or not.
Other useful candidates for pages that
should be freed up from physical memory
are the pages that don't need
to be written out to disk,
to secondary storage.
And that is because the process
of writing pages out
to the secondary storage takes
some time, consumes cycles,
so we'd like to avoid the overhead
of the memory management.
To assist with making this decision
which pages don't need to be written
out, the operating system can rely on
the dirty bit that's maintained by
the MMU hardware that keeps track of
which particular page has been modified.
So not just accessed and
referenced however, modified during
a particular period of time.
In addition there may be certain pages,
particularly certain pages containing
important kernel state or used for
I operations that should
never be swapped out.
Then making sure that these pages are
not considered by whatever replacement
algorithms are executed in the operating
system is going to be important.
In Linux and most OS's, a number of
parameters are available to allow
the system administrator to configure
the swapping nature of the system.
This would include thresholds such as
the ones that we mentioned earlier
that control when our page is swapped
out, but also other parameters such as
how many pages should be
replaced during a period of time.
Also Linux categorizes the pages
into different types and
then that helps narrow down the decision
process when it's trying to decide
which pages should be replaced.
Finally, the default replacement
algorithm in Linux is a variation of
the LRU policy we described,
and it gives a second chance.
It basically performs two scans of
a set of pages before determining which
ones are really the ones that should
be swapped out and reclaimed.
And similar types of decisions can be
made in other operating systems as well.