I created my manifest.json file,
it includes the name and
short name of full set of icons,
the start_url I want the browser to open
when the user clicks on it from their
home screen, display: stand alone, so
that it opens without any browser UI and
background and theme color.
Then in index.html,
I added a link to the manifest file and
added a meta theme-color.
Well, it's not required,
it does add a little extra to
the address bar when it's still visible.
I also added the tags for
add to home screen on mobile Safari,
apple-mobile-web-app-capable, to
hide the browser UI.
Apple-mobile-web-app-status-bar-style,
to set the status bar style.
Apple-mobile-web-app-title, to
set the title
when the app is added
to the home screen.
And the full set of icons.
One note about the icons, to make sure
they look their best, I gave the Apple
touch icons a white background and
left the other one's transparent.
Finally, I deployed
the weather app to Firebase.
If you want to see exactly what I did,
the solution I built is linked
in the instructor notes.
And that's it, you've built
your first progressive web app.
Congratulations.