You just learned about an exciting clustering algorithm
that's really easy to implement called k-means.
To give you the algorithm in pseudocode,
initially we select k cluster centers at random and then we repeat.
In a corresponding step, we correspond all the data points to the nearest cluster center,
and then we calculate the new cluster center by the mean of the corresponding data points.
We repeat this until nothing changes any more.
Now special care has to be taken if a cluster center becomes empty--that means no data point is associated.
In which case, we just restart cluster centers at random that have no corresponding points.
Empty cluster centers restart at random.
This algorithm is known to converge to a locally optimal clustering of data ponts.
The general clustering problem is known to be NP-hard.
So a locally optimal solution, in a way, is the best we can hope for.
Now let me talk about problems with k-means.
First we need to know k, the number of cluster centers.
As I mentioned, the local minimum.
For example, for 4 data points like this and 2 cluster centers that happen to be just over here,
with the separation line like this there would be no motion of k means.
Even though moving one over here and one over there would give a better solution.
There's a general problem of high dimensionality of the space
that is not dissimilar from the way k-nearest neighbor suffers from high dimensionality.
And then there's lack of a mathematical basis.
Now if you're a partitioner, you might not care about a mathematical basis.
But for the sake of this class, let's just care about it.
So here's a first quiz for k-means.
Given the following two cluster centers, C1 and C2,
click on exactly those points that are associated with C1 and not with C2.