I'm Eric an Android Developer hear
at Udacity and I'm here with Sam.
Sam, can you tell us a little
bit more about what you do.
>> Sure, I'm an Android coach and I help
students taking the Android Nanodegree
with Office Hours and things like that.
>> Great, so I have an application and
I need to be able to share
data with other applications, how would
I at first initially approach that?
>> So sharing data between apps, I mean
if the data is going to be unique to
your app and that your app is generating
some kind of data that only that app
has or only that app would store
than I would use a content provider.
Content providers it, pretty much
interacts with some sort of database,
some sort of data persistence on the
back end of maybe shared preferences or
something like that or
SQL database, SQLite.
But then if you have a content
provider that then becomes
accessible to any app on
your Android device via URI.
So you could call your content
resolver to find where this URI is and
communicate with the content provider
to manipulate that database,
either pull data or
perhaps push data or update data.
>> And so what would be a good
example where a content provider would
make sense, so
something provided by the system?
>> Mm-hm.
So I think a good example is just what
comes standard on an Android phone and
that would be your contacts list.
Say you want to upload
a contact from some new way,
maybe a website or take a picture
of their contact information.
And you build up that data, and then
using the content resolver you access
the address at address book and you
push that contact into your contacts.
>> Yeah, that's perfect.