All right, you're done.
Let's take a look at the solution.
While we cannot insert
a vector directly,
we can easily convert
a vector to an array.
Once we've done this, the bulk insert
method will insert very efficiently.
As you can see, we've uncommented
out this next series of lines.
This allows us to test
our output to make sure
that we've actually inserted
the right thing into the database.
Let's actually run our app.
And as you can see, we're actually
reading the data out of the database
that we just inserted all correctly.
Now our back end will update
efficiently, but we really need to be
querying things before requesting
them from the internet.
After all, the main point is to
have a responsive application.
We're still not even updating
the screen until we've
pulled data down from the web.
We also want to avoid doing
our query on the UI thread,
because doing operations like queries on
the UI thread cause Android to not be
able to draw frames fast enough,
which introduces frame rate jitter.
Fortunately, Android offers
a pattern for that known as Loaders.