So now that we understand how
services work, let's review how
Android determines your app's priority
when it kills off applications.
App priority is divided into four
general buckets, critical, high, medium,
and low.
Within each bucket the apps
are prioritized in
a queue with the app that's
been at the lowest priority for
the longest the first
in line to be executed.
Critical apps are those
which are active.
They're in the foreground
interacting with users.
That includes activities
in the foreground and
apps running a foreground service.
An activity in the foreground
is slightly more important than
a foreground service only
on recent Android releases.
But both are considered critical.
So if you're running a very heavy
weight app in the foreground or
your foreground service
process is very heavy itself,
Android may kill your
other foreground services.
Visible activities are high priority,
while less impactful than killing
a foreground app or foreground service,
destroying visible activities
is still quite undesirable, because
users will most likely notice it.
Services are important, but
they can be killed much of the time
without impacting the user directly.
That being said the system
tries to keep them alive and
will even try to restart
sticky services.
Apps that are running in
the background are either completely
empty apps with no active
Android component or
apps with a stopped component,
but not yet destroyed.
They're the red shirted instance
of the app priority landing party.
Android keeps both of these
around as much as possible,
killing empty apps first,
because keeping allocated memory
around is cheap, while restarting
apps can be relatively expensive.
They'll be killed as
needed in a last seen,
first killed order to support
the higher priority apps.
I like to think of this as the three
laws of Android resource management.
Law one, Android will keep all apps that
interact with the user running smoothly.
Law two, Android will keep all apps with
visible activities followed by services
running, unless doing so
violates the first law.
And third, Android will keep all
apps in the background running,
unless this violates the first or
second law.