All right, so
here we are back in the Android Studio,
reviewing the source for
our DroidCardsView.
Again, this is our custom view.
Just to recall, it's in this custom view
that we build our stacked playing cards.
For example,
each card has its own bitmap, and
we draw them to the screen by
overriding the onDraw method.
Now remember,
by overriding the onDraw method,
Android won't be able to optimize
the rendering of this view, so
it's our job as developers
to properly clip each card
as it's drawn to the screen to
avoid the unnecessary overdraw.
Fortunately, the Canvas API gives us
just the right methods we need to draw
our cards more efficiently.
Let's take a look at the documentation.
Let's use the canvas.clipRect
method to improve our code.
We're going to use this variant here
that takes four floats as parameters.
All right,
now we're back in Android Studio.
Let's tweak how we draw each cascaded
card so that we reduce this overdraw.
I'm going to use this nifty feature
within Android Studio to bring up a diff
view, so you can see the before and
after state of the code.
'Kay, all right, here we are in our
comparison view, and let's look
particularly at the onDraw method,
which is the one we're overriding.
We've got the old state of the for
loop here on the left,
but let's focus here on the improvements
that we're going to make on the right.
Now, as we iterate over the cards,
let's go over each step of improvement.
Number one, first, we're going to
calculate the position for the card.
Then we need to call this
function canvas.save,
which is going to save our
existing canvas state.
In other words,
it maintains the existing state of your
screen before we apply the clipRect API.
Now, when we call this clipRect method,
we're basically doing some
geometric restrictions.
When we pass in these parameters,
we're basically telling the system
to only draw a portion of the card
that we want to see visible.
Obviously, the rest of
it would be hidden.
Now, only the parts of the card that lie
within the bounds of the restriction
that we just put will get drawn.
Finally, we're going to
call canvas.restore,
which is going to revert the canvas
to a non-clipping state.
In other words,
it's going to undo the restriction that
we put in place when we called clipRect.
And then we repeat this loop for
all the cards except the top one.
Now specifically, we process the top or
last card differently than
its underlying siblings.
For this one, no clipping is needed, so
we're going to go ahead and
draw it in its entirety.
You can see that via
the statement right here.
All right,
let's build our improved code and
see if we've reduced
a bunch of overdraw.
All right, awesome.
As you can see here, much less overdraw.
Now I hope it's clear that with the
Canvas API, we have a straightforward
way to draw efficiently when
working with custom views.
Oh, and in case you want to
explore the Canvas API some more,
be sure to check out the full
documentation in the instructor notes.
Now, views like these are great for
helping us create a unique and
compelling UX, but
remember that we must clue in the system
to help Android render such
views in a performant fashion.
So whenever you're creating a custom
view, be sure to check for overdraw, and
be ready to revive your friend,
the clipRect method.
All right, awesome work.
Let's head back to Colt for
more perf wisdom.