So when you're done your
unconnected should look like this.
I've removed the old code where
as using the Plus.PeopleApi and
I've replaced it with new code where
I'm using Plus.AccountApi instead.
As you can see I'm calling the get
account name and I'm passing and
it the Api clients.
I'm then setting the text
on my status label
to be this email address that I got
back when I called getAccountName.
It just returned a string email
address and I'm setting that here.
So I say signed into My App as
whatever the emailAddress is.
When I'm in email scope I don't
have access to my full name or
other meta data like that,
I just have access to the email address,
as the name of the scope would suggest.
So lets run this application and
see what it looks like.
So now we can see
the application running.
So if I click the Sign In button,
first I'm going to get
the permissions dialogue, and
once I do that I'm now going to hit
my breakpoint because I've signed in.
So if I step over the breakpoint here,
and I look in my debugger window,
we can now see that my email address
has been set, and I was signed in as
lmoroney@gmail.com and the email
address string now contains that.
So if I then just set text
on that to the status and
I'll continue running the application.
If I switch back to the emulator
you'll now see I'm signed into
my app as almoroney@gmail.com.
And you'll also see that I've set
the button to be disabled, so
I'm using the disabled state
on the button and that's it.
It's as simple as that in
order to get email access and
your users may prefer this instead
of giving access to their profile.
And if all you need to do is a simple
thing where you're tracking users
that are signed in, and
their email address is unique enough,
this might be a better way, and
a much more user-friendly way.