All right,
welcome back to Computer Vision.
What we're doing in this lesson is,
we're basically going to finish up
motion estimation, and this is the raw
estimation of motion with respect
to sort of a motion field.
Going forward, we're going to do
things like tracking, and other, and
other sorts of examples where we'll sort
of use motion in order to essentially
process an entire video, but here only
talking about frame to frame motion.
In the previous couple lessons we talked
about methods that gave us dense flow,
except for that sparse l k thing.
Where we had a different estimate for
each pixel and we didn't have any
real serious constraint between them
other than something like,
local smoothness or something like that.
That is, we, we were just imposing
this on the image without any sort
of real thought to what's
going within the picture.
But suppose you know that the motion
is actually constrained, okay?
So for example, maybe you know, you're
just looking at something rotating and
you want to recover the motion
all right, so that would co,
constraint on the motion field.
Or suppose you know that some
object's variation in depth
is small compared to
the depth to the camera.
Okay, so
delta z is small compared to total z.
That gives you another
constraint on how things move.
In these cases, you might want to
have sort of a model for the flow,
that is, how do I think the points
could be moving within a region?