So when you talk about
software vulnerabilities,
it is affected by what
language you program in.
So there's safer programming languages
compared to programming languages
that are less safe where
it's easier to make or
have bugs that can be exploited or
bugs that become vulnerabilities.
So one idea is strongly typed languages.
They're basically every piece of data
that we have must have a type, and type
defines what you can do, what kind of
operations you can perform on the data.
So strongly typed
languages allow only that
operations to be performed which
are defined for their data type.
Weakly don't care so
much, they may sometimes allow you to
do something that is not consistent.
Java is a strongly typed language.
I should say that there is no strict
separation in terms of where strongly
ends and where weakly type starts,
but Java is strongly, C or
Python or something are not
as strongly typed languages.
So this quiz is how does strong
typed versus weak type languages,
now how do they help or hurt in terms
of software security is concerned.
Or whatever it is that can arise in
software that can impact its security.
Is it helped by strongly?
Certain things that we talked about here
in the options actually are relevant to
potential vulnerabilities.
This quiz question is actually asking,
how does that strongly versus weakly
typed language either make these
things possible or not possible, okay?
So if the first option, for
example you think this is possible with
strongly typed then put S, otherwise put
W, and do that for all three options.