>> All right, let's build off our knowledge from the last problem. >> We know
that here we had an equal sign here last time, so when this was equal x had to
be two. >> So there is one solution, but we don't have an equal sign here, we
have an in equality sign. >> So I want this right side to be larger than eight.
>> If x was two, I get eight. >> So that means if x was any number bigger than
two, then this side would be larger than eight. >> I'm going to try plugging in
3. >> If I plug in 3, I get 9 plus 2 on the right. >> So 8 is less than 11. >>
This is great. >> This is a solution that works. >> And in fact, any number
bigger than 3 would give me a number larger than 8 when I plug in. >> So,
there's gotta be more than one solution. >> There's not just 1 or 2, there's
infinitely many. >> There's more than three. >> If you choose this one, nice
work. >> You might be skeptical just looking at this one solution. >> Let me
show you four. >> When I plug in 4, I get 8 is less than 12 plus 2, or 8 is less
than 14. >> Plugging in any number bigger than 2, like 3 4 5 or even 500 would
work. >> That's why there's infinitely many solutions here.