Okay, let's have a quick look at the
triggers and the tags that you created.
So the triggers,
the new triggers are openScreen,
which fires when the event equals
openScreen and Daily Special Screen,
which fires when the screen
name equals Show Daily Special.
So those were the triggers and
then the tag that you created.
We'll see, was a tag to send the Daily
Special Screen Hit to Analytics.
You created a variable for
the Analytics account ID.
The track type must be App View,
App View.
And you must set the screenName field,
must be spelled exactly this way,
to the value of the screen name
that gets set in the code,
which in our case is Show Daily Special.
We only want it to fire when screen
name equals, Show Daily Special,
and when the event was open screen.
In the process of doing that you have
created the variable My Tracking ID,
which is a constant who's value
is your analytics account id.
And if you did all that,
you should see your hits coming into
analytics when you run your app.