So which is your favorite option to deal with edge issues?
Load up the image package, read an image, create a gaussian filter.
Remember gaussians are special.
Now when you apply it, specify an edge parameter.
Passing in zero is equivalent to the default.
You can see the black seeping in along all the edges.
This is because we passed in zero.
What happens if we put in some other number?
Try it out.
What about circular?
If you look closely, you'll see the green seeping in on this side, and
a little bit of red on the opposite side.
Replicate.
Replicate is not too bad.
No obvious effects.
And lastly, symmetric, or reflect across edge.
Not bad either, actually not too different from replicate.
Feel free to experiment with these different options, filter sizes, and sigmas.