Let me now show you an example of
a simple translation using our
browser code here.
Basically again, we start off by just
simply doing things like importing
a computer vision two kit and
numpy and there from there on,
we're going to look at basically
doing things like read the image.
How just reading the tech image itself,
get more information from it.
Again we can show it and
here basically just see me
creating a simple translation or
transformation matrix.
If you notice of course it's transform
by 100 pixels and 50 pixels and
the diagonal terms are one and
one in my matrix.
Of course, using this now,
this translation matrix we can print the
translation matrix, and then, of course,
apply the transformation using this
piece of this co, function here which
actually takes the transformation
matrix and applies this to this image.
Let's see what it looks
like when we run this.
So here, of course, you see the
translation matrix being printed out.
Here is my image.
This is the original image.
And of course, this is the final image
that has been translated by, of course,
100 pixels and 50 pixels.