Hey, Catherine, so now,
that we don't insert feature,
can I add on my new pets into it?
So, I have Clyde, my pet rock,
Paul my shoulder turtle,
my toaster, and
then Boo Boo my imaginary pet dragon.
>> What?
Jessica these are not pets.
What do you mean?
Some of them have names and
the pets app allows me to enter them
into it even if some of them empty
names or negative weight values.
>> No, we don't want all those
invalid data into our database
because then the UI won't
know how to handle it.
Like it doesn't know how
to show a toaster or
a rock, we need to fix the code.
You're missing a sanity check.
>> Excuse me, I am perfectly sane.
[LAUGH] No,
I meant sanity check the data,
making sure we only allow valid
values in the database and
we block invalid, weird values
like your imaginary pet here.
Okay, let's make sure we help
the staff capture data accurately.
>> All right, fair point,
it's okay Boo Boo,
you're always be in
the database of my heart