Consider an ideal cache of
size Z equals four words.
Assume that the transfer or
line size L is equal to one word.
Now consider a program that consists
of the following sequence of 10 load
operations.
Pretend that these 16 bit hexadecimal
values are word aligned addresses.
Now, suppose our cache
is initially empty.
Then suppose you execute
the first instruction.
It loads the value at hex address BEEF.
Since the cache is empty,
the hardware can store the value at
this address somewhere in cache.
I've denoted that action by writing the
hex address in brackets in a cache line.
Remember that by the rules of
how an ideal cache operates,
we can assume full associativity.
That means for an empty cache I could
have placed this address anywhere.
Here's your first task.
Suppose you execute the first
nine instructions, that is,
all the instructions except the last.
Here's my first question, what's
the state of the cache at this point?
That is, I want you to fill in
the addresses that would be in cache
after the first nine
instructions have executed.
You can just type the addresses in
the same notation square bracket and
hexidecimal address into the lines.
Now that's not all.
Here's your second task.
As you simulate what the cash would do,
I want you to count
the number of evictions.
Enter that value in this box.