[Thrun] The essence of HMMs are really simply characterized
by the following Bayes network.
There's a sequence of states that evolve over time,
and each state depends only on the previous state in this Bayes network.
Each state also emits what's called a measurement.
It is this Bayes network that is the core of hidden Markov models
and various probabilistic filters such as Kalman filters, particle filters, and many others.
These are words that might sound cryptic and they might not mean anything to you,
but you might come across them as you study different disciplines of computer science
and control theory.
The real key here is the graphical model.
If you look at the evolution of states,
what you'll find is that these states evolve as what's called a Markov chain.
In a Markov chain, each state only depends on its predecessor.
So for example, state S3 is conditioned on S2 but not on S1.
It's only immediate through S2 that S3 might be influenced by S1.
That's called a Markov chain, and we're going to study Markov chains quite a bit
in this class to understand them well.
But what makes it a hidden Markov model or hidden Markov chain, if you wish,
is the fact that there is measurement variables.
So rather than being able to observe the state itself, what you get to see are measurements.
Let me put this to perspective, showing you several of the robots I've built
that possess hidden state.
And where I only get to observe certain measurements,
let me infer something about the hidden state.