Let's talk about reflection models.
Here we have our surface, okay.
And we have our incident light, and it's coming in.
And it's coming in at some particular direction, and this'll be some theta i,
which is going to be the tilt off of the surface normal.
The first physical process I want to talk about is referred to as sort of
body reflection.
And what happens is, is the light comes in, and
it sort of scatters around at the top part of the surface.
And then it comes out in lots of different directions.
And therefore, it's impacted by the stuff that's in the surface,
all right, and that's referred to as diffuse or body reflection, okay.
And, it tends to have what's referred to as a matte appearance, and
some sort of very, lets refer to it as non-homogeneous,
sort of particulate matter, have that kind of reflection.
So, an example here is this clay pot, if you think of this clay pot and
you look at it, in some sense there's no shininess to it at all.
Right? It's purely matte, it's purely diffuse.
And in particular we'll talk later no matter what direction you look at it,
it seems to be approximately the same brightness.
It turns out it's actually pretty hard to make purely matte surfaces.
Like if you take matte spray paint and you spray something even then
there's sort of a certain amount of shininess to it.
Which we'll get to in a minute.
But the, the general model we're that looking at of body reflection is
the light comes in, is scattered about in the medium of the surface and
then goes out in variety of directions.
So that's the body or diffuse reflection model.
So what else can happen to the light?
Well the other thing that can happen to the light,
is referred to as a specular reflection, okay?
So a specular reflection just like you think,
some of the light before we saw penetrates down et cetera.
But, some of the light doesn't, it just bounces straight back up.
Okay? And that's referred to as surface reflection.
And surface reflection is a specular reflection, and it, it's responsible for
sort of the glossy highlights that you see on shiny surfaces.
And in metals in particular.
So here's a picture of a variety of things.
I'm going to, this one, by the way, is, is a fake picture.
That's just to show you the highlights.
But for example, shiny metal things this metal pot.
Here's an interesting one, right,
here's a can, that clearly has stuff painted on it, right?
So that's affecting the light coming in, it scatters around and bounces out.
But you see also that there's this stripe here, right?
Well that stripe is the specular component of what's there.
By the way, if you want to study more about specular things,
the reason it works in metals, it has to do with the way the light interacts
with the electrons that are in the surface.
And, that's part of what you know, makes metals metals, or these free electrons.
Go take a look at your material, science stuff, but those sort of,
atomic physical properties have an impact on how
light behaves when it hits the the surface.
All right?
And that's your specular reflection.
And the general overall view of the universe, is that the image intensity can be
thought of as a combination of the body reflection, plus the surface reflection.
Okay.
And as a reasonable model for what's going on,
we can sort of model most surfaces as having a certain component of body or
matt reflection, plus specular reflection.