By now, you should be done with the
sleeping in the library app but what I
want you to do is see if you can explain
it in your own words to someone else.
The reason I'm asking you this question
is because it's a very common interview
type of question.
The question has many answers and
there's probably no single right answer,
that's the point.
Depending on how you
answer the question, and
how much detail you provide,
an interviewer can get a good
quick idea of your technical
understanding of the problem.
So, in your own words, I want you to
describe the interactions between
the client and the server in
the sleeping in the library app.
Write your description in the box below