In this question I would like you to check all the boxes that are true.
First, there exists at least one environment in which every agent is rational,
by which I mean optimal.
For every agent, there exists (at least) one environment in which the agent is rational.
To solve the sliding-tile 15-puzzle, an optimal agent that searches will usually require
less memory than an optimal table-lookup reflex agent.
By "usually" I mean there are always extreme cases that he can construct
where this isn't the case. I ask about the common case.
Here is the sliding-tile 15-puzzle,
and you can see this is a puzzle where you move these pieces around
until all these numbers are in order.
It's a somewhat combinatorial search problem.
Finally, to solve the sliding-tile 15-puzzle, an agent that searches will always do better--
that means it will always find shorter paths--
than a table-lookup reflex agent.