To learn more about design, we'll be
improving upon a Visual Polish app
that displays a list of the topics
we'll be covering in this lesson.
Colors and fonts, styles and themes,
building responsive layouts, and
creating touch selectors.
And when you click on any of these,
it will lead you to a unique activity.
Where we'll be creating and
coding things like colors and fonts.
Or another example,
building a layout for a sample article.
The starting state for all of these
activities will look pretty simple,
with a default color scheme and
unpolished UI.
Then throughout the lesson,
we'll learn about design.
And step by step add visual
polish to each activity.
At the end we'll get to this state,
we'll have a custom color scheme and
each activity will have a polished UI.
One thing to note in the starter code
that you'll be given is that each
of these activities is separate and
they have separate layouts as well.
The layout files are where we'll be
working for much of this lesson.
They're in the resources
directory in the layout folder and
their names according to their activity.
There's one for the colors and
font activity, the style activity,
our responsive layout activity,
and our touch selectors activity.
We'll also be using some simple
icon images in this app.
Like the icons commonly found
in mail Inbox is here and
all of these icons are in
these drawable folders.
And we'll learn a little more about
these drawable folders later on.
Next, you have find instructions for
downloading the starter code.
And then we'll start coding to
reach the final state of our app.