This course has four major sections.
The first is this introduction,
where we talk about the fundamentals
of ubiquitous computing.
The following sections each deal
with an area of ubiquitous computing
that are industries in their own right.
In wearables, we'll discuss the design
philosophy for wearable computing, and
then dive into the Android Wear platform
with notifications, watch faces,
and a watch app.
We'll then make our way into the living
room and discuss building for
the big screen with Googlecast and
Android TV.
Finally, we'll take a road
trip with Android Auto.
At the end of the course, you'll have
all of the knowledge and tools you need
to build an app across multiple new
form factors, creating an experience for
your user that works across contexts and
throughout their day.