Normally, only one program can listen
on a given port on a machine at a time.
But once a program starts,
it can run threads or
child processes that handle
incoming connections on a port, or
a loop between several connections and
handle all of them.
That's what a web server does to
be able to handle more than one
connection at a time.
NC-L doesn't do that.
It's not really a full server as such
just sort of a listener that only
accepts a single connection.
There's a standard Linux program that
you can use to find out which programs
are listening or otherwise,
using network connections.
The lsof program, name stands for
list open files, and
it has an option -i, to make it
list internet sockets specifically.
You'll have to run it using sudo
to give it root privileges.
Try that now on your Linux box.
Use sudo lsof-i and
in its output, look for
the names of programs
that are listening.
They'll say, LISTEN,
in all capitals and write them here.