Emily, you know what bothers me more than anything?
>> What's that, RJ? >> Jittery GPS tracks. >> Yeah, I hate Jittery..
>> What's jittery GPS tracks? >> Well, you know,
is when the GPS tracker has low accuracy,
and seems I'm driving on the side of the road,
it drives me crazy. I mean, why can't they
just know that I'm driving on a
particular Road?
>> Why's it always gotta be so jittery? >> Well, RJ,
I know the perfect solution to
your problem.
>> Have you heard of the Google Maps roads
API? >> No, but tell me more.
Well, the roads API takes in those
questionably accurate GPS points, such as
these jittery points around Munich
Germany on the Blumen straße and
Frauen straße, and snaps them to the road
that you are most likely on. You simply
pass in up to a hundred of these jittery
GPS coordinates, and poof, the roads API
returns a similar set of data with the
points snapped to the most likely road the
vehicle was traveling along.
Optionally, you can request that the
points be interpolated, resulting in a
path that smoothly follows the geometry
of the road.
>> Are you serious? That's amazing! >> I know,
think of all the fleet tracking and ride
sharing applications that could benefit
from something like this.
>> And guess what? >> What? >> There's more! >> what?
>> With the roads API you can also get back
posted speed limit data for a particular
Road segments. >> That is super useful,
now you can identify vehicles that might
be speeding. >> Exactly, remember, the roads
API is only available as a web service,
also, it's important to note that this
date is only available to Premium plan
customers, so the API key that you
generated and your newly created
developers project won't work for these
types of requests.
Let's test out a few speed limit data
requests. This is a snap to roads request,
so will input the required parameters,
which is our path, a set of eight jittery
GPS points. And we'll set interpolate to
"true".
We are also including our API key, of
course.
What we get back is a set of nicely
fitted points, which if I plot them will
appear right along a road, as you can see
we get back way more than eight points
because we've interpolated to get many
more points.
This on the other hand, is a speed limits
request. We still pass in a path which
consists of GPS points and our API key.
What we get back is speed limit data
about points along that route.
Keep in mind that these are specifically
web services,
there isn't an equivalent service within
our JavaScript API.
However, if you're running a delivery
service or taxi hailing app,
this can be really useful in getting you
accurate location data.
Wow, that was some really cool stuff,
thanks for solving my GPS problem, now
let's go get some ice cream.