Cudit has a lot of moving parts, and
we'll see them all in lesson four.
But for now we're pairing things
down to their essentials.
When objects are persistent, they live
on the hard drive, often in SQL light.
We need to be able to pull them
up out of the Core Data stack and
into our working memory.
When we use Core Data to bring
these objects into memory,
we can't use plain old
Swift objects anymore.
Our classes need to be a special
subclass that fits into
the Core Data system.
It'll have to be subclasses
of NSManagedObject.
It's not such a terrible price to pay.
We can work this into an inheritance
hierarchy if we need to.
When we write the first lines
of the class definitions here,
this is our movie class, we can see
the inherits from NSManagedObject.
It's not a terrible price,
but I think that it begins to capture
the feeling of working with Core Data.
The system owns our
objects in a new way.
We're still going to have movie
objects and person objects, but
each of these objects will be closely
monitored by the Core Data system.
Core Data is going to keep a reference
to every single NSManagedObject.
In a way it's really nice.
Let's say we make a change to one
of our objects inside our code.
At any time,
we could tell Core Data to save.
When we do, it'll capture the state
of our real live objects,
persist them on the hard drive.
That's what we mean when we say
that they're managed objects.
Even though we use them in our code,
we tell Core Data to save and
they're all saved.
Notice that I'm referring to this object
quite a bit at the top of the stack.
We call this a managed object context,
often we will refer to
it just as a context.
We're going to start our exploration
of Core Data by working with
a context that's all set up.
It's the object that'll keep
track of all our managed objects,
it's the object that will
handle the save method.
We'll also see that when we want to
get our objects up and into memory,
we also used a context.
We'll accomplish this by
invoking a fetch method.
In fact, let's jump into our favorite
actor's app and see this in action.
The app is already fitted out with
a Core Data stack as you'll see, and
it's pre-configured with a few actors.
Let's jump right into the action.
We'll use fetch to get to managed
objects from the context.