Let's start looking at this with a little bit of an eye for the mathematics.
What we're interested in is computing the change in appearance by
shifting the window.
And we're shifting the window in two different directions, u and v.
So of course this is my measure that I want to look at.
This is my image.
Basically what I do with this image is I move it by u and
v in different directions.
And of course subtracted by the original and
look over some squared differences or the difference in the square of it.
Of course, to help us look at this carefully,
we'll also create a small function, a box function like this.
Which basically, any time I'm with in this, I get the answer one.
Outside I get 0.
Or I can put a Gaussian curve like this.
So, in essence this is my intensity function.
This is my shifted intensity.
Again, recall all the kinds of stuff we've done with intensities.
And how we've looked at the neighborhoods of it in all of our work on
convolutions and correlations and filtering.
And this is the window function, how big the window is and
how actually want to keep the size of the window impacting what I'm looking at.
And this is my function, which basically captures the change in appearance.
Let me actually showcase a little bit of how we can compute this by
the simple example.
What we basically want to do, is compute the change in appearance by
shifting a window by you know, it's small u and small v.
Here's a simple image, and here I've basically shown you
a small window within this that I won't actually compute information on.
So here is the response function E u, v for this one.
Computed by using an equation like this.
And again, just assume that we picked up one w x y to allow us to do this.
And the value, of course, here is E 0, 0.
And this is the window that I have.
And of course, I can now compute the whole E u, v, for that window u, v.
I can also compute the E three, two for this win, pixel here.
Which is three down and two up, or three sideways and two up.
Which allows me to kind of look at the whole function which would
be this part here.
And of course, that results in an additional window, like this.
This allows me to do the computation I want.
And again, remember the tools we looked at again,
that lets you do neighborhood calculations on images.
And in essence, this basically allows us to do that kind of stuff.
Looking again this corner mathematics, let's build on this concept a bit more.
So let's take this equation.
And take a quadratic approximation of it using Taylor expansion.
And the result is something like this.
An approximation where E u v basically now is written in
a matrix form with u and v, M u and v transpose.
So what is M?
M is the second moment matrix computed from the image derivatives, Ix and Iy.
Remember how to compute I x and I y?
We have done this before when we looked at derivatives of images.
So a second normal matrix is a matrix derived from the gradient of a function.
And in essence, it summarizes the predominant directions of the gradient in
a specified neighborhood point.
Then again, repeating, it summarizes the predominant directions of
the gradient in a specified neighborhood of the point.
And the degree of this, basically what happens with this,
is the degree to which the directions are coherent.
Allow you to say something specific about an image or a feature.
In essence what that means is M, again with the weighted window here, is the x
derivative twice squared of that one, x and y derivatives and x and y.
Well the, the forms of the off diagonal terms, and
of course, the square of y would be here.
Visually what this means is that if I had an image like this,
for any point here, basically I'm looking for, two axes.
And in essence, what I'm looking for is the maximal directions that allow me
to kind of encode the information that makes this feature unique.
So in essence, at the gradient of the function,
it gives you the predominant directions of the gradient in a specific point.
And we compute this using this methodology here,
where basically we compute the Ix and Iy's.
And use this to create a matrix.
And it basically starts giving me information about how the gradient
directions are dominant for this image at this point.
Remember [INAUDIBLE].
We'll come back to this in a second.