Just want to write that, M in a slightly different way, because it's the way
that we're actually going to make use of when we solve for this thing.
So, here we have the same equations written out.
You see, we have the world coordinates mapped through M,
gives us the homogenous pixel coordinates.
And what I've done, written here is,
I've taken this M matrix, which, remember, is a three by four.
And I said that you can think of it as three vectors each of
length four transposed as the rows, so each of these rows is a vector.
I've also introduced something new here,
I don't think I've showed it on this slide before.
Remember, this is what we said before, okay?
I'm, I'm using s as a scale, instead of z, right, and so
we have s times u, s times v, and s.
And later to get out u and v, we just just divide by s.
And I've put this little operator here, but it's just a squiggle with
a straight line underneath, sometimes two straight lines underneath.
And it's what's known as projectively similar.
So you'll notice that this vector and
this vector are exactly the same except for a scale factor, all right.
The vector on the left multiplied by s, gives you the vector on the right.
And remember, in homogeneous coordinates or using the projective,
those two vectors are essentially the same, because when I use their values,
I divide out by the left, by the last, component.
So, that's what's referred to as projectively similar, so
that's also introduced here.
So, just finishing, the way I recover u and v is, I divide the dot product,
the dot of the vector of the point p in the world with the first row,
divided by that dot product with the third row, that's what's right here.
And then to get the v value, I do the same thing, but
now with the second row, all right.
So basically, what we have to find, when we're going to find,
when we're going to do camera calibration, is, we have to find those m elements.