Here we're back to our diagram where we've got our incident light coming in,
light going out in some direction, and
the surface appears equally bright from all directions.
That is, it is independent of your viewing direction, all right.
So one way of thinking about this is that the BRDF of a Lambertian surface is
simply a constant, and that constant is referred to as the albedo.
And here it's just written as rho, and this is the rho sub-d for diffuse.
By the way, often, when this is written you'll see a cosine theta
i in the denominator, and that's for compensating for this viewing condition.
But I think that just makes life confusing.
So, we're just going to think of the,
the BRDF as being a constant for a, a Lambertian surface.
And so, what that means is that the surface radiance
is just going to be that constant times the source intensity,
i, times the cosine of the incident angle.
Right? because the, the irradiance is a function of the radiance of
your source times the cosine of that angle, and
then the thing looks equally bright from all directions.
So that's usually written this way,
as just the magnitude of the source times the albedo.
And you can write this as the dot product between the normal and
the incident direction, right.
It's just the dot product, the cosine, between the normal of the surface and
the angle of the light coming in.
And that's what's referred to as Lambertian shading.
Here's an example of, again, a fake sphere Lambertian shaded, and the idea of
course is that, you know, when it's pointing in the direction of the light
source it's brightest, and then it falls off by the cosine of that angle.
Okay, so that's the matte component, the body component.