Our favorite actor app is up and
working.
But it's time for
us to tackle the class that we took for
granted in lesson three,
the Core Data stack manager.
We've been using a convenient
singleton method to get a hold of this
stack manager.
The class method named sharedInstance.
It gives us a handle to an object
that represents the whole stack.
Let's consider this whole diagram
to be that very shared object.
What does it consist of?
What kind of objects
does it hold inside?
One thing that we know for
sure is that it holds context.
An instance of NSManagedObjectContext.
We've been accessing this context
through the managed object
context property.
We've insinuated that this context
sits on top of a Core Data stack.
What is this stack?
Well, quite a bit as it turns out.
Let's take a look deeper.
One of the things that this stack
contains is an object that describes
the movie and person entities.
This object is called the manage
object model or the model.
And it's created using
a special Xcode tool.
We're going to learn to use
that tool in this lesson.
Any time that you use Core Data,
you will make one of these models.
Your virtual tour staff will have
a similar model that describes
the pins and pictures.
After that, we get into the standard
machinery of Core Data.
The machinery that actually persists
the objects into the hard drive.
At the very bottom of the stack is
the file that actually holds the data.
Our manager starts out with a handle to
the familiar documents directory where
the files live.
And what is this file?
Core Data is capable of using an XML
file or bites from an NSData, but
usually Core Data uses a database
file in the SQLite format.
Our Core Data stack manager has
code to help it find this file.
In our case,
it's called FavoriteActors.sqlite.
Rest easy.
You don't need to know how to uses
relational databases to use Core Data.
Xcode makes this file for us, and
we never interact with it, directly.
Instead, our stack manager has an object
named the persistent store coordinator.
Again, we won't need to work with
this object directly, either.
But in order to write
the Core Data stack manager class,
we'll need to know the steps
required to make one.
When we invoke save or fetch on the
context, it works with this persistent
store coordinator to interact
with the SQLite file.
In this lesson,
we're going to go line by line through
the whole coredatamanager.swift
file and make sure that there's
nothing mysterious about how
this class gets built.
As we said, it's good to have that
kind of confidence in an interview.
But first, we're going to focus on
this managed object model, or model.
The tool that we use to configure this
object is one of the more interesting
Xcode features.
It's a little bit like storyboard,
but for data.
It's called the model editor.
We'll use it to define the person and
movie entities, purely logically.
In a second, we'll take a look.