If we subtract expected values from observed values, we could get positive or
negative. But then we square it, so the numerator will always be positive.
Frequencies are also always positive. We can't get negative ten of something.
Negative ten successful climbs. That doesn't really make sense. So, all of
these values will always be positive. And then you'll just sum up positive
values. Therefore, chi-squared statistics are never negative. And just like the
F-test, this means that it's one-directional, in the positive direction. This
is what the chi-squared distribution looks like. And again, we have a chi
squared critical value here denoted by chi squared star. That cuts off a
certain probability. Remember that the total area under this probability
distribution is 1 or, 100%. And just like we've been doing with all of our
other tests, we want to find the critical value that cuts off a certain
probability as defined by our alpha level, 0.05 or 0.01. In this class we've
been using 0.05.