Well isolation involves
a lot of strategy, and
some of this you just learn by playing.
Shelly and
I are going to play a few games and
see if we can actually show some of
these interesting points of isolation.
Shelly, last time I went first,
why don't you go first this time?
>> Okay.
Let's see, last time I went in
the center, so let's try something else.
Go up here.
>> You don't like the center,
but I often like the center.
I'm going to go for it.
>> I'm going to try to go over here.
>> Well, one thing I found as a human
player is at often pays to stay
close to your enemy, that way you can
block them off as quickly as possible.
The other thing is, you block off their
access to the rest of the board quickly.
The question is,
what can I do here to actually cause
Shelly the most inconvenience?
I would think that one thing I could
do is to go in this place here, and
that blocks her this way, but
she can still go that way.
I really kind of like this diagonal,
because that way I can jump either
way depending on how she goes.
I'm going to do this.
>> Okay, I'm going to try to and
go far away from Thad.
I'm going to jump to, let's say,
this opposite corner.
>> I'm going to keep on attacking and
being very aggressive here.
I'm going to do the same
thing to her I did last time.
I'm going to go here.
>> I'm going to keep going around,
see what happens.
>> I'm going to do something a little
different than what I normally do.
Normally I would go here and
just keep on limiting her options, but
now if I go here I'm going to have this
big diagonal that I can play with, so
I'm going to try that.
I have no idea if it's going to work.
>> Now I can't move to the right, but
I can go down here on the diagonal,
and maybe I can still get to
the right side of the board.
This is a little weird.
I'm starting to get
a partition of the board where
we're going to be
isolated from each other.
In that case, the person who has
the least number of moves or
least numbers of squares filled out
on their side board is going to win.
But it's on a diagonal and
it's very hard to fill up the diagonal.
But I can see what happens.
Let's see if I can keep Shelly
out from my upper right corner.
>> I think the right side has more
empty squares for me to go, so
I'm going to try and run up here
>> I really love that Shelly did that,
because now I can actually
finish isolating her off.
I'm going to go here, and
I'm going to get her stuck.
>> Uh-oh.
It looks like I'm stuck.
I only have one spot to go to now,
so I have to take that.
>> And now I can go here,
and on the next move, I win.
>> That was an unusual game in that we
were bouncing around the board a lot.
A lot of times, it's more step by step.
But it kind of shows what'll happen
when we have a computer player, too.
One of the things that I find,
when I'm playing the computer player, is
that it will jump all around the board,
and I can't figure out strategy
until the last minute, I get stuck.
Generally, when I'm playing another
human player, we're much more in
lock-step, trying to figure out
which way the move is going to work.
It generally comes down to
the last detail whether or
not one person is going to win or
the other.
Should we try one more?
>> Sure, why not?
>> Let me try something
a little different.
Let me try here.
>> Okay, so I'll try up here and
stay away from the corners this time.
>> Well, I'm already starting to think
about if I can partition the board.
So, I am going to start making a wall
and see if Shelly falls for it.
I'll go here.
>> I'll try going here.
>> What Shelly is doing is, she's trying
to think that we're going to make
a wall like that, and that she's
going to to hop over this side,
because this side already has
one spot taken out of it.
Well, I think I'm going to change
the rules of the game on her.
Not really, but what I'm going to do is,
I'm going to try to create a partition
in a different way than she expects.
I'm going to go.
I'm going to go here.
>> Thad is smart and
has blocked off a lot of my moves.
I'm going to go this way.
>> I really don't know which
way this is going to go.
We've both eliminated a lot
of our opponents moves, but
also limited our own moves.
We have a partition growing vertically
here, but also horizontally here.
Well, when you don't know what to do,
and you don't have a winning move,
confuse your enemy.
Actually, what I did there,
is I'm keeping all my options open.
I have not blocked off
any partition yet.
I can always double back and
always get to any side of the board.
I haven't made that partition yet.
My question is, which way are you
going to jump to, and whether or
not you're going to
fill out a partition?
>> Well, I think I also want
to keep my options open,
so I don't get stuck again.
I think I'm actually
going to go up here.
>> I guess if I go here,
no matter what I do,
if I go here or here, I'm basically
I'm sealing my fate into this
space, because she could probably
get over here and stop me.
Now I gotta start counting squares.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Where she has one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven.
We might split these,
I think, I think, no,
as soon as I go here, if I go here,
then I can't get back around.
I actually stick myself into
this port or this port.
If I go here, then I'm actually
stuck in this section, or
this section if I move up into those.
So I'm really in quite
a predicament here.
Let's run away.
Well, I'm going to keep trying and
try to close in on Thad,
so I guess, I think he can still escape,
but, I'll go over here.
>> Ouch,
I was hoping she wouldn't see that.
Well, I'm still in
a relatively good position,
I still have lots of area open to me.
Now it becomes,
who can get where, how quickly.
Let me actually start
closing off partition, and
we'll see who's going to win this one.
>> I want to keep as many squares as I
can, so I'm just going to go one over,
horizontally.
>> I have no idea if Shelley's
strategy's going to work out here.
She's being conservative and
filling in square by square.
And I'm going to try to jump over
into her side, and mess with her.
This might backfire on me, but
then again, it might work.
>> I only have one choice now.
>> So,
I've now played the game far enough,
that I can start seeing the end game.
I can see the future and
it does not look good for me.
Well, in that case, I'll try to
stay alive as long as possible, and
hopefully Shelly wasn't listening
to me and will make a mistake.
>> I'm again going to try to keep
as many squares open as possible.
I think I'll go here for now.
>> In some games, you can actually
have the end game happen within
half the board being filled out.
Here, Shelly and
I are both being conservative and
trying to fill in as many squares
as possible, to avoid dying.
We will see.
I'll continue this and
see how far it's going to go.
>> I think I'm going to go and
try and close off this gap.
Let's see if this works.
>> She's obviously not
going to go back up here,
because that's going to be a lose for
here.
Now we're fighting over
these last five squares.
If I take this square I have a chance to
still live, so I'll take this square.
>> I think if I close off this gap, I'll
have two squares, right here, and then
it looks like Thad only has one move
>> I have one thing left,
and Shelly can take any move she wants,
with the two remaining.
>> Sure, I'll go here.
>> And now I can't move,
and Shelly wins.
>> Yay.
So you can see that these games can
get quite complex, quite quickly and
even somebody whose played a lot
of games, can't see the end game.
What's going to happen is,
as we teach you these algorithms,
they're going to be able to
search way far in the future, and
pick up moves that we
as humans can't see.
With isolation, what's called the
branching factor is small enough that
our computer programs can look at all
the different moves that can possibly
happen in the future, and choose
the ones that will guarantee a win, or
as much as it can guarantee a win,
given the opponent is playing awfully.
With these games,
when the depth is too much,
the computer can't see far enough in
the future, and then has to pick a best
move given it's current understanding
of where the game is going.
And we'll show you how
all these tricks work.
In particular, five-by five
isolation is very interesting,
because it's one of the few
games that's complicated enough,
that humans can't really see
the end game, but computers can.
So, stay tuned.
We're going to teach you how to make
an expert isolation player next.