From the list of apps that we just saw,
I want to focus on one in particular,
Facebook.
And I want to use it as an example
of how apps use the network.
Facebook, for
those of you who have not used it,
is an app that allows people to
share social data over the network.
Users can share thoughts, photos, and
videos of everything from cute
kittens to current news items.
Each of these features,
uses the Network.
More specifically,
each of these features uses
the network to send and receive data.
Data can be text, images, video,
or any media that's sent and
received over the network.
But in order to make use of data, apps
have to be able to send and receive it.
So, how does this happen?
One of the most common ways, is by
HTTP or Hyper Text Transfer Protocol