So in main.py,
we have this SetAnnouncementHandler and
all it's going to do is call
cacheAnnouncement in the ConferenceApi.
And then in conference.py, we have
getAnnouncement, which needs to get
the MEMCHACHE_ANNOUNCEMENTS_KEY
from memcache.
And if it's not there,
this is going to return none so
we need to make that
a null string instead.
So that we can initialize
the string message with the string.
Once you have all this, and
you deploy it on App Engine, you'll be
able to call the getAnnouncement method,
and probably just get back a null
string in the data in the response.
And you'll also be able to access
the URL /crons/set_announcement.
It'll just return an empty page.
But it's actually trying and setting
the announcement in the back end.
If, by the way,
you get back a NeedIndexError,
well we've seen that before.
You just need to deploy the app locally,
so that index.yaml gets updated.
And then deploy it to App Engine.
And then this will go away.