One challenge is,
what happens when multiple CPUs
reference the same data, x in this case?
The data could appear
in multiple caches.
Or in this case when we have
multiple memory modules,
x is actually present in one
of the memory modules, but
both of the CPUs referenced it, and so
it appears in both of their caches.
On some architectures, this is a problem
that has to be dealt with purely in
software, otherwise the caches
will be not coherent.
For instance, if on one CPU we update x
to be 3, the hardware is not going to do
anything about the fact that the value
of x in the cache of another CPU is 4.
This will have to be fixed in software.
These are called
non-cache-coherent architectures.
On other platforms, however,
the hardware will take care of
all of the necessary steps to make
sure that the caches are coherent.
So, when one CPU updates x to be 3,
the hardware will make sure that the
cache on the other CPU is also updated.
These are called
cache-coherent platforms.
The basic methods that are used in
managing the cache coherence are called
write-invalidate and write-update.
Let's see what happens with each of
these methods when we have a situation
where a certain value is
present in all of the caches
on these two different platforms.
In the red invalidate case,
if one CPU changes the value of x,
then the hardware will make sure that
if any other cache has cashed that
particular variable x,
that value will be invalidated.
Future references on this
CPU to that same value x
will result in a cache miss and
will be pushed over to memory.
The memory location clearly
has to be updated based on
one of the methods write-through or
write-back.
In the write-update case, when one CPU
changes the value of x to x prime,
then the hardware makes sure that
if any other cache has cached that
same memory location,
its value gets updated as well,
as the name of this method suggests.
Subsequent accesses to this memorial
occasion from the other CPU will
result in a cache hit and will return
the correctly updated new value.
The trade off is that with
write-invalidate, we actually post lower
bandwidth requirements on the shared
interconnecting the system.
This is because we don't actually
have to send the full value of x,
just its address so that it can
be invalidated in other caches.
Plus once the cache line is invalidated,
future modifications to the same memory
location will not result in
subsequent invalidations,
that location is already invalidated.
So if the data isn't needed on any of
the other CPUs anytime soon, it is
possible to amortize the cost of the
coherence traffic over multiple changes.
So basically,
x will change multiple times over here,
before it's needed on the other CPU.
And it's only going to
be invalidated once.
That's what we mean by
this amortized cost.
For write-update architectures,
the benefit is that the data will be
available immediately on the other
CPUs that need to access it.
We will not have to pay the cost
to perform another memory access
in order to retrieve
the latest value of x.
So then, clearly programs that will need
to access the value of x immediately
after it has been updated on another
CPU will benefit from support for
a write-update.
Note that you as a programmer,
you don't really have a choice
in whether you will use write-update or
write-invalidate.
This is a property of
the hardware architecture, and
whichever policy the hardware uses,
you will be stuck with it.