Well, if you want to know what I think,
and
I'm sure you don't,
I think the answer is yes.
Intuitively, system B is three
times faster than system A but
at only the cost of twice the energy.
So in terms of energy and time you get
more bang for you buck from system B.
Now to really convince you,
let's be a little bit more precise.
First, observe that as given system
b uses six times as much power as a.
So what about DVFS?
The key relationship that DVFS
enables you to control is
what is the one in which power
goes like frequency cubed?
So we can define the power of
systems A and B as follows.
The power of either system A or
B is basically some system dependent
constant, kA or kB,
times frequency cubed.
Now we rescale B to
match the power of A.
Let's call this new system C
notice that it's the same as B,
except for its frequency.
The frequency of C is what
we're adjusting relative to B
in order to match the power of system A.
Now write down the power
relationships that you know.
The first one is that
the power of B over A is 6.
Notice that this determines the
relationship between the frequency of B
and the frequency of A.
The second power relationship
is between C and A.
Which have the same power.
Again, this tells something about the
relationship between their frequencies.
Now let's consider the execution time
on system A relative to system C.
If this ratio is greater than 1 then
system C is faster than system A.
So let's see if it is.
This ratio can be re-written,
namely the time of A divided by the time
of C is equal to the time of A divided
by the time of B, times the time
of B divided by the time of C.
The Bs cancel.
Now systems B and C are the same except
for their differing clock frequencies.
This tells us how the ratio of
their execution times will differ.
That's because time is inversely
proportional to frequency
assuming that we can neglect any
other non local compute cost.
Now, to simplify this ratio, let's do
a little bit more algebra kung fu.
Hi-ya.
Inserting these two fa factors,
which cancel, allow us to substitute the
known for the frequency relationships.
In particular,
their product is just the constant,
1 divided by the cube root of 6.
Neat.
All the unknown constants went away,
which is great because man,
life is complicated enough
when you know the constants.
Am I right?
The last step is just recognizing that
you already know what the ratio of
TA divided by TB is.
So plugging in all the constants, you
should get the cube root of nine halves.
That is ugly.
In regular people numbers,
that's about 1.65.
That's greater than 1, which means
system C is still faster than system A.