Let's look at another example of this.
This time around,
what I want to do is I want to project
an image, but I have a bigger display or
a bigger screen and I actually been
allowed four different projectors.
What I want to do now
is take an image and
use that four different projectors
to project one large image.
A much different aspect ratio
onto this large screen.
So this is the output I want.
So, to achieve this,
what we need to do is start thinking
about what's going to happen.
Of course, what I can do is,
I can convert this large image into four
smaller images and distribute them
to the four different projectors.
Of course, the first projector's
going to project it this way, of course,
going to have a different
aspect ratio here.
Another one is going to
project it beneath,
make sure there's some
sort of an overlap.
Third one projects another image here,
and the fourth one is projecting.
Now what we can do is what we'd actually
talked about in the previous slide
the quiz itself.
If I actually had a camera, you know,
a camera looking at this scene, I can
basically get the information about all
four of the different images and suggest
to each one of the four projectors
how to inverse transform the image,
and then also kind of do
the processing at a central server
that actually does the stitching.
So I can basically do stitching for
four different images
after I've done simple transformations
and applied to generate a full image.
That is actually the idea that
we will see in action next.
So here we are actually going to see
an example of how they've done this with
six roughly aligned projectors.
What each projector does is it basically
it displays this gray code pattern.
We know the gray code pattern,
and actually it projects it, and
using this projection, and getting
the reflections, captured by a camera,
we can now use the inverse transform
to be able to transform each and
every one of the projectors.
Here, of course, we see the process
of it doing this for each and
everyone of the six projectors.
Now of course, by just doing analysis on
this one I can actually learn more about
the shape of all of the images.
And this of course now you see all
six cameras have been aligned.
This is the final projection
of the six different cameras.
Here, basically now allows you to
generate a much larger display
by combining all six of the cameras,
here you still see a little bit
of an artifact, but you basically see
that if the camera intensities and
alignments can be done correctly,
you won't see any.