So, in summary, what we learned today was, we learned how to merge two different
images, but we wanted to actually use the frequency domain in much more detail.
We use the gaussian's and the Laplacian pyramids.
We learned the mathematical formulations, how to compute a Laplacian and
a gaussian.
And then we learned how to basically blend two images using these
pyramid structures.
Next class, we will actually go into deeper of trying to
understand how to do merging of, blending of images, but this
time rather than just fading from pixels, choosing which pixels are the best.
So, for further information,
I encourage you all to look at these papers in a book that I'm referring to.
These will give you more details on how to do it.
You will be doing an assignment on pyramids, and I encourage you to
play around various types of coding to actually write big span and
the reduced function that you've talked, w e've talked about so far.