Now you might ask, why are we doing that transformation?
>> Why are we doing that transformation?
>> Here's why.
It's going to let us do some very cool substitution.
So we're minimizing DV-transpose m.
Let's do a substitution of y equals V-transpose m.
So now we're minimizing just Dy.
Subject to the magnitude of y equals 1.
Right? because V transpose M is y.
Its magnitude has to be 1.
Okay.
So y is a unit vector.
Why?
Why not?
No, never mind.
Because it is.
All right?
But think about D times y.
Dy right there.
Remember, D is a diagonal matrix whose elements are in decreasing order.
So, what is the smallest that Dy can be?
When is it the minimum?
Well, it's going to be a minimum when y puts all of its weight,
remember y is the unit vector, just in that last element, all right?
So the best y for minimizing Dy given that D is a decreasing order
diagonal matrix is just 0,0,0,0,0,1 okay.
That's the y that minimizes Dy.
And, since we defined y to be V transpose m, then m is equal to Vy.
Why?
Well, remember I said that V is orthogonal.
Right. So when V is orthogonal its transpose is its inverse.
So if y is equal to V transpose m,
the inverse of that is just V, so m is equal to Vy.
So now we've solved for m in terms of y, but, V and y, but remember.
Y is just 0,0,0, all the way 0,1.
So that means that this equation just pulls out the last column in V.
All right, because if I take a matrix, all right, and
I multiply it by some vector that's all zeroes down to 1.
That 1 just multiplies the last column.
So I just pull out the last column.