Well so,
let's look at some quiz questions.
The first one is
the Electronic Frontier Foundation
is concerned about online privacy.
And one thing it does,
it ranks websites with privacy scores,
and the scores are really
based on how do they deal with
some of the things we discussed
should go in a privacy policy.
So if we look at,
there is a link that you can go look at,
at the 2015 scores for
major U.S. companies.
And one of them is AT&T,
who gets just one out of five stars.
So that's a really low score.
So this lowest score is
explained by a number of things
that its privacy policy doesn't address.
So I have three options here.
Check all that you think could be the
reasons for AT&T's score being so low.