[Thrun] I want to show you a little animation of hidden Markov models
used for robot localization.
This is obviously a little toy robot over here that lives in the grid world,
and the grid world is composed of discrete cells where the robot may be located.
This robot happens to know where north is at all times.
It's given 4 sensors, a wall sensor to the left, to the right, to the top
and the bottom over here, and it can sense whether in the adjacent cell there's a wall or not.
Initially this robot has no clue where it is. It faces what we call a global localization problem.
It now uses its sensors and its actuators to localize itself.
So in the very first episode the robot senses a wall north and south of it
but none west or east.
And look what this does to the probabilities.
The posterior probability is now increased
in places that are consistent with this measurement,
like all of those places have a wall in north and east, like these guys over here,
and free space in the left and the right,
yet they have been decreased in places that are inconsistent, like this guy over here.
These states over here are interesting. They are shaded gray and lighter gray.
What this means is they still have a significant probability
but yet not as much as over here,
the reason being that this measurement over here would be characteristic
for the state over here if there had been exactly 1 measurement error--
if the bottom sensor had erred and erroneously detected a wall.
Errors are less likely than no errors, and as a result, the cell over here
which is completely consistent ends up to be more likely than the cell over here,
yet you can see the HMM does a nice job in understanding the posterior probability.
Let's assume the robot moves right and senses again
and gets the exact same measurement.
Of course it has no clue that it is exactly over here.
It can see the probability as being decayed.
Interestingly enough, this guy over here has a lower probability,
and the reason is by itself it is very consistent with the most recent measurement,
but it's less consistent with the idea of having moved right and measured before
a wall to the north and the south.
And similarly, these places over here become less consistent.
The only ones that are completely consistent are these 3 states over here
and the 3 states over here.
The robot keeps moving to the right,
and now we get to the point where the sequence of measurement
really makes 2 states equally likely--the ones over here.
They are equally likely with symmetry.
Those are still pretty likely, and those are gradually and likely over here to the left.
As the robot now moves, it moves into a distinguishing state.
It sees a wall in the north but free space in the 3 other directions,
and that renders the state over here relatively unlikely,
and now it has localized itself.