In addition to the multiple
synchronization constructs
that we already saw, there are many
other options available out there.
Some, like serializers,
make it easier to define priorities and
then also hide the need for
explicit signaling and
explicit use of condition
variables from the programmers.
Others, like path expressions, require
that a programmer specify the regular
expression that captures the correct
synchronization behavior.
So as opposed to using locks or
other constructs,
the programmer would specify something
like many reads or a single write.
And the runtime will make sure that the
way the operations are interleaved that
are accessing the shared resource
satisfy that particular regular
expression.
Another useful construct are barriers,
and
these are almost like a reverse from
a semaphore in that if a semaphore
will allow n threads to proceed
before it blocks, a barrier will
block all threads until n threads
arrive at this particular point.
Rendezvous points is also a
synchronization construct that waits for
multiple threads to meet that
particular point in execution.
Also for scalability and efficiency,
there are efforts to achieve concurrency
without explicitly locking and waiting.
These approaches all fall in a category
that we refer to as wait-free
synchronization.
And they're optimistic in the sense
that they bet on the fact that
there won't be any conflicts
due to concurrent writes and
it's safe to allow reads
to proceed concurrently.
An example that falls into this category
is this so-called read-copy update log,
RCU log,
that's part of the Linux kernel.
One thing that all of these methods have
in common is that at the lowest level,
they all require some support from the
underlying hardware to atomically make
updates to a memory location.
This is the only way they can actually
guarantee that the lock is properly
required, and that the state change
is performed in a way that is safe.
And that it doesn't lead
to any race conditions, and
that all threads in the system are in an
agreement of what exactly is the current
state of the synchronization construct.
We will spend the remainder
of this lesson discussing
how synchronization construct can be
built using directly the hardware
support that's available from
the underlying platform.
And we will specifically focus
on spinlocks as the simplest
construct out there.