Here is a diagram of the state space for the vacuum world.
Note that there are 8 states, and we have the actions connecting the states
just as we did in the Romania problem.
Now let's look at a path through this state.
Let's say we start out in this position,
and then we apply the action of moving right.
Then we end up in a position where the state of the world looks the same,
except the robot has moved from position 'A' to position 'B'.
Now if we turn on the sucking action,
then we end up in a state where the robot is in the same position
but that position is no longer dirty.
Let's take this very simple vacuum world
and make a slightly more complicated one.
First, we'll say that the robot has a power switch,
which can be in one of three conditions: on, off, or sleep.
Next, we'll say that the robot has a dirt-sensing camera,
and that camera can either be on or off.
Third, this is the deluxe model of robot
in which the brushes that clean up the dust
can be set at 1 of 5 different heights
to be appropriate for whatever level of carpeting you have.
Finally, rather that just having the 2 positions,
we'll extend that out and have 10 positions.
Now the question is how many states are in this state space?