So you've made your contract.
Nice work.
Now, before you move on,
a word of warning.
So you'll be using a contract
in many parts of the app.
And throughout the rest of the course,
we'll be giving you a code that
refers to these constants as well.
So because the code that will be giving
you has constant in the contract,
we have two choices.
First, you can either change your
contract to reflect the constant names
that we’ve chosen, or make sure that
you update any code that will give you
in this lesson and beyond to match
the constant names that you've chosen.
So to regenerate, now is the time to
either match our constant names or
be willing to resolve a few naming
errors when copying our code later on.
Back to our regularly scheduled program.
So now that we have a contract that
defines the schema of our database,
we can actually implement another
Android class that will help us create
the database in SQLite.
So Android provides a class
that helps us create, open, and
manage database connections.
And that class is called
the SQLiteOpenHelper class.
And here are some of the handy things
that this SQLiteOpenHelper class
can help us do.
First, when an app first
accesses the database.
The SQLiteOpenHelper class will create
the database that we're using, and
it does so by either using the get
readable database method or
a get writable database method.
Next, the next time that we open up the
app on the device, instead of creating
a new database, SQLite will help us get
access to the one that already exist.
Thirdly, this SQLite open
helper class will assist us
in updating the schema of the database
if the version ever changes.
So because our SQLiteOpenHelper class
is in charge of creating the database,
it's what we need to implement next.
And doing so involves these five steps.
So first off,
we need to create a class that extends
from this SQLiteOpenHelper
abstract class.
Secondly, we need to create
constants for the database name and
the database version.
Following, we'll need to
create a constructor, and
then implement the onCreate method,
and this method is used for
when the database is first created, as
well as implement an onUpgrade method.
In this method is used when the database
schema for the database changes.
And this happens say when we're
adding a new column to the database.
So because we're sub classing
the abstract class or
SQLiteOpenHelper class that's why we'll
need to implement these two methods,
our onCreate and onUpgrade methods.
So looking at the feed
reader example and
the link to this code can be found in
the notes below we notice that the feed
reader db helper class extends
from our SQL open helper class.
So our step one.
Step two it contains the constants for
the database name.
And the database version.
So the name or
database name is a string representing
the file name of the database.
Here it's called FeedReader.db and
version is an integer.
And by convention
the integer sets as one.
So for our next two steps,
three and four,
our constructor was created here and
ourCreate method was set up here.
And lastly, is our onUpgrade method.
So notice inside the onUpgrade method,
the version number will
be very important here.
So let's zoom in on the onCreate method.
Notice the parameter it takes
in is an SQLite database object.
So this is an object
representing your database.
So at our stage right now
our database is blank.
But you can execute this execSQL method
in order to create and initialize
the schema using our SQL statements.
So notice here this method
takes on the parameter
SQL_CREATE_ENTRIES, So
this is a constant here.
So from the same page that
this documentation was found
we see that this constant
SQL_CREATE_ENTRIES is a section of code
that's a string containing
the create table SQL statement.
So let me point out two things
about our execSQL method.
So first off, this method must not
be used with any select statements,
and that's because this method
doesn't return any actual data,
it's simply designed for
executing statements that modify the
database configuration and structure.
So to summarize,
this method takes in different SQL
statements such as create table and
it executes them.
So notice that this statement
will heavily use consents
from the contract in order to ensure
consistency and avoid errors.
So an example of that is in our
feed reader database helper class.
Inside onCreate.
This method takes in this constant.
SQL_CREATE_ENTRIES.
In else where this constant or
SQL create entries was defined as
this create table SQL statement.
And this statement itself takes
in quite a few constants.
Our second method onUpgrade
is also implemented here.
And what it does is simply drop
the database table and recreates it.
So notice in onUpgrade,
it executes this SQL statement.
SQL_DELETE_ENTRIES.
And that constant define here.
So this constant is defined
as this SQL statement.
DROP TABLE IF EXISTS and
the name of the table.
And then, it creates a new table.
So this leads me to my second comment.
So the purpose of
the onUpgrade method is that,
it gives you the opportunity
to update the database file
based on changes that you've made
to the structure in your code.
So for newer version of your
application, say, alters a table or
maybe adds a column.
So for example, if we add a column maybe
a height column to our pets table,
we can implement the database version.
And this update information
is passed to the helper and
on upgrade lets you then execute
additional SQL statements to modify
the database file so that our app is
using the most recent information.