When building the onGetRoot method,
it's important that you think about
the security of your content.
By default, any application running on
your phone has that ability to call
this, and
interact with your music library.
You might not want this, and
only want to allow official
Android apps to access your media.
To do this,
we need to verify the origin of the
package accessing your onGetRoot method.
Here, you can see we're calling
a PackageValidator class
that takes this information in the
isCallerAllowed method, and checks it.
If the package is not allowed,
we return null and
this will not allow the media
browser operation to continue.
To get yourself a copy
of the PackageValidator,
you should use one of the Android Auto
samples that I'll introduce later,
to see what the PackageValidator
class looks like.
You should probably just use this code.
Instead of trying to write your own.
Also at the bottom here,
you'll see that we're doing a test
to see if we're being
queried by Android Auto.
This is useful if your app needs to
adapt itself differently for ads,
music libraries, or anything else
when it's running in the car.
For the onLoadChildren
method shown here,
you get to build up
a hierarchy of media ID's.
Each call returns a list of media items,
which we show here, and
an item can be playable or browsable.
So what does this mean?
Let's look at a diagram.
Browsable items imply that there
is another level underneath, and
further calls to
onLoadChildren will be made.
OnLoadchildren is call recursively,
until we reach only playable nodes.
At the top level,
we have a root node and
then we have browsable categories
of genre, artist and album.
Genre is broken-down into classic and
rock.
And then,
classic contains a reference to Song1,
while rock contains
a reference to Song2.
It's totally fine for
the same music item to appear multiple
times, under different categories.
So there's also flexibility here.
If you have a large music hierarchy
that will take some time to build,
like if you have to fetch it from
the network, then you need to do this in
the background and
not block the user interface.
To do this,
you should spawn off an AsyncTask and
then call this detach method shown here.
When the result is ready, the AsyncTask
can then return back the results,
using another method called sendResult.
Using an AsyncTask ensures that
the user interface is responsive, and
is not blocked while your code
is querying your media library.
Since the user will be in a car,
it's important that you present items in
a way that minimizes user interaction.
You should put frequently used
items like playlists, channels, or
popular content right at the top.
You should also avoid showing unbounded
broad categories like all artists,
because these lists will be too hard for
users to navigate through.
So definitely don't do that.
Instead, you should try to create
bounded content that is going to be what
the user wants.
Android Auto has a limit of six
touch interactions to reach
any point in your media hierarchy,
to ensure the user does not spend too
much time distracted while driving.
If you try to exceed this limit,
the UI will prevent it,
and you'll need to present your
media hierarchy differently.