So hopefully you were able to connect the rolling count bolt.
And I'll just show you the solution, and
probably more importantly the process that I took to do it.
So in the first hint after creating your rolling count bolt.java file, and
again, we are taking this code from the Apache Storm,
storm starter rolling count bolt file.
After Copying and Pasting this into our project, the first thing we need to do
is change the package name from storm.starter.bolt to our package.
As an example we can go to our tweet topology, and
see that our package is udacity.storm.
You can Copy and Paste that into our storm.starter.bolt.
I'll leave this as a comment.
Next, we see the import statement used in the original Storm starter,
is storm.starter.tools, and there are three of them in the import statement.
We created our tools folder under Storm, and so
therefore, our import statements are going to be udocity.storm.tools.
I'll just Copy and Paste these, I'll comment out the originals, and
I'll simply change these to udocity.storm, and there we go.
Well now what we need to do is copy it nthlastmodifiedtimetracker
slidingwindowcounter and tuplehelpers into our tools folder, and
we can find those with the path udocity.storm.tools.
Therefore we come to storm/examples/storm-starter/scr/storm/starter and tools.
Remember this is the structure of the storm.starter source code.
And we see we have N, NthLastModifiedTimeTracker, SlidingWindowCounter, and
we see in storm.tools, we have NthLastModifiedTimeTracker here.
And we have SlidingWindowCounter here.
Let's go ahead and Copy those two.
And we create them in the appropriate place in Tools.
Add a File.
NthLastModifiedTimeTracker.java.
And we'll Paste that in.
Let's make sure to change our package name to udacity.storm.tools and
we navigate back, come to our sliding window counter, Copy.
Add a file in tools.
Remember the name is called sliding window counter,
SlidingWindowCounter.java, and paste.
And just to make sure see our m.last modified and
our sliding window counter in our tools folder.
Next we come back to rolling count bull.
And we see that storm.starter.util is our tuple helper.
And we'll just put those in the tools as well.
So we want starter, util, and TupleHelpers.
We can Copy and Paste and complete the same exercise.
We're going to tools.
Add file.
TupleHelpers.java.
And we'll Copy and Paste that.
And again, we remember to change this too.
Udacity.storm tools.
Make sure we do that with our sliding window counter too.
Now taking this approach and we have three files.
Let's run a Maven package and we see that we have an error, and
the error is the slot based counter.
And this means that we have at least one additional file to copy.
Back in storm.starter.tools we find the SlotBasedCounter, and
again we see that here where the symbol class slot based counter is missing.
So, we open SlotBasedCounter.
Complete the process, Copy.
Let's add it, again, to tools.
Add file, SlotBasedCounter.java.
Copy, Paste.
Change the package name, udacity.storm.tools.
And let's Rerun.
And here we need to be careful on another build failure, and
I'm just leaving this in to show you the process that I went through.
And here we see the variable TupleHelpers is missing, and
It turns out that I have the same structure as udacity.storm.utill, but
we don't have a utill folder.
I put TupleHelpers, in tools.
So, this needs to change.
Well, Maven package again, and we have a build success.
Finally, in step seven of the written instruction,
we want to ignore the count-bolt and use the rolling count-bolt.
Remember that we'll have to check the rolling-count-bolt for the correct syntax.
To do this, let's Copy and Paste an existing bolt.
Let's ignore the count-bolt, set the rolling-count-bolt.
Component ID with the new rolling-count-bolt.
Note that the default constructor for RollingCountBolt with no
arguments takes in the DEFAULT_SLIDING_WINDOW_IN_SECONDS and
the DEFAULT_EMIT_FREQUENCY_IN_SECONDS.
The DEFAULT_SLIDING_WINDOW_IN_SECONDS takes in the number of window chunks,
which is 5, times 60.
We don't want to wait this long, so we see that the rolling count bolt
that takes in arguments windowLengthInSeconds and emit frequency in seconds.
Let's use this constructor in our topology.
Here for the rolling count bolt in seconds, and
let's set this as 30 seconds with an emit frequency of ten seconds.
Finally we want to connect this to our report bolt.
And again we can Copy.
Comment out our old report bolt.
Finally, once we connect our report bolt to the rolling count bolt,
let's try to run this in Maven.
Maven package.
And we have a built success.
Let's submit the job, storm jar target.
Udacity.storm.TweetTopology.
And I'll leave it on the terminal,
simply because we see that we have a runtime error.
Basically, the halting process that a worker died at the report bolt.
And this is one of the difficulties of Storm that I found after
working through it.
In that Storm has runtime errors that are usually type based.
So let's explore our rolling count bolt a bit more in
detail to figure out what's happening.
If we go to the report bolt which is the worker that's dying,
we see that the report bolt expects a tuple with a string word
that's labeled word and an integer count of count.
Looking deeper at the rolling count bolt,
we scroll down to the emit function and the declare output fields,
first we see that declare field is declaring an object and a count.
Again the report poll is expecting word and count.
To make it more robust we could either change the report bolt to take in
a string at location zero and an integer at location one,
or we can change the field name to match the report pulled.
I'm going to call object word, in order to match the report poll word and count.
The next problem we have in the report poll is that the count,
looking up to the emit function, is a long.
Therefore, we need to change the long to an integer to match our report bolt.
To do this we can use integer intCount equals count of not null,
and returned count.intValue or null.
And simply this is an if then statement and
instead of returning count, we will return our in count.
So therefore we have word and count.
Word is as expected.
We will get an object that's a string of the words that we're counting, and
an integer of in count.
Finally we just recheck our topology, and
see that the rolling count bolt is connected.
And we'll go back to maven package.
Finally, we have a build success.
And we'll submit storm jar target.
And submit our TweetTopology.
And we see now that the program continues to run we'll open up
our visualization, and
we see that the rolling count bolt is now driving the visualization.
And we know the rolling counts of each word is being displayed.
And finally we know that we can take the rolling comp bolt or other bolts that
are open sourced or spouts word for that matter, and integrate them into our
storm typology to be able to use other's codes and develop more efficiently.
Great job.