Ideally, we want to test more people. That will give us a better indicator of
whether or not the drugs are effective. We also want to give each drug to very
similar groups of people. This is why we randomize. And we also want to test a
large dose of the medication, because we really want to see how that will
affect the subject rather than other factors. Larger samples result in higher
power. Remember the standard error of the mean? When n increases, this standard
error decreases. Lower within-group variability also leads to higher power. We
can be more sure of significant differences when the distributions aren't
overlapping. However, if the variability increases, it's harder to tell if
there's a significant difference. And finally, choosing treatments with strong
effect sizes will increase power. To do this, you could make treatment
conditions last longer, make them occur more often. The treatments could just
have strong effects. Or you could make the treatment conditions last longer,
make them more intense, make them occur more often, etcetera. These are all
ways to detect whether or not there's a significant difference.