To help us understand this phenomenon
we'll take the help of an old friend,
probability theory.
It gives us a formal mechanism to
capture uncertainty in the real world
and lets us make sensible
decisions even when we're
not fully sure about something.
>> Since the assignment of cars and
goats is random, it doesn't really
matter which one we pick first.
The chances that the car is
behind one of these doors
is the same as the chances that it's
behind either of the other two.
>> We represent this by saying that the
probability of the car being behind door
A, which we denote by P(CarA) is equal
to P(CarB) and that is equal to P(CarC).
Also, we know that one of these
doors surely has the car behind it.
And by convention the probability
of something that is certainly true
is set equal to one.
Therefore, we can say that the sum
of these probabilities equals one.
>> From these two statements
we can conclude that
each of these doors has a one third
probability of the car being behind it.
This is known as prior probability,
which is essentially our best guess,
given no further evidence.
Now let's say we now pick
Door A as our first choice.
>> Monty then opens one of the other
two doors, say, B, to reveal a goat.
Which clearly implies that
Door B does not have the car.
Here, OpenB is
an observation we just made.
And the expression P(CarB | OpenB) is
known as the posterior probability,
that is, our belief after
incorporating an observation.
And in this case, it is 0.
Now, one way to think about this is
that we have two doors left undisclosed.
So the probability of the car
being behind either one of them
should be equal to half, right?
>> Wrong, you glossed over the fact
that Monty knowingly opened a door with
a goat behind it.
He would never reveal
the car at this stage.
>> So we are actually interested in
finding out the posterior probability of
the car being behind Door C,
given Monty opened Door B and
the implicit rule that he
would never reveal the car.
>> Correct, we can now express this
posterior probability in terms of
other quantities that we can
compute using Bayes' Theorem.
Here the first term, P(OpenB | CarC)
known as the likelihood must be 1.
Because if the car is behind Door C,
Monty's only option is to open
B since we already picked A.
The second term,
P(CarC) is simply the prior which
we already computed to be 1/3.
And the last term known as marginal
probability is a little tricky
to compute.
There are three possibilities
we have to consider.
The car could behind Door A which
happens 1/3 of the time.
And in this case, Monty could open
either of B or C with equal probability.
Therefore P(OpenB) given
CarA would be half.
Note that Monty cannot open Door A as
we've picked it as our first choice.
Or the car could be behind Door B,
which also happens 1/3 of the time.
But in this case,
Monty will certainly not reveal it.
Therefore P(OpenB | CarB) is zero.
Finally, the car could be behind Door C.
Also one-third of the time, in which
case, Monte is forced to open Door B.
Hence, P(OpenB | CarC) is 1.
>> Let's plug these values back
into our Bayes' Rule formulation.
As we can see, the probability that
is is behind other close door,
has increased to 2/3.
And even empirical evaluation indicates
that a consistent switch strategy
wins 2/3 of the time.
>> It is fascinating how a careful
characterization of a given situation,
combined with a formal method
can help us make decisions
even in the face of uncertainty.