Okay, let's take a look at the code.
I'm looking at the removeMeal
method in the ShowDinner activity.
I didn't make any changes to
the way we start the activity.
So here's the code to send
the hit to tagManager, repeat.
the hit data to tagManager.
You get the tagManager.
We get the DataLayer and
then we push the event.
So we push the openScreen event.
It's okay if you used
a different name for
your event, as long as you set
up the appropriate trigger.
And then we need to set the screen name,
Dislike Dinner.
You may have set something different.
Then I use the key selected-dinner.
Then I used the key selected-dinner
to record the dinner.
And again it's ok if you used
a different key name here, so
long as you set up the appropriate data
collection variable and tag manager.
You absolutely want to make
sure you've commented out
the analytics code, because you do not
want to send this twice to analytics.
Otherwise, you'll get over-reporting.
Oh, and of course,
one more thing you'll need is,
make sure you have the right imports for
the Data Layer and Tag Manager classes.
Now let's take a look at what
we needed to do in Tag Manager.
I created a new data layer,
current special,
to hold the current special and again,
this is a value that we set in the code.
This is the value of the key,
that we set in the code.
And I created one new trigger,
dislike dinner trigger.
I set it to fire when the screen
name equals Dislike Dinner,
which is the screen name
that I set in my code.
So, we had one new variable,
one new trigger, and one new tag.
I called mine
Send Dislike Dinner EVENT hit.
You can call yours what you like.
Its an analytics tag and
in the tag I provided my tracking ID
as a variable, the track type is event.
I called my dinner actions and
I just copied exactly what I had
previously in the code,
when we sent the data to analytics.
I set the action to be Dislike dinner.
For the label,
I chose the selected dinner variable,
which gets set in the code.
And I set it to fire on
the dislike dinner trigger, so
when the screen name
equals Dislike Dinner and
on the openScreen trigger when
the event equals openScreen.
And you may have done yours differently,
it doesn't really matter how you did it
so long as you do see
the hit going to analytics.
So, then I started and stopped.
We'll do that again.
So then I started and stopped my app.
This time go to the What's for
Dinner button.
I prefer vegetarian today.
Oh that sounds disgusting.
Okay, pick a few more things.
Let's see what's for dinner.
I prefer fish, yuck,
it came up with that.
And here we have some hits showing
up in our real time report and
we see the, actually let's go to events.
Now we have the button
click from before.
Now we have our Dislike dinner actions.
Hopefully you got your new
tag manager tag to work.
This exercise gave you practice
at figuring out what variables,
triggers, and tags you needed.