Up until now,
you've seen a lot of strings and
characters, two examples of Swift Types.
Let's talk about some of the other
commonly used Types in Swift,
starting with Swift's primitive Types.
Swift's primitive types
offer few surprises.
Let's say we have a variable
representing whether a light is switched
on or off.
A Bool would be a good type
to represent the switch.
Swift Booleans always have
a value of true or false.
They can't be assigned to zero or
one as in C, or yes or
no, as in Objective-C and
some other languages.
For properties that need to
hold whole number values,
we might want to use the int type,
which holds an integer, for
example, if our light
switch had a dimmer.
Here, I'll create a dimmer
with the type int, and
I'll simulate sliding
the dimmer to seven.
Although now that I think of it, I'd
really like to be able to set my dimmer
to Pi, so I'll use a float instead of
an int to represent decimal places.
If we use a double here, we can get
a more precise for a presentation of Pi.
Here, I've carried it out to 11 digits.
Between float and double you can
decide which type to use based
on the level of precision you need.
But there's a secret I
haven't revealed yet.
See how I've indicated the type for
each of these variables?
I can actually take all
these type indicators out,
and the compiler has no trouble
inferring the correct type.
You can see this by calling
the function typeOf,
which tells you the type
that's being inferred.
And we'll print it out, and here we can
see that the type of light switch on is
a Bool, and we can see that the type
of very precise dimmer is a double.