We've spent quite a bit of time
talking about the activity lifecycle,
the Android component that is tied to
the user interface of your application.
But some tasks just don't fit nicely
into the lifecycle of a single activity.
For example, you might trigger a change
inside of the preferences activity
that require the database
to re-sync with the server.
It doesn't make sense to run
a synchronization task within
the preference activity.
Which will soon be destroyed when
the user return to the MainActivity.
In fact it doesn't make sense to do
network transactions that talk to
a database inside of an activity.
It has nothing to directly do with
the user interface of the application.
That's where services come into play.
Services are one of the four
primary Android components as
described in the Android manifest.
Including activities, content providers,
and broadcast receivers.
All connected using Intents.
Services are meant for
long running background tasks which
don't need a visual component.
Because of this services,
unlike activity,
do not provide a user interface.
An activity can start a service,
which will then continue to run even
after the activity is shut down.
Therefore, services are great for things
like processing loading and processing
of data in the background even when
non of these activities are open.
For example, the fact you will get
email, text messages and calendar
reminders even when all these apps are
closed is because there are background
services running on your phone
listening for and downloading data.
When you send an email message and
navigate away from Gmail a service is
what makes sure that that
message gets sent out,
even though your activity is closed.
All right.
Now that we know the basics of services,
let's compare them to a framework
component we're already familiar with,
loaders.