And there's one more thing.
We know that anyone with
the right mindset and
commitment can learn to build apps for
Android.
But the work's going to be challenging.
To succeed, you need to commit to
working hard and learning like crazy.
So we're really excited to announce
that the first 50 students who complete
the Android Basics Nanodegree
will receive a full scholarship
from Google to
the Android Developer Nanodegree.
Which means the whole path to an
in-demand career as an Android developer
is now wide open for you.
So to monitor and assess your progress,
we've created a nifty Android
basics leaderboard where
you can track how you're doing as well
as see what your peers are up to.
To get to it, click this trophy
in your classroom sidebar.
Best of luck and happy learning.
[MUSIC]