Model checking actually
is correctness proof.
If it is correct,
that means there is no problem.
Actually, it cannot show
absence of a problem.
It's true for testing but
it is not true for formal verification.
If you're able to verify, you are able
to show that there is no problem.
It can show the absence of a problem.
If we can verify means
there is no problem,
and that means this is demonstrating or
showing the absence of a problem.
So the first option is not correct.
It would have been correct
if there was testing, but
we're talking about verification.
See the problem really
is the second option,
which is that because of the exponential
nature of the work that you have to do,
it doesn't scale to practical
large size systems.