Let's talk about a different
evaluation function.
Let's use #my_moves- #opponents_moves.
I really like the variance of this
function for simple isolation games.
The point of isolation Is to
eliminate the opponent's moves.
#my_moves- #opponents_moves causes
our computer player to seek moves
with the most options, while trying to
get in the way of the opponent's moves.
We can even weight the components to
the formula to try to encourage more
aggressive or less aggressive game play.
For example, #my_ moves- 2 *
#opponent_moves will cause our
computer player to chase
after the opponent.
>> That makes the examples you gave for
the horizon effect
much more interesting.
>> How so?
>> Well, the winning move now has
the highest evaluation function result.
Here's the winning move, and
the evaluation function now returns a 1.
For the move immediately to the right,
results in a -2.
The move to the far right returns a -1.
And the far diagonal move returns a 0.
>> Maybe that is the answer.
Maybe keeping your options close, but
your enemies closer,
is the right strategy in isolation.
>> I'm not so sure.
I think the only way to really
know is to try lots of variants of
evaluation functions and
see which ones are the best.
>> You're right.
But in addition to minimax and
iterative deepening,
there is one more trick we have to teach
that can really affect the efficiency of
game tree search before we spend
time tuning the evaluation function.