Likelihood weighting is a great technique,
but it doesn't solve all our problems.
Suppose we wanted to compute the probability of C given +s and +r.
In other words, we're constraining Sprinkler and Rain to always be positive.
Since we use the evidence when we generate a node that has that evidence as parents,
the Wet Grass node will always get good values based on that evidence.
But the Cloudy node won't, and so it will be generating values at random
without looking at these values, and most of the time, or some of the time,
it will be generating values that don't go well with the evidence.
Now, we won't have to reject them like we do in rejection sampling,
but they'll have a low probability associated with them.