So we're going to pick
the first option here.
It's positive because
A is able to log in.
So login process is successful or
the outcome of the login
process is positive.
Okay, that's why we're
going to pick positive.
Why is it false?
It's false because it's an incorrect
outcome because E was able
to log in as Alice,
stolen or guest password,
whatever it is, we actually have sort
of a security problem here isn't it.
Alice's account is being compromised.
We allowed authentication,
that's the positive.
And it's an undesirable
thing that we just did, so
that reference to the outcome not
being desirable, which makes it false.
So this is a false positive.
It will authenticate even if
it's authenticating as Alice,
which is undesirable and
the positive is actually false here.
It's not a true negative.
Negative would have meant that the
authentication process doesn't succeed.
Request is denied,
which is not the case.