I feel like this is the best I can do.
Our output Y should equal
the square root of X.
But it looks a whole lot
like our signature so-
>> Well, not only does it look like
the signature, but
it's circular definition, right?
>> Right.
>> Okay, we haven't gotten any place.
So what is the relationship, the numeric
relationship between X and Y?
State it in words.
>> X times itself equals Y.
>> Y times itself equals X?
>> Oh, yes, sorry.
Backwards.
[LAUGH]
>> So why don't you write that down?
>> Okay.
>> So, Y*Y=X.
That, in fact, is something that must
be true after square root executes.
And so it's a post-condition.
And in fact it is the only thing
we need to worry about, okay?
So it completely specifies
any routine which we would
believe to be a suitable
square root routine.
As long as the output that you get when
multiplied by itself gets the input,
you say it's the square root.