Now, before we get into the math of reinforcement learning,
let's review MDPs--
which are, of course, Markov Decision Processes.
An MDP consists of a set of states--
S is an element of the state, S;
a set of actions--
A is an element of the actions that are available in each of the states, S.
And we're going to distinguish a Start state,
which we'll call S-zero,
and then we need a transition function that says:
How does the world evolve as we take actions in the world?
And we can denote that by
the probability that we get a Result state, S prime--
given that we start in state, S,
and apply action, A.
That's a probability distribution
because the world is stochastic.
The same result doesn't happen every time,
when we do the same action,
so we have this probability distribution.
In some notations, you'll see:
T of S, A, S--for the transition function.
And then, in addition to the transition,
we need a reward function--
which we'll denote R.
Sometimes that's over the whole triplet--
the reward that you get from starting in one state,
taking an action, and arriving at another state;
sometimes we only need to talk about the result state.
So in the 4 by 3 Grid World, for example,
we don't care how you got to this state--
it's just, when you get to one of the states
in the upper right, you get a plus 1 or minus 1 reward.
And similarly, in a game like backgammon--
when you win or lose,
you get a positive or negative reward.
It doesn't matter what move you took to win or lose.
And so that's all there is to MDPs.