Now that we have Unity installed and
opened, we first have
to create a project.
Let's name it Hello World.
Next, choose location.
I'm going to be using
the default Desktop.
Also, make sure you're
project is set to 3D.
With that set, go ahead and
click Create project.
After a few seconds,
the editor will open up.
Now you might be thinking,
what in the world am I looking at?
So let's break that down.
Smack in the middle here,
we have the Scene view.
Which is where you'll be able to
view the world you're creating.
By default,
Unity creates a really simple scene that
allows us to see the sky and the ground.
While holding down the right mouse
button, you can press W to move forward.
A to move left.
D to move right.
And S to move backwards in your scene.
To the left of the scene view,
we have the hierarchy.
This is a place where we can see a list
of all of the game objects we've added
to our scene.
A game object is Unity's way of
representing anything that can
affect our scene.
This could be a light, a cube,
or a complex character.
Currently, we have a main camera and
a directional light.
Each game object can
have many components and
we can see those in the Inspector,
which is the window on the right.
To view components in the Inspector,
we need to click on a game object.
Lets click on the Main Camera.
We now see a list of all of the
components, specifically, the Transform,
the Camera, GUI Layer,
Flair Layer, and Audio Listener.
Each component has a list
of properties that we
can use to customize the way
a component behaves.
Let's examine this by taking
a look at the Transform component.
The Transform component has
three properties, Position,
Rotation, and Scale.
Every game object has a transform.
And for each game object, there's also a
tool in the top left where we can change
these properties visually.
For example,
we can select the Rotation tool and
drag the camera in the Scene view.
This changes where the camera is facing.
You can pause the video here and
play around with this tools.
When playing around with
the rotation of our camera,
we can actually see our changes in the
Camera Preview, and also the Game view.
The Game view is located in a tab
next to the Scene view, and
is the view that users will be able to
see when you finally publish your app.
So, it's pretty important to keep an eye
out on what they'll actually see.
In fact, because it's so
important to see the Game view, I prefer
to actually view it all times, which is
why I drag it next to the Scene view.
The Unity interface
is very customizable.
So feel free to pause the video
here to drag anything
around to match the work
style you desire.
Unity even provides a few templates
of common interfaces to use,
if you go to the Layout drop-down and
choose one.
For the purposes of clarity,
we'll be sticking with the Default
layout in this nanodegree.
But practically,
anyone in the industry can use
the interface to suit their needs.
The last window I want to discuss
is the Projects at the bottom.
This is a place where we can access any
file we save or import into our project.
This includes code we write, 3D models
we build, or just full out scenes.
Let's actually go ahead and save our
scene now by going to File &gt; Save Scene.
Just like a Word doc we can save our
scene anywhere in our file system.
For now, I'm going to save it as
OurFirstScene in the Assets folder.
And now we can see our scene
file in the Assets folder.
And that pretty much covers
all the windows we see,
right when we start up Unity.
It's time to start practicing
navigating around.
But overall, not too bad right?