So far, in our discussion of algorithms,
we've restricted our
attention to problems that we
can solve in polynomial time.
These aren't the only
interesting problems, however.
As we saw in our discussion
of NP-completeness.
There are many practical and
important problems for
which we don't think there
are polynomial algorithms.
In some situations, the exponential
algorithms we have are good enough.
But we can't obtain any guarantees
of polynomial efficiency for
these problems unless P is equal to NP.
Besides resorting to
exponential algorithms,
we also have the option
of approximation.
For instance,
we might not be able to find the minimum
vertex cover in polynomial time, but
we can find one that is at most
twice as big as it needs to be.
And many other NP-complete problems
admit efficient approximations as well.
This idea of approximation,
will be the subject of this lesson.