Given this idea that any signal, certainly any periodic signal,
can be made up of a sum of sinusoids, we're going to start to move to,
from just this notion of a series, to notion of a continuous signal.
And we're going to talk about a, something that will allow us to know how
much power of any given frequency there is in an image.
That is, we want to transform our image from, just something that's or, or
our signal that's something a function of time, or
just of space, to know what it is in terms of its frequency.
And that transform is called what?
It's called the Fourier transform.
And now we're going to, so
we did Fourier series, then we go to Fourier transform, and then we'll go to
discrete Fourier transform, which will get us to that image stuff, alright?
So we want to understand the frequency, and
frequency is usually written as omega, of our signal.
So, we want to parametrize, we want to transform our signal,
instead of by x, which is in space, by omega.
And we do that by what's known as the Fourier Transform.
And the Fourier Transform is going to take some spacial signal out and
it's going to give us some properties that encode both
the phase and the magnitude for each given omega.
Okay, so we need the phase and the magnitude for each given omega.
Specifically for every omega from zero to infinity,
and actually its from minus infinity to infinity.
The idea is that f of omega holds the amplitude and
the phase alright of the corresponding sinusoid.
So this f has to have the amplitude and phase.
How can f single thing, hold both amplitude and phase?
Notice I didn't say a single number.
Cause remember, f of x is just the value of F, right, so it's a number.
F of omega is going to be amplitude and phase, how do we that?
Well, f is actually, the capital F, is actually a complex number.
Now hopefully, you remember something about your complex numbers.
If not, I'm going to [LAUGH] give you a really, really brief review, okay?
So basically, F of omega is made up of two parts.
A real part and then what's referred to as an imaginary part, okay?
So remember, A plus BI.
Okay well in this case its the real part of omega plus the imaginary part.
And you may remember that the magnitude of a complex number
is just the square root of the sum of the two elements.
Normally the square root of A squared plus B squared so
here its the square root of the R squared plus the I squared.
And re R is for real and I is for imaginary and
the phase the relationship between these is going to be written this way okay.
Its the arch tangent of the imaginary plus the real.
And the thing that's missing here is the idea that the real part is going to
be due to the even function and the odd part is going to be and
the, and the imaginary part is due to the odd.
And all that means if I have a function here this is
my cosign function, alright.
And that's even with respect to the origin that is
symmetric about respect to the origin.
The sinusoid and I'm going to screw this up right because it has to come here.
And then be there, and then, so it has to be zero, there we are,
that's my sinusoid.
because it, it has to come down to zero when that thing is high, all right.
It is odd, that is sine of, of negative x is minus sine of x,
whereas cosine of negative x is equal to the cosine of x.
So the bottom line is, is that this part is,
the real part is going to be the cosine part.
And the odd, and the imaginary part will be the sine part.