There are a lot of essential topics
that you'll need to cover to become
an iOS developer.
Building interfaces with the ui kit,
accessing the world
content with networking.
But right now it's time for
us to figure out what happens
when the app is turned off?
When the phone is turned off, or
even when just the app is turned off,
there's app state that
should be persistent.
You need to get some of the state out
of the RAM and onto the hard drive.
We're going to want Apple's four
main persistence techniques,
listed here in increasing complexity.
There's a good chance that you haven't
heard some of these, or all of these.
That's okay.
We'll cover the material in
five lessons.
This is lesson one,
and you can see that we cover the two
straightforward techniques right away.
By the end of the five lessons you'll be
able to start the virtual tourist app,
the fourth portfolio project
in the iOS nano degree,
to let you collect travel
pictures without leaving home.
The app stores travel locations on
a map and lets you download and
store Flicker images for locations.
If we select a location we can download
images from Flicker associated with
the latitude and longitude.
We can remove pictures that we don't
want and then save the collection.
Now, if the app is turned off,
the location and images are saved.
There are a number of different
ways that apps can be turned off.
The easiest way is to double
click on the home button.
This displays the app switcher,
we can turn apps off by sliding them up.
The virtual tourist app will use
core data for its persistence.
But in this first lesson let's start
with some simpler technologies.
I want to help you master these two
simple persistence technologies that all
iOS developers need to have in
their tool kit: user defaults, and
saving files in the documents directory.
To give us something
concrete to work on,
we'll revisit the app from Kunal's
course, the pitch perfect app.
One more note on this course: the format
will be different than courses
one, two, and three.
The content is mostly going to be
presented to you in written form.
We think that at this stage,
this is the most efficient way to guide
you through the material, but it's all
the more reason to keep in contact with
your fellow students as you try it out.
All right, let's start out
by seeing what it means for
an app to be turned off.