In this course, we tackled six different
projects. We started by curing dataset
and developing a predictive theory
so that the neural networks would be
able to identify correlation between the
input and output data. We've been
validated this theory us  ing some simple
count based heuristics and found we were
able to identify words with both
positive and negative correlation to
output data. However, when we train our
first network on this data, it was only
barely able to find correlation,
struggling to cut through the noise. So
what we did next we increase the amount
of signal and decrease the amount of
noise and found that each time we did
this, our network was able to converge
much much faster. Whereas our first
network struggle to convert all, barely
reaching accuracy of sixty percent, and
only running it around a rate of a
hundred reviews per second.
Our final network was able to classify a
tell accuracy level eighty-six percent,
and went to knit properly was able to
classify 7,000 views per second. Helping
you find a piece these tools and
techniques for framing a problem are
incredibly general. Whenever you
encounter a new dataset, you're going to
need to come up with a new predictive
theory, and then tune and tweet your
model in your data set to make the
correlation your data most obvious to
the neural network, so they can protect
both quickly and accurately. Hope you've
enjoyed this tutorial, and
hope you can continute to enjoy your Udacity
course. Now let's go back to the classroom.