So now, let's think about the geometry of stereo and get to the mathematics.
The basic idea is this.
If I have two cameras and
remember, cameras are defined by their optical centers.
All right?
And they're both looking at some scene point,
if I can figure out which two points in the two cameras are the same point.
And furthermore, if I can tell which way, if I know something about which way
the cameras are pointed, then I can figure out the depth of that point.
That's it.
So for estimating the depth between the stereo, remember the shape
between the two views, there are two things we have to consider.
First is information on camera pose and sometimes referred to as calibration.
How are the cameras oriented in space with respect to each other.
And the second is on image point correspondences,
that is which point corresponds to which.
So here you see the red dot in the two images, left and
right are both corresponding to that front corner.
What we're going to do is we're going to swap that order.
We're going to talk about doing the image correspondence first,
because that's the what you're going to do for your problem set and
it's all, it's the fundamentals between stereo matching.
And then we save calibration for later, because calibration is also used for
whole bunch of other types of geometric processing that we're going to do
with the cameras.