So now that we have the Fundamental matrix, well, so what?
Well as we said, it relates between the pixel coordinates in the two views.
And it's much more general then the in, then the essential matrix,
because we've removed the need to know the intrinsic parameters.
If you told me the intrinsics, okay,
then I could figure out the rays that correspond.
And if I know the rays that correspond in,
in the, the 3D camera coordinates, I can compute the essential matrix.
I could figure out the real rotation of translation.
But if I have two arbitrary cameras that aren't even necessarily the same,
the fundamental matrix allows me to relate them without worrying about
the intrinsics or the extrinsics.
So the bottom line is if we estimate the fundamental matrix from
the correspondences, then we can reconstruct our epipolar geometry without
having to worry at all about the intrinsics or extrinsics of the camera.
And that's what's done here.
Here you see two pictures.
I think this is also courtesy of stealing from Andrew's instrument.
And you have some pixels on the left and
some pixels on the right and then they were put into correspondence.
The idea is I gave you corresponding points, and now the lines that
are drawn on here, those are the corresponding epipolar lines.
So, in fact if you take a look real quick.
So you'll notice that, you know, here's a point right on the bottom edge of
that window, and this line lands right on the bottom edge of that window.
So these are corresponding epipolar lines.
Any point that's along this line, is also going to be along that line.
Let's see, does that really work.
Let's see, it goes across this chimney thing, yep there it is right there.
Okay, so that's finding the epipolar lines by
giving the correspondences through solving for the fundamental matrix.