More generally, a distributed file
system is a file system that can be
organized in any of the following ways.
The first model is when the client or
the clients and
the file server are on
different machines.
The second model is when the file
server is not just single machine but
instead, it's distributed
on multiple machines.
This may mean that all the files
are replicated, and available,
on every single machine.
This helps in the event that there
are failures, because there's always
a replica of the file that's available
on one of the other servers.
And this also helps with availability
since all the requests that are coming
in can be split across
these different servers.
Another way that the file server can
be distributed among multiple machines
is by splitting the files,
dividing them, or partitioning them.
So that different physical
machines store different files.
This makes the system more scalable than
the replicated model because if you need
to store more files,
you simply add additional machines.
In the replicated model, we still need
every single server to store all files
so if we need to scale the file system
to be able to store more files,
we'll have to buy machines
with larger discs.
At some point, unfortunately,
will likely reach a limit, whereas
with the partitioned model, we can
just keep adding additional machines.
Or we may use some combination of
both approaches, replication and
partitioning.
For instance,
we can partition all the files and then
each of the partitions can independently
be replicated across multiple machines.
A lot of the big data file systems that
are used by companies like Google and
Facebook use this kind of approach.
Finally, the files may be stored on and
served from all of
the machines in the system.
This solution blurs the distinction
between client machines and
server machines.
Because all the nodes in the system
are peers in the sense that they're
all responsible for
maintaining the shared files and
also providing the file systems service.
Each peer in the system
will take some portion of
the load by servicing some requests,
likely those that are for
files that are locally
stored on the peer machine.
In this lesson, we will primarily focus
on discussion of the first model,
clients and separate server machines.
And, we will focus on issues
related to caching and
consistency management
in such environments.
Note that, in the next lesson,
we will discuss, more generally,
issues related to distributed
state management,
when there are multiple peer nodes
in a distributed environment,
that are involved jointly in the
management of some distributed state.
Then we will talk about memory
ascending sample but there will
be a lot of similarities between
the mechanisms that will describe for
distributed memory management and
the ones that one could apply for
distributed file management
in this kind of model.