So this is Sensitive Data Quiz.
Again, select the best answer.
Assume that label L1 of a document D1
dominates label L2 of document D2.
There are two documents, D1 and D2.
The label are L1 and L2, and
these labels are defined
the way we've been discussing.
So these are, let's say,
DOD kind of documents.
So sensitivity level could
be top secret or secret and
compartment is what kind of information
is contained in this document.
The question here is
that L1 dominates L2.
It dominates L2, so
we know L1 is greater than L2.
This is sort of what is
the interpretation on that domination.
I guess that three options sort of
present three different interpretations
and you have to say based on what we
understand about label domination
which one is the correct interpretation.