So, in summary, I introduced the whole
concept of video stabilization,
with the caveat that of course,
I introduced our own algorithm,
a very specific, but very simple
algorithm, to do video stabilization.
I demoed a working system.
This is a widely used system, used by
millions, you should have access to it.
I encourage you to
upload videos to it and
try it out, and tell me what you think.
Discussed the whole concept of
degrees of freedom that are used to do
the motion modeling of a camera that
can be used to create smooth paths.
Discussed how can we actually
take the rolling shutter and
remove the rolling shutter artifacts
from the video to actually improve our
video stabilization for
casual hand-held cameras.
And again, I showed a system that
you can play around with yourself.
I encourage you to look at the papers,
the two papers of ours up there.
I've also listed two other papers
that actually talk more about
rolling shutter.
I'm going to put pointers to
other additional papers on
video stabilization
with this lecture also.
Again more information is available
from there and from my website.