So right now,
the saveProfile method only returns
a profile without really saving it.
And the getProfile from user function
will change all of the fields back to
the defaults every time.
That means that if we use it from the
front-end every time we'd have to fill
in the correct values to
replace the defaults.
Instead, we probably want to get the
existing entity from the datastore and
maybe just update one field not all.
So the getProfileFromUser function
should actually get a saved profile from
the datastore,
instead of always creating a new
one from the default values.
Let's see how to do that.
Getting an entity from the datastore,
if you know the entity's
key is extremely easy.
You just perform get
on the key like this.
So now,
it's your turn to do this in your app.
Since you're already creating the
profile key, all you need to do is get
the entity from the datastore
instead of defining that it's not.
And then in doProfile,
if you get a save_request,
we also want to put the modified
profile back to the datastore.
And of course, don't forget to deploy
your app to local host and test.
So, as you complete each one
of these check them off and
then fill in this missing code to
fetch a profile from the datastore.