This reminds me a lot about what it
was like to work on the contacts app.
I remember looking at the code base for
the very first time and
it was really overwhelming.
There was just so many different files,
and it was just a maze to kind
of sort through to figure out
which files were corresponding
with which screen in the app.
But slowly with the help from
tech lead and other teammates,
like I started to understand
how it all fit together.
Like I started to see
how the contact editor
would read the information from the
fields, create a content values object,
and then insert it into the database.
Or that the list of contacts was just
a query to fetch a list of contacts.
Or that the favorites page
would use a different query.
It was starting to all make
sense to me over time.
And this was happening during the Ice
cream Sandwich release of Android.
Our team was actually charged with
revamping all of the UI in the app and
there was a lot of work to do
in a very short amount of time.
Luckily other team mates on
other apps finished early so
they were able to jump on board and
help us.
And it was a little bit hectic because
there was all these new people joining
and I was trying to explain the code
base to them and delegate tasks to them.
But I don't know how it happened,
[LAUGH] but by some miracle
through working late nights and working
weekends, we were able to ship on time.
And our app actually got featured
in as part of the launch event,
which was really exciting.
So, I think my big take away from
the experience was that communication
was just really important.
In a team environment you have to be
able to talk about code with each other,
you have to clarify expectation if
you were giving someone a task and
you want it to turn out a certain way.
So in this exercise I want to give you
the opportunity to practice talking
about technical concepts with people.
I want you to find a family member or
a friend around you and
describe how the app works so far.
Talk about how you added a SQLite
database to your app, and
then how you were able to query it and
get a cursor pack.
All of these are really tough concepts.
So be patient with the person
you are trying to explain it to,
especially if they don't
have programming experience.
And also be patient with yourself
because sometimes you'll have
ideas of how this concepts
work in your head.
But then you'll just have a very hard
time expressing it in words, and
I totally know how that feels.
So it just take a lot of practice.
I wish you good luck and I please share
your experiences with us in the forums.