So let me show you another example of exactly how this kind of
taking pictures would be done.
And this time around with a handheld camera, which is on a iPhone, iPad or
an Android tablet, whatnot.
Here we going to use a piece of software from Cloudburst Research,
which lets you do this by autostaging.
So here you see the video as the person is rotating the camera.
Panning the camera in this instance, new picture is taken,
they are merged together, and again feature matches and
all that kind of stuff is done in real time.
So using this we can generate panoramas, just took five pictures.
And you know, it's basically doing the alignment and
generating a panorama right there.
Of course, a whole lot of processing was captured and
you know, controlled to generate this.
Another example would be another system again in a handheld system like
this here,
moving the camera, or moving the handheld device you're generating a panorama.
And in this case it's pretty much doing it live also.
And stitching things together and aligning them.
Again, the reason for showing this panorama as an example,
this is an easily accessible example and you have tools already doing it.
Of course now let's look at exactly the steps going on
in basically capturing to matching to warping to generate a panorama.
Here I'm basically going to show you the steps as used by
this specific software, but of course these are general steps that would be
applied across the board for any method.
So, if you notice what we've done in this case is basically put all of
these images.
And as I click on each and every one of the image, basically see
that image highlighted so there are you know, six and seven images here.
The same images I showed you.
And basically now all of them are a little bit warped,
registered, aligned to generate this panorama.