[man] Now let's go back to the 2-location vacuum world
and represent it in first order logic.
So first of all, we can have locations.
We can call the left location A and the right location B
and the vacuum V, and the dirt--say, D1 and D2.
Then, we can have relations.
The relation loc, which is true of any location;
vacuum, which is true of the vacuum;
dirt, which is true of dirt;
and at, which is true of an object and a location.
And so if we wanted to say the vacuum is at location A,
we just say at (V, A).
If we want to say there's no dirt in any location, it's a little bit more complicated.
We can say for all dirt and for all locations,
if D is a dirt, and L is a location,
then D is not at L.
So that says there's no dirt in any location.
Now, note if there were thousands of locations instead of just 2,
this sentence would still hold, and that's really the power of first order logic.
Let's keep going and try some more examples.
If I want to say the vacuum is in a location with dirt without specifying what location it's in,
I can do that.
I can say there exists an L and there exists a D
such that D is a dirt and L is a location
and the vacuum is at the location
and the dirt is at that same location.
and that's the power of first order logic.
Now one final thing.
You might ask what "first order" means.
It means that the relations are on objects, but not on relations,
and that would be called "higher order."
In higher order logic, we could, say, define the notion of a transitive relation
talking about relations itself, and so we could say
for all R, transitive of R is equivalent to for all A, B, and C;
R of (A, B) and R of (B, C) implies R (A, C).
So that would be a valid statement in higher order logic
that would define the notion of a transitive relation,
but this would be invalid in first order logic.