Let's walk through this step by step.
This time the method you want to use is
authentication/token/validate/with_lo-
gin.
This method takes four parameters,
the api_key,
the request_token,
the user name, and a password.
And if we take a look at the example
response, the key that we're looking,
success, and
we want the value to be true.
So let's go back to Xcode and
see how it's done.
First, I'll create our
methodsParameter dictionary.
And we'll add the APIKey, the
RequestToken, and then the Username and
Password that are supplied
by the TextFields.
Next, we'll build the URL and
this time we'll use the PathExtension
authentication/token/validate_with_lo-
gin, and
this will create our NSURLRequest.
From here it's a lot of repeat code.
We'll create our displayError function
again, and then do our series
of guard statements, the first
checking for the error not being nil.
And then for the successful response.
And then for the data not being nil.
Then let's turn the JSON into
a dictionary and look for
that success key.
So to check for our success key we'll
look in parsedResults and we'll look for
the key Success.
And then with the Where clause,
we can check that the value that
we pull out is equal to true.
If we make it this far then let's print
something that says we're logged in and
we're ready to get the session ID.
Also, we need to make sure to
resume our task so that it starts.
So let's run this to see if
we get our print statement.
This time I want to make sure to use
my actual username and password,
otherwise this won't work.
And there we go,
there's our print statement.