Let's step through the sample
now to refresh your memory
on how notifications work.
So let's go to the code for the sample,
which is in Applications, Java,
in this package, Main Activity.
So this variable here is the first
item of interest notification ID.
This is the unique identifier for
the notification.
Each notification we generate
has a unique value, and
if we issue two notifications with the
same ID, we'll override the first one.
The interesting code is down here,
in the sendNotification method.
This here creates an intent that is
fired when the notification is clicked
by the user.
We need to create a PendingIntent, so
that the notification service can
run the intent later on for our app.
We need to set up a builder
NotificationCompact objects.
We will call methods
on this to set it up.
This sets up the icon we show for
the notification.
This tells the notification what pending
intent to use which we created earlier.
This here makes the notification
automatically disappear
when it's clicked on.
This is a different kind of icon used
on the left of the notification.
These three lines configure
the main title, the main text, and
also some smaller subtext,
all which is shown on the notification.
This grabs a reference to
the NotificationManager,
and this takes the builder and
generates a NotificationCompat object
using the build method, and passes
it to the NotificationManager using
the NOTIFICATION_ID value
we created earlier.
As we said before, the NOTIFICATION_ID
value must be unique,
amongst the other notifications
that you might want to create.
Now let's [INAUDIBLE] run the sample.
So let's click the green play button,
which runs the assemble
debug task to compile it.
It then asks us if we want to run it.
So we select the emulator and
we hit okay.
This then starts the installation
process to the emulator, so
the samples now running, so we click
Do It to generate the notification,
which calls send notification
that we looked at earlier.
You can drop the notification
shade down and see the contents.
Exactly as we described
during the code walk-through.
When you click on it, you'll see it
launch a web browser and open up a URL
for the notification documentation which
is what the intend is configured to do.