Now that we have our login sessions
in place, lets go ahead and
make an actual button that the users
can click to log into our app.
Create a new file in your templates
folder and name it login.html.
Add some opening and closing html tags.
And nested inside of them some opening
and closing head and body tags.
Inside of the head tags,
I will add the following scripts.
This will create an anonymous function
that inserts a script into the DOM of
the login.html page.
Now, inside the body,
let's create a div to hold
the actual Google sign in button.
Go ahead and
make the div ID equal to sign in button.
Add a span with the following code
inside the div you just created.
Let me point out some of the important
attributes inside this span tag.
This data-scope parameter specifies
what Google resources we want to
be able to access.
Looking at the Google documentation for
OpenID, we see that this asks for
the user's name, their profile picture,
and their email address.
Which is enough information for
this project.
Also be sure to replace your client
ID with the value that you generated
when you registered your web
application with Google Plus.
The data redirect URI
parameter sets a post message,
enables the one-time use code flow.
In this data-accesstype equal to offline
means that our server can make requests
to the Google API server even
if the user is not logged in.
The value of the data
cookie policy attribute,
determines the scope of URIs
that can access the cookie.
We use the single host origin, if our
website only has a single host name, and
no subdomains.
The data-callback parameter
specifies a callback function.
If a user clicks and
grants our application access to their
profile, this callback method is called,
and given the one time use code,
along with an access token.
And this data-approvalprompt
set equal to force
means that our user has to login each
time we visit the login page, and
doesn't check to see if
they're already logged in.
This is useful for debugging your app,
but you should probably disable it in
production since it
gets kind of annoying.
Change the logout function so that now
it renders the login.html template.
Save your changes and
visit the login.html page.
Now we have a nice Google login for
our users to click.
Once we're logged in, the button
doesn't do anything interesting,
just yet, since we still
have to let our server know
that the user has
successfully authenticated.
We'll get to that in the next exercise.