One of the main results of this
lesson is going to be a lower-bound
on the amount of communication needed
to sort on a machine with slow and
fast memory.
And here is that lower-bound now.
For an input of n items on a machine
with a fast memory of size Z and
a transfer size of L words per transfer,
the lower-bound is n over L,
log base Z over L n over L.
Again, the base of the log is z
over L rather than our usual two.
Now what's a lot of
symbolic mumbo jumbo.
But what does it really mean?
For instance,
how would this function compare to,
I don't know, plain old n log n?
Or maybe even other quantities.
I have an idea, let's have you find out.
Now suppose you're given the following.
The first is an input data set
of total size 1 pibibyte, or
2 to the 50th bytes of information.
A pibibyte is the power of 2
analog of a power of 10 petabyte.
Now, this input consists of records or
items, each of size 256 bytes.
Initially, let's say this input
all resides in slow memory.
Slow memory in this
case is probably disk.
Let's say that the fast memory is DRAM.
Suppose the DRAM can hold 64 gibibyte,
or 2 to the 36th bytes.
Finally, let's say that the minimum
transaction size is 32 kibibytes.
That's also 2 to the 15th bytes.
That's probably a reasonable average for
an efficient disk to memory transfer.
Now suppose I give you
a bunch of algorithms,
each of these algorithms performs
different numbers of transfers.
Algorithm a does n log n transfers.
B does n log n / L transfers,
c does exactly n transfers,
d does n / L log of n / L transfers.
E does n / L log of n / z transfers,
and finally,
f does n / L lob base z /
L of n over L transfers.
Notice that these are log base 2
where a log appears except for
the last case which
is log base z over L.
What I want you to do is evaluate
each of these expressions
given the numerical values.
In each case, I want you to compute
the value in trillions of operations or
Terra-ops abbreviated Tops.
So one Tops is ten to
the twelfth operations.
In this case,
all the operations are transfers.
Let me make this slightly less tedious,
and you are welcome.
So I've given you the answer for
a, which is 185 Tops,
and c, which is 4.40 Tops.
In each case, notice I've written
the answer to three significant figures.