I'll get started just by adding
the onStart and onStop methods.
These are the easy ones.
As you can see, onStart is just doing
the GoogleApiClient.connect, and
onStop is just doing
the GoogleApiClient.disconnect.
Next I'll add the onPause.
As you can see, onPause just
gets a LocalBroadcastManager,
gets an instance on this, And
uses that to unregister the receiver
that we called mBroadcastReceiver.
And once we're done with that we're
just going to just super onPause.
Now let's take a look at onResume.
And here you can see the onResume.
I just used a Local Broadcast Manager,
getInstance on this to
get my local instance.
And then I called registerReceiver,
giving it the same Broadcast receiver.
But setting it up with an IntentFilter
defined by Constants.BROADCAST_ACTION.
This is the same name as we had used in
this service when we first created it
with a localIntent called
Constants.BROADCAST_ACTION.
That way, we keep the Intent
consistent across pausing and resuming.