So let me take this opportunity to first introduce myself.
My name is Irfan Essa.
One of the first things anybody who has ever taken a class with me gets to
know is how to pronounce my name.
Again, it's Irfan Essa.
I've been a professor here in the School of Interactive Computing at
Georgia Tech for about 18 years now.
Prior to that I actually did a master's and PhD at the MIT in the media lab
there, and actually stayed on there for a few years as a research scientist.
And my whole 20 odd or
more than years of work has been in the areas of images and videos, where I've
actually been doing work on analysis and enhancement of images and videos.
And including disciplines like computer vision,
computer graphics, machine learning, and robotics.
And of course, now computational photography is also a discipline of its own,
and I've been teaching courses on it for many years.