Now I've told you what
a successful plan looks like, but
I haven't told you how to find one.
The process of finding it can be done
through a search just as we did in
problem solving.
So remember in problem solving
we start off in a state, and
it's a single state,
not a believe state.
And then we start searching a tree.
And we have a big triangle of possible
states that we search through.
And then we find one pair that gets
us all the way to a goal state.
And we pick from this
big tree a single path.
So with the least states and with
branching plan structures we do the same
sort of process only the tree is
just a little bit more complicated.
So here we show one of these trees,
and it has different possibilities.
So for example we start off here and
we have one possibility that the first
action will be going right or
another possibility that the first
action will be performing a suck.
But then it also has branches
that are part of a plan itself.
So this branch here is actually
part of a plan as we saw before,
it's not a branch in the search space,
its a branch in the plan.
So what we do is we search through this
tree, we try right as a first action,
we try suck as a first action, we keep
out expanding nodes, until we find
a portion of the tree, like this path
is a portion of this search tree.
We find that portion,
which is a successful plan according
to the criteria of reaching a goal