Time for a little quiz.
So when objects are really very, very far away.
The real X, that is how far off from,
from the center they could be, might be huge, as the real Z.
Could be miles.
So if I move the camera, the origin, those numbers hardly change, right.
The location of the real x out in the world,
the real layout in the world with respect to this point, and it's miles away.
If I move this a few inches, nothing actually changes very much.
So this explains which of the following?
A, why the moon follows you.
I hope the moon does follow you.
It follows me, but maybe I'm special.
Why the North Star is always North, that's b.
C, why you can tell the time from the sun regardless of where you are.
And d, all of the above.