With print debugging,
we used individual print statements
to examine a program state.
And this required us to know what
state we were interested in prior
to printing it.
And we also noted that print statements
themselves can be hard to maintain.
In practice, there's a better way to
debug that offers us the maximum amount
of state information available
at any given point of execution.
I'm talking about breakpoint debugging
or debugging by using breakpoints.
Breakpoints let developers pause
the execution of a program, so
they're able to see all
the program state available at
a point at which
the breakpoint was reached.
Xcode makes break points
extremely easy to use.
It only takes one simple click.
In fact, you've already probably set
some break points by accident, but
let's do so on purpose now.