Okay, so let's look at the solution.
So to see the number of sessions
where the user got as far as
viewing the product, you go to
the Shopping Behavior Analysis page.
So the Shopping Behavior Analysis
page shows us all the sessions and
here you see the sessions
with product views.
To see the number of sessions where the
user got as far as starting the checkout
process, you go to
the Shopping Behavior Analysis page and
you can also go to
Checkout Behavior Analysis.
So here in the Shopping Behavior
Analysis we can also see the sessions
with checkout.
Additionally, we can actually go,
the Checkout Behavior has it's own page.
Go to Checkout Behavior and
we see the number of sessions.
Let's start at the checkout.
And in this case, completed it.
To see the products that were purchased,
you go to the Product Performance page.
Now, if you go to
the Shopping Behavior Analysis or
the Checkout Behavior Analysis,
we see the number of sessions
that had a transaction.
But you don't actually see
the products that were purchased.
So here in the products performance
page, you see the products and
you can drill down into more
detail on the products.