All right, enough talk.
Are you ready to look at
your very first Java file?
Well you actually have already done
some work to create that file.
Let's go back in time.
Remember the Wizard we used
to create our project?
We chose the Empty Activity template
which automatically created
a new activity for us.
It prompted us to provide a name for
the activity and
we just accepted the default
name of MainActivity.
An activity represents a single
focus thing that the user can do.
Sometimes an activity is one screen and
an app.
Other times, a single activity
can have multiple screens.
Essentially an activity is how
you can display your layout and
interact with the user.
In this case we also accepted
the default name for the layout,
which is activity_main,
which is an XML file.
So this MainActivity is
displaying this layout file.
In the Gmail app, for example,
we have a ConversationListActivity.
This activity displays
a list of conversations.
If you click on this hamburger icon,
it opens up the navigation door, and
you can switch to other views like the
social emails, the promotion emails, or
updates.
Even though these go
to different screens,
they're all part of
the ConversationListActivity.
They all revolve around viewing emails.
Gmail also has another activity
called Compose Activity.
This activity is for
the user to create a new email.
So you can see how each activity
is focused on a certain
thing that the user can do.
Here's another example.
This is the sunshine weather app.
This is actually the project
that you can build up
in the Android fundamentals
Udacity course.
The main activity is the main screen
which shows the list of weather
forecasts for the whole week.
The detail activity shows the details
for the weather forecast for
a single day.
And then the settings activity is where
you can go to change the location or
temperature units.
So you can see how each activity
is focused on a certain thing that
the user can do.
In our coffee ordering app, we're
just going to have the MainActivity.
Speaking of our app,
the main activity for
our app is defined in a file
called MainActivity.java.
Notice that the file extension, or
the suffix here, ends in .java.
That's how the computer will
know that it's a java file.
By the way on your computer
it'll look something like this.
This is simply a new file extension
that you probably haven't seen before.
Other file extensions you may
be familiar with are .xml, for
the activity_main xml file, or
png or jpeg for image files.
You can find this file in your computer
by navigating through the files in your
app in Android studio.
A lot of these files were
automatically generated for us.
So look in the app folder under Java and
then com.example.android.justjava.
Justjava is the name of our app.
There are also other files if you
expand out the gray arrows but
we don't need to worry about them now.
Okay.
And then we can find MainActivity.
Just double click on that to open it.
I'm going to slide this view over so
that I can see MainActivity better.
Now here's all the code the Android
studio automatically generated for
us for the MainActivity.
Seeing Java code for the very first
time can be scary and overwhelming.
So don't worry, it's totally normal
to not understand any of this.
I felt confused when
I first started off.
And I still get confused when I look
at files that I have never seen before.
When you see this you may just see
a bunch of random symbols everywhere.
With blank spaces in weird places.
Some words might be recognizable
in English, while others,
just don't mean anything to you.
Don't worry though, we're going to
understand all of this code soon.
What we will do now is modify the code
that Android Studio gave us, so
that our app does something when
the order button is clicked.
The new code for
MainActivity is included in the link
below in the instructor notes.
We want you to copy over
all of this code here, and
then in Android studio go ahead and
select all of this and delete it.
Then paste the new
version that we gave you.
In the code that you just copied, notice
that we included some comments as well.
A comment follows the following format.
It starts with these symbols and
it ends with this, and it can go on for
as many lines as you want.
The purpose of a comment is to
describe the code in some way.
And you can describe it
using plain English or
any language that you want to use.
And it doesn't have to
follow the format or
the rules of the programming language.
So we have a comment up here to describe
the purpose of the MainActivity.
And we have comments on these
methods here to explain what
the individual methods do.
If you want more information
on writing comments in Java,
just Google search that.
It's aimed to help the person who's
reading the code, either you or
other people, better understand the
intent behind why that code was written.
It's also really good habit to
always comment your code so
that when you go back to it,
it's easier to read.
If you want to learn more, feel free
to click on any of these links.
So feel free to read
the comments that we left here.
Now, in order to make the order
button do something in our app,
we also need to make one more change
to the activity_main layout file.
We need to add an extra attribute
to the button XML element.
The attribute name is onClick.
And the value will be submitOrder.
Use this exact name so
that your code matches ours.
Also remember the o, because this method
name is in camel case with no spaces.
Don't worry about what this means for
now.
We'll learn more about
it in the next video.
Also, if you haven't already done it,
make sure that this TextView here has
an ID of quantity_text_view.
These changes will make your
layout work with the new
main activity Java
code that we gave you.
Go ahead and make these changes now.
Modify the activity main layout file,
and then replace the entire
MainActivity.java file with
the one that we give you.
And then also run the app on the device
to make sure that it still works.
After all of this,
if there are no errors,
then can you tell me what happens
when you click on the button?
Write your answer here in this text box.