Now that we have working end points,
let's add a database to our application.
In the downloadable section there's
a new version of our web app,
called end points project three dot pit.
Along with a models dot pie file that
contains our database configuration.
The code has been refactored to use
SQL Alchemy in order to execute
actual crud operations.
On a puppies.db file, instead of
just returning print statements.
Your assignment is to add a serialized
decorator to the database model.
In order to properly creat JSON
objects from the results of
the database queries.
Add the serialized property to your
models.pie file, and run the tester
found in the instructor notes to see
if your serializer works properly.