Here are the answers.
So how did you find this exercise?
Now if you found it difficult
because you misread a question or
had trouble typing the class names
correctly, that's not a big deal.
If you had trouble because you're
not super familiar with the Android
framework or the Java,
I would take some time to brush up on
both of those topics before continuing.
I've put some resources in the
instructor notes to get you started if
you need them, and please trust me.
You'll enjoy making this app more and
learning Firebase if you're not also
trying to learn Java and
the Android framework at the same time.
I'll show you how I got to these
answers, but before we get to that,
let's just take a look at
what the app actually does.
Right now, it's two screens, a meal
screen and a shopping list screen.
Now meals are a feature that you're
going to implement much later in
the course, so we're not
going to focus on them right now.
Shopping lists are what you're going to
be working with in the immediate future.
If you're curious what this sliding
motion here is controlled by, it's done
by a layout manager called Viewpager
which you'll see in the code soon.
In this area here we're
going to actually be
listing out all of the shopping
lists that we make.
I took the liberty of putting
a single list item for
one shopping list here,
that's not filled in with any data yet.
The green floating action button
down here is for adding a new list.
When I press it,
it opens up a DialogFragment, and
here I can enter the name of a new list.
Now, when I hit create, eventually
it'll add the list to Firebase and
show it on this screen.
It doesn't do anything yet, but
that's because you haven't
incorporated Firebase yet.
Not to blame anyone, though, you're new.
And that's pretty much what
I've coded for you so far, so
let's take a look at
the actual code now.
Here, I've got a list of the packages
and classes that are in the app.
In the main shopping list plus plus
package, I've got a UI package and
a Utils package.
The Utils package contains a class for
utility functions and
a class for constants in the app.
Meanwhile the UI package contains code
related to all the screens in the app.
In it you'll find the main activity
which controls the first screen you see.
There's also a base activity class which
all activities in the app extend from.
It's meant to do some setups
that's common between all
the classes in the app.
Then we have these two sub packages
here, activeLists and meals.
And those are for the two major
parts of the screen that we saw.
In activeLists we have
the ShoppingListsFragment,
which controls what we see
on the ShoppingLists screen.
And AddListDiaglogFragment which is
a dialog fragment that appears when you
press this green plus button.
The two classes here are similar to
the classes found in activeLists, but
they're for meals instead.
And before I forget, you also have
a ShoppingListApplication class
which you'll use to set up
global application state.
The first question was, what's
the name of the class that creates and
controls the meals fragment and
the shopping list fragment?
And you can answer either
MainActivity or more specifically,
section page or adapter.
Let's go ahead and
take a look at the MainActivity class.
Okay, I'm going to go ahead and
open up main activity.
So here we are in
the main activity class.
And if you scroll down to here, you'll
see that SectionPagerAdapter is a public
inner class, and it's extending
FragmentStatePagerAdapter.
Scrolling a little farther down,
I can see there's the logic for
switching between the fragments and
getting the titles for the fragments.
Farther up in MainActivity,
here in the initialized screen method,
which is called in
MainActivities on create.
And here I'm actually making
the section pager adapter and
setting everything up so
that's part of the screen.
Okay so the answer for what's making
those fragments is section pager adapter
but I would have also
accepted main activity.
The next question is,
what is the method called when the green
floating action button is clicked?
And we're given a hint that
the XML on click method is used.
To solve this one, the first thing you
should do is try to figure out what
layout XML has this floating
action bar button in it.
Now it seems to me like it's pretty
necessary to this part of the shopping
list screen here, so
I'm going to guess that it's part
of the ShoppingListsFragment.
Let's take a look at that code.
Here I am in the ShoppingListsFragment.
I'm going to scroll down
to the CreateView method,
which is where the layout
typically gets inflated.
And here in the onCreateView method,
I can see that it's inflating a layout
called fragment shopping list.
So I'm going to go over
here to the res directory,
layout and open fragment shopping lists.
Okay and down in this file,
I see that the fab is right here, woo!
And somewhere in here there should
be an OnClick attribute, here it is.
And since the method that's
calling is showAddListDialog.
So that's the answer to
the second question.
When I click the green tab, this is
the method that's immediately called.
So the next question is,
what static method do you call to
create an AddListDialogFragment?
If you remember from a second ago,
when you pressed the green fab,
it called a method called
Show AddListDialog.
So this is probably where
the List Dialog gets created, so
I can see how it's created.
Okay, I'm here in
the main activity class.
And I'm looking at the method
showaddlistdialog and
right here in the first line,
I create a dialog fragment using
the static method new instance.
Using new instance is the best
practice to create fragments
due to how the fragment lifecycle works.
When you destroy your fragment such
as when you rotate the screen of your
phone, it rebuilds
the fragment from scratch.
The issue is it rebuilds it
using a save state bundle.
If you create your fragment
using a constructor and
you pass a lot of parameters in there,
those all get lost if they're
not stored within that bundle.
By default, the fragment is
recreated with the instructor.
Okay, so now I'm in
the AdListDialogFragment class, and
I'm looking at this new instance method.
Now, you can see here,
what's it's actually doing is it's
using the empty constructor to
make a new ListDialogFragment and
then it is sending
a Bundle of Arguments.
Now this Bundle of Arguments
doesn't contain anything yet.
But in the future,
you can add some parameters here,
shove those arguments in this bundle,
and then attach the bundle.
And that'll let you pass
values even between rotations.
Hopefully, you're at least a little bit
familiar with the fragment life cycle in
Bundles because we will be
using those in the future.
Let's take a look at the final question.
And that final question is what method
is called when you press the Create
button in the dialog?
So you press the tab, a dialog pops up
and then you press the Create button and
what method gets called?
The answer to this will be in
the AddListDialogFragment class, so
I'm going to go ahead and open that up.
Okay here I am in AddListDialogFragment.
Okay, and now I'm going to scroll down.
And here's where the dialog builder
is actually building the dialog.
And here's where the Positive
button is set up.
We see that it's made to
save the string create.
So that's actually the Create button,
this positive button.
And when you click it,
this onClick method occurs and
that adds a shopping list using
the addShoppingList method right here.
So you could have said onClick but
addShoppingList is more interesting.
Right now that is not doing much, but
that's because you
are going to code this.
Okay so if that wasn't too tricky,
you're now ready to learn some Firebase.