As we go through the report results,
keep in mind that,
depending on your selections and
all of the configuration settings and
because the starting seeds are
randomized, the actual results may vary.
What you should focus on
as we go through this
are the concepts in
interpreting the results.
Let's open the results
up in a new window, so
they're more easily able to be seen.
The first table shows
the results of the clusters.
The cluster numbers themselves
are just arbitrary identifiers.
The size column tells us how many
objects are in each of the clusters.
If one of the clusters had
a really small number of objects
relative to the total number of objects,
that might indicate that the variables
related to those specific
objects are really unusual or
could be considered
outliers in themselves, and
you might want to look specifically
at why this is the case.
The next column reports
the average distance.
This represents the average distance
of each observation within the cluster
to the centroid of the cluster.
When comparing clusters, the clusters
with the smallest average distance
are the most compact of the clusters,
and the ones with the higher average
are less compact and might show
more variability in the results.
The maximum distance column shows
the distance of the observation that is
farthest from the centroid.
Since this could be just a single
point with all the other points
relatively close to the centroid, this
isn't of much use other than to show
how far out the farthest outlier is.
Separation shows the distance
of the closest point
not in the relevant cluster.
So here, the larger the number,
the more separation there is between
that cluster and all of the other
clusters and the better for the model.
The chart with the individual variables
showing can best be used a way to
characterize each cluster.
To do this, it is best to use
it within variable comparisons.
In other words,
you don't look across horizontally but
compare the cluster results only for
a specific variable.
So that when you look at the numbers
represented within the same variable,
a high positive versus a high
negative would indicate that for
that variable, those two clusters
are opposite of each other.
For example, if you look within
the Snow variable for PC1,
cluster 6, with the largest
positive value, and cluster 7,
with the largest negative value, are
the extreme clusters related to snow,
one with potentially lots of snowfall
and the other with little snowfall.
Now, keep in mind as you interpret
these numbers that the positive and
negatives indications don't necessarily
correlate with most snow and
least snow respectively but
just that they are the most different.
In other words, in this example,
the most snow could actually have
a negative indicator, and the least
snow could have a positive indicator.
We'll be able to determine that when
we start validating the results.
For example, I've seen cluster
solutions where there were only four or
five stores in a cluster.
When looking at these
store characteristics,
they were stores that were
intentionally configured differently
from an operational standpoint.
We actually ended up excluding those
stores from the cluster analysis
entirely, and this then created
a better clustering solution for
the remaining stores.