So the first malware, an email
attachment that when being opened
will send itself to all people
in the user's address book.
As we have discussed a little
bit earlier, this is a virus.
The second malware, a customized
keyboard app that logs user input and
sends it to a server on the Internet.
This is a Trojan Horse, because while
it performs some useful function,
it also performs some
malicious activities.
The third malware, part of a program
that will only run if the computer
is at the user's home and it will upload
Microsoft Word documents to a website.
This is a logic bomb, because
the triggering condition is the place or
geolocation or
IP address of the computer.
Which is at the user's home.
And when the triggering condition is
met, it performs malicious activities.
The fourth malware, login program
with an undocumented option, for
example DEBUG, that would allow
an attacker to supply any username and
password to gain access to the computer.
This is a trap door, because it allows
an attacker to gain access to system
without going through
the proper security check.