Let's look at that in
the context of this image.
Very complicated, beautiful image here.
Mountains at the back.
Bunch of rocks and a small rock here.
This rock is much nearer to us,
much farther and then,
of course,
much farther at the back there.
So, the parallax basically suggested
that the motion of the scene features
at, located at different
distances will appear different.
So, for example, any point or
any object that's
this close here is, any motion, this
is going to move up here to move a lot.
Right?
While,
all of these objects that are just
a little bit would move a lot
less than this.
So, all of them.
But, of course, the farthest point
here is going to appear to move very,
very little.
So, all of the points in the mountain
back here will have very small
displacements because of simple motion.
But the, these more distant rocks
will have smaller displacement and
this one will have
a larger displacement.
You can experiment this yourself by
actually looking at a scene that has
a lot of different types of elements and
just looking at it and moving your head
just a little bit and you will see all
of the objects that are near to you
seem to move a lot more than all
of the objects that are farther.
The same thing is, of course, something
which you see because of perspective.
Farther things are looking smaller and
of course,
they'll also have smaller displacements.
So, in essence, this kind of starts
telling us more about far, mid and
near types of information
from simple images.