Now that we've coded the three
basic operations we'll be using,
let's start on the first part of
the Gaussian Elimination Algorithm.
Taking a system and
putting it into triangular form.
Here, I've added a function called
compute_triangular_form to my module.
It won't take any inputs but it will
return a new system in triangular form
that has the same solution
set as the original system.
Note that I'm using deepcopy
from the copy module, so
that I'm not modifying
the original system directly.
That way it's still left intact
in case I need it later on.
Now go ahead and
code a compute_triangular_form
method of your own.
So you can check your work, I'll
provide some test cases for you to run.
I should note that there
are many valid triangular
forms based on some
choices that you make.
For example, which row to swap for
a row with a zero coefficient.
But the answers that will be used in the
test cases will assume the following.
First, if you swap a row with a zero
coefficient for one below it, swap with
the topmost row below the current
one that has a non-zero coefficient.
So for example,
if we have this system, y + z = 1,
2y- z = 2, x + z = -1,
and 2x + 3y + 2z = 1,
then in order to get a non-zero
coefficient for x in the first equation,
we could swap row one with
either row three or row four.
But according to our assumption, we will
need to swap rows 1 and 3 in this case.
Second, for
this portion of the exercise,
do not use the operation
multiply coefficient and row.
We will use it later in the algorithm
but not for computing triangular form.
And third, only add multiples
of rows to rows underneath.
For example,
you don't want to add a multiple of
row three to row two or row one.
Good luck,
this might be a bit challenging.
If you need a hint,
the first portion of the solution video
will have some suggestions on
how to write the algorithm.
You can access the solution
video by just clicking submit
without checking the box here and
then clicking view answer.