An email client is a perfect choice,
since you interact with your
e-mail often and
you may want to read it offline.
A static blog never changes, so
it's easy to leave on the server side.
A form that goes to the server to
send an email doesn't need anything
special on the client.
You're probably going to use it once.
It's much easier for a searchable
map to be a client side application.
Think about having to wait for
a new map tiles and
the entire page refreshing if
you want to move around, yikes.
Something that receives real time data,
like a stock ticker,
should live on the client.
You don't want to resend
the page with every update.
But change it locally instead.
A blog page with a comment
section could go either way.
Normally the server generates a new page
when you add a comment, though a client
side program could collect all
the comments from a database instead.