So, the first thing to do is define your projection matrix.
Note that it has a size of 3 cross 4.
That is three rows, four columns.
Next, we convert p to homogeneous coordinates and transpose it.
The resulting size should be 4 cross 1.
That is a column vector with four rows.
It is easy to append an element to any vector.
A single quote after a vector transposes it.
Finally, we can apply the projection transformation, and
this ends up being a simple matrix multiplication.
Note that we use star,
not dot star, because we are not doing element-wise multiplication.
Remember to convert back to non-homogeneous coordinates when
returning the value.
u equals x by z, and v equals y by z.
And that's it.
Here's a quick check to see if the function's return values make sense.
Say we keep the focal length at 50 millimeters.
Then we know that any point at 50 millimeters should be
projected at the same x, y coordinates.
Let's try this out.
This should be true regardless of what the coordinates are.
Let's try something else.
Similarly, points that double the focal length should be reduced to
half the size.
See, perspective projection is not too bad.