Congratulations, you've reached
the end of this introduction to
relational databases.
You now know the basic operations of
SQL and elementary database design, and
you've beaten some of the biggest bugs
in the area of database backed websites.
Relational databases are a big field and
there are a lot of next
steps you can take.
If you're into math, you might want
to look into the relational algebra.
If you are more interested in
production systems, there's a lot to be
learned about building bigger and
more reliable databases.
If you are looking to learn more about
database baked web applications in
Python, we have some other awesome
courses that you could check out next.
I put some links to them in
the instructor notes below.
I hope you enjoyed this course,
see you around.