Now that we know how to compute smooth derivatives and
gradients, we can return to the question of how do we actually find the edges.
And fundamentally it's a multi-step process, right?
You're going to create smooth derivatives to suppress sort of little bit
noise and we're going to compute sort of the main gradients, then we're going to
threshold that gradient somehow to find sort of significant areas of change, and
then we're going to take those areas and then we're going to take those areas
and we're going to do what's called, thinning and
there's an example of that shown down here, we'll talk more about that, so
that a fat edge becomes just a single contour, and say that's the edge, and
then finally, we're going to have to somehow connect or
link those pixels if you actually want to have a connected contour.
So the edge operator I want to talk about is done by John Canny,
actually as his masters, thesis, when I was,
still at school there as well, went on to do some really cool stuff in his PhD,
but everybody knows it because it was called the Canny, edge operator.
And the Canny operator works the following way, you first filter the image with
derivative of a Gaussian, you find the magnitude and
orientation, then you do what's called non-maximum suppression,
which is this thinning, and we'll talk about that in a minute.
And then, there's a linking operation, we're going to talk about that in detail,
that was really the cool insight, where you're going to define not just one
threshold, but two, and you're going to use the, the high threshold to start to
edges, but you'll use the lower threshold to continue.
By the way, MATLAB does Canny edges, so you can just take the Canny edges by
calling the edge function, and I encourage you to do doc edge or, or help if,
if your doc thing's not set up, to learn all about the edge detection in MATLAB,
it's actually a great source of image processing information,
the documentation of the image processing tool box in MATLAB.