First, cookies are created
by ads that run on websites.
This is true,
cookies are created by ads, widgets, and
elements on the web page
the user is visiting.
Second, cookies are created by
websites a user is visiting.
This is true, as we have just explained.
Third, cookies are compiled
pieces of code.
This is false, cookies are plain text.
They're not compiled code.
Fourth, cookies can be
used as a form of virus.
This is false,
since cookies are not compiled code,
they cannot be used as a virus.
They cannot replicate themselves.
And they cannot be executed and
are not self-executing.
Fifth, cookies can be used
as a form of spyware.
This is true, cookies store user
preferences and browsing history, and
therefore they can be used as spyware.