Okay, so for our next question,
I find it important that a full stack
engineer is able to reason about
the entire stack of web development.
So maybe we could go into as much
detail as possible about what happens
when you visit Google.com.
>> Okay.
>> Just take it from the top.
>> Cool, so starting, so I guess,
the user goes to their browser.
They click the, I guess,
they type the url.
>> Maybe, can you also just
write down the steps as you-
>> Cool, okay, I'll dive in a stack.
>> Okay, perfect!
>> So we'll say at the top level,
we have, I guess,
I'll have two kind of layers here,
we'll have two stacks,
we'll have over here the user's PC,
or computer ,or smartphone, whatever.
It's all kind of this
is actually similar.
And then over here we'll
have a Google server.
So.
Cool, okay, so at the highest level
we have a user clicks a button.
User clicks.
>> Mm-hm.
>> They typed in the URL,
they're clicking, and
their browser starts doing things.
>> Okay.
>> So the browser needs to go to
Google.com and get some data to serve.
So the first thing the browser needs
to know is, where is the server.
So it takes that string and
it says, Google.com.
And usually you can turn
that into an IP address.
So what their browser does is it goes,
I guess, it's network stack,
and it makes an even DNS request
to get the IP address of this.
So that's probably going to be cached
somewhere, either on their own computer,
even, or their local network,
or they're ISP's network.
So next, I guess, what's called
the DNS step, so now we have IP.
Let's just call it a 8.8.8.8, because
that's one of google's IP addresses.
Great, okay, so
now the browser has that.
>> Quick question here,
what if I want to make my own domain
that's not registered with DNS.
Is it still going to work if I
make a fake, a fake domain .com?
I just want to test it on my computer.
>> Okay, so,
let's see if i understand the question.
So you're saying what if the user
enters a domain that isn't valid?
>> That isn't propagated through DNS,
let's say.
>> So i guess we kind of go
through the same process.
They would make a DNS request and
they would go through the chain.
They would ask it's local DNS server,
do you have an IP address for this,
and they'd be like, no, but I can ask my
next higher up server if it knows that.
And that'll work upwards and
upwards, DNS is complicated.
But there's a big hierarchy of servers
that kind of record the each domain
of each sub domain for each,
the entire public internet.
And it kind of work that entire
hierarchy until it realize that no one
no one has this IP address and
then that'd return to your browser, and
that's where you get a DNS
unresolve error in your browser.
>> Okay, cool
>> Anyway you could
use your Etsy host file.
>> Sure, yes if you have like
a test server for instance, yeah.
So what you could do is, you could make
a mapping between that domain name and
the IP address of your test server,
which would be a local host
in some port, I guess.
So yeah,
that kind of bypassed the DNS look up.
>> Perfect, all right, cool.
>> Yeah, so
once this process has happened we can
actually communicate with the server.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So
what will happen then is a get request,
because that's kind of
the default HTTP action.
Your browser will do if you're not,
if you're just going to a URL, so
it'll get to this IP address.
And what that does is it initiates kind
of the HTTP transaction or session
between your computer, or where you are
on the network, and the Google server.
>> Okay, and what port is it
connecting to the Google server at?
>> Because we didn't specify one,
it's going to be port 80,
because that's the default one for
the world wide web and
that's what a browser uses for
the websites if you don't specify.
>> Okay, does that happen when you go,
when you type in Google.com right now,
it connects to port 80 for you.
>> Correct, yeah, that's what,
on Google server,
that's where they're running
the web servers, on port 80.
>> Okay, what if I type in
HTTPS at the beginning.
>> Okay, that's a good point,
HTTPS runs on a different port,
I don't know it off hand.
>> Okay.
>> The difference there is just
it's on a different protocol,
the server has to recognize that, so
that's why it runs on another port, so.
>> Can you tell me the difference
between HTTP and HTTPS?
>> Yeah, so it's really a wrapper
around the same protocol, but
the idea is that before it begins
transmitting the information of
the contents of the web page.
>> Mm-hm.
>> I guess, it kind of does two things,
it verifies the identity of the server.
>> Okay.
>> And
the way I bought a certificate from
a certifying authority ahead of time.
>> Okay.
>> And I guess also, so
it verifies your identity.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And it also encrypts the traffic
from their server to your PC.
>> Okay.
>> And so that's all negotiated
before the main, I guess,
the main content delivery happens.
>> I see.
>> Yeah.
>> I see, okay cool.
So at some point we figure out whether
we're talking to the HTTPS port and
the centered ATT port,
then we're making a GET request.
>> Yeah.
>> Right, okay, go ahead.
>> Yeah, so I guess, we can get into
a lot of detail here, but what happens
here is the, there's an entire network
stack that we're talking about.
But your computer and the Google server
kind of, they initiate like a handshake,
just so they can establish
a TCP session between the two.
>> Can you tell me
what a TCP session is?
>> Yeah, so what that is, is it's a way
that, I guess, previous developers have
kind of simplified the process
of networking for us.
Because in real life when you have
a network, you have like a bunch of
cables and fiber optics, and
wireless links between things.
>> Sure.
>> And there's a lot of traction in
between us, the application developer,
and the physical electrons moving in,
and,
I guess, this TCP connection
is one of those attractions.
So what it does for us is, it kind of,
on top of all that, the physical layer,
as I just described, it gives us
a simple model of networking to use.
Where every message that's sent from
server to server will reliably arrive,
even if there's some
break in the network.
The net would automatically, TCP will
resend it to make sure it gets there, so
you don't have to care
about error control.
>> I see.
And it does other cool things too,
for instance,
sometimes if you send two packets at
the same time, or the similar time,
crazy things can happen in the routers.
Maybe one gets there before the previous
one, it may happen out of order,
TCP decides all that detail from us.
So that the application it can just work
in a really simple model of the network,
instead of the more complicated.
>> Okay perfect, great, keep going.
>> Yeah, so let's assume that
TCP is already been negotiated,
we have that connection.
So at that point, this string,
this GET query is like a string,
that has the name of the resource
that it's requesting from the server.
I guess,
requesting something like slash.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So, this point,
we're not on the user's PC anymore,
the data's going through the network,
and now, it's a service job to
understand this response so
it can serve the correct content.
>> Hm-hm.
>> So, Google server, it gets this HTTP
message, and says, we have a server,
I mean, client, that's come to us,
it's asked us for this content.
And so at this point, well,
I don't actually know how Google works
internally, but there's probably
complicated things happening.
So even before the server, Google
probably has some sort of load balancing
servers, or some kind of edge gateways,
or something going on.
>> Yeah, definitely.
>> So, I guess,
maybe even on top of the server
there's some edge of Google's network.
And what that will do is, that will,
depending on where you are physically
located, this DNS query will kind of
route you to the nearest Google server.
>> Okay.
>> Or the nearest Google network, or
whatever.
And so once you're in
Google's network at least,
you get to an IP address
in Google's network.
It will determine which content server
is available as the lowest loader, or
is closest to you,
whoever can respond to you the fastest.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So this will route you
to the actual server,
who will like actually
fulfill this request.
So in a way, that finally happens,
a whole bunch of this networking
happens in basically.
Yeah, so now we're finally on an actual
server, has the actual know HTML and
things it's going to return to you.
So now I guess, a running code on
the server on this web server and
so that'll, it's job is to
construct an HTTP response,
which is kind of like you sent it a GET
and it will respond with its response.
So that will have some headers,
it'll say, 200, meanings of success.
This is a good URL you chose to come to.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And then there'll be some
other like header details,
like how big this response is.
And then we get to the meat of
the response which is just like
an HTML page.
>> Okay.
>> So, and I guess depending on how
Google works like it will like see,
if it like recognizes that
you're a user that's logged in.
It might format this differently,
it might tell you your news articles or
your default background picture
if it's Gmail or whatever.
>> Mm-hm.
>> But the server,
it will just construct your response and
then it will use that
pre-established HTTP connection that
it has
>> And
send it just back through
that tired at work stack and
kind of reversing the direction
until you're a happy user.
Did I leave out any of the details?
>> Maybe once the browser gets the HTML,
how does it become the pixels we see?
>> Okay, yeah.
So that's in between the response and
the happy user.
Okay?
So i guess, this issue to your
response is basically a big string.
And so the browser needs to turn that
string like you said, into pixels.
So HTML is very well specified
language and then CSS and all too, so
the browser has are rendering engine
where it takes in that string, And
it is engineered very well to
quickly parse that string.
And constructs the interface elements,
like paragraph tags and images.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And I guess i glossed over a detail.
Like, earlier,
when it responds with this.
HTML page.
It'll also make multiple responses,
probably, like the different images or
assets on the page.
So all those get
returned to the browser.
And it recognizes all these things and
it's like okay,
let's make a coherent
document out of this.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And
that's the job of the rendering engine.
>> Mm-hm.
>> I've never written
a rendering engine, though, so
the specifics are beyond me.
But yeah the browser just
get's the information and
like parses the responses and
makes the images.
>> Okay, alright perfect.
That sounds great.