First, send a huge amount of traffic.
This is true.
This can cause denial of
service of the IDS and
cause it to not be able to analyze
traffic that contains attacks.
Second, embed attack in packets
that cause non-uniform processing
by different operating systems,
for example, bad checksum and
overlapping fragments.
This is true because
the result of this is that
the IDS is seeing different traffic
as the end host, and as a result,
the end host may be attacked by
the traffic, yet the IDS will miss it.
Third, this is true because this
will result in a lot of alerts
that need to be analyzed
by the sysadmins.
And when the sysadmins are overwhelmed,
then the attacker can send his attack
that although the attack is detected and
an alert is produced,
the sysadmin will not have time to
look at the alert until it's too late.
Fourth, send a packet that would trigger
a buffer-overflow in the IDS code.
This is true because the buffer-overflow
is a typical exploit method
used to attack a program.
For example,
the attacker can inject his own code
using buffer-overflow into a program.
In other words, if the attacker
can buffer-overlow an IDS,
that means the attacker
can now control the IDS.