In order to create China's red dot,
we'll need to figure out how to
map data values to pixel values.
As you recently learned,
D3 provides a scale function
which lets you do just that.
As you can see here, there's a couple
functions that are available,
like a linear scale and a log scale.
There's also ordinal in power.
For the y axis of the gap minor chart,
we'll be using a linear scale.
With this scale, we'll be mapping
a domain of 15 to 90 years
to a range that corresponds
to 0 to 250 pixels.
Now we're not using the entire 300
pixels of the entire chart area.
We're going to have a little
bit of a buffer at the top.
Remember that for SVG elements,
the y axis has a value of 0 in
the upper left-hand corner.
And then the y value increases
going down the SVG chart.
Normally we would want our
range to be from 0 to 250,
but because we're talking about the y
axis, we need to reverse the values.
We want the lowest input value to
correspond to the highest output value,
and the highest input value to
correspond to the lowest output value.
So the lowest value of 15
years will correspond to
the highest pixel value of 250.
So all together,
this D3 code tells us to create
a linear scale that has
a domain from 15 to 90,
and maps those values
to a range of 250 to 0.
Running the code,
we can see that it returns a function.
As previously mentioned,
a scale can be thought of as a function
that maps a domain to a range.
And this is exactly what D3
returns to you, a function.
Let's store this function
into a variable called y
which will correspond to
the y axis on our graph.
This is so
that we can make use of the scale
to transform our data
values to pixel values.
Now let's just check to see
if this works as expected.
I want to make sure that my scale will
return a value of 250 pixels
when I input 15 years.
So if I input 15,
I should get an output of 250 pixels.
Great.
And when I input 90,
I should get an output of 0.
Now because life expectancy
is a linear scale, we
know that the value in between those two
should return the halfway pixel point.
So an input of 52.5 years
should return a value that's
exactly in between the max and
min values of our pixels, which
should be 125 pixels, in this case.
D3's API are methods are very general
and adaptable, so I'd like to see if
you can create a scale for
the x axis based on the gapminder plot.
You'll want to save your
scale to a variable named x.
So go ahead and
play around on the console and
see if you can create this x-axis scale.
You'll want to map the input values
GDP per capita from 250 to 100,000
to a range of the output which
is between 0 and 600 pixels.