By now, you should have built
a small neural network using NumPy.
However, deep learning networks can have
hundreds or thousands of hidden layers.
Clearly, NumPy is not up to the task.
Instead we'll be using
TensorFlow to build and
train deep learning models
in the rest of this course.
If you haven't heard of it,
TensorFlow is a neural network
library developed by Google Brain.
But before you get into TensorFlow
we've built a lesson to help you
learn about differentiable graphs.
The fundamental abstraction TensorFlow
uses to run and train networks.
You'll build a small library called
Miniflow that will be your very own
version of TensorFlow.
Along the way, you'll gain an
understanding of differentiable graphs
as well as backpropagation.