Here I am in the code.
I've tried my best to keep
things modular for you.
Here is this AudioVisuals folder,
and inside of it is all the code for
the audio playback and
visualization of the audio.
You're welcome to take a look at this,
but
you won't actually need to modify
any of these classes in this lesson.
Your only interaction with this code
will be the visualizer view class,
which if you scroll down to the bottom,
you will see has a bunch of center
methods that you will be working with.
The classes that you will be directly
modifying will all be outside of this
AudioVisuals folder.
And you've only got one right now,
which is the visualizer activity.
Visualizer activity is the activity
that actually shows our visualization.
During this lesson,
you'll be creating a settings activity
to go along with this
visualization activity.
Here's the code for visualizer activity.
Looking at this code, we can see that
we've got a default setup method,
this calls those setter methods
that we saw in VisualizerView.
If you scroll down further, you'll
also see that there's some code for
permissions.
This permission code you
do not need to modify for
this lesson,
setupPermissions is called an onCreate.
And it's basically just making
sure that the user has the correct
audio permissions before even
trying to play the audio and
launching the visualization code.
If the user's on Android M or later,
they'll see a permission screen.
And if you'll scroll down, you'll see
that once they've responded to that
permission screen, OnRequest
permission result will be called.
If they accepted the permission,
which is checked here,
a new audio input reader object is
created and the visualization starts.
If not, the visualization exits
with a helpful error message.
And well, beyond that, there isn't
really much else in the class.
Let's see what this code
looks like when we run it.
Now as I mentioned,
I already have all the code to
actually change the visualization.
I can do this by calling
the methods on the VisuaizerView,
just like you see here in
the default setup method.
These are all of the methods
that you can call.
They are: setShowBass, setShowMid,
setShowTreble, setMidScaleSize and
setColor.
The color is currently a string which
can be found in your string resource
file, which if you don't remember,
is right here.
Here are the other colors
currently available.
If I wanted to change the visualizer
to be blue and just show the base and
double the current size of the circle,
I could call these methods
a little bit differently.
For example, I could hide these two,
multiply the minimum size by 2 and
change this to blue.
All right, let's try edit again.
[SOUND] Cool.
So, we can see that these
changes are possible, but
there's nowhere in the UI that I
can trigger those sorts of changes.
That's the goal of this lesson.