In the code example here,
you'll notice that we've declared four
string variables, using the keyword var.
Here we've got var name,
var introduction,
var nobleGoal, and var yourDream.
Let's see what happen
if I'll press Test Run.
I'm, type your name here and I'll use
to dream building an app the could,
what is the problem you
like to solve with an app?
Mm-hm, that's sound little silly
The output contains placeholders for
the variables.
We should fix this.
I'm going to set name to be my name,
Gabrielle.
And then I'm going to set nobleGoal
to be a problem I'd like to solve.
How about find the most delicious steak.
We've inserted these two variables
into a string using the syntax,
backslash open parenthesis,
variable name, closed parenthesis.
This known as string interpolation.
You can we are inserting
the variable name here and
we are inserting the variable
noble goal here, and finally, we
are concatenating the two strings plus
operator and printing out the result.
And now if we press Test Run, we can see
it prints out the beginning of my story.