[Thrun] For this question we will be exploring a little trick
about non-normalized probability.
We will observe that P of A given X1, X2 and not X3,
the expression on the left can be resolved by Bayes' rule into this expression over here.
We will take X3 to the left and replace it by A,
both conditioned on the variables X1 and X2.
Then we have PA given X1, X2 divided by P not X3, X1, X2.
Next we employ 2 things.
One is the denominator does not depend on A,
so whether I put an A or not A has no bearing on any calculation here,
which means I can defer its calculation until later, and it will turn out to be important.
So I'm going to be proportional to just the stuff over here.
And second, I export my conditional independence
whereby I can omit X1 and X2 from the probability of not X3 conditioned on A.
These variables are conditionally independent.
This gives me the following recursion
where I now removed the third variable from the estimation problem
and just retained the first 2 relative to my initial expression.
If I keep expanding this, I get the following solution.
P of not X3 given A, P X2 given A, P X1 given A times P of A.
You might take a minute to just verify this,
but this is exploiting the conditional independence
very much as in the first step I showed you over here.
This step lacks the normalizer,
so let me work on the normalizer by expressing the opposite probability,
P of not A given the same events, X1, X2, and not X3,
which resolves to P of not X3 given not A,
P of X2 given not A, P of X1 given not A,
and P of not A.
I can now plug in the values from above.
So the first term gives me 0.8 times 0.2 times 0.2 times 0.5.
In the second term I get 0.4 times 0.6 times 0.6 times 0.5,
which resolves to 0.016 and 0.072.
This is clearly not a probability because we left out the normalizer.
But as we know, the normalizer does not depend on whether I put A or not A in here.
As a result, it will be the same for both of these expressions,
and I can obtain it by just adding these non-normalized probabilities
and then subsequently divide these non-normalized probabilities accordingly.
So let me just do this.
We get for the desired probability over here 0.1818
and for the inverse probability over here 0.8182.
Our desired answer therefore is 0.1818.
This was not an easy question.