So which one's right, Charles?
I think I know which one's right, but
I'm going to try to figure
this out by talking through.
Is that alright?
>> Yeah, of course.
>> Okay, so
I'm going to look at the first one and
I'm going to say that can't be right,
for
sort of a similar argument that we had
when we were going from V(s) to Q(s,a).
And I said,
well why can't you just have Q(a).
And it's because the action doesn't make
any sense without some kind of state.
And so here, you're talking
about a continuation you said,
from the state, but actually you
wanted it to happen after the R.
>> Right.
>> So, it just sort of doesn't work.
Also I'll just point out syntactically
if you look inside the equation and
asking for A, but
where is A coming from.
>> All right so that's good enough
to kind of rule this one out.
>> Yeah, so let's rule that one out,
let's just mark it no.
Good I feel pretty good about that.
So, I actually think the second one is
right, but let's see if I can
convince myself that's true.
You've gotten your state,
you took an action and
then you sort of got your reward.
And now I want to know
what's going to happen next.
So, let's see.
So the next thing that happens
is I'm going to get the discount
sorted towards the future.
What's the future?
Well the future is,
I have to get to the next state.
So that summation over S prime
is my expectation on where
I'm going to end up next.
It refers to s and a, which are passed
in, on the left side of the equation.
And then what I'm going to do next,
is I'm going to actually take
the best action, and
then I will see the word that I got for
taking the action in
this data ended up in.
And that puts me in the same place I was
in before and so that I can continue so
to speak with the rest of the sequence.
>> That seems convincing.
>> That seems to me
like a good argument.
But before I believe that,
let me just sort of convince
myself the other two aren't right.
So if I look at the next one,
c, s, a and r.
I actually think that could be right,
except if you look inside
the equation there, it's the same
reasoning holds, I was in some state.
Is that prime underneath the summation?
>> Yeah, sorry.
>> Okay, so I'm going to do
the same thing to my expectation.
Or the state end up in the state.
S prime then I take
the best action that I can.
And then I receive the reward
that I received already?
That doesn't make any sense.
The reward I'm going to
receive next has to depend on
where I'm going to be afterwards.
So the r is in the wrong place so
that can't be right.
>> Yeah and also the next
call requires the reward for
the following state which of
course we don't know yet.
So there's nothing to pass in here.
So this just doesn't work.
>> Right.
Yeah, that's right.
Actually, you can use the same
argument to eliminate the next one.
So this is an interesting function.
I want to know, I was in a state, took
an action, ended up in the next state.
It seems like something you kind
of might want to keep track of.
So, I do the gamma,
I'm going to go to the next state, but
I'm summing over the next
state I'm going to get to, but
you passed in already the next
state that I'm going to go to.
So just on syntactic grounds
this doesn't make any sense.
And I think the rest of it has the same
problem you described before with
our prime, which is I now have to know
the next state I'm going to end up in.
>> Right, and
that just hasn't been computed yet.
>> So this would work if we
could go back in time maybe?
>> We've done that before today.
[LAUGH]
>> [LAUGH] We have done that
before today.
But you can only use the Scooby-Doo
flashback effect once or twice in a day.
So I think I've convinced myself
that the other ones don't work and,
in fact,
the second one is the right answer.
>> Excellent.
All right, that's what I was going for.
So we now have three double equations,
V, Q and C.
We're really going to focus mostly on C.
All right, sorry, Q, from now on.
But I thought we really just kind of
see the relationship between these.
>> Okay, well that makes sense.
I mean what you're saying, is that we
have an infinite sequence of things.
And where we choose to start
the sequence, really sort of,
mathematically doesn't matter, right?
But you might choose to do one versus
the other because it's easier to
think about or easier to kind of learn
or to do what it is you're trying to do.
And you've argued so far,
although you haven't told me why yet,
that the Q is kind of going to be easier
if you're doing reinforcement learning.
>> Exactly.
And
actually that makes me think that maybe
it would be helpful to have a quiz.
>> We just had a quiz.
>> Maybe it would be useful
to have another quiz.
>> Okay, sure.