Let's talk briefly about
the Sun RPC registry.
Remember we said already that the actual
code that the server needs to register
with the registry's auto generated
in the RPC general process, and
it's part of the main function.
In Sun RPC the registry process or
the registry daemon
is a process that runs on every single
machine and it's called portmapper.
To start this process in Linux you have
to have administrative permissions or
sudo access privileges and
then you can launch it with
the following command, sbin portmap.
This is the process that has to be
contacted both by the servers when they
need to register a service, and also
by the clients when they need to find
what is the specific
contact information for
a particular service
they are looking for.
Now given that the client already
got to talk to this RPC daemon,
it clearly knows what is the IP address
of the machine that it will need to
interact with.
So the information that the client can
extract from the port mapper includes
things like what is the port
number that the client
needs to use to talk to a server, or
whether the particular version and
protocol are supported for
the server that the client requires.
Once the RPC daemon is running we can
explicitly check what are the services
that are registered with
it using our rpcinfo -p.
You may need to explicitly type in
the full path for this command but
once you run it you will see that
it returns information like what is
the program ID,
the service name, the version
of every single service that's
registered on that particular machine.
Also for every service it will
incorporate the contact information.
So what is the protocol that
that service speaks so to say.
And what is the socket port number that
needs to be contacted by the client
side RPC runtime when it wants to
initiate communications with a service.
When you run this service, you will also
probably notice that the port mapper
service is registered with tcp and
udp on the same port number, 111.
This means that there
are two different sockets
that this server is listening to.
One is a tcp socket, and
the other one is a udp socket, and
they both happen to use
the exact same port number, 111.
This means that this service,
the port mapper,
will be able to talk to both the tcp,
as well as udp clients.