ClassPass is a website that
allows members to access fitness
classes in their local area.
Members view this map page to see and
find studios in their neighborhood.
What type of data analysis project
is the ClassPass map feature?
Do data analysts have to
analyze trends from data?
Or did this project involve
applied statistics and
machine learning algorithms?
Or was there
a recommendation system that
analyzed customer activity to make
suggestions about what studios to visit?
Or did it help clients visualize
data in a way that was more engaging
through a data visualization?
Choose the correct answer
from these options.