Let's illustrate synchronization and
synchronization mechanisms using our toy
shop example, synchronization in
operating systems is like waiting for
a co-worker in the toy shop to finish so
that you can continue working.
When an elf is waiting on a co-worker
to finish, several things can happen,
the elf can continuously check
whether the other elf is done or
they can ask the co-worker to
signal them once they are done.
At any rate, the time that an elf spends
waiting will hurt the performance of
the toy shop, for instance the elf
may repeatedly check the other
elf whether it's completed the work,
asking questions like, are you done now?
What about now?
Are you still working?
This can have a negative
impact on the elf
that is working because it will delay
its processing, he will be annoyed.
The second approach of hey, I'm done
you can come and do your work now
is maybe a little bit more laid back but
this other guy may have gone out for
lunch in the meantime so it may take
it longer to actually come back and
precede with the execution with
the processing of the toy.
So regardless, in both of these cases
the workers are wasting some productive
time during this wait period,
similar analogies to these exist in
synchronization in operating systems.
Processes may repeatedly check
whether it's okay for them to continue
using a construct called spinlocks
that's supported in operating systems.
We already talked about mutexes and
condition variables and
we saw that they can be used in order to
implement this behavior where a process
waits for a signal from another process
before it can continue working.
Regardless of how we wait, and
which synchronization mechanism we use,
this will affect performance, this can
result in CPU cycles that are wasted
when we're performing this checking or
performance may be lost due to
certain cache effects when
we are signalling another
process that was periodically blocked
to come back and start executing again.