Check out my solution for this quiz.
Again, to get started I
reviewed over the test
before popping open Developer Tools.
I also stuck Developer Tools
to the bottom of the page so
I could get a better view of the header.
The first two tests involved
adding style to the header.
To find the header, I inspected
the area at the top of the page and
started parsing through the HTML.
Instead of finding an element
with the class header,
this particular page used
a header semantic tag instead.
Pretty cool.
We'll actually touch more on
semantic elements in a later lesson.
To pass the tests,
I added the style for color and
changed the font-weight from 800 to 400.
The next test asked to
change the Udacity logo
to a fixed width of 200 pixels.
To complete this,
I inspected the Udacity logo and
simply corrected the style to
be 200 pixels instead of 500.
Finally, to pass the last test I located
the body tag, which was pretty easy,
because the body tag is always
towards the top of your HTML.
Then I added the background
color to finish the quiz.
One more thing worth pointing out here,
is that as I started typing
background-color in the Styles section,
you can see that Developer Tools started
auto-populating a list of properties
that began with the word background.
This is really helpful when testing
styles live in the browser.