Okay, so now when we have
started with our first ad app,
let's look at the AdListener
abstract class.
AdListener provides you with information
about the ad loading process and
how your app and
user interact with the ad.
It has the following methods,
onAdFailedToLoad,
which is called when there
is a problem loading the ad.
This method also takes
the error code as an argument.
And these are the ERROR_
constants in the AdRequest class.
Then we have onAdOpened, which is
called when the user clicked on the ad.
onAdLeftApplication is called when
the ad opens another app, for
example, a browser.
And finally, onAdClosed, which is called
when the user is about to return to your
application after clicking on an ad.
So by extending this class and
overloading these methods,
you can get callbacks for
all of these different events.
And once you've implemented
your adListener class,
it's very easy to add it to your view.
Simply call addListener
before you do loadAd.
And that will now be your task,
to add an addListener to your app.
Here is what you should do.
Create a class calls ToastListener
that extends the AdListener.
Overload the AdListener methods and
display an Android Toast message for
each of them.
If you don't know what
an Android Toast message is,
please check out
the Android documentation.
Also implement the method
called getErrorReason.
This method should return
a human readable string
based on the error code
received in onAdFailedToLoad.
And finally, set an instance of
ToastListener in your AdView.
Check here when you're done.