Hi, my name is Mark Barunstein.
After a long career in
Health Informatics,
I've been teaching it here at
Georgia Tech for the past few years.
It's about the applications of
information technology to healthcare
delivery.
This is distinct from Bioinformatics,
a related field with which
it is often confused.
That is about building
computational models.
And using other
approaches to analyze and
understand the complex, intracellular,
biochemical mechanisms.
The term Biomedical Informatics is often
used to denote the merger of these two
fields into one training,
and or research program.
As you'll learn, even though healthcare
delivery is a very data dependent
activity, here in the US it has long
resisted the adoption of information
technology even though they're in
common use in other industries.
Partially as a result,
the US has many problems delivering
efficient high quality care.
Many people feel the solutions,
at least in part,
are through the widespread adoption and
proper use of the information
technologies you'll be learning about.