The code in our service worker doesn't
do anything yet, because it hasn't been
registered, but I've been talking long
enough, so this is a job for you.
Once again, we pick up the video
phone to our taskmaster, Mike Wales.
>> Hello again.
>> Now, this
is the first coding task of the course
Mike, so, you know, don't be too cruel.
>> Who do you take me for?
Okay, we're just saw Jake add of fetch
listener to a service worker script.
But now you need to
register it from the page.
To get your copy of the project
into the same state as Jake's,
run git reset --hard.
And then git checkout task-register-sw.
If you've already got
the server running,
you don't need to stop
it to switch branches.
Just open another command
window to the project.
Once you're on the correct branch,
take a look at public/js/sw/index.js.
This is the service worker script.
And it contains the fetch event
listener from the last chapter.
And if you navigate the browser to
http://local host.port 88/sw.js,
you can see the output of that code.
Along with a little extra
that babel has thrown in.
We want to register the service worker
as soon as our app starts up, so
let's go into
public/js/main/indexcontroller.js.
And its controls constructor is
taking care of the set up of our app,
including setting up the web socket for
the live updates.
Don't worry about this stuff.
This would be the custom code for
your app, whatever it is.
In this case it's setting up our views,
and getting ready to receive wheats.
Also, JavaScript doesn't
have private methods, but
it's common practice to start
methods with an underscore
if they'll only ever be called
by other methods of this object.
Just notice that at the end there,
it calls _registerServiceWorker.
Here's the implementation
of _registerServiceWorker,
which is currently empty.
And this is where you come in.
Add the code to register
the service worker here.
We want the scope to be the whole
origin, so the default scope is fine.
Once you've done that, reload the page
so your code runs, and check for errors.
The best way to do this is
to open Chrome dev tools.
You can also use command
+ Alt + J as a shortcut,
which is Alt + Ctrl + J on Windows.
Once you're happy the service
worker has registered,
head to the Settings page and
type registered into the test field.
Then press Enter.
It'll test to see if
everything's working.