Now that we have our item layout and
ViewHolder for
our RecyclerView, it's time to connect
the RecyclerView to a data source.
And for that,
we need to create an Adapter.
The adapter is called by
the RecyclerView to create new items
in the form of ViewHolders,
like the one we just created.
It also populates, or binds,
these items with data.
And returns information about the data,
such as how many items there
are in a given data source.
This data could come from an ArrayList,
the JSON result of a network request, or
any other data source you can model.
The Adapter requires us to
override three functions.
The first is onCreateViewHolder,
which is called when the RecyclerView
instantiates a new ViewHolder instance.
The second is onBindViewHolder,
which is called when RecyclerView
wants to populate the view
with data from our model, so
that the user can see it, effectively
binding it to the data source.
And third is getItemCount, which returns
the number of items in our data source.
Let's talk a bit more about how
these three functions are called.
Here we have an empty RecyclerView.
And our data source is an array of name
objects that contain a family name and
a first name.
When the RecyclerView is being laid out
and drawn, it will first ask the adapter
for the number of items
that it will be displaying.
It may ask multiple times
during the layout process.
So it's important that
this be a fast operation.
The RecyclerView will then ask the
Adapter to create ViewHolder objects.
And in the process, inflate individual
item views from their corresponding XML
by calling onCreateViewHolder.
It will create as many
ViewHolders as are necessary
to either display all of the items or
fill and scroll the screen.
Whichever option requires
fewer ViewHolders.
The onCreateViewHolder function is
responsible for creating the views,
either by inflating the item views
from XML or creating them in code.
It then returns a new ViewHolder
object associated with this new view.
After each ViewHolder is created, the
RecyclerView will call onBindViewHolder
to populate each item with data.
And when you scroll, the RecyclerView
will reuse those ViewHolders,
asking the Adapter to
bind new data to them.