In the next few sections,
we'll look at how to track the way your
users view products and buy things.
This course does not teach how to
implement the shopping
cart functionality.
What it does teach is how to add
Analytics code to report data
about the different steps
in the shopping process.
However, our dinner app needs
a bit more functionality
to be useful as a learning tool,
in this case.
You'll add an activity to the app
to display all the dinners.
This list will let your users
see all the dinner choices and
pick which ones they want to view.
The dinner class already has a method,
getAllDinners,
that returns a list of all the dinners.
So now we need to add an activity.
To display all the dinners
as a scrolling list.
We also need to add
a button on the home screen
that starts the activity
to display all the dinners.
So you're going to need to
add some code to your app.
To start with, you're going to need to
add the ShowAllDinnersActivity class.
And then you'll need to add the method
showDinnerList in the Main Activity.
And the onClick action
of the items in the list
will be to go to
the Order Dinner screen.
So, currently the Order Dinner
screen just displays an info
box about ordering the dinner.
But as you work through the next few
sections, you'll be adding buttons to
this screen to simulate steps
in the purchase process.
So you'll need to add the Show all
the Dinners button to activity_main.xml.
And then you're going to need the layout
files for the scrolling list of dinners.
So you'll add list_all_dinners.xml for
the scrolling list itself.
Then show_dinner_in_row.xml for
each row in the list.
If you're up for the challenge,
write the code yourself, or
if you want, you can just get the
predefined code from GitHub, up to you.