So today what I've done is I've introduced the basic concept of a panorama and
presented a variety of steps to make a panorama.
And I've basically related back to the steps of how a panorama making is
related to the whole concept of computational photography and
of different elements of computational photography.
Next I'm going to now, again, push on the whole concept of why are we trying to
study computational photography.
I'm going to show you different examples of it.
And again what I'm going to talk about is why is computation photography and
interesting discipline and how it relates to traditional photography.
Something I've been covering a little bit in previous lectures but
I'm going to try to unify them together in the next one.
Just to conclude here the some of the softwares that I
used to generate the panoramas that you saw in this lecture.
There are of course many other different types of software with
many other capabilities.
I'm not trying to advertise for any one of them, just the fact that I used them.