Once you've become comfortable with how
the increment method is working and
how to update a variable based on
the current value of that variable,
then do the same for
the decrement method.
In the decrement method, initialize the
quantity variable to two cups of coffee,
then decrease it by one cup.
I bet you never thought you'd be
doing so much coffee cup math, but
it's helping us learn Java,
so it's worth it.
Also use the debugger
to step through and
verify that the quantity variable
is being updated as expected.
Once you become more
comfortable with variables,
you can eventually skip this step of
using the debugger because you'll be
able to keep track of all the values
of the variables in your head.
But since you're starting out, if you
like seeing the concrete value in front
of you at each step in the code, then go
ahead and continue to use the debugger.
Check these boxes when you're done.