The first one an employee uses a laptop
on the company network and at home.
In this case a personal
firewall is required because
when the employee takes the laptop
to his home it needs protection.
That is when the laptop is at home it
is not protected by the conventional
network firewall at a company, so
it requires a personal firewall.
The second one,
an employee uses a desktop
on the company network to
access websites worldwide.
In this case, it does not require
a personal firewall because the desktop
is within the company's network.
The third case, a remote employee
uses a desktop to create a VPN
on the company's secure network.
In this case,
a personal firewall is required.
In fact, a personal firewall on
a desktop is typically used to create
a VPN, so that the remote desktop can
access the company's secure network.
And obviously,
this last statement is false.