Okay, so what do you have for the viewport?
>> So for the viewport, we've added our resize operation and
we've left some space for, you know, this new position that we'll be giving it.
>> Okay and what remember we said that
the viewport is an, can hold an integer number of lines of text, so
it makes sense that we express the size in terms of the integer data type.
>> Okay. >> What's the return type of this operation?
>> I guess we could return the new verified size or
like maybe a Boolean that it successfully executed.
>> Or nothing at all.
You know, in this case, we're performing the operation for
its effect rather than its return value.
Okay, so we'll use the UML void type to indicate that
there's no return value of interest to us here.
>> And I guess that I had a question in regards to,
if we're going to list some types for the arguments and
then also the return values, but without getting too implementation specific.
We're going to use types that are UML-based and not language-based.
You know integers for Java, for instance, might be expressed a certain way.
It might be different than another language, right?
>> So we're not, we're not, we're not concerned with implementation data types,
however, the particular tool that you may use to actually draw this,
might express the UML types in terms of programming language types.
So for example Argo UML does make exactly that
choice and map the UML types to, to Java types.
But for purposes of doing an analysis model we're concerned with kind of
the concepts and we're willing to abstract away those implementation details.
>> Okay.
>> So how about the other use case in terms of moving the scroll bar handle?
So that's added to our rectangle for the scroll bar and
I indicated that there would be an argument for the new position of the handle.
And it-
>> And a, and a return type?
>> So void two.
>> Okay.
>> Based on our last one.
>> Now, conventionally the operations go in the lower, the,
the lowest of the three compartments rather than, than the middle.
But UML is actually flexible and you can have anything between one and
number of, of boxes there and you can use them however you want.
Your particular tool may, may differ.
There are some subtleties here which ultimately we're going to have to,
to deal with.
The requirements didn't say only that the size of the viewport was an int.
It said that that int must be between 1 and 100.
So the UML diagramming notation doesn't allow us to express that, and
we would have to use some other mechanism to to get at that particular detail.
And also our GUI tool kit, when it's dealing with the scroll bar is,
is probably going to return some kind of pixel position.
But we're at, we're at the analysis stage and not the design stage, and so we're
just going to, once again, assume that we could deal with, with numbers between
between 1 and, 1 and 100 as the particular position of the scroll bar handle.