We've just seen that labels and
text fields have the same
compression resistance, 750.
That's a pretty high value.
What this means is that once they
reach their intrinsic content size,
squeezing them requires a lot of effort.
Some other view of the lower compression
resistance is inside the stack view.
That's the one that will be crushed.
On the other hand,
the content hugging of a label is
slightly higher than
that of a text field.
This means that a text field will
increase its width before a label does.
I have some homework for you now.
Write down on a piece of paper
a table with a content hugging and
compression resistance
of the following views.
A label, a text field, a button,
a slider and an image view.
Can you see some pattern there?
Are labels and
image views different from other views?
Try to make some sense out
of what you found out.