Now that we finished building out a home
for our weather data, it's time to
consider how to make sure that data
can be updated in the background.
One of the most powerful features of
Android has always been the ability for
any app to run in the background.
As is usually the case though, with
great power comes great responsibility.
So if you're building an app that has
significant background components,
you need to be very conscious
of how it's consuming resources.
A poorly behaved background app can
have a seriously negative impact on
the overall user experience.
In this lesson,
you'll learn more about how the Android
framework manages background apps.
You'll be introduced to the two final
Android components, the service and
broadcast receiver.
And you'll be introduced to Jobs,
the new way Android is
having background tasks.
And running in the background wouldn't
be complete without being able to notify
users when something
important has happened.
So you'll also learn how to send
notifications when your app is running
in the background.