Ember is constantly improving, which is
really great because there's an active
community and bug fixes
are usually just one update away.
But that also means the API
might change suddenly.
So it's very important to know
about Ember's documentation and
to refer to it often.
Using Ember CLI to generate a route
will create a route file and
a template file with the same name,
and that's what i've done here.
For this quiz, I want you to use
the Ember docs to create a route
that matches Lego, but
loads the bricks template.
Here are the specific instructions for
this quiz.
A link to the starter code for
this project is in the instructor notes.
When you finished building the template,
the feedback extension will give you a
code, enter that code on the next page.
Ember uses the queue unit
testing framework, and
I have created a number of
tests that you need to satisfy.
These tests help guide you through
completing the assignment.
Once all the tests have passed,
the feedback extension will give you a
code, enter that code on the next page.
You can find a link to this project's
test page in the project's read me file.