So far,
we've seen how you can use tag manager
to dynamically update
things like UI strings and
configuration parameters in your app,
without having to redeploy the app.
Another compelling use of tag
manager is to manage your tags.
A tag is a piece of code that sends
information to third parties for
things like analytics, remarketing,
affiliate programs, attribution,
e-commerce tracking and more.
The codes that sends the data to Google
Analytics is fed throughout your app.
It can be hard to keep track of
which hits your app is sending.
Using Tag Manager you can well,
manage your tags.
See what your app is tracking.
And see what your app isn't tracking.
The specific example of tag manager that
we're going to explore in the rest of
this lesson is how to manage
the tags for Google analytics