Now if we look at the consumer code, so
this is the code that's executed by every one of the consumer threads.
There, what every one of the threads needs to do, it's going to, in a loop,
so in a continuous loop, it will try to remove elements from the shared buffer.
In every pass through this loop, the consumer thread will try to remove
an element from the buffer and update the rem and num variables accordingly.
To these kinds of modifications we have to lock the mutex, and
then once we're done we have to unlock the mutex.
Again, like in the producer case, we do some sanity error checking to
make sure that our buffer doesn't have a negative number of elements.
And then before we actually start removing elements from the buffer,
we have to make sure that there are any elements in the buffer to begin with,
that the buffer isn't empty.
If the buffer is empty, so if this variable num that indicates the total number
of elements in the buffer is 0, the consumer thread has to wait.
The wait is associated with the consumer condition variable.
Remember this is the condition variable that the producer thread was
signaling to, and
also with this wait we have to use the mutex that protects this piece of code.
Once we have successfully completed the wait part,
so a producer has generated more data, the consumer has been notified,
it has come out of the conditional wait, and yes indeed,
re-verified that now there is data in the buffer that can be consumed.
Then we can safely move on to execute this portion of the code.
To remove an element from this buffer, what we really do is we read out
the element of the buffer that's pointed by the rem variable.
So rem points to the next valid field in
the buffer where there is valid data that could be removed.
We also make sure to print out that value i, just for
sanity, to make sure that we're doing the correct thing.
Now that that element that was pointed by rem is no longer valid,
we have to make sure we increment rem to point to the next entry in the buffer.
Just like in the case with the add index, we have to do some
modular computation to deal with wrap-arounds around the end of the buffer.
And we have to also make sure we decrement the total number of
elements in the array.
Now in the producer code, the producer was checking the value of this variable
num against buffer size to determine whether or not the buffer is full.
Whenever you determine that these are identical so
that the buffer is full, the producer was waiting to be
notified on a condition variable that's associated with the c producer.
Therefore, in the consumer code, now that we've decremented this, variable num,
now that we have consumed an element from the buffer and it's no longer full.
We need to go ahead and notify a producer thread that there is
now room in the buffer to insert other elements, to produce more data.
The consumer consumed one element of this buffer, so
it makes no sense to broadcast.
Only one producer can insert one element in the buffer.
Therefore, we will just use pthread_cond_signal.
And note how here we are using this pthread_cond_signal outside of
the lock-unlock operation.
Given that we will always signal once we complete this code that
this operation is not conditional upon some specific values of any of
the shared data structure, we can release the mutex and then signal, and
this will avoid the spurious wakeups issue that we talked about before.
Again, the printf's are for debugging purposes.