Typical ways in which user processes
interact with a device is as follows.
A process needs to perform an operation
that requires access from a hardware
device, for instance, to perform
a send operation to transmit a network
packet or to read a file from disk.
The process will perform
a system call in which it will
specify the appropriate operation.
With this, the process is requesting
this operation from the operating
system, from the kernel.
The operating system then
will run the in-kernel
stack related to this particular device.
Like, for instance, the TCPIP stack
to form the appropriate packet
before the data is sent out to the
network or the file system that's needed
to determine the particular disk
block that stores the file data.
And the operating system will invoke
the appropriate device driver for
the network or for the block device for
the disk, and then the device driver
will actually perform the configuration
of the request to the device.
On the network side,
this means that the device driver will
write out a record that configures
the device to perform a transmission
of the appropriate pack of data.
Or on the disk side, this means that
the device driver will issue certain
commands to the disk that configure
the disk head movement or
where the data should be read from,
et cetera.
The device drivers will issue these
commands using the appropriate
programmed IO or DMA operations, and
this will be that in
a device-specific manner.
So that driver sort of wants that
are understand the available memory
registers on the device.
They understand the other
pending requests.
So the driver is the one that will
need to make sure that the requests
aren't somehow overwritten or
undelivered to the device.
So, all of this configuration and
control will be performed at this level,
at the driver level.
And finally,
once the device is configured,
it will perform the actual request.
In the case of the network card,
this device will perform
the transmission of the data.
In the case of the disk device,
the device will perform the block
read operation from disk.
And finally,
any results from the request or
in general any events
that are originating
on the devices will traverse this
coal chain in a reverse manner.