Any given model type, so
whether it's a line or transform,
they have what's known as a minimal set.
The minimal set is
the smallest number of samples
from which the model can be computed.
So for a line, how many points is that?
Well, two, all right?
But what about transforms, when we're
transforming one image to the next?
Image transforms are just models.
So what is the minimal set
of our different transforms?
Well, first of all,
what are we sampling from?
Well, we're sampling
from proposed matches.
Corresponding pairs of points, okay?
So suppose I think that one image is
just translated of another image.
So the transformation is a translation.
How many pairs do I need?
One.
Because if you tell me where
this point a is in this other image,
I now know the translational
shift between any two points.
Another way of thinking about that is
I need a delta x and a delta y, and
you give me two, an x and a y match.
So I know what delta x is, I do this
complicated thing called subtract, and
I do it on y and that's my offset.
Okay, homography,
ooh we talked about this.
How many pairs of corresponding points
do we need to compute a homography?
Do you remember,
paying attention out there?
Four, Megan got it right.
How about a fundamental matrix?
We showed you something called
the eight point algorithm that said
if you had eight points, corresponding
pairs, you can compute that.
By the way, it's actually seven.
We didn't really talk
too much about that.
Do you remember when with eight
points we could solve for
the fundamental matrix, but then you
would sometimes end up with a rank
three fundamental matrix so
you had to reduce it down to a rank two?
We did that whole getting rid
of the smallest icon value.
That's because there's actually
fewer degrees of freedom.
So in principle you can do
it with seven points, but
we're just going to think
of it as eight points.
So the idea is, for translation I need
one pair, for a homography I need four
pairs, for a fundamental matrix
I need seven or eight pairs.
This is the minimal set that it
takes to compute these things.
Then you can write down
the general RANSAC algorithm.
Randomly select, it says s points or
point pairs, s elements of a sample set.
So you form a sample by pulling
out s things that you need.
You instantiate your model.
So you either draw your line or compute
your homography, whatever it is you do.
And then you get a consensus set,
C sub i.
And these are the points that
are sort of within the error bounds.
So if you think of homography,
homography maps this image to that
image, and I can see are all these
points map, how many of the proposed
matches now land in the same place
that they said they came from?
That's the number of inliers.
And, in fact,
you might even terminate this algorithm
as soon as that consensus
set is big enough.
Or you might just repeat it for
n times and
then you return whichever model
gave you the biggest set.
So that's the general RANSAC algorithm.
And of course, like any other algorithm,
there are some parameters to be chosen
in order to make this thing work.
So the first parameter is this number s,
the minimal set.
This how big is the minimal set.
That number is actually usually set by
whatever model you're using, right?
So if you're fitting
lines that number is two.
If you're doing homographies
that number is four, four pairs.
So that's set by the model.
A little more problematic was
this distance threshold t, or
delta as wrote in the Greek,
of saying how far away
from the model that you're computing
is excitable to be an inlier.
So let's look at that
one just a little bit.