After going through
some simple examples,
now we're ready to show you how to build
a real media app for Android Auto.
We've built a very complete sample that
is a great reference point for you.
So, let's load it up.
Go to File, Import Sample and
search for Universal Music Player.
Select it.
Click next, and
then finish with all the defaults.
Let's now run the sample and
see what it looks like.
Click the green play icon here, and
we're going to use a simple debug to
build and install it to the emulator
just like we did before.
We select the emulator, press OK.
So now, it's running on the emulator.
You can see that we can browse by genre.
We can pick one, and then pick a zone.
And once again, we have music playing.
It's pretty easy, hey?
So, how does this work?
In the previous simple
example we walked through,
there was no UI on the Android side.
We needed to run the media simulator.
In this case there is
an Android activity.
Let's go over to the code.
The UMP sample implements it here.
Go to Java, Package, UI and
Music Player Activity.
This activity implements a media browser
and media controller that connects
to the media browser's service to
retrieve the music hierarchy and
then start the music play back.
The activity implements
exactly the same API,
as what the Android Auto simulator did.
Let's go back to the home screen,
start the media simulator.
And if we go to the top, we can now see
that the Universal Music Player is also
available, and we can browse in
the same way that we did last time.
So, the same media is visible here, too,
but with an Android Auto experience.
The UMP sample is nice because it
implements user interfaces for
many different platforms as well.
It also provides an activity that
Android TV can start, showing the same
music library suitable for presentation
in the Leanback UI on Android TV.
If you're implementing
a large media application,
UMP is a great starting point to see
best practices in implementing this, and
how to make a professional,
polished looking app for many platforms.