The objectives of this lesson are for
us to learn about, how we can actually
control illumination in a scene.
How we can actually use a projector
to control a light source.
How we can use a projector as a
controlled light source in a scene to be
able to then project the right
kinds of illumination in a scene.
And with the construction of both these,
how we can actually build
a projector camera system.
We'll talk a little bit about how we can
calibrate the illumination in a scene
from a projector.
And then I will actually showcase
a variety of different existing examples
of projector-camera systems or
procams, as it's usually referred to.
Now, in this lecture I'm going to be
showing you a whole lot of videos.
So please watch these videos,
I will also be providing you
links to these videos and
you can watch the full length versions
of these videos, offline, on your own.