You've gone through how an application
accesses data through a provider.
And now you're ready to program
the rest of the methods that the task
content provider needs.
There are six functions that every
content provider is required to have.
The first is onCreate,
which initializes the provider, and
which you've already implemented.
Then there are the four so-called
CRUD methods, where CRUD stands for
create, read, update and delete.
And these are the four main functions
used for persistent data storage.
This will be pretty similar to the CRUD
functions you implemented in the SQLite
lesson.
To let users of your
app create new data,
you need to code the content
provider's insert method.
This will take in a content Uri which
tells the correct directory to insert
data into, and a ContentValues object
that contains the new data to insert.
After the data is inserted,
this returns a newly created content Uri
that tells you the location
of the inserted data.
To read data and display it in your UI,
you'll write the query method which asks
for data from your content provider.
This returns a cursor that
contains a row, or rows,
of data that the query has asked for.
Next is the update method.
This takes in the same
parameters as entered, so
it knows where to update data by
the Uri, and with what ContentValues.
And this will return
an integer value for
the number of rows that were updated.
And then to delete,
you'll implement the delete method,
which needs to know the Uri that
points to the row, or rows, to delete.
And this should return
the number of rows deleted.
The last method that a provider
requires is called getType,
which returns the MIME type of
the content being returned.
And a MIME type is just a way of
identifying what format the content is
in, in a similar way to file types.
So these are all the functions you'll
need to have in a complete content
provider.