As we mentioned multiple
times in this course,
understanding the workload, in this
case, that will be the access pattern,
how the files are being accessed.
This is an important piece of
information, that's useful when we're
trying to design and optimize
a particular solution in a certain way.
When we're thinking about
how to design the system so
as to support a particular
file sharing semantics,
we need to understand things like
what is the sharing frequency,
what is the write frequency,
so what is the access pattern.
And also how important is it to
maintain a consistent view for
that particular type of files.
Once we understand these workload
properties, the design of the file
system must be done so
that it's optimized for the common case.
One issues, however, that file systems
have two different types of files,
regular files and directories.
In these two types of files, we often
have very different access patterns in
terms of what is the locality,
what is the lifetime of the files,
the size distribution,
how frequently are they accessed.
For these reasons,
it is not uncommon for
these two types of files
to be treated differently.
For instance, we can adopt one type of
semantics for the regular files and
another type of semantics for
the directories.
Or, if we use periodic
updates as a mechanism for
both, then we may choose to use
less frequent write-backs for
the regular files versus for
the directories.
This can be based on observations that,
for instance,
directories are more frequently shared,
than individual files in them.
Later in this lesson,
we will look at the choices,
how to treat these two
different types of files, for
the network file system manifest,
and the sprite file system.