RequestAnimationFrame should be your
go to tool for creating animations.
Nobody likes to be interrupted
in the middle of a task, and
the browser is no different.
Remember how little time
the browser has to render the frame
at 60 frames a second.
If one second is a thousand
milliseconds and
we have to fit 60 frames in,
well we have 16 milliseconds.
Realistically though,
there's some overhead to running a frame
and the browser has housekeeping to do.
So we should aim for
about 10 milliseconds instead.
The JavaScript part of your frame
should typically be kept around
three to four milliseconds at most.
Because there's going to be other work,
like style calculations,
layer management, and
compositing that will come afterwords.
I want you to imagine that the browser
is in the middle of doing some
style work.
And then, in comes some
JavaScript that needs attention.
The browser now has to deal with
the JavaScript that just came in
before it can move on to other tasks.
That new JavaScript may cause the work
for the frame to be redone, and
that could well mean missing the frame.
RequestAnimationFrame schedules
your JavaScript
to run at the earliest
possible moment in each frame.
That gives the browser as much
time as possible to run your code,
then style, then the layout,
painting, and compositing.
A lot of older code around the web that
is used for animation, uses setTimeout
or setInterval, because back in
the day that's all there was.
In fact, jQuery still uses
setTimeout for its animation today.
The problem with both of these
functions is that the JavaScript engine
pays no attention to the rendering
pipeline when scheduling these.
They're good functions to use when you
want to wait some time to elapse or do
some repeated task every so often, but
they're not a good fit for animations.
This is how you use
requestAnimationFrame.
You make a call to it and tell it
which function you want it to call.
That gets called where
you do your animation.
And at the end of it you
schedule the next one.
The browser takes care of
when it should run and how.
Of the many browsers available to users
today, the only one that doesn't support
requestAnimationFrame is
Internet Explorer 9.
So, for that you'd need to use
a polyfill, which would use setTimeout.
It's not ideal as a fall back,
but it will allow you at least to
use requestAnimationFrame in your code
and not worry about compatibility.
Check out the instructor notes for
more information.