Here's what my onHandleIntent
should look like.
It of course accepts an Intent that I'm
just calling intent with a lower case i.
From this I'm going to create
an ActivityRecognitionResult object.
And I do this by extracting
the Result from the Intent.
I then create a new Intent
that I call localIntent and
I initialize this with
Constants.BROADCAST_ACTION.
Now what is Constants.BROADCAST_ACTION,
you may ask?
Well, I've created
a Constants.java file, and
in that Constants.java file,
I create a number of constants.
Now when I'm creating the broadcast
intent, I need to identify that.
So I'm using BROADCAST_ACTION
to identify it.
And I set up BROADCAST_ACTION
as PACKAGE_NAME Plus the string
.BROADCAST_ACTION.
While package name can
be anything I want, but
of coarse I'm just using
the full package of my app.
And as you can see here I called it
package lmoroney.com.udacityactivity,
and that's what I called it here.
So the broadcast action would be
that with .BROADCAST_ACTION added.
So that's my new Intent.
Now I'm going to create an array
list of detected activity.
And this array list is
going to be initialized
based on result.getProbableActivities.
So this will return to me the results
that the activity API is saying,
this is what I think is going
on at this moment in time.
And if you remember when I
showed the demo earlier on,
it had a number of different options,
and
that's all the different probable
activities that are available.
And they are returned in an array list.
And of course its an array
list of detected activity.
So I just log out what I'm doing and
now in my localIntent I put this data,
the detected activities
as an extra on it.
And I just want to identify
that again using a constant and
I call it Constants.ACTIVITY_EXTRA.
If we go back to my Constants file,
you can see ACTIVITY_EXTRA
is just the package name with
ACTIVITY_EXTRA added on the end.
And then finally, back in my
DetectedActivity Intent service.
I'm just going to call the Local
Broadcast Manager, getting an Instance,
and then sending
a Broadcast of this Intent.
We;ll be catching that Broadcast
in the main activity, and
in the main activity
we'll update the UI.
With what the activity recognition
API's detected about the actual device.
There's one final thing, we need to tell
Android about this intent service, and
we'll do that in the Android manifest.
Here you can see
the Android manifest and
I just have to paste
the service details in.
Now I usually do it here just
before the closing application tag.
And in doing this I just
create a service tag.
I give it the name prefix by a dot.
So our service was detected
activities intent service so
the name is
.DetectedActivitiesIntentService and
then to just say android
exported="false".
With this we've now
created the intent service
when we're ready to build the main app.