All right, let's go over
the solution to the problem.
The question asked us to write code for
the function word_in_pos,
which takes in a string word and
a list parts_of_speech as inputs.
If one of the words in parts_of_speech
is a substring of word,
then we return that word.
Else, we return none.
Since we want to potentially
compare word to all the words in
parts_of_speech, let's use a for loop.
Now, we need to check if
word is a substring of pos.
We'll do this by using the in
operator to check if pos is inward,
and if it is, we'll return pos.
So for example, let's say word is a noun
exclamation mark, and pos is noun.
It's true that pos isn't a word.
Noun is in noun exclamation mark,
and if that's the case,
we'll want to return pos, or
the part of speech that's in word.
Let's write that down.
Now, if the word wasn't in any
of the words in parts_of_speech,
we'll simply return none, and
we'll do this outside of the for loop.
Since you want to first compare word
to every word in parts_of_speech.
And there we have it.
Now that we have this function working,
let's move on to the final
function we'll write, play_game.