In this lesson you'll become more familiar with Anova. By going through a full
length example that not only includes calculating the F-statistic. But learning
about and calculating a measure of effect size for the differences between
three or more groups. This is similar to Cohen's d for the t-Tests. To improve
the lives of dairy cows, a researcher examined three types of food. They wanted
to assess cows' preference for one food over the other. All were equally
nutritious and affordable. Together, the farmer and the researchers gave the
cows each type of food. There were nine cows. Bessie, Frank and Slim got food A
Bob, Red, and Pippin got food B, Sam, Merry, and Chip got food C. They were
randomly assigned to each type of food. Over eight hours, this is the amount
that these cows consumed in pounds. The data can be visualized with bar graphs.
Before we get started with our analysis match the independent variable,
dependent variable, null and alternative hypotheses with the column on the
right. Not all of these will be used. Put the appropriate letter next to each.