Wonderful.
One of the first things
you'll note about my answers
is that two of them have
a range of accepted values.
That's because you can build
a prototype which does or
does not contain certain screens.
For the home screen we certainly
have the fav and the menu button.
But we may also have
an interaction point for any or
all of the events themselves.
That means we have a range of two to
five interaction points for this screen.
For the menu screen, we have six
interaction points on the main menu.
But could also have a settings screen,
terms and conditions screen,
logout screen or a profile screen
accessed by the picture or name up here.
That means a range of six
to ten interaction points.
The new events screen is
the only straightforward one.
You can leave this screen either by
going back to the home screen or
by clicking Create.
That means there are exactly
two interaction points here.