Let's take a closer look at
this version of Color Maker.
We go in here to the red switch.
Oh, yikes, this looks like
a pretty serious problem.
Fatal, fatal error.
Unexpectedly found nil while
unwrapping an Optional value.
Okay, so something's nil, and
the compiler is pointing us
straight to this line where our
colorview is getting accessed.
So, the first place to look
might be the colorView.
So, let's go up to where our
colorView property is set, and
oop, the outlet is not set.
So, to fix that outlet, we're going to
want to go back into Storyboard,
then we're going to open up the pop
up menu for the colorView, and
drag from New Referencing Outlet
to the view controller.
Let's run it again, and
see if that took care of the problem.
Red switch seems to work.
Green looks okay.
Blue.
All right, back in business.