First things first with an Ember app.
Nothing happens without a route.
So we need to generate
all of the routes first.
Now that the routes exist, we can add
the link to the store in the navigation.
The nav is in the application template.
Here's the home route.
So I'll add the link to
the store right next to it.
Loading the store route should give
us links to the different types of
baked goods.
So we need to add links to each one.
There we go,
now to add the headings for each page.
The cakes template gets
the heading All Cakes.
The cupcakes one gets All Cupcakes.
And the cookies one gets All Cookies.
And we're almost done.
We just need to add the HTML with
the cookie data from the instructions.
I've gone ahead and
filled out all of the data.
Notice that there was a lot of
duplication going on to display
the information.
We'll take care of this duplication and
these hardcoded values in the next quiz.