Let's take a closer look at
the major elements of a script.
Pop open the Unity Editor,
and create a new project.
Now, create a new C# script,
called MyFirstBehaviour.
You'll notice that I;m
spelling behavior with a u.
That's because even though I'm in the
US, Unity originally comes from Denmark.
All of their names use
European English spelling.
So, for consistency,
we'll adopt that style as well.
Speaking of behaviors,
you might be wondering why these scripts
are called Behaviors in the first place.
In Unity, you write scripts
that describe behaviors
that get attached to an object.
For example,
a dog might have a bark behavior.
A walk around behavior.
And a love humans behavior.
This makes it much easier for
you to organize and reuse your scripts.
So remember, scripts describe behaviors
that get attached to game objects.
Okay, double-click and
open up your new script.
Let's take a look at
the part labeled Start.
What you see here is called a method.
You use that to give a name
to a part of your script so
that you can more easily find and
execute that part.
For instance,
remember that the start method happens
when the script is first loaded.
An update happens every Friday.
But, what are methods anyways?
Programming is a lot like writing
instructions for a recipe.
Think of methods as the major verbs for
your instructions.
In this example, the start method
contains all the instructions you need
to happen when you first load the scene.
The update method contains
all the instructions for
when this behavior actually happens.
All right, now you know
the major elements of a script.