So welcome back, and
here are the changes that we
need to make in the code.
Now, let's start with
the straightforward part of just pasting
this provider type into the manifest.
So let's copy it and paste it
at the end of the manifest file.
So we see that Android Studio
is complaining, and
it's because we haven't created
a PetProvider class yet.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So in the data package, I want you to
right-click, go to New&gt; Java Class.
And then name the class
PetProvider class.
All right, now let's copy and
paste over the code from the gist.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
All right, so we're not done just yet.
Remember that there was one
more to do left in on create.
We needed to create and
initialize a PetDBHelper object to
gain access to the pets database.
And we are given a hint to
create a global variable.
So in order to do that, I'll create
a private variable out here of
the type PetDBHelper, and
I'll name that variable MDBHelper.
So to help me remember what this is,
I'll add a comment that this
is a database helper object.
Now that that's done, let's initialize
the variable in the on create method,
using the PetDBHelper constructor.
So this line MDBHelper set to
PetDbHelper with a parameter getcontext.
All right, so that completes everything.
Now let's compile the app,
and run it and
double check that there
are no visible changes.
So with these coding
steps taken care of,
we'll have added our content
provider to our pets app.