All right, so
to empty this main content area,
we want to empty this div
with the class of main.
Looking at the d3 documentation,
I can see that there's a couple
functions that might work.
.text, get or set text content.
Well, we don't actually
want to change text,
we want to change
the HTML that's inside.
So, selection.html seems
like a better choice.
Get or set inner HTML content.
Reading a little bit closely
about the HTML method,
we can see that it allows us to get and
set the inner HTML.
If a value is specified as the parameter
then it sets the inner HTML content
to the specified value on
all the selected elements.
And a little bit further down,
we can clear the content
by passing in a null value.
Let's see if that works.
If you chain the .html onto a selection,
then you can see the current inner
HTML content for that selection.
That's everything that's
inside of our main div tag.
We want to clear this out, so
let's pass in a null value.
By passing in the JavaScript
keyword null,
we can reset the main content area.
And any undefined value or
no value would have worked.
So, I could have also
passed in undefined here.
And finally,
the last method that would have
worked is passing in an empty string.