So we've done DI identification,
we've done generalization, and
then we're logging these queries
that return the average value.
Can let's say Alice and
Bob both come from the Midwest?
Is it possible for
Alice to figure out Bob's grade?
I'll seek and ask for the average score
of students who come from the Midwest.
So she knows the average of her and
Bob's scores.
She knows her own score.
Based on that she's going to,
it's easy to see how she will
be able to compute Bob's score.
So the answer is yes here.
It is possible when there
are only two students.
Remember?
We said a generalization ensures that
there are at least two students.
So let's say from Midwest that we're
talking about, the two students,
Alice and Bob.
Okay so, Alice can get the average for
herself and Bob.
There were only two
coming from this region.
And she knows her own grade based
on she can make an inference about
what Bob's grade is,
can you exactly compute Bob's grade.
So yes, an inference attack.
It's possible even when we do this with
de-indentification and generalization.
If you do generalization course grant
generalization with there more and
more people,
this likelihood would reduce.
But clearly the example that we have
here, this is certainly possible.