Flick Finder is starting
to look pretty good, but
some of you may have noticed
the same problem that I have.
We're not truly doing a search
of Flickr's photos if we only
select a random image from
the first page of results.
We can see this pretty quickly by
playing around in Flickr's API Explorer,
so as an example I'll use
the search term baseball.
Now I've searched this term before and
I know that it's going to return
a large number of results.
And as we can see,
this search returns 264,506 images.
And currently we're looking at page 1.
So with a query like this, our current
implementation only grabs a random image
from this first page,
which contains 100 images.
That's not bad, but
it's not a true search.
So how do we accomplish a more random,
a more true search?
If you read through the documentation
you might have this idea,
we could perform a first
search like this one here and
we could look at this pages value.
And then we could randomly select a page
number, and make a second request,
using that page number as a parameter.
So, here at the bottom we
have this page number.
So, we could use something like 36.
So now we're getting results for
the 36th page.
Now in theory, this should work, but
when I tried implementing this myself,
I ran into a problem because I did not
read all of the documentation carefully.
So let's go to the documentation.
Here in the documentation
it specifies that, at most,
only the first 4,000 results will be
returned for any given search query.
So if I try to pick a random page
number that request images beyond
the 4,000 result, then Flickr
automatically returns results for
the last possible page that does
not exceed that 4,000 limit.
If you don't believe me, you can try it.
Now this implementation detail
took me about an hour or
so of banging my head into
a wall until I figured it out.
But really, these kinds of setbacks
are pretty common in development.
We're often required to take a deeper
look into documentation to solve
problems.
So as an exercise, I really want you to
dig into the documentation to understand
the problem of making
our results more random.
Take a close look at the documentation
for the flickr.photos.search method and
answer the following questions.
First, what is the maximum number
of images Flickr will return for
any given search query?
I just mentioned the answer
to this question, so
this one should be pretty easy.
Second, if the per page
argument is not specified,
then how many images
are returned per page?
And finally, if we have a query that
requests images beyond that 4,000 limit,
then the results of what
page number are returned?
And you can assume that the per page
argument is not specified in this case.
Mark your answers in these boxes.