So is the 2-D summa scheme intrinsically
more scaleable than the 1-D block
row scheme?
The answer is quite possibly.
First note that the strip width is
a tuning perimeter of the algorithm.
Its range is between 1 and
N over square root of P.
Again, that's assuming square
operands and a square process grid.
To analyze the efficiency,
let's start by assuming the tree
based broadcast implementation.
If you compute the efficiency,
you should find that it's equal to this.
Now if you stare at this long enough,
one of two things will happen.
One is you'll glaze over.
The other is being observant,
you'll see that this factor
determines the isoefficiency.
In particular the isoefficiency
function is as follows.
Let's compare this to the 1-D algorithm.
The isoefficiency function of the 2-D
scheme is asymptotically lower
than the 1-D scheme.
That means the 2-D scheme is
intrinsically more scalable.
You don't need to increase the problem
size as fast as you need to with the 1-D
scheme.
Now you can of course do the same
exercise with a bucketing scheme.
In that case you'll find a slightly
different ISO efficiency function.
Asymptotically, this is a little bit
worse than the tree based scheme.
If you work it out you'll find that it
comes from trading a lower communication
volume with a higher latency cost.