All right, now comes something cool, again a little bit complicated.
We know that p prime is on the epipolar line,
corresponding to p in the other image, Okay.
That's what this equation says.
If, if, if this equation holds.
But suppose p prime was on the epipolar line,.
In the prime image for every point, P, in the original image.
You might say, well, how could that be?
>> How could that be?
>> Thank you, Megan.
Well the way that could be is, suppose Fp' equals zero.
Well, in order for a point to be on every epipolar line well
there is only one point that's on every epipolar line.
That's the epi pole.
So the way you find the epipole given the fundamental matrix.
Is you solve this equation.
And remember this two epipoles.
There's the epipole in the original frame and the epipole in the prime frame.
And so you just solve each of those equations.
Fp prime equals zero.
Or F transpose p equals zero.
And that identifies for you the epipoles in the image.
So this F matrix is very powerful.
It tells you everything you need to know or almost everything you need to know.
About the way the points relate to another other in terms of
their projective geometry, and
that lets you do things like find the epipolar lines and the epipoles.
Pretty cool.