The vast amount of work in the field
falls into the area of supervised learning.
In supervised learning
you're given for each training example
a feature vector
and a target label named Y.
For example, for a credit rating agency
X1, X2, X3 might be a feature
such as is the person employed?
What is the salary of the person?
Has the person previously defaulted on a credit card?
And so on.
And Y is a predictor
whether the person is to default
on the credit or not.
Now machine learning
is to be carried out on past data
where the credit rating agency
might have collected features just like these
and actual occurances of default or not.
What it wishes to produce
is a function that allows us
to predict future customers.
So the new person comes in
with a different feature vector.
Can we predict as good as possible
the functional relationship
between these features X1 to Xn all the way to Y?
You can apply the exact same example
in image recognition
where X might be pixels of images
or it might be features of things found in images
and Y might be a label that says
whether a certain object is contained
in an image or not.
Now in supervised learning
you're given many such examples.
X21 to X2n
leads to Y2
all way the index m.
This is called your data.
If we call each input vector Xm
and we wish to find out the function
given any Xm or any future vector X
produces as close as possible
my target signal Y.
Now this isn't always possible
and sometimes it's acceptable
in fact preferable
to tolerate a certain amount of error
in your training data.
But the subject of machine learning
is to identify this function over here.
And once you identify it
you can use it for future Xs
that weren't part of the training set
to produce a prediction
that hopefully is really, really good.
So let me ask you a question.
And this is a question
for which I haven't given you the answer
but I'd like to appeal to your intuition.
Here's one data set
where the X is one dimensionally plotted horizontally
and the Y is vertically
and suppose there looks like this.
Suppose my machine learning algorithm
gives me 2 hypotheses.
One is this function over here
which is a linear function
and one is this function over here.
I'd like to know which of the functions
you find preferable
as an explanation for the data.
Is it function A?
Or function B?
Check here for A
here for B
and here for neither.