Step one for this lesson is to check that your downloads are complete.
You should see a command prompt waiting instead of a download percentage.
If you see a download percentage, that means your box is still downloading and
you can feel free to continue on with the course and
then just come back to this reading node, when you're ready to move forward.
So, once your download's complete, in step two in the reading node,
you're able to log in to your virtual machine.
You'll be using the SSH or
Secure Shell command to remotely log in to your guest machine.
So on your local machine at the command prompt, type in vagrant shh.
Hit Enter and what's happening now is you are logging in in
a secure shell into your Ubuntu machine.
And when successful, you'll see that your, your command prompt has changed from
whatever file you are in to vagrant@ubunu-tu1404 for i386,
meaning that we're using a 32 bit machine.
in step three, once you're in your Ubuntu machine,
you can check your Storm version simply by typing storm version,
and you should see as of the time of this recording, 0.9.2-incubating.
Incubating means that's an Apache incubating project, but Storm
recently graduated to a top level project so this number will be changing soon.
But it's good to know that the API and the entire course should remain the same.
If you don't see a Storm version here that may mean that you haven't logged into
your Ubuntu machine.
So in your local machine type vagrant ssh again.
This is a common mistake.
In storm 4 we navigate through the vagrant machine by typing cd.
. And that goes up one level Ls for list files.
Do cd.
one more time and you'll see that we're in a top level directory.
Next type cd /vagrant.
The forward slash is an absolute directory that
will take us to the vagrant folder.
Once we're in the vagrant folder, type ls, and
you'll see the same files that you saw when downloading the file ud381.
These shared files between your host machine and
the guest Ubuntu machine is called guest additions.
So any file that you put in your local machine into ud381 will show up in
your forward slash vagrant file here.
Optionally in part 7 I'll show how quickly to log out.
You simply type log out, Enter, and you'll see the connection is lost and
we're back in our ud381 folder in your local machine.
Either Windows, Mac OSX or your own Linux machine.
Next you can re-login with vagrant ssh and cd into /vagrant.
Ls will show us our files again.
Optionally in step eight, on your local machine you can copy a picture of
yourself or avatar in a .jpg or .png format into your local ud381 folder.
This will be put in to the visualization at a later time so
that you can personalize your visualizations for your screenshots.
So, download a picture of yourself.
I've downloaded mine.
And I'm in a Mac OSX so this is my finder window.
And here's my picture, louis@udacity.
And I've opened a second window here with UD 381.
And so I'll just copy.
And drag this over to, to my file.
Next in our Ubuntu machine, I'll just type LS, and I'll see LewisATUdacity.
So again, this is the virtual machine.
And I copied the picture into my local machine and this shows the shared files.
In the next optional step nine,
simply move the picture into the folder vis/static.
And you do this using the command, mv, or move.
Lewis, and I can type in Tab to complete the entire JPEG file name.
Next type the destination viz/static, s-t-a and Tab.
Hitting Enter will actually move that file.
Ls will show that it's gone.
And we can move into the viz directory static.
Well let's go into viz, ls.
And you see that there's a static folder, cd static.
And finally, in optional Step 10, simply come into this folder and type ls.
And you should see a Twitter logo, the Udacity logo, and
yourname.jpg in the viz/static file.
Great job, and you can continue on to the next lesson.