So here's what I want all of you to do.
First, I want you to try to
make a Photosynth for yourself.
The best way to do of course is
go to the Photosynth site and
actually create a account for yourself
and then upload some pictures and
then use that to kind of
showcase a variety of things.
And of course, if, just,
this is one of those things,
completion is just entering your
a Photosynth ID in this box here
to showcase that you've done this.
Again, make sure that there's
no private stuff on this thing.
You don't have to make
all of this public.
Just, this is just for us to know that
you've actually accomplished this goal.
You will actually be doing a complete
assignment on Photosynth as one of
the assignments in the class.
So here, we are at the site.
You can sign in by creating
an account for yourself.
I'm going to sign in as
myself very quickly.
So when you are on this site, you can
basically kind of walk around and
see a variety of things.
There's a whole lot of detail about.
It will tell you how to also do
different types of synths and
explore different types of things.
Of course, these are a variety of
things other people have been doing.
In addition to that, of course, you can
also go and create your own synths and
there are a variety of ways
of doing this kind of stuff.
I recommend that you play
around with that technology.
They just announced
a newer version of this,
which basically also lets you do this
kind of synth in 3D and the best way to
create it is basically going in here and
uploading a bunch of pictures.
Again, there is a lot of help on how
you can actually learn how to do this.
This new version allows you to do four
types of different synths spinning
camera, walking Circulating around to
create a panorama also walking this way.
Again, there's a lot of details.
And of course, there are also apps
available on an Android, iOS and
windows platform for
you allowing to do this kind of stuff.
So please create an account, try to
upload an image or two, but you'll need,
of course, more than two to
create any kind of synth.
Load a variety of images.
For those of you who have what,
Windows Workstations,you can actually
do much more with Photosynth.
And of course,
you can just use the browser for
what I do these kinds of things to.
So please explore and
return to this site when you're done and
enter your Photosynth ID.