So, Mr. Algebra, what do you get?
>> That's Dr. Algebra.
I did not spend 12 years in evil algebra
school to be called Mr. Algebra.
>> [LAUGH]
>> Okay.
>> My apologies.
>> [LAUGH] All right, well I think
there's actually only one answer here,
and that answer is two.
>> All right, which one is that?
>> Both of them.
>> So there's two twos.
>> Two twos.
>> How do you get that?
Okay, so you squared both sides, and
that causes the epsilon to be squared.
Gets rid of all the square roots.
Then, oh, but
then because we squared both sides,
we get a divided by 4 over here.
Which ultimately is going to meet
up with the half over here, and
we're going to get a 2.
Yeah, that's right, very good.
>> And thus, more proof that every
single thing in computer science gets
generalized once you have two of them.
>> Two is very important
in computer science.
So let's see what we actually get here.
What we're saying is that if we sample
an arm at least this many times,
2 times 1 over epsilon squared.
Now, 1 over epsilon
squared is polynomial.
And 1 over epsilon, 1 over delta n k,
times the logarithm of 2k over delta.
So again, this quantity here is
polynomial n k, and 1 over delta.
And we're logging it.
And that gives us a count, that if we
do that enough times we're actually
going to be sufficiently certain
that we're sufficiently close,
that chosing the maximum arm
is going to be a good idea.
And it's interesting to note
here that the dependence
on the certainty parameter
is actually quite weak.
Right, so it's 1 over delta,
and it's stuffed into the log.
So this is having not a huge impact.
But the dependence on the epsilon
parameter is actually quite profound.
It's 1 over epsilon, so if we're talking
about 0.0001, that's like, I don't know,
1,000 or 10,000 or something.
And then we square that.
And so, we could actually need a ton
of samples if we want to be very,
very sure that we're very, very close.
In fact, even if we want to be
moderately sure that we're very,
very close, there's just this
big dependence on the epsilon.
>> So what you're saying is that the
hard part is getting very, very close,
not being certain how close you are?
>> It looks that way, yeah.
That's what this equation is telling us.
>> So we've said this before, since it's
all hufting here, and hufting there, and
hufting all the way down,
that you're going to get stuff
that looks like PAC bounds.
But this looks really similar to the PAC
bound for agnostic learning right?
>> Hmm.
>> There was a 1 over epsilon squared,
and a natural log of delta in there,
1 over delta or something in there.
>> Yeah, and it uses a union bound too.
It uses the union bound and the huffting
bound, just like we just did.
But I mean, it's not exactly
the same thing, but you're right.
It has a very similar flavor.
>> I look at this and I just think,
one of these looks a lot like
this says something about hypothesis
space, and the other is about the error.
It just feels like there's
a connection there.
>> Hm, that there's a sense
in which you can think about
the payoffs of the arms as hypotheses,
in some sense.
Or each arm is a hypothesis.
That we want to find
the best hypothesis,
it's like finding the best arm.
It has the lowest error, or
the lowest suboptimality.
Yeah, maybe, maybe.
Other than using one kind of math to
solve the other kind of problem, I don't
quite see what leverage we get from
that, but that's a good observation.
>> Well, in that case,
k is the hypothesis.
This is the size of
the hypothesis space.
>> Yes, like the number r is, exactly.
>> Right, it just seems like
there's something there.
I don't know, I'm sure that if we
thought about it long enough or
gave someone a homework problem,
they'd be able to connect the two.
>> [LAUGH] So just to sum up here,
what we've been figuring out is a kind
of PAC-style bound for
these kinds of bandit problems.
That we want to say we can get near
optimal payoff after a polynomial number
of pulls, or we can get a near optimal
arm after a polynomial number of pulls,
or we can make only a polynomial
number of mistakes in an infinite run.
That all these things actually all
boil down to essentially this result.
We just have to pull each arm enough
times that we have an accurate estimate.
>> That's pretty good.
Well, PAC-style is better than
either monkey style or cream style.
[NOISE]
>> Well, monkey style is quite good, hm.
>> I'm impressed with your PAC-style.
>> [LAUGH]