Okay, welcome back to computer vision.
Now this is going to be our third lesson having to do with essentially how
intensity and shape, and light interact with one another.
In the first one,
we talked about the physics, in terms of how how that interaction works.
In the second one, we talked about, what if you want to try to recover something
about the surface properties of the object, you know, the reflectance function.
Basically, you have to make some assumptions about the shape, or, or
the illumination.
Well, today we're going to turn around the other way and
we're going to say, well, how can I recover something about the shape of
the object based upon what I'm seeing.