So then the question arises, what makes a good kernel?
Well obviously a very successful major.
That was joke.
So let's consider a uniform filter.
Did you get that one Megan?
Yes, you got it, good.
All right, so you remember the averaging filter?
Right, so the averaging filter was just this box filter of all one-ninths.
And as we moved it around, we took this image on the left and
we created this image on the right, all right?
So the question actually arises.
What if I had some image like this, and I apply that box filter.
What would I get?
Well, I would get this, and that is known as really, really ugly.
Okay, that does least not to me, as a nice smooth version of the original.
Now if you're looking at an itty-bitty monitor, it might look nice.
But trust me it's really ugly.
And the question is, what went wrong?
Well, really what went wrong is squares are not smooth.
Which is probably a statement from the 60s, but it's, it's what I mean.
Basically filtering with something that's not smooth to try to think about
blurring or filtering an image to make it smoother doesn't seem right.
And in fact we’ll be able to say a lot more about what smooth means in terms of
mathematics in a few more lectures when we talk about [INAUDIBLE] analysis.
You know, so what was the problem?
To get sense of what’s wrong, imagine that you had a single point of
light that you’re looking at very far away, right?
And you’ve blurred the camera, so it was out of focus.
What would the image look like?
Well, it would look something like that.
Okay?
Brighter in the middle, falling off towards blackness at the edges.
Very, very deep.
All right.
And in fact, if we think of images as functions, I could take this image, and
I could plot it as this function.
If I've taught at that blurry spot, what kind of function would I get?
Well it would look something like here on the right.