I decided to write three functions.
One to group the records by account_key.
One to sum up all the entries for
each account_key.
And one to print out summary statistics
like the mean and standard deviation.
I named my function group_data.
And I decided to make it take
the data as an argument, and
return the dictionary mapping
account keys to lists of records.
Now I could have left the function
like this, and made it always group
by account key, but I wanted to
leave some flexibility there.
So I added an extra argument
key name which would
indicate the key to group by.
Then I indented the code
I had previously, so
it would be part of the function.
And I changed the variable I was
looping over to be the input data.
I also changed the field
name I was grouping by,
to be the input key_name
rather than account_key.
Then I changed each of the variable
names to be suitably generic.
And finally return to the grouped data.
Finally, I called this function
to create the same engagement by
account dictionary
that I had previously.
Now the calculation I asked you
to do for a number of lessons,
will use this same engagement
by account dictionary, so
it actually wasn't necessary to
write this function just yet.
But I liked the idea of writing it,
because this felt like a clean
interface for our function.
It takes in some data and
it groups it by some key name.
Later, you'll see that the library
pandas has some function that works
pretty similarly to this one.
Next, I moved on to the function to sum
up the entries for each account key.
I named my function,
sum_grouped_items and
I had it take as inputs the grouped
data and the field name to sum up.
In this case, the field name
definitely needed to be an argument.
Because I wanted to sum up both
the total minutes visited and
the lessons completed.
Again I indented the code I had
previously to be a part of the function.
Next I changed the dictionary I was
looping over to be the input grouped
data, and I changed the field name I was
summing up to be the input field name.
Again, I updated each of the variable
names to be suitably generic.
And finally I returned the summed data.
Again, I called my function to recreate
the total minutes by account dictionary
that I had created recently.
Next I was ready to write a function to
print summary statistics about the data,
such as the mean and standard deviation.
I named my function,
describe data and I had it take one
argument, the data to describe.
Then I moved all these print
statements within the function, and
I changed the data I was
summarizing to the argument data.
I also moved the import statement
to the top of the cell.
And I called my new function to
describe the total minutes data.
When I re-ran this cell, I got the same
results as before which is good.
Next I was ready to analyze
the lessons completed by account
using the functions I'd just written.
I started with the engagement
data grouped by account.
And then I summed up the number of
lessons completed for each account key.
Then I called the describe
data function and
again, I needed to take the values of my
lessons completed by account dictionary
before passing into
the describe data function.
When I ran this cell,
I saw that the mean number of lessons
completed in the first week
is about one and a half.
With a standard deviation of three.
It makes sense that there would be a lot
of variations, since some students might
complete a lot more lessons in
the first week than others.
The minimum number of lessons competed
is zero, which is not surprising.
I certainly expected there would be
some students who didn’t complete any
lessons in their first week.
And the maximum is 36,
which is quite some.
Now you probably didn't write exactly
the same functions that I did,
and that's fine.
There's a lot of valid ways to do this.
As long as you got the correct answers,
then you're good.