For this next question, I would like
you to do what every machine learning
engineer is doing these days,
image categorization, all right?
So let's image that you have images,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Like that.
These images are HD quality, so
they're 1920 pixels wide and
1080 pixels high.
And say we have,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Three channels, for RGB.
That's red, green, and
blue colors, okay?
[BLANK_AUDIO]
All right, so,
Given an image of whatever,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
You need to classify whether
this is a cat, a dog,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
A human,
Or none of these, right?
This is your overall task.
And somebody has already written
a machine learning algorithm,
implemented it for you.
But it turns out that it's
taking a long time to run.
Your data set has, say,
around a million images.
So that's a lot of data to process.
Can you help speed up
this overall pipeline?
What can you do to improve this?
>> Okay, so
just to better understand the question.
Right now, I have millions of
these pictures, all 920 by 1080,
with three channels.
And I'm feeding them directly
into my machine learning algorithm, and
the performance is slow.
>> It's slow, correct.
>> Okay, so,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
One thing we could do is
to perform a transformation
on this data before we feed it into
the machine learning algorithm.
A transformation that I'm thinking
of may be something like a Fourier
transform, that will look for
frequencies of different color patterns,
which could dramatically reduce
the dimensionality of our data.
>> Okay.
>> And then feed that into
the machine learning algorithm.
And by having a much smaller
feature space that doesn't lose too
much of the information, we might be
able to get a higher performance.
>> Okay.
Do you anticipate any changes in how
accurately the model would perform?
Or the number of errors it would
make if you chose to go that route?
>> Yes, so
by using a Fourier transform, we are,
instead of counting every pixel by
pixel, we're looking for the patterns.
And so we don't see where in
the picture those patterns occurred.
We're just checking to see if
the pattern occurred somewhere
in the picture.
So there is a loss of information
that happens in this transformation.
But by setting up a simple
experiment using both ways,
we can see how the accuracy is affected.
And if it's not too big of a hit,
and the performance gain is really
worthwhile, we might be better off
using some of these transformations.
>> Okay, that's a really good point.
Are they any other ways of
speeding up this process
besides a transformation like
the one you just mentioned?
>> Yeah, so in the actual hardware that
we're using to perform this analysis,
maybe implementing a multi-threaded
parallel processing solution would allow
us to process these images much faster.
>> That's going to be quite
a task if the algorithm is
already not quoted up to
be able to perform that.
Like, some algorithms might be
bottle-necked by some sort of sequential
processes.
But I can see that in some cases you
might be able to parallelize a lot of
the operations.
So what do you think about
the nature of the data?
In this case, you said you might
use dimensionality reduction,
like a Fourier transform.
Are there any other kinds of data where
a transformation like that might not
be applicable or reasonable to use?
Can you think of something like that?
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>> A transform like,
Fourier series works really well on,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
On audio and on video.
Sort of these devices that are capturing
wavelengths and
transferring those into frequencies.
But something that doesn't really
follow a sort of wavelength type,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Something that doesn't come in
the form of expressing wavelengths and
intensities of these wavelengths
would not be a good solution for
a Fourier transform.
So something like user input from
a survey, a Fourier transform
would not be an optimal solution,
because it would be
cutting out a lot of the user behavior
which doesn't operate on a wavelength.
>> That's a very good point.
Yeah, it's very important to realize
that some dimensional reduction
techniques only can be applied
in certain situations.
So that's a very good answer.
>> Thank you.