One of the necessary prerequisites for
setting a network request is that your
app must create a network connection
over which to send the request.
Now, when you create an app on Android,
by default,
it doesn't have access to the Internet.
Let me show you what I mean by using
the Tsunami app that we created for
this lesson.
Now, this app is supposed
to perform an HTTP request,
to retrieve earthquake information.
Instead the app crashes.
If we check the Android logs
we see a security exception
saying that there's a missing
Internet permission.
The tsunami app has not asked for
permission to access the Internet, so
the Android operating system denies
tsunami's attempt to make an HTTP
request.
The result is that the app crashes.
Your app needs to ask permission
to perform protected actions on
a user's device.
Protected actions include
creating a network connection,
accessing the camera, setting an SMS
message, calling a phone number,
recording audio from the microphone, or
even determining the user's location.
There also permissions to be informed of
certain changes in the device's state,
such as network connectivity status.
For the full list of possible
formations your app can ask for,
you can check out
the intro documentation.
You may be wondering, why do I need
a permission if I can just send
an intent to the camera app
to take a picture for me or
send an intent to send an SMS message,
or dial a phone number?
The power or intense is that you can
request a different action to perform
an action on your behalf without needing
to declare the permission yourself.
However, if you're building a custom
camera app, for example, then you must
request the camera's permission to
get direct access to the hardware.
For each permission you'd
like to request, you want to
add a uses permission element to
the Android manifest file in the app.
For example, if you create a messaging
app and want users to be able to send
SMS message directly within your app,
then you declare the app requires
the send SMS permission string
in the Android manifest.
There must be a users permission
line in your manifest for
each permission your
application requires.
Application permissions have
different protection levels.
The two most important levels for
you to know are normal and dangerous.
Normal permissions have little
risk to the users privacy or
the operation of other apps.
So the system will approve
the permissions automatically.
Dangerous permissions get access to
the users personally identifiable or
private information but
also they cover functions that could
affect how other apps operate.
This include using the camera, accessing
contacts or the phone call log, or
recording audio with the microphone.
These permissions must be
requested at run time and
the user must explicitly grant
them through a system dialogue.
The dialogue will look like this.
This app is requesting permission
to access the user's contacts.
Once the user accepts the permission,
the dialogue won't pop up anymore.
Know if the user denies permission,
the apps should still continue to
operate as normal but
without that feature.
Note that the run time permission model
was only introduced with the Android 6.0
Marshmallow release and applies to
any devices more recent than that.
For example, in the Instagram app
the user will be prompted to plenty of
access to the photos and media files on
the device directly when trying to push
the photo from the gallery.
However, on Android devices
running Android 5.1 or older,
the user is prompted to accept all
formations when they install the app.
If you use an older Android device,
you may have seen this screen before.
Now, the old model is all or nothing.
The user must accept all
the requested permissions or
the app can't be installed.
With runtime permissions,
the user can be selective about what
permissions are granted to the app.
And the developer must be able to
react to having permission revoked.
There's a useful article on best
practices when it comes to permissions.
Generally, you should strive to
define as few permissions as possible
while satisfying your app's needs.
For example,
consider using an intent instead.
And then, apps that ask for
a lot of unnecessary permissions
may appear suspicious to users and
then consequently won't
get installed as often.
So don't overwhelm the user.
We won't be using dangerous permissions
in this course, but if you do,
be sure to sufficiently explain why
you need the permission to the user.
In this quiz,
answer the following questions.
Do you need to declare
permission in order to read and
write events on the user's calendar?
How about to play audio or
video on the device?
Or how about to access
the user's current location, or
lastly, how about to show
a notification on the device?
You can check the documentation
links below the quiz to help you.