Awesome, now the intents
are working on our app.
However one issue I do see is,
that the numbers activity we opened,
still says Miwok at the top.
I want to change the title of
this activity to say numbers.
And for the other activities that we
open, they should also say colors,
phrases, and
family members respectively.
I mentioned earlier that we're going to
come back to the Android manifest.xml
file and now, is that time.
To change the title of
the numbers activity,
only to modify the Android
manifest .xml file.
There is a way to modify
the activity name, but
I forget the exact syntax,
so let's look that up.
I'll do a web search for
Android manifests activity tag and
this first result looks good.
In the navigation pane on
the left hand side of the screen,
we're looking at the activity
tag under the app manifest.
So, we are in the right place.
On the right hand side of the screen,
we can see some possible attribute names
related to the name of the activity.
Use the keyboard shortcut command F or
control f on Windows to
pop up the find menu.
Then type name.
Looking closely at the name
attribute description,
it seems like name is the name
of the activity java file.
Scrolling through
the attributes some more,
I think the one we're trying to look for
is called label.
So, let's take a look
at that attribute and
sure enough, it says that the label
is what's displayed to the user.
Oka,y so
going back to our Android manifest .XML,
we'll find the activity tag
related to the numbers activity.
Then, will add an extra attribute called
Android label and the value will be
the text that we want to show in
the app bar for this activity.
Which is numbers.
If we refer back to our
mental model of the app,
this string was actually already
declared in the strings.XML file.