Here's an example of what SIFT would do, where basically we're looking for
different types of features.
Here is a car, again, in a completely different location, a different image.
And if you look at it, it found this region, which looks like this,
which is again found again with the rotation of the image and
viewpoint scale and everything here.
Similarly, you can see that these are the five features it found in this one,
and they were matchable in both of them.
So, in essence, this allows us to look for features,
even with a lot of different transformations, of translation rotation scale and
other imaging parameters.
And again, if I find this, I can match them across the two images.