You may remember from CS101 that
any comparison based algorithm for
sorting scales like this.
That is in the sequential case.
And in fact, you can't go any faster,
asymptotically,
if your only primitive
is a simple comparison.
[SOUND] But that's not the only
tool in your sorting toolbelt.
For instance,
in CS101 you might have learned
about algorithms like Bucket sort.
Me hunter, not gatherer.
Bucket sort can achieve linear
time if you set it up just right.
Here's the basic idea.
Start by assuming that you know
the range of possible values.
So these might be integers from,
say, 0 to m minus 1.
Further assume that the values
you want to sort are uniformly
distributed over this range.
You would then start by dividing the
possible values into a bunch of bins or
buckets.
Each bucket will hold a subset
of the possible values.
For instance, this first bucket will
hold the first m over k values,
assuming that k divides m.
The second bucket will hold the second
set of M over K values, and so on.
Now suppose we have some values to sort.
A bucket sort first figures out to
which bucket each element belongs.
So for instance,
maybe it turns out the three smallest
elements belong in the red bucket.
And you'd do the same for
all the other colors.
The last step is to sort within each
bucket and then concatenate the results.
So how is this a linear time scheme?
Start by asking yourself how many
elements are in each bucket.
Now suppose there are n elements and
they really are uniformly and
randomly distributed over this range.
Then the expected number of elements
per bucket will be n over k.
Now, there's a constant
which I've hidden.
Now within each bucket, you can use
your favorite sorting algorithm.
Tiny bubbles.
Something, something.
Let's supposed you use an asymptotically
optimal comparison based sort.
Then the expected run time would be
n over k log n over k in each bucket.
Since there are k buckets,
you just multiply the time
to sort each bucket by k.
So, if you can choose k to
be some constant times n,
then you get a linear time sort.
Now there's one more minor, technical
detail here about the choice of k, but
for that, see the downloadable section.