All right, so for the first question,
here's the code used to instantiate
an ArrayList object
called restaurantsToTry.
And we specify that we only want it
to contain elements of type String.
And remember that in creating
a new ArrayList object,
you don't need to specify
the length of the list.
For the next comment,
that asks us add a restaurant called
Morning Cafe to the ArrayList.
Here's the code for that.
So we have restaurantsToTry.add and it
takes in Morning Cafe as the parameter.
So visually this is what it looks like.
By using the .add method, we've added
Morning Cafe at the zeroth index of
the restaurantsToTry array list.
So, for the third comment,
that asks us to add another restaurant
called BBQ Time to the array list.
Here's the code, it looks very similar.
We have restaurantsToTry.add and
it takes in the input BBQ Heaven.
And here's what that looks
like again visually.
So, here's the code, and
using the .add method we'd add BBQ Time
at the first index of the array list.
Now for the fourth comment,
the user's tried Morning Cafe and
we want to remove that
from the array list now.
So we have restaurantsToTry.remove and
it takes in Morning Cafe as the input.
So using the .remove method, we removed
Morning Cafe from the zeroth index,
and then BBQ Time moved
up to the first index.
Now for the fifth comment it asks us
to get the length of the list and
store it as an integer variable
called numberOfRestaurants.
And the code for this is int,
followed by numberOfRestaurants,
which is our integer variable.
And in it we assign
the restaurantsToTry.size and
it does not take in anything
as the input parameter.