Okay, again, C might be true, but it's false.
No, C is true, but you get no credit.
The answer is true, in this case, because it's division by a constant.
All right, so in this case, if I'm dividing by Z, so if I sum up X plus
Y divided by the Z, it's the same thing as X divided by Z plus Y divided by Z.
Much later we're going to be doing perspective projection, and you're going to
end up having to normalize the X and Y values, by the Z value of a point.
And then the Z is actually going to be a component of the element.
And since that component can change, that's not going to be a linear operation.
But in general, division is a fine linear operation because the last time I
checked, dividing by two is the same as multiplying by point five, and
multiplication is a part of the linear operation.