Finally, two more surveillance is a huge issue.
This ideas of being able to monitor environment for
crowd safety, a variety of reasons.
These are screenshots taken from Siemens sells a system for
doing port monitoring.
Just to know whether, say, people are loitering, or
vehicles are approaching that aren't supposed to be.
This is also a computer vision.
A more direct effect on a single individual with computer vision is work in
medical imagining.
Okay, so here you see an example.
There's all sorts of 3D imaging, MRI, CAT scan,
stuff like that, but here you see some work.
This came out of Eric Grimson's lab a while ago at MIT where on a screen,
a the computer vision system is registering the skull
that's on the table with a model that has been created from the 3D imaging.
So while, when the surgeon looks at this monitor, he sees the real person, and
by the way, if there were a scalpel here, he'd see the hand with the scalpel or
drill or whatever you're using to make a hole in the person's head.
And where the various structures are underneath that you wanted to see, and
that's also computer vision.
Look, this is just a quick taste of the state of the art,
hopefully, it inspires you.
One of the things I want you to realize is that
almost everything that I showed you here is less than ten years only, and
in fact, many of them are less than five years old.
So the field is rapidly changing, and
there's a tremendous amount of opportunity in computer vision right now, so
this is exactly the right time for you to take this class.
So that you can invent some cool technology.
Make, $3 gazillion and
send a very large donation to the people who made it possible.