Suppose you wish to multiply
a dense n by n matrix by a vector.
Recall that the work,
ignoring any structure in A,
is proportional to n squared.
Now suppose the matrix is
stored in column major order.
Column major order means that
the elements of the matrix are laid out
in memory column wise.
That is elements have consecutive
addresses within a column
with one column following
the previous column.
In other words,
viewing A as a 1-D array,
the IJ element is indexed
as I + J times N.
Now consider two algorithms to
compute a matrix vector product.
Here is algorithm one.
Rows are indexed by me and columns by j.
In algorithm one, the outer most
loop iterates over rows and
the inner most loop
iterates over columns.
Take a moment to make sure you
understand the iteration structure.
Algorithm two does just the opposite.
The outer loop iterates over columns and
the inner loop iterates over rows.
In the basic ram model,
these algorithms are identical.
Here's my question.
In our IO model,
which one does fewer transfers?
Is it the one with i as the outer most
loop and j as the inner most loop?
That is outer most rows,
inner most columns.
Or is it the one that does the opposite?
That is, outer most loop over columns
and inner most loop over rows.
To help you answer this question let me
give you a few simplifying assumptions.
First, assume that the fast memory
is large enough to hold two vectors.
You can also assume it has a little bit
more space to store a few extra blocks
of size L.
Secondly, you can assume
that L divides n.
Lastly, let's assume all the arrays, and
matrices are aligned
on L word boundaries.
These last two assumptions essentially
avoid the data alignment issues, so
you can ignore floors and ceilings.
One last hint.
From these assumptions, you might
as well assume that the algorithm
preloads x and y at the very beginning,
and stores y at the very end.
What does that, in turn, imply?
Well, the number of transfers
will be at least 3n over L.
In other words, the real question is,
how many additional transfers
does loading the matrix require?