So there's a cool way of thinking about image reprojection,
sort of a natural geometry.
The first is, think about take one picture, another picture, another picture and
you'll see here that all of these pictures were taken by rotating my camera.
And I've drawn it as if my camera's center projection was perfectly aligned.
Of course it's never perfectly, but pretty close.
Although you can buy little tripods that make it
easy to rotate the camera right above the focal point of the lens.
In fact, if if some of you have a really good camera it'll show you where
the film plane, or the sensor plane of of of the camera is.
And then if you know the focal length of your camera, of your lens, sorry, you.
Let's suppose it's a 50 millimeter lens, you would measure 50 millimeters from
that point, and you know that's the focal point of my lens.
And you could set your tripod up so that the axis of rotation is
right underneath that, and that's how you'd actually do that rotation.
So anyway, so
we show here that we have three images taken from three different orientations.
Then, what we want is, we're going to project all of
these images onto some single mosaic projective plane.
All right?
So here we're showing projecting image one, projecting image two, and
projecting image three.
All right?
And you're, so the idea is that you're projecting everything down
onto a common plane.
And of course, there is some overlap.
Which is actually a good thing,
because in order to figure this out you're going to need overlap.
But of course you're also going to have to figure out a) how to
transform these images, and b) how to blend them.
So this is way of thinking of mosaics is that these are images that
are reprojected on a common plane, and the mosaic is formed on that plane.
Before we go further, this only works for sort of a limited field of view.
But you might be thinking to yourself, wait a minute,
can't I take pictures all day?
Spinning around on my tripod,
now you get to see how much hair I don't have on the back of my head.
I know you've always wondered about this.
Anyway, it feels like you should be able to paste together pictures going all
the way around.
And you can.
And in fact Photoshop and even little cameras that you buy do this for you.
They're not actually projecting it onto a plane.
They're projecting it onto some other surface like a cylinder.
And then you unwrap the cylinder.
And you get a panorama.
It turns out that's not actually a real picture.
It's sort of a, I mean it's a real picture, it's made up,
but, but it's not a particular scene.
Whereas when you do a panorama onto a plane,
it's as if you had a super wide field of view camera.
So it's, it's two different kinds of things.
But in the,
in the, when you do the really wide ones it maps it on to a cylinder.
So, how are we going to do this, all right?
So here's an example.
Again, courtesy of Steve Sikes.
So what we're going to do is, we're going to take these multiple pictures.
These are from the Great Wall of China.
Thank you Steve.
And, you know, what's drawn here is this idea that we've taken all of
these pictures from the same center of projection.
So, how do we do this?
Well, as we talked about before, the projection between two planes,
shown here as, P prime equals H P, is just a homography.
Remember that from last time?
A homography that allows us to map from one plane to the next.
In fact, a little bit later I'm going to show you a,
a nice little proof that says a mapping,
a projective mapping between any two planes can be represented as a homography.
But here we've represented it as just H going from one set of points to another.