Hi.
Welcome to the Introduction to Computer Vision.
I'm Professor Aaron Bobick here at Georgia Tech.
I'm thrilled to be able to teach this course in this medium.
I've been teaching this for quite a while.
I've been a professor for, oh my gosh, almost 25 years in computer vision.
Spent some time at the MIT Media Lab, and
I've been at Georgia Tech for the last 15 years.
My own research has been predominantly in activity recognition.
And now it's moved a little more to robotics in terms of vision for
robots understanding people.
But the basics of this course is,
is to cover sort of the fundamentals of computer vision,
to give you a background enough that you could just enough to be dangerous.
So before we tell you more about the course, it's important that you meet
a couple of other people who are responsible for the success of this course.
And it will be a success or I'll be really, really annoyed and, and then people,
see everybody's going to see this and they'll think really poorly of me.
Anyway, the first person you have to meet is probably the most important person
in making this a success, no pressure, is Dr.
Arpin Chuckarvarde who is our course developer.
Come on over, Arpin.
So tell the good folks at home or
sitting at their desks at work a little something about yourself.
>> Sure I got my PhD from North Carolina State University in
biologically inspired computer vision.
>> What is, what is that?
>> Oh you take human vision systems and animal vision systems.
Study them, how they function and use those ideas in an artificial setting.
>> Cool.
And what made you want to do this course development work.
Well I heard that Udacity is making this
online computer vision course with Georgia Tech and I thought,
this is a good way to use the knowledge I've put together over the years.
>> Okay, great, well thanks, and
you guys will be hearing more from Arpin as the time goes on.
So the other really important person you have to meet is Megan Smith.
Megan is our video guru.
She is the film person, the editing person, the production person.
She makes my hair look non-existent and yeah, just makes everything look great.
She also allows me to illustrate the difference between the illusion of
power and actual power.
See, the illusion of power is I can call Megan over and
she'll probably come over and say hello.
Megan, come on over and say hello.
Say hello to everybody.
>> Hello. >> The reason I say that that's the illusion of power.
The person who has the real power is Megan because she does the video editing.
So, if she wanted to, she could make me look incredibly foolish.
But, you would never do that, would you?
[SOUND].
Never.
>> Uh-huh.
Okay, well you'll be hearing from her sometimes when we ask some questions and
she makes some interesting noises in the background.
But I just wanted you to put a,
a face with the beautiful melodic voice that you'll be hearing later.
So thanks, Megan.
All right, so that's the crew.
And I think this is going to be a good time.
I mean it's maybe, maybe, okay.
Maybe that's a little bit much.
I think you'll enjoy the class.
There is a lot to be learned.
We can't actually cover all of computer vision, but
we can sort of go over a whole bunch of the fundamentals and
I think you'll learn a lot if you actually do the work.
And it is a bunch of work, I don't want to, I don't want to pretend otherwise.
But if you do it I think you'll come away with the ability to do
things that you couldn't do before.