So far all the features of the app have
been contained in a single screen on
a single activity.
Splitting up information based
on the action your users want to
do makes your app easy for you to code
and for your users to understand.
As we saw just a little while ago, when
an item is clicked in the Sunshine app,
the app shows a new activity
with the weather data.
So how do we start one
activity form another?
Well, instead of having an activity
call each other directly,
Android facilitates communication using
messaging objects called intents.
Intents let an app request
that an action take place.
That can be anything from starting
a new activity to picking or
displaying a photo from your phone
gallery, or making a phone call.
So why are we using intents rather than
just passing in the class name directly?
Well, intents are a little
more complicated than that.
I like to think of them as envelopes.
Each one includes who, or in this case
which, component you want to deliver to.
There's even room for
a small amount of data to be delivered,
packaged as extras which
are primitive topples.
That can be read by the application
component that ultimately receives and
opens the intent.
So using this metaphor,
an explicit intent uses the name
of the target component