Now let's consider games like chess and checkers,
which we define as deterministic, two-player, zero-sum games.
The deterministic part is clear.
The rules of chess say you make a move, take a piece, and that's it. There's no stochasticity.
It's two players, one against another,
and zero sum means that the sum of the utilities to the two players is zero.
If one player gets a +1 for winning the game, the other player gets a -1 for losing.
How do we deal with these types of games?
Well, we use a similar type of approach.
We have a state-space search. We have a starting state.
There are some moves available to player one.
Then in the next state there are moves available to player two.
We're going to draw them like this, and we're going to give names to our players.
The first player we're going to call Max, because it's a nice name,
and because player one is trying to maximize the utility to player one.
The next player, who operates at this level, we draw with a downward-pointing triangle.
We call that player Min, because Min is trying to minimize the utility to Max,
which is the same thing as trying to maximize the utility to himself or herself.
Then we have a game tree that continues like that, alternating between Max and Min moves.
Now, the search tree keeps going and let's say we get to a point where one player,
and let's say it's Max, has a choice, and there are two states,
and these, rather than being states where it's Min's turn, are states that are terminal.
We'll draw them with a square box.
Let's say one of them results in +1, a win for Max,
and one of them results in -1, a loss for Max.
Now if Max is rational, of course, Max is going to make this choice to the +1.
What we're going to do now is show we can determine the value of any state in the tree,
including the start state up here in terms of the values of the terminal nodes.
The tree keeps on going. We assume it's a finite game.
After a finite number of moves, every path leads to a terminal state.
Then we look at each state and say whose turn is it to make the decision.
In this state Max is making the decision, and Max, being rational,
will choose the maximum value, saying, "I'd rather have a +1 than a -1,
so I'll get a +1 here."
We start going back up the tree, and maybe we get up to a point here
where Min has a choice, and we've used this type of process to go up the tree,
and Min has a choice between a +1 and a -1.
Min is going to choose the minimum and will have a -1 here.
If we go through all the possibilities, let's say these all result in -1,
but this move results in a +1. Then Max will take that move.
He'll say, "Out of my four possibilities, I know this is the best one. I'll take that move."
Now we've done two things.
One, we've assigned a value to every state in the search tree,
and secondly, we backed that all the way up the top.
Now we've worked out a path through that state to say,
if all players are rational, here's the choices they would make.
The important point here is that we've taken the utility function,
which is defined only on terminal states.
Here's a state here. The utility of that state was +1.
Here's a state here. The utility of that state was -1.
We've used those utility values in the definition of available actions
to back those utilities up and tell us the utility of every state, including the start state.