[Thrun] The answer is a little bit involved.
We use total probability to re-express this by bringing in A.
P of X3 given X1 is the sum of P of X3 given X1 and A
times P of A given X1 plus the A complement, which is X3, conditional X1 and not A
times P of not A given X1.
That is just total probability.
Next we utilized conditional independence by which we can simplify this expression
to drop X1 in the conditional variables
and we transform this expression by Bayes' rule again.
The same applies to the right side with not A replacing A.
All of those expressions over here can be found
either in the table up there or just by their complements,
with the exception of P of X1.
But P of X1 can again be just obtained by total probability,
which resolves to 0.2 times 0.5 plus 0.6 times 0.5,
which gives me 0.4.
We are now in a position to calculate the last term over here, which goes as follows.
This expression is 0.2 times 0.2 times 0.5 over 0.4 plus 0.6 times 0.6 times 0.5 over 0.4,
which gives us as a final result 0.5.