Analytics, and
the results from our analyses,
are only as good as the data
that you have to work with.
But not all the data that you have
available to you is easy to use.
Data could come from many sources,
there's transactional data,
like what's recorded at
the supermarket for every purchase.
Data captured from devices we use,
like our TV, cable boxes, or
cellphones, and collected data like
weather, census, or flight data.
As you work with data to
solve analytical problems,
your challenge will be to think about
how you can use all the data available
to you to make your analyses as rich and
powerful as possible.
But now you might be thinking, how can
I integrate social media reviews or
survey results into my analysis if
it's just a big paragraph of words?
How could I make sense of
the chaos in the data?
To the answer these questions,
we need to first understand
the structure of data.
Data falls into one of three categories,
structured,
unstructured or semi-structured.
Coming up, we'll look a little
further into each of these
three ways that data is structured.