You've built the user interface and
imported the class extension for the
Play Sounds View Controller. We're on
the final step to get Pitch Perfect to
playback audio. Let me walk you through
what you need to set this up. If you
think back to earlier of this lesson, we
wired up all six sound effect buttons to
the playSoundForButton function.
What we need now is a way to distinguish
between those buttons and then call the
appropriate function in our extension to
play the sound effect. There are several
ways to distinguish one UIButton from another,
but the easiest is using the Tag
property of the button. If you select any
of the buttons in the Play Sounds View
Controller and go to the attributes
inspector, you can scroll down and find
its Tag property.
This property is just an integer value
that we can assign to each button and
then we can use it later to identify the
button that's pressed for the
playSoundForButton function. By default the
Tag value for any button is set to 0.
Because we haven't changed any Tag
values up to this point, all of our UIButtons
have zero as their tag value.
It's time to change that. The slow
playback button, the button with the
snail icon on it is our first button.
So it can have a tag of zero, but for the
other buttons, we should change their tag values.
So for the fast playback button
with the rabbit icon, lets set its tag
to 1. For the high pitched chipmunk button,
lets set its tag to 2.
For the low pitch Darth Vader button 3.
For the echo button 4, and finally for the
Reverb button, lets set its tag to 5.
Great now we have different tag values for
each playback button, from 0 to 5.
The next step is to change the
playSoundForButton function, so that it
does a different audio playback
depending on what button was pressed.
Let's go back to that function in the
PlaySoundsViewController.swift file.
Remember the enumeration you added
earlier called ButtonType? it has values
called slow, fast, chipmunk, vader, echo
and reverb. And each of these values,
starting with slow, map to an integer value.
Slow is equal to 0, fast is equal to 1,
and this pattern continues all the way
to reverb which is 5. This enumeration
gives us the ability to map the tag
values we just said in the storyboard to
an enumeration value. And then we can use
the enumeration value with a switch
statement to call the playSound
function differently for each of the
buttons. Add the following code to the
playSoundForButton function, so that
it appears as you see here. This code
contained within the switch statement is
what converts the button’s tag to a
ButtonType. Then using the ButtonType,
we can play a sound appropriately. So for
the slow and fast buttons, when they are
pressed, we’ll play the sound at a
different rate. If the low or high pitch
buttons are selected aka the chipmunk
or vader buttons, then we’ll alter the
pitch. And if the echo or reverb buttons
are pressed, then we'll pass those
settings onwards to the playSound
function. Now while playing audio is
great, it would be nice if we could stop
the playback when we want to. We already
have a stop button, and it's already
wired up to call the stopButtonPressed
function in our PlaySoundsViewController.
All we need to do is add a
call to the stopAudio function that is
in the class extension and it will do
the work of calling out
the AVAudioEngine to stop the playback.
If you follow along to this point, we
should be able to test the Pitch Perfect app.
You should be able to record
yourself and hear the playback with a
variety of sound effects.
Let's try it. “Swift is great”
“Swift is great” “Swift is great”
“Swift is great”
Wow that's pretty cool, in a very short
amount of time you got Pitch Perfect
built from the ground up, a fun iOS app
that can record and playback audio with
different sound effects. If you're
curious about the calls to AVAudioEngine,
I’m going to go over that next.
For now,
pat yourself on the back, you're already
an iOS developer.