Perhaps you have some experience
with minimax alpha-beta and
probabilistic games already.
Let's try a quiz to help you
gauge your knowledge and
give a preview of what
we'll be learning.
Before I teach each section, I will
use the starting quizzes to emphasize
the knowledge and
skills I'd like you to learn.
Here's an expected max game tree.
Maximizing nodes are indicated
by upwards facing triangles.
Minimizing nodes are downward
facing triangles and
probabilistic nodes
are circles with a chance of
each outcome labeled on
the branches below it.
The values of the game board nodes
can range from -10 to +10 and
the game tree is evaluated
from left to right.
Mark which branches do
not need to be visited
by the alpha beta algorithm to calculate
the value of the optimal choice.
Don't worry if you feel lost
trying to answer this question.
By the end of this segment you will
understand this question and its answer.
If you already understand this question
and its answer, congratulations.
This section will be an easier one for
you.
But perhaps I can bring a different
perspective to the material than you
have heard before.
Try the quizzes anyways
to test your knowledge.