This is a question about logic.
We have four different statements.
Pink is True,
Pink or Green is True,
Pink and Green is True,
and not Pink implies that Green is True.
Now these statements could imply each other,
and in this matrix over here,
I'd like you to select each circle
where an implication is necessarily true. It's always true. For example,
if you believe that Pink implies
that Pink or Green is True,
then mark the A implies B circle, over here.
If you believe the Pink is True implies
Pink and Green must be True,
then mark the circle A implies C, over here.
And so on for the entire matrix.
One hint, D looks complex,
but it happens to be the same as one of the previous cases.
So if you fill out the matrix for A to C first,
and then copy the result over for D,
it will be easier, than if you start thinking about D separately.
And to find the equivalency of D,
just write down the Truth Table of these different things over here,
and observe D is already represented among A to C.