Now let us see how we can handle the case where your input data rate is
greater than the processing rate.
That assuming we are getting 10,000 tweets per second,
we can develop them into small four packets.
Which is, each one is doing 2,500 tweets per second.
And literal Java/Python backend do only 2,500 seconds.
So which means, what we have essentially done is
you're duplicated whatever you are doing with one data stream.
By dividing the data stream into four streams.
And running the same your Java/Python Backend program.
And this is simply know what everybody calls a sharding rate.
So essentially you're kind of divided input into multiple streams.
And you, each of the same instances of the program is working on
the different streams.
So if anybody gets the URL they will know that these are the three
URLs everybody has to look for and each one will have a localized count.
Somehow.
Right?
Now the web app that you wrote initially,
now it has to go to all the guys in order to collect our global count.
Because each one will lower count on nytimes.com.
Because the tweet that is containing the nytimes.com might come here, or
might come there, might come there too.
It can be in any of those streams, right?
So similarly the nytimes.com might occur there as well too.
So now, if you wanted to make it such a way
that the New York Times start count comes into only one guy.
Rather than the web app going to several guys,
think about the fact that you need to do like 10,000 of these.
So then web app has to branch out 10,000 guys and get it, right?
And you don't know whether they're going to be alive or not too, right?
So you get into all these other complex issues.
So inside a sim dad, like, if you want to get the New York Times account at one
single place, what do you do?
So which means like, we need to do another level of some kind of,
Java Python backend.
And we have to route the data that this,
this guide is producing, on account he's producing.
Especially with respect to some news articles,
like newyorktimes.com, to one guy.
So that, if everybody is routing thenewyorktimes.com URL to one guy,
that one guy can accommodate the count appropriately.
Right?
So that is what what we call as some kind of moving data
based on some groupings, or some kind of positioning strategies.
And so you'll go into those groupings and packaging strategies more detail.
And this is kind of a,
what do you call, a basis for most of our big data processing.
Sharding and partitioning So if you
understand these two concepts most of the beginner later the infer or
the infrastructures are all based on these two concepts.
So, if, so in this case if if all the accounts that we just seen.
And periodically for
descending deleted on the NewYorkTimes.com to one of these guys.
Then this guy will have all the cones for NewYorkTimes.com, right?
So in reality, what happens is like they have this notion of queues and
that's how it works.
Each of those process also have this notion of queues.
And once this data stream is processed across each one of them
they dump into the queue of the other process which is responsible for that.
Newyorktimes.com or USAtoday.com or.
So that variant of using queues is the fact that this guy can go at
it's one speed, as long as there is enough buffering inside.
So that as long as you're keeping up with the rate of the processing and
not letting the buffer go beyond certain limit.
As long as you can do that both of the processes can go at a different speed.
Now, what are the problems that it represents?
First of all, scaling is painful.
So, think about the fact that I ought to start these end process on n
different missions.
And if we have a multi stage like the way at least two stages in this case.
And there are other jobs that will require eight stages, nine stages in all.
Think about managing that processes on these different stages across different,
hundreds and thousands of machines.
It gets really painful, because what happens if one guys dies?
And I don't know what the guy died, or
whom died, and how to relocate that to another machine.
So these are all, all kind of operational problems,
which is nightmare to handle any of, in any way.
So on poor fault tolerance, like worker failures, or
even process failures, and mission failures and relocating them.
And third one is coding is very tedious.
I mean think about writing your own Java program,
and for two different stages, on hooking them up together in certain fashion.
Then and making sure the data is moving to the right processes and all, right?
So it makes it tedious to write all these things again and again.
Especially for every job that you have to do, right?
Because there could be a lot of analytic job that you'll keep running.
And finally like there's no guarantees in terms of whether what do you call,
whether the message that I sent out from one stage to another.
Is it lost?
Or has got, again, replayed.
Or it's post-processed.
So you don't have any idea but
there are, reasonable you get results in a clean, cleaner way.
So what I meant is, there are two different kind of guarantees.
Engine build realtime system tend to provide.
But this hard oscillation will not provide that.
So one of the first one is at most once.
And another one was call at least once.
And finally, there's call exactly once.
So at most once, what it does is,
your data, the realtime data is guaranteed to either processed or not.
So at most once is up to, only once it can be processed and
at least once, your data is always guaranteed to be processed at least once.
But there are instances where it could be processed multiple times.
And exactly once is to ensure that your data is processed only once.
And exactly once will give you very exact result.
This end's like the other two will have approximation.
The second one, at least to once will have a word, probably word counting or
averaging or whatever might be the case.
But at most once will give, kind of a low,
an approximation from the point of if you do an undercount.
If your count is aggregation that you are doing.
Okay, so that is the broader discussion, definitely.
I can go into those details, I mean, major details,
but I think that I'll take it to offline.
So if you want we can talk [INAUDIBLE] detail.
>> Sure.
>> But the cost is exactly once is probably a higher cost,
at most once is the least cost, at least once is.
That's is the, some So, that is probably the broadest spectrum.
So what we need in if you really want to do some kind of real time analytics.
Some kind of a guarantees.
Like the one of the guarantees.
Okay, like am I getting at least one.
So that most ones are exactly ones.
I need some kind of guarantees.
So that when you analytics you know what you can do with it, right?
Second one is, scalability of course.
And scalability without having to deal with mission failures and
process failure.
So that you can scale.
Just dump a new set of missions, and automatically the job is,
take those mission if it needs, right?
So, automatically scalable and usually scalable.
And robust fault tolerance.
Whenever any failures occur, automatically it
should the system should relocate some of the jobs automatically.
So that you do not do any [INAUDIBLE].
You won't want to get woken up at 3 a.m in the morning because a pager went
off, right?
And finally you want to do, do a concise code.
You just out write analytics.
You should not be writing about how to route the data from one stage to
another stage.
And going from one mission to another mission and
all these meanings and aspects.
Which is not really related with analytics.
It's more of a, intra or
a more of a plumbing that you learn how to do for every program that you write