One last thing about Matlab.
Matlab is incredibly powerful at
displaying images and plotting.
There's unlimited number
of ways of doing this.
What I would suggest you do is look
at the Matlab im show function,
and in fact as a shows here
you can do im show function.
In fact, as it shows here,
you can do im show of some image and
then if you give it just a range low to
high, what it does is it will display
that image with the value low as black,
or anything less than low, and the value
high, or anything more than high, as
white and it will scale it in between.
Matlab also has different color maps,
different ways of mapping
the value of the function to what
gets displayed on the screen.
Sometimes when you look at the results
and you're not seeing what you expect,
it's because you messed
up the display function.
Your computation was correct,
it was just the display that was wrong.