So it turns out that the previous
algorithm outputs a minimum cut
set with probability
at least 2 / n(n- 1).
Now, at first you might look at this
result and ask, what good is that?
The algorithm doesn't even promise
to be right more often than not.
The trick is that we can call
the algorithm multiple times, and
just take the minimum of these results.
If we do this roughly n squared
times the log of 1/epsilon times,
then there's a 1- epsilon chance that
we will have found the minimum cut set.
The proof for
this corollary is that each call
to the algorithm is independent.
So, the probability that all the calls
failed is given by this expression here.
Then in general,
(1-x) is at most, e to the -x.
So, applying that quantity
to this case here,
we have the n-1 and
the 2 factors cancel.
Leaving us with this expression here,
which then just simplifies
to the quantity epsilon.
So the probability that all
the iterations fail is at most epsilon.
This, down here, by the way,
is extremely useful in analysis, and
is one you should always have
handy in your mental toolbox.
So then,
we have that if this theorem is true,
we can boost it up into an effective
algorithm, just by repeating it.
But why is this theorem true?
Consider a minimum cut set C, and
we'll let Ei be the event that
the edge chosen in the the ith
iteration is not in C.
Note that there could be other
minimum cut sets, as well.
But we're going to focus on just one
of them, which we're going to call C.
Returning the cut set C means not
picking an edge in C in each iteration.
So it's the intersection
of all the events Ei,
which we can turn into this
product as we've done before.
We are just conditioning the probability
of avoiding C in the ith iteration,
given that we have avoided
it in all previous ones.
Actually that quantity will be a little
easier to analyze if we write it
like this.
And I claim that this
is at most n-j-2 / n-j.
We'll warm up just by considering
the probability of E1, that is,
avoiding the cut in the first
iteration as we choose an edge.
Letting k be the size of the cut,
we have that every vertex
must have degree at least k.
Otherwise, the edges incident
on a smaller degree vertex
would be a smaller cut-set.
This then implies that the total
number of edges is at least nk/2.
Every vertex must have degree at least
k and summing up the degrees for
every vertex counts every
edge exactly twice.
Therefore, the probability of avoiding
the cut set in the first iteration Is
1 minus the size of C divided
by the over all number of edges.
This is at least this expression here,
which then simplifies to n-2/n.
The more general argument
will be similar,
given that the first j edge is chosen,
we're not in C.
Then C is still a minimum cut-set for
the current graph.
If not,
then taking the edges in the smaller cut
would also be a smaller cut for
the original graph.
And note throughout, as we count edges
we're always counting the parallel ones.
So again, we can let k be equal
to the size of the set C.
And we have that there have to be
at least k(n- j) / 2 edges left.
The n-j now comes from the fact
that there are only n-j vertices
left after the j iterations.
With the same argument as before, we
have that the probability of avoiding C
in the j+1th iteration, given that
no edges in C has been chosen yet,
is at least n-j-2 / n- j.
Which was what we were trying to show.
Substituting this into
our expression here,
we have that we are down to a 1/3
probability in the last iteration.
2/4 in the iteration before that, etc.
This product telescopes and
leaves us with a bound of 2/
n(n-1), which was what
we were trying to show.
Altogether then,
this extremely simple procedure
has given us a fairly efficient
algorithm for finding a minimum cut set.