Turns out that there are some other rectangular grids,
it's really nice when somebody spray paints the rectangular grid.
Here you're seeing a movie, of a American football play, in fact,
this is a college football play.
But you'll notice they're running around on a plane because to play football,
on bumpy things is hard.
All right?
So since it's a plane, we can rectify that to a different plane.
In particular, what about the plane that you would see if
you were looking sort of overhead?
Okay?
So what we've done is, this is just the same frame, mapped to a different view,
where we've taken these lines which converge and we've made them all parallel.
All right.
Now you'll notice that all the points go to the right place,
except, the players of course, right, they are not on a plane.
Just their feet are on the plane, so
their feet go to the right place, but the players themselves are stretched out,
because the players are not on the plane.
But what we did is we applied the entire homography, the, sorry.
We applied the homography to the entire image, so everything on the football
field went to the right place, the players went to a slightly different place.
But you'll notice, if you look at this, you could see exactly what's going on.
Here you see two videos playing at the same time, one is the play as
observed by the camera, the other one is this rectified thing, a little bit of
shaking is going on here because this was done all automatically.
And by the way, this is like one of the few results I'll show you
that was actually done by a student of mine.
When we were doing that interpreting American football plays, and
this way just a pre processing step.
But the, we're able to recover the projection.
So if you need to save money on a blimp, this is what you do so
you can see an overhead view.
In fact in some sense this is easier because you see the side of the players,
not just their overhead.
So I probably should have patented this and
made a billion dollars and then I well, didn't happen.