Now we're going to write Click Counter
without any help from Storyboard.
You'll begin by creating
a fresh project.
We're going to use the Single View
template in this case.
And remember if you need help,
you can always follow the steps
in the instructor notes.
Here I've opened
the ViewController.swift file in
the Click Counter project.
If your ViewController.swift file has
extra methods when you first open it,
go ahead and delete them.
The template automatically creates
those, but we don't need them right now.
Our next goal is to write swift
statements that will create the subviews
for the label and the button.
We can put the code here in viewDidLoad.
You may remember from course
one that this executes once,
after the initial view object is set.
Let's start with the label.
We can allocate it and
initialize it here.
Without Storyboard,
we're going to have to position
our label on the screen with code.
All views have a frame property
that we can use to do this.
And we can use the method
CGRectMake to set the x and
y coordinates here and
also the height and width.
So I'll go ahead and set our label's
text to 0, and then try running it.
>> Okay.
So we're not seeing anything yet.
That's because we still need to add our
label's view to the view hierarchy.
That way the label's view is
associated with our existing view.
So here I'll call up the view property,
add the label as a Subview, and
that's, let's try running it again.
Awesome!
We can see our label now.
We can do similar work with the button,
so let's go ahead and
add some comments so
that our code's a little more organized.
So here I'm setting the button's frame,
setting the title,
giving that title a color
we can actually see, and
then adding the button's view
as a Subview of our real view.
And, now we run it again.
And now we can see our button and
our label.
Not too bad for a few lines of code.