The information included in ls's
long listing includes the file name,
the modification time, the file size and
whether a particular file is a file or
a directory.
Let's head over to the terminal so we
could see what this output looks like.
There's a lot of information here.
The file name is in this right column.
And this column to the left of
it that looks like a date and
time, is the modification
time of each file.
The next column over is
the size of each file in bytes.
We can find out whether
a file is a file or
directory by looking at
this left most column.
There's going to be a d for
each directory and a dash for
every regular file.
There's a lot more information here,
too.
But ls doesn't know anything
about the content of your files.
It can't tell you whether they've
been scanned for viruses, and
it doesn't what program should be
used to open a particular file.