Let's go back to our second example,
the one with the two text fields and
also a label.
I want the label to take
the space it needs, and
the text fields to share
equally the remaining space.
Can you think of a way of doing this?
We know how to make several
views fill equally.
Hint, hint.
Why don't we change
the distribution to fill equally?
Close, but no cigar.
I want the label to take
only the space it needs, and
then have all the remaining space
equally filled by the text fields.
How can we fix this?
The answer is by composing stack views.
The two text fields will be inside
a stack view with Fill Equally.
Well, this Stack View will
be inside another one,
along with a label with
a fill distribution.
Da-dum.
This strategy of stuffing
stack views inside stack views
is going to be a bread and
butter from now on.
However, before we move to more advanced
layouts, lets try some vertical layouts.