You actually already
modified the theme of an app
in the CourtCounter app
in practice set two.
You modified the styles at XML
file to have this app theme.
However, we didn't get
into any specifics.
So, let's do that now.
So, what is the style versus a theme?
Well they're both defined as
resources in the app in the same way.
You can add them to the styles.xml file.
However, the difference is that
a style is applied to a single view,
whereas a theme is applied to
an activity or application,
meaning that it's applied to all the
views in that activity or application.
If you want a text feed to show up
in italics with a blue font color,
you could define a style for that.
But if you want all of the text feeds
in your activity to use that blue font
color with italics,
then you could define a theme.
Themes are also used to apply style
properties to the window of the app.
So you can change the color for things
like the app bar or the status bar,
which is exactly how you use
the theme in the CourtCounter app.
The following are three
examples of themes in action.
Notice how the colors used in
the app bar and the status bar
are also reflected in things like
the headers and also the button text.
This is an effective use of
color to convey the brand
of the Google Play Music app.
Similarly, the Google Movies app
uses red as the branding color.
Its use in the app bar, status bar, in
this large image here and the buttons.
In the Google Play Games app, you can
see how specifying different shades of
green for the theme of the app
leads to a cohesive experience.
To make development of an app easier,
there are a few standard system
themes that come with Android.
Each of these system themes follows
the material design principles.
There's Material Dark, which has a dark
content area and a dark action bar.
There's Material Light,
which has a light content area and
a light action bar.
Then there's the Material Light
with Dark Action Bar theme,
which has a light content area with
a dark action bar as the name entails.
When picking a theme, you should pick a
system theme that is closest to what you
want in your final design.
You will make this the parent of
the custom theme you define in
the style.xml file.
That way you'll inherit all
the styling from the parent theme, and
then you can add additional
styling of your own on top of it.
This is a helpful article on
how to use material theme.
It tells you all the things you get for
free by using this theme.
It also talks about the Material theme,
the Material Light and
the Material Light With Dark Action Bar
themes.
Here's some example XML that you
can put into your styles file.
This style is inheriting from
the parent Theme.Material, so
it has a dark content area
with a dark action bar.
We want everything that
the Material.Theme provides for us, but
we do want to change three
of the theme colors, so
we've listed them here in
the properties of this style.
If you're not sure which
properties you want to change,
you can look at this
helpful diagram here.
If you change color primary dark, that's
going to change the status bar and
so on.
These material themes were introduced in
the Android Lollipop Platform version.
But most developers want
the apps to work on
versions of Android older than Lollipop.
In order for your app to run
on older versions of Android,
you should use the support library.
By using the support library,
you can apply one of these themes.
Theme.AppCompat.Light is the same
as the Material.Light theme,
it's just that this one works
on older versions of Android.
And by the way, AppCompat stands for
app compatibility.
Defining a theme using the AppCompat
version is slightly different, so
pay attention to the syntax here.
This example is a good one to follow.
All right, let's go and
change the theme for our app.
We'll start by picking sensible colors
for the app and the status bar.
I open the material
designs spec on color.
You may remember this from
lesson one of our course.
The spec recommends that we use a 500
color for the primary color of the app
and a 700 color for the status
bar within the same color group.
Scrolling through this list, I'm
randomly going to choose the teal color,
so I'm going to use the 500 color for
the primary color of the app.
And then the 700 color for
the primary color dark of the app.
By the way, another helpful tool for
picking colors for
your app, is this material palette tool.
If I click on this color and this color,
then it shows a preview of
what the app would look like.
And down here is a list of all
the colors in the color palette.
Here's the hex color for the primary
color, for the dark primary color,
the accent color and so on.
Once you've picked your colors,
you can go ahead and
define a theme as a style
resource in the styles.xml file.
We ask that you include
these three properties.
Within Android Studio
open the styles.xml file.
We will define our theme here,
this is the same file
that we modified in the last quiz,
where we added the HeaderTextStyle.
But default you should see that
the AppTheme is ready to find.
The parent is
Theme.AppCompat.Light.DarkActionBar.
So, this has a light content
area with a dark action bar.
And we're using AppCompat,
meaning that this will work
on older versions of Android.
Any customization we
do to our theme here
is going to override the defaults that
were provided by the system theme.
This is what the XML looks like for
a theme after you specify
the primary color, primary color,
and the accent color.
The value for
each of these is the hex color here.
This color will show up in the app bar.
This color will show up in the status
bar and contextual app bars.
And the accent color will show up
in UI controls, like checkboxes and
check fields.
Once we've made this style resource,
we want to apply it as a theme.
Lucky for you, AppTheme is already
applied as a theme by default, so
you don't need to change
anything in your code.
Let's look at where
the theme is applied,
in case you want to make
more themes in the future.
You'll need to open up
the AndroidManifest.xml file.
It's located within the Manifest
folder of your app.
This XML file provides important
information about your app
to the system.
For example, it specifies
the package name and the app name,
and it also lists all the components
in your app such as all the activities.
The line that we're interested in now
is this line that specifies the theme
of the application.
The value of the theme
is @style/AppTheme.
This is referring to the style resource
in the @styles.xml file called AppTheme.
By specifying this theme for
the application, all the activities
are going to use this theme.
If we only want to apply this
theme to the MainActivity
then we can copy this line and
paste it here for this activity XML tag.
Since our app only contains one activity
now, there isn't a whole lot of
difference between setting
the theme on the application or
setting the theme on the activity.
But for other more complicated apps
that contain multiple activities,
then the distinction is important.
Complete these tasks in your
version of the Just Java app.
Feel free to choose your own colors for
the theme.
These are just the colors that we
picked for our version of the app.
When you're done,
check these boxes and continue.