All right,
back to our regularly scheduled program.
All right, we're going to introduce
this using one-dimensional signal and
then we'll go to 2D.
So here we have a signal, and
it's a 1D signal, and here's a filter.
And that filter,
if you take a look, actually
this filter here looks a lot like,
oh yeah, something like that.
And that's because I made this and
I actually pulled out that chunk.
Okay?
But the system doesn't know that yet.
And what we're going to do is we're
going to do the normalized correlation
of this filter with that signal.
When you do that,
you get a result that looks like this.
And you'll notice its maximum is at
this peak, this peak here in red, right?
Right here, okay?
And that's the location
of where this filter
came from out of that signal, okay?
So the highest value is exactly
when these things match.
There are a couple of reasons to explain
that, here's the one that I like best.
Pretend for a moment that both of
our signals were normalized, or
were sort of shifted, so
that they were about zero.
So sometimes they went positive and
sometimes they went negative, okay?
And remember we've got the scale
being approximately the same.
because they scale up, so
their standard deviation is one.
If I take one filter and
I lay it over the image and
I'm going to multiply them and
then sum them up.
Remember, some of my values are positive
and some of them might be negative.
I realize this is the first time
we've talked about negative signals.
In fact, on the drawing here you'll
notice it's zero in the middle.
But if I've got positive numbers and
negative numbers and
I've got positive numbers and negative
numbers in my filter, if I want to do
a multiplication and have it come up as
high as possible, when does that happen?
Well the obvious intuition is,
well whenever my pixels in the image
are positive, I want my coefficients
in my filter to be positive.
Because positive times positive
is what negative, Megan?
>> Positive times positive?
>> Yeah.
>> Positive.
And what do I want where
the image is negative?
I want the filter coefficients
to be negative also, right?
Because negative times negative is what,
Megan?
>> Positive.
>> Positive, very good.
Yeah, she went to film school,
but she's doing great.
Anyway, and so if you think of
sort of a filter as having,
because we've scaled it, it can't go
arbitrarily high and arbitrarily low.
If you get that signal to
be lined up exactly, so
wherever it's positive
the other is positive and
where one is negative the other is
negative, you get the maximum value.
There are a lot more sophisticated
ways of showing this involving
differences in distributions and
things like that.
They all basically will show you
that the maximum value you can get.
The product of these is when
they're exactly the same.