Before answering we should consider the
access algorithm, like single reader,
single writer, multiple reader,
multiple writer.
If we only have single reader, single
writer then migration is okay, but
it's not good in all of the other cases.
In a more general problem
that has multiple readers and
multiple writers, with migration,
pages would have to be flipped back and
forth between nodes, and so migration
is really not a good technique.
Migration can in fact lead to
an increase in latencies for
the more general problem.
If we look at the other two options,
caching brings the data on the node,
where it's accessed, and therefore it
will definitely improve the latency of
the subsequent operations to that data.
And similarly replication in
general will create copies of
the data that are potentially closer
to where the data is accessed and
therefore can leads to
improvements in latency.
Now whenever there are multiple
concurrent writes in the system,
caching and replication can
also lead to high overheads.
If you remember in the distributed
file system lecture,
we mentioned that in
the sprite file system,
whenever it was detected that there
are multiple concurrent writers,
caching or in general the presence of
multiple copies of the particular state,
a file in that case, was disabled so
as not to have to deal with multiple
invalidations or loss of consistency.