In this lesson, we're going to introduce
a new element to our algorithms.
Randomization.
In a full course on complexity or
one on randomized algorithms,
we might go back to the definition
of turning machines,
include randomness in the model and then
argue that other models are equivalent.
Here, we're just going to assume that
the standard built in procedures
available in most
programming languages work.
Of course in reality these only
produce pseudorandom numbers, but for
the purpose of studying algorithms,
we assume that they
produce truly random ones.
The lesson we'll use a few
simple randomized algorithms
to help motivate probability theory,
and then use the basic theorems
to characterize the behavior of a few
slightly more sophisticated algorithms.
Some ideas that come up
include independence,
expectation, Monte Carlo versus
Las Vegas algorithms, derandomization.
And the end, we'll tie our study
of algorithms back to complexity
with a brief discussion of
probabilistically checkable proofs.