Here's another table.
This one has some people's heights and
weights in it.
Each row of this table contains the same
sort of data about a different person.
As programmers, we're familiar
with the idea of data types.
A string, like Alan, is a different
type from a numerical value like 188.
But 188 is the same type as 72 even
though they represent values with
different meanings.
One is a height in centimeters and
the other is a weight in kilograms.
Every column in a database table will
have some type associated with it.
All the values in that column will
be of the same type, but moreover,
they'll also have
the same kind of meaning.
We wouldn't mix centimeters and
kilograms in the same column.
The database system itself doesn't
know which numbers are centimeters and
which numbers are kilograms.
We have to keep track of that for
ourselves when we write code.
Here's another example.
Georgia is a string, a piece of text.
But a string that represents
the name of a country, like Georgia,
does not have the same kind of a meaning
as a string that represents a U.S.
state, like Georgia, or the font
Georgia, or someone's first name,
like Georgia O'Keeffe.
And the number 413 means something
different if it's a hotel room number,
or an amount of money, or the telephone
area code for western Massachusetts.
To think about this more clearly,
let's have a quiz.
Here are five pieces of data.
Think about what type each of these is,
and mark the check boxes next to
two pieces of data that
definitely have the same type.