Now we're going to get our hands dirty with a real code base.
No more small example applications anymore.
We'll be working with a well-written and
complete to-do application called TodoMVC.
TodoMVC is actually a project where professional developers have written
exactly the same to-do application in all these
different popular organizational libraries and frameworks.
It's meant to let people see the differences between libraries and frameworks.
Now, given your knowledge of KnockoutJS, you could take a look at the entry
under Knockout and understand most of it pretty quickly if you apply yourself.
But that is not what we're going to be doing this lesson.
After all, this course is not about learning KnockoutJS.
We've learned separation of concerns with our model view octopus paradigm, and
we've learned about Model View ViewModel in Knockout.
And now we're going to see how another organizational library does it.
Once you're done with this lesson, you'll feel empowered to pick up
projects that you've never seen before and learn them.
Now, this new code base that you're going to be working with will be
based on one of these, but I'm not going to tell you which one.
You're going to have to figure that out.
Go ahead and get the code from the GitHub repository in the instructor notes and
then we'll explore it all together.