Here are the answers.
First question.
Analysis models can adapt well to changes in customer requirements.
This is true because analysis models are constructed before design,
therefore they should not be affected by design constraints and
can adjust more easily to changes in customer requirements.
Second question.
Analysis models should represent the approach that will be taken in design.
This is false.
We actually want to avoid mixing analysis and
design together or else we might bias the design approach that is taken.
Third question.
Analysis models are resilient to changes in hardware.
This is true.
Analysis models should not make assumptions about the running environment of
a system and can adjust to changes in hardware.
Fourth question.
Analysis models include all components required by a system.
This is false because there will likely be additions to a system for
collection classes or
other types of utility classes that an analysis model would not specify