Let's make an app with a free and
a paid version.
We're starting out with the base
template, everything absolutely vanilla,
if we run it, it looks just like normal.
Unlike buildTypes, the Android plugin
doesn't create any for us by default.
If we want to declare product flavors,
we do so
just like we do with buildTypes,
except we put them in a productFlavors
block instead of a buildTypes block.
Here, we've gone ahead and
created our free and paid flavors.
Along with unique applicationIds for
both.
Now, if we open up
the Build Variants tab.
We see, we have options not
just between Release and Debug.
But freeDebug, freeRelease,
paidDebug, and paidRelease.
Of course, these different flavors don't
actually do anything different yet.
By default, source and
resources in the main source set,
is included in all app variants.
However, when we declare
additional flavors,
the android plugin automatically
creates new source sets for
us, where we can place flavor
specific code and resources.
So if we want to include
code specifically for
the paid version, we can have
src/paid/java and src/paid/res.
Similarly we can have
src/free/java and src/free/res.
When gradle builds each app variant, it
will automatically bundle the additional
source in each of the flavor
specific folders.
The new app template in
Android Studio makes an app that
just displays a string.
Let's open up the res >
values > strings.xml file and
here's the Hello World
string that will display.
Let's create new strings in our free and
paid versions, so that the free and
paid versions display
different messages.
The easiest way to do this is first,
we'll copy the hello world string.
Then we'll right click
on the app directory.
And I know it's a little bit off screen,
but if you navigate up to the very top,
there's New > Android resource file.
We'll name the file strings.
Resource type is values, and
here's the interesting part,
where we choose the source set.
We'll make this part of
the free source set.
Okay.
Now if we look at the src folder,
we'll find src > free
> res > values > strings.
That's what we're editing right now.
Let's put in our new message.
And we've also done the same thing for
the paid flavor.
Now if we open up the gradle pane, and
go to the install section, let's try
installing the free debug version.
And we can also go ahead and
install the paid debug version.
One more thing that's useful to know,
in addition to including additional
sources in a flavor variant,
we can place flavor-specific
configuration in our gradle build file.
Basically, any configuration that we can
put in the defaultConfig script block,
can also be placed in
the flavor configuration block.
For example, let's say the paid version
of our app requires a new Android SDK,
we can enforce that like so.