The first statement,
an intruder can also be referred
to as a hacker or cracker.
This is true.
For example, we sometimes use
hacker to refer to an intruder.
Second, activists
are either individuals or
members of an organized crime group
with a goal of financial reward.
This is false.
Instead of financial motives,
activists typically have a social or
political cause.
Third, running a packet sniffer on
a workstation to capture usernames and
passwords is an example of intrusion.
This is typically true,
unless such packet sniffing is
done with proper authorization.
Fourth, those who hack into computers do
so for the thrill of it or for status.
This is false because it only
describes some attackers.
But there are many attackers who attack
computers for other reasons, for
example, for illicit financial gains.
The last statement,
intruders typically use steps
from a common attack methodology.
This is true.