What about changes to intensity?
Right. I change the intensity somehow, what happens to my corner detection?
Well it turns out, that it's mostly invariant to additive and
multiplicative intensity changes.
So as it says here.
Look, the moment matrix is just made up of IXs and IYs and
the products of them, well IX is the derivative in X,
the IY, the derivative Y, if I add a constant to my image, nothing changes.
My derivatives are the same.
So it's totally invariant to changes in intensity shift.
I just add a value.
What if I multiply everything?
Well when you multiply an image, you multiply the gradients, right.
Well when you multiply the gradients, you multiply the R value, and
that's what's shown here.
Here we have an R function with certain peaks that were above a threshold.
And if you were to scale the image by a scaler you would just grow those peaks.
All right? But the shape would be the same.
And the only thing you have to worry about is since you're using some threshold,
maybe some points wi-,
That were above the threshold or below, depending upon whether you're going up
or down, maybe they would now change which side of the threshold they're on.
In practice, intensity variation like that is not an issue.
What about change to scale?
Well, what will be clear is, it is not invariant to image scale.
So, here what we have two different curves.
Here I have my original curve, like this, and here I've just zoomed out and
I have a much tighter curve like that.
And the little boxes here, those are meant to be the size of the window.
And if you take a look at each one of these,
all these points will be classified as being edges, because,
essentially, there's not much gradient in the directions parallel to the edge.
But, if I zoom out, this is now a very good corner, and so,
the problem is, is that.
By changing this smooth curve.
By zooming out so this curve becomes tighter and tighter and tighter.
It goes from being a bunch of edges to being a corner.
So in general, the Harris corner finder or
corner detector is not invariant to scale and guess what.
The data proved that.
Okay?
Here's a another graph taken from a similar paper.
And you can see that it falls off pretty drastically as you get to scale.
In fact eve with just a scale factor of two.
So I just.
Zoom in or zoom out by a factor of 2.
I've already lost almost 80 percent of my repeatability.
So it's really, really not invariant to scale and
we're going to have to do something about that.