While the previous example gave us a
good idea what type of scheduler to use,
that the scheduler should mix CPU and
memory bound tasks.
The question that is open at this point
is how do we know if a thread is CPU
bound versus a memory bound.
To answer this question we
will use historic information.
We will look at
the thread's past behavior.
And this is similar to what we said was
useful when we were trying to determine
whether a thread is interactive or
I/O bound versus CPU bound.
However, previously we
used sleep time for
this type of differentiation
of I/O versus CPU bound.
And that won't work in this case.
First of all, the thread is not really
sleeping when it's waiting on a memory
reference, the thread is active and
it's just waiting in some stage
in the processor pipeline and
not on some type of software queue.
Second, to keep track of the sleep time
we were using some software methods, and
that's not acceptable.
We cannot execute in software some
computations to decide whether a thread
is CPU bound or memory-bound.
Given the fact that the context
switch takes order of cycles, so
the decision what to execute
should be very, very fast.
Therefore, we somehow need some kind of
hardware support, some information from
the hardware in order to be
able to answer this question.
Fortunately, modern hardware has
lots of so called hardware counters
that get updated as
the processor is executing and
keep information about various
aspects of the execution.
These include information
about the cash usage for
instance such as the L1, L2, or
the last level cash misses or
information about the number of
instructions that were retired.
So that we can compute the IPC or
in your platforms there's also
information regarding the power or
energy usage of the CPU or
particular components of the system.
There are a number of interfaces and
tools that can be used to access
these hardware counters via software.
For instance, oprofiler or the Linux
perf tool are available in Linux, and
one of the things that's useful is that
if you look at the oprofile website,
it actually has a list of all of the
hardware counters that are available for
different architectures.
Because the hardware counters are not
uniform on every single platform.
So, then how can hardware
counters help a scheduler
make any kinds of scheduling decision?
Many practical as well as research based
scheduling techniques rely on the use
of hardware counters to understand
something about the requirements of
the threads in terms of the kinds
of resources that they need,
CPUs or memory.
So then, the scheduler can use that
information to pick a good mix of
the threads that are available in the
run queue to schedule on the system so
that all of the components of the system
are well utilized or that, so
that the threads don't
interfere with one another.
Or, whatever other scheduling
policy needs to be achieved.
For instance, a scheduler can look at a
counter like the last level cash misses
and using this counter, a scheduler can
decide that a thread is memory bound,
so its footprint doesn't
fit in the cash.
Or the same counter can also tell
the scheduler that something changed in
the execution of the threat so that now
it's executing with some different data
in a different phase of its execution,
and it's running with the cold cash.
What this tells us is that,
that one counter can tell us
different things about a thread.
So, given that there isn't a unique way
to interpret the information provided
from hardware counters,
we really sort of guesstimate
what it is that they're telling us
about the thread's resource use.
That doesn't mean that the use of
hardware counters is not good,
in fact schedulers can use
hardware counters to make
informed decisions regarding the
workload mix that they need to select.
They would typically use some
combination of the counters that
are available on the CPU, not just one,
in order to build a more accurate
picture of the threads resource needs.
And they would also rely on some
models that have been built for
a specific hardware platform and
that have been trained using
some well understood workloads.
So we ran a workload that we
know is memory intensive and
we made some observations regarding the
values of those counters and therefore,
we now know how to interpret them for
other types of workloads.
These types of techniques
really fall into much more
advanced research problems,
which are a little bit out of the scope
of this particular introductory course.
However, I really wanted to make sure
that you're aware of the existence of
these hardware counters and
how they can be used.
And how they can be really useful when
it comes to resource management in
general not just
regarding CPU scheduling.