So let's go over this for a bark ment.
One of our features that our
competitors don't have is on call vets.
And we also have insurance for
the animal and the sitter's home.
Now for price,
we actually have a little bit of
a lower price than our main competitor.
But we have added value that we
just talked about in the product.
Now for promotions,
I don't want to give too much away, but
we have the Pal + Paws Walk.
This is where our sitters and
our owners get to meet each other and
do a 3K for
charity to save shelter animals.
For place, we're only going to
accept nice homes and yards.
We're going to vet the environment
the sitters have for each dog.
We'll talk more about
this part in a few.
And for
people, well we have Ronnie and me,
we're both passionate about what we do.
And we're going to go above and
beyond to make sure this
company gets off the ground.