And the answer is W0 = 0.5, and W1 = 0.9.
If I were to draw a line, it would go about like this.
It doesn't really hit the two points at the end.
If you were thinking of something like this, you were wrong.
If you draw a curve like this, your quadratic error becomes 2.
One over here, and one over here.
The quadratic error is smaller for the line that goes in between those points.
This is easily seen by computing as shown in the previous slide.
W1 equals (4 x 118 - 20 x 20) / (4 x 120 - 400) which is 0.9.
This is merely plugging in those numbers into the formulas I gave you.
W0 then becomes ¼ x 20.
Now we plug in W1-- 0.9 / 4 x 20 equals 0.5.
This is an example of linear regression,
in which case there is a residual error,
and the best-fitting curve is the one that minimizes
the total of the residual vertical error in this graph over here.