All right, so here I am in the
Command Prompt in the SQLite3 program
inside my shelter database.
Now using this create statement,
I've created a new pets table
with a couple of constraints
on different columns.
Now I want you to follow along,
I suggest taking a look at the insert
statements that I've linked
down below in the notes.
They matched the one
that I've inserted here.
And so I've created new data
inside this pets table.
So back to our overview
of the CRUD SQL commands.
Now thus far we've talked
about creating a table for
the pets, where we're inserted
a new pet into the database
as well as inserted default
pet data into the database.
Next for the read commands,
we've learned how to select or
read a list of all
the pets at the shelter.
Now if you notice the next few actions
are all specific to a single pet
as indicated by the ID we need.
All right so to refer to a pet by
its ID, we can use the where clause.
So let's take a look at an example.
So let's say I use that SELECT * from
statement that we've used before,
select from the pets table.
But now I want to use the WHERE keyword.
And so this WHERE keyword specifies the
pet, or pets that we're interested in.
In our case,
we're only interested in the pet where
the ID column is equivalent to 1.
id == 1.
So notice here that it prints
out the first pet of our table.
So Tommy.
And to help us look at that better,
let's turn on the header and
then set the mode to column.
And once again here's what
that information looks like.
So in our case we're only
interested in the pet
where the ID column was equivalent to 1.
And notice here that we used ID, but
it's not specific to the where clause.
We could have used
various other columns to
specify the information that we wanted.
So for example, say I wanted all the
pets that weigh more than 18 kilograms.
So like FROM pets WHERE weight &gt;= 18.
And so that command gave us that our one
pet Duke has a weight of 70 kilograms.
Another example case we
could have looked at,
although pets whose gender are females.
So let's try that.
WHERE gender equals,
remember we had the value of 2
set as the equivalent for
female in our use case.
So we have our two pets,
Lady and Arlene.
So WHERE helps us specify which rows
of the database we're interested in.
And as I mentioned before, SELECT allows
us to specify which columns we're in.
So for example, I can SELECT
specifically from two columns.
So say name and
breed column FROM the pets table.
So what that does is it pulls up the
information from just these two columns
that I've asked for.
So this is useful if you
have a huge database but
are only interested in one or
two attributes from the database.
So what that ORDER by keyword here
does is change the output ordering.
So it takes the column, so
what we specified here name, and
then orders that column
by either ascending.
So ASC or descending DESC orders.
So in total, this command is telling
us to order all these information
by the name column in ascending order.
So from A to Z.
So using a combination of
the keywords and then various syntax,
we can grab specific information to get
just the particular data that we need.
So for example, we can grab all
the animals that don't have an unknown
breed, and
then show their names and gender.
So for example, SELECT, pet name and
gender FROM the pets table
WHERE the breed !="unknown".
So in Java,
the exclamation mark means not.
So combined with the equal sign,
this reads as not equals.
So in this statement we're just
selecting the column's name and
gender for
the pets whose breed is not unknown.
So that includes these six right here.
So as you learn other operations
in SQL used to delete and
update data, keep in mind that
you can use the WHERE clause
to specify the data that
you want to affect.
So for this practice set, select just
the name and weight from the male pets
and then order that by weight with
the highest weight at the top.
And I like you to paste the command
that you used in this box here.