Nothing like a year free of [INAUDIBLE] and all the things you
might have done this [INAUDIBLE] like the combination of technologies.
Like I mean in the [INAUDIBLE] you maybe wanted to look at [INAUDIBLE] and
real time and sudden fashion, right?
If you think you are going to focus on more on the batch [INAUDIBLE].
I will not produce then hive, then probably scalding and
cascading all these various tools, that they need to understand and
how those tools work, in general all right.
And if you run the real time aspect of the things,
then you might want to understand more on the as well as the technologies,
like storm and And some of the abstractions,
like something brought the maps into the storm to Paulise, right?
These technologies are very important to know how you can extract data, and
how can do starts, doing some simple analytics on top of it, right?
And your peer, your pull and analytic person then not only.
Understanding these components help you better understand how to write analytic
and also you will know how to tune it to get the results that faster, as well.
And the analytic of the extra burden of knowing some of the statistics, and
the data-mining algorithms, and all the various, like being in a Christian
clustering and all the various other outcomes, but they need to know about it.
>> Mm-hm. >> Yeah.