So as you can imagine,
there are different situations where you
use banner ads and interstitial ads.
Since banner ads just covers a portion
of the screen, it allows the user to
engage with your app and see the ad
at the same time, while interstitial
ads take over the entire screen, so the
user can't see anything except the ad.
>> How do we make money out of this?
>> I was just coming to that.
As an app developer you can earn money
whenever you display an ad
in your app to a user.
Or if the user clicks on the ad.
So this is the way ads
can help you earn money.
And although, it sounds very easy,
you have to remember that you
need to create an awesome app, so
you have a big enough user base
looking and engaging with the ads.