So, let's see which storage
class was the best match for
each of these attributes.
So for the first attribute, name,
this should be text since it's
essentially a string input.
Next would be breed.
So given that there are many different
types of breeds and that we might add
a new breed into the system,
we can go ahead and sort this as text.
Now in the case of there were just
limited number of susceptible breeds,
you could have made a choice
before using integers.
Moving on we have gender,
and in this example
we listed here that there will
only be three options for gender.
And because of this,
we like to sort as an integer.
So for example,
we have zero equal unknown, one for
male, and two for female.
And next off would be weight.
So, you could have made a real
strong case that this can be sort
as a real value, but
to keeps things simple,
we're not going to support
weights with decimal points.
So we'll just use integers