So as far as a deposit is concerned, in addition to appending that particular
amount into the transactions list, we have to update the running total.
And, as you recall from when we talked about doing OCL invariants when
we're updating state.
You have an equation, in this case,
it says running total equals running total at pre.
That is the value before the operation started,
plus the amount of the deposit, which is A.
Similarly for withdrawals, we have to say that the running total that is at
the end, equals the running total at the start minus the amount being withdrawn.
As far as the balance operation is concerned,
here's where we save those computations.
No longer have to do the sum,
instead we can just return as the requested value the running total.
As far as initialization is concerned,
in addition to initializing the transactions to be an empty sequence,
we have to initialize the running total to be zero.
And finally, here's the invariant, here's what we have to ensure is always true.
Which is that the value of the running total has to,
at all times, be equal to the sum of the transactions.
Otherwise this optimization that we are proposing to add in
our refinement is not going to be correct.
'Kay, note that, as in this example, it is typical for
invariants to relate the values of two or more attributes.