Let's go through the prediction and
correction just a little
bit in the Kalman 1D case.
Remember, we're going to assume
that the state of time t, okay,
is just a constant times whatever
the state was at t minus 1,
plus some noise that's added,
some process noise.
Right?
So the first thing we would like to do
is we would like to know our estimate.
What's our best guess?
At time t, given everything t minus 1,
when we've got this Gaussian model.
Well, we're going to write
this the following, right.
If, if something is a Gaussian, and
I multiply it by a constant,
what does that become?
It becomes another Gaussian.
Or another way of saying it,
I have some variable that's distributed
by a Gaussian, and
I multiply that variable by a constant.
I get a new value out.
But it's also a Gaussian, all right?
And in fact,
if you remember from probability right?
It's mean is just going to be that
constant times the previous mean.
So that's what this equation here says.
This equation says that if I have my
belief about the mean at time t minus 1.
After I've done all
my work at t minus 1.
And if I believe that my
dynamics are multiplying
the state at every time step by d,
my belief before
I take a measurement about what the new
mean is just going to be d times that.
That's what this equation at
the bottom says here, right?
Mu minus a time t,
the predicted mean is just d times
the mean from what I had before.
Okay?
Because d is my multiplier.
All right, so you remember that when I
multiply something by a constant and
it's Gaussian, the mean just multiplies.
But what about the variance, okay?
Now we have to update the variance.
There are two things that are going on.
First of all,
we're taking some previous variable and
we're multiplying it by constant.
That variable had some sigma,
sigma squared to it.
And maybe you remember if you have
a Gaussian, when you multiply that by
a constant, its variance goes up
by the square of that constant.
So just In the multiplication part,
all right.
Whatever the variance was before is
going to go up by now d squared.
But wait, we're not done.
We also added in some more noise when
we took that step, right, of d squared.
So that means the new variance
before we take a measurement
is made up of two components.
It's d squared times whatever
the variance was before so
that's written as d sigma
t minus 1 plus squared.
Sigma t minus 1 plus is the standard
deviation if its squared.
It's the variance of what we
had at the end of t minus 1.
We multiply everything by d.
So we multiply that
variance by d squared.
That's what this term over here is.
And then, we added in some more noise.
Because of uncertainty of how
the thing actually then moved,
that is this d squared okay?
So even if we were multiplying by
a one that is even if we had no idea.
There was that, you know,
everything was just a one,
our variance would still grow
because of the added uncertainty.
All right?
So the, the update of the mean or
the update of the variance for
the Kalman is written like this.
All right.