There are many advances that can
be considered the beginning of
virtual reality.
You could look at the origins
of computer graphics or
maybe start with the philosophical
concept of alternate realities.
You could draw a line from the many
advancements in film an animation.
Or you could say it all started
with the invention of the computer.
And I think those are all
valid places to begin, but for
me, the history of VR begins
with 3D display technology.
That's the first line of invention that
leads directly to what we call VR today.
In the beginning of 3D
display technology,
really starts on earnest with
the stereoscope in 1838.
This device was created by
a brilliant English inventor
names Sir Charles Wheatstone,
and it worked like this.
One picture is shown to the left eye,
and
another picture is shown to the right.
The two pictures are of the same object.
One from the viewpoint of the left eye,
and the other from
the viewpoint of the right.
There are a pair of mirrors at 45
degree angles to the user's eyes and
each is reflecting
a picture off to the side.
When the two views of the same
object are shown to their
respective eye in the same location
they fuse to form a view of
a solid three dimensional object.
It's a pretty amazing invention right?
After the stereoscope, there were
a number of improvements on 3D displays.
And folks experimented with
various kinds of immersive
entertainment machines.
But if we skip past all of those,
the next biggest VR advancement was
undoubtedly the Sword of Damocles.
Many folks consider it the first VR and
AR device and
it was invented by
Ivan Sutherland at MIT in 1968.
The Sword of Damocles was the first
device to track a users head motion and
overlay synthetic 3D stereoscopic
computer generated graphics
into their vision.
The device had a long mechanical arm
that extended from the ceiling and
attached to the user's head.
And the user was shown primitive,
wireframe 3D objects projected
onto a transparent display.
In this way,
the Sword of Damocles was the first
augmented reality display as well.
Ivan Sutherland accomplished a great
deal in the field of computer graphics.
And make no mistake, he deeply
understood the potential of VR.
His pioneering work brought us a lot
closer to the virtual reality technology
we have today.
later, in the early 1990s,
we saw virtual reality first
promoted to the general public.
Thanks to advancements made by, NASA and
VPL, consumer virtual reality
seemed like it was a possibility.
Movies were released that used
virtual reality as a plot device.
Successful books were written
that depicted virtual reality
as a completely realistic
alternate universe.
But the virtual reality devices
that actually sold didn't
live up to those unrealistically
high expectations.
Nintendo's virtual play
had set was a red and
black, low quality display
that often cause headaches.
Headsets with tracking were
extremely expensive and bulky, and
the displays were poor.
Input systems like data gloves
left a lot to be desired.
In short, virtual reality simply
wasn't ready for the general public.
And after a while, the hype died away,
the industry shrank and
VR was relegated to academic and
military use.
That is until 2012.
When a kick starter was announced for
a new inexpensive VR device
called the Oculus Rift.
The booming mobile phone industry
had driven down the price of
high quality display technology.
And Oculus leveraged this fact and used
a clever single paneled display system
to manufacture an inexpensive,
high quality VR headset.
Shortly thereafter,
Occulus was acquired by Facebook for
$2 billion and we've seen the VR
industry take off like a rocket.
We're now experiencing
the second wave of consumer VR,
and this time it's here for good.
It exciting to see how far thing have
come,and we are just getting started.