The definition of the expected sum of future
possible discounted reward that it has given you
allows me to define a value function.
For each status, my value of the state
is the expected sum of future discounted reward
provided that I start in state S,
then I execute policy pi.
This expression looks really complex,
but it really means something really simple,
which is suppose we start in the state over here,
and you get +100 over here, -100 over here.
And suppose for now, every other state costs you -3.
For any possible policy that assigns actions to
the non-absorbing states, you can now
simulate the agent for quite a while and compute empirically
what is the average reward that is being received
until you finally hit a goal state.
For example, for the policy that you like,
the value would, of course, for any state
depend on how much you make progress towards the goal,
or whether you bounce back and forth.
In fact, in this state over here, you might bounce down
and have to do the loop again.
But there's a well defined expectation
over any possible execution of the policy pi
that is generic to each state and each policy pi.
That's called a value.
And value functions are absolutely essential to MDP,
so the way we're going to plan is we're going to iterate
and compute value functions, and it will turn out
that by doing this, we're going to find better and better policies as well.