So let's take a look at this working.
Here is some images taken from there's something called,
the mpeg flower garden sequence.
It was used for demonstrating certain kinds of image processing algorithms.
It's just convenient here.
So the first thing is, let's take a look in a low textured region, all right?
So, there's not very much going on there.
The gradients there have very small magnitude.
And what's being shown here, both as an image, and as a plot.
Is, how does that error function change, as I move around in u and v?
And what you can see is, there's no sort of,
obvious peak anywhere, be a positive or negative in here.
To say that, that that's' the obvious place for,
where you would want to find a feature.
And remember, we're, we're looking for that.
Now, let's take a look at another region.
So here we have a point that's on this edge that's where the,
the roof line is, okay?
And you'll notice that we have this ridge here, okay, of a, of low error.
And that's sort of, represented through here and
by the way, in this just make the, the pictures easier to understand.
The bright thing here is, is, is good and, and black is bad.
And you know, you don't want to go this way, but going along this way,
you don't know exactly, where your corner is.
So, let's take a look at sort of another patch, another place, and
here we are right in the middle of the flower bed.
Now, both of our gradients are large.
Our lamp, the gradients are large in many different directions.
So we have a large l1 and a large l2.
We get this nice peak down here, and that's shown, as this nice peak here.
The idea is that, this would have a nice large, r value, Harris corner r value.
That would find you, that says, you know, what?
If you give me that point.
And I'm looking for that point again in another image.
Any small motion is going to give me a big error change, so
that's a good suggestion for, where a corner might be.