Here I'll show you an example of Hough running on
a real image to show you that what it does well and what it doesn't do well.
This is a picture of an American football field.
This is American football, you know, played with a ball that's not round.
We run an edge detector of some flavor, and we get out these edges, and
those are some interesting looking edges.
And then what we do is we run that through a Hough accumulator array.
You can see the sinusoids here, sort of spread out, but
you're seeing that these, these squares are all of these peaks that were found,
and this is using some code that tries to look for peaks.
So you'll notice that a whole bunch of them are very close together, right?
So being very close together would mean that they're about the same angle, and
that they're approximately in the same location.
Same angle, same location, well, yes, I mean, here are lines that are the same
angle and about the same location in here, and here, and here.
And even here, about the same angle, about the same location.
So you would expect to find peaks that are nearby.
So I'm showing you this peak image here.
If I were to draw the lines associated with each one of these peaks,
I would see something that looks like this.
So, there's good news and bad news on here.
The good news is that it found an awful lot of line segments.
Okay, you'll notice it also missed a bunch.
Okay, why is that?
Well, that has something to do with the nature of the edges that were found in
the bins in the voting.
These are all details that are going to matter in terms of how
well you find the edges.
You'll also notice that there is this cyan line, here, and
that's the longest line segment found.
Now, somebody should be saying, wait a minute, line segments?
What do you mean by line segments?
>> Line segments?
>> Well, in the Hough transform, when you find a theta and d, or an m and b,
for that matter, that's an infinite line, right?
That, that's a line that goes as far as you want to,
certainly goes through the entire image.
If you want to find the line segments, of the points that voted for that line,
and just connect them or just connect the two that are furthermost away.
Or do some other operation of running along that infinite line,
seeing if there's an edge point near there or anywhere near there.
So you have to do some other operation besides the voting we just showed
in order to find the line segments.
The good news for
you is that in your problem set, I just want you to find the infinite line.
You don't have to worry about finding the line segment that's actually
supported in the image.