The two answers I was looking are either
little b or square root of Z.
These answers are equivalent because
of our assumption about the size of
fast memory.
The work is still n cubed.
What about the transfers?
Each block read or write involves
the transfer of a b by b, or b squared,
sized block.
Each loop nest does n
divided by b iterations.
From these two bits, we can now
count out the total number of reads.
For example, let's take the C blocks.
Each block read involves
b squared words, and
this is repeated, n/b squared, times.
So that's a total of n squared reads,
same thing goes for the writes.
What about a and b?
In each case, there are b squared
reeds nested in n/b cubed iterations.
So that's a total of n cubed,
divided by b reads.
The same thing holds for matrix b.
The total number of transfers is
therefore dominated by an n cubed over
b term.
The intensity is just the ratio of
the work and the transfers, or O of b.
And by our assumption of the size of b
in relation to the fast memory size,
that's the same thing
as square root of Z.
Remember that the conventional
matrix matrix multiply algorithm has
an intensity that is constant, so
blocking is a much better idea
algorithmically speaking.