Let me now show you some examples
of what we can do with this.
So, here is an example of
something I did myself
in the earlier version of Photosynth.
I was in Barcelona, and of course,
I took a bunch of pictures
at the Sagrada Familia.
So, these are all the pictures I took,
and I'm going to show you how we can
actually use this to
generate a Panorama, or
a Photosynth, not a Panorama.
So, these are some of the images
that I'm just showcasing.
I just did a captured of
screen from my laptop.
When I was doing this, and
I'm just showcasing the video to you.
Variety of interfaces are available here
you can now see the same kinds of things
you saw on the research version that
became a complete technology preview,
that Microsoft invested quite a bit in.
Several of my students have worked on
that team that generated some of these
technologies, and now you can see,
just by clicking on different images.
You can browse,
you can see all of different types of
details of this amazing structure.
If you haven't seen it yourself,
I mean, I'd recommend,
if you're in Barcelona to want to go see
this church, but again, just by photos,
you can start browsing this,
ie the term photo tourism.
You can also see things
like overhead views.
Very hard to see it, but now as you
browse through, you can actually see
pictures that are actually used to
generate the cloud of points in 3D.
And this is the cloud of points, hard
to see on this screen most probably for
you all, but if you notice, when I
click on different types of things,
it basically shows the bounding
box of the original image.
Then you can then zoom into, or
actually get much more details for.
Again, purely based on pictures taken by
me walking around the Sagrada Familia,
and now we have this whole
wonderful visualization of a site.
Of course, the newer version allows you
to do different types of things, and
continuing in my theme of taking
pictures of Sports Stadiums,
this was me at a game of
the Georgia Tech Yellow Jackets.
Just took a bunch of different
pictures there, and here,
now you see a visualization of me just
now taking, and generating a panorama.
Except that if you notice,
there are exact different pictures here,
and you can see people moving around,
and I can interactively control it.
So, if you were able to do this,
you should have been actually been able
to see simpler things like this on your
scre, on your own screen
from your own pictures.
We can also, of course, see these
different types of additional scenes,
here's a beautiful example of
another just walking scene.
Bunch of different pictures, not perfect
registration across the board, but
a very nice visual,
of course, in this instance,
the person who generated
this also showed details.
Here I'm just scrolling through to kind
of move through the videos faster.