So now, the question is,
we need to compute this descriptor about this local image region, all right.
And remember, we want two things for the descriptor.
We want it to be highly distinctive, that is, given two different points in
the image, I should be able to come up with two different descriptions.
But, we like it to be invariant as much as possible,
to just small changes in viewpoint, maybe even large changes in viewpoint.
Sir, illumination in other kinds of imaging parameters.
So, before we build that descriptor we normalize.
What's the normalization?
Wherever our little window is, we're going to say, okay, this is our new north.
We're going to rotate north to be north, to be up let's say.
So we're going to move them, rotate them all back.
And the other thing is that we're going to scale it to be some uniform size.
So if the, if the, when we did the, the detection to begin with,
it said it was a small scale we're going to blow it up to be that size.
And if it said it was a large scale we
might shrink it down to be some fixed size.
So the idea is we you know, pick particular sizes.
By the way, getting SIFT to work is painful.
And that's one of the reasons people tend to use libraries for descriptors.
it, because it's a lot of you know the,
the expression, the devil's in the detail?
There are a lot of details to makings this work.