So the very last part of this lesson,
we'll do some simple analysis about what different filters we'll do, and
then we'll do more sophisticated filtering later.
Here we have a picture, there's the original one on the left,
somebody's eye, maybe you know whose eye it is,
and I convolve it with that filter that's an impulse, what do you get back?
Well what do you get when you convolve an image with an impulse,
you get the original, and there it is, it's no change, 'kay so
when you filter with an impulse, all right.
So here's a slightly interesting one, what happens if I've got an impulse but
it's actually not centered at the reference point but
it's shifted over right, by one.
Well what's going to happen is, when I place my filter down the, in the middle,
it's going to go get the fill, the pixel from the right, and
put that down at the reference point, then I move it over,
and I get the right, now whether I get the one on the right or
the left will depend on whether I'm doing correlation or convolution,
remember correlation I just move it around, convolution I flip it over and
then move it around, but what you're going to end up with is a shifted image, so
in this case you'll shift to the left if you're doing correlation, so
by shifting the impulse you get a shifted function, and
that's because the idea is that the center coordinate here is 0,0.
All right, what about this?
So now I've got all ones divided by 9 so
it's so it sums to 1, what is that going to look like?
Well, we've already seen that, right, that's just a, kind of a crummy
smoothing filter, it's a blur, all right, so I just get out the blurred eye.
All right, now comes something really cool.
All right?
What if my filter, is actually the combination of these two?
Okay?
This is essentially twice the impulse, minus the blur.
All right.
Now, this is still all linear, so, the output of applying this kernel,
where the kernel is made up of sums and multiplies, can just be done by
taking the sums of the original two outputs, and that would look like this.
And you'll notice, I'll show you a better example in a minute,
that it's kind of sharpened up the image, it's accentuated the differences, and
this is, drawing something like this, so here, this is filter is called,
a sharpening filter, and it's got these little parts that have to do with the,
the minus, and then the part in the middle.
And if I show this applied to the whole filter, okay, you'll see that,
and you, so, now you know whose eye it is, there is Einstein's eye and
you'll, and if you take a look on your screen,
you'll see that this one is a good deal sharper than the, than the previous one.