We've kept talking about warping images from one to another.
That is we take an image, we pump it through is the phrase I'm using or we
transform it by homography, which means we have to go and transform this image.
We have to warp this image.
So the question is, how do we do that?
The answer is, there are two ways.
The forward and the backward.
And theres another word for those, the wrong way and the right way.
Image warping can be thought of this way.
Suppose I have an image transformation and I have some source image f of x,y and
I know how that maps to x prime y prime.
Or, or another way of thinking about it,
I know how that maps in the other image I'm going to create some new image g and
for every x prime y prime in it, or call it a and b or ij.
What value should go there.
And this t of x,y is the transformation that says, given x,y in one image.
That value should go to x prime y prime in the second image.
So forward warping works as follows.
You basically send every pixel f of x,y.
So I've got the first image it's at x,y.
I send it to its corresponding location in the second image.
So I have some pixel here, a little red dot.
I know where it goes and
I put that same color that was down on the first image down in the second image.
And that's okay but you might ask the question, well,
what happens if this pixel lands between pixels in the new image.
Lets take a look at that.
So.
Here's a, a picture and I credit Alyosha about this.
And in this picture, let's assume that the lines are exactly,
you know, y equals 2, y equals 3 and x equals 14, and
x equals 15, so the intersections of the lines are the precise pixels.
So if I have a pixel here and I map it across.
I may land somewhere between a pixel, okay?
And somehow, what I have to do is,
I have to take the color that came from this location and
I have to distribute it among all the pixels that are around where I landed.
In graphics, that's known as splatting, that's the technical term.
I mean, I guess it's the idea if you threw some paint down there and all
the paint had to drain out to its neighbors, where would that paint all land.
And that's sort of an annoying way of doing things, and
that's why I said that, that was the wrong way of doing warping.