In this scenario, in order to deal
with an increase in the order rates,
it would mean that we would
need to add more workers,
which is analogous to the processes,
or add more work benches,
analogous to the servers,
where those processes need to execute.
Or add more tools and parts,
so analogous to the storage,
the state that's needed for
the execution of the service.
But we don't have to perform
any additional decisions
to decide what exactly are those
workers intended to do or
what specific tools or
parts do we need to add.
Just a little bit more of everything.
The bottom line is that,
in this scenario,
the management is fairly simple.
Still takes some time to do this but
we don't have to put a lot of thought
into exactly how we need to
configure these increased resources.