The answer is 198.
And in general, it's 2 times n- 2.
We could go in the wrong order among
all the non-centered vertices.
So it's possible that every
edge costs 2 except for
the ones leading in and
out of the center vertex.
Of course, the optimum involves
just using the blue edges
which only have cost 1.
So in this case,
the optimum has cost 100.
By choosing n large enough, we therefore
can get this ratio of 2n- 2 over n,
as closest to 2 as we want.
So our analysis that this gives
a factor of 2 approximation is optimal.
The example just given
shows that our analysis
of that particular approximation
algorithm for metric TSP is tight.
There are some graphs at least
that really could return a tour
that has twice the cost
of the optimum 1.
So we can't improve on the theorem
just by better analysis.
It turns out that for
the metric traveling salesman problem,
there are algorithms out there
that give better approximations.
The most famous being
a 3 over 2 approximation
called the Christofides algorithm.
If you're familiar with matching
with general graphs, and
Eulerian tours, then understanding
it and the approximation guarantee
isn't too much more work than
what we've done already.
So I encourage you to
look it up on your own.
In addition,
there are many more results for
when various alternative assumptions
are made about the costive edges.
All of them giving different
approximation factors and
running time guarantees.
If you ever find yourself needing to
solve a traveling salesman problem,
think carefully about what
assumptions you can make and
look up the best approximation
result for your case.
Chances are,
you won't be the first person to
encounter that version of the problem.