The first code snippet is correct because it perfectly aligns with the policy.
If new_order is equal to 3,
clearly an incoming thread will not be able to proceed.
So this will guarantee that there cannot be more than
three new orders processed in the toy shop.
Note, by the way, that new_ order cannot be larger than 3, given that the only
way that it will get updated is once we come out of this wait statement.
So, the maximum value that new_order can receive in this code is 3.
The second part of this statement also perfectly aligns with the second part of
the policy.
If we have a situation in which there are some number of old_orders in
the system, and one request for a new_order has already entered the toy shop,
then any incoming new_order will have to be blocked at the wait statement.
So, this piece of code, this answer, is correct.
The second code snippet is almost identical to the first one,
however, it uses if as opposed to while.
We explained that if creates a problem, in that, when we come out of
the statement, when we thought that this condition was satisfied.
It is possible that, in the meantime, another thread has come in and
executed this particular lock operation or even the critical section entry for
the old_order, and has therefore changed the value of this predicate.
If we don't go back to reevaluate the predicate, it is possible that
we will miss such a case and therefore enter the actual critical section.
So, enter the toy shop in a way that violates this policy.
So this answer is not correct because it uses this if as opposed to a while.
The third statement is incorrect because it
checks whether old_order is greater than or equal to 0.
So, what this means means if that a new incoming order will be blocked if
there is already one new_order in the system and old_order is equal to 0.
And basically no other orders for
toy repairs, no other old_orders are in the system.
That is clearly not the desired behavior.
We want to allow up to three new orders to be processed in the system.
So this statement is incorrect.
The fourth statement is basically identical to the first one except for
the fact that it uses greater than or equal to 3.
As we already pointed out, new_order will really not
even receive a value greater than 3 the way it's updated here.
So this statement will result in the identical behavior as the first statement.
So both of these are correct.