Now, let's say we have multiple such processes.
Clearly we will need copies of these user-level thread structures,
process control blocks, and kernel-level thread structures to
represent every single aspect of every one of these processes.
So, we'll need to start maintaining certain relationships among them.
With respect to the user-level threads within the threading library, it keeps
track of all of the user-level threads that represent the single process.
So, there is a relationship between them and
the process control block that represents that address space.
For each process we need to keep track of what are the kernel-level threads that
execute on behalf of this process, and vice versa, for
each kernel-level thread we have to make sure we
know what is the address space within which that thread executes.
If the system has multiple CPUs,
we need to have a data structure to represent the CPU.
And then we need to maintain a relationship between the kernel-level threads and
the CPU.
So what is the CPU that a kernel level thread has affinity to, last strand it
was scheduled on, and then for a CPU, a pointer to its current thread or
a pointer to the threads that typically run there, and similar information.
When the kernel itself is multithreaded, we said we
can have multiple kernel-level threads supporting a single user-level process.
When the kernel needs to schedule, or
context switch, among kernel-level threads that belong to different processes,
it can quickly determine that they point to a different process control block.
So they will have different virtual address mappings, and
therefore can easily decide that it needs to
completely invalidate the existing address mappings and restore new ones.
In the process, it will save the entire process control block
structure of the first kernel-level thread, and
then if it's context switching to the second one,
it will restore the entire process control block structure of the second one.