Let's start exploring cameras by
opening up a brand new Unity scene.
Go to File &gt; New Scene.
Now on the hierarchy locate
the main camera and click on that.
Every time you create
a new scene in Unity,
it'll be populated with a main camera.
Perfect!
Take a look at the inspector panel,
you should now see a camera component.
The camera component
has many properties.
Let's look at them.
First up, we have clear flags.
Clear flags are a property that
indicates what the camera should render
if, for a given pixel on our screen,
the camera does not see a 3D object.
Think of this as a control for
the background.
By default this is set to skybox.
Skyboxes are a wrapper
around your entire scene
that shows what the world
looks like beyond your models.
This could be a cityscape, the depths of
the ocean, or just the plain old sky.
At their core,
skyboxes are another type of material
which you learned about in lesson two.
So let's go create one.
In the project pane,
navigate to the Skyboxes folder.
Then create a new material and
let's call it sky.
In the inspector, select the shader
drop-down and select skybox procedural.
Unity has done an amazing job of making
it really easy to customize our sky.
As you can see,
there are several properties that allow
us to control the appearance of it.
Let's make a really small
change by changing the sky tint
to a nice sunset red.
As you can see,
making this change to this material did
not change the skybox set in the scene.
But if you look at the preview
at the bottom of the inspector,
you can see that we did
change our skybox material.
Let's apply our skybox to the camera.
Find the camera component in the
inspector and add a skybox component.
Drag and drop the sky material
into the material property
of our skybox component.
Our skybox is still not
applied to our scene view.
However, if we look at the game view,
we'll see that it's now applied.
We'll talk more about sky
boxes in the next lesson and
how to apply them to our scene.
But for now, know that they are a very
great way to efficiently show the user
distant objects like the sun or
sky without having to
create a 3D model for them.
Which is super cool.
Returning back to clear facts,
let's quickly check the other options.
Our second option is solid color.
As you can probably guess, this sets
the background to a single color,
which we can change with
the background property.
The depth only option is useful in
cases where we have multiple cameras.
For example,
in shooting mixed reality footage.
In that scenario, we need one virtual
camera to capture foreground content
without any background.
In creating VR applications, it's very
unlikely you'll need to use this but
still good to know it exists.
Lastly is the don't clear option.
Never use this for VR.
The don't clear option uses
the image from the previous frame as
the background for the next image.
This results in a very
disorienting experience.
And that covers clear flags and
skyboxes.
Next we'll be looking
at the culling mask.