In this question I'm going to ask you about whether certain image functions are linear.
A function is linear if each resulting pixel of the processed image
is a linear combination of input pixels.
They could be weighted by constants like plus 1 or minus 1,
and they could be added up. Addition is linear.
But for example, taking the square of a pixel is a non-linear operation.
I realize this question goes beyond what we discussed in class,
so please think a little bit about it and understand the difference
between linear and nonlinear in trying to answer these questions.
First is our gradient kernel here: minus 1, 1.
Please check if it's linear or nonlinear.
Again, the linearity of an output image is given if the output image is a linear function
of the pixels in the input image.
How about our Gaussian kernel that we discussed in class of size 5 by 5?
Is the kernal linear or nonlinear?
How would we take the absolute value of a pixel?
If pixels are negative, we just ignore the negative sign and map back to the absolute value.
Is it linear or nonlinear?
We talked about the gradient magnitude kernel,
which was defined over a square root of the squares of the image gradients.
Is this a linear or nonlinear operation.
Finally, if you were to calculate the absolute brightness of a grey-scale image,
or let me call this the average brightness.
We have an imager of a certain size and like to calculate just the average brightness
of all the individual image pixels. They are all in greyscale.
Is this linear or nonlinear?