Hey Tommy, what do you think of our app?
>> Yeah, look, you can even put
your paw on this red paw button.
>> And if you want,
we can add you to it too.
>> Yeah,
I don't think he's a fan of our app.
>> Man, Tommy,
why do you have such high standards?
>> I don't know.
This just means we need to step
up our game in the next lesson.
>> Actually, speaking of which, we had
a problem with the previous lesson.
>> What, then why did we teach it?
>> Well, we don't want to directly call
the SQLite database like we're doing
right now from an activity code.
because that's just an easy
way to introduce bugs.
because for example,
if we were to have a typo in activity,
that would just insert invalid
data into the database.
>> I guess so.
>> Well, how about in this lesson, we'll
be introducing a concept called content
providers, which will act as a layer
between the database and the activity.
So there's going to be a lot of
benefits to using content providers.
So one reason that we're going to be
using it in our app is to ensure that
the data we're inserting
into the database is valid.
>> Okay, I think that makes sense then.
Content providers then.
But we're going to have to introduce
things like URIs, UriMatcher,
content resolver,
all of these different things.
Are you sure you want to cover all that?
>> Yeah, absolutely,
I think our students are ready for that.
And so is Tommy, right?
So content providers are going to help
us a lot later on when we want to take
advantage of other framework classes
to load data from a database
more smoothly into the UI.
>> Yeah, the content provider works
well with those framework classes.
I guess we should use it then.
Let's go for it.
>> All right, let's go Tommy.