Let's check out the features
of the My Favorite Movies app.
When open the app we're presented
with this nice login screen and
the user is prompted for
their username and a password.
I'll go ahead and
enter my credentials and log in.
Once we're in were presented with this
tab control and it has four tabs.
And the log out button is in
the top left hand corner.
And on the first three tabs we have
the statically defined movie genres.
We have sci-fi, comedy, action.
And in any of these tabs there's 20
movies listed in no particular order.
Then on the last tab we have
our favorite movies list.
For some of you,
you may have no movies here if you
haven't favorited anything yet.
But as you can see I have three movies
here that I've already added to my list.
I happen to know that the movie
Fury is on the Action's tab and
this is a movie I just recently
watched and I really liked it.
So I want to add it to my favorites but
I need to select it here first.
Then on the detail view, I'll tap the
heart icon to add it to my favorites.
If we go back to our Favorites list.
There you can see Fury's
been added to the bottom.
What's happening here is when I
tapped the heart button here I
favorited the movie and
that data was posted to the server.
Then when I returned
to the Favorites tab
on a separate request that movie was
returned to my new favorites list.
It's pretty cool.
Now that you know what this app should
do when it's done the next step is to
figure out to use the movie
database to create this app.