For the first one,
Messages is the correct answer.
This is very timely information and
it's not going to be relevant many hours
later, if the wearable is not connected.
This one is Data Items.
These are settings which would
be useful to store permanently
in case a new wearable
is paired up later on.
For this question,
the answer is Data Items.
While on a run, the wearable
might not have data connectivity.
So store it in the data layer to
ensure it will be synced up later on
when possible.
This one is Messages.
This is information which
is only relevant right now.
Later on it will not be useful, so
there's no need to store it
permanently in the data layer.
And for this question here,
the answer is Data Items.
This notification may be around for
a while, and it's important that it
shows up on the device,
even if it's not currently paired.
This cannot be lost, because it
might be important to the user.