You can think of, the first one
is the default discard policy.
The second one,
is similar to default allowed policy or
default forward policy.
The third one is in between the two.
The first one accepts only
packets it knows are safe.
It is similar to default,
discard policy.
In terms of security,
it is the best among the three.
In terms of ease of use, it is the
worst, because it may stop traffic that
is actually safe and useful to user,
but the firewall does not know it yet.
The second one,
drops packets it knows are unsafe.
In terms of security,
this is the worse because
of our knowledge about packets or
what traffic is unsafe is limited.
Because attackers are constantly
implementing new methods.
But in terms of ease of use,
it is the best.
Because the users will have access to
most of the traffic that they want.
The third one,
queries user about questionable packets.
This is in between the two.
Therefore, its security
is in between a two, and
ease of use is also in between a two.