We mentioned timeslices very briefly in
the introductory lesson on processes.
To define it more specifically,
a timeslice is the maximum amount of
uninterrupted time that
can be given to a task.
It is also referred
to as a time quantum.
The timeslice determines the maximum
amount, that means that a task can
actually run a less amount of time
than what the timeslice specifies.
For instance the task may need
to wait on an I/O operation or
to synchronize with some other tasks in
the system, on a mute tag that's locked.
In that case the task will
be placed on a queue,
will no longer be running on the CPU.
The task will run less amount of time,
once it's placed on the queue
the scheduler will pick
the next task to execute.
Also if we have
a priority-based scheduling,
a higher priority task will preempt
a lower priority one, which means that
the lower priority task will run less
amount of time than the timeslice.
Regardless of what exactly happens,
the use of timeslices allows us to
achieve for the tasks to be interleaved.
They will be timesharing the CPU.
For I/O bound tasks, this is not so
critical since they're constantly
releasing the CPU to
wait on some I/O event.
But for CPU bound tasks,
timeslices is the only event that
we can achieve time-sharing.
They will be preempted after some amount
of time as specified by the timeslice.
And we will schedule
the next CPU bound task.
Let's look at some examples now,
consider for
an instance the simple
first-come-first-serve and
shortest job first scheduler that we saw
earlier in this lesson, they both had
a same mix of task with same arrival
times but led to different metrics.
And, note that the metrics that we
computed for first-come-first-serve
also apply to a round-robin scheduler
that doesn't use timeslices.
Given that these tasks don't perform any
I/O, they just execute for some fixed,
specified amount of time.
Then, round-robin would
have scheduled them one and
after another the way they
showed up in the queue.
And, that would have been identical
to first-come-first-serve.
Now let's calculate the metrics for
a round-robin scheduler with timeslices,
and let's say we'll first
look at a timeslice of 1.
The execution of these
tasks will look as follows.
T1 will execute for 1 second,
that happens to be exactly the time
that T1 requires, so T1 will complete.
Then, with timeslicing, we would have
preempted the execution of T1 anyways.
We will execute T2.
Now, T2 needs more time to execute,
10 seconds.
So, it will actually be preempted.
T3 will run for 1 second.
At the time when we're about to preempt
it, the T3 will anyways complete, and
the only runnable task in the system
is T2, and we will execute T2.
So T2 will run for
the remainder of the time.
Now if we look at some of
the metrics for throughput,
we'll see we have the exact same thing.
It's still takes us 12 seconds to
complete these three tasks, so
the throughput will again be the same
as in the previous two systems.
Looking at the wait time,
we have a wait time of, 0, 1, and
2 for each of the tasks respectively.
So wait time is 1 second.
If we look at the average completion
time, the tasks complete at 1,
at 12, and at 3 seconds respectively.
So the average completion
time is 5.33 seconds.
So without even knowing what
are the execution times of these tasks,
with a timeslice of 1, we were able to
achieve a schedule that's really close
to this best one that we saw before,
the shortest job-first one.
This is good.
We keep some of the simplicity that
we had in first-come-first-serve.
We don't need to worry
about the going out,
what is the execution time of the task.
And yet
we're able to achieve good wait time and
good completion time for
all of the tasks.
Some of the benefits of this
timeslice-based method,
particularly when the timeslice is
relatively short like in this case,
is that we end up with a situation
where the short tasks finish sooner.
So T3 was able to complete much
sooner than in the first come,
first serve case.
And we're also able to achieve a
schedule of that is more responsive and
any I/O operations can be executed and
initiated as soon as possible.
So for instance, consider if T2 is
a task that the users interact with,
it will be able to start
as soon as possible,
only 1 second into the execution.
The users will see that it is running.
And yet it will be preempted to
squeeze in T3 at this point.
If T2 needs to initiate any I/O
operations, those will be initiated
during this interval that
it's running at this point.
That would not have been the case with
the shortest job first scheduler, and
because T2 would have only
been scheduled after all
of the shorter jobs complete,
so T1 and T3 in that case.
The downside is that we exaggerated so
far a little in that we had these tasks
immediately starting their execution
after the previous one was interrupted.
However, there's some real overheads.
We have to interrupt a running task.
We have to run the scheduler in order
to pick which task to run next.
And then we actually need to perform the
context which when we're scheduling from
the context of task of
one task to another.
All of these times are pure overhead.
There's no useful application processing
that's done during those intervals.
Know that these overheads, so
if we have a timeslice of one
these set time-outs for the timer will
appear during the execution of task
T2 except at that point since there
are no other runable tasks in the system
we're really not going to be
scheduling or contact switching.
And that's the dominant
part of the overhead.
And exactly how these
sticks are handled,
we're not really going to
discuss further in this class.
The dominant sources of these overheads
will impact the total execution of
this timeline, and increasing the time
will cause the throughput to go down.
Each of the tasks will also start
just a little bit later, so
the wait time will actually
increase a little bit.
And the completion time for each of the
tasks will be delayed by a little bit so
the average completion time
will increase as well.
The exact impact on these metrics will
depend on the length of the timeslice
and how it relates to the actual time
to perform these context switching and
scheduling actions, so as long as
the timeslice value significantly larger
than the context switch-time, we should
be able to minimize these overheads.
In general, we should consider both
the nature of the tasks as well as
the overheads in the system when
determining meaningful values for
the timeslice.