Most of the fields we can use as is
without any kind of transformation,
since they are all mostly
continuous in nature.
The two fields related to the first and
last winter freeze will probably be
important to have in our analysis.
But since they are both date fields,
they will need to be transformed
into something that we can use.
As I mentioned earlier in
reference to transforming dates,
since these are dates where the year
itself is not significant, but
rather just when they fall
within the yearly time frame,
one thing we can do is to calculate
the mean or median of the fields and
use that date as a reference
point to create a before and
after value to the reference
point we calculate.
In this case, I have already calculated
the median last winter freeze as
being April 23rd, and the median first
winter freeze as being October 6th.
With a Formula tool, I can create new
fields called LastWinterFreezeDiff and
FirstWinterFreezeDiff.
As you can see, it is basically the
difference between the calculated median
date and the date for each store.
It will provide a positive or
negative number that we can then
use in the clustering process.
Now when we run the process again,
we can see the newly calculated fields.
And since the data is
sorted by latitude,
then we can eyeball the data and
see that it makes sense.
The closer the store is to the equator,
the earlier the last winter freeze is,
as represented by a negative number, and
the later the first winter freeze is,
as represented by a positive number.
And now that we have our data
as we want it, we can save it
to a new file that we will use for
the next step in the process.
I just drop in an Output Data tool and
save the results to a new file.
I'll save it as a CSV and
call mine Data Prep Exercise Results.
To save that, you'll need to
run the process one more time.