However, packet filtering
also has weaknesses.
Since packet filtering firewalls
do not examine upper layer data,
they cannot prevent attacks that employ
application-specific vulnerabilities or
functions.
For example,
a packet filtering firewall cannot block
specific application commands or
contents because, if the firewall allows
a given application, then all functions,
all commands, all contents within
the application must be permitted.
For example,
once Web traffic is allowed,
the firewall cannot block
certain offensive page contents.
The logging capabilities of packet
filtering firewall is also limited.
Again, this is because packet
filtering firewall does not examine
upper layer data.
For example, the packet filtering
firewall may allow FTP traffic but
cannot log the actual FTP data, such as
which files are being transmitted, and,
since packet filtering firewall
makes decisions on per packet basis,
it cannot prevent attacks
that span multiple packets.
That is,
it cannot see attacks that require
multiple packets of a connection.
Finally, as our example shows,
packet filtering firewalls tend to have
rules that have a small number
of variables or conditions.
That is, these rules may
not be specific enough, and
attacks can bypass the firewall.