This nanodegree will help you become
a data analyst, but before you start,
you should have solid understanding
of programming and statistics.
If you're not sure if you have the
needed prerequisites, you should take
the readiness assessment and see if you
can confidently answer the questions.
If you haven't yet,
this is required to continue.
Please pause this video and follow
the link in the instructor notes to now.
>> Time commitment is the other most
important thing to think about when
trying to decide if this is the right
time for you to start the nanodegree.
You'll need to commit at least ten
hours per week for your courses,
projects, and community events.
>> And you should most definitely
be excited and driven to learn.