Another similarity metric that
we can play around with would be
compute the Manhattan Distance
between two frames.
So, here basically again, we look
at the two different frames, p and
q, how each one of them has an elements.
And here the difference basically is
taking the difference from each, and
every pixel value intensity one by one,
and
just adding them together will
give you a very large number.
Again, if they're completely different,
very small number, of course,
that they're not very different for
each and every one of them.
And so, a simpler equation that does it,
if it a summation would be this, and
of course,
this metric is referred to as L1 norm.
And just to note the the bars here
to kind of give it an absolute
value of this because we don't want to
get negatives, and stuff like that,
we just want to get the positive value
out of it, that's another metric.
Actually, in practice,
both of them work quite well.