To achieve its goals,
an operating system supports a number of higher-level abstractions, and
then a number of key mechanisms that operate on top of these instructions.
For instance, some of these abstractions, like process and
thread, correspond to the applications that the operating system executes.
Some corresponding mechanisms would be mechanisms to create, to launch
an application to start executing, or to schedule it to actually run on the CPU.
Other OS abstractions like file or socket that we've mentioned before or
memory page, they may more closely correspond to
the hardware resources that the operating systems need to manage.
Storage device like disk, or a network card for the socket, or the actual
memories, so, memory pages in abstraction abstract memory as a resource.
To operate on these abstractions, the operating system may
incorporate mechanisms to open gain access to a particular device or
hardware component, to write to it, to update its state, to allocate to
make sure that a particular application has access to that resource.
These are some examples of mechanisms.
Operating systems may also integrate specific policies that determine
exactly how these mechanisms will be used to manage the underlying hardware.
For instance, a policy can control what is the maximum number of
sockets that a process can actually have access to.
Or they may control which data will be removed from physical memory, for
instance, based on some algorithm like least-recently used.