There are many details related to interrupt handling that we'll not discuss in
this class.
I would like to make some final notes about interrupts.
And specifically, interrupts in the presence of multi-core Systems.
Actually, this applies not just to multi-core Systems, but
to multi-CPU systems in general.
On the multi-CPU systems,
the interrupt routing logic will direct the interrupt to any one of the CPUs.
That, at a particular point of time, has that Interrupt enabled.
The reason we put this crown here is, what we can do in these multi-CPU systems.
We can specify that only one of the CPUs,
only one of the cores, is designated for handling the interrupts.
That one will be the only CPU that has the interrupts enabled.
And so, what that will allow us to do is we'll be able to avoid any overheads or
perturbations related to interrupt handling from any of the other cores.
The net effect will be in proof performance.