Up until now, we've been declaring lots
of variables with the keyword var.
Now I want to talk about its companion,
the keyword let.
In Swift, there are two different
ways to assign a name to a value,
values can be assigned to constants or
variables.
Constants are declared
using the keyword let and
variables are declared
using the keyword var.
Not surprisingly,
once the value of a constant is set,
it can't be reassigned,
the value remains constant.
So once you use let when assigning
a value that's not expected to change.
Variables, on the other hand,
can be reassigned.
So once you'd use var, when assigning
a value that's expected to change.
Here, the encouragement sting stays
the same so it's declared as a constant.
The personalized encouragement string
changes so it's declared as a variable.
Here's another example.
Birth year doesn't change, but
time keeps progressing forward.
So current year does change,
as does age.
But notice that context matters as well.
The previous example assumes
that the variable age
is going to be calculated
multiple times.
If age was only intended
to be calculated once,
then we would go ahead and declare
age and current year as constants.
When in doubt,
declare a constant over a variable.
Anytime a value is altered,
it should be explicit.
This protects our code by preventing us
from inadvertently changing values that
we don't want changed.