To start,
let's open up the unlit apartment scene.
Now it's time to add our first light.
To clearly see a difference,
we'll add a directional light.
Go to Game Object, Light,
Directional Light.
And just like that, our scene is super
bright, maybe a little too bright.
Think of a directional light as light
that comes from a far away object,
something like the sun.
As a result, no matter where we
move the light in this scene,
our scene will be lit the same.
However, if we rotate our light, notice
how the lighting in our scene changes.
Think of this in the way
that lighting from a sunset
is different from high noon.
Both are coming from a distant object
like the sun, but the angle at which
they hit our world is different and
that creates a different effect.
Let's move on to another light.
Put the directional
light in the hierarchy.
If we look at the inspector, we'll
notice that there's a light component
and within that light component
there's a type property.
Since we just created
a directional light,
the type component is
set to directional.
Let's now go ahead and
change it to point.
As soon as we did that,
you'll see that the whole scene pretty
changed back to where we started.
That's because unlike
a directional light,
a point light emits light from its
current position just like a light bulb.
Let's move our light to a place
where we can really see its effect.
Change its position to
0.5, 1.5, -1.
Now if we look at that area of the scene
you should it looks a bit brighter.
To really see the lighting effect,
let's drag the light around.
If you look at the wall, you can
clearly see the light effects move
as you drag the light with
the translation tool.
Just like a light bulb, a point light
emits light in the sphere around it,
which means rotations don't affect it,
unlike a directional light.
If we zoom out of our scene,
we can see the range of our light bulb.
We can actually control this property
and it's conveniently called range.
Let's set the range to 100.
If we zoom back in we can see that
the light got a lot brighter.
That's because Unity
fades the light intensity
as you travel further away
from the point light.
If we increase the range,
that fading slows down
since the fade needs to cover 100 units
instead of the ten it defaulted to.
Let's now explore another light by
changing the type property to spot.
Like the point light, the spot light
is dependent on its position but
also its rotation,
just like a directional light.
Its equivalent use in the real world
is like a lighthouse, flashlight, or
a stage spotlight, which is where
the name actually comes from.
A spotlight basically shoots
out a cone of light, and
we can control the range of it
as well as how wide the cone is.
We can control that width by
changing the spotlight angle.
Let's make it huge to light up our whole
apartment, and try something like 120.
As you can see, that widens our
spotlight so it hits everything nearby.
The last light we need to
talk about is the area light.
As soon as we do that, you'll notice
there is no light in our scene anymore.
You probably noticed, but
the area light is marked as baked,
which is actually the reason why it
doesn't immediately show any lighting.
The reason for this is because area
lights are pretty complex, and
can't be run in real time.
We'll discuss this in more detail later.
But for now, know that area lights have
to be baked, which means we need to do
some computation before we run our
experience in order to view our lights.
But before we see these area lights in
action, I just want to mention that
you can intuitively think of them
as flood lights in a stadium.
They have a width and
height parameter that we can control,
which floods light from
the rectangle that we create.
And with that we've briefly touched
on all four Unity lights and
how they are different.
We can now check out the properties
that make them the same.