We're not done yet.
Things are working, but
there are lots of things that
aren't being handled well.
What happens if there
are slow connectivity?
isn't any connectivity?
We're going to add a bit of polish to
make for a better user experience.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The to-do manager is, once again,
wow, [LAUGH] that's a lot of to-dos.
Don't panic.
Remember the polish takes time, and this
is the kind of stuff that distinguishes
pro-Android apps from the rest.
We'll start by adding an error
string called error_message.
We're going to display this
whenever the response is null, so
we're going to make
the message very generic.
Failed to get results, please try again.
Sounds pretty good to us.
Let's talk about layout.
We're going to display something
alternate in the area that currently
houses our scrollview when there
is an error or during progress.
To begin to do this, we'll wrap
the scroll view with the frame layout,
meaning that we add a frame layout
to the linear layout at the same
level as the scroll view and move
the scroll view into the frame layout.
We want to make sure that the frame
layout takes up all the remaining space
in the linear layout, so we tell it to
match the parent in height and width.
Next, we'll add a text view to
display the error message, setting
the text size to 22 sp and giving
it an ID of error_message_display.
We'll give it the same padding as the
scroll view, set it to the error stream
we just created, and
make it start off as invisible.
Let's now go to MainActivity.
First, we'll create a member variable
to store the reference to our
errorMessageText and
then set it in onCreate.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now we'll add some helper methods,
first one to show the JSON data view and
then one to show the error message.
These methods will show
the selected view and
hide the other by setting
the visibility of each view.
Finally, let's go to onPostExecute.
If our result is not null or empty,
we'll add an else to show the error
message with showErrorMessage,
but we're not done yet.
When we have a successful transaction,
we'll show the JSON data view
with our new helper method.
Otherwise, the view might be hidden if
the user first had a failed transaction.
Let's run this to see what happens
when we don't have Internet now.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now we'll hook up the progress bar.
We go back to the main activity layout,
and add a progress bar
to the frame layout.
We'll fix its layout, height, and width
and tell frame layout to center it.
We'll give it an ID of
pb_loading_indicator.
Then, we'll make it invisible.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Back to main activity, as before, we'll
start by adding a member variable and
setting this in onCreate.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
In our onPreExecute, we'll set the
visibility of this loading indicator to
visible, and in the onPostExecute,
we'll begin by setting it to invisible.
Because it is last in
the frame layout XML,
it will draw on top of
any of the other views.
[BLANK_AUDIO]