Now we know that adding levels to our
address translation process will reduce
the size of the page tables.
But it will add some overheads to
the address translation process.
In the simple,
single level page table design,
a memory reference will actually
require two memory references.
One to access the page table entries so
that we can determine the physical
frame number, and the second one to
actually perform the proper memory
access at the correct physical address.
In the four level page table,
however, we will need to perform four
memory accesses to read the page
table entries at each level
of the memory hierarchy, before we can
produce the physical frame number.
And only afterwards are we able to
actually perform the proper access to
the correct physical memory location.
Obviously this can be very costly and
can lead to a slowdown.
The standard technique to avoid
these repeated accesses to memory
is to use a page table cache.
On most architectures, the MMU
hardware integrates a hardware cache
that's dedicated for
caching address translations, and
this cache is called the Translation
Look Aside Buffer or TLB.
On each address translation first
the TLB cache is quickly referenced and
if the resulting address can be
generated from the TLB contents then we
have a TLB hit and we can bypass
all of the other required memory
accesses to perform the translation.
Of course, if we have a TLB miss, so
the address isn't present in the TLB
cache, then we have to perform
all of the address translation steps by
accessing the page tables from memory.
In addition to the proper
address translation,
the TLB entries will contain all of the
necessary protection and validity bits
to verify that the access is correct or,
if necessary, to generate a fault.
It turns out that even a small number
of entries in the TLB can result in
a high TLB rate and this is because
we have typically a high temporal and
spatial locality in
the memory references.
On recent x86 platforms, for
instance, there is a separate TLB for
data and instruction.
And each of those has
a modest number of entries.
64 for the data and 128 for
the instruction TLB.
These are per core and
in addition to these two,
there is also another
shared second level TLB
that's shared across all cores and
that's, that one is a little bit larger.
It has 512 entries.
So this is for the I7 in platforms.
And this was determined to
be sufficiently effective
to address the typical memory
access needs of processes today.