Congratulations, you
just made a web page.
And even though it's simple and
not very interesting, that's coding.
You told the computer what to do and
it listened.
You'll learn a lot more about how to
do this in the rest of Nanodegree,
but first let's take a couple minutes
and talk about what the Nanodegree is,
how it will work, and
what you're going to get out of it.
So what is this Nanodegree?
Most importantly it's a path.
And this path starts with nothing.
We assume you can open a web page and
nothing else.
But as you progress you're going
to gain three important things.
You'll gain new knowledge, new skills,
and even new ways of thinking
about problems that aren't even
related to computer programming.
At the end of it all, you'll get to
a point where you can make a choice.
You'll understand your options and
be able to evaluate what
it is you want to do next.
You could choose to learn
Full stack programming.
Or maybe Front end web development.
Or, maybe you want to
be an iOS developer.
You could learn that, too.
Or you might choose to learn
something else entirely.
Or even nothing else at all.
But at the very least,
at the end of this Nanodegree,
you will know enough to be dangerous.