It's finally time to
import your first project.
So, we're going to do is we're
going to open up Android Studio and
get to this splash screen.
If you can't see it, then go ahead and
close any projects that you have
open and you should get back here.
Then you want to select import
project Eclipse ADT, Gradle, etc.
Now, you want to navigate to wherever
you put the downloaded code.
If you put it on the Desktop
you can just click this button
to jump straight to the Desktop.
So here's my ud405 folder.
If you can't see it you might
try hitting these blue arrows.
That'll refresh Android Studio's
view of your file system and
that might make it pop up.
Anyway, I'll open up this folder and
we'll start with
Getting Started With LibGDX file.
Just go ahead and
highlight it and hit okay.
Now this next step might take a while.
This is where Android Studio is talking
with Gradle to figure out what source
files and
resources are part of this project, and
what tasks can be done
with this project.
Also, Gradle is telling Android Studio
what dependencies this project has,
what other libraries it's going to use.
And Gradle is downloading those
libraries from the Internet.
If all goes well there
will be no errors and
we've successfully imported
our first project.
If you want to see the files in
the project you can open up this
project pane.
If you have something that looks like
this then you did everything right.
All right, it's your turn to
import your first LibGDX project.
Open Android Studio,
close any open projects so
that you get to
the Android Studio splash screen
click on the import project
to Eclipse ADT, Gradle, etc.
Button.
Then navigate to wherever
you put the course code,
/1.2.01-Demo-GettingStartedWithLibGDX,
and click okay.
That's all there is to it.