[Thrun] One of the oddities of the maximum likelihood estimator is overfitting.
So for example, we observed that we always have a single first day,
and this becomes our prior probability.
So in this case the prior probability for rain on day 0 would be 1,
which kind of doesn't make sense, really.
It should be more like the stationary distribution or something like that.
Well, you might remember the work on Laplacian smoothing.
This is a great moment where I can test whether you really think
like an artificial intelligence person.
I'm going to make you apply Laplacian smoothing in this new context
of estimating the parameters of this Markov chain
using the smoother of K = 1.
You might remember you add something to the numerator, like 1,
and something to the denominator to make sure things normalize,
and then you get different probabilities
than you would get with the maximum likelihood estimator.
So I'm going to ask you a quiz here, even though I haven't completely shown you
the application of Laplacian smoothing in this context.
But if you understood Laplacian smoothing, you might want to give it a try.
What's the probability of rain on day 0, and what are its conditional probabilities?
Sun goes to sun, sun goes to rain, rain goes to sun, and rain stays in rain.
The way probabilities work, as you surely know, these 2 things over here
have to add up to 1, and these 2 things over here have to add up to 1.