All of these are true. This is all the data that we have. There's no way to
calculate a mean or standard deviation. And the data are based on frequencies
and proportions. The proportion of successful attempts out of unsuccessful
attempts for Summit Up. And for the whole population of everyone that has
attempted to climb Mount Shasta. The data is nominal. Successful versus
unsuccessful. And finally the data are not based on normal distributions.
They're just frequencies. If we go into this point a little bit more, what
would our raw data look like? If we could document each attempt to climb Mount
Shasta. The first, second, third, all the way to n. the result would either be
success or failure. Rather than writing out n success or failures, we'll just
count the number of successes and failures and either write them as a frequency
or proportion where the proportion of successes plus failures has to add to 1.