Before we move on to creating
our own if statements,
let's look at a few examples.
To see these examples in action,
open up the ifstatements.playground file
which is part of the iOS
playground collection.
To see your results in the console go
to the view menu, click debug area, and
then show debug area.
First focus on the following
lines of code in example one.
Notice that as our playground executes,
nothing's being printed
out in the console below.
Now try changing hungry to be
true like this, what happens?
Notice that when hungry is true,
the function go eat is called and
a message prints to the console.
And the message that's
printed is nom nom.
Now let's move on to example two.
Try changing the value of the bull have
money to true and see what happens.
I'll go ahead and change it myself, and
now we see snuggle snuggle
printed to the console.
That's because the buyTeddy function is
being called, because wantTeddyBear and
haveMoney are both true.
Moving on to example three.
See what happens when you
change raining to true.
And now we're getting this third
output in the console area.
It says, where's this movie quote from?
I don't scratch my head
unless it itches, and
I don't dance unless I hear some music.
I will not be intimidated,
that's just the way it is.
That's actually a quote from
one of my favorite movies.
You can look it up if you'd like.