When you start talking about
Version Control Systems.
There are a lot of options.
You could be using Git, Mercurial,
or even older ones like Subversion.
There's also a bunch of proprietary
enterprise systems, all of that said,
most of the open source dev apps tools
easily integrate with get repositories.
And they also work well with GitHub, and
so that's what we're going to use for
this course.
Beyond deciding what Version
Control System you're going to use,
you also have to decide on the strategy
for using version control.
Depending on the size of the project and
the team,
different strategies can be used.
The most important thing is that
everybody agrees to a strategy and
sticks to it.
In general,
there are three major strategies.
Those are Release Branching,
Feature Branching, and Task Branching.
For each of these version
control strategies,
you're going to have some space for
developers to work on new code.
And that new code is eventually
going to be merged back into one or
more main branches.
This merging or integrating into the
main branch is generally what triggers
the rest of the continuous integration,
continuous delivery process.