Algorithmically it's pretty
straightforward to do this.
All right.
We start off at any point in time we
have a set of particles at the last time
step and each particle has a state,
like its position and a weight.
And we're also going to be given a new
action, like let's take a step to
the meet, to the right two meters, and
we're going to take a new measurement.
And then here's how
the particle filter runs.
We start off with a new
set of particles,
empty and a normalization constant of 0,
makes sense.
And then we just do
the following n times,
where n is the number of
particles that we need, all right?
So, the first thing we do is we sample a
particle from the previous distribution
that's from this distribution here,
according to its weight.
Okay, so
we just sample a particle, okay.
The next thing we do,
this is actually a combined step, okay.
It says control, but it really
should say control and control and
diffusion, right?
We sample a new state using two things.
Whatever the old one was,
so that's the value we pulled
from the particle, right?
That's this xt here.
We've sampled the particle.
It has a particular state
that goes right in there.
We also have the action.
And then, we have to sample
from the new distribution.
So, let's suppose the action is taking
a step immediately to the right.
Every time we do this,
make it go all right?
Take a step meter to the right and then,
I'm going to sample from a distribution
because there's actually some
uncertainty about that step, right?
That's our process noise, so
it's a little tight Gaussian.
I generated a,
a little bit of noise and I add that.
That's what this sampling value is here.
Using the previous sample, the control,
and then whatever the noise is, okay?
Then what I do is I
re-weight that sample.
What do I weight it by?
I weight it by how likely would
the measurement have been,
this is my likelihood, okay?
How likely would that
measure have been if that
new sample is actually where the the
object was or where the robot was?
That becomes my new weight.
All right.
That's the multiplication
step we did before.
We took our prior, we had those lumps,
we multiplied and we got them through.
We just keep track of
the sum of those weights,
we add that particle to our growing set
of particles, and we do this n times.
Now we're all done, except one problem,
our weights don't sum to what?
They don't sum to 1 because
they were whatever they were.
We just did this multiplication.
So all we have to do is because we've
been keeping track of the sum of the sum
of the weights, that's theta.
We divide all the weights by that value.
And that's normalizing the weights.
When we're done, we have a new
distribution, bunch of particles.
Each particle is at a particular state.
Each particle has a weight.
And the sum of those weights is 1.
And so that's a valid,
sampling-based representation
of the probabilistic density.
And that's it.
That's all of particle filtering.