Okay. Our final homework question for this unit is to implement logout.
Logout is very simple. Let me give you a demo of this.
We are at our welcome page here, and if I reload this welcome page,
it continues to say "Welcome, spez!" because my cookie is linked to the spez user.
I want you to implement a URL "logout," and when we visit it, it redirects you to the signup page
and it clears the any cookies.
You can see the user ID cookie here is empty, which is basically how you delete a cookie.
You set that cookie to empty.
If I were to go back to that welcome page, it would redirect me back to signup,
because I don't have a valid cookie.
Logout--all you do is delete the cookie and redirect to signup.
When you have that working, enter the URL here.
Once you've gotten this working, you are a master of user accounts,
and you should be proud of yourself.
Good luck.