So now we recognize that there
are potentially two types
of content URIs that
we can use in our app.
So one to get all the rows
from the table and
another type to get just
a single row from the table.
Now, let's put these into context and
actually see them in some use cases.
So in this use case, we need to display
the list of pets in our CatalogActivity.
Which means that we'll need to
query the whole pets table.
Now, to do so we could use the content
URI that ends with the table name,
and this means that no ID will
be added at the end of the URI
because we want all that information
from the entire pets table.
So here's our second use case, in the
editor activity say we need to display
the existing pet details of
a pet already in our pets table.
Well, since we need information about a
single pet, we need to grab a single row
from the table, which means we need
the URI that ends with the ID.
And this will help us grab
information about just this pet.
So to help you practice,
here's an exercise to help you determine
when best to use each type of URI.
So for each situation listed here, I'd
like you to chose whether Option A, or
Option B would better help us get
the information that we need.
So first, Option A is one where the
content URI is for the whole pets table.
And content B is one for
the URI where we just want
a single row from the pets table.
So here are the situations that
I'd like you to check out.
So the first one, in the EditorActivity,
which one do we need when we use
Update in existing pet if
we're given this id is 1?
Secondly what about deleting that pet,
also having an id of 1.
And then, lastly,
in EditorActivity, what about
if we're saving off a new pet.
Now, in the CatalogActivity which one
of these two options will help us out
if we're inserting new dummy pets.
And then, lastly, which one would
we need to delete all the pets.