Distributed shared memory can be
supported either in hardware, or
by software.
The key component of the hardware
supported distributed shared memories,
is that they rely on some
high end interconnect.
The operating system running
on each individual node,
is under the impression that it has much
larger physical memory, constituting
memory that spans multiple memory nodes,
multiple physical nodes in the system.
So, the OS is allowed to establish
virtual to physical memory mappings that
correspond to memory locations
that are in other nodes.
The memory accesses that reference
memory locations that don't correspond
to the local physical memory are then
passed to the network interconnect card
and this is a NIC that
corresponds to this advanced
high end interconnect technology.
So, these NICs know how to translate
that memory operation, into
an actual message that gets sent to the
correct remote node, the correct NIC.
The NICs in these nodes will
participate in al aspects
that are necessary to deal
with memory accesses,
and management of memory consistency and
we'll also support certain
atomic operations just like the atomics
that we saw in shared memory systems.
Now while it's very convenient to rely
on the hardware to do everything,
this type of hardware is typically
very expensive and it's used only for
the ultra high end machines or for
the super computing platforms.
Instead, distributed shared memory
systems can be realized in software.
Here the software would have to detect
which memory accesses are local
versus remote to create and send those
messages to the appropriate note,
whenever that's what, what's necessary.
The software would also have to
accept messages from other notes and
perform the specific memory operations
for them and also be involved in all of
the aspects of memory sharing and
consistency support.
This can be done at the level
of the operating system or
it can be done with support
of a programming language and
the runtime product
programming language.