Now what's also interesting, is that
you can use the allocation tracker tool
to identify the extraneous memory bloat,
that arises from stale
views residing in memory.
Now as you can see here,
I've selected a common set of objects or
classes that are still
residing on the heap.
Now these objects are put onto the heap,
when we call onCreate on
this particular activity.
Now each time the device is rotated,
a new activity is created and
thus a similar set of objects are
basically inflated and put on the heap.
So if a leak exists, and
we rotate the device,
the garbage collector won't be able
to cle, clean up these items and
will essentially replicate a large
set of these on, on the heap.
An allocation tracker
will help you see this.