In the last two exercises,
I've been meddling with the network
connection, turning it off and back on.
The tool I'm using to do this is
called the Network Link Conditioner.
It's one of many tools that Apple
makes available to developers for
testing their apps.
In fact, this tool can do a lot
more than just turning the network
on and off.
It can also vary the network connection
by what are known as profiles.
A network profile, like the ones listed
here, 100% loss, 3G, DSL they allow
us to specify things like the up and
down bandwidth and packet loss rates.
So you can choose from
any of the presets here.
Or you can even create your
own in Manage Profiles.
I think it goes without saying that
this tool is an invaluable resource for
testing your networking apps.