All right.
So the next thing we want to show
is if we have an algorithm that
has a bounded number of mistakes in
the sense that we just talked about.
That that algorithm will
eventually do well,
in the sense that it will achieve a
total reward that is arbitrarily close,
epsilon prime close to
the per step optimal reward.
So let's imagine that we have an
algorithm that pulls epsilon suboptimal
arms at most this bounded number
of times with high probability.
So this is something that
has very few mistakes.
Oh.
Except this wants to be tau.
Right.
Given that algorithm,
we want to make a new algorithm,
that with high probability,
one minus delta prime, has a per step
reward that is epsilon prime close
to the optimal per step award.
In other words,
what we would've gotten for
pulling the optimal arm on every step.
And that bound starts to hold after
some number of steps, tau prime,
k epsilon prime delta prime.
>> So does that mean we get to do
the same thing that we did before?
>> Let's try that.
>> Okay.
>> We run this mistake bound algorithm
that makes very few mistakes.
What's our tau prime?
When is it that we're going to
have achieved near optimality?
>> Because algorithm b is the same as
algorithm a, it means that by running
algorithm b, we're going to end up
with an arm that is epsilon optimal.
>> Yes that's true, but
I don't want to think about it that way.
I don't want to bring algorithm
A in to this at the moment.
Lets stick with the algorithm
on the slide, algorithm B.
>> So, we have an algorithm that pulls
epsilon suboptimal that many times.
That implies the way it's written,
that you could have pulled
a bunch of epsilon optimal arms,
many, many times during that.
>> Yes.
>> But not during that time period, like
you could have pulled epsilon optimal
a zillion times and then pulled
epsilon sub optimal tau times.
>> Yes.
>> And
then it would be tau plus a bezillion.
>> Yes.
>> Would be the total number of steps.
>> Yes, so yeah, this is all true.
>> So, okay, so
we need to kind of think about how we
can use that fact to build a bound.
>> Hm.