In this lesson,
we'll cover the minimum changes required
to get your app running on Android tv.
We'll also discuss how to prep
your development environment.
Users will launch your app from
the Android tv home screen.
Your app will appear in the apps row,
and
will be represented by a 320
by 180 pixel banner image.
When the user chooses our banner,
Android tv will launch an activity
we specify in the manifest.
But first,
I want to show you there's an even
better way to attract users to your app.
That's recommendations.
This is the recommendations row, and
your app can suggest content to appear
right here, front and
center on the Android T.V. home screen.
For example,
let's say the user just watched the
first couple of episodes in the series.
Your app could recommend the next
episode to appear right here.
And of course,
since Android TV is built by Google,
users can find your content by
searching for it with their voice.
More on Reqs and Search later.
Let's take a look at our
application manifest.
The most important thing to note is
the leanback launcher intent filter.
This identifies our app as being
enabled for TV, and it's required for
our app to be considered
a TV app in Google Play.
It's also used to specify the activity
that will be launched when a user
chooses her app on the Android T.V.
home screen.
Above that, you can see an activity that
will be launched when the user runs our
app on a mobile device.
If you plan to use the lean back support
library, as we will in this class,
the new must include Theme.Leanback.
This is required by most of
the fragments provided by
the support library.
If you'd like to create your own theme,
no problem, but
be sure to inherit from Theme.Leanback
and override specific styles.
Now, if you're modifying
an existing app to also run on TV,
it's important not to reuse the same
activity layout as for mobile devices.
Building a slick user interface like the
one we saw earlier can be challenging,
but I've got great news for you.
The leanback support library
includes fragments and
widgets that will make this hella easy.
Leanback provides fragments and
widgets for building T.V.
apps, including a catalog browser,
a details view, and playback controls.
Also included are nice card views for
displaying text and pictures.
Recyclerview helps us scroll through and
display large lists of
media items efficiently.
This is important to do on a T.V.
device where media is rich and
memories limited.
In order to be listed as compatible
with TV devices and Google Play,
your app must declare that you use
the feature android.software.leanback.
If your APK will also run in other
devices like phones, tablets or wear.
Then you must declare
that required is false.
Also note that leanback here refers to
the Android TV home screen launcher app,
not the support libraries.
So you use this regardless of whether
you use the support libraries or not.
Now, if you're using Android Studio,
all of the dependencies for the Leanback
libraries will automatically be
added to your build.gradle file.
On the other hand, if you're using
Eclipse, see the instructor notes.
Also, a quick note for
completeness, Leanback depends
on the v4 support library.
Users will interact with your app
using a TV remote control, or
a game controller.
Because of this, make sure your app
supports a d-pad control scheme.
Android automatically applies
directional navigation between your
layout elements automatically.
So you usually don't need to do anything
extra to have your app work with
a remote control.
Just in case navigation
doesn't work out of the box or
it doesn't work the way you prefer.
You can create a custom control scheme
by checking out the instructor note.
Let's talk for
a moment about T.V. hardware.
Now obviously T.V.'s have a lot
of hardware differences with
a mobile device.
I don't know about yours but my T.V.
doesn't have an accelerometer for
example.
Will cover these in detail later.
But for now there's one feature you
always have to specify is not required
in your manifest.
And that's a touch screen.
More detail soon.
Last, let's talk for
a moment about Android versions.
Android T.V.
support first appeared in Android 5.0.
Before you begin building Android T.V.
apps update your SDK to version 21 or
higher.
Also update your S.T.K.
tools to version 24 or higher.
And be sure that your project targets
at least A.P.I. level twenty one.
More details on these are in the notes.
Okay, that's everything you
need to know to get started.
In the next lessons, we'll talk
about hardware differences and
the lean back support library.
Then it's on decode.
What's the name of the intent filter,
you need to specify for
your main activity on T.V. Refer to
the developer training if you get stuck