So now our users can view dinners as
a starting step in the shopping process.
The next step is to let them
put dinners in the cart.
We're going to add a button
to the Order Dinner screen
to let users put the dinner in the cart.
So far, the order dinner activity
has used the generic show_info
layout but now it needs its own layout
file so we can add the buttons to it.
We'll still use the show info fragment
to show the information
about the dinner.
So you're going to add a new layout file
called order_dinner.xml to the layout
folder.
This is a scroll view with
a linear layout, and it uses
the UseInfoBoxFragment to show the
information about the selected dinner.
And then it has some buttons.
The first button is Add to cart, and
there's some more buttons in here.
And they're commented out for now, and
you can add them in as you need them.
So you're going to be adding
the button to the Order Dinner screen.
And first you're going to
add order_dinner.xml.
And then you're going to need to update
order dinner activity
to use the new layout.
And you do that in the on create
method and specify the new layout.
So to send a hit to analytics when
a user puts a product in the cart,
you need to create the product and
the product action as before.
And set the product
action to ACTION_ADD.
So you're going to need to
define some methods in
the Order Dinner Activity class.
To add the dinner to the cart and
to send the Add to Cart hit.
Now for the add dinner to cart,
skeleton code only is enough.
Since this is a course about analytics,
not about implementing shopping carts,
we can gloss over the code to actually
add the dinner to the cart with a wave
of our hand.
But since this is a course
about analytics, I do expect
you to implement the method that sends
the add to cart hit to analytics.
So a full implementation here please.
So a method that's used as the action
of a button must take a single argument
of a view.
So you'll need to define a method,
let's call it addDinnerToCart,
that takes a view.
And then it adds the dinner to the cart
and sends it here to analytics.
And for now, we don't need to implement
the code to actually add the dinner to
the cart, but it's nice to get
the feedback that something happened.
So I always like to Add a toast,
so go ahead and show a toast so
that when the user clicks a button
they see that something happened.
You're going to need to make some
other changes in the code for
the order dinner activity because you
won't be able to pass the dinner and
the dinner ID, from the method that's
activated by clicking the button.
And of course, you'll need to make sure
that the button action of the Add to
Cart button calls the add
dinner to cart method.
So go ahead and do this coding and
then try out your app.