So some pros and cons of the Hough transform.
All the points are processed independently, so it's okay if, you know,
part of my stuff is occluded because each point just gets to vote.
There's a modest amount of robustness with respect to noise so,
because the noise points, as we said before, there are,
they're unlikely to sort of collude to vote for the wrong thing.
And you can use it to find multiple instances of the object
within the single image.
There are some downsides.
The biggest challenge is that the complexity goes up
exponentially with the number of model parameters.
So you're never going to use this if you've got, like, seven model parameters,
or maybe even four, that you're, that you're trying to explore.
You'll have to use other methods.
And the other thing is if you have sort of non-target shapes, suppose instead of
circles, you actually had slightly squashed ellipses, then the voting can
break down, and you have to be careful in terms of how you handle that.
And as we said before, the quantization is hard to pick of good grid size and
does require experimentation.