All right, welcome back to computer vision.
Last time, we were talking about, still estimating these transforms, and
we're talking about how it was a model fitting problem.
And, one way of doing it, robustly, because we'd have some bad matches,
was to use these robust error functions.
And I promised you, and I always deliver on my promises,
though the next time we would look at a more algorithmic approach and
sort of a more CS oriented approach.
So, to remind you our feature-based alignment algorithm is
first extract some features, compute some putative matches,
some possible ones based on the descriptors.
And remember last time, we,
we looked at this ratio of the best match to the second best match and we said,
oh, you know, that's a good way of getting rid of some of our bad matches.
And then, the algorithm was supposed to do the following,
it was supposed to loop until we were happy, hypothesizing a transform, and
I'll say actually, from some matches.
And then we were going to verify, the the transform by looking for
other matches that were consistent with the transform that we had solved for.
And, that's really fundamentally what we're going to do today,
is talk about finding consistent matches