Hi, and welcome.
>> Hi, how's it going?
>> Good, how about you?
>> Pretty good.
>> All right, can you give us
a quick introduction of yourself?
>> Sure thing, my name is Lorenzo Brown.
And I'm a content
developer here at Udacity.
>> All right, I'm glad to have you here.
>> Thank you for having me.
>> Cool, we're considering you for
a machine learning engineer position.
And I'm going to ask you a few
questions, would that be okay?
>> Awesome.
>> All right, so
let's start with a probability question.
>> Okay.
>> So
I observed over the last month that
about 20 of the days
were kind of cloudy.
And out of those 20 days,
5 days it actually rained.
Now I'm trying to figure out if there
is some correlation between these two
events.
So if I observe outside
that it's cloudy today,
what are the chances that it'll rain?
Can you help me answer that question?
What's the probability of it?
>> Sure thing,
do you mind if I use the board?
>> Please.
>> All right, move this out of the way.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So when we talk about the probability
of cloudy weather based on, or
rainy weather based on
the fact that it's cloudy,
the first thing that pops up
into my mind is Bayes' rule.
So I'm just going to go ahead and
write the formula out.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So Bayes' rule says that
the probability of an event
A given B is equal to
the probability of B given A times
the probability of A divided
by the probability of B.
So you said that you observed cloudy
weather 20 days out of the month.
>> Right, and you can assume
that the month was 30 days.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>> Okay, and
you said you observed rainy weather,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
For 5 days?
>> 5 days.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>> Out of the cloudy days.
>> That is true.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>> Okay, so let's see if we
can take this information and
fit it into Bayes' rule somehow.
So I'm going to create an event C,
which is cloudy weather
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And an event R, which is a rainy day.
So using Bayes' Rule,
I could say the probability
of it raining given that
it is cloudy weather
is going to be equal to
the probability that
it's cloudy given that it's rainy.
And the probability that,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
It is cloudy,
No, I'm sorry.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The probability that it is rainy over
the probability that it's cloudy.
>> Yeah, I hate Bayes' rule for
the same reason.
I keep forgetting which goes on top and
which goes on the bottom.
>> Yeah, it's kind of confusing
getting all the pieces together.
But once they're there,
hopefully everything will work out.
Okay, so let me see if I can
calculate some of these things.
I said cloudy weather
happens 20 out of 30 days.
So I would say a probability
of cloudy weather is
20 over 30,
which is equal to two-thirds.
And then I said rainy weather
happens 5 out of the cloudy days.
So the probability of rainy,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Equals 5 over 20,
which is equal to one-fourth.
Wait a second.
No, the probability of rainy
shouldn't take cloudy into effect.
>> So
this should be over all of the 30 days,
which is going to change
this to one-sixth.
>> That does look better.
>> Okay, and so now let's see
if I can plug all this back in.
First, the probability that it's
cloudy given that it's rainy.
So we know that all of the rain
happened on cloudy days.
>> That's right.
>> So if it's raining, it's cloudy, so
the probability of
this is going to be 1.
>> That's a very good observation.
>> Okay, and the probability of it's
raining, we already calculated it.
It's going to be one-sixth.
And the probability of
cloudy is two-thirds.
So doing a little math,
this is one-sixth divided by two-thirds.
Which is the same thing as
one-sixth times 3 over 2.
Which is going to give us 3 over 12.
Which equals one-fourth, or a 25% chance
that it's going to rain
given that it's cloudy.
>> [CROSSTALK] That's very good.
Yeah, thanks for
walking me through this explanation.
I noticed that you made a small mistake
and then corrected yourself here,
where you were assuming the probability
of rainy weather being 5 over 20.
Can you tell what that
quantity actually referred to?
>> So it's interesting to see that
the probability that I calculated here
actually equaled one-fourth,
which was my final answer.
I think that happened because the
probability of cloudy given rainy was 1.
Which means that inside this cloudy
space, rain was contained inside.
Which means that this could have been
a quick way to calculate the solution.
But if this didn't hold, then Bayes'
rule would have been a good sanity check
to make sure that all
the probabilities were correct.
>> That's a very good point, and
thanks for the clear explanation too.
>> Thank you.