So that's the end of this lesson and
its the end of our entire discussion about Hough transform.
It's an interesting example of a general approach in this case it's voting that
was first developed many years ago like I said back in the 80s.
Which resurfaces in sort of more sophisticated forms as things come along.
In fact, there's something recently called Hough forests and
Hough forests combine the Hough offset ideas that features vote for
offsets with an ensemble or a collection of classifiers similar to
random forests and that's why these things are called Hough forests.
Fortunately for you your only going to be using the basic Hough transform for
lines and circles for your problem set.
It's more work than it looks, so, you know, make sure you leave plenty of time,
and I think after you get that working, you'll have an appreciation for
what it means to get these more sophisticated methods to work.