I'm going to show you how I use print
debugging to figure this one out.
Since I know that we make it
to the addBugToView method,
I'll add a print statement before and
after the if block.
Before the if block I'll print out the
current count of bugs in the bugs array
and the value of max bugs.
And after the if block I'll print
out the count the bugs again to
see if anything's changed and
then I'll rebuild and run.
I'll select the print debugging scene,
let's do a couple of taps.
And here in the debug area we
see that each time a tap occurs,
the bug count is less than max bugs,
so zero is less than a 100 here.
And then the bug count's
also increasing after
we can assume that a bug's been created.
So we've gone from two bugs and
then three bugs here.
So this suggests that the bugs are being
created and added to the bugs array.
So that doesn't seem like our problem.
So let's stop and dig back into this.
If we look carefully into
this if statement and
you have a little bit of intuition
then you'll see the problem.
The bugs which are instances
of a UI image view
are not being added to the view
after they're created.
So technically the bugs exist,
but our view's not aware of them.
So I'll go ahead and add that in and
then let's run one more time.
Debugging, and we'll tap.
And there we go, the spiders are being
spawned on screen as expected.