For this step,
I decided to use localForage.
The API is simple and easy to use, and
it takes JavaScript objects,
no need to JSONify anything.
In index.html, I added a link
to the localForage script.
Then in app.js, I created a
saveSelectiveCities function that saves
the array of selective cities using
the localforage.setItem function.
I also had to update the click event
handler for the add button in the new
city dialogue to save the selective
cities when the user hits add.
To get content on screen, I called
the localforage.getItem function and
ask for the list of selectedCities.
If there is one,
I save that to app.selectedCities and
then got the forecast for
each city by iterating over the array.
If the user didn't have
any selected cities,
I updated the UI with
the injected weather forecast,
then save the list of
cities to the localForage.
I wrapped all of that in
a DOMContentLoaded event handler,
because I need to make sure that
local forage has been loaded
before I can make calls to it.
You can download my solution linked
in the instructor notes below.