First you need to get it
working on your local machine.
All of the commands I use here
are in the present as notes for
you to run yourself or
even copy and paste.
But before you run them, you'll need to
install Node.js as all the server and
build scripts are written in JavaScript.
Once that's installed,
clone the project from GitHub.
This will download it all
to your local machine.
If you're new to Git and
want to learn more,
there's a whole Udacity course on it.
So if you're already
bored of my face and
voice, you could do that course instead.
I've linked to it in
the instructor notes.
But you don't need to be one of
the Git elite for this course.
We'll give you all the commands
you need along the way.