People have been doing derivatives and edges for a very long time.
The most classic one is referred to as a Sobel operator, named after Leonard.
I have no idea.
It's named after some guy named Sobel.
And the Sobel operator looks just like what I was showing you.
But instead of one-half and
minus one-half, it's got this weird thing where it's doing these eighths.
And you can see that it does, not only plus 2 minus 2,
which you would then divide by 4 and you get the same value.
But it also does a plus 1 minus 1 on the row above me,
and a plus 1 minus 1 on the row below me.
And the idea here is, that if I'm taking a derivative.
Remember how we said before we assume that our images are sort of
locally this smooth, that is they change similarly?
So the idea here is that if I'm going to compute a derivative at a pixel,
I won't look just left, right at me, but also look nearby me.
And then to normalize this thing, you have to divide it by 8.
By the way, having just finished,
almost finished teaching the course here on campus, we had a problem set where
people were having a heck of a time that they hadn't had a problem with before.
Turned out,
somebody had discovered that MATLAB has a built in function called imgradientxy.
And they said, could we use that function to compute the gradient?
Since it was for part of a problem set that was more advanced and
they had already done gradients, I said sure.
And all the sudden people are having all sorts of problems.
And the reason was, if you look up imgradient,
it tells you that it applies the Sobel operator by default.
Well here's the Sobel operator.
Looks great, but you know what?
It doesn't divide by 8.
So all their gradients were scaled by a factor of 8 and
it totally screwed up the entire class.
A hundred people got screwed up because of this.
So, now we tell them you can use im gradient, but you better divide by 8.
Oh, by the way,
the y one is here as well, and in this case y is positive going up.
Remember, it can go in either direction.
Alright, so the Sobel gradient would just be made up
of the application of this sx and sy to get you these values.
And the magnitude is just the square root of the sum of the squares.
I should have said that gx is the application of sx,
gy is the application of sy.
So the magnitude is just what we did before.
And here is the arctan2,
the atan2 that we were talking about in order to get the gradient.
So here's an ancient example.
It's so ancient I know because that's X Windows, so
that even predates when most of you were born.
And here you have a picture on the left that's an image.
Here is a gradient magnitude, so
you just apply the Sobel Operator, take the sum of the squares, square root of.
And then by the way you could just threshold it.
And you'll notice two things.
One, it's not an awful edge image and two, it's not a great edge image.
All right?
So we're like part way there.
We're partly towards getting that done.