[Norvig] Now I want to talk about 1 more representation for planning
called situation calculus.
To motivate this, suppose we wanted to have the goal of moving all the cargo
from airport A to airport B, regardless of how many pieces of cargo there are.
You can't express the notion of All in propositional languages like classical planning,
but you can in first order logic.
There are several ways to use first order logic for planning.
The best known is situation calculus.
It's not a new kind of logic;
rather, it's regular first order logic with a set of conventions
for how to represent states and actions.
I'll show you what the conventions are.
First, actions are represented as objects in first order logic,
normally by functions.
And so we would have a function like the function Fly
of a plane and a From Airport and a To Airport
which represents an object, which is the action.
Then we have situations, and situations are also objects in the logic,
and they correspond not to states but rather to paths--
the paths of actions that we have in state space search.
So if you arrive at what would be the same world state by 2 different sets of actions,
those would be considered 2 different situations in situation calculus.
We describe the situations by objects, so we usually have an initial situation,
often called S0,
and then we have a function on situations called Result.
So the result of a situation object and an action object is equal to another situation.
And now instead of describing the actions that are applicable
in a situation with a predicate Actions of S,
situation calculus for some reason decided not to do that
and instead we're going to talk about the actions that are possible in the state,
and we're going to do that with a predicate.
If we have a predicate Possible of A and S, is an action A possible in a state?
There's a specific form for describing these predicates,
and in general, it has the form of some precondition of state S
implies that it's possible to do action A in state S.
I'll show you the possibility axiom for the Fly action.
We would say if there is some P, which is the plane in state S,
and there is some X, which is an airport in state S,
and there is some Y, which is also an airport in state S,
and P is at location X in state S,
then that implies that it's possible to fly P from X to Y in state S.
And that's known as the possibility axiom for the action Fly.