So this third and final lecture on
the topic of camera calibration,
again, I'm going to show you a video
that was recorded by Aaron Bobick for
his computer vision class
on camera calibration.
In this one, he actually takes much more
of a practical approach and teaches you
how we're going to really do camera
calibration in an, a real environment.
He'll showcase variety of things,
like, for example,
using checkerboard patterns like this,
where we know the size of each and
every part of the cell here and
knows the dimensions which can be used
as real in, information that could
be then used to calibrate cameras.
Again, you hopefully you'll enjoy it.
This is much more of a practical
approach on how we can do camera
calibration.
And, again, this is optional material
that I just want you all to know about.