At the beginning of this section,
we gave a challenge question.
Let's go over it carefully now.
The leftmost branch's value is
calculated by multiplying 0.1
times the minimum value which is 8,
plus 0.5 times the minimum
value of the next branch,
which is 5, plus 0.4 times 8.
The sum of that is equal to 6.5.
The bottom left node of the middle
sub-tree returns a value of 0.
0.5 times 0 is still 0.
We don't even need to evaluate the right
branch of the middle tree now.
The maximum we could get is
a 0.5 times 10 which equals 5.
Since 5 is less than 6.5,
there's no possible way for
the right branch of the subtree
to matter, so we can ignore it.
Note that if our nodes
were ordered better,
we could have had a zero
on the left most branch.
Then we could have
ignored everything else.
As we know, that the value of this
sub-tree is going to be five or lower.
In other words, we would have
known that 0.5 times zero or
less, plus 0.5 times 10 or less,
is still going to be less than or
equal to five.
For the right sub-tree,
we have 0.1 x 3 = 0.3.
We still could get a 10 in the next
branch or in the sum of the next
branches so we'll get a 0.9 times
10 out of the rest of the sub tree.
So we should still continue.
because we could actually
get a 9.3 in the end.
Note that there is a lesson here.
We should probably evaluate
these sub-trees with the highest
probabilities first and
the highest expected values first,
however in this case we
continue with 0.5 x 9, or 4.5.
So, we have 0.3 + 4.5 so far,
which is equal to 4.8.
There's still a possibility that we
can get a value better than 6.5.
So we continue.
The next branch yields a two.
At this point we know that
we know that this sub tree
is going to have a value that is
less than or equal too
0.1x3+0.5x9+0.4x2 which equals 5.6.
Thus, we are done.
The last branch does not matter.
Our player is going to
choose the left most branch.
Let's go to Shelly and
one final quiz on this section.