So let's expand on this whole concept of filtering using a kernel.
And this time around, what I'd like to take the concept of cross-correlation to
define the concept of convolution.
Let's start off with a, again, a simple image.
Here, actually, there's, of course, an interesting variant on this image.
This is sometimes referred to as an impulse image because in essence what I
have is zeroes everywhere else and then a peak.
A brightest value and then down to zero.
And again, there's only one simple impulse in this image right here.
So zeroes everywhere else and
a bright peak in the middle is what we're looking at with this image.
We want to do a cross correlation.
In this case, a filter with a kernel like this.
And we will take a kernel just to have values.
We've been playing around with these parametric values of a, b, c, d, e, f,
g, h, i, to represent this kernel.
We're now interested in asking the question, what happens if we slide this
kernel over this image here, this example image, then what would be the output?
So this would be the the output that we would actually like to generate.
Of course, this is the output G[i,j].
What we would like to do is now take the cross correlation of
this with kernel and start filling in the values here.
Let's start off with a region here.
Again we just do a cross-correlation of this with that.
All of the values here are multiplied by 0.
So their answer here would be 0.
Let's now move this one like that.
And of course the computation here, if you look at this region with this,
f multiplied by 1 the answer here would be f.
Move this by 1 again.
Do the computation e multiplies by 1, the rest of them are 0.
The response output here would be e.
Next one, d multiplies by 1.
Response here would be d.
Moving one more, we get to 0.
And of course, now, we should fill in the other two rows also.
So this is basically what my response would look like if I
took an impulse function with a cross-correlation kernel.
A kernel like this, do a cross-correlation and that's what,
our response would be this.
To reiterate, taking this kernel on an impulse image like this,
doing cross-correlation.
This is the response we get.
Let's look at this three by three region.
If you notice, an interesting thing happened, and we constructed this and
you noticed what was happening.
D, e, and f got switched, and similarly b, e, h, h, e, b have been switched.
So in essence what has happened is this there's been a flip in this axis.
Right, and there has been a flip in this axis, both axes there's been a flip.
So this is what my output region this three by three looks like, and
again as I noted they've been rotated.
One axis, another axis, and of course I can flip it.
And this is my kernel.
In essence, what happened by doing this process was the internal parts all got
flipped around.
So, the bottom line of this exercise we went through was to showcase that if
you have an impulse function like this and
you have a kernel that has different properties like this, these values here.
We do cross correlation, the result is a reverse response.
Let's look at that with a real example.
Here what I've done is basically created an original impulse function.
Black values here, white peak in the middle.
Let's actually create a simpler version of this too.
Showcased here, black value, white here, and ramps going up this way and
also coming up this way.
So different gray values here.
Zero, one and different values here.
And let's see what happens when we run this process.
So the actual output is, again, if you noticed just like this,
but flipped in both axes, both in x and y or horizontal and vertical.
So now let's look at exactly what happened.
This is referred to as a convolution method, and
a convolution is basically a mathematical operation where we
take two different function, F was our input, h was our kernel.
And it actually produced a third function that actually modifies the answer.
And it actually gives the area of overlap between the two first functions.
And it actually does that by basically showing an amount that one of
the original functions is translated by.
Lots of words, basically showing what we actually looked at in mathematical
version, or at least a practical version, let's look at it with math.