The contacts app is actually a perfect
example of when you would want to
use a content provider.
You can the provider and
then under the hood, it'll either
access the database or it might talk
to the file system to get photos.
And having it all wrapped up
inside the content provider
also makes it really easy to share this
data with other apps on the device.
Say, for example,
you have a social networking app.
It might want to have access
to your list of contacts, or
it might want to add information
to existing contacts.
And the way that these apps communicate
with each other is through an agreement,
which is the contacts contract.
There's one more benefit
that I wanted to mention.
The framework actually
takes care of security for
you with the content provider.
So the data is safe and
it won't be provided to other apps
unless those apps have the proper
permissions to access it.
If you want to explore more
about the contacts provider,
you can check out
the documentation link below