Okay, while J.P.
was talking to you, I found out how we
could perform searches in Firebase.
Here's an example statement
that I want you to look at.
What this code does is it returns all
the lists names that start with do.
Let's break this statement apart.
Ref is a Firebase location,
in this case it's a reference to
all the shopping lists of a user.
Next, you need to order
the objects in that location
by whatever property
you want to search on.
In this case we're searching
on the property list name.
If you want to search through values or
keys you can order by
those constraints as well.
And then we have this startAt ednAt.
The startAt says begin with
all words that start with do.
Remember, startAt is inclusive so there
could be a list name that's just do and
that would be included in
the results returned by this query.
Okay, so we're starting our
words that begin with do and
we're ending at words that begin
with do and then this tilde.
So what's the purpose of this tilde?
Well the tilde has the special
characteristic of being one of the last
characters of the ASCII alphabet.
All right, now they give a little bit
more of an idea of what this is actually
saying let's see what
it does in practice.
Let's say that I have a user with
these lists in their user lists.
Ref here would be
referring to these lists.
Now these are currently ordered by
the time which the user saves them, but
we're going to do an order by
childless name which will sort them
by their lists name.
So, here are the sort of lists,
notice how the space here comes before
all the characters in the alphabet.
So do space comes before don.
So I've done these two commands
now I'm going to startAt do.
And what that means is I skip over
things that start with da and
di and
I start at this one that starts with do.
I ended do told again tilde,
again tilde is character that comes
after all of the other characters.
It's kind of like saying endeAt doz, but
tilde actually comes after Z as well
as punctuation in the ASCII alphabet.
So I'm trying to find things
that fall between these two.
Do not delete this
list as one such thing.
The space character comes before
the tilde character so it's included.
Same thing with donut run.
Don comes after do, and don and comes
before do~ because n is before tilda.
Similarly with donut run, donut run
would come after the string DO, but,
before the strike DO [INAUDIBLE],
because you is before told them.
Dpans misspelled list, on the other
hand, does not start with do.
It starts with DP,
which comes after do, so
it would not be included in this range.
So this is what we end up with.
And these are the lists here
that are returned by this query,
which happen to be all
the lists that start with do.
Hopefully that makes some sense, but
I've got a couple questions just to
make sure that you're following.
Okay, so here's the same list of
shopping lists, and I've gone ahead and
put them in order for you.
And here are two queries that
are similar to the query that I just
showed you, but with something
a little different in each.
This one doesn't include the endAt and
this ends at doZ.
Note that this is a capital Z and
it actually does matter.
Given this query, check off
the lists that would be returned.
Similarly, given this query check
off a list that would be returned.
This one's a little bit more tricky so
I highly suggest that you check out
the ordering of the ASCII alphabet
before answering.
I've included it in the instructor
notes below if you need it.