Hi, I'm Jared and I'm Gabrielle.
We’re course developers at Udacity. we're just
a few of the faces you'll see in this
iOS developer Nanodegree program built
to transform you into a full-fledged iOS developer.
iOS powers millions of Apple
devices like the iPhone and iPad
For many, their first touch with computers
will be with one of these devices.
That's why there's never been a better
time to go from being a user of these
technologies into a creator. In this
program, you’ll learn by doing. Building apps
like PitchPerfect that can record your
voice and play it back in interesting ways.
MemeMe, an app for creating memes
to share with friends. On the Map, an app
that visualizes the locations of your
cosmopolitan classmates.
And Virtual Tourist, an app that lets you
travel anywhere without leaving the
comfort of your couch.