So obviously the answer I'm looking for
is this one.
because what we're
interested in is basically,
if I take a picture of this scene here
as shown here, basically it will show me
that this original image is deformed,
transformed, right?
Of course in this case this appears
to be a perspective transformation or
projected transformation.
Now I actually can link this
camera to my projector through
a computation process.
Which will take this and
can now do the inverse of this image to
kind of basically say, okay, I know that
this, I know the original image because
I actually know the original
image because they're controlled.
This has already been displayed.
Knowing the original image and,
perhaps, not even the original image,
just that kind of the outlin,
outline of the boundary here.
Knowing the image will
help us a lot more,
I can now figure out
the inverse transform.
So what basically it would mean is I
would actually change the way the image
is displayed on the projector to
make it have the right you know,
aspect ratio on the screen.
So in essence this would
mean in the process,
sometimes moving this kind of around is
keystoning, and we can actually do this
much more in detail by actually
transforming the image at the display so
the projection is actually appropriate.
So that basically starts
saying that we can actually do
calibration by combining a camera and
a projector system.