Right now we have the same
problem as we did before,
where spiders are not appearing
on the screen when we tap.
We're already able to reproduce
the problem by tapping on the screen.
So the first step of our
debugging process is complete.
So let's begin gathering information
about the problem at the most likely
candidate for what could be causing
this, the handleSingleTap method.
So instead of our print statement,
we'll use our Breakpoint here.
And if handleSingleTap is called
at any point then our Breakpoint
should pause the execution of
the app when it reaches this method.
But if handleSingleTap is not
being called then the Breakpoint
will never be triggered and
our app will not pause.
So we'll run our app and
as we saw a second ago,
when we tap we are reaching
the Breakpoint.
So it does work.
That was more of just a verification
step in how you might work through
the problem if you were
starting from a clean slate.
So let's talk more about what
Xcode is displaying to us when our
application's paused.
Right now on the left side
in the navigator panel
we're seeing the Debug Navigator.
If you don't see if right away,
you can use the hot key, Cmd+6.
In the Debug Navigator, the first thing
we see are gauges which represent
the CPU, memory, disk and network usage.
You can toggle the gauges on and
off by clicking this icon here.
If you click on any of the gauges,
you'll get some really valuable insight
about of the app's resource usage.
But we're not going to focus on
those diagnostics in this course.
So let's go ahead and
turn the gauges off for now.
The next thing that we see is a list
of threads associated with our
running application.
So right now we have one, two,
three, four, five, six threads.
And the thread that's handling the code
where the Breakpoint was triggered
is Thread 1.
We can see that by this arrow here.
If we look at the drop down
list under this thread,
we'll see what's known as a stack trace.
It's also commonly referred to as
a call stack or the back trace.
A stack trace is a report
of all the available stack
frames which lead up to
a point of execution.
And yes, as the name implies,
the stack trace is literally a stack
like structure where stack frames
are pushed and popped off of the stack.
In each stack frame, that's what we're
seeing in these lines here, is a record
of all the program state available at
the point in which the frame was active.
So typically there are stacked
frames for each time a method or
a function is invoked.
In each frame with black text includes
code that we've written while everything
else, these gray ones, is either
library code or some other framework.
Where we don't have access
to the actual source.
So if you look at this full stack trace,
we can see that we're currently
examining the state available when we
called the handleSingleTap method.
So, go ahead and tap on that.
And we'll drag back.
And the state that we can see
includes what's present here and
the variables view.
So if we look we have a
UiTapGestureRecognizer that's in scope.
And we have
the BreakpointBugViewController.
If we click down on
the UiTapGestureRecognizer,
we can see its current property values.
You'll notice that Xcode tries
its best to display the values
in a format that we can
understand as developers.
So for some properties,
like this _ButtonType,
we see that it's value is currently 0.
And for other values like the _Imp,
we see a raw memory address.
Now you may be thinking to yourself,
what am I going to do
with the memory address?
I mean it's just a raw address
that's not very useful.
But there's actually a couple
things that you can do.
I'm going to show you some of
those later in the course.
Right now let's just focus on what
we've learned from this Breakpoint.
We know that the handleSingleTap method
is being reached when we tap the screen.
And if we look at the stack trace,
we see that our method handleSingleTap
is indeed being called.
And if we click on the main stack frame,
we can see that the main application.
Or the app delegate, I'm sorry.
Is in sub class of UIResponder.
And it appears that this particular
class is sending an action.
Some kind of gesture.
To our BreakpointBugViewController.
And if you didn't catch that,
I can jump around between the frames
by just clicking on them.
You can see the variables
update based on the context for
that particular stack frame.
And this is a really
powerful way to debug.
It allows us to, by clicking, trace the
steps which led to our particular error,
or to our particular Breakpoint.