Time to dive into how you can use
the Youdassi scripts to create
a high performance ocean
complete with moving waves.
For this,
we'll be taking a look at shaders.
If you recall, a shader is code that
is used to create custom materials and
runs on the GPU.
We're going to try to modify the way
the ocean looks to change the scene from
pleasant float to a tumultuous storm.
If we stop the scene from playing
we'll see that the ocean disappears.
This is because it's created
dynamically with the scene game object.
Assigned to that script
is the ocean material.
If we click on the Sea_Island material,
we'll reveal that with in the project.
If we look at the top,
we'll see the name of our shader.
Let's take a look at it with in
the shader folder, and open it up.
As you can see,
the script is pretty complex and
it can take a lot of time and
deep understanding to be able to modify
and understand what exactly is going on.
But, luckily for us most high quality
scripts will expose their important
values publicly, which with shaders
is done using properties right here.
This means that they will
appear in the inspector.
Instead of picking apart
this intricate shader,
let's think about our objective,
to make a sea stormy.
And let's see if we can accomplish this
using the public values listed right
here.
Let's go back to Inspector,
and find our ocean material.
Here again is the list of
properties we can change.
But we want to see our effects live,
so let's start by running our scene.
Now to edit our material, we need to
find it on the ocean game object.
Pause the video here,
to spend a few minutes playing with
the sliders to get a stormy appearance.
The properties that are probably
most relevant, are the water color,
the roughness, the refractive index,
and the wave height.
Nice, we now have a bit more realistic
looking ocean, with values we can modify
in the inspector to make
it feel the way we want.
Let's move on to a script which uses
something called a flocking algorithm
to create cool swarming visual effects.