Here's a very nice table of some experimental results.
Just shows you the different kinds of perturbations that they did.
Okay?
And they're talking about different ways of comparing the matches.
About whether you just, you know, do you get the right location and scale?
And what about orientation?
The thing that really matters is that you're doing all these different things.
You're looking at changes in intensities, rotations, scalings,
stretching 10% noise.
And you can see if you do all of those things,
depending upon whether you're looking at just location scale or
including orientation, you still get above a 70% match.
And that's pretty remarkable.
In fact, there's a nice figure that comes from here.
So, here's an original image, and drawn on on top of this pic,
in fact you can almost not see the picture underneath.
There are all these feature points, okay?
And, what they did is they took the picture and they rotated it 15 degrees.
They scaled it down 90%.
They stretched it 10%.
Okay another, an extra 10%.
They changed the brightness down by 10%, changed the contrast, multiplied out,
and they added some noise.
And then they went back and they took a look at all their feature points.
And how well did it match?
Well I love this little animation.
See the whole thing flies in here and says 78%.
That's pretty cool.
What that's showing you, is that you have this very robust descriptor, and
yet it's distinctive enough that you can find the correct matches.
Here's another example again from the paper.
What you're looking for are these little things.
Okay, so this is a little piece of the house this is a little piece of
the totem pole, this is something else that was on the totem pole.
In fact, it's a little hard to see, so I put these little colored dots.
So what they're look, so we're looking for these patches over here.
What you're going to do is you're going to create little SIFT features on
all these things.
And you're going to look for those patches in the corresponding image.
And what are you going to find?
Voila!
Basically, the thing works, which is not a surprise.
It came from the paper where they're claiming it.
By the way SIFT is actually intellectual property owned by the University of
British Columbia.
So before you go implement it and
put it in your iPhone in order to do something clear.
Make sure you hire a really good lawyer.