If we try the smaller image,
then we see that the image is actually
smaller than the size of the screen.
So it doesn't matter if we choose scaleType
to be center or centerCrop.
The full image will be able
to be shown in the view.
And this is what it looks
like with a photograph.
Now let's try the icon.
That was called Android.
So the size of the icon is smaller
than the size of the screen so
if we do wrap_content for the width and
height then it should fit on the screen.
It doesn't matter if we use center or
centerCrop.
Now what happens if we set the image
view to be larger than the device size?
Say we pick a really large
number like 900dp and width and
height, then the image you will take
up a size larger than the screen size.
But the scaleType is set to center.
So, the icon will be centered
within that humongous image view.
If we choose centerCrop though,
the system tries to scale the image
up to be a square of 900dp by 900dp.
And then it centers and crops the image.
Now that you've experimented
with the imageView xml,
hopefully you have a better idea of
how to display images in your app.