All right!
Your done.
Lets go over my solution.
Before we actually go to lay out
the bottom half of our details view
lets strategize.
We have two columns,
one that contains these headers, and
one that contains data.
The headers column is pretty
easy it's all left justified,
32 dp away from the edge.
The other column is also justified
right from the other edge but all three
of those elements are aligned left.
This would be very tricky to do with
anything else other then a grid lay out.
We're going to let these three elements
actually take up the expanded space.
Let's look at how we implemented that.
All right, so
let's take a look at our grid layout.
As you can see, the padding in
the bottom and top is 16DPR.
Abc_action_bar_content_inset_material.
Our padding in left and
right, in start at end, for
right to left languages,
is forecase_detail_horizontal_padding.
Or 32DP as we defined
it in our dimensions.
Let's take a look at our first row and
column.
As you can see,
we're using columnWeight 1.
Let the layout manager know
that this text view is actually going to
expand to take up any additional space.
We use a rowWeight of 1 to also show
this row is going to participate in any
additional space that
the layout manager may have.
And here's our first column.
And here's our second column.
Notice that we're not using
any weights here at all.
Other than that this is pretty simple,
all of our rows have
a row weight of one, so
they'll all participate in the extra
space, so they'll all be spaced evenly.
This gives the layout a nice even look.
And that's it.
That's pretty straight forward.
Again, there's not necessarily
one solution to this.
One of the things I like about layouts,
is that each one of them is
like solving a little puzzle.
All right, it's running in the emulator.
And there's our new detail view
with that bottom section
looking exactly as we intended.