Okay Katherine, our app is coming along,
but there is one major problem with it.
>> What's the problem?
>> Well it only orders
two cups of coffee.
>> What's wrong with two cups of coffee?
>> Well three is better than two,
four is better than three,
sometimes I need more.
>> Okay I get it, you need more coffee.
So what I can do is just
change the code, so
that instead of two it just says three.
>> Okay, so in our code here,
we will need to change
the number of cups of coffee
>> Here and here.
So what if I want ten cups of coffee for
myself and my friends later on?
>> You have that many friends?
Oh.
Well, we need something else, then.
>> Yeah, we need a better solution.
>> How about, oh, I know,
we can use variables.
>> Variables?
As in something that varies?
>> Yeah,
a variable doesn't have a fixed value.
You can think of a variable
like a box [SOUND] like this.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, so this is a variable.
It's a box and
you can put a value inside of it.
>> It says int.
>> Yeah, int stands for integer.
>> Okay, so you can put an integer,
or a number, inside of this box.
>> Exactly!
And you can even give it a name.
>> Let's call it number of
cups of coffees ordered.
>> Okay.
You had to pick a long name.
Ordered Barely fits.
>> Okay.
>> So now we can refer to
this variable using this name
in a code instead of
putting the value two.
>> Okay.
>> Later we can also
update it if we want.
Let's put the value inside now.
How are we going to do that?
Well, I have some Post-its.
>> Where did those come from?
>> Let's call the number of cups
of coffees ordered to be 2.
>> Why only 2?
>> One for me and one for
my friend, Katherine.
>> Thank you.
[LAUGH] So now we have a variable that
is called numberOfCoffeesOrdered and
it holds the value 2.
>> Let's implement this in our code.
>> Before we were using
a literal value to represent
the quantity of coffee cups ordered.
A literal means a fixed value,
like the number 2.
Technically the 5 and
this 2 are also literal values but
we're just talking about using
literals for the quantity right now.
So if we say the quantity is 2
cups of coffee ordered, then
when we calculate the price, we have
to do 2 times 5, since each cup is $5.
If we want to charge the customer for
a paper cup because they didn't bring
their own cup and they like to waste
trees, then we charge them $2 per cup.
So that's 2 cups times $2.
When we use a literal, you can see
that it's not ideal because we have to
keep repeating the quantity
number over and over again.
On the other hand,
we can use a variable to represent
the quantity of coffee cups ordered.
So if we say the quantity is this
variable called numberOfCoffees,
then when we calculate the price,
we can just use that variable name,
numberOfCoffees, and
multiply it by $5 a cup.
To calculate the charge for the paper
cup, again we take the variable name,
numberOfCoffees, and
we just multiply it by 2, for $2.
So the difference between these two
is that instead of the actual literal
value, we use a variable.
And then the value of that variable
will be substituted when we
actually evaluate this expression.
So when we go and calculate the price,
we just have to go check what this
value is before we multiply by 5.
The one additional step that you need
to do when you use a variable is,
in the beginning,
to set the variable, numberOfCoffees,
to have an initial value.
In this case we set it to an initial
value of 2, which is also a literal.
But this time we only use the literal in
one place instead of in multiple places.
The end result is still
going to be the same,
because of numberOfCoffees
will map to the value 2.
So the quantity will still be 2,
the price will still be 10,
and the paper cup
charge will still be 4.
The real advantage to this
approach is that you can
change the variable value at any time.
Say I want to change
the numberOfCoffees to be 3.
I just need to change it
in one place here and
then everything else is still accurate.
The quantity is still
the numberOfCoffees,
which now has a value of 3.
The price is now
numberOfCoffees times 5.
And the value is 3 times 5, and
the paper cup charge is still
numberOfCoffees times 2.
Which is now 3 times 2.
If we were using a literal,
then we would have to change
the quantity to be 3 here.
We would have to update the price
calculation to be 3 times 5.
And the paper cup
charge to be 3 times 2.
So when we use a variable,
we don't have to refer to
the specific value each time.
We can just refer to
the variable name and
that will automatically get us
the latest value in that variable.
We can look more closely at what
the actual code would look like for
creating and using a variable.
To create the variable,
we say int numberOfCoffees = 2.
This creates a variable for
us with this name numberOfCoffees and
it puts the value 2
inside that variable box.
These next two lines use the variable
that we created on the first line
in order to update this screen.
We can display the number of coffees,
which involves looking at that variable
and checking the value inside,
which is two.
So we show 2 here.
To display the price.
We look at the value of the variable,
numberOfCoffees, which has 2 inside.
So, we say 2 x 5 equals 10,
and so the price is $10.
I can easily change this code, so
that the numberOfCoffees
ordered is 3 instead of 2.
For the box that represents
our variable, numberOfCoffees,
now we put 3 as initial
value inside this variable.
These two lines of code
don't have to change though,
because we are using the variable name.
When we called display numberOfCoffees.
The value in this variable is 3.
So we show the quantity 3.
To display price we look at the value
for the numberOfCoffees which is 3.
And we multiply that by 5 so
that gives us $15.
This is what the code change
would like in Android Studio.
Currently it's using the literal
value of 2 for the quantity.
Instead let's create a variable,
I'll type int numberOfCoffees 2.
So now I have a variable
with the value 2.
By the way, this text is grayed out and
it says variable number of coffees is
never used because I never referred to
it again, but I am about to use it now.
Instead of displaying
the literal value 2,
I'm going to switch it to
use the variable name.
It pops up as an autocomplete option,
so you can just hit Enter and
it fills it in automatically for you.
Then this variable name is no longer
gray because now we've used it
in at least one place.
I can do the same for displayPrice.
Instead of the using the literal
value of 2, I'm going to change
it to be the variable numberOfCoffees,
and I just hit Enter to auto complete.
Technically I could also create
a variable for the price value of 5.
However, it's only used in one place so
I might as well just leave
it as a literal value.
Okay, now let's save the code and
run it on the device.
And this is what it looks
like on the device.
When you hit Order, the quantity is 2,
and the price is $10.00.
This is exactly the same behavior as
before, but now our code is more robust.
Robust means that the code is less
prone to errors in the future.
For example, if someone else
is trying to change this code,
and they were trying to use
the quantity in many other places,
then they would have to change the
number 2 in so many different places.
Instead if we used a variable,
numberOfCoffees, then we only have to
change it in one place and then
everything will automatically update.
This way someone won't
mistakenly miss a line of code
that needs to have the latest
numberOfCoffees ordered.
They only have to change
it in one single place.
Now before you go ahead and
do this in Android Studio,
I want you to to first practice
doing it in this quiz.
Go ahead and type out this
line of code right below it.
This line of code will create
a new integer variable, and
these two lines will use
the integer variable.
The reason why I want you to practice
this first is that you can pay
attention to every single
character when you type it.
Otherwise, if you miss a character,
you may get an error in Android Studio,
and it may be hard to
read the error message.
So go ahead and
type it exactly as you see it.
This is helping you become aware
of every single character here,
whether it's a capital letter or
a lower case, or if there's no spaces or
if there is a space.
You'll also start getting
used to the rules of Java
in terms of creating a variable or using
a variable, and as you learned before,
every Java code statement also
has to end with a semicolon.
If you type this incorrectly,
for example,
the variable name,
that would give you an error in Java.
However, other things are more
conventional and best practices.
For example adding a space before and
after operators like this.
If you don't follow this spacing, it
won't give you an explicit error however
it's just better programming practice
to follow these code style conventions.
That way it's easier to read your code,
when you're done typing this out go
ahead and continue to the next video.