I went through our code and
added log messages in the places
specified in the quiz.
In the earthquake
activity's onCreate method,
I log when the onCreate
method is called for
the earthquake activity, I log when
we call loadermanager.netloader.
As you can see, I also print out
whenever a loader callback is invoked.
For example, when the onCreateLoader
function is called or
the onLoadFinished method is called, and
then lastly, onLoaderReset,
when that's called as well.
We also print messages when
onStartLoading is called as well as when
loadInBackground is called.
And then lastly, we print a log when the
fetchEarthquakeData method is called.
And when I run the app on my device,
I can start to see the log messages
printed out here in logcat,
detailing the sequence of
behavior taken in our code.
Now first, the activity is launched, so
we can see the onCreate method being
called, followed by initLoader.
Now since there is no
loader instance yet,
our onCreateLoader callback is called.
Then our earthquakeLoader
gets instantiated, and
onStartLoading is called.
Soon afterwards, loadInBackground
gets run on a background thread.
And then we finally see that our
query util's fetchEarthquakeData
method is executed.
Now at this point, we get a response
from the server and parse it into a list
of earthquake objects which
are returned as a result of the loader.
And then lastly, we see onLoad finished,
and the activity gets called with
this list of earthquake objects, and
then we can update the UI successfully.
Now you'll realize that rotating
your device doesn't trigger a new
network request.
So even though the activity
is created again,
when we call initLoader,
there is already a loader instance, so
we reused that existing loader, which
already has a response from the network.
Now you can also go ahead and experiment
with other ways to leave enter the app.
You find that if you
hit the home button and
return to the app,
a full load is triggered again.
Now that makes sense,
because if you think about it, if
the user leaves the app and comes back,
we'll want to refresh the data so they
have the latest earthquake information.