The viewDidLoad function can be very
useful for running code once our
View Controller is loaded into memory.
But what about running some code right
before the view appears on screen?
Again, for that we’ll use the functions
viewWillAppear and we could also use
viewDidAppear. viewWillAppear happens
right before the view and View
Controller appear on screen.
And viewDidAppear it's called
immediately after the view
appears on screen. Remember that the View
and View Controller are linked.
A UIViewController and any subclasses of it
have at least one IBOutlet that always
goes to a UIView. For now, in the viewWillAppear
function,  let's add another
print statement that says “viewWillAppear called”
If we run the app by pressing the
Run button, we can see this print
statement is being called when our
View Controller appears on screen. Let me
adjust our simulator and there's our
print statement.