There are two more things I want to show you.
One is just some nice little mathematics to explain to you
about homographies and planes, and the second is some of
the cool things we can do with homographies and planes besides just, mosaics.
So, let me show you a simple proof, if you will, or a demonstration,
about this eight degrees of freedom being a mapping between any planes.
So, let's go back to our calibration from the external world to the internal.
So you remember this?
Right, X, Y, Z, 1 is mapped through a 3 by 4 homogeneous matrix.
Or I should say it's a matrix we're doing this homogeneously.
To get out the projective similar UV 1 over there.
And remember we talked about solving for
all the 12 M's using lots of extrinsic points.
But suppose.
Just suppose, all the points in the world were lying on a plane.
So you might remember from your algebra that simple equation of plane.
aX plus bY plus cZ equals d.
Right? So that's the equation of a plane.
Basically what it says is it, it gives me the normal to the plane and
where along the, that normal the plane has to be.
What this equation means is that I could solve for Z in terms of X and
Y and a, b, c and d, and I could plug that in.
And that's what we did here.
Here we removed Z, and put in its equivalent expression in terms of X, Y and
the a, b, c and d which define the plane.
And so, now, it's the same end matrix that we had before.
But we've gotten rid of the Z.
But wait.
If I have only X, Y and a constant in this term for
Z, I can put all the influence of this column, 02, 12,
and 22 of m, I can put that in these other.
Coefficients.
Right? I don't actually need this column, since that's just multiplying
the terms that have the XYs and the constants in them.
I can put all the effect into those other three columns.
So when I do that, it looks like this.
Okay? And you'll notice I now have a column of zeroes here.
Okay, so that's really not doing very much.
I just have these three columns multiplying X, Y, and 1.
All right?
But, that's just a 3 by 3.
That's my homography.
Okay?
That's why the mapping.
From any plane to any plane can be done by a 3 by 3 from
a location on 1 plane to a location on the image plane?
And so basically between any planes.
In fact a way of thinking about that is this, right?
Mapping between planes is a homography.
You give me four points on this plane and four points on that plane,
I now know how all the other points on the plane map to each other.
And whether it's between a plane in the world and an image plane, or
just thinking about it between arbitrary planes, that's the warping that
it takes in order to do this homography or projected projection warp.
Between the planes.
And mapping between planes is something we do a lot in Computer Vision.
Which is why these homographies show up quite a bit.
We're going to do even more sort of sophisticated way of thinking about
lines and planes in the next lecture.
Where we do even more about projective geometry.
Got it?
Cool.