Some of you may be asking yourselves why should you take this class.
So, let me give you a little bit of context how this class came to be.
Most of the masters and PhD students at Georgia Tech want to or
need to take a, the Advanced Operating Systems class 60210,
and likely, many of you will consider taking it in the future.
But as the title of that class suggests, Advanced Operating Systems,
that course deals with a number of advanced topics related to operating systems.
However, over the years,
the population of the graduate students at Georgia Tech has diversified a lot.
And a lot of the students that come to us either don't come with
formal operation systems training, so they may not have seen some of
the more introductory topics related to operating systems, or
maybe it's simply been a number of years since they've looked at that content.
To address this gap,
we offer this course, CS 8803 Graduate Introduction to Operating Systems.
The intent with this course is to teach for
the first time, or review, operating systems basics.
In terms of metrics, once you finish this course, you should be able to
answer every single one of the questions on the diagnostics test that's
associated with the Advanced Operating Systems course.