I/O management is all about managing the
inputs and the outputs of a system, to
illustrate some of the tasks involved in
I/O management, we will draw a parallel
between I/O in computer systems and
a shipping department in a toy shop.
Let's see what are some of
the similarities we can find between
how operating system manages I/O and
how the shipping department
is managed in a toy shop.
For instance, both in the toy shop and
in the operating system there will be
protocols, in terms of how the needs
to be managed, in both cases there will
be dedicated handlers or some dedicated
staff that will oversee these protocols.
And in both environments the details
about the I operations are the cop out
from the core processing actions, in
a toy shop the I/O protocols determine
how and what parts exactly come from
a storage facility into the toy shop and
which toys and toy orders are being
shipped out in which order and how.
To make sure that these protocols
are enforced in the toy shop will have
dedicated staff that handle all aspects
related to shipping and in the toy shop,
the process of making toys
is completely separate from
any details regarding
the shipping process.
What are the carriers
that are being used?
What are their protocols?
Are there any slaves
that are being used?
It doesn't matter.
This has analogies in the context of
the I/O management in operating
systems in multiple ways.
For instance, operating systems
incorporate interfaces for
different types of I/O devices and
how these interfaces are used
determines the protocols that are used
for accessing those types of devices.
Similarly, operating systems
have dedicated handlers,
dedicated operating system
components that are responsible for
the I/O management their device drivers,
their interrupt handlers,
these are used in order to access and
interact with devices.
And finally,
by specifying these interfaces, and
using this device driver model operating
systems are able to achieve this last
bullet, they're able to abstract
the details of the I/O device and
hide them from applications or upper
levels of the system software stack from
other system software components.