Over the next several months, Matt and
I will be your guides for this program.
I'm Saraj, I'm a data scientist,
author of the popular O'Reilly book,
Decentralized Applications, and
I teach developers how to build
AI on my YouTube channel.
While working at
the Robotics Lab at Columbia,
I realized that solving intelligence is
the most important problem in the world.
Because if we solve it,
we can use it to solve everything else.
I'll keep releasing videos and
live streams on my channel, but Matt and
I have teamed up with industry experts
to take your game to the next level.
We'll give you everything you need
to take what you've learned and
apply it to IRL projects.
>> I'm a former physicist,
a former neuroscientist, and
current huge fan of all things data.
I've been working with Python and data
in general for the past eight years.
I've used machine learning models to
detect electrical signals from neurons
and created a library called Sampyl
to build Bayesian statistical models.
I love Bayesian statistics.
I'm fascinated by deep learning
because automation is the future, and
deep learning is
the future of automation.
Along the way, you'll be learning
from several other experts and
Udacity instructors.
We're bringing the brightest minds to
bear to make this experience the best
it can be.