Interviewing for
a machine learning engineer position
can be quite intimidating but
also incredibly exciting.
The company you're trying to join might
be at the forefront of innovation
in healthcare, education,
robotics, or user modeling.
Whatever the domain, in order to
be successful at machine learning
you need to have a strong
problem solving mindset.
You should be able to take almost any
business challenge presented to you,
break it down, and figure out how to
apply machine learning to solve it.
The concepts and skills that you may
need to demonstrate in an interview
include Computer Science Fundamentals &
Programming Techniques, Probability and
Statistics, Data Modeling and
Evaluation, Applying Machine Learning
Algorithms and Libraries, and
finally, you also need to know about
Software Engineering & System Design.
Take a look at the machine learning
interview guide for detailed topics and
some sample questions.
Ready to watch the interview?
Let's get started.