If the architecture is 12-bit,
that means that the addresses
are 12-bit long.
If the page size is 32 bytes,
then we need 5 bits for
the offset into that page.
That will leave 7 bits for
the virtual page number, and therefore,
we will need 128 to do the seven total
number of entries in the page table.
Using the same logic for
the 512 byte pages,
we will need 9 bits out of the total
12 bits for the offset into the page.
And therefore, we will be left with
3 bits for the virtual page number.
As a result, the page table
will need to have entries for
all of the 2 to the 3rd
number of virtual pages.
So it will have total of 8 entries.
As you can see,
this example illustrates the impact of
using a larger page sizes on
the requirements of the page table size.