We've just taken a look
at boolean expressions.
They're great for determining whether
an expression is true or false.
What if we wanted that result to control
something that happens in an app?
Or we can use it for that, too.
For example, imagine an app where
the user can win or lose a challenge.
If it's true that the user wins,
then you might want to
display a winning screen.
Otherwise, you might want to display
a screen that says, try again.
Boolean expressions can be used to
execute different actions in our apps.
Programmers refer to
this as control flow.
This statements are a fundamental
tool of control flow.
We'll use if statements to check for
conditions and then execute actions.
For example, if you're hungry,
you probably want to eat.
The Swift code for this decision
might look something like this.
For a slightly more complex example,
if you want a teddy bear, and
you have money for it, then buy it.
And in code,
this action might look like this.
Finally, if it's raining, then we
should stay inside and watch a movie.
These conditions and executions
are already a part of our daily lives.
You're probably thinking this
way without even realizing it.
We can think of programming this way,
too.
The basic syntax for
an if statement is as follows.
In the example here, can
be replaced with the boolean expression
that evaluates to true of false.
can be
replaced with any code you want.
Any code that should be executed
when the condition is true.
Also notice that the code to execute
is always surrounded by curly braces.
[BLANK_AUDIO]