Let's look at number 1.
Before I reveal the answer,
I'm going to copy this code and
paste it into Android Studio.
I want to show you what kind
of error would come out.
Now when you were solving this quiz,
you didn't need to use Android Studio,
you could have solved it by just
looking at the code here and
then writing in the answer.
So, whether or not you use
Android Studio, it's fine with me.
To make the code work,
I created a new project and
then I modified the activity
main layout file so that it
would have a bunch of views with these
ID's that we're going to be referencing.
I'm not even sure what this
layout would look like, but
I just wanted to put the views in here
with the corresponding view ID names.
That way, my code will work here.
So for number one, I pasted the code
here, and I see that there's an error.
Android Studios says it cannot
resolve the method setText.
If you remember from the last video,
I mentioned that setText
is a TextView method.
That means you can only call
this method on TextView objects.
In this case,
we're calling it on nameTextView.
A nameTextView is declared
to be a view object,
we need to change this
to be a TextView object.
Then we get an error saying
there is incompatible types.
A textview, an object of type
TextView is required, but
instead it found an object of type view.
That's because find view
by ID returns a view, and
this left-hand side requires a TextView.
That means we have to add this to cast
the view returned by
findViewById into a TextView.
Then we can store this whole thing,
which is the nameTextView,
into the left-hand side variable.
Then the error goes away, and we can
set text, "Laura" on this TextView.
The error is on line 1, so
I wrote the correct code right here.
The general explanation is that we need
to cast this view into a TextView and
then store that inside
a nameTextView variable.
That way,
we can call nameTextView.setText,
which is a TextView method,
on the next line of code here.
Let's move on to number two.
I'm going to copy this code and
put it into Android Studio.
Here's the code I pasted in.
The first line of code seems to
be correct, there's no errors.
But the second line has
a red underline and
it says there's
an incompatible types error.
It says, a string is required but
instead it found an int.
To understand this better,
we should look up the method getMaxLines
within the TextView documentation.
In the TextView documentation,
I'm going to search for
the getMaxLines method.
And here it is.
There's no input parameters, and
the return value of this
method is an integer.
So that's why Android studio was
complaining, because this method,
if it's returning an integer, but
we were trying to store it
into a String variable.
As a result, I need to change this data
type of the variable to be an int.
Then the error goes away.
So, the return value of
this method is an integer.
So, we can store it inside
this maxLines variable.
There is a warning still remaining.
Saying that the variable
maxLines is never used.
But this is just a code snippet.
I assume that if this
was in a regular app we
would actually want to
use this variable later.
So, the error's on line two and
here's the updated code.
The general explanation is that
the return value of this method should
be an integer.
Let's move on to number three.
Here's a code for number three.
I copied and pasted the code for
number three in Android Studio.
There's an error message that
says incompatible types.
An ImageView was required,
but instead it found a view.
This is similar to the error
we just saw with the TextView.
This method returns a view.
And, on the left-hand side, we're
trying to store it inside an ImageView.
So we need to cast this view
object into an ImageView.
This is valid because the view with
the ID icon actually is an ImageView,
so it's okay to cast
it into an image view.
Now that the right-hand side
evaluates to an ImageView,
we can store that into the variable
on the left-hand side.
This variable has a data type ImageView
so now everything matches up and
the error is gone.
On the next side,
we can call an ImageView method,
SetImageResource, onto
this IconImageView object.
There is one remaining error saying
that it cannot resolve symbol logo.
That's because I just didn't add
an image in our app with the name logo.
If I added that, then the error would
go away, so our code here is correct.
Here's the correct code where I
cast this view into an ImageView.
Lastly, we have number 4.
I pasted the code here in Android Studio
and surprisingly there's no errors.
The code is trying to find
a view with the id title, and
that should return a view, and that gets
stored in this variable called TextView.
TextView has a data type of View, so
that matches with the right-hand side,
so this whole line of code is correct.
On the next line we're taking
this object, which is a View And
we're calling a setVisibility
method on it.
The method takes in one input
parameter which is View.GONE.
I can check the documentation
to verify why that is.
In the documentation for
the view class, I can search for
the method setVisibility.
I can see that setVisibility is
a method within the view class.
It takes this input, an integer that
represents the visibility state.
The possible visibility values
are VISIBLE, INVISIBLE, and GONE.
Since setVisibility is a method
within the view class,
this is a valid call here.
There's no need to cast
this into a TextView
because the method that we're calling
is a method of the view class.
Now if we were trying to
use a TextView method,
then we would need to
cast it to a TextView.
So for this question,
you should put no error, because
setVisibility is a View method, and
it's okay to leave it as a View object.
These were hard questions.
It's okay if you didn't
get them correct.
In the next test, you'll have
a chance to practice this more.