Remember that when you create an
activity it moves through the life cycle
stages of first being created,
started and then resumed.
And then the user can
interact with the activity.
When the user moves away from the
activity, it moves into the paused and
then stop state.
If the system kills the activity
because it's no longer needed,
then it moves into the destroyed state.
So since the onDestroy
method may not be called,
we can only be sure that the onPause and
onStop methods will be called.
So let's revisit the documentation for
the release method within
the Media Player class.
So here it says that when an activity
is paused via the on paused method or
stopped via the on stop method,
then this method
our release method is called in order
to release the Media Player object.
So in this case either activity
lifecycle method is fine.
Either the on pause method or
on stop method.
Because you only need to
release it just once.
So we'll choose to release our
resources in the on stop method.
So when activity is fully hidden from
the user, we'll release the media
resources, even if it hasn't finished
playing the current audio file.
All right, so let's make those
code changes in our app now.
So here are numbers activity, down right
before the release Media Player method.
I'm going to override the on stop
activity lifecycle callback method.
So remember that will never we overwrite
an activity life cycle method as shown
here we should call this super
class version of that method.
So what I've done here with super.onStop
because the activity knows how to handle
stopping activity and doing other
behind the scenes cleanup work
that we as developers
don't need to worry about.
So if you've ever tried
commenting out this line of code
you'll see that the app
will crash unexpectedly.
So don't do that.
Now here instead of just
calling the release method
directly on the MediaPlayer object,
I'm going to call the releaseMediaPlayer
helper method that we added earlier.
So the reason that we use
the releaseMediaPlayer method instead of
just the release method,
is that this one has some actual logic
about setting the media player variable
back to null if it's not currently
configured to play a sound file.
In this way will consistently handle
releasing the media player resources in
our activity whether it's released
by finishing the audio file or
because the activity was stopped
now only to test our device.
Now with this new version of
the app running on my device,
when I tap into any category activity,
let's say numbers.
I can play the sound for
each word as usual.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> But now if I play sound and
then leave the app immediately by
hitting the devices home button
the sound should immediately stop
because of my code in the onstop method.
So as to give it a try.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> Nice so that's working as
expected because remember previously
the pronunciation of each word
would keep going even after I left
the activity and now it cuts
off when I leave the activity.
So great the logic is
working as expected.
So now I'm going to replicate it for
all the other activities.
So here's onStop method overwritten
in the codes activity and
the family activity.
And lastly in the phrases activity.
So let's run the app one more time to
make sure all the other activities
are working as expected.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[FOREIGN]