In the last two examples,
you saw subnet masks for a /24 and
a /16 network, both of those being
multiples of 8 bits, which meant
that the subnet mask decimal form had
only 255 octets and 0 octets in it.
But prefixes do not have
to be whole octets.
Networks can be allocated in
lots of different sizes and
organizations can split their
assigned net block into chunks for
subnets to make management easier and
control traffic.
For instance, a network with
22 bits of network part and
10 bits of host part,
still adding up to 32, is a /22 network.
/22 doesn't evenly divided by eight.
Or here's another example,
171.64.0.0/14,
is the net block assigned
to Stanford University.
The /14 is less than 2
octets of network part.
So all of the addresses on this network
will have the same first 8 bits they'll
all start with 171.
Only six bits of the second
octet will be fixed and
two bits of that second
octet will be free,
meaning there are four different
values that will occur in that octet.
Specifically, all addresses
starting with 171.64 or
171.65 or .66 or .67,
will all be in this /14 netblock.
So here's a quiz,
what's the decimal subnet mask for
a /14 network like Stanford's?
And about how many addresses
are on that network?
Are there around 2,500?
Or around 25,000?
Or are there around two
hundred fifty thousand or
is it around twenty five million?