So, we've just learned about what's probably the most important
piece of math for this class in statistics called Bayes Rule.
It was invented by Reverend Thomas Bayes, who was a British mathematician
and a Presbyterian minister in the 18th century.
Bayes Rule is usually stated as follows: P of A given B where B is the evidence
and A is the variable we care about is P of B given A times P of A over P of B.
This expression is called the likelihood.
This is called the prior, and this is called marginal likelihood.
The expression over here is called the posterior.
The interesting thing here is the way the probabilities are reworded.
Say we have evidence B.
We know about B, but we really care about the variable A.
So, for example, B is a test result.
We don't care about the test result as much as we care about the fact
whether we have cancer or not.
This diagnostic reasoning--which is from evidence to its causes--
is turned upside down by Bayes Rule into a causal reasoning,
which is given--hypothetically, if we knew the cause,
what would be the probability of the evidence we just observed.
But to correct for this inversion, we have to multiply
by the prior of the cause to be the case in the first place,
in this case, having cancer or not,
and divide it by the probability of the evidence, P(B),
which often is expanded using the theorem of total probability as follows.
The probability of B is a sum over all probabilities of B
conditional on A, lower caps a, times the probability of A equals lower caps a.
This is total probability as we already encountered it.
So, let's apply this to the cancer case
and say we really care about whether you have cancer,
which is our cause, conditioned on the evidence
that is the result of this hidden cause, in this case, a positive test result.
Let's just plug in the numbers.
Our likelihood is the probability of seeing a positive test result
given that you have cancer multiplied by the prior probability
of having cancer over the probability of the positive test result,
and that is--according to the tables we looked at before--
0.9 times a prior of 0.01 over--
now we're going to expand this right over here according to total probability
which gives us 0.9 times 0.01.
That's the probability of + given that we do have cancer.
So, the probability of + given that we don't have cancer is 0.2,
but the prior here is 0.99.
So, if we plug in the numbers we know about, we get 0.009
over 0.009 + 0.198.
That is approximately 0.0434, which is the number we saw before.