Now, I'm going to just try to outline the different things we will cover in
this class.
First module of this class is introduction.
We will talk about, what is computational photography?
I'll just give you an example of a kind of a,
a newer type of a camera that has been an artifact that's been produced, as we
have started diving deeper into the whole concept of computational photography.
We will learn more about what are different artifacts of
computational photography, and
what I'll do in this module is introduce you to two simple concepts.
Well, actually, they are not that simple, but some concepts that actually would
be valuable for you to kind of remember throughout the course and
these will be the things that I'll kind of use as examples throughout,
will help us understand how we are going to do computational photography.
I'm going to provide some sort of a context on the scope of
what is computation and how does it really relate to all the other disciplines.
As I've stated, computational photography is a discipline of it's own now, has
its own conference and publications and stuff like that in the academic manner.
But of course what we're interested in
is learning what other disciplines impacted.
In this one, in the first, when we get started,
initial weeks, we'll have a couple of assignments for you.
One to get started basically doing simple processing with images and
stuff like that.