So let's look at this matrix and try to expand on it.
This is R, which is another matrix which basically is the determinant of
M minus alpha trace of M and actually is this set of values here of lambda1,
lambda2 minus alpha lambda1 and 2 and
alpha is a constant that we basically go from 0.04 to 0.06.
By varying lambda one and lambda two, just to help us kind of do this.
This is an example of what we can come up with.
And this will start telling us what kind of feature we have.
R here now depends entirely on the eigenvalues of M.
Okay? If you notice that's the case here.
What we interested in is basically looking at different things.
R is large for a corner.
For example, right here.
Anytime the right values of lambda one and
lambda two are large, the magnitude of this would be larger.
R is negative with large mag, magnitude for an edge.
So if the edge is like this, you're going to get more information like this.
Magnitude of R is small flat region shown here.
So in essence I'm showing you the whole landscape.
R is large when you are there, R is small here in the flat region.
R has got different variations of lambda one and
lambda two, our ellipses are narrow, that means you most probably have a niche.
And in essence, what is important to note here is the way we
did this we do not have to even do explicit computation of Eigenvalues.
This is great because the kind of computation we want to do we want to do
very fast.
And actually even in the early days of computer vision types of
techniques from late 80s and
early 90s this was something you could do very quickly on a small computer.
And that's what you want to do.
You want to be able to do corner detection quite efficiently.