Here's how I implemented
my solution using burlap.
Let's take a look at our constructor.
As before, we have six states.
We only have two parameters
now instead of four,
not counting the discount factor.
And these parameters are now
probabilities of transitions
instead of rewards.
I use these probabilities
in the last parameter
In the stochastic transitions
denoted in our state diagram.
Then, as before, we can conclude
by generating the domain,
setting the initial state to 0, setting
the reward and terminal functions,
and then instantiating
a DiscreteStateHashFactory.
You'll notice that I'm using the classes
SpecificRF, and SingleStateTF here.
These are custom classes I wrote
to implement the reward and
terminal function interfaces.
We'll look at these next.
For the reward functions, since we now
have non deterministic transitions,
we need to look at both the state
s each transitions leaves, and
the state t each transition enters.
Like before, I get integer IDs for
the nodes by calling
the static method getNodeId.
Then using our state diagram, I assign
the appropriate value to the variable
r based on the state
the transition leaves, and
then based on the state
the transition enters.
I also have a few cases that throw
exceptions for debugging purposes.
For the terminal function,
my constructor takes a single
integer as an argument,
the id of the terminal state,
and then stores it in the member field,
terminal sid.
Then, whenever the isTerminal
method is called,
it compares the id of the argument
with the terminal sid.
If they are the same,
then the method returns true, and
we know that the state is terminal.
Otherwise, the method returns false.
As before,
I have a private computeValue method
that takes the discount factor gamma and
runs a value iteration from the initial
state that we find in the constructor.
It then returns
the ValueIteration object
with the values of each
state stored in it.
In the bestActions method,
I pass this ValueIteration object as an
argument to a GreedyQPolicy constructor.
This object allows me to access
the best action to take at each state
based on the values in
the ValueIteration object.
I do this by calling p.getAction,
followed by the state whose
action I wish to query.
Since the output actions
are either action0 or action1 for
these two states, and since their output
needs to be in the form of letters a, b,
c, and d, I call some string replacement
methods before returning the answer.
If you were able to come up with
a solution for this problem, great.
You should be well on your way to being
able to tackle further reinforcement
learning problems using
the burlap library.