Now I noticed a couple problems
when looking at the data.
The first thing I'm wondering is why
were there more unique students in
the enrollment table than
in the engagement table?
The engagement table is supposed to
include a row for each day that each
student is enrolled, even if the student
didn't visit the site at all that day.
So there should have been
the same number of unique
students in both tables.
The second problem was that the column
containing student account keys was
named account_key in two of
the tables and acct in the third.
This one isn't really a big problem but
it is inconvenient.
I kind of expect to keep forgetting
which table has account_key and
which table has acct.
The first problem is confusing.
When I first started analyzing this
data, I didn't know how to fix it.
I didn't even know why it had happened.
We'll investigate this
together in a minute.
Fixing the second problem is easier.
You can simply the column name from acct
to acount_key by removing the value for
acct from each row and adding it
back under the name account_key.
Go ahead and
write code to fix the problem.
Once you're done, check whether your
code worked by running this command, and
enter the output in this box.
If you prefer to create a new
variable rather than modifying
the existing variable,
then use your new variable name in place
of daily_engagement in this command.
If you're not sure how to remove
an element from a dictionary,
the post in the instructor
notes might be helpful.