Before we wrap things up here, we want
to leave you with some final tips for
how to be as successful as
you can be in this program.
As we've already talked about,
stick to your schedule.
Working regularly on your courses and
projects and
staying up to speed with your cohort
will help you learn most effectively,
and will help you make sure you don't
find yourself rushing to finish
a project right up against a deadline.
>> More words of wisdom
from an early grad.
Be relentless in searching for
an answer on your own.
The struggle in search is
where you learn the most.
If you come across a term you don't get,
spend some time reading up on it.
Using resources outside Udacity to
supplement your learning is really
important.
You'll do research everyday on the job.
And we want to make sure that you have
what you need to do that from the start.
>> Also, give us feedback.
We care deeply about your experience.
We want to keep improving this
nanodegree program over time.
The best way for
us to learn is by hearing from
you what works and what doesn't.
Also, be an active member
of your community.
When you're stuck, search the forum for
relative information and
reach out to your community for help.
We want you to give back
to your community too.
As another nanodegree graduate
emphasized, help other students.
This will actually make your
understanding more solid too.
>> By the end of this program,
you'll have a new found expertise and
a portfolio.
And you will have demonstrated
a tremendous amount of drive and
work ethic.
But you've gotta start somewhere.
So go ahead and
dive right into the first course.
Kunal will be teaching you how
to build a pitch perfect app.
He's an incredibly gifted instructor and
developer, and
you'll have the first version of
the app up and running in no time.