So how to get the putative matches.
We talked a little bit so
far about essentially doing exhaustive search, where you, you know,
compare one against every other and you, pick the one that's best.
We also talked about hashing and nearest neighbor, techniques.
But.
You now find a best match.
How do we know it's a good one?
Okay.
So, in this next lesson, not today, we're going to talk about looking at
the global solution that's suggested by this match and
using that to prune off some, some of these, but even before that,
there's something we can do at the local level.
And here, here's the idea.
So, we don't want to.
We're not going to match everything.
We're only going to take, match the ones that have good enough matching.
All right?
So, how do we do that?
Okay? Well here would be a simple idea.
You find the best match.
And you take the correlation.
A little patch from here.
A little patch from there.
And you do it says here SSD.
Sum of squared differences.
Remember where we talked about that?
And we could say, all right, well if that number is less that
a certain threshold, we're going to accept that match.
By the way, something that I've said before and is implicit here and
we'll say it again later.
The general idea is I need to find enough good matches.
Not all of them.
And I need to not find too many bad matches.
So the goal is to try to get a bucket of good matches with
only some bad matches thrown in.
So, going back to the SSD, the question would be how to set that threshold.
So, empirically, you can start to take a look at this.
All right.