The delay alternatives in the spinlock
implementations that we saw in the last
morsel address the problem that
everybody tries to acquire
a spinlock at the same time
when that lock is freed.
In this paper, Anderson proposes
a new lock called a queuing lock,
and that lock is trying
to solve the problem that
everybody sees that the lock
is free at the same time.
If we solve this problem, if not
everybody sees that the lock is free,
then we're essentially also
solving the second problem,
because then not everybody will try
to acquire the lock at the same time.
So let's take a look at
what this lock looks like.
The queuing lock looks as follows.
It uses an array of flags,
with up to N elements where N is
the number of processors in the system.
And every single one of the elements
will have one of two values,
either has-lock or must-wait.
In addition, we will have two pointers.
They will indicate
the current lock holder, so
that one clearly will
have a value of has-lock.
And they will also indicate the index
into this array that has the last
element on the queue.
When a new thread arrives at the lock,
it will get a ticket and
that will be the current position
of the thread in the lock.
This will be done by adding it after
the existing last element in the queue.
So basically the queue last
value will be incremented and
the new thread will be assigned
the next position in the array.
Since multiple threads may be arriving
at the lock at the same time,
we will clearly have to
make sure that the way that
this queue last appointer is
incremented is done atomically.
So basically this queuing clock depends
on some support for an atomic read and
increments.
It will rely on that kind of
hardware atomic operation.
This is not as common
as test-and-set that we
used in the previous
spinlock implementations.
For each of the threads that
are arriving at this queuing spinlock,
the assigned element of this
flags array, the queue[ticket],
that acts like a private lock.
What that means is that as long as
the value of queue[ticket] is must-wait,
then the thread will have to
spin just like with a spinlock.
When the value of this
element becomes has-lock,
that will be an indication that the lock
is free and you can go ahead and
proceed and enter the critical section.
When a thread completes
the critical section and
needs to release the lock,
it needs to signal the next flag in this
queuing array that it
currently has the lock.
So these are the steps that control who
gets to execute and what needs to happen
when a critical sections is complete and
a lock needs to be released.
Other than the fact that this lock
requires some support for some read and
increment to be performed atomically,
clearly it's going to require a size
that is much larger than the other
spinlock implementations.
All other locks we saw needed
only one memory location to
keep the spinlock information whether
the spinlock is free or busy.
And here we need N such locations
to keep the values has-lock or
must-wait for
each of the elements in this array.