Here's an image of a STOP sign
that's viewed from an angle.
And I'll show you how to create and
apply a Perspective Transform so
that it looks like we're viewing
this sign from the front.
Remember, we care about the perspective
transform because the software
we write will eventually do
this to images of a road, so
that you can find the lane curvature.
We're using a traffic sign as
an example here mainly because it's
easiest to see that you've performed
a perspective transform correctly
on images with text or
other distinct reference points.
To create a perspective transform, we'll
first select four points that define
a rectangle on a plane in this image.
Four points are enough to
define a linear transformation
from one perspective to another.
And in this case,
we're selecting point that define
a plane on the surface of the STOP sign.
And we'll also select where we want
those same four points to appear and
are transformed,
often called warped image.
Then, we can use open CV functions
to calculate the transform
that maps the points
in the original image
to the warped image with
the different perspective.
In this notebook,
I've written a STOP sign image.
Here it is displayed in
an interactive window.
You can see that the image has been
taken at a bit of an angle, and
I want to apply a transform
to make it look as if we're
viewing the sign from the front.
First, I'll manually create my four
points on this original source image,
and on my warped destination
image that doesn't exist yet.
These points will define
the perspective transform.
I'll do the source image points first.
And I'll choose them by
looking at the X and
Y coordinate values for
each point I want.
This interactive window
lets me see the X and
Y value of each point
where I place my mouse.
So let's zoom in on the STOP
sign to get a better look.
I'll define my first point at this
top-right corner on the sign.
The second one right
to the bottom of that.
Then, to the left of that, and
finally, my top left corner here.
Here are the four X, Y coordinates for
the points I selected.
These four points define
a rectangle plane on the sign, and
I can even display them on my image,
just to see that they're where I want,
using plt.plot, the X, Y coordinates,
and this top character.
So here are the four points all
displayed, and they look pretty good.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
This was the first step.
But applying a Perspective Transform
takes a couple of steps.
So I'm going to put these
coordinates on a function named warp
that takes in an image and
will return the warped image.
So here's our work function
that takes in an image.
In here those same four
coordinates I chose above
placed into an array of points
named source for source image.
Next, I'll define a desired rectangle
plane for the warped image and
I'll choose four different points that
are where I want the source points to
end up.
This time I choose my points
by just eyeballing a rectangle
in that same image.
And picking the four
points that define it.
>From the top-right corner,
around to the top left.
So these four points define a desired
rectangle and I'm putting these points
in my work function in a point
array named dst for destination.
Now that I have my source and
destination points,
I can compute the Perspective Transform,
which is a matrix that's returned by
the function Get Perspective Transform.
The function Get Perspective Transform
just takes in our four source points,
and our destination points, and
it returns the mapping perspective
matrix which I'll call M.
You could also get the Inverse
Perspective Transform to unwarp
the image, by just switching the source
and destination points in this function.
This would just reverse the transform.
Next I just need to transform M to
the original image to get the warped
image and I do that with
a call to warped perspective.
Warped perspective takes inner image the
perspective matrix M the size we want
the warped image to be which I'll leave
as the same size of the original image,
and how to interpolate points which is
just filling in missing points as it
warps an image and
I'll put that as linear interpolation.
So this returns a perspective warped
image based on this matrix M and
the given image.
And finally,
I'll just return that warped image.
Now, let's see what happens when I
apply a warp function to an image.
And here's code to plot the original and
the transformed image
next to one another.
So here's the original and
the warped image.
It looks pretty good,
I can see the stop sign as if I
were standing right in front of it.
Now, it's your turn to apply
a perspective transform to a new image.