File systems use several techniques to
try to minimize the access to disk and
to improve the file access overheads.
Much like hardware caches are used to
temporarily hold recently used data and
avoid accessing main memory,
file systems rely on buffer caches,
except these buffer caches
are present in main memory and
they're used in order to reduce
the number of necessary disk accesses.
With caching the file will be read or
written to from the cache and
periodically any changes to the file
that have not been backed up on
permanent storage will be flushed
from memory to disc, by forcing these
flushes to happen only periodically,
we can amortize the cost of performing
a disc access over multiple intermittent
rights that will hit the cache.
File systems support this operation
using the fsync system call,
another component that helps reduce the
file access overheads is what we call
I/O scheduling,
this is the component that orders how
disk access operations
will be scheduled.
The intent is to reduce the diskette
movement that's a slow operation and we
can do that by maximizing the number of
sequential accesses, which are needed,
so, for sequential access, this kind of
movement is not expensive It's expensive
for these random accesses, so
that's what we want to avoid.
What that means is, let's say we have
two operations that have been issued,
write block 25 followed by write block
17 and if the disk head is at position,
let's say 15, these operations will
be reordered by the I/O scheduler so
that they're issues as write
first block 17 and then block 25,
and this will achieve this objective
of maximizing sequential and
minimizing random accesses.
Another useful technique is prefetching,
since for many workloads there is a lot
of locality in how the file is accessed,
it is likely that if one
data block is accessed, the subsequent
blocks will be accessed as well.
File systems can take advantage
of this feature by prefetching
more than one block of a file
whenever a single block is accessed,
this does use up more disk
bandwidth to move larger,
in this case, three x worth of
data from disk into main memory.
But it can significantly impact,
or reduce,
the access latency,
by increasing the cache hit rate
because more of the accesses will be
served out of cache, potentially.
Finally, another useful technique is
journaling, I/O scheduling reduces
the random access, but
it still keeps the data in memory, so,
these blocks, 17 and 25,
are still in memory waiting for
the I/O scheduler to interleave
them in the right way.
That means that,
if something happens and
the system crashes,
these data blocks will be lost, so,
we want to make sure that the data ends
up on disk, but we still want to make
sure that we reduce the level of
random access that's required.
This is where journaling helps,
as opposed to writing out the data
in the proper disk location,
which will require a lot of random
access we write updates in a log, so,
the log will contain some description of
the write that's supposed to take place.
If we specify the block,
the offset, and the value,
that essentially describes an individual
write, now, I'm over trivializing
this there is a little bit more that
goes into it, but this is overall,
the nature of the journal link or
the logging base systems.
The following file systems to
execute called the ext3 and
the ext4 they're also part
of current Linux versions,
they use journaling as well
as many other file systems.
Note that a journal has to
be periodically updated
into a proper disk location, otherwise
it will just grow indefinitely and
it will be really hard to find anything.
So if we look at these four techniques
and summary, every single one of
them contributes to reducing the file
system overheads and latencies.
This is done by increasing the
likelihood of accessing data from memory
by not having to wait on
slow disk head movements,
by reducing the overall number
of accesses to disk and
definitely the number of
random accesses to disk.
These techniques are commonly used
in current file system solutions.