Let's recall our path of analysis so far.
We started with the question, can we predict the next time a person will tweet?
In order to quantify this question,
we chose the number of seconds since the last tweet.
Now, the nature of the question suggests creating a regression estimator.
We want to directly predict how long until the next tweet.
Taking a look at the initial histogram of inter-tweet times
suggested creating an exponential fit.
After seeing how well that did, we saw that it was
usually underestimating the actual inter-tweet time by just a little amount.
And so we added an offset.
After adding that offset, our model became to always guess 8,585 and
a half seconds.
We found that when we did that,
our model was correct to within about five minutes, 50% of the time.
Now, of course, we would like for
it to be more accurate, but there was a problem.