In addition to creating
a unifying style for your app,
it's also important to design your app
to look good across different devices.
Android devices include everything from
small watches to phones to large tablets
and even TVs.
And the same layout on the phone
won't necessarily look
great on a screen with a different size.
Fortunately, the platform has
been built with that in mind.
So there are already tools that you can
use to optimize the user experience
across different devices.
You've already seen an example of this
when you created this landscape layout
in the last lesson.
This lets you customize the appearance
of the app when it changes its
orientation from portrait to landscape
and we'll go through the same process to
customize the layout for
different screen sizes.
This is called responsive design.
Responsive design is the act of
creating designs that respond to and
work well on a variety of screen sizes,
shapes and orientation, and
we'll see examples of this in a bit.
But first, let's talk about
the different screen sizes and
resolutions you might expect
your app to be installed on.