Hi, my name is Thad Starner.
At Georgia Tech, I teach the AI course,
the mobile ubiquitous computing course,
and when I'm lucky, the computer science
rapid prototyping hardware class.
In this course, we are doing
something a little different
that in other Georgia Tech
courses up to this point.
We're taking parts of Sebastian Thurn's
and Peter Norvig's original AI course on
Udacity, and mixing it with the best
parts of my teaching at Georgia Tech.
When Sebastian and Peter first presented
the idea of these online courses,
one hope was that we could mix the best
parts of the best courses of top
lecturers, and make a class which is
better than what anyone of us could do.
Peter will be covering search and
logic and planning.
Sebastian will be teaching the section
on probability and bayes nets.
And I will be covering
the rest of the content.
Let's get started.