So far we've worked with an isolation
board with only five possible moves.
In searching to end game caused
huge game trees that were hard to
show on the screen.
How bad will it get with
an interesting game board?
Well let's pull up the five by five
board Shelly and I were playing on.
How many different leaf
nodes can we expect?
>> Well, it's easy to put an upper
limit on the number of nodes.
>> How so?
>> On the first move O can put its piece
in any of 25 places.
Then, on the next move,
X can put its piece in any of 24 places.
After that there are 23 empty
places followed by 22 and so on.
Now, all of these spots
are always possible moves so,
we know there have to be less nodes
than 25 times 24 times 23 and so on.
So less than 25 factorial nodes.
>> 25 factorial, how big is that?
>> About 10 to the 25th power.
>> Ack.
Okay.
If we assume a modern
multicore gigahertz processor
which can do 10 to the ninth
operations per second,
it will take 10 to the 16th
seconds to search the entire game.
Okay, each hour is 3600 seconds,
and each day is 24 hours, and
each year has 365 days.
That means over 300 million years.
>> Actually 317,097,920
years to be precise.
>> I don't think we
have that long to wait.
>> I just gave you a quick upper bound
estimate of the number of nodes,
it isn't really that bad.
>> You're right, let's see if
we can do a better estimate.
Okay, there's not much we can
do about the first moves.
There really are 25 times
24 potential first moves,
but after that, each piece moves like
a queen, and there are less moves.
What is the maximum number of moves
possible in the third move of the game?
>> That sounds like
a great quiz question.