There you have it.
Everything you need to know to implement
the first stage of your project.
Thank you very much, for
the enlightening discussion of
image distortion, warping,
color spaces, and gradients.
>> It was my pleasure.
I hope you enjoyed learning
a bit about how cameras work.
And how you can extract
the maximum amount of information
from your images and a video.
So Ryan, what do you think?
Will we be able to build a better
lane mapping algorithm after this?
>> Yes indeed.
I've tried these techniques out myself.
And here is a sneak peek at
the results I came up with.
Here, I'm mapping out the lane and
tracking its position.
While measuring the lane curvature and
the position of my vehicle with
respect to center in each frame.
Now, I think that's pretty cool.
But I'm sure you'll come up with
an even better implementation.
So have fun and
we'll see you in the next section.