When I was a Udacity coach, I saw a lot
of students do amazingly well, and
some students disappear.
The differentiator wasn't ability or
free time or age or gender.
It was consistency.
The best students had
a consistent schedule and
they stuck to it, always making
progress, even if it was sometimes slow.
So, if you're serious about
completing this course,
there's one more thing I
want you to do right now.
And that is figure out when during
the next two weeks you're going to be
working on this course and
write it down somewhere.
I recommend an hour every weekday
ideally before worker class.
If you've got a scheduler or
a Google calendar,
that's a great place to write this down.
But even if you don't,
write it down somewhere,
even if it's on the back of a receipt
you're about to throw away.