The way ember handles nested
routes is one thing that makes it
a fantastic framework.
So it's important that you're
comfortable both generating nested
routes and
working with them in a nested format.
We're going to be working
with our toy store again.
You're going to be working
with nested routes and
then modifying their templates.
Here are the instructions for this quiz.
Make sure to go in order,
If you try to do this second step
before this first one it won't work and
you'll get a blank page.
So start at the top and
work your way down.
The link to the starter code for
this project is in the instructor notes.
When you finish building the template,
the feedback extension
will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page,
have fun.
Ember uses the queue unit
testing framework, and
I created a number of tests
that you need to satisfy.
These tests help guide you through
completing the assignment.
Once all the tests have passed, the
feedback extension will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.
You can find a link to this project's
test page in the project's read me file.