Let's first look at how threads should be represented by an operating system or
a system library that provides multithreading support.
And also what is necessary for thread creation.
Remember, during this lesson we will base our
discussion on the primitives that are described and used in Burrell's paper.
These don't necessarily correspond to some interfaces that
are available in the real threading systems or, or programming languages.
And in our next lesson we will talk about Pthreads which is
an example of a threading interface supported by most modern operating systems.
So that will make the discussion a little bit more concrete.
You can think of this lesson and the content of
Burrell's paper as explaining this content at a more fundamental level.
But first we need some data structure to represent a thread actually.
The thread type proposed by Burrell is the data structure that contains all
information that's specific to a thread and that can describe a thread.
This includes the thread identifier that the threading system will
use to identify a specific thread.
Register values, in particular the program counter and the stack pointer,
the stack of the thread, and any other thread specific data or attributes.
These additional attributes for instance could be used by the thread
management systems so that it can better decide how to schedule threads or
how to debug, errors with threads or other aspects of thread management.
For thread creation, Burrell proposes a fork call with two parameters,
a proc argument, and
that is the procedure that the created thread will start executing.
And then args, which are the arguments for this procedure.
This fork should not be confused with the Unix system called fork that we
previously discussed.
The Unix system call creates a new process and
is an exact copy of the calling process.
And here fork creates a new thread that will
execute this procedure with these arguments.
When a thread T0 calls a fork a new thread T1 is created.
That means that new thread data structure of this type is created and
its fields are initialized such that its program counter will point to
first instruction of the procedure proc, and
these arguments will be available on this stack of the thread.
After the fork operation completes, the process as a whole has two threads.
T0, the parent thread, and T1, and these can both execute concurrently.
T0 will execute the next operation after the fork call, and T1 will start
executing with the first instruction in proc, and with the specified arguments.
So what happens when T1 finishes?
Let's say it computed some result, as a result of proc,
and now somehow it needs to return that result.
Or, it may be just some, some status of the computation like success or error.
One programming practice would be to store the results of
the computation in some well-defined location in
the address space that's accessible to all the threads.
And they have some mechanism to notify either the parent or
some other thread that the result is now available.
More generally, however, we need some mechanism to determine that a thread is
done, and if necessary, to retrieve its result, or at least to determine
the status of the computation, the success or the error of its processing.
For instance, we can have an application where the parent
thread does nothing but create a bunch of
child threads that process different portion of an input array.
And the parent thread will still have to wait until all of
its children finish the processing before it can exit so
as not to force their early termination, for instance.
To deal with this issue, Burrell proposes a mechanism he calls Join.
It has the following semantic.
When the parent thread calls join with the thread ID of the child thread,
it will be blocked until the child completes.
Join will return to the parent the result of the child's computation.
At that point the child, for real, exits the system, any allocated data
structures saved for the child, all of the resources that were allocated for
its execution will be freed and the child is at that point terminated.
You should note that other than this mechanism where the parent is
the one that's joining the child in all other aspects, the parent and
the child thread are completely equivalent.
They can all access all resources that are available to
the process as a whole and share them.
And this is true both, with respect to the hardware resources, CPU memory, or
actual state within the process.