So far in this lesson we mentioned several useful metrics.
For instance, we talked about execution time and
throughput, response time, CPU utilization.
But there are many other useful metrics to consider.
For instance, user may not just care when they will get an answer, but
they may also care when their job will actually start being executed.
We call this metric wait time.
The job is interactive, so the user needs to interact with this.
Obviously the sooner he starts,
the sooner the user will be able to do something about it.
If the job is a long running job and the sooner it starts,
the user has a chance to find out maybe that something's going wrong.
So It can reconfigure the task, it can stop it and
then reconfigure and launch it again.
So wait time could be an important metric in some contexts.
Then let's think about throughput for instance.
We know throughput helps evaluate the utility of a platform.
So how many tasks will it complete over a period of time?
How many processes, how many jobs will we complete at over a period of time?
This can be relevant in the context of a single machine, a single server.
Or in the context of an entire data center for instance.
Now, if I'm the owner of the data center,
throughput is not the only thing that I care for.
I'm probably more concerned about some other type of metric that we
can call platform efficiency.
And this says some combination of how well I
utilize my resources to deliver this throughput.
So it's not just a matter of having higher throughput, but also being able to
utilize the resources that are available in my data center more efficiently.
The reason for
this is that as a data center operator, I make money when I complete jobs.
So the higher the throughput, the greater the income for me.
However, I also spend money to run the machines, to buy more servers.
So it's important to have a good ratio.
So platform efficiency would for instance, capture that.
If it's really just the dollars that I'm concerned about,
then a metric like performance per dollars would capture that.
So if I'm considering buying the next greatest hardware platform.
Then I can think about whether the cost that I will pay extra for
that new piece of hardware,
will basically be compensated with some impact on the performance that I see.
Or maybe I'm concerned about the amount of power,
the watts, that can be delivered to a particular platform.
Or the energy that will be consumed during the execution.
So then defining some metrics that capture performance per watt, or
performance per joule will be useful ones.
You may have heard of the term SLA.
It stands for Service Level Agreement.
Enterprise applications will give typically SLAs to their customers.
One example, for
instance will be that you will get a response within three seconds.
Or, it may be even more subtle than that.
For instance, a service like Expedia perhaps, has an SLA with it's customers.
And it's customers would be like Delta Airlines and
American Airlines, that it will provide most accurate quote for
95% of the flights that are being returned to customers.
So then for that enterprise application,
one important thing would be whether there any SLAs that are violated.
Whether there are any customer requests that took longer than three seconds, or
that did not provide quotes for airfare that were all 100% accurate.
A metric-like percentage of SLA violations would capture that information.
For some applications, there is some natural opportunity for
a slack in the application.
For instance, if you think about a regular video application,
humans can't perceive more than 30 frames per second.
So being so focused on the frames per second, and
trying to maximize that frames per second rate, that's not the goal.
However, making sure that there's at least 30 frames per second.
So that users don't start seeing some random commercials during the video that
they're watching on YouTube, that's something that's important.
So it's not so much about this raw request rate or
wait time, but rather it's a metric that really is
concerned whether the client perceives the service as performing well or not.
You may be concerned with the performance metric of an individual application.
Or you may need to try to come up with some kind of aggregate performance
metric that tries to average the execution time for all tasks, or
average the wait time for all tasks.
Or maybe even this would be a weighted average based on the priorities of
the tasks.
Also in addition to just being constrained with CPu utilization,
there are a number of other resources that we may be concerned about.
Memory, file systems, the storage subsystem.
So some metrics that are concerned with the average resource usage
are also useful