All right, that ends today's, relatively short lesson.
We've just, a flavor of projective geometry.
There are entire, I want to say books,
there are entire lifetimes dedicated to projective geometry, mostly in France.
They've got this thing about it.
But in particular, out of France, came from [FOREIGN] group and
others was the application of projected geometry to computer vision.
And it really revolutionized some of the, the work that was done in terms of
how people thought about stereo and other types of relationship between views.
What we're going to do, is we're going to discuss,
we're going to use this a little bit in our next two lectures where we
talk about what's called the essential matrix, and the fundamental matrix.
Those are a little more intense, so hang on.