Okay so,
here I am in my download section.
So, I'll click on
the madlibs generator link.
Which will open up a new tab,
with all these raw text.
So I'll just highlight all of it like
so, or you can also just do Ctrl+A.
Now, I'll do Ctrl+ C, or I can also
just do right-click and hit Copy.
Now, I want to put this in
my text editor of choice.
So I use Sublime.
So I'll open up a new Sublime window.
And I'll paste it in by doing
right-clicking using Paste.
Or you can do Ctrl+V.
And here we have all this raw
text in my Sublime window.
Now, I want to save
this as a Python file.
So I go to File>Save As, and
I'll say mad_libs.pi.
And I'll save this on the desktop.
Cool.
All right, now you can see all
of this color changed here so
that means it's a Python file.
So we're in good shape.
Now that we've saved it on the desktop,
let's run this file.
So I will open Idle,
which should come pre-installed if
you already downloaded Python 2.7.
So I'll open up Idle.
And now I want to open the file that
I just saved, the madlibs file.
So I'll go to File>Open>Desktop.
And here's my mad libs file,
so I'll double-click it.
Now it's opened.
Cool.
So, I will now run this by going to Run,
and
Run Module, so
you can either click this or F5.
When I click that, here we go.
Now we have our mad libs generator up
and running on our local machines.
So I can type in adjective,
so I'll do blue.
Verb run, occupation,
let's go to teacher, and
skateboard, place San Francisco.
There we go, what a blue day.
I can run the day off
from being a teacher and
go skateboard at San Francisco.