When a developer fixes a bug,
makes a new feature or
even just updates the color of a button.
How does that change get
delivered to the end user?
As you've seen this is not a cut and
dry process and
there are quite a few
things to think about.
>> Luckily for you and your coworkers
you now know the tools to start
implementing continuous integration and
continuous delivery into
your team's workflow.
Simply streamlining the CI and
CD process isn't enough though.
You should aim to have a robust
testing suite that covers some or
all of the testing domains we
talked about in this lesson.
>> When you're writing these tests you
can start with low weight smoke tests
that make sure the most important
features of your product are working.
>> Next you and your team should strive
to test the majority of the functions
and classes in your code base.
You can get a general idea of how
thorough your testing suite is
by taking code coverage measurements.
In addition you can set up static
analysis tools in your integration
process to help developers catch issues
before even building their code.
>> Then once you're done
testing all of your components.
You can test how well they work
together with acceptance tests,
which you can automate running.
>> Beyond these more basic forms of
testing you should incorporate manual
acceptance testing by making
deployment to a test server painless.
Finally you should also run security
tests and performance tests.
>> As part of the DevOps team, you're
uniquely positioned to help define and
automate testing and deployment.
To make life easier for your whole team.
[SOUND]
>> We hope you take the skills you
learned in these lessons into the
workplace to support delivering great
web apps, mobile apps,
and more to your users.