[Thrun] Here is a very early example of structure from motion by Carlo Tomasi
and Takeo Kanade.
They used Harris corner detectors to find corners in the image of this toy 3D house,
and they were able from a number of images to fully recover the 3D structure
of every single corner point, as shown in this video.
So as they then take this 3D data set and turn it in arbitrary directions,
you can see the full 3D structure was recovered.
This is work in 1992.
It used principal component analysis to solve the problem
and is one of the most amazing pieces of early computer vision research.
Carlo, who used to be a Stanford professor for many years,
then scanned his kitchen and with the same Harris corner detector
was able to reconstruct a 3D structure of his kitchen, as shown over here.
Again, this is one of the most impressive early computer vision research results I've seen.
Here is a flight video of flying over the hills of Pennsylvania.
As you can see, using the same technique he was able to recover the 3D structure
of the outdoor terrain and build elevation maps, as shown over here.
Marc Pollefeys, who presently teaches at ETH Zurich,
came up with a beautiful solution to the structure from motion problem,
here imaging different buildings in his hometown.
From this video you can see multiple snapshots of a single building
where the different perspective distortion has an effect on the appearance of the building,
quite obviously.
Using those images he was able to reconstruct the 3D shape of the building facade,
as shown in this video.
Again, at the time it was one of the most impressive results ever achieved
in structure from motion.
You can see amazing detail as he zooms in to his building model.
He then moved on to map entire cities,
and here is an example of a map that he produced from an entire city block.
You can see how he reconstructs the building facades in unprecedented detail.
There's also a lot of occlusion gaps where the original imager wasn't able to see anything.
Those show up in black, and they look a little bit disturbing in this image over here.
But in reality, your camera can't see everything.
So even if you do a perfect job with structure from motion,
it's really hard to reconstruct every single inch of the environment.
Still, this stands out as one of the most impressive results ever
in what I would call the Holy Grail of 3D computer vision.