Hi there, welcome back.
This week we're getting into
the cool stuff with Tensorflow.
In this lesson, Vincent will show you
how to build a multilayer network,
which you've seen before but
now you going to do it in Tensorflow.
Next, you'll learn how to
use a deep neural network
to extract features from images.
These types of models are called
Convolutional Networks or ConvNets.
That could be used to detect and
recognize objects and
pictures with amazing accuracy.
Also AWS credits, you'll each get $100
of credits to use on AWS Cloud machines.
We've built a lesson to teach you
how to use an AWS EC2 instance for
training your networks on a GPU.
It'll change your life.
And finally we're launching
the second project.
It's on object recognition.
You'll train a convolution network on
a bunch of images from the data set.
It'll be able to differentiate between
frogs, and cats, and cars, and planes.
I think you'll find it
an interesting challenge.
Cheers.