So let's look at this example again--let me redraw the data.
What makes these clusters so different
is not the absolute location of each data point,
but the connectedness of these data points.
The fact that these 2 points belong together
is likely because there's lots of points in-between.
In other words, it's the affinity
that defines those clusters, not the absolute location.
So spectral clustering gets annotation of affinity
to make clustering happen.
So let me look at the simple example for spectral clustering
that would also work for K-means or EM,
but they'll be useful to illustrate spectral clustering.
Let's assume there's 9 data points as shown over here,
and I've colored them differently in blue, red, and black.
But to clustering algorithms, they all come with the same color.
Now the key element of spectral clustering
is called the affinity martrix,
which is a 9 by 9 matrix in this case,
where each data point gets graphed
realtive to each other data point.
So let me write down all the 9 data points
into the different rows of this matrix--
the red ones, the black ones, and the blue ones.
And in the columns, I graphed the exact same 9 data points.
I then calculate for each pair of data points their affinity,
where I use for now affinity as the
quadratic distance in this diagram over here.
Clearly, the red dots to each other have a high affinity,
which means a small quadratic distance.
Let me indicate this as follows--
But realtive to all the other points, the affinity is weak.
So there's a very small value in these elements over here.
Similarly, the affinity of the black
data points to each other is very high,
which means that the following block diagonal
in this matrix will have a very large value.
Yet the affinity to all the other data points will be low.
And of course, the same is true for the blue data points.
The interesting thing to notice now
is that this is an approximately rank-deficient matrix.
And further, the data points that belong to the same class--
like the 3 red dots or the 3 black dots,
have a singular affinitive vector to all the other data points.
So this vector over here is similar to this vector over here.
It's similar to this vector over here,
but it's very different to this vector over here,
which then itself is similar to the vector over here,
yet different to the previous ones.
Such a situation is easily addressed by what's called
principal component analysis, or PCA.
PCA is a method to identify vectors that are similar
in an approximate rank-deficient matrix.
Consider once again our affinity matrix
with prinicple component analysis,
which is a standard linear trick,
we can re-represent this matrix
by the most dominant tivectors you'll find there.
And the first one, might look like this.
The second one, which would be orthogonal, may look like this.
The third one, like this.
These are called eigenvectors, and the principle component
now is each eigenvector has an item of value
that states how prevalent this vector is in the original data.
And for these 3 vectors, you're going to find a large eigenvalue
because there's a number data points that represent
these vectors quite prevalently
like the first 3 does for this guy over here.
There might be additional eigenvectors like something like this,
but such eigenvectors will have a small eigenvalue
simply because this vector isn't really
required to explain the data over here.
It might just be explaining some of the noise
in the affinity matrix
that I didn't even dare draw in here.
Now if you take the eigenvectors with the largest
eigenvalues--3 in this case,
you first discover that the dimensionality
of the underlying data space.
The dimensionality equals the number of large eigenvalues.
Further, if you re-represent each data vector
using those eigenvectors,
you'll find a 3 dimensional space
where original data falls into a varity of different places.
And these places are easily told apart by conventional clustering.
So in summary, spectral clustering builds
an affinity matrix of the data points.
It strikes the eigenvectors with the largest eigenvalues,
and then re-map those vecotrs into a new space
with the data points easily clustering the conventional way.
This is called affinity-based clustering or spectral clustering.
Let me illustrate this once again with the
data set that has a different spectral clustering
than a conventional clustering.
In this data set, the different clusters belong
together because they're affinity is similar.
These 2 points belong together
because there is a point in-between.
If we now draw the affinity matrix for those data points,
you find that the first and second data points are close together
and the second and the third, but not the first and the third.
Hence these 2 off diagonal elements here have remained small.
Similarly for the red points as shown here
with these 2 elements over here relatively small.
And also for the black points
where these 2 elements over here are small.
And interestingly enough, even though these aren't blocked diagonal,
your first 3 largest eigenvectors
will still look the same as before.
I find this quite remarkable
that even though these aren't exactly blocks,
those vecotrs still represent the 3 most
important vectors for which to recover
the data using principle component analysis.
So in this case, spectral clustering would easily
assign those guys and those guys and those guys
to the respective same cluster,
which wouldn't be quite as easily the case for
expectation-maximization or k-means.
So let me ask you the following quiz.
Suppose we have 8 data points.
How many elements will the affinity matrix have?