Now sometimes it may be very difficult to specify
exactly what states can be reachable by an abstract action,
because the refinements are complicated.
We can go with the notion of an approximate set of reachable states.
That's what I've shown schematically here.
For this abstract action, I've shown a lower bound and an upper bound
on the states that are reachable.
What do I mean by that?
Consider the abstract action of going to the airport in San Francisco.
Now, some things I know are going to be true about the resulting state.
I know it's going to take, say, half an hour to get there no matter what way I go.
That's always going to be true.
Other things depend on which choice I make.
I may consume some money if I take a taxi.
I may consume some gas if I take a car,
but I may not be able to specify exactly which of those combinations hold true.
So we approximate the set of reachable states by this lower bound
of things that we know we can get to
and this upper bound of things that we might be able to get to,
but we're not quite sure if all combinations of them will check out depending on the refinement.
Here, similarly, there's another set of lower and upper bounds and here as well.
These are the goals.
What I want you to tell me is for each of these three actions,
is it guaranteed, yes, that I can reach the goal state if I choose the right refinement,
or is it never possible--no, that I'll never be able to reach the goal state--
or is it uncertain yet because the description of upper and lower bound
doesn't tell us enough about whether we can reach the goal state.
Answer that for this abstract action here,
and for this abstract action here,
and for this abstract action here.