Now let's talk more specifically about
what happens with each method call.
So in our pets app,
the catalog activity calls on the
content resolver using the query method.
In order to help the content resolver
know which provider to eventually
resolve to, we'll be passing a content
Uri inside the query method.
And remember, the Uri here helps
us specify the resource that we're
interested in, inside the data base.
So next up, the content resolver having
gotten the information from the query
method has an identical query method of
its own which it uses on the appropriate
provider and in this case,
it knows to check out the pet provider.
Next, in order to get the data,
the query method essentially translates
the parameters that was passed into SQL,
and using this,
it will act on the database.
So for example, in order to query all
the pets back from the pets table,
we pass the appropriate query method
parameters equivalent to this statement.
So once the information is queried,
what's returned is a cursor and
this cursor contains the rows of
interest and this goes all the way back
to our catalog activity, that
originally called for the information.
So in our second kind of example,
let's take a look at the insert method.
So the insert method is very
similar to the query method, but
with an additional parameter here,
our content values.
So this parameter contains what
we actually want to insert
into the database, whereas the URI
tells us where it should be inserted.
So the catalog activity again
calls the Content Resolver
using this insert method and then
the Content Resolver has an identically
named insert method of its own which
it uses only appropriate provider.
And in this case again, it's going to
be the pet provider in order to
insert our specified
value into the database.
So to actually insert the data into
the database, the information that
were passed in the insert method
are translated to SQL, and this is
used to determine what values should
be inserted where Into the database.
Now this time for the insert method
rather than a cursor being return.
The insert method returns a content
URI telling us exactly where
the specific pet was
inserted in our database.
Now next up, is the update method.
So the update method
situation as you see,
looks very similar to our insert
method because both of them need
the information of where to update and
what information to update it with.
So the URI and the ContentValues.
And so again, the catalog activity
calls on the content resolver
using this update method which contains
the URI and the ContentValues parameter.
And again, we see that the content
resolver has an identically named
update method which it uses
on the appropriate provider
to update the specific
value in our database.
Now as we actually update the database,
the information that was passed in the
update method is translated to SQL and
that helps us determine what should be
inserted and where inside this database.
Now for the update method,
what we get back is the number of rows
that were inserted into the database and
this is different from what we
got back from query and insert.
All right so on to our last CRUD method,
our delete method.
So notice that this input looks
really similar to our query method
where we only pass in the Uri.
And this is because we don't need to
pass in content values because that
information is not needed to actually
delete anything from the table.
So next you know the drill by now, where
the content resolver has an identically
named delete method which we will use
to find the appropriate provider and
help us act on the database.
So once that information is
passed into the delete method,
it's translated to SQL so
we can determine more specifically, what
needs to be deleted from the database.
So similar to the update method,
the delete methods
returns the value of the number of rows
that were deleted in our situation, and
this goes back to the catalog
activity that originally called it.
So here's a concrete example
of how we'll be using one
of those CRUD methods.
So in this case,
in order to display a list of pets, so
here in the catalog activity, we'll need
to use the query method on the whole
pets table, and this will help us query
the provider for all the pets data.
Now here's another example.
In order to insert dummy data from
the menu item, we'll need to call
the provider's insert method to
insert a new pet into the database.
All right, so
here's your chance to give it a try.
So given the discussion we just had
about the flow of each of the four CRUD
methods, so query, insert,
update and delete,
I want you to finish identifying which
provider method should be called for
each piece of UI
functionality listed here.
So in the EditorActivity,
we'll have these four functionalities.
We'll need to save a new pet,
display an existing pet,
update an existing pet, and
then delete an existing pet.
Similarly in the catalog activity,
we'll need to delete all the pets.
So which method corresponds to
each of these functionalities?