The main way in which PCI interconnects
devices to the CPUs is by making
devices accessible in a manner that's
similar to how CPUs access memory.
The device registers appear to
the CPU as memory locations
at a specific physical address.
So then when the CPU
writes to these locations,
the integrated memory PCI controller
realizes that this access, the access
to this physical location, should be
routed to the appropriate device.
What this means is that a portion of the
physical memory on that computing system
is dedicated for
interactions with the device.
We call this memory-mapped I/O.
And the portion of the memory that's
reserved for these interactions is
controlled by a specific set of
registers, the Base Address Registers.
So how much memory in starting it,
which address,
will be used by a particular device.
This gets configured during
the boot process and
it's determined how exactly it's done
by the PCI configuration protocol.
In addition, the CPU can access
devices via special instructions.
For instance, in x86 platforms,
there are special in/out instructions
that are used for accessing devices.
Each of the instructions has to
specify the target device, so
the I/O port, and some value that's
going to be stored in registers.
That's the value that needs to
be written out to device or
the value that will be
read out of the device.
This model is called the I/O port model.
The path from the device to the CPUs
complex can take two routes.
Devices can generate interrupts to
the CPU, or the other option is for
the CPU to poll the device by
reading its status register
in order to determine, does the device
have some data for the CPU?
Does the device have a response to
a request that was sent to the CPU?
Or some other information.
There are overheads associated with
both of these methods, and as always,
there are trade-offs between the two.
With interrupts, the problem is due to
the handling of the interrupt routine,
the interrupt handler.
There are the actual steps involved in
the handling of the interrupt routine.
There's several operations
like setting and
resetting the interrupt mask depending
on what kinds of interrupts are allowed
to interrupt the interrupt
handling routine or not.
And also some indirect effects due
to cache pollution that's related to
the execution of this handler.
So all of these are overheads, but
on the flip side, it is possible
to trigger an interrupt as soon as
the device has something to do,
some kind of notification,
some kind of data for the CPU.
For polling, the operating system
has a possibility to choose
when it will poll at
some convenient times,
when at least some of the cache
pollution effect won't be too bad.
If that is the case, then that's great.
Some of those overheads will be removed,
but potentially
this will introduce some delays in
the way that event is observed and
in the way that the event is handled.
The opposite of just continuously
polling will clearly introduce some
CPU overheads that may simply not
be affordable if there aren't
enough CPUs in the system or the system
is busy otherwise doing other things.
But our interrupt or polling
mechanism should be selected will
really depend on the kind of device that
we're dealing with on the objectives,
whether we want to maximize
things like throughput or
latency, on the complexity of
the interrupt handling routine, and
the characteristics of
the load of the device.
So, what is the input data rate,
the output data rate that needs to met,
and number of other factors.