We already talked about the one way
requirement of these kind of functions.
So given a hash value,
we can't go back to the password itself.
So this is obviously a requirement.
The inverse should be
very hard to compute.
Actually, we do want
different hash values for
different passwords,
because what would happen otherwise?
If user one and
user two had the same hash values,
then user ine can actually
log into user two's account,
using user one's password, because user
two's hash value is what we compare.
So, when user 1 claims to be user 2,
types his password, the right hash
value is produced, right for user two.
So user one is able to get into
user two's account if we don't have
the different hash values for
distinct passwords.
So second option is also a requirement.
Provide more efficient storage for,
that's not really a big deal.
We said passwords produce
a fixed size output.
Could be a couple of hundred bits,
128 or
256 or something like that, but
storage itself is not a big deal.