The next step is going to be to convert
that data into a format that's a lot
easier to manipulate. We don't want to
keep the data on disk. We want to load up
in memory so that we can access it very
quickly, and we want to load it in
formats that is a lot more amiable to
manipulation.
So down the road we'll be using
Tensorflow. Tensorflow uses tensors as
the basic representation for everything.
Tensor is justin a dimensional array,
so we're going to convert every image
data set into a multi-dimensional array
where at each index you have, in the
first dimension and image, then you have
x and y coordinates and you have at each
coordinate of that 3d array, a point value
that says is it black or is it white.
Along the way while you're, we are
loading up all this data into that array,
we're going to start normalizing it as
mentioned in the lecture. You want your
data to basically be 0 mean and small
equal variance. So we're going to do that
at the same time and so that we don't
have to do multiple passes of processing.
To make things simpler and so that you
don't have to restart the process if you
accidentally run out of memory, or if you
run into problems, and we're going to
save those big tensor arrays into a
pickle file for each of the letters of
each data sets and this way you don't
have to restart from scratch if this
takes too long.
So this can take a while, you know it
needs to run a whole bunch of small PNG
files.
Some of them are bad for whatever reason.
Don't worry about those you have plenty
of data to play with and you don't need
to have everything there.