Now that you've completed
your paper prototype,
it's time to, you guessed it,
share it with your friends and
family as well as with your
fellow classmates on the forum.
Now the important thing here is to put
the paper prototype in front of people,
and to not say anything.
See if they can figure out
how the app works without
any guidance whatsoever from you.
Make particular note of where
the app might not feel intuitive,
or where a user might get stuck.
>> For example, what screen do I go to?
What button do I press?
If they're asking those
kinds of questions,
you definitely want to fix it before
you go into final development.
Jot down any notes that you might have
in this box below, or, even better,
make note of it on your blog.