The correct answer is sometimes. There are actually cases where we can do this.
It's not always possible because, as we learned before,
the camera doesn't really record the distance.
If we look into an arbitrary scene, we normally can't recover the depth from a single image.
But in certain cases it's possible. Here's a dollar bill.
A dollar bill is a fixed size, and you can know the size. All dollar bills have the same size.
And by understanding the internal projection size of this bill,
you can actually really recover how far it is away,
if you know things like focal length and so on.
The answer is yes in cases we know the size of the object
and no in cases where you don't know the size.
Therefore, sometimes was the correct answer here.