Now to complete this exercise, first
in the EditorActivity, I'll start by
calling our insertPet method from
our onOptionsItemSelectedMethod.
And I do that inside this switch case
statement where the R.id is action_save.
So putting this in here means that the
save button in the app was clicked and
will trigger this method.
Now, after I insert the pet,
I call the finished method here.
So this means the editor will close and
return to the previous activity, which
is the CatalogActivity in our case.
So this means when I press
the save button here,
the insertPet method is triggered.
Now let's move up to the insertPet
method inside our EditorActivity.
And inside it, we'll need to define
what happens when that method is called.
So first, I'll read from
the three edit text fields.
So I already have my name string here.
Let's finish it up for
our other three text fields.
So for breed and weight,
we call the same sequence of getText and
toString in order to get a string value.
Then optionally,
you can also call the method trim as
mentioned in the instructor's notes.
So this makes sure if the user
accidentally typed a space before or
after the text is typed,
it's removed from the string.
Now for the weight value,
we want to store weight as an integer,
not a string, so we'll be using
the integer.parseInt method
in order to convert
the string into an integer.
So next, to create the content values,
we can actually copy over the code from
our catalog activity to get
a writable database and
then create content values and
then insert that into the database.
So let's copy that code here.
Now all we need to do is simply change
the values inserted to the ones that we
grabbed from the edit text instead of
referring to the Toto dummy data here.
So changing the name value here to
nameString, which we defined above.
Changing the breed from
the hard-coded Terrier to breedString,
and then changing the gender
to the mGender value.
And mGender should be updated as soon
as the drop-down option is selected.
And the last one, let's change it to
weight, which we defined up here.
Now, we're throwing an error here
because it can't resolve the MDB value.
So remember to also create an instance
of the database PetDbHelper class.
And we're passing in a context this,
which is our current activity.
Now, as mentioned in the quiz,
if a new row ID is returned
from the DB.insert method,
then we want to show a toast that
the insert was completed successfully.
Otherwise, if this method returns a -1
value, this means an error occurred
with the insertion and we want to
show a different toast message.
You can write a simple if else statement
to show the correct toast message
depending on the value of the row
ID returned by our insert method.
So here's what that if-else
statement looks like.
So with those changes done,
let's run it on the emulator.
So first, let me go ahead and
clear the app data so I start fresh.
So back to Settings &gt; Apps,
select the Pets app,
then hit Storage and then Clear Data.
All right,
let's go back to the Pets app again.
So my pets database table has 0 rows.
And then let's go to the editor and
add a pet in.
So I've added Garfield our Tabby,
and I'm going to click Save now.
And with that, we see our toasts appear
down here showing that a pet with a row
ID 1 was inserted.
And the number of rows in our pet
database table was increased to 1.
So let's try it one more time.
Let's insert another pet in.
How about let's insert Binx the Bombay.
Let's make him a male of weight 6 kg.
So let's save him to the database.
And the row ID properly increases to 2.
So if when you're running the app,
the row count in the catalog activity
doesn't increment by 1,
remember the hint we gave in the quiz.
We need to modify the CatalogActivity
to query the database again
when the activity is restarted.
And this is because the catalog
activity already exists.
So if displayDatabaseInfo,
we're inside of it,
the old number of rows
would be displayed.
So, because onCreate isn't called again,
we'll need to move
the displayDatabaseInfo method into the
overridden onStart method as shown here.
And doing so
means that when you insert a new pet and
go back to the catalog activity,
the row count increases.
Now you can double check that the pets
that we inserted exist in the database
by downloading the shelter.db file and
then opening it up in the terminal or
command line with the select
* from pets command.
So to recap,
first you're triggering insert pets
when the Save button in
the editor is pressed.
Then you get all the string data
from the EditText fields and
then save them in
a ContentValues object.
Lastly, you insert that ContentValues
object into the pets table.
So after all these steps,
we've completed inserting
data via the Save button.