As I mentioned before, the cursor class
has numerous methods so allow us to
handle the cursor object once we
get it back from the create method.
One of the easiest things you
can do with the cursor object
is to see how many rows
are part of that cursor and
we can do that Using
the cursor.getCount method.
And currently we're actually using this
method already in our code, which is why
you're able to see the number of rows
change as you add a new pet each time.
A cursor object represents rows and
columns of data.
In addition it has a current
position within all these rows.
In order for us to get the data from
a specific row, we'll need to move our
cursor position to the the exact
row of data that we want.
Now when we first get our cursor back,
the position starts at -1.
And this is an invalid position
that starts right before that
first actual position 0,
the first usable position I mean.
Much like in array, you might
notice that the positioning numbers
start at 0 and
then incrementally move upward.
Now looking at the cursor
documentation for
Android, there's several method
that we can call to help us
move around that cursor object, and
let's explore a couple of these further.
The first one is our moveToFirst method,
which moves the cursor position to
the first row that's in our results set.
Say our results set is return
back the entire pets table.
Well, if we invoke moveToFirst,
this takes our cursor position
to the first row here.
And this allows us to access
data in this first record.
Next stop is moveToLast.
In this method moves the cursor
position to the last row
that's in the result set.
And again,
if our result set is the entire table
move to the last jumps it
down to this last row here.
Next we have the moveToPosition method.
And notice this method actually
takes in a parameter, so
it takes in the position.
Specifically, this method moves the
cursor position to a specified position.
For example,
you can have moveToPosition, and
have the position be 3 and
this would move us to the fourth row.
Visually, this is what this
method call looks like.
Say we have the entire table again.
Remember the numbering starts from 0 and
move upward.
If we want to go to position 3,
we're taking to the fourth row here.
All those move methods that we saw for
the cursor class, return either true or
false.
And this is to help us indicate whether
we can actually make that move.
For example, if we're at the last
position of our cursor object already,
and we call the moveToNext method.
Well, if the cursor position tries to
move downward, we notice that there is
no row to be found and so
this method will return to as false.
Cause we can't actually
move to another row.
Now we just covered methods that we
can use to get to the position that we
want in the cursor.
And once you're at that row, we can
use these different types of getType
methods, to help us retrieve those
specific values from the database.
Here are all these get methods.
We have getFlow, getInt, getLong,
and a couple other ones.
Notice that they all take a parameter
which is the columnIndex and
this is the columnIndex
of the attribute or
the column name that we're
interested in, inside our cursor.
Column indices are ordered according to
the names given in the projection, and
you can use the getColumnIndex method
in order to discover the index
of a column by a name.
I know that was a lot of
information going on.
Let's take a look at a specific example
and see how all these connections work.
In this example,
the cursor object return is all
the information from the pets table.
For this specific case,
we want to get the name of the pet
stored at row 4 of this cursor.
In order to do that, we can use this
block of code, so this first sign here,
cursor.moveToPostion 3 gets us to
position 3 which is the fourth row.
In this next line,
nameColumnIndex = cursor.getColumnIndex.
This method allows us to get the column
index from the column name that
we've passed in.
And in this case, we've passed in
the column COLUMN_PET_NAME, so
passing that in we get the value 1 back.
And remember this is because
column indices are ordered
according to the order, given in the
projection which we specified earlier.
Now the last on here
name = cursor.getString.
This method here returns the value
of the requested column as a string.
The requested column is this one
here which we've indicated as 1.
And using these two bits of information,
we see the name of the pet here is Cat.
One important thing about cursors is
that when you're done using them,
you should always call cursor.close.
This completely cleans up your
cursor and makes it invalid.
Be sure to use it only when
you're completely finished.
Not closing your cursor can cause
poor performance due to memory leaks.
We've seen an example of this method
call ready in our CatalogActivity.
Down at the bottom of the display
database info method,
in the finally clause,
we have the cursor.close call.
Forgetting to close your cursor is bit
like leaving dirty dishes in a kitchen,
after you're done eating, and
if you did it too many times,
the cursor becomes an unusable mess
because of all the unwashed dishes.
In this situation,
the kitchen is your app and
you don't want it to become
an unusable memory mess
because you haven't cleaned it up and
close up the cursor.
Let's pack this all that new
information on this exercise.
Assume I've called the query
method on our full pet's table,
using the projection that just
returns the pet name and pet weight.
Then on this cursor variable,
I execute these lines of code.
First off, I'm moving through
the different cursor positions here.
Then I'm getting the column indices and
using that information,
I get an integer back.
Now after executing these lines of code,
what is the integer value of
these result variable here?
And go ahead and
write your answer in this blank here.