Now let's take a look around
the code repository for this course.
We have provided some examples and
scaffolding for
the main app you'll be working on.
Follow the link in the Instruction Notes
to get the course code repository
on GitHub.
From there, you can choose either
to clone the repository or
just download it as a zip file.
You can see that there are folders for
each of the lessons.
We'll provide you with the starting
code for all of the exercises.
All the exercises build on the previous
ones, so you can start with the first
one and continue working on your
version until the end of the class.
Or you can grab the starting code for
a particular exercise and
continue from there.