Another process between them is once I have these multiple images that actually
have overlaps and everything registered, I need to figure out how to blend them,
crossfade across them, or cut them.
Again, something we will cover in extensive detail in a future lecture.
But here I just want to set the context.
So again, I have all of these images.
Seven images that we've seen before.
Just kind of put them on top of each other and kind of shown them to have
a little bit of transparency so we can see the overlap amongst all of them.
Warping has been done, but
now of course you notice some of the lighting conditions are different.
This can be done basically by figuring out which pixels from
which images should be visible.
What percentage of the mixture of these two pixels be visible?
Or should I just choose one pixel or set of pixels from one image to the other?
The fade and blend are merging those two images together.
Cut is choosing which one of the original image pixels do I want to choose.
This basically shows the step, now I can basically merge them and
then slowly, see notice that all of the boundaries are gone.
And this shows a perfectly clean and smooth panorama.
Another simple part, the step 5,
is cropping panorama basically just to kind of create a rectangular image again.
Again these are optional.
Sometimes I actually like to see panoramas without the cropping because it
kind of shows a nice transition across different viewpoints.
But this is now a much bigger image.
Shows the space much nicer.