Our description of the algorithm has
talked about paths in the state space.
I want to say a little bit now about how
to implement that in terms of a computer
algorithm.
We talk about paths, but we want to
implement that in some ways and
the implementation we talk about nodes.
A node is a data structure and
it has four fields.
A state field indicates the state
at the end of the path.
A action was the action
it took to get there.
The cost is the total cost and
the parent is a pointer to another node.
In this case,
the node that has state S and
it will have a parent which points
to the node that has state A and
that will have a parent
pointer that's no.
So, we have linked list of
nodes representing the path.
We'll use the word path for
the abstract idea and the word node for
the representation in
the computer memory.
But otherwise, you can think of
those two terms as being synonyms,
because they're in a one
to one correspondence.
Now, there are two main data
structures that deal with nodes.
We have the frontier and
we have the explored list.
So, let's talk about
how to implement them.
In the frontier, the operations we have
to deal with are removing the best item
from the frontier and
adding in new ones.
And that suggests, we should implement
it as a priority queue which knows how
to keep track of the best
items in proper order, but
we also need to have an additional
operation of a membership test.
Is a new item in the frontier?
And that suggests
representing it as a set,
which can be built from a hash table or
a tree.
And so, the most efficient
implementations of search
actually have both representations.
The explored set on
the other set is easier.
All we have to do there is be able
to add new members and check for
membership.
And so we represent that as
a single set which again,
can be done with either a hash table or
a tree.