So let's see what happens when we try an example on this. I'm going to give you
a paragraph describing a small program for counting the number of leaves on
a tree. A tree is a data structure consisting of nodes connected by directed
arcs, in which occurs a single root node from which all other nodes descend.
Nodes without outgoing arcs are called leaves, and the intent of the program is
to count the number of leaves in a given tree. Here's the paragraph description.
So counting tree nodes, keep a pile of the parts of the tree that have not yet
been counted, initially get a tree and put it on an, the empty pile.
The count of leaves is initially set to zero. As long as the pile is not empty,
repeatedly take a tree off the pile and examine it. If the tree consists of
a single leaf, then increment the leaf counter and throw away that tree.
If the tree is not a single leaf but instead consists of two subtrees,
split the tree into its left and right subtrees and put them back on the pile.
Once the pile is empty, display the count of the leaves. Okay, step one,
go through the description and underline all the nouns, see what you get.