[BLANK_AUDIO]
Welcome to your first day.
I'm Kelly, and I'll be your
mentor as you get settled in.
That means I'll be assigning you
projects, giving feedback and
connecting you to
the resources that you need.
I was in your shoes when I joined
the company a few years ago,
and I know the first
few weeks can be tough.
But don't worry,
I'll be with you every step of the way.
Come, I'll show you your desk.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Thanks for joining me, so
we've been pretty busy lately.
One of the reason we've had so much work
is that we specialize in a certain type
of analytics,
called predictive analytics.
It's all about finding trends and
patterns in existing data to help
make predictions about the future.
Tons of companies are using
predictive analytics to make
better decisions about marketing,
production, finance, really anything.
Check out this recent project we did.
Our client was a manufacturing firm, and
they were losing a bunch of money,
because of unexpected machine failures.
We worked with them to predict
when the machines might fail,
so they could do
the repairs before hand.
They ended up reducing the impact
of machine failure by over 40%.
And now they've hired us
to some more projects.
[SOUND] Come in.
&gt;&gt; Here you go.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, thank you, sir.
&gt;&gt; No problem.
&gt;&gt; Our manager thought this
would be a great project for
you to get started with.
I'm excited to see you
what you'll do with it.
It'll give you a good idea of
the process we go through while working
on projects.
After you turn it in I'll
give you some feedback.
And don't worry about
this project too much.
Think of it as your warm up.
You ready to get started?
[BLANK_AUDIO]