You're probably getting
sick of me saying it but
everything starts with the routes so
we need to add the cart route.
And since we're already here let's
generate the shopping cart service.
Now we can add the navigation link for
the cart in the application template.
I've added some fake cart content for
now so
that we can work on the cart template.
To get access to this data
in the shopping cart.
The shopping cart service needs to
be injected into the cart route.
There we go and now we'll return all
cart content from the model hook.
This get cart function just returns
the contents of the shopping cart's
cart property.
It's simple enough, but
allows us to separate our concerns.
Now that the shopping cart's data is
being passed through the model hook
to the template,
we can loop over that data and
display the brick's color,
size and price.
The store now has a cart page, and
shows us the default content returned
from the shopping cart service.
Now we need to create and
add to cart button for the brick items.
I've added this button that calls and
add to cart function when clicked.
This function will need to know
about which brick is being added so
we need to pass along the color,
size and price.
Let's create this function.
Remember that action functions
go inside an actions object.
To add this data to the cart, we need
to access the shopping cart service.
Now that we have the shopping cart,
we can add this data to it.
The addToCart function gets the cart,
and
then adds an object with
the brick data to it.
Since we can now add items to the cart,
let's clear out this default data.
So the cart page doesn't display
anything since the cart is empty.
But adding an item to the cart causes
it to show up on that cart page.
Perfect.
The last step is to decrease the
quantity when it's added to the cart.
Everything's already set up to handle
when the button is clicked on, so
we just need to tell the warehouse
to put one item on hold.
We're telling the warehouse to reserve
one brick with this color and this size.
This first line gets the current
quantity and decreases it by one.
The bottom line sets the quantity for
this specific brick to
the decreased size.
And with that we're done.
The app handles user interaction and
passes information to different
parts of the app using services.
Great job.