Based on what we described so far,
let's take a look at how a distributed
shared memory system can be designed.
This type of system consists
of a number of nodes,
each with their own physical memory.
Everyone of the nodes may contribute
towards the distributed shared memory
system, only a portion of their physical
memory, or it can contribute all of it.
Let's assume here, that only
a portion of the physical memory,
is contributed towards the DSM service
and can explicitly be addressed.
Whereas the rest of the memory
is used either for caches or
for replication or for some metadata
that's needed for the DSM layer.
The pool of memory regions, the memory
pages that every single one of these
nodes contributes, forms the global
shared memory that's available for
applications running in the system.
Every address in this memory pool
will be uniquely identified based
on the identifier for
the node where it's, residing,
as well of the page frame number of that
particular physical memory location.
The node where our page is located
is typically referred to as
the home node of that page.
Now let's say, we're trying to
solve the most general case
where the system is supposed to support
applications that have multiple reader,
multiple writer requirements.
For that reason, in order for the system
to deliver acceptable performance, and
achieve low latency with which
the memory accesses are performed,
the DSM layer will
incorporate use of caching.
Pages will be cached on the nodes
where they are accessed, and for
a state that's cached, for memory pages
that are stored on these remote nodes.
The home node, or the manager node,
will be responsible for
driving all of the coherence related
operations, so, it will maintain state,
that's necessary to track
the number of readers,
the writers, whatever cache
has been modified, et cetera.
In this way, all of the notes in
the system are responsible for
some portion of the management
operations for that distributed memory.
The information that's
maintained at the home, or
the manager node is similar to the kind
of information that we saw that
the servers have to maintain in
the distributed file system example.
Except that in this situation every
single one of the nodes is responsible
for both providing the service,
the acting as a server for
that particular portion
of the shared memory.
And also being the client with
respect to the other nodes.
So every one of the nodes will
participate in interactions with,
a home node in case they
are locally caching some of
the memory that's stored
at a remote site.
The home node will have to
keep track of states, such as,
what are the pages accessed, who is it
accessed by, whether it's been modified.
We may also choose to incorporate
mechanisms to dynamical enable/disable
caching for.
For a similar motivation, like what
we had in the sprite file system.
What are the pages locked, that's
another useful piece of information.
All this information is
used in enforcing the,
shearing semantics that this
particular DSM system will implement.
One particular page is repeatedly and
even exclusively accessed on
a node that's not its home node.
It would be too expensive to repeatedly
contact the home node to perform any
necessary state updates, so one
mechanism that's useful in DSN systems
is to separate the notion of home node,
from the so-called owner.
The owner is the node that
currently owns the page that's,
like the exclusive writer for instance.
And that's the node that can control
all of these state updates and
can drive any consistency
related operations.
So this owner may be different from
the home node, and in fact the owner may
change, as, whoever is accessing this
page migrates throughout the system or
new processes, new threads require
access to this particular page.
They may become owners as well.
The role of the home node for that page,
in this case, that was node two,
is to keep track of who is
the current owner of that page.
In addition to creating page copies
via caching, in an on demand manner,
page replicas can be explicitly created,
for reasons such as load balancing,
hot spot avoidance, or
reliability reasons so
that the page contents do not disappear
if some note in the system fails.
For instance, in data center
environment that have lots of machines,
where a certain distributed shared
state is managed, it makes sense to
triplicate such shared state on the
original machine, on a nearby machine,
for instance in the same rack, and
then, on another remote machine,
whether it's in another rack or
even potentially in another data center.
The consistency of these replicas is
controlled either by the home node or
by some designated management node.