Things need to be fast when you're
interreading on a website or app.
So if you change a line and
reload the page,
you really want to see
those changes instantly.
And disrupting that flow is a no-go.
So make sure your actual build time
never goes beyond a few seconds.
Build tools are pretty
useless by themselves.
You either need to write a lot of
custom code or rely on plugins.
So make sure to pick one that
has the plugins you need.
Individually contained task allow you
to easily enable and disable certain
steps of your build process, and
they're important prerequisite.
There is no point in saving bytes
when writing server-side code.
The important bit is that you understand
what the configuration of your build
system does,
not how short the notation is.