Where do new directories come from?
You can create new directories using
the M-K-D-I-R or mkdir command.
All you have to give mkdir is a path
to where the new directory should be.
When you make a new
directory with mkdir,
the path you give it can be
a relative or an absolute path.
So you could mkdir notes
to make a directory called notes
inside the current directory.
Or you could make dir/tmp/cache
to make a directory called
cache inside the tmp directory.
Remember, the entire file system
descends from the root directory.
When you make a new directory,
It's created with some existing
directory as it's parent.
So in the examples we just saw,
the working directory is /home/vagrant,
and we mkdir/notes, then the notes
directory's parent is vagrant.
And if we mkdir/tmp/cache, the cache
directory's parent directory is tmp.
Once you've made a directory, you can
move files into that directory with mv,
or copy them with cp
like you've seen before.
And if you're done with a directory, and
want to get rid of it, the command for
that rmdir.
You can't use just plain
rm on a directory.
You have to use rmdir.
But if a directory has files in it,
you can't rmdir that directory.
For instance,
this directory called junk.
If we try to remove it, Linux will
tell us the directory is not empty.
There is a way to recursively remove
a directory and all the files inside,
and we've actually seen
it before in this course.
Which of these commands do you think
will remove the directory junk and
all of its contents?
Rmdir -f junk, curl -o junk empty,
rm -r junk, or mv junk Trash.