Although, virtually,
all companies have firewalls in place,
the number of security breaches
continues to increase.
The reason for this is that a firewall
is not all things to all malware.
There are some security breaches that
cannot be stopped by a firewall.
Let's do a quiz on firewalls.
Look at this list of items, and check
all those items that firewall can stop.
The first one,
hackers breaking into your system.
The second one, Internet traffic that
appears to be from a legitimate source.
The third one, viruses and
worms that spread through the Internet.
The fourth one,
spyware being put on your system.
The fifth one, viruses and
worms that are spread through email.
Check all those items
that a firewall can stop.