So, we're on Team Awesome.
Just came up with that.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So, our project is based on doing sentiment analysis and
displaying that geographically.
So, we're doing it on various components.
One based on emoticons and emojis.
But another one based on the words itself and kind of using
a natural language processing to get, you know, is it positive or negative.
And then, we are also getting URLs associated with,
you know, is it happy or sad.
And, at the end we'll kind of display visually,
the top URLs that were happy or sad.
and, you know, you can click on it and go to it eventually.
And also, we're also having another component of geographical stuff.
So, we have a map of the US and the various cities, and so when you say,
hover over it, you'll see, like, the top tweet that's going there, or-
>> Mm-hm. >> The top words, and, you know, we're color-coding it and
various things, like your happiness ranking.
And then, another one, which we're going to be doing as well,
is based on saying top, you know, things that you want to look at.
For example, Apple, or Google, and things like that.
>> Mm-hm. >> Counting them and the sentiment associated with that.
So, we'll show how that progresses over real time.
>> Okay. So, there seems to be like, multiple projects.
[CROSSTALK]. >> There are multiple projects, but.
>> To follow people in multiple jobs, different jobs in today.
>> well, I know it's like you one spout, right now.
we, I think one spot, right?
And then, we might have various filters, right?
>> Mm-hm.
>> That are all happy happening and trained for it.
And so, we have a bunch of it already comprised of just,
you know, finding the score, output sentiment, you know.
And- >> I think that probably your best way to do is like spilt it
up into multiple even though you might be thinking about sharing the spout.
>> Uh-huh. >> Because.
I use from an, what is your focus point of your having one type of
analytics versus a different type of analytics, right?
>> Mm-hm. >> So, think about, like, just a sentiment on the day you are based on
using emojicons and the happier you are in the words that are in
the tweet which is whether it's happiness or not, right?
>> Yeah. >> So, that itself is a big, to pull you on it's own.
>> Mm-hm. >> But then,
the second one that you mentioned about what is second, the second [CROSSTALK].
>> Brands.
>> Yeah, brand.
The sediments of brands over time.
>> Yep.
>> That is a completely different one,
because the other correlate, some specific brands, right?
>> Yeah. >> so, brands themselves are already input,
because Topology doesn't know about brands, rightt.
>> Mm-hm. >> So then, there are hundreds and thousands of brands.
>> Yeah. >> [INAUDIBLE] to do that, right?
So, when you want to do the brands, like the brands themselves and
the corresponding words.
And, you try to correlate a particular brand world with happiness and
all the various things along with it.
Right? >> Yeah. >> So, maybe it's.
This is a good wall [INAUDIBLE] right?
>> Uh-huh. >> This is a kind of brand where I sent him and
which where he's [INAUDIBLE] all the time.
>> Yup. >> So, that way like what happens is like it keeps the cold isolated.
>> Uh-huh. >> Rather than mixing everything.
Your endurance time does not prevent you from mixing these two in
some fashion because, ultimately it's a [INAUDIBLE] program.
>> Yup. >> But, in terms of complexity and direction of complexity.
And, during part of it, it makes it easier to have [INAUDIBLE] in Java.
>> It says that, that you would say.
>> But, we can build the code.
I mean, like, the spout takes up can be reused and
some other components of computations that whatever,
you can stack them as a library, you can link it into each both separately.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah.