An important question
here is what is risk?
So let's take a look at that in
the context of a particular stock.
So here's how the price
of a particular stock,
let's call it XYZ,
has changed over time.
So over this time period
it's gone up say about 10%.
Here's now another stock that
over the same period of time,
it ends up, it's gone up about
the same amount, also ten percent,
but notice how the volatility
of ABC is much less than XYZ.
And this volatility is
one measure of risk, and
it's the measure of risk typically
used in the finance world.
So consider for example here for XYZ,
we see this large excursion here.
And all along its timeline,
it's been quite volatile.
So that excursion is a measure of risk,
and if we look at it
similarly for ABC,
we see the excursion is much lower.
So the specific metric that finance
folks use for this is that risk is
essentially the standard
deviation of daily returns.
So to calculate risk we would calculate
the daily returns for each one of these
stocks, take its standard deviation,
and that's our measure of risk.
And we can compare that
one stock to another.