Ok, so you saw that the UI button has an
intrinsic size based on the text for the
image that it may contain. That means we
only need two constraints to center this
button on our view. One for the x-coordinate
and one for the y-coordinate. There are
two ways to add these constraints and
I’ll cover both here. With the Record
button selected, click on the aline button,
which is here on the very bottom most
part of the editor and looks like a bar
graph. If you're having trouble selecting
the Record button, you can always use the
document outline. We want to select the
two options on the bottom to center it
horizontally and vertically in the
container. So we'll select them both and
click “Add 2 Constraints”.
Now you can see both Constraints under
the Record button in the document outline.
Make sure to click the
disclosure triangle if you want to see
them exactly. Now if you're like me, you
may have just encountered your first
AutoLayout issue. We see this orange line
here in the editor as well as a warning
at the top of Xcode. This indicates we
have a problem.
Let's fix it first before we run our
application. I forgot to mention, we also
have this yellow arrow here in the
document outline. That's also showing
that we have a problem. If we click it
and I’ll drag out a little bit to give
ourself some more space, We can see what
the problem is. It says that expects the
button to be at a certain x position
with a certain width but it's actually
at a different x position and a width
that it doesn't expect. If we click the
yellow triangle, we can see some
suggestions that Xcode has to fix our
problem. I like the first option that is
recommending to update the frame.
This will fix the size and position of the
button so that matches the constraints
that we've declared. And let's click Fix Misplacement
Cool, let's see if adding
our constraints worked. Press the Run
button or hit command + R to run the simulator.
Great we can see that our
Record button is on the center of the screen.
With the iOS simulator selected,
hold down the command key and press the
right or left arrow key to rotate the simulator.
I’ll go ahead and rotate
it left and then I'll rotate back and
then go right.
You can also go to the Hardware menu and
select Rotate Left or Rotate Right.
In any of the orientations, we see that our
button has stayed in the center. Now let's
try running the app on a different
device like an iPad which has a much
larger screen than iPhone. I’ll stop the
simulator by clicking the Stop button.
And here we can see a list of the devices.
I’m going to select one of the
iPads. And lets hit Run. It may take a
couple of seconds for the simulator to load.
But that's because it has to switch from
the device you were on to the new device.
Once it's launched, we can see our Record button,
but the iPad simulator is too big
to fit on the screen. So what do we do,
we could go out and buy a large Thunderbolt
Display and I actually recommend that, if
you have the cash lying around or maybe
we could petition Johnny I have to bring back
the 17-inch Macbook Pro laptop, either a
decent options. But perhaps there's an
easier solution. With a simulator
selected, go to Window > Size > Scale, and
this gives us the ability to change the
size of the simulator. I’ll select
33-percent. This is pretty tough to see,
so maybe I’ll try something a little bit
bigger.
You can use the hotkeys to change the
size as well. So we have command+1
command+2 command+3. Let's go back
to command+2. This size fits our screen
okay. Now that the iPad is in full screen,
we can see that the Record button is
still in the middle of the iPad. This is
also true if we rotate the iPad to one
of the landscape modes. It looks like our
Constraints are working.