It written out in nice predicate logic we have what's shown here. It says for
all i, okay, so i, sorry for all is the quantifier, i is the index variable.
And we're going to qualify i by saying it's, it's greater than or
equal to 1. And it's less than the length of Y when we put a vector
inside of the vertical lines that's the, the length or cardinality of it.
It must be case so the, the dot that we have here separating the two parts,
you can read it must be the case. We can, use that i to pick out an element
of Y and compare it to the element that Y plus 1 if in fact we have ordered
output it had better be less than or equal to it. Notice that we said less than
the length of Y and that gets us around the problem of trying to index into
a value of the vector into a position of the vector that doesn't exist.