Welcome back.
In the previous lecture, I gave you an idea of what this class is
about in terms of the discipline of computational photography.
In this lecture,
I want to tell you a little about, more about what computational photography is.
We will actually now,
tease apart the whole process of how light is used to generate pictures.
And we will look at each and every aspect of how computation can impact it.
This will kind of create a framework,
a foundation of what we now will leverage throughout the entire term.
To understand computational photography at it's core.
So we will actually look at different aspects and
frameworks associated with what makes computational photography a discipline.
And we will actually keep on looking at it throughout the whole term.
I look forward to working with you on it.