I'll start off by creating
an empty dictionary.
Then, I'll loop through
the enrollments and
notice here that I'm using the new
enrollments variable I created,
which doesn't include
the audacity test accounts.
I want to add the student to the
dictionary if they haven't cancelled yet
or if it was at least seven
days before they did cancel.
Then I'll pull out the account,
cancel the enrollment date and
save those in variables.
And I'll add those to the dictionary
with the account_key as the key and
the enrollment_date as the value.
Then I'll use the line function to
see how many students this is and
it comes out to 995.
Now this works, but there's
something a little strange about it.
Earlier we saw that the same student
can enroll multiple times and
if that happens,
then I'm just going to be saving an
arbitrary one of those enrollment dates.
Instead, I think it makes sense to save
their most recent enrollment date in
that case.
To accomplish that, I'll add another
check and I'll only add the enrollment
date to the dictionary if either the
account key was not already present, or
if this enrollment date is more recent
than the date that's already present.
And I'll rerun the cell.
Of course, that shouldn't change
the number of paid students,
it just changed what enrollment date
was saved for certain students.