Yes, nearby pixels
tend to move together.
This is because an object
seen moving in a certain way
occupies more than a few pixels.
Well, otherwise it would be hard to see.
This can be thought of
as a local constraint.
And we'll see more of this later.
Saying that motion must be
consistent over an entire image
is a pretty bold claim, but
it is still fairly valid and
useful, especially when
used as a soft constraint.
This means you're not saying that motion
across the image has to be identical,
it's just that solutions
to the optical flow problem
that generate consistent
motion are preferable.
As you might have guessed,
this is a global constraint.
Remember that our goal is to
compute optical flow at each pixel.
That is dense flow.
Now if we consider
only distinct regions,
then how are we going to do that?
Well, at distinct regions like corners,
the ambiguity of flow
direction is small.
If we compute optical
flow at these regions,
we could interpolate
the flow between them.
So yes,
this is a useful approach as well,
although it might result
in approximate flow.
Anything else you have in mind?
Don't agree with these constraints?
You know where to discuss.