Let's go ahead and double click on
the clock handle seconds controller file
which will open up the animator window.
This window houses all
the information pertaining to
animating our clock second hand.
As you can see the two animations we
already created already exist here and
are represented by boxes.
In addition to these boxes we also
have a box called entry in any state.
If we drag over by pressing Alt and
left clicking,
we'll find another box called exit.
All these boxes are called
states which are all part
of a gigantic state machine.
A state machine is a system that
connects multiple states together
via transitions.
At any given point our clock hand
can only be in one state and
that state represents what animation
our clock hand is currently doing.
The states entry and
exit are special states for
when our state machine starts up and
ends.
The any state is a special state that
represents all animation states.
It will make a bit more
sense when we talk about
how to transition between states.
In order to move to a different state,
we need to define a transition.
To do that, right-click on a state that
we want to make a transition from and
click Make transition.
Once we do that,
an arrow will began to follow our mouse
until we click on a state
we want to transition too.
Let's strike to the reverse
seconds rotations state.
To make this a bit more readable,
let's move our states around just
by clicking and dragging them.
Let's also create another
transition between reverse seconds
rotation and exit.
If we now switch over to scene view and
hit play, we'll see that our clock
hand is now swinging back and forth.
Now surprisingly, the hand doesn't
do a full rotation back and forth.
And this is because unity is actually
interpolating the transition
instead of completing
the full transition.
If you want to resolve this issue
check out the extra reading for
more information on how to solve it.
But since we're going to be able to
dynamically control when we transition
in upcoming videos this
problem will disappear.