So, so real time analytic's.
Again real time analytic's can be broadly divided into two different segments.
And the first one is what you call as real time streaming.
And in streaming what you do is you do
analytic's immediately after data is produced.
So the moment where data is produced, it goes through some kind of
real-time pipeline and it's constantly spitting out analytic's.
And one of the characteristics of streaming is the analytics is
running continuously on and on for days and months, keeps on running.
The second broad real-time analytic's is what we call as interactive.
And so in this case, what happens is like the analytics is the data,
whatever data is stored in some kind of persistent storage,
later it might be in the disks, or flash, or whatever might be the case, and
whenever you like to look at some kind of analytic's on top of this data.
You kind of come up with a query or I do a job, whatever it is.
Then moment you find the job, and it should return it in a few seconds or
even in milliseconds.
So the whole idea is like you are exploring the data, then you
discover something, then immediately you wanted to drill down farther into that.
So that it's kind of funny.
It gives you a more often interactive session.
And in order to be interactive, you don't want to be like, I type a query,
go and have a coffee, and chat with my friends, and
come back, and the analytic's is ready.
Because that cycle is too long.
So in a manner of seconds and
milliseconds, if it comes back, then you need it more productive.
So the focus of the, the whole Udacity code says with respect to streaming.
Because the storm is essentially a tool,
to get your streaming analytics down as quickly as possible.
That is a border.
So now what is real time?
I mean in different domains and different markets and
different enterprises, real time means different things for different people.
So loosely, like, we define, real time in certain ways.
But before we get to what exactly it is, let us see the spectrum of,
what are the various type of, what do you call?
The time duration.
So the first is, what we call is a [INAUDIBLE] systems so
[INAUDIBLE] systems tend to have, kind of defined millisecond budget.
And, that is probably the fastest, kind of analytics that you can think of.
And it is very latency-sensitive.
In the sense, like, whenever a, let's say you go to an ATM and
say I'm withdrawing some money, and immediately the account has to be updated.
Similarly, like whenever a tweet is what do you call,
posted by you, like then you might have a lot of followers.
And those followers have to get the tweet right away.
Within a budget of 500 milliseconds.
So think about doing that kind of, what do you call, fall-out.
That's what we call the term.
The fall-out for 30 million users.
For example, in the case of Obama having 30, or 33, or 35 million users.
How do you replicate that tweet, whatever he does for
all his followers in within 500 milliseconds.
So on the other end of the spectrum is like the batch which takes a lot of
hours and days and that is a characteristic by high throughput,
because the reason why the batch takes long amount of
time is because of in the sense like you're munging through so much data.
And you've there's a lot of data than the disk class is
limitation of 100 megabytes per second.
You can more, go more than that so, so in order to what would combat limitation?
We'll employ multiple disks, so that you can get some,
there some simultaneously across each disk.
Seen parallel.
So, when you employ a lot of such disk and
the data is much higher than that it takes hours and
days and hence is very important for this kind of anal, batch analytic's.
And mostly the batch analytic's is used for doing idol queries.
And in between the two.
It's what we call loosely a real time.
I mean, in the sense like, it's like, a few seconds.
And one of the characteristics of the real time is
what you call this approximation.
So the real time may not be very exact.
I mean, there could be requirements where it could be exact, but
from a strong definition point of view or from intuitive notion point of view.
Real time is more an approximation.
So, so that it gives the visibility into your business right away,
or, or that you are monitoring for real time analytics right away.
And still, it gives you some kind of a approximate AD.
And so, one of the I mean.
Downsides of the approximation is how close are you to exact?
So there should be some kind of, bounds to, the actual real value, right?
So as long as the, the approximation is like 5 to 10 percent off from the,
actual values, then you're okay.
So, so then what we also do at Twitter is, like, we do run a batch analytics.
But that is, comes a little bit like four or five hours later.
On fixes this approximations of real time as real time keeps forging ahead.
So, so
that is where we kind of what do you call this a more of real time [INAUDIBLE].
[INAUDIBLE] is a few seconds.
Now why we do Real Time,
we should be care that we, things should be in real time.
And world is going, going real time.
And of course tutor is synonymous with real time and
that there's a bunch of examples.
First there's real time trends.
Of course, Twitter is known for break, break out news stories.
Break, break our incidents.
And that spreads like fire in real time.
So, so to be able to be on top of.
Real time clients.
Second aspect is real time conversations.
As you're watching a sports game, and
surf some either somebody scored or something that they did and
people, you want to instantly start a conversation, Twitter is one the places
where people start a conversation and millions of conversations keep going.
At any given time.
And third aspect is real time recommendations.
As these real time trends and conversations are emerging.
To the ones who take advantage of those,
by injecting the appropriate product recommendation during the time.
So that people can do some kind of impulsive buying.
Or even add, so that you can click on those ads,
which translates into bottom line for us.
So then finally, like, Real Time search, where, as, new events and
Real Time incidents and trends are happening and
you wanted to search it because, in your, in the context of [INAUDIBLE]
you will be getting those incidents with respect to whomever you are following.
But the search that I put in allows you to search for all the tweet.
So in other words as these tweets are coming in,
we have to continuously mix them so that when you go to it is Real Time.
In the sense like all the tweets that happen in the last second or
last few second is immediately available to you.
As part of the search.
So we have a budget of less than 200 milliseconds in order to do that.
So some kind of discussion.
Louie you want to?
Louis you want to [INAUDIBLE] some discussion about.
>> Sure. >> The big data applications.
>> Sure so this is just a question for the group.
You know, what?
What are some the examples of Real Time systems that you've seen?
Real Time alo,.
Applications, and maybe ideas that you want to see.