If you run the game for long enough,
you'll notice it start to slow way down.
That's because we never get rid of
the icicles that the player has
already dodged.
They just keep falling away
below the bottom of the screen.
Let's add some logic to remove icicles
as soon as they're no longer visible.
With a simple change, we can make sure
that the game keeps running at a silky
smooth 60 frames per second.
No matter how long we let it run.
The trick to removing the stale icicles
is that we want to remove elements from
an array while we're iterating over it.
Thankfully, libGDX provides
the incredibly convenient
DelayedRemovalArray.
Check out the to-dos in
the course code to get started.