The answer is in
the CreateAccountActivity class.
Specifically, I'm going to scroll down,
so
here in the onCreatAccountPressed
method, you call createUser, which
creates the user in what I'm calling
the Firebase credentials data store.
And then, if it's successful,
it'll call onSuccess.
And then, this location is where you
should create your own user POJO,
which would contain all that
extra app specific data,
and then you can put that POJO
in the Firebase database.
Okay, so to reiterate,
you should be doing two things.
First, making a user POJO, and
second, adding the code here
to then effectively create the user
in your Firebase database.
I'll send over the spec right now.