I don't know about you, but
I'm going to go with system A.
I started with the definition
of average power for
the two systems,
which is just energy divided by time.
Then, I recognize that this inequality
on time can be written a little
bit differently.
Namely, 1 over the time of A is
less than 1 over the time of B.
If you now compare these two relations
to the definitions of power,
you should see that the power of
A has to be less than the power of B.
You can see the same thing in
the energy time phase plot.
Power is energy over time, and
energy over time in the plot
corresponds to the slope of the lines.
And since the slope of B is
steeper than the slope of A,
then it must use more power.