Now the loftiest desire would be to predict the precise time of day.
And so, we would consider using time of day as the quantity.
Now I said the loftiest desire,
because this would actually be the most difficult form of prediction.
This means we could produce any time of day in the future at all and ask,
when is the next time the person is going to tweet, relative to that time?
For example, at eight in the morning, I could ask, at 3 p.m.
later today, when is he going to tweet soonest after that time?
Now alternatively, we could think of the phenomenon of
tweeting as a process that starts over after each tweet.
In that case, a more appropriate quantity to think about might be the amount of
time since the last tweet.
Let's make the hypothesis that this is the right way to
think about the phenomenon.
How long until you tweet next, and how it is influenced by any other factors.
Let's call this quantity the inter-tweet time.