So here we start our little mathematical foray down into making it
from geometry to algebra.
So I just wrote what we had before.
The X prime, the position or location of X in the prime frame can
just be expressed just having rotated the X frame by the R amount and
then translating it by T.
All right?
Great.
Let's just cross both sides of that equation by T.
So we have T cross X prime on the left, but on the right, we have T cross and
it's just, because of distributive property it's T cross RX plus T cross T.
All right?
And by the way, I, I wrote here that this is normal to the plane.
Remember that T cross X prime is going to be something that's perpendicular to
both of them, so
that would be perpendicular to the epipolar plane that, that we're showing here.
We'll, we'll maybe make use of that in a minute, but
I just want you to realize that.
More importantly, what you should see is that we've got T cross T here.
What's T cross T?
Not very much.
Otherwise, known as zero.
Okay?
So that just means that T cross X prime is equal to T cross RX, got it?
Okay.
Now let's take both sides of that equation and I'm going to dot it with X prime.
So we got X prime dot T cross X prime equals X prime dot T cross RX.
I sure hope you're reading this, because listening to me sounds ridiculous.
Okay?
Well, let's take a look at this left-hand side.
T cross X prime gives us what?
Well, it gives us a vector that's perpendicular to the plane containing T and
X prime.
So it's perpendicular to T and it's perpendicular to X prime.
And then I dotted it with X prime, so what am I going to get?
Zero, right?
because it's perpendicular and if everything goes well, there it is in yellow.
Zero is equal to X prime dot T times RX.
Okay?
So far so good?
Good.