Here are two important differences.
One difference is scale.
When you're doing software design, iit's probably because you
are dealing with a big problem that's going to have a big solution.
If you're doing programming, you're more likely concerned with programs that
are going to end up being 100 or 1,000, or maybe even 10,000 lines.
The International Space Station has 30 million lines of code.
Another key difference between programming and
design, software design, is the role that non-functional requirements play.
For programs, you may at a, occasionally be concerned with performance but
by and large, non-functional requirements don't play a big role.
With software design, the whole story is how you
are going to deal with trade-offs among non-functional requirements.