So what does a process look like?
A process encapsulates all of this data for running application.
This includes the code, the data,
all of the variables that that application needs to allocate.
Every single element of the process state has to be uniquely identified by
its address.
So an OS abstraction used to encapsulate all of
the process state is an address space.
This is what we have here.
The address space is defined by a range of addresses from V0
to some Vmax, and different types of
process state will appear in different regions in this address space.
What are the different types of state in a process?
First we have the code,
the text, and the data that is available when the process is first initialized.
So all of this is static state that's available when the process first loads.
Then during the execution, the process dynamically creates some state,
allocates memory, stores them per our results, reads data from files.
This part of the address space we call a heap.
In this picture here, the heap is shown as contiguous portion of
the address space starting immediately after the data, but
in reality there may be holes in this space.
It may not be contiguous.
There may be portions of it that don't have any meaning for that
particular process and, in fact, the process isn't even allowed to access them.
I will talk in a little bit how the operating system knows what's okay for
the process to access versus what isn't.
Another very important part of the address space is what we call a stack.
It's a dynamic part of the address space state, in that it grows and
shrinks during execution, but it does so in a last-in, first-out order.
Whatever you put on the stack will be the very first item to be
returned when you're trying to read from the stack.
Consider for instance we're executing a particular portion of the process.
And now we need to call some procedure to jump to a different part of
the address space.
We want to make sure that the state that we were in at this point of
the execution, before we called this other procedure, is saved, and
then that it will be restored once we come back from the execution.
We can place the state on the stack and
jump to execute this portion of the code.
So the procedure y.
When we're finished with y,
the state x will be popped from the stack and we can continue the execution in
the same state that we were in before the call to y was made.
There are lots of points during a process execution where the last-in,
first-out behavior is very useful.
So the stack is a very useful data structure.