Okay, and now that we've tested our
application, we're going to create
a project on Google App Engine so
that we can deploy our application and
share that URL with our friends,
family and anyone else.
I'm back in the tutorial page.
I'm going to scroll up and click on
step nine, Uploading Your Application.
It's on the left-hand side
of the screen right here.
Okay, now we are going to
follow the instructions to
upload our application and
deploy it live.
First, it says we need to sign in to
App Engine using your Google account or
if you don't have one,
create a Google account now.
Let's go ahead and click on the Visit
the Google Developers console link.
And that'll take us to the sign in page.
I'm going to input my password.
Then I'm going to click sign in,
and there we are.
I'm on my app engine page and
I haven't created a project yet.
So let's get started.
Let's click on Create Project.
Now it gives us a couple options,
first is the project name and
second is the project ID.
The project ID is going to be
a unique ID across all of Google.
No one else can use that same ID.
Think of it as a username for
any site you're going to use.
It needs to be unique.
Your project name, on the other hand,
is something just personal to you,
whatever you want to call it.
Since this is our first
google App Engine project,
I'm going to call mine First Project.
Now we can select a project ID here.
You can put anything you like but
Google will auto-generate one for you.
I'm just going to use the one they
gave us, clean-utility-88718.
And I'll go ahead and
create this project.
Okay, now that we've created our
project we're going to go ahead and
highlight our project ID and copy it.
I'm going to hit Ctrl+C, Cmd+C for
all you Mac users out there, and
then I am going to
switch back to Sublime.
Okay, I am back in Sublime now,
before we didn't have any application ID
inputted, but
we were still able to run it locally.
If you want to deploy your application,
run it online and
share that link with someone else,
you're going to need to input your
application ID you just
created with your project.
I'm going to highlight your-app-id.
And then I'm going to paste in
the application ID we just copied.
To do that on Windows, I'm going to
hit Ctrl+V, on Mac, it's Cmd+V.
Okay, now let's go ahead and save.
Great!
Now we are ready to deploy our
application.