So, eventually, we want to take
user info from the editor and
save that often to the database.
But first, let's just start
off with some baby steps.
Now, remember we've always encouraged
you to plan your work ahead of time
when adding any complex feature.
And this is to help you focus
on small winds along the way,
it can help you verify if
you're on the right track.
So, on our case,
let's focus on these two steps.
So first, getting pet attributes
from the user input fields and
then inserting a new pet with those
attributes into the database.
So once the user enters pet data
into these fields, we first need to
read the data from these fields and
then sort them off into variables.
Second, we need to save these values
into the database as a new pet.
So first,
let's actually focus on just the part
of inserting the pet into the database.
And that means for now,
let's not worry about this part
of reading the attributes
from the user input fields.
So, one easy way we can insert
a new pet without worrying about
the editor just yet, is to use
our Insert Dummy Data menu item
in the overflow menu of
our catalog activity.
So the Overflow menu also known
as the Options menu in Android
is characterized by these three dots
that you can see here up in that bar.
And so clicking on it reveals
a list of our menu options.
Now to clarify,
earlier when I said Dummy Data
what I meant is fake data
that we can use for practice.
So, similar to how a crashed dummy is
used for testing car safety, we can
insert fake pet data into our database
to help us test our apps functionality.
So, we've already added this menu item
into the version that pets app that we
provided for you.
But currently, clicking on it
doesn't do anything just yet.
You can notice there's no
action listed below this case.
So since we haven't formally
discussed menu options before,
let me show you a code that
makes this actually work.
Just like we use XML to declare layouts,
strings and
style resources, we can also
use it to declare menu layouts.
So here under Res, under Menu we've
defined a menu catalog XML file.
So let's open that up.
So inside this file
using the menu XML tag,
we declare a menu with two menu items.
Notice there are specific XML
attributes that we use for
menu items such as ID,
Title and Show As Action.
And this one here shows action,
determines whether this item should be
shown as an icon in the app bar or
in the Overflow menu.
So the Overflow menu is those three
vertical dots on the right
hand side of the app bar.
So here we have
Show As Action set as never.
This means that this menu item will
always be shown in the Overflow menu.
Great, so now that we've
defined our menu resource file,
how do we connect it to
the Catalog Activity.
Well, in the Catalog Activity file we
can actually override specific methods
that were originally defined in
the Activity super class, so
our AppCompatActivity class here.
And those methods are these down here.
So first,
by overriding onCreateOptionsMenu,
we can inflate a menu resource
by referring to its resource id.
So, in this case the resource
id is R.menu.menu_catalog
where this tag here was the name
of our menu in the XML file.
So, we can see this name over here.
So, this method on Create Options
menu will be caught automatically by
the system when the catalog
activity is first being created and
will display these menu
items in the Options menu.
Now in order to add behavior
to each of these menu items,
we'll need to override this method here,
on options item selected.
So this method will be called by
the system when an Options menu item
is clicked on.
So determine which item is clicked on.
We can take a look at the input
which is this parameter here.
So item of type menu item.
We can check the item ID and
then create a switch statement
that handles the different cases for
the different menu items.
So in the case that the user clicks
on the insert Dummy Data Menu item so
this one here, it's going to
fall to this specific case.
And this is because this case
ID matches this ID here.
So back in the onItemSelected method,
note that this case statement
currently is blank.
So even though the user clicks on
it no action is set to happen.
So I want to modify the code
to call an insert pet method
which I'll need to create later on.
So first let me just type
the name of the method.
So delete this comment here and
type in insert pet.
So this is calling a method
that I haven't created yet.
So right now it's throwing
an error because I haven't even
defined this method.
So let's go ahead and do that up here.
So I'm going to set it as a private
method, with no return value and
the name will be insertPet.
So it's going to take no inputs,
and there we go.
So Android Studio is okay
with this blank method here.
All right, so armed with that knowledge,
now it's your job to insert some dummy
data by adding the insertPet method.
Now remember I want you to do it
proper way using content values.
So for the following exercise, I like
you to insert this example of content
values into the database when
the user hits insert dummy data.
Now when using insert data
with the SQLite insert method
take note of what
the insert method returns.
So normally it says here that it returns
the ID of the row that was inserted.
But if there was an error notice
that no row is inserted and
instead the value
negative 1 is returned.
So if you do this correctly
two things should happen.
One, you should find that
whenever you go to the menu and
select the Insert Dummy Data option
the row count on the main screen,
or our catalog activity, increments
because you've inserted a new pet.
So notice here, it increases from 0,
hit Insert Dummy Data,
and then increases to 1.
And if I were to hit it again, the row
count increased to 2, and so and so on.
And the second thing you should
notice is that you should find
all these dummy pets in
the downloaded database.
So I recommend to you checking
out this code snippet
found with a tutorial that
I've linked down below.
And that tutorial is from our
Android documentation site of how to
insert a row into the database.
So again,
here's a summary of what I'd like you
to do in this following exercise.
First, modify the app so clicking on
the Insert Dummy Data menu option.
First, Inserts this pet Toto
with all his information here
as well as updates the TextView on our
catalog activities screen with the row
count of the database and thus so
using our display database info method.
Remember to check out the instructor
notes down below if you need some help