The last thing that we need to think
about is how to draw this actual circle.
We'll need to define a radius for
the circle.
In the Gapminder visualization,
the area of each circle corresponds, or
is proportional to the population.
Now, before we dive into
drawing the circle,
let's talk about what can go wrong when
you draw circles in the first place.
Vox published an article about
charity donations and fatal diseases.
The article discussed
the hype around donations and
the ALS Ice Bucket Challenge.
This is the visualization that
was posted in the article.
However, this graphic was not
the one that was released
when the article was
originally published.
The original graphic looked like this.
Notice that the circles for the largest
values of the money raised and
deaths are huge, while the circles
corresponding to the smaller values of
money raised and
deaths are nearly tiny specks.
The data values were exaggerated
in this first graphic.
By using the data values as
the radius of the circle,
the author visually showed the squared
amount of the original data value.
Here's a better look at the original
graphic and the remake.
Notice that in the original graphic,
again, the circles we're created
by squaring the radius,
which was the data value itself.
In the remake graphic,
the square root of the radius
was used to create the circles.
Notice how these circles are in
a better proportion than these circles.
Whenever data appears to be exaggerated,
whether intentional or
not, you lose trust with your audience.
You want to avoid this type of mistake,
so
that way, any claims that
you make about the data or
any action steps to take because
of the data can remain credible.