one of things that goes wrong when you
try to actually run gradient descent on
a complex network with a lot of data is
that you can get stuck in these local
minima and then you start to wonder boy
is there some other way that I can
optimize these weights i'm trying to
find a set of weights for the neural
network that well that what that that
tries to minimize error on the training
set and so gradient descent is one way
to do it and it can get stuck but
there's other kinds of advanced
optimization methods have become very
appropriate here in fact there's a lot
of people in machine learning who think
of optimization and learning is kind of
being the same thing that what you're
really trying to do in any kind of
learning problem is solved this this
high-order very difficult optimization
problem to figure out what the learned
representation needs to be so i just
want to mention in passing so various
kinds of advanced methods that that
people brought to bear there's things
like mom using momentum terms in the
gradient which basically where the idea
in the momentum is as we're doing
gradient descents imagine this is our
error surface we don't want to get stuck
in this little Bowl here we want to kind
of pass all the way through to get to
this bowl so maybe we need to just you
know continue in the direction we've
been going so instead of you know think
of it as a kind of physical analogy
instead of just just going to the bottom
of this hill and getting stuck it can
kind of bounced out and pop over and
come to what might be a lower minima
later there's a lot of work in using
higher order derivatives to to better
optimize things instead of just thinking
about the way that individual weights
change the error function to look at
combinations of weights Hamiltonians and
whatnot there's various ideas from
randomized optimization which were going
to get to in a sister course that can be
applied to two to make things more
robust and sometimes it's worth thinking
you know what we don't really want to
just minimize the error on the training
set we may actually want to have some
kind of penalty for using using a
structure that's too complex missed when
do we when do we see something like this
before Charles when we were doing
regression and we were talking about
overfitting what's a more or less
complex network
well there's two things you can do with
network you can add more and more nodes
and you can add more and more layers
good so right so if we do
more nodes that we put into network the
more complicated the mapping becomes
from input to output the more local
minimum we get the more we get they have
the ability to actually model the noise
which brings up exactly the same
overfitting issues it turns out there's
another one that's actually really
interesting in the neural net setting
which I think didn't occur to people in
the early days but it became clear and
clear over time which is that you can
also have a complex network just because
the numbers the weights are very large
so same number of weight same number of
nodes same number of layers but larger
numbers often leads to more complex
network and the possibility of
overfitting and so sometimes we want to
penalize the network not just by giving
it $PERCENT fewer nodes or layers but
also by keeping the numbers in a
reasonable range set that makes sense
that makes perfect sense