Okay, here's my solution.
I suggest that you check whether
a partner is less than P, and
you only post the receive
if that's true.
So if partner is less than P,
you'll post the receive, and
you'll continue on.
If partner is not less than P,
then you just won't do anything, but
you'll keep executing the while loop.
Now if you go back and you look at the
animation, you'll see that in fact there
was an oddball processor who kind
of stuck around until the very end.
And I claim this patch will
give you that behavior.
Let me put it a little differently.
Start by considering
the following two facts.
First, only senders drop out.
Second, senders always have a 1
at the current bitmask position.
Let's think about that.
Suppose the current
bitmask looks like this.
So it's 0 everywhere except
1 in the current position.
The two facts imply the following.
Any process that's still participating,
meaning it hasn't dropped out yet,
must have a bit string
that looks like this.
In particular, All the least
significant bits will be 0.
P xs are don't care bits.
Here's another handy fact.
A sender must have a 1 in
the bitmask position, so
its bitstring is
going to look like this.
Its partner will have a flipped bit, so
the matching receive bitstring
will look like this.
This means that the sender's rank is
always greater than the receiver's rank.
And, of course, to be a valid sender,
the rank has to be less than P.
So a sender's rank is less than P.
And a receiver's rank is
less than the senders rank,
which in turn will be less than P.
So a candidate receiver who's
partner has a rank greater than P
can't be valid.