Looking at the diagram, both T2 and
T4 have attempted to get the lock before it was released.
So, their requests will definitely be in the queue that's associated with
the mutex, the queue of pending requests.
Any one of these two requests could be one of the requests that can get to
execute first.
The specification of the mutex doesn't make any
guarantees regarding the ordering of the lock operations.
So, it doesn't really matter that the thread 4 issued the lock operation,
the lock request before T2.
We don't have a guarantee that these requests will be granted in order.
But, regardless, since both T2s and T4s requests are pending on the mutex,
then either one of these two threads will be viable candidates of who gets to
execute next after T1 releases control.
Thread T3 is definitely not a likely candidate, since it doesn't get to
issue the lock operation until after T1 released it and
their already pending requests.
So it's not going to be one of the next threads to execute.
For T5 it's a little tricky.
From the diagram we see that the lock is released just as T5
is starting to perform the lock operation.
So, what can happen is T1 releases the lock and
then we see that both T2 and T4 are actually pending on it.
But just before we give the lock to one of these two threads, on another CPU,
say T5 arrives, makes a lock request.
The lock is still free at that particular time,
and so T5 is the one that actually gets the lock.
So, it is the one that gets to execute next.
So, either one of these T2, T4, or T5 is a viable candidate of
which one of the threads is going to get to execute after T1 releases the lock.