As we said, pages are the more
popular method for memory management.
Now, let's take a look at one of the
major components that enables page based
memory management, and
that's page tables.
As the component that's used to
translate the virtual memory addresses
into physical memory addresses.
So, here's a page table.
For each virtual address, and entry in
the page table is used to determine
the actual physical location that
corresponds to that virtual address.
So in this way, the page table is like a
map that tells the operating system and
the hardware itself where to find
specific virtual memory references.
All of the sizes in this
drawing are a little bit off.
The sizes of the pages of
the virtual memor,y and
the corresponding page frames in
physical memory are identical.
By keeping the size of these
two the same, we don't have to
keep track of the translation of every
single individual virtual address.
Instead, we can only translate
the first virtual address in a page
to the first virtual address in
a page frame in physical memory.
And then the remaining addresses
in the virtual memory page
will map to the corresponding offsets
in the physical memory page frame.
As a result,
we can reduce the number of entries we
have to maintain in the page table.
What that means is that only the first
portion of the virtual address
is used to index into the page table.
We call this part of the virtual
address the virtual page number, and
the rest of the virtual
address is the actual offset.
The virtual page number is used
as an offset into the page table.
And that will produce
the physical frame number.
And that is the physical address
off the physical frame in DRAM.
Now, to complete the full
translation of the virtual address.
That physical frame number needs to be
sent with the offset that's specified in
the later part of the physical address
to produce the actual virtual address.
That resulting physical
address can ultimately be
used to reference the appropriate
location in physical memory.
Let's look at an example now.
Let's say we want to access some data
structure, some array, for instance,
to initialize it for
the very first time.
However, we have already allocated the
memory for that array into the virtual
address space of the process,
we've just never accessed it before.
So since this portion of the address
base has not been accessed before,
the OS has not yet
allocated memory for it.
What will happen the first
time we access this memory is
that the operating system
will realize that there isn't
physical memory that corresponds to
this range of virtual memory addresses.
So it will take a page
of physical memory,
P2 in this case,
a page that is free, obviously.
And it will establish a mapping between
this virtual address, so this is the V-K
and the offset address, where
the array is placed in virtual memory,
and the physical address of
page 2 in physical memory.
Note that I said,
that the physical memory for
this array is only
allocated when the process
is first trying to access it,
during this initialization routine.
We refer to this as
allocation on first touch.
The reason for this is that we want
to make sure that physical memory is
allocated only when it is really needed,
because sometimes programmer may
create data structures that
they don't really use.
If a process hasn't used some of
its memory pages for a long time,
and it's likely that those
pages will be reclaimed.
So the contents will no longer
be present in physical memory.
They will be reclaimed,
they will be pushed on desks and
probably some other content will find
its way into the physical memory.
In order to detect this,
page table entries don't just consist
of the physical frame number.
Instead they also have a number of
bits that tell the memory management
system something about
the validity of the access.
For instance, if the page is in
memory and the mapping is valid,
then this bit is one.
If the page is not in memory then this
bit is zero, and if the hardware MMU
see's that this is a bit zero in the
page table entry it will raise a fault.
It will trap to the operating system.
If the hardware determines that
the mapping is invalid and
false, then control gets passed
to the operating system.
The OS at that point gets to
decide a number of questions.
Should the access be permitted.
Where exactly is the page located.
Where should it be brought into DRAM.
So long as a valid address
is being accessed.
Ultimately in fault, there will be
a mapping that will be re-established
between a valid virtual address and
the valid location in physical memory.
It is likely however,
if the page was pushed in disk and
now it's being brought back into memory,
that it will be placed in a completely
different memory location.
So for instance, here.
This page is now placed in P3,
and it use to be in P2, as
a result clearly the entry in the page
table needs to be correctly updated.
So as a final note to summarize,
the operating system creates a page
table for every process that it runs.
As a summary, the operating system
will maintain a page table on
every single process that exists.
That means that whenever
a context switch is performed,
the operating system has to make
sure that it switches to the page
table of the newly
context switch process.
We said that hardware assist
with page table accesses by
maintaining a register that
points to the active page table.
On X86 Platforms there's a register CR3.
And so basically, on a context which
we will have to change the contents of
the CR3 register with the address
of the new page table.