Now for a little more terminology.
We'd say that a valid sentence is one
that is true in every possible model for
every combination of values
of the propositional symbols.
And a unsatisfiable sentence is
one that is true in some model but
not necessarily in all the models.
So what I want you to do,
is tell me for each of these sentences,
whether it is valid, satisfiable but
not valid, or unsatisfiable.
In other words, false for all models.
And sentences are P or not P, P and
not P, P or Q or P is equivalent to Q.
P implies Q or Q implies P.
And finally, food implies party or
drinks implies party.
Implies food and drinks implies party.