Now we're going to talk a little
bit about these terms in detail.
And I'm going to start with the process
of the pipeline known as continuous
integration.
Generally, this includes the code and
test portions of the pipeline.
And those could be expanded to
look a little bit more like this.
So, usually when you're in
an organization different teams or
people may work on separate
functionality of an application.
But there always comes some time when
all these separate functionalities
actually need to be combined
just to form a release.
And this is important because you
need to combine all of this code
to ensure that the product
works as intended.
So these changes from
different developers or
teams are merged together
in one code base.
And the application is built and
the tests are run to ensure
that it actually works.
And this process is called integration.
Now, before continuous integration
came about, developers might code for
long periods of time on their local
machines without checking work into
the code base.
Then, when it came time to integrate,
the integration process
would be unpredictably long.
And that's because they'd be
committing a huge amount of code.
And because combining two huge
code commits is difficult
this would cause all sorts of problems.
Think of issues with interfaces
connecting well, implementations that
don't quite work together,
conflicting components and more.
So what people eventually figured out
is that the more changes that there
are the harder it is to integrate them.
Now on the other hand if you make
small changes and then when you merge,
you find some sort of error,
this is a pretty easy fix.
So teams start to move
away from yearly or
monthly end of project
integration cycles.
So instead, they went for approaches
like nightly bills that are triggered
and run at night after all
the developers have gone home.
And with this approach it's a lot
easier to figure out when and
where a problem occurred.
But there's still chance that when
developers came in the next morning.
They'd find the build had broken and
they need to spend a few
hours digging through a bunch of commits
to figure out who broke the build and
who could fix it.
The logical next step
was to run the build and
test every time the code is checked in.
And this ensures that problems will
be caught and fixed right away.
So to summarize, continuous integration
is a practice of rigid code change in
a shared code base frequently,
often several times a day.
And then performing an automated
build and test process.
Also continuous integration ensures
that changes from different developers
are integrated often and that the
software is always in a working state.