by the late Ott's the internet had made
it easier to generate and collect images
storage costs had dropped so that was
cheap to save large collections of
images and services like amazon's
mechanical turk had even made it more
cost effective to label images that
confluence of factors gave rise to
imagenet a huge database of hand labeled
images and the image net database gave
rise to the image net large-scale visual
recognition competition the image not
large-scale visual recognition
competition is most famous as an annual
competition where teams from industry
and academia try to build the best
networks for object detection and
localization kind of like this image is
this a dog or a horse it's a horse
anyway this bird really intense
competition between teams and industry
and academia to produce the best image
classification network and as these
teams published their approaches we
learned a lot about the best ways to
build neural networks the first big
breakthrough was in 2012 when the
winning submission really changed the
field it was called Alex net and it
looked a lot like you on the Coons
neural network from way back in nineteen
ninety-eight