All right you're done.
I'll show you what I did.
As I said before,
we're going to change our base app
theme into a no action bar them.
In styles.xml.
Next we added a toolbar style.
Again we're doing this just so we can
set our background color consistently
and also set this pop-up theme.
We then reference this in our app theme.
In activity_main we created a new
linear layout for our new tool bar.
So we could sit it next to
the fragment that was already there.
It was a little easier in our tablet
version of our main activity.
And again we added a linear layout
here as well to add our toolbar
in our activity detail.
Finally, we had to register
it as our action bar.
So once we have set our ContentView,
we find the Toolbar by id, and
call setSupportActionBar
on our AppCompatActivity.
Then we can get the action bar
with full action bar methods, and
call setDisplayHomeAsUpEnabled
equals true.
For a detail activity.
We do something similar
in the main activity,
except that we call
setDisplayShowTitleEnabled equals false.
And that's it.
And there you are with
our exciting new look.
Well, as you can see it looks
exactly as it did before,
except now we're using toolbars.
We'll take advantage of this later on.