I think probability
problem is a very good way to see how
a person tackles a problem initially.
There is very many ways to
solve a probability problem.
And just seeing them navigate to a
solution tells you a lot about how they
think, how they remain composed
under a certain situation.
because every time you're solving
a probability problem, you're kind of
nervous if you're going the right way,
and now you're never completely sure.
So I think,
probability problems are very good
at testing how a person thinks.
I am looking for, one, see how they
explain why they got the solution.
Two, seeing how they consider
the entire scenario of the problem.
So, in the case of probability problems,
there's always uncertainty of whether
you're considering everything.
It's hard to explain, but whenever
you're solving one, you don't know if
you're considering all the possible
scenarios which will ruin your solution.
Yeah, likely just looking to see how she
will take me from the problem statement
to the solution.