So to wrap up let's talk little bit about doing some recognition using our
SIFT features.
So basically at training time, you I give you some object.
You somehow have to get hold of the, just that object in the image, okay?
So what's the easiest way?
Well, you put it against the black background.
Okay.
So you find the outline, everything inside there is the object.
And you compute your keypoints,
you find your little SIFT descriptors located all over the object.
And in here, you find these outlines, okay?
But again, there'd be little SIFT features all over them.
The outlines are what we're going to overlay when we
say that we've found the image.
Okay?
So at test time, what do we do?
Well, we take the keypoints from our test image and we compare each
one of them against, let's suppose we're looking for, I don't know, telephones.
So we take the keypoints of the telephone,
we try to find the best one that matches.
Exhaustive nearest neighbor best bin first locally sensitive hash,
whatever it is.
I try to find the best one and I compare a whole bunch of them.
Here comes the trick.
Now I want to find a consistent set of matches, okay?
So, what that means is that I'm going to do the following.
Let's suppose that I believe that the difference between this picture and
that picture is an affine transform.
Okay.
Now you're scratching your head to try to remember that whole affine transform
thing, because I'm about to ask you a really hard question.
How many pairs of corresponding points do I need for an affine transform?
Then answer is not four.
Four was a homography.
One for translation.
Two is similarity, translation, rotation, scwale, scale.
It was three for an affine.
So an affine will let you do a translation, rotation, scale and a shear.
So if I find three good points here and
three good points there, that allows me to compute my affine transform.
So then what I can do is that tells me where every point from the left
image should appear in the right image.
So I can now check to see if I take all my key points from my teddy bear,
do they all land at matching keypoints when I apply that same affine transform?
Okay. We'll actually spend a lot more time talking about how to search for
transforms over matches on the next lesson.
But for now, you can just think about doing it sort of this brute force way.