Hi, my name is Thad Starner.
At Georgia Tech, I teach the AI course,
the mobile ubiquitous computing course,
and when I'm lucky, the computer science
rapid prototyping hardware class.
In this course, we're taking
parts of Sebastian Thron's and
Peter Norwick's AI course on Udacity and
mixing it with the best parts
of my teaching at Georgia Tech.
When Sebastian and Peter first presented
the idea of this online courses,
one hope was that we could mix the best
parts of the best courses of top
lecturers and make a class which is
better than what anyone of us could do.
Peter will be covering search and
logical planning.
Sebastian will be teaching the section
on probability and base nets.
And I'll be covering
the rest of the content.
Let's get started.