Ready to have some fun?
This is a QR code app that
Paul Kinlan put together.
You'll need a copy on
your local machine, so
check out the instructor notes for
download instructions.
You can find it below.
It's a really cool app, but
right now it's a bit janky.
In this first quiz, you'll be replacing
setInterval with requestAnimationFrame.
And in the second quiz you'll be
moving all the image decoding work off
the main thread and into a web worker.
Before you start working on the app,
you'll need to install gulp
if you don't already have it.
Once you install gulp, run npm install
to get all the dependencies, and
that will allow you to run gulp serve
to build and then serve the web site.
Gulp serve also watches all
your files for changes.
So if you save a change to
any of the JavaScript files,
it'll automatically rebuild and
refresh the page.
So for this quiz navigate to
app/scripts/main.js in your favorite
text editor and
start using requestAnimationFrame.
Build and run the page with gulp serve
and you'll know you've done it properly.
When the app loads and you're seeing
animation frame fired in the timeline.
When you're done check this
box to let us know that you're
firing animation frames.