Let's talk a little bit more about system calls.
Using this diagram I'm going to trace through where control and
data are exchanged during a system call.
I will use this icon to denote where I am in the diagram.
We will start by assuming we are currently in an executing user process.
Then because the user process needs some hardware access,
it makes a system call.
On a system call, control is passed to the operating system, in privileged mode,
and the operating system will perform the operation and
then it will return the results to the process.
Executing a system call involves changing the execution context from the user
process to that of the OS kernel,
also passing arguments, whatever necessary for the system cooperation.
And then jumping somewhere in the memory of the kernel so that you can go
through the instruction sequence that corresponds to that system call.
With the system call, control is passed to the operating system.
The operating system operates in privileged mode.
And it's allowed to perform whatever operation was specified in the system call.
Once the system call completes, it returns the result and
the control back to calling process.
And this again will involve changing the execution context from,
now from kernel mode into the user mode, passing any arguments back into
the user address space, and then, jumping to the exact same location
in the execution of the user process where the system call was being made from.
But the entire process involved changing the execution context from user to
kernel mode and back, passing arguments,
jumping around in memory to locations where the code to be executed is.
So, it's not necessarily a cheap operation.
To make a system call, an application must write arguments,
save all relevant data at a well-defined location,
make the actual system call using this specific system call number.
The well-defined location is necessary so that the operating system kernel,
based on the system call number, can determine which, how many arguments it
should retrieve and where are they, at this well-defined location?
The arguments can either be passed directly between the user program and
the operating system, or
they can be passed indirectly by specifying their address.
In synchronous mode, the process will wait until the system call completes.
I will talk about an alternative where we can issue asynchronous system calls,
but that we will leave for a later discussion in this course.
For now, you must understand that there are some basic steps involved in
calling an operating system service and obtaining the results.