Now its time to apply
what you've learned.
We are going to add some
networking to Sunshine.
Open project SO2.01-Exercise-Networking.
Look at your to-do's.
First fill in network details,
you can use the technique we
used in the toy app if you wish.
Delete the dummy data-related code.
Then create a FetchWeatherTask to
perform those networks across some
background threat.
Override the doInBackground and
onPostExecute methods to get and
display the weather results.
Override the doInBackground
an onPostExecute methods to get and
display the weather results.
Create a loadWeatherData function to
get the preferred weather location from
SunshinePreferences and
then call it from onCreate.