The packet filtering or the state fill
inspection firewalls on a two main or
more traditional types of firewalls.
There are other more modern firewalls.
In particular,
an application-level gateway, or
sometimes called an application proxy,
is an application-specific firewall.
It essentially acts as a relay of
application-level traffic, or a man or
system in the middle.
That is, to the external server,
this gateway acts as the client, and
to the internal client, this gateway
acts as the external server.
For example,
many organizations have a web proxy, and
that is a application-level gateway.
Let's discuss a typical workflow
of an application-level gateway.
First, the user contacts the gateway
using an application such as FTP or
the browser.
The gateway then asks information such
as the name of the remote server,
the user login information, and so on.
The user then provides the valid
authentication information
to the gateway.
The gateway then contacts
the external server and
provides the valid user
authentication information.
In other words, the gateway acts as
the user to the external server.
When the external server
sends back a response,
the gateway is going to analyze it, and
if the traffic is allowed, it's going to
forward it to the user, but in order for
the gateway to be able to correctly
analyze the server response,
the gateway must implement
the correct application logic.
For example, if this is a web proxy,
you must be able to process web traffic,
just like a browser.
As we can see, if you want to
use application-level firewalls,
we must implement proxy code for each
application that we want to protect.
The advantage is that we can then
restrict certain application features.
For example, a web proxy can prevent
active scripts in web pages.
This can be accomplished by the proxy
removing the scripts in the pages
returned by the remote server, and
therefore application-level
gateways tend to be more secure.
On the other hand, application-level
gateway does incur additional overhead.
This is easy to see,
because each connection
from the user to the external server is
actually spliced into two connections.
One is from the user to the gateway, and
the other one is from the gateway
to the external server.
And the gateway must examine and
forward all traffic in both directions.