All right, you're done.
You are over the hurdle.
This is the hardest thing we're going
to teach in this entire class, I think,
in a lot of ways, or
at least the most involved.
Let me show you what my
solution looked like.
So we talked a lot about what was
going to happen in ForecastAdapter.
This is where most of the code for
this one actually was,
it was in ForecastAdapter still.
So the first thing we did is we
created a member variable for
this ForecastAdapter onClick handler.
This onClick handler's one that was
designed for our specific use case,
it's not just a duplicate of
the framework's onClick handlers,
because it actually
returns a view holder.
And as well as we're destroying this
empty view construct, so that we can
have a view that we can alter
depending on how many items we have.
Then we have our view holder implement
view.OnClickListener, which is very,
very important.
Then, as I said before, when we create
the view holder in the constructor,
we can set an OnClickListener.
So here's what we're actually
going to do on this onClick handler.
because this is kind of important.
We're actually going to get the date,
which is what we need to do actually,
use onClick.
And then we're going to send that
blissfully away into our click handler,
which is a lot nicer than
actually sending the cursor in.
This is a nice data abstraction
thing we're doing here.
And as you can see,
here's the interface we created for
that OnClickHandler, which is going to
return a date along with our ViewHolder.
And as you can see in our constructor
now, we're actually taking
the OnClickHandler and the emptyView,
and in fact, those are both final.
So if we didn’t construct them here,
we could not survive as a class.
So one more change we do here is that
in swapCursor, we have a cursor.
We can check to see what
the item count is, and
make ourselves visible or invisible.
Very nice to have that now
that we have an empty view.
So that’s most of the work for
this, actually.
But there's a little bit to do
in ForecastFragment as well.
So again, we already had
our empty view here before.
Now what we're going to do is
we're going to pass that into our
ForecastAdapter as well as create
now a ForecastAdapter OnClickHandler
that gets a date and our ViewHolder.
And the reason why we're getting the
ViewHolder is actually because I want
the adapter position.
So I could've just sent
the position back, but
it was kind of nice to have that there.
And so that'll make onClick work again.
Yeah, so that's it.
We didn't have to do much
at all in ForecastFragment.
So that's it for
this using RecyclerView part two.
You guys are over the hump
now with RecyclerView.
You're feeling confident that you can
use this in your programs, hopefully.
And, let's get on to the next.