Now let's move on to
stochastic environments.
Let's consider a robot that
has slippery wheels, so
that sometimes when you make a movement,
a left or
a right action, the wheels slip and
you stay in the same location.
And sometimes they work and
you arrive where you expected to go.
And let's assume that the suck
action always works perfectly.
Now, we get a belief state space
that looks something like this.
And, notice that the results of actions
will often result in a belief state
that's larger than it was before.
That is, the action will increase
uncertainty because we don't know
what the result of
the action's going to be.
And so here, for
each of the individual world states
belonging to a belief state, we have
multiple outcomes for the action.
And that's what stochastic means.
And so we end up with
a larger belief state here.
But in terms of the observation,
the same thing holds as in
the deterministic world.
The observation partitions the belief
state into smaller belief states.
So, in a stochastic partially
observable environment,
the actions tend to
increase uncertainty, and
the observations tend to bring
that uncertainty back down.
Now, how would we do planning
in this type of an environment?
Well, I haven't told you yet, so
you won't know the answer for sure.
But I want you to try to
figure it out anyways,
even if you might get the answer wrong.
So, imagine I had the whole belief state
from which I've diagrammed just a little
bit here.
And I wanted to know how to get from
this belief state to one in which all
squares are clean.
So I'm going to give you
some possible plans, and
I want you to tell me whether you think
each of these plans will always work,
maybe sometimes work depending on
how the stochasticity works out.
And so here are the possible plans,
remember I'm starting here, and I want
to know how to get to a belief state
in which all the squares are clean.
One possibility is suck right,
then suck.
One is right suck, left suck.
One is suck right, right suck.
And the other is suck right,
suck right, suck.
So some of these actions might take you
out of this little belief state here.
But just use what you knew from the
previous definition of the state space
and the results of
each of those actions.
And the fact that the right and
left actions are non-deterministic.
And tell me which of these you
think will always achieve the goal.
Or will maybe achieve the goal.
And then I want you to also answer for
the fill in the blank plan.
That is, is there some plan,
some ideal plan, which always or
maybe achieves the goal?