So let's go over some of how actually you program this stuff.
From the programming perspective it's pretty simple.
You just use all of the CUDA you've learned so far, except inside a kernel.
So the kernel launches, streams, events, synchronization,
all that kind of stuff as normal from inside a kernel,
so your CUDA from the GP program looks pretty much exactly like your CUDA from the CPU program as well.
So what I've got here is a typical hello world in CUDA.
What you can see with this version of hello world, I'm launching a kernel to print hello from the GPU,
and then I'm following it up with a print of world from the CPU.
Note how I need the synchronization here after the launch to ensure that the hello happens first,
that it's flushed out to the screen, and then the world will print.
And here's the equivalent code for dynamic parallelism.
You can see it looks pretty much exactly the same.
I have moved the code that was on the CPU directly to the GPU, and the same rules apply.
I'm calling hello to be printed from another kernel, I'm synchronizing so that the output completes,
and then I'm printing world from the GPU kernel.
I would end up launching this just trivially as a single kernel launch of hello world
from the CPU to make all of this work.
So as you can see, the basic idea is that all the CUDA that you already know how to use from the CPU,
you just use it directly from the GPU in exactly the same way you've learned.