Now let's see how can
this be implemented.
So at the lowest level,
we need to be receiving some events,
some messages from the network or
from the disk.
So information about completed requests
to read a portion of the file,
write the file, etc.
The operating systems use
these two abstractions to
typically represent networks or disks.
So sockets are typically used to
represent interface to the network.
And then files are what's
really stored on disks.
So these are the main abstractions
when it comes to storage.
Now although they are called
differently, sockets and files,
it is quite fortunate that internally,
the actual data structure that's
used to represent these two different
obstructions, is actually identical.
It's called the file descriptor.
So then an event in the context
of this web server is
an input on any of the files descriptors
that are associated with it.
So in any of the sockets.
Or any of the files that are being
accessed by the connections that these
sockets carry.
To determine which file
descriptor has input, so
to determine that there is an event
that has arrived in this system.
The flash talks about
using the select call.
The select call takes a range
of file descriptors and
then returns the very first one
that has some kind of input on it.
And that is regardless is whether
that file descriptor is a socket or
a file ultimately.
Another alternative to
this is to use a poll API.
So this is another system call that's
provided by current operating systems.
The problem with both of these,
is that they really have to scan through
potentially really large list of file
descriptors, until they find one.
And, it is very likely that along
that long list of file descriptors,
there going to be only
very few that have inputs.
So, a lot of that search
time will be wasted.
An alternative to these is a more recent
type of API that's supported by, for
instance, the Linux kernel and
that's e poll so
this eliminates some of the problems
that select and poll have.
And a lot of the high performance
servers that require high data rates and
low latency use this
kind of mechanism today.
The benefits of the event driven
model really come from its design.
It's a single address space,
single flow of control.
As a result, the overheads are lower.
There's no need for context switching.
Overall, it's a much
more compact process so
it has smaller memory requirements.
And the programming is simpler.
We don't need to worry about use
of synchronization primitives,
about shared access to variables, etc.
Now, in the context of this single
thread, we are switching among multiple
connections, so we are jumping all
over the code base of this process and
executing different handlers,
accessing different states.
That will have some effect on
basically loss of localities and
cache pollution effects.
However, that will be significantly
lower than would have been happening
if we were doing a full
blown context switching.
So the overheads and some of
the elimination of the synchronization,
these are some of the things that really
make this an attractive approach.