It's almost launch time, but
we need to have some place to launch it.
Let's create an emulator AVD or
Android Virtual Device.
Android virtual devices are great.
One of the important things to do is
test your app on a wide variety of
screen sizes and platform versions, and
it allows you to do much of this testing
and debugging without having to
have a closet full of devices.
On Windows and Mac, the x86 emulator
relies on a special kernel driver called
HAXM for hardware virtualization.
If you can't run using HAXM, check
out the link to troubleshooting HAXM.
Let's create an AVD for
a Nexus 5X x86 64 running Nougat.
We start by clicking on this icon
to bring up the AVD manager, and
we can select Create Virtual Device.
And then we select Nexus 5X.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We select Nougat running x86
64 targeting Android 7.0.
If possible,
target 7.0 with Google APIs because
we'll need Google APIs in addition to
Android before the end of this course.
So let's finish creating our AVD.
And there we have it,
a Nexus 5X virtual device.
We can use the Play icon to
launch our new emulator instance.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And here we are with a new emulator,
it's time to launch our app.
Return to Android Studio and
press the Play button to launch.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And in a short while,
we've gotten our starter app going.
Keep in mind that the emulator
is not just a simulator.
It's actually running
the complete Android stack.
So you can test and
debug your app on different hardware and
software configurations.
You can interacted your app on
your emulator using the screen or
nav controls.
Invoke other apps, play audio or
video and much more.
It also includes debug capabilities,
including log output, and
the ability to simulate app
interrupts or network latency.
To run on the device is
usually very simple as well.
But on Jelly Bean release two and
higher devices, the developer
options are hidden by default.
Shh, to find this secret
menu option go to Settings,
about the device, build number,
and now tap seven times.
And then developer options will
show up in the settings menu.
Go try it.
Now you can turn on USB debugging.
On Windows you need to install a device
driver for the Android Debug Bridge,
or ADB.
You'll also have to do some work
on Linux, check the link for
the individual set up for
your development platform.
Once you've gotten ADB installed,
plug in your device.
If all is working,
JellyBean V2 devices and
above will have you confirm
debugging on the device screen.
After that, it's time to run your app
from Android Studio just as before.