So to recreate China's red dot,
we need to map certain data
values to pixel values.
In particular, we need to map the value
of 13,330 to x pixels, and then we
need to map the value of
77 years to y pixels.
That will give us
the center of the circle.
So to actually change these
data values into pixel values,
we'll make use of D3 scales.
To use scales in D3, you specify
the range of possible input values that
you'd like, and then you specify
the output values which they can map to.
So for our chart area, the x-axis scale
would range from about 250 to 100,000.
Also, notice that this is on
a logarithmic scale, whereas for
life expectancy, the scale is linear.
You want to keep these two things in
mind because it will determine which
type of scale we can make in D3.