Okay, you've set up an account.
And with that, I'm off.
>> Wait.
J.P., where are you going?
>> It's 10:00 AM,
gotta head back to my day job.
But I like where this is going.
>> Okay, you got it, J.P. I'll check
in with you after the developer and
I figure out how to write
some data to Firebase.
All right, it's just you and
me for a bit.
Okay so you've got your online Firebase
backend and you've got an Android app so
now it's time to connect the two.
There are four steps to do this.
You'll need to do these steps for
any Android app that you
plan to use Firebase in.
Before we start,
I've linked a quick guide for
setting up Android in Firebase if you
prefer text to me talking to you.
Okay step one, install Firebase.
So the first thing you're going to do is
you're going to add the library to your
Android apps gradle file.
So I'm here in the build.gradle file.
Okay and you're going to add two pieces
of code and they're in the instructor
notes so don't worry about copying them
off the screen or anything like that.
First is down here in
your dependencies and
what we're going to do is declare that
we're using Firebase as part of the app.
And that you needed to run the app.
Now, let's see what happens if I run,
well I get this error here
about duplicate files.
And to avoid that,
you need to add some packaging options.
So to fix this error, I'm going to need
to exclude those duplicated files and
I do that by adding a packaging
options directive inside of Android.
You're doing this with
the same build.gradle file and
I'm just going to scroll up and
put it right below the signing configs.
And as easy as that you've installed the
Firebase library as part of your app.
If you're looking for
alternative ways to install the library
such as if you were using Mavin or
another build tool
those are included in the Android Quick
Start guide, which is linked below.
So step two,
you need to add some permissions
to your Android manifest file.
Is there a permission that
Firebase is likely to need?
If you said yes, the Internet
permission, you are absolutely correct.
Your Fire-based data store is online, so
you're going to need to be
able to access the Internet.
I'm going to add that permission now.
Okay, so
you've added Firebase to Gradle and
you've also added the Internet
permission to your Android manifest.
Next you're going to need to
initialize Firebase in your app.
The Firebase library needs to know about
your Android context object, so this
initialization needs to happen before
you do anything else with Firebase.
And to ensure that I'm going to do
that in a Android application class.
Specifically the shopping
list application class here.
This class is really good for any kind
of global setup that you need to do.
So it's a perfect place to put
this Firebase initialization code.
And that's what the code looks like.
Firebase.dryAndroidContext.
And you pass the NA context.
Now an application is a context.
You can also do this in the on
create of an activity class, but
I'm doing it in the application because
I want to make 100% sure that I can use
Firebase anywhere in my code.
Okay, and I'm going to do one more sort
of optional thing to get us ready.
As JP mentioned, I'm going to go over
to the Constance class in utils.
Right here under Firebase URL I'm
just going to make a constant.
And I'm going to call it Firebase URL.
And what I'm going to set that
equal to is a string here
which represents the URL
that JP mentioned.
Remember every Firebase app has
a URL associated with it, so
you should put yours here.
Now I'm actually going to put something
a little bit different than just
the root URL string that
I was talking about.
I'm going to set it equal to this build
config constant called unique Firebase
root URL.
And to explain what this is, let's take
a look at the gradle properties file.
Which is right here.
So the gradle.properties file is a file
that sits within the root directory
of my project folder.
And it basically lets me set
some config things for the app.
And why this is important is
because I've decided that
I'm not going to track
the gradle.properties file with git.
It's included in the git ignore.
So you can have a different
gradle.properties file than I have.
So, here I've put my shopping
list plus plus Firebase URL and
you can put your shopping list
FIrebase plus plus URL and it's
going to be fine because the get repo
is not going to overwrite this file.
And then this unique Firebase
key value point here
is read in the build.gradle file,
right here in this built type section.
You can see here that I have
unique Firebase root URL,
and I'm setting that to the unique
Firebase root URL constant that you saw.
And then just going back
to the constants file.
You can see I'm actually
using the constant here.
So you don't need to do this in any app
that you're not planning on sharing
the code with someone else, but
it's sort of a useful tip if you want to
share your Firebase code
among different people, and
they're each going to be using
a different Firebase database.
And that's it.
If you haven't been following along,
take a moment now to go ahead and
pause and
make these changes to your app.
The instructor notes have all the little
snippets and things that you need.
And once you're done check this box.