So you apply to a job and
you get a call back for an interview.
Congratulations.
Yay.
Employers get dozens,
if not hundreds, of job applications.
And you were one of the few
they picked to interview.
That means they believe you're
qualified for the role, so
you should believe it too.
Interview structures vary.
Usually a recruiter at
the company will first call you
to do a phone screen interview.
Then an in person interview follows.
This interview can be conducted
online or over video chat.
Sometimes you have multiple
in person interviews.
Each company has their
own hiring policy so
keep that in mind when you're prepping.
What won't change regardless of which
company you are interviewing for is you.
The reason for why you want the job
won't change, your qualifications for
the job won't change.
You need to be sure of all of
this going into the interview.
In this lesson,
we'll go over strategies for
you to best prep yourself for
an interview.
Come on, let's do it.