Time to use our knowledge of Slerp and
put it into practice.
Let's hop back into our
rotate light script.
Instead of using the rotate method,
let's use Slerp
to rotate our directional light 180
degrees over a fixed time interval.
To do that, we need to define
a start and end rotation.
We'll use quaternions,
which is a very convenient way to
handle rotation calculations in VR.
Let's first define our start
rotation by typing Quaternion
startrotation = Quaternion.Euler(50,
30, 0).
Next, let's define our end rotation with
Quaternion endRotation
= startRotation times
Quaternion.Euler(0,180, 0).
In this line,
we define what our end rotation should
be with some Quaternion mathematics.
If we multiply quaternions together,
we're able to add their rotation.
In this case,
we're adding a rotation of 180 degrees,
in the y direction,
to our start rotation.
If you want to learn
more about quaternions,
make sure to check out the Unity
documentation on them.
The last thing we need to do, is provide
the time perimeter that Slerp requires.
For Slerp, or Lerp, the time
parameter is the value between 0 and
1, which dictates how close
the interpolated value should be
to the start or end rotation.
So for this, we can't use
Time.deltaTime, because that is
just the time between frames, not the
time since the application has started.
Instead, we can use Time.time, which is
the time since we hit our play button.
So to update the rotation,
we can delete the Rotate method, and
instead write Rotation =
Quaternion.Slerp (startRotation,
endRotation, Time.Time).
And now, if we go back and
hit Play, for the first second,
the sun will start to rotate
until it's night, and then stop.
Note that the update method
is still calling Slerp, but
after Time.time is greater than 1,
Slerp outputs the end rotation, which
is the night rotation we're seeing now.
You might've noticed the rotation
happens way too fast.
To solve that,
we need to go back into the script and
scale our time value by multiplying it
or dividing it by some scalar value.
Go ahead and play around with that value
and find something that feels natural.