The very first question, is a search question.
You probably know about the Towers of Hanoi,
if you don't then please go and Google them.
It's a single player game, by which you try to move the tower of four slices over here,
onto the right peg, over here.
You can use the middle peg, but the rules are you can only move one disk at a time.
And it might never happen, that a small disk sits below a larger disk.
So the way to solve it is to move the disk over here,
the second largest disk to the right side,
the small one over,
and the third largest to the center, and so on.
If you know it, you know what I'm talking about. If not, just Google it.
So, I would like to know,
what is the size of the state space of valid disk configurations in this puzzle.
Please enter this here.
I'd like to know, whether the number of the disks on the left peg
are an admissible heuristic, if you use A* search.
And I'd like to know, what is the number of steps
that an optimal solution will require
to move all the disks from the left peg, to the right peg.