So what do we do?
>> Well perhaps we should include a
check in the evaluation function to see
if a partition is formed
by the next move, and if so,
start counting the number of
moves left to each player.
>> That sounds like a good idea, but
how much is it going to cost us?
>> What do you mean?
>> Our evaluation function goes from
a very simple function to compute to
something that may involve a complicated
check followed by a lot of counting.
Simply counting the number of
contiguous squares a player can use is
similar to searching more
levels down in the search tree.
We know that it's very time consuming.
More to the point,
we just doubled the amount of time
the evaluation function takes.
That time becomes
multiplied exponentially
due to the branching factor
as the search goes deeper.
>> Ouch, are complicated evaluation
functions always not worth it?
>> It really depends on the game.
Changing the rules of isolation slightly
can dramatically change whether it is
better to use a simple evaluation
function and search deeper, or
to use a complicated evaluation function
that catches these dangerous situations.
I've tried isolation variance,
like having the players
like a knight in chess, or
allowing wrap around on the borders, or
even having each player
control two pieces.
And I'm often surprised at
which strategy seems to win.
It always pays to think carefully about
the evaluation function, whether it is
capturing the desired behavior, and
how efficiently it can be implemented.