So in essence, if you were to look at a simple example like this,
if I have a signal that goes in, changes directions like this,
I'm going to be able to pick up these changes, so this is yet
another way of looking at the same example.
If I had a flat region, if I move my window around in this flat region,
there is no change in any direction.
If I was to do this at an edge.
This changes, in direction this way, but not along the edge, but, even a slight
change, in any direction around this corner, will actually give me information
of changes in all directions, and therefore, this makes this point a very,
very significantly important feature that has the characteristics we discussed,
while, there's nothing here nor here that we can use.