I walk through my solution of visualizing Storm with Redis and d3, here.
In step 1, I opened a new tab on my local computer, and
typed vagrant ssh with login success.
In step 2, I navigated to lesson 1, stage 1, and you can simply copy, and paste.
In step three we're using the lettuce module to link Java to Redis.
So in your local text editor, navigate to lesson1 > stage1 > source > jvm >
udacity > storm and ReporterExclamationTopology.
Next, we copy the dependency to dependency area and open the palm.xml file.
Next, we scroll down, find the COPY AND
PASTE, paste our dependencies, and finally uncomment.
Notice that you need to copy and
paste your dependency outside the comment statements.
Briefly, if you're unfamiliar with XML, XML is simply a tree structure.
Where there's an opening and
a closing tag for every element in a nested fashion.
Therefore dependency is closed by dependency, group ID is closed by group ID.
And a larger section, build for
example, is always followed by a closing tag of build.
Finally remember to save your palm.xml file.
And step 5, on the command line run MVN package.
Once you have a build success, we move on to step 6.
We first import the RedisClient and RedisConnection.
You can do this simply by copying, navigating back to
your report exclamation topology, and paste your import statement.
Next in step 2 of 4 at the class level, we declare our RedisConnection variable.
Notice that the class level we declare but
in the prepare method, we instantiate.
We can simply copy, scroll down to the class level,
where we see another variable OutputCollector_collector declared but
not instantiated, and finally paste to declare our RedisVariable.
So in the prepare method we are going to copy and
paste to instantiate the RedisConnection.
And we scroll down to the prepare method where we see another
variable _collector.
Instantiated with collector and paste to instantiate the redis connection.
Next we copy the actual connection, and
again in the prepare method we instantiate the actual connection.
Finally, in step 4 of 4, in the execute method,
we define the logic of what happens when a tuple comes into our.
We scroll down to the execute method that receives a tuple and
complete some logic.
Finally, in part 4 of 4, we simply un-comment the long count = 30.
And our redis.publish.
Throughout this course we'll have a number of opportunities to both update and
use all of these different methods.
So for now, let's just run our updated topology.
In step 7, we build again, by typing maven package.
And once we have another build success, in step 8,
we submit the new topology ReporterExclamationTopology.
You can copy and paste the ReporterExclamationToplogy submission here, or you
can simply enter at the command line using storm jar target with a tab udacity
hyphen tab because we want the jar-with-dependencies throughout this course.
Udacity.storm and the ReporterExclamationTopology.
That one submitted, hopefully you will see your visualization running.
Your word cloud, with a number of test names, with three or
six exclamation points following each name.
One final point, you may need to do a Ctrl+C at the command line to
terminate your Storm topology.
That simply your Ctrl+C and you'll see your command prompt up here again.
Congratulations on modifying your first Storm topology.