For a start off quiz,
lets consider the situation when you're about to begin object oriented design.
You come in with a set of UML diagrams, possibly including OCL constraints,
which you produced during the analysis phase.
When you've completed the OO design, you also have a set of diagrams and these
diagrams serve as a direct expression of what the target program will look like.
What I'd like you to consider for
a moment, is what is the difference between these two sets of diagrams.
In particular, what UML elements used in the OOA models don't
have direct equivalents in object-oriented programming languages,
thereby requiring some change to be made to the object-oriented design diagrams.