So the scenario here is kind
of little interesting one.
There is a particular user.
The user does belong.
User is Alice,
she does belong to this group.
The system specifies that members
of this group can read file foo so
that's a positive access right.
Think of that as plus read says in the
column it's going to be for file foo,
the row is going to be for this subject
All-Students we're talking about.
And if you look at, in the entry in the
access control matrix corresponding to
this subject and to this object or file.
Then it's going to say, there's.
They're allowed to read it,
but Alice is denied access.
Maybe Alice is no longer a student,
a member of this group
that we are talking about.
So if you look at Alice's entry for
this file foo, okay, so the role
would be Alice's role in the access
control metrics, and the column is foo.
If you go in there,
then access is denied.
So we have a negative
read that says Alice
should not be allowed to read this part.
We're exploring a couple of different
questions here or ideas here.
We're exploring the idea of a group and
users being part of a group.
The idea of a positive access right
as well as a negative access right.
And actually the important thing
that this question is exploring is
what happens when you run
into a situation where
you kind of seems like
you have a conflict?
Where Alice is a member of this
group and the group has access.
But then if you look at Alice herself,
she is denied access to this file.
So what does enforcement
do in this case?
That's the question you are exploring in
this quiz, and there are two options.