This table is about individual
animals that live at a particular zoo.
The first row says that the zoo
has a gorilla named Max,
who was born on April 13th of 2001.
That's three pieces of data
that are all related, and
that there all about the same gorilla.
Every row has three pieces of
data fitting the same pattern.
Notice that it's totally possible for
two animals to have the same name.
Max the gorilla isn't the same
animal as Max the moose.
When we create a table in a database,
we'll give the table a name.
This one's named animals.
The name of the table and the names and
types of the columns,
make up what's called the table header.
These aren't values in the table,
they just tell us what
the data in the table means.
The body of the table consists
of any number of rows, and
each row contains a value for
each column.
Let's see a little more of the table and
do a bit of a quiz.