In this unit, we're going to
talk about problem solving.
The theory and
technology of building agents that
can plan ahead to solve problems.
In particular, we're talking about
problem solving where the complexity of
the problem comes from the idea
that there are many states.
As in this problem here, a navigation
problem where there are many choices to
start with and the complexity comes
from picking the right choice now and
picking the right choice at
the next intersection and
the intersection after that, stringing
together a sequence of actions.
This is in contrast to the type of
complexity shown in this picture where
the complexity comes from the partial
observability that we can't see
through the fog where
the possible paths are.
We can't see the results
of our actions and
even the actions
themselves are not known.
This type of complexity will
be covered in a later unit.
Here's an example of a problem.
This is a route-finding problem
where we're given a start city.
In this case, Arad and
a destination, Bucharest,
the capital of Romania from which
this is a corner of the map and
the problem them is to find
a route from Arad to Bucharest and
the actions that the agent can
execute are driving from one city to
the next along one of
the roads shown on the map.
The question is, is there a solution
that the agent can come up with given
the knowledge shown here to the problem
of driving from Arad to Bucharest?