Welcome back to Computer Vision.
This is going to be the second in a series about stereo.
In particular, we're going to focus on what's called epipolar geometry.
We'd said last time that if we had two images and
we knew something about the cameras, if we could find correspondences given that
known relationship, we could find the depth.
And we talked about disparity.
And disparity was the idea that the location of a point in an image would
change, depending upon the depth of the scene as I move my camera.
And if I actually had the disparity I could make a disparity map,
which tells me how all the points have shifted.
And disparity was inversely proportional to the depth, and
that's was this disparity map on the right is.
But, how do we find the disparity?
Essentially given one point in the image, we need to search for it in the other.
But our intuition tells us, if I know something about how the two
cameras are aligned, you give me one point in the picture on the left.
It can't be anywhere on the picture on the right,
it has to be somehow constrained in terms of where it can be on the left.
This lesson is going to be about those constraints, and
then we're going to assume those constraints when we go about actually finding
the points in the next lesson.