(Sebastian) So welcome to our first online office hours. We're here to answer questions that many of you asked
through Google Commentator. (Peter) And I wanted to thank you for all the questions and all the votes on the questions.
So we had over 300 questions and 12,000 votes, and you came up with a set of very interesting ones.
So let's get right to them. (Sebastian) Okay. "Is there a chance you'll continue with a A.I. two class, a successor class?"
Peter, what do you think? (Peter) We're definitely going to do more classes,
and we're going in a bunch of different directions, I think. We'd like to do this class again, just to see how much easier
it is to do it the second time than the first. I think before we settle on a advanced A.I. class, we'd probably go more
in the other direction, of maybe doing some more basic classes. And then hopefully at some point farther in the future,
we can get back to the more advanced ones. (Sebastian) Yeah, there's also a sub-question here about more math
and programming tasks. I agree, the lack of programming exercises is a bit of a lack in our class right now,
and I'd like to fix this. We currently don't have the technology for this, but we're working on it,
and I hope the next class that comes out, we can have much more engagement on the programming side as well.
(Peter) Right. And we will, we haven't quite figured out how to do programming assignments and get them all graded
for all of you. But we will have something outside of the class where we'll be having an A.I. programming contest,
and we'll have details for that up in about a week or so.
(Sebastian) Does Stanford at all have plans to make more courses available to go deeper in the understanding of A.I.
and getting your hands into applications? Fairly the same question. (Peter) Yeah, pretty much the same question.
So that's on the top of all your minds. I should say the first came from M. Diagonav in Russia,
and this one comes from Zupperman23 in Spain.
So yes, we definitely want to do more, and we haven't quite worked out the schedule yet, but we'll keep you posted.
(Sebastian) The next question asks about an online programming contest.
Peter just commented on it--there's going to be something on the website pretty soon. Stay tuned, please.
We're trying that out. But it won't count towards any grades.
"Can you review or discuss common or open source A.I. tools which you might have wanted to use to further our learning,
like Mahout or Octave, Peter?
(Peter) Yeah. So there's a lot of good stuff out there, and I guess we can make a list of our recommendations.
So Mahout is a machine learning toolkit. I think it's useful to apply; it's also useful to try to build these machine learning algorithms yourself,
rather than use somebody else's toolkit. Octave is a mathematical programming toolkit, do matrix multiplication and that kind of stuff.
And those kinds of languages are really great. They really help you be able to mock up an application quickly
and get some nice results. (Sebastian) I have to admit, in all my life I never used any toolkits, to be honest.
I've always coded straight in C++ or Java. And more recently, as I aged, more in MATLAB.
MATLAB is really nice for rapid prototyping. The reason why I like MATLAB is it doesn't really give me the A.I. I want,
but it gives me the tools to process the data, visualize the data really really quickly. So it's fantastic to try out an idea.
In terms of programming environments, I think A.I. can be done in any programming environment:
In Python, C++ and Java, you can take any of the algorithms we learned here and just apply them.
(Peter) Okay. Let's see. Next question is, "Are there any open A.I. problems or projects suitable for amateurs to work on?
"Things we could work on after class finishes." (Sebastian) Well, I consider myself a lifelong amateur and learning student.
So obviously, there must be some. I don't recommend building a self-driving car because it takes a lot of work to make your car obedient.
But there's a ton of opportunity with very simple means. For example, if you have a camera, you can take images of your environment,
maybe install it in the kitchen, observe what type of objects you use, walk around your neighborhood,
and right there you have a lot of interesting eye problems. There's a ton of online databases and competitions.
Peter will tell you about some of those. (Peter) Yeah. So Sebastian's been into robots and cameras.
I've been more into things like language understanding. And there, there's lots of data available.
So there's specific data sets, like Google has counts of how often words and phrases occur and how often they occur over time.
And you can use those to do various kinds of machine learning, natural language ideas.
You could write a spelling corrector program. You could write a program to try to grade essays and separate out good ones from bad ones.
You could try to parse sentences. So there's a lot you can do with that kind of data, and if you don't like the data that's out there,
it's just so easy to gather your own. Just go out to some websites, slurp up some text, and do some analysis on it.
You know, maybe go to a site that rates songs or movies and see if you can make recommendations for somebody based on
what they like, to find other things that they like. (Sebastian) Yeah, you could just capture websites and then
make a discriminator whether you like it or not, and that could be a great problem. In fact, if you had this, you might be able to
automatically construct the websites later on using the tools for development from looking at (unintelligible) existing web pages.
In my field of A.I. the holy grail right now is to understand the world, take a camera image and understand what's in there.
Maybe there's a person, a friend, an object, a knife, a kitchen counter, what have you.
This is a largely unsolved problem. So if you just take images of common household items and try to recognize them,
and you do a good job, that'll be just amazing.
(Peter) And so that gets into the next question: "What are some of the most challenging unsolved problems in A.I. today?
"And which of those would have the greatest impact on the world if it was solved?"
So certainly object recognition would be one of those. (Sebastian) Yeah. It used to be that people thought a chess system
was the impactful problem. And chess at the time, I guess, was a really hard problem.
And the hypothesis was that A.I. is really about human thought, and the pinnacle of human thought was to solve
really complicated problems, like playing chess. And then someone came along, IBM, and just solved chess,
and we realized, "Wow, this is just a search exercise. The machine needs to be fast enough."
And today's, I think, more harder problems are more perception problems.
"Do you understand the situation in fuzzy situations?" The human brain takes on hundreds of millions of images
through a lifetime, and makes or brings order to this chaos.
And that's something we don't understand really well. There's people who believe it has to be done through specialized computers
that emulate human neural structure. I personally believe existing computers are just fine,
although we might have to have a certain scale to get there. But the word is still out there.
I'm pretty sure if you could replicate a human brain, for example, you could be really successful,
and I hate to say this, make a lot of money.
(Peter) So those are some good problems. I think another way to look at it is a challenging problem would be
to have an assistant that could be useful. And that would have an impact on the world because if we could everybody
twice as effective by giving them an assistant, that would make the world twice as wealthy and healthy and so on.
(Sebastian) And there's easy ways to do this on a small scale. For example, an assistant that would recommend to me
how to reply to an email in an intelligent way, so that most of the time I wouldn't have even to type the email.
That'd be useful because then it could generate more email for all of you. What's the next question?
(Peter) Let's see. This is from Swagatata in New Delhi. "Hi, the A.I. class is wonderful. Could you suggest any ideas
"for small projects so that someone with a programming background can go a step further?"
So I guess we already covered some of that. Do you have another smaller project or...? (Sebastian) No, not really.
(Peter) Okay. Then here's from Masroor in Islamabad. "Can we have statistics and changing trends about this class
"after it's over? Like how much percentage attempted what homeworks, and what percentage advanced in basic level."
(Sebastian) Yeah, we don't have good statistics right now, and we're trying to compile them. We'll certainly make them available
after the class. There's still many tens of thousands of people doing homeworks regularly.
And you guys are my heroes. It's really amazing. It takes a lot of time, I know this.
And many of you dedicate significant amount of time and effort into this. You're learning a lot.
You're going to be much more enabled afterwards, and really powerful. Thanks for doing this. This is really amazing.
There's one interesting statistic I'd like to share, and it's very preliminary, it's not official.
But we checked the number of people who have a perfect score in all homework assignments so far,
And compared this to our Stanford class. And the ratio of those, the percentage in the online class is about
twice as high as it is in my Stanford class. I find this staggering and mind-blowing.
I know that our class has lots of deficiencies. You had (silver crutches) and all these wonderful things.
But you're sticking with it. That's really really amazing.
(Peter) So I think you guys are doing a great job, so keep it up, and we are gathering all that statistics and they're somewhere on our server;
We just haven't got around yet to taking the time to analyze them because we've been so busy keeping up with class
and getting the next video out and so on. So when the class is all over, we'll take a break and we'll go back and
try to understand better both the summary stuff, which we're very happy to share with you.
I've shared some of that on my Google+ account. We'll keep doing that.
But also looking into it in more depth and trying to understand what worked and what doesn't work.
(Sebastian) Yes. Here's a question from (Sona Klian) in Japan.
"Since Bayesian networks cannot contain cycles in them, how can we model cyclic phenomena,"
"where two events depends on each other? For example, you invite two friends to a party,
"and probability of each of them is going depends on whether the other ones goes to the party, or doesn't go."
There's actually two answers here: There's a method to do Bayes networks without direct (starts) with undirected links,
and they're called Markov networks. And they allow for cycles. A link in a Markov network can be thought of as an affinity.
So if two variables have an affinity and they can reinforce each other, you could link in there,
and if there happens to be a cycle in the link structure of the many undirected links, then you can't solve it close form,
but there's wonderful approximate methods to relax the structure and find a good answer.
So if you care about this, check out this thing called Markov networks.
The other part of the answer is sometimes these dependencies evolve over time.
We talked about unfolding in time in the context of hidden Markov models.
So the state transition functions in the hidden Markov models did have cycles.
But when we unfolded them, each (stavar) had a different time index, and then the (unintelligible) just go away
and you can apply Bayes networks. (Peter) All right. So I think in the example you gave of two people
going to a party, and each of those depending on each other, if you broke those out and don't consider them as single variables,
but rather said, "What do I know now about whether you want to go?" and then I learn that you're going to go,
and now I'm in a different state, so that would be a different variable.
And you'd have what I know now, what I know afterwards, what you know afterwards.
And if those are all separate variables, then there's no cycles involved, but you can still represent the problem
in the way you want to represent it. And I think if we have these Bayes nets that are causal,
then I think you'd have to agree that there shouldn't be any cycles, because if there's causality with cycles,
then that would mean you're going backwards in time. And well, I guess if you wanted to model a time machine,
that would be good. But for the real world, you don't need it. You can always un-pull them.
ire
"to look up formulas, definition, references, and so on, rather than re-downloading the entire video," and look at us cute people,
you and me, Peter, again and again? "This is my daydream. Anon18 in San Diego." Peter?
(Peter) Yeah, I totally agree. I think you're right. (Sebastian) Really? (Peter) Yeah.
(Sebastian) I like watching myself. (Peter) Well, yes. I like watching, but I also like reading.
And I think they're modalities, and there's pluses and minuses to each.
And I think especially for something you want to study and for something you want to quickly browse through
and find a particular point, a particular definition, that's easier done with a glossary or a list than with video
(Sebastian) I was joking. I should say I completely agree. And this is on our list.
I really really think the many many thousands of you who have given us really constructive suggestions like this,
and many others, and gave a list right now of things we'd like to implement for the next iteration of this in other classes,
and being able to edit nodes, and also to have a discussion around lectures, is really high on our priority list right now.
(Peter) Yeah. (Sebastian) We agree, it's annoying to watch the same video over and over again.
The first time it might be really good. In the midterm exam I'll make all the questions available as a PDF or similar,
So you can just download them and print them out and don't have to watch all the videos.
(Peter) Right. So we'll try and do that better.