Anything that involves actual
money is considered a transaction.
So in concrete terms,
that means that the purchases and
refunds are transactions.
For purchases,
the action is ACTION_PURCHASE,
and you must set the quantity for
product.
After all,
if the user's buying zero products,
there's no purchase taking place.
You also need to send
the transaction ID.
Each transaction ID must be unique.
And you set the transaction ID calling
setTransactionId on the productAction.
So go ahead and
add a purchase button to your app.
You should know the drill by now.
Add the purchase button
to the layout file.
Define the method to purchase the cart.
Skeleton code only.
And to send the analytics hit.
Don't forget, we need the full
implementation of the method that sends
the purchase hit to Analytics.
And this method is going to need
to set the unique transaction ID.
One way to make unique transaction
id is to concatenate the product id
with CurrentTime.
We'll supply the code to do
this if you want to use it.
You'll need to add the code
to the utility class.
Course, you're welcome to
invent your own way to generate
unique transaction ID.
Then you'll need to update
the start checkout button so
that it hides itself and
shows the purchase button.
And then run the app and
buy some dinners.