Invariably, you will land on a project
where you don't know much about
what's involved.
It's completely okay to say, you know,
I have not the slightest idea
how to solve this problem.
This is very normal, and
it is normal for every single person.
>> I remember still just,
just starting full time work.
And realizing, wow, I'm not sure I
know how to work with big code bases.
Or, I don't know this language,
and it's frightening.
And there's a lot you don't know.
Find a little nugget you can take on,
and take it from there.
>> There's a lot of times when
you run into areas where you just
don't know what to do, and you feel like
you can't make it all come together.
>> And the most important thing
is to not get caught up in that.
Sometimes the best thing you can do is
actually just take a little time off of
a problem, and then circle back a little
bit later when you have a fresher mind,
and then it'll be easy.
>> Imposter syndrome is
the feeling that you're a fake.
And somehow you snuck in, and
you don't deserve to be where you are.
There are so many times at work,
where I get projects,
to work on, and internally I feel like,
there's no way I can do this.
I'm totally going to fail at it.
The only person expecting
me to fail is myself.
And so if I can get over that
I can gain more confidence and
do anything that I want to do.
>> You have just asked me to code
up something or to fix a bug.
I don't even know where to begin, the
best people I know learn to live with
uncertainty, fear, doubt, confusion,
and they just plow right ahead.
>> Failure is
>> It's going to happen if you take
risks.
And taking risks is
important to succeed.
I have a few tips on
how to cope with that.
Number one is try to see
the silver lining of failure.
Number two is,
I think preparing is really important.
It will help you a lot in
>> Taking the risks that
are more manageable and
being able to succeed more often.
>> I think it's absolutely vital that
when you go into building something you
accept that sometimes
you're going to be wrong.
If I had an opportunity to
sort of go back in time and
tell a younger version of myself,
just say I was getting started.
What should I do?
I honestly think the main thing
would be to experiment more.
And just always trying,
be learning new things.
>> You don't have to have all
of the knowledge right now, but
just realize that you
can always learn it.
And the whole coding process
is a learning process.
>> So, if you're in a class, and it's
been a while, and you made progress,
first of all be proud of that progress.
And you find yourself now feeling
a little stuck, it's okay.
Being overwhelmed is not a bad thing.
That's my first advice.
It means there's a lot of information
coming your way, and you're so
lucky that that is the case.