So what Aaron, who's the video editor for
this class who's been working with me and doing an amazing job so far.
What he does is takes these two videos.
One from the camera that actually has the hand, and
the other one which is the screen capture of the screen itself,
which of course has also my hand writing on it.
These two are merged to generate an image like this which is
basically a combination, a blend of the screen capture and the camera.
And it's because of this you kind of see artifacts like this where
the hand seems to be sometimes in front and
sometimes in behind that image which actually is on the tablet itself.
Of course the reason to kind of have this is we do like to show you
the hands moving around interacting with different aspects of the image.
So, this of course hopefully is not confusing you so
since you've seen the hand and the pen several times.
So now let's try to kind of build on this concept and switch to what is going on