Listing out those difference
gives us a good starting point.
From those, I can make a to do
list of what I need to change.
So now, you're going to go
through each one of these and
slowly transform this
into the final goal.
We'll start with this first step,
which is making the text larger.
And here's the app once
you're done coding.
At each step, make sure to
run the app on your phone so
that you know that it looks
good on a real device.
All right, let's get started.
Here's a list of attributes.
Make a check next to the attribute or
attributes, and
then submit your answer
to see if you're correct.
Once you've selected the correct
attributes, go ahead and
change them so that the text is 36sp for
both text views.
When you're done,
your app should look like this.