So to conclude this lecture,
let me summarize what we've learned.
In this lecture, I've given you
more details about image warping.
We've covered a variety of topics on
how we can actually do much more of
the non-rigid effects like spherical,
and also defamation of images.
Specifically talked about
the basics of forward and
inverse warping applied
to image transformations.
Then actually extended the whole
approach to take a mesh and
use that to warp an image.
We looked at both triangular and
quadrilateral meshes, used that to
introduce the concept of image morphing
and then discussed variety of methods,
including how we can do
feature-based image morphing and
different applications
of image morphing.
For full details, I recommend
you look at the classic paper
on feature-based image metamorphosis.
This is the paper that actually was used
as a foundation of some of the effects
that we've seen in this class.
And of course, the chapter three of Ri,
Szeliski's book also has more details
on all forms of image transformations.