Let's talk about particle filters for localization
that is commonly called Monte Carlo localization.
We learned in the particle filter lesson that the state is retained by a set of particles.
Each particle is a three-dimensional vector here,
comprising x,y, and the heading direction theta,
as indicated by these little arrows that I'm going to just draw here.
A set of particles like these would be a representation for the distribution at any point in time.
Now let me look at the 2 main steps in particle filters.
On is the prediction step, and one if the measurement step. Let's start with prediction.
Just to make things simpler, let's assume our vehicle has only 2 wheels.
It's called a differential-drive robot, and it can navigate by moving both wheels forward,
but if 1 wheel moves faster than the other one, it'll turn.
Let's understand how to apply a particle filter to a robot on that simplicity.
This is simpler than a car, but not much simpler. It's about the same complexity.
As I said, the state of this vehicle is given by the following 3 values: x, y, and θ.
And to predict the outcome of an action, we need to write a function
that predicts those values based on values Δt over here where Δt might be a 10th of a second.
Now the math for this in first approximation is very simple.
It turns out this approximation is good enough to do pretty much anything in robotics
even though it is not very accurate.
Let's assume the robot just keeps moving forward at a fixed velocity v.
Then the new x is given by the old x plus the progress it makes along axis x with velocity v.
So you get v times Δt, which is the total distance traversed,
but the x portion of it is cos θ.
Similarly, for the y coordinates, you get the old y plus the distance traversed--
velocity times Δt times sin θ.
This is a robot that doesn't really change heading directions,
and it'll be sufficient for very small Δt to assume that robot doesn't change heading directions.
These are actually good equations even if the robot is turning.
However, to understand the change of heading direction,
we also have to assume that there is an angular velocity,
and we call this ω [omega], which is a Greek letter.
So the new heading direction is the old one plus ω times Δt.
These are really nice equations to model relatively complex mobile robots.
They're really simple geometry. If you understand cosine and sine,
you realize this is basically a robot that moves on a fixed straight trajectory.
For time Δt it then applies the rotation and it moves again for fixed time Δt on a straight trajectory,
which is an approximation to the actual curve the robot might be taking.