Let me show you one of
the earlier examples using this
in a way that was kind of intriguing.
Moghaddam and Yang, they did some nice
work on gender classification, okay?
So given a face, can you tell me
whether it's a man or a woman?
That's it, that's it basically.
And what they were doing is you can
see they were just cropping out
sort of the center of the face here.
In order to do that, they had some they
had some machinery to take this image.
I think this is still the the old Mayor,
I think it's Mayor White of
Boston a while back, and essentially
finds the face, scales it, finds the,
the, the features, can warp it and
straighten it out and
then cut out just the part of
the face that they want, okay?
So they can automatically go gener,
remember, generate the candidate?
They can automatically generate
the candidates, all right?
So they trained it.
Their training examples
had about 1000 men,
700 women which is a pretty
reasonable ratio in academic labs,
but really, they should have tried to,
to balance it.
The images were shrunk down to
being only 21 by 12 pixels, okay?
So, it's a relatively small feature.
It's still got, whatever,
21 times 12 is, let's see, 210 and
42 times, so 252 numbers, right?
But, they're not just
going to base it on that.
They actually used a Gaussian kernel,
okay?
A Gaussian RBF.
So that's defined as xi and xj, and
when you compute some new input,
x against your support vectors,
so here is kx,
so x is your new input, and
the xj is each of the support vector.
So you have to compute this
quantity at testing time,
in order to determine whether
it's a man or a woman, okay?
What's interesting is,
remember we had support vectors
which were actually the points.
All right, and these are the points
that are sort of the harder points.
Right?
They're the ones near the boundary.
Well, we still have support vectors.
But now,
you can call these things support faces.
Remember eigenfaces?
And by the way, Babock Magadon
was a student of Sandy Pendleton.
Sandy Pendleton, Matt Terk,
the people who do the eigenface,
and then Babock did his own thing
on parts of faces and face space.
All right, but what you can do is you
can now find the support vectors which
in some sense, are the the faces that
are closest to the boundary, right?
In some sense they sh,
not in some sense, they are the faces
that are sort of harder to, to label.
Okay?
So male versus female,
you can see these are pretty similar,
all right, these are pretty similar, and
yet, one is, one is male, one is female.
Here's another example.
Maybe this one's not so hard.
So, this is just some of
the support vector's faces.
Well, what's kind of nice about this,
is that they trained a variety
of classifiers, all right?
Here they are,
some simple nearest neighbor,
which you could see down at the bottom.
A Fisher linear discriminant, which
says, let me try to find a single line
that separates things the best, but
in the original, dimensional space.
Then they tried a variety of methods,
and what's really cool is the SVM, all
right, the Sport Vector Machine with the
radial basis function, the Gaussian one,
only had an error rate of like 3.4%,
which is pretty good.
In fact, how good is it?
Well, you should see what,
how well can humans do on this data set?
'because remember, they just cropped
the middle of the face, all right?
So, they did a test with people,
where they had 30 subjects 22 male,
eight female.
That's also closer to an academic lab,
typically.
And their test data was 254 faces.
60% male, 40% female.
I don't know why they wouldn't use
50 50, but that's what they did.
They used low-res versions and
high-res versions.
We'll get to that in a minute.
And then the task was,
is it male or female?
We'll give you all day to decide,
but you have to make a choice.
You can't say I don't know, and
you can take as long as you want.