when you're tackling a new problem with
a neural network it might help to start
with an existing network that was built
for a similar task and then try to fine
tune it for your own problem there are a
couple of good reasons to do this first
existing neural networks can be really
useful if somebody has taken days or
weeks to train a network already been a
lot of intelligence is stored in that
Network taking advantage of that work
can accelerate your own progress second
sometimes the data set for the problem
you'll work on might be small in those
cases look for an existing network
that's designed for a problem similar to
your own if that Network has already
been trained on a larger data set then
you can use it as a starting point to
help your own network generalized better
in order to do this it makes sense to
learn a little bit about the most
prominent pre-trained networks that
already exists