So, lets look at what's happening
here in this declaration.
We're saying not only give us
a variable called targetpwd that is
12 characters long, but
assign the value MyPwd123 to it.
So initialize this variable with
this value that we are providing.
So we have to actually
store this MyPwd123
into this variable that we
are allocating in the stack.
So this are the initialized
we're going to access it.
What does gets do?
I have checked that as well.
So gets remember, reads a string,
that's user input.
And stores that into this
variable called pwdstr.
So remember we declared
again at size 12,
this character string
that's where we're reading.
So when we gets is going to ask for
input, it's going to take that input and
place that input in this pwdstr.
As a result,
it needs to access this variable and
we know this variable is
allocated on the stack.
So, in particular the stack frame for
this function call, so
it's going to access addresses
when we do gets as well.
Next statement, you see several of
them checked because they're all
access variables that are being
allocated on the stack.
That's what we're trying
to illustrate here.
So here, this is comparing two strings.
Again, the string strncmp
is string compare and
tells you the size of the string,
the max size of the string.
So it saying compare password
string that we just was input.
Target password that has this MyPwd123,
so
to compare these what do we have to do?
We have to go fetch those values.
Character by character or
whatever this scheme is that
we're using to do the comparison.
But we have to see what
is in this variable.
And what is stored here so
to read those values again,
we have to access the stack because
remember both the the local variables
are allocated in the stack frame.
Once we do the comparison,
if the comparison is successful,
we are writing this variable.
We are writing one into
this allow_login variable.
Storing this value into this variable
that's on the stack that was allocated
in the stack frame is again going to
require that we access the stack.
And as a result, we have checked
it because this again requires
access to this variable
that's on the stack.
In this if statement that we have here,
we have to find out what is the current
content of this variable allow_login.
So we have to read it.
Earlier we stored a value in it.
If the comparison was not successful,
actually we will not do that.
So this will not be executed if
the two strings didn't match, but
in case they did match, we store one.
But when we come here we're saying,
we're going to check this
variable allow_login.
If its value is zero,
then we're going to print one message,
if it's not then we're going to
print a different message.
So to find out the value of allow_login
we have to read it which requires
access to an address that
is in the stack frame.
Then we're doing this printing, so
if you look at these are function calls.
And I told you earlier function
calls result in a stack frame
when you make the call.
But remember they're not
accessing any variables
that we have in our current frame.
So, I haven't checked
these three boxes here
because we are not accessing
any of the variables
that exists over that allocated
space in the current stack frame.
That is what we are discussing here for
this particular function.