Let's walk through
the solution step by step.
First, when specifying the parameters,
the request token method
only needs the API key.
So, we can just create
this empty dictionary,
because the task forget method will
add the API key when we call it.
Now when we call the task forget method,
we want to use the method
authentication token new, and
then we'll pass in our parameters, and
now we need to move on to step three.
First, we'll check to see
if an error was returned.
If an error is returned we'll print it,
and
then we'll call our completion handler
for token, we'll pass, success is false,
there's no request token, it's nil,
and we'll give some error strain.
Otherwise, we need to pull the request
token out of the results, so
we'll look at the request
token key here.
We'll grab a request token.
And then we'll call the completion
handler for token where success is true.
We'll pass our request token.
And there's no error string.
Or, if we can't find the key,
then we'll handle that accordingly here.
Let's go ahead and run this,
and see what happens.
If everything works correctly,
then when I click this button,
it'll start our off flow.
And there's our request token.
Now, all the steps we've taken to
get back to this point may seem like
a lot of work for
what we already did, or
something that we did
similarly in lesson three.
But, that's the wrong mindset.
By splitting our code up like this,
it becomes much easier to manage.
And as we move forward,
it'll be easier to add new methods
to interact with the movie database.