Now it's your turn to add code to your
app to track when users do something.
So add code to your app to
track the remove meal event, or
you can choose your own event to track.
Then you're going to need to
run the app on your device.
Make sure it's connected to
android studio, and use the app.
And in particular,
make sure that you do the event that's
going to fire the event hit code.
You can look in the logs to see the
event being sent to the analytic service
for dispatching.
Then you need to review the events
in the Analytics dashboard.
It's a good idea to keep an eye on
the real time data because then you'll
see the hits showing up fairly soon
after you actually send the event.
And it's nice to have that feedback
just in case it takes a while for
the data to percolate to
the rest of the dashboard.
Then think about what events you
might really want to track in this
particular app.
Is it helpful just to record
what dinners people don't like?
Go ahead and discuss it in the forum.