All right, Charles, so
what did we learn on this extended
unit on convergence related stuff.
>> Well, I think the first thing
we learned was Convergence.
Convergence is a thing and
it's something that we would like to be
able to prove in our other algorithms,
and we can in fact prove
them from other algorithms.
>> Like what?
>> That for
example Q-learning actually converges.
It doesn't just converge to something,
it converges to Q star.
>> Oh yeah, that's pretty good.
Now we did that in the form of
a generalized theorem that broke
the Q-learning rule down into actually
kind of two little sub-update rules.
And the proof basically says,
well if both of the sub-update rules do
the right thing, then the overall
update rule does the right thing.
And that got us
the Q-learning converges.
And as you said, not just converges, but
converges to the optimal Q function for
the corresponding MDP,
which actually is pretty amazing
when you think about it, right?
We have all these algorithms for
solving MDP's and
Q learning is like one line
of code that just says,
whenever you make a transition,
do a little update like this, and
nonetheless, that actually works
in the limit it computes Q star.
It's almost too simple
not to try Q learning.
>> Right, but it's generally the case
that simplicity is often the right
thing to do we call that elegance.
>> Ooh, nicely said.
>> What else have we learned?
I learned some other
words like nonexpansive.
>> Or even better, contraction.
>> I do not like that word.
>> Really?
>> It makes you uncomfortable.
>> [LAUGHS] Okay, so
the last thing that I remember is
talking about is speaking of
generalized, generalized MDPs.
>> Right, generalized MDPs have
these nice structure that as long as
the operators that are inside
of it that are doing updates or
non-expansions then we get these
other kinds of convergence.
We get the convergence
of value iteration.
We get the convergence of Q learning.
So, we can actually combine these
generalized MDPs with the generalized
convergence theorem and kaboom.
>> Yeah.
And
that's actually pretty cool because it
would allow us to think about different
kinds of decision processes.
Different situations we
want it to be in and
we would know that all the math would
go through and so we could just do it.
All we have to do is worry about
whether they're non-expansive or not.
>> Great!
Exactly and there's a whole
set of things that we've shown
are non-expansions.
Oh, maybe that's even worth remembering.
What are some things
that are non-expansions?
>> A max.
>> That's a good one.
>> Min.
>> More generally, order statistics.
>> Yes, order statistics.
>> Fixed convex combinations.
>> Uh-huh.
That's my favorite.
>> Actually, I think all the things
are kind of variations of those two.
>> Yeah I think so.
>> You can get fixed convex
combinations of order statistics, so
we can actually combine
those two things together.
>> Oh, that's cool.
Is there anything else?
I think that's all that we covered.
Yeah.
>> Cool.
>> But I think importantly, you said
something that I think was important,
which was that, not just any convex
combinations, but it has to be fixed.
That if the value of it can change,
like with the Boltzmann exploration,
then you do not know
that it will converge.
>> That's right.
It's actually kind of,
maybe an interesting open problem.
It's definitely the case
that we can prove
that Bolton updates
are not non expansions.
They can be expansions.
But that's not quite the same as saying
that therefore it doesn't converge, and
there are some examples of
Q-learning-like update rules that have
update rules that are not non-expansions
and yet it converges anyway.
There's the one that I was involved
with really recently that we called
coco- Q learning.
>> Of course you did.
>> Which is a two player game set up.
And that one you can show that
it's not a non-expansion, but
it converges anyway.
Phew.
>> Okay, so one last thing and
I think we've covered everything but
one last thing and
I realize we have an open question.
>> Okay.
>> So up in the very first line I
we have convergence.
And it's not just convergence for
Q-learning but
the Q-learning actually converges to
Q-star, which is mildly miraculous.
All these other things we were looking
at, these generalized operators and
the order statistics stuff,
those things converge, but
do we know what they converge to?
>> Right, they converge to
that which they converge to.
So in general it's not Q*
because we're actually defining
a different set of Bellman Equations.
So it actually is defining
a different fixed point.
In some cases those fixed
points have good names.
[LAUGH] In some cases not so much.
>> But do they converge to something
that looks like the corresponding Q*?
>> If you know what I mean,
do you know what I mean?
>> Yeah, yeah yeah.
So the idea is that they
converge to something that
makes sense with regard to how
the Q equation is defined.
So for example if we replace
the max in the action selection
with some fixed probability
distribution over actions.
That's kind of equivalent, or
maybe even is exactly equivalent,
to having a fixed stochastic policy.
And what we get convergence to in that
case is the value of that policy.
>> Okay.
So that's good.
That's a big win.
All right.
So, did I forget anything?
>> No, these are the things that I think
were the critical high points of this
fairly formal section, right.
We did a fair amount
of proving of stuff.
I think we're going to do a little more
of that before we get into some more
implementation and practical stuff.
>> Okay cool so
then you'll be doing those.
>> Yes.
>> That's great well then I
look forward to next time.
>> Awesome.
All right.
Thanks Charles.
>> All right.
Bye.