As Travis mentioned,
the movie database and
its API provides methods to users
through its account services.
This would include things
like rating movies or
making a list of your favorite movies.
When data like this takes on
a personal or a private element,
such as my private Flickr images or
my favorite movies list,
we might call this user access data or
user data.
Sometimes all the data that's made
available by an API will be user data.
And the reason an API might do this is
just to make sure that the data that it
provides is more secure and private.
It has to go through a user.
This user data is very different from,
say, data just about movies.
The data just about movies
should be accessible by anyone.
Data like this we might call anonymous
data, or anonymously accessed data.
And as developers, we will want to
work with both kinds of these data.
As we saw in lessons one and
two, to access anonymous data,
we typically call a method.
And we might use an API key and
pass it some arguments.
This type of interaction's not always
this simple, but it's pretty standard.
For user access data,
we can't just get to the data so easily.
This is especially true if we
wanted to change our rating or
add something to our movie list.
How does the API know if the user
is actually authorized to do this?
APIs handle this by authentication,
and as you explore different APIs,
you'll find that each API handles
authentication differently.