So why are some students missing
from the daily engagement table?
When you see something
strange like this,
it can be tempting to just
move on with the analysis.
But it's actually really important
to investigate things like this.
If you don't understand why
something's happening in your data,
you could be missing something
important in your analysis, and
you can't really trust your results.
The process I like to use to
investigate this type of problem is,
first, identify which specific
data points are surprising.
In this case,
that would be any enrollment record
with no corresponding engagement data.
Next, I like to print out one or
a few of the surprising data points.
Sometimes I can tell just by
looking what the problem is.
So go ahead and do that.
Find any one row in the enrollment table
where that student is not present in
the engagement table,
and print that row out.
If you're not sure how to
print only one of the rows,
you could try using
Python's break statement.
There's a link describing
it in the instructor notes.
And, here's a hint.
The sets I made earlier containing
the unique students in each table might
come in handy here.
Do you see anything strange
about the record you printed?
Describe what you see here.