This is a suprisingly challenging question.
If you look at these numbers from 3 to 6.
When we increase X by 3, Y decreases by 3,
which suggests W1 is -1.
Now let's see if this holds.
If we increase X by 3, it decreases Y by 3.
If we increase X by 1, we decrease Y by 1.
If we increase X by 2, we decrease Y by 2.
So this number seems to be an exact fit.
Next we have to get the constant W0 right.
For X = 3, we get -3 as an expression over here,
because we know W1 = -1.
So if this has to equal zero in the end, then W0 has to be 3.
Let's do a quick check.
-3 plus 3 is 0.
-6 plus 3 is -3.
And if we plug in any of the numbers, you find those are correct.
Now this is the case of an exact data set.
It gets much more challenging if the data set cannot be fit with a linear function.