Support vector machines are widely
used for classification tasks.
But not everyone understands
how they fully work or
what is the function or parameter
that they're trying to optimize.
In this case,
Lorenzo's answer was really good.
He identified two key things
that the support vector
machine algorithm is trying to look for.
One, it's trying to look for
a decision boundary that reduces
the misclassification errors.
And it's also trying to optimize the
separation between the support vectors.
It is also very important to understand
when algorithms like SVMs fail.
In this case,
Lorenzo explained very well that when
the two classes that it's trying to
separate are kind of intermingled,
then you don't have a clear separation.
That's where you might have to adapt
the algorithm using a kernel or
use a whole different algorithm.
That insight was really good.