What do you think, David?
>> So, from the bottom, we have
the brick has to support two blocks.
Not necessarily two bricks.
We know that those can
be any kind of block.
We also have that those
two blocks cannot touch.
So, that condition is important.
And we also have that those two
blocks must then support a brick.
And when we learned earlier,
it's not sufficient for
that to be any kind of block.
The block on top has
to be a brick as well.
So, if these three conditions.
Are as efficient to find
a Foo in terms of logic.
>> That is good David.
So what we are learning here
is given conceptual knowledge
how can we translate it
into the language of logic?