When you want to insert data
into a table from your code,
there's one more step you have to do
after executing your insert queries.
You have to commit your
changes to the database.
Why do we have this extra step?
Well imagine that we were
writing an accounting system.
And we wanting to debit some
money out of one account, and
credit it to another account.
That might even be changes
to two different tables.
But, we want them both to take
affect at the same time, or
if something goes wrong,
we would want neither to take affect.
And if some other user was accessing the
database at the same time that we were,
we wouldn't ever want them to see
one change and not the other.
This is one of the big
ideas of databases.
When we make changes such as inserts,
they go into what's called
a transaction in the database.
When we call commit,
the transaction actually takes effect.
If we close the connection
without committing,
our changes will get rolled back.
On the next page,
there's some python code that tries to
insert a row into a table,
but it doesn't commit.
It then reconnects and
tries to find that row, but
that row has been rolled back.
Try running the code as it is, and
then add the commit call in the right
place to make the changes get saved.