This first line of text
is the log in message.
When a new terminal is
opened it's common for
some informational
message to be printed.
The exact contents of this message
depends on the particular system you
are using and how it's configured.
On the next line we
see a command prompt.
The appearance of a command prompt
can vary from computer to computer.
But in this case it
includes my username and
the name of the computer
I'm logged into.
You might have noticed that there's
actually more than one prompt
on the screen at the same time,
this top one and the bottom one.
This first prompt is one I used
earlier to run a command, so
this is the previous prompt.
The command I ran earlier was cowsay.
You can see I entered the command here,
and
below that is the opposite
of the command.
Some terminal commands are pretty
cryptic, but in this case,
cowsay is pretty self explanatory.
It takes one argument,
the name of the string which
you would like your cow to say.
After the output of the cowsay command,
we get a new prompt for
entering the next command.
And finally the last interface
element on the screen, is the cursor.
You'll probably notice the cursor
doesn't quite look like the ones
you've seen in other programs.
For instance in a web browser or
word processor,
the cursor is usually a vertical bar.
In the terminal is usually a block, but
you might also see it as
an underscore in some cases.