So far we've looked at code
snippets floating in isolation.
In this video we'll look at how
the code fits within an Android map.
Well, since EarthquakeAsyncTask
is its own class,
why don't we use a separate Java file?
Once we perform a network request for
the earthquake data and
get back our result and our
onPostExecute, we want to update the UI.
But how can we get a reference to
the views on-screen to update?
Those views are part of the layout
that we set in MainActivity.
In Java, it turns out that
we can actually declare
the EarthquakeAsyncTask As
an inner class.
That means the whole
AsyncTask class definition
could go inside the MainActivity
class definition.
An inner class like EarthquakeAsyncTask
holds an implicit reference to
the outer MainActivity class.
An instance of
the EarthquakeAsyncTask class
can only exist within an instance
of the main activity.
Or in other words,
there is no EarthquakeAsyncTask
without an enclosing main activity.
There are some real memory
risks associated with this,
which we'll cover later in this lesson.
But for now know that as an inner class,
the EarthquakeAsyncTask instance can
access any global variables and methods
from the closing MainActivity instance.
For example, in the MainActivity,
if we declare a global variable for
the TextView that shows the strength
of the earthquake, we can refer to
the TextView in the AsyncTask
onPostExecute method to update the text.
Another reason you may choose to declare
something as an inner class of another
class, is to keep your code
condensed and with fewer Java files.
This is particularly useful if
the two classes are closely related.
For example, the EarthquakeAsyncTask
is only ever used in the MainActivity,
so we can make the EarthquakeAsyncTask
a private class instead of a public one.
Now I'll hand it over to Chris to walk
you through an example with real code
instead of horizontal black lines.
>> With the sample I'm
about to show you,
hopefully you'll start to see how all
the concepts we've been talking about in
the last few videos come together.
This is the code in the project for
the network connect app,
which is one of the sample apps
available in Android Studio.
To get to it earlier I went to
the File menu, selected New,
and then selected Import Sample.
Here you'll find a UI to browse all the
sample code available on Android Studio.
As you can see you have a bunch of
sub-menus here separated by topic,
things like Android TV, code samples
about doing background work.
But I'm going to go ahead here and
use the search bar and look for network.
And cool, underneath the connectivity
menu, the second item
here is the network connect app, which
is what we're going to talk about now.
So the network connect app is meant to
fetch the first 500 characters of raw
HTML from the Google.com website.
When we click the Fetch Menu
button the app goes ahead and
makes a network request
on a background thread.
And we'll see the raw HTML
response appear in the text view
in the bottom half of the screen.
Let's go ahead and look behind
the scenes at how the code is written.
Here we see that the download
task is a sub-class of AsyncTask.
It calls the load from network method,
which performs a network request and
converts the resulting input string,
which is just an arbitrary string of
data, into a string
response that it returns.
Now if you noticed,
the download class is actually declared
as an inner class of the MainActivity.
That means that the full download class
definition is actually located between
the opening closing braces of the
broader MainActivity class definition,
we'll see the implications
of this later.
And when the app launches,
the main activity is created, and
here we can see the layout is set up.
When the Fetch button is pressed
in the options menu, a new
download task is created, and then the
execute method is called on that task,
passing in the Google.com website
as a URL, as a parameter.
Now let’s examine the download
task more closely.
As mentioned before,
we subclass AsyncTask and
then specify three generic parameters.
We specify the string data type for
the first parameter which is the input
to the background method, then we use
Void for the progress parameter, because
we don’t actually report incremental
progress updates to the UI in this case.
The key giveaway is there's
no actual onProgressUpdate
callback implemented here.
And lastly we have a string data type
for the result of the doInBackground
method which is also passed in as
the input to the onPostExecute method.
So looking more closely at the
doInBackground method, which is called
when we first execute the task, we go
ahead and we expect a variable number
of string input arguments which
are stored in the array called URLs.
Then in the call to load from network,
we actually extract the first element
in the URLs array using the zero index.
We then load data from the network.
Again, notice that the load from network
definition is actually outside of
the opening and
closing braces of the download task.
Now normally,
we can't call private methods or
variables in a different class, but,
since download task is actually
an inner class, this is acceptable.
Now after the background work is
complete, the string response is
actually returned as the result
of the doInBackground method.
After this method is executed, the
system calls the onPostExecute method,
passing in the string result,
then we log the message.
There's actually special behavior in
this sample that makes the log fragment
work, which displays the system
log messages on the screen.
So when you call log.i or
log.v to log messages,
The output will be shown in the bottom
half of the screen in our app as well.
You won't need to use
the log fragment in your app,
but this is a helpful class for samples.
Anyways the key takeaway is in
the AsyncTask onPostExecute method
we take the response from the background
thread and update the UI.
Now that you've seen how an AsyncTask
can be declared as an inner class
of an activity, you're going to
have the chance to do the same
by writing your own subclass of
AsyncTask in the Digifield app.