When we put an app on
the Google Play store,
we'll have a whole range of users.
It's hard to anticipate what type of
device our app will be running on.
Maybe a phone or a tablet, maybe an
older version of the Android platform or
maybe a different language
than what we're using.
There are many best practices that
you can follow when building your app
to make it work well for
all these types of users.
One best practice is
to localize your app.
There's a handy localization
checklist that you can refer to.
Localization means adapting your app to
different locales, meaning language and
country combinations to make it
a positive user experience for
all types of users.
At the surface level, this can have
an impact on the design of your app
as well as the texturing
that appear in your app.
For now, we're going to focus on how
we can make your app support different
languages.