So imagine at a point, you compute one of these scale and variant functions like
average intensity, over a range of neighborhood sizes, okay?
So, we're, we're at a single point and
we're computing this function f over different region sizes.
And you'll notice that, well it goes down, and then it goes up, and
then it goes down again.
So that's my function that I computed over different region sizes, all right?
Now, let's suppose in my next picture I shrink the thing down by half.
Well now, as I compute that same function over the same region sizes,
two, four, eight, 16, right?
It's going to take the same shape, but it's going to get there faster.
Which is why this function is essentially just a squashed version of
the one on the left.
But it's the same function, just squashed.
Ha.
Well, what that means is, suppose we pick the maximum of that function.
I'm going to call that S1 in the, in image 1 on the left.
And I take the same function and I'm at some other point.
I'm same, same function on the point of the second image.
If I were to take the maximum there, it would be a different size, right?
Because that image had been squished in half.
That would be S2.
But these two neighborhood sizes would be covering the same
region of the image between the two pictures.
So they would be matching scales.
So, the important thing is, I do each one of these things independently.
That is, I do this thing and at this particular point,
I find my maximum function my, my maximum of the function.
I say that's the natural scale size that I'm going to use.
Then I come over here and I go to my other image.
And I do over here, and
I'm at some interest point, remember we found our interest points.
And I look over all these different region sizes, and I say, aha!
This is the scale there, and I compute that function, and
magically, these two scales correspond.
These are the same chunk of image.
Here's a very nice illustration of that.
Here's a picture of probably some beautiful church on the inside here,
it says white and
gray, in some church, in some mountainous area in Europe I'm going to guess.
And you'll notice that there's a function here that we're computing,
that's a function of scale and here it is, and this is the maximum point.
And this circle is meant to reflect the scale size of that maximum.
Here we have that same image zoomed way out, computing at this interest point,
so we've got the same interest point.
So, notice that this interest point is just sitting at the top of
this little chimney thing here.
We compute the function again, and
again, we take the maximum, and that's going to be this circle.
And the really cool thing, is that this circle, and this circle,
are the same components of the image.
Those are the two scales to operate at.
If we want to find descriptors that match, that's coming later.
Basically, the scale of my detectors in one image should be big and
in the other image should be small.
Also the scale of my my descriptors and my detectors.