So I'm back in dev tools, and
one of the things you can do is hit
escape on your keyboard and it brings up
this extra menu here with Console,
Search, Emulation, and Rendering.
We're interested in
the rendering options.
What I'm going to do is switch on
Show Composited Layer Borders.
When it's switched on,
the page will show you a grid.
These light blue lines represent
the tiles that each layer is split into.
But as developers,
there's nothing we can do about that.
It's just how the browser
chose to split up the layer.
But the interesting ones
are these orange boxes here,
which you can see around the circles.
These orange boxes are elements that
are on their own composited layer.
So how, then,
do we make one of these layers?
Seems like it might be pretty useful.
Well, there are ways that
virtually every browser uses and
some are hackier than others.
Let's start with a newer, not hacky way.
In Chrome and Firefox you can
use the will-change CSS property
to tell the browser to
expect visual changes.
It can then choose to put the element
on a new compositor layer.
In this case we have, will-change
transform, and that tells the browser
that we intend to change the elements
transform at some point.
And so to prepare for that,
it creates a new layer.
Instead of transform, you could also
put left, top, width, or height,
or any visual property.
But even if the browser's
expecting those changes,
it would still have to run layouts and
paint for them.
So the forewarning that you plan
to change them won't actually
yield much improvement.
The benefit of will-change transform
comes because creating new layers
can be expensive because they need
to be created and then painted.
And doing that on the fly
can be expensive.
For older browsers, and Safari,
you'll need to use something
like a 3D transform.
In fact, a transform of translate z zero
is the most common form of this hack.
It's called the no transform
hack by most people.
And it applies a 3D transform,
pushing the element in Z
space by absolutely nothing.
It's enough though to persuade
the browser to create a layer.
In a production environment,
you'll probably need both transform,
translate z zero, and
will-change transform.
You shouldn't use hacks unnecessarily.
But today, not all browsers support
will-change, so you may well need to.
The null transform hack
forces the browsers hand.
But will-change is a hint that
the browser can ignore, and
that gives the browser more options.
It's better to let the browser
decide what to do where you can.
With will-change of giving it the hint,
but
letting it decide what to do with it.