Distribution is by far the most
important of the stack views properties.
Through this property, you can control
the way the views are displayed
along the axis of the stack view.
There are two groups of
distribution algorithms.
Those that try to preserve
the size of the views, and
those that will try to preserve
the spacing between the views.
Let's start with them.
Equal spacing does its best not to
change the intrinsic size of a view.
Instead, it will distribute
the views along the available space
with an equal separation between them.
Of course, if there is not enough space,
it will reduce the size of the views
starting by those that have
the lowest compression resistance.
If all the views have the same
compression resistance,
which is pretty common by the way, it
will shrink the first one from the left.
Equal centering is similar
to the previous one.
Instead of measuring the separation
from the edges of the views,
it measures them from their center.
If your views have very different sizes,
it might look good.
Otherwise, I would stay away from it.
There's not a lot of difference
between these two algorithms.
Let's check out the other group.
Fill equally.
This one divides all
the available space in
equal chunks among the available views.
It if has to change the intrinsic
content size, then it will go ahead.
Fill proportionally.
If the size of the views doesn't
match the available space,
it will change the size of the views.
However, it will do it while keeping
the compression resistance and
hugging priority in mind.
This one is pretty tweakable as you
can change which view gets squeezed or
expanded by changing the compression
resistance and the hugging priority.
The last one, fill,
is similar to the previous one.
But when it comes to changing a view
size, it shows some preference.
It will always try to change the first
view, and this is a default value.
Let's wrap it up before moving to Xcode.
By far,
the most important property of a stack
view is the distribution algorithm.
They are several distribution
algorithms, and at this point,
you don't have to worry about
remembering exactly each one of them.
What you should remember is that some
try to change the size of the views,
the fill ones, while others will try to
change the separation between the views,
the equal ones.
Fill proportionally is perhaps the most
tweakable where you can easily change
which view gets the squeeze or expanded
by playing around with the compression
resistance and the hugging priority.
And fill is the default.