The last bit of work we need to do is to
pass what we've typed in the edit text
to the child activity.
Open this exercise that's titled
passing data between activities and
follow along.
The first thing we'll need to do
inside the main activity is to
store the contents of
the edit text into a string.
I'll do that here inside
the button click listener so
that it happens when I click the button.
And I'll store it in
a string called textEntered.
Now to send that string to
the child activity let's check out
the documentation on the intent
to find out what we could use.
If you open the intent documentation
in the Android Developers website,
you'll find this method putExtra.
What it does, is it stuffs
this data that we want to pass
into this envelope or the intent rather.
The intent extras store
data as key value pairs.
You can store primitives like characters
or numeric types, strings, or
even complex objects, but we'll talk
more about those later in this course.
In our case, the data we want to send
to the child activity is a string.
But we need to come up with a key or
a name to be able to retrieve
that string on the other side.
This is what the first
parameter in putExtra is.
The second parameter is what
data you want to pass through.
For the key or the name you could
come up with your own string or
you could use one of the constant
strings defined in the intent class.
In our case here,
I'll use the string that is defined as
EXTRA_TEXT inside the intent class.
This makes our code a lot cleaner,
and easier to understand.
And then I'll pass in the textEntered
string I just created.
And just like before we start
the activity with that intent.
Now if we try to run the app,
it will start with the new activity, but
nothing gets updated, so let's fix that.
In our child activity, after getting
a reference to the text view,
we need to get the intent
that created this activity.
So that we could retrieve
the data that was passed in it
pretty much like opening the envelope.
If we go back to the documentation
of intent, we'll see that the method
getStringExtra would retrieve
a string using the string name.
This is what we need to extract
the extras from the intent.
However, we shouldn't
immediately call it.
Activities always have an intent
which triggers to stop that activity.
Even in the earlier exercises an intent
was being created for a child activity.
But it didn't have any data in it.
So you shouldn't assume that
every intent has extra data and
always check if it does.
Otherwise, your app might crash.
To do that, we use the function
hasExtra, which returns either true or
false.
And if it's true,
we call the getStringExtra on the intent
to retrieve that string and
then set that text view with that text.