Okay, how do we figure this out?
Suppose you were sending a message
of just one word instead of n.
That is, suppose n=1.
Then the time would be
this fixed startup time
plus the time to traverse all
the links which is t(P-1).
Now suppose instead of sending one word,
we're actually sending two words.
So we'd pay the startup time,
little a, as before.
Then the first word would hit
the network and find its way to node 1.
Eventually, it arrives.
Then in the second step,
word 1 continues to node 2,
while the second word starts
its way from 0 to node 1.
Now this step and
this step happen simultaneously, so
we only see the cost of this step.
And this continues.
Eventually, the first
word makes it all the way
down the network to the destination.
The second word always
lags one step behind.
So what does that mean?
That means to send two words, we pay
the same cost as sending one word,
plus an additional T units of time for
the second word to go the last hop.
I think you can see how this would
work for n = 3, n = 4, and so on.
So for any n, there's the time to
send the first word plus the time for
the remaining words to
arrive at the destination.
Let me reorganize this
algebraically into this form.
Now this formula has three terms.
There's one that depends on P, and
there's one that depends on n.
And then of course,
there's the startup time.
So let's interpret these.
The first term is just
the message startup overheard.
What about the second term?
In practice,
the time t effectively measures the
message transmission time along a link.
So you can interpret the second
term as a kind of wire delay
in going across the network.
And finally, the third term captures
a dependence as a function of
a message size.
And as it happens, even when P is very
large, let's say tens or hundreds
of thousands, it's actually still small,
or only comparable to little a.
Little a is typically associated
with a software overhead for
preparing messages for delivery.
In fact, a is typically many
orders of magnitude larger than t.
So we typically treat these two terms
as being effectively a constant.
That's what becomes alpha
in our alpha-beta model.
And then beta is something that's
sort of proportional to one over t.
Anyway, this is a really rough analysis.
The textbook actually has
a more detailed explanation.
So head to the instructor's notes for
our reference.
My hope is that if Alpha-Beta
seemed mysterious before,
hopefully you have a little bit
better of an intuition for it now.