For this first question,
we're backing up some files from the www
directory to the backup directory.
Since we're making a copy, we'll use cp.
The destination of the cp
command will be backup,
since we want all the copies of
the files to land in that directory.
Be aware, though,
that this command will only work if
the backup directory already exists.
Cp doesn't create
directories on its own.
All right, so
what goes between cp and backup?
Well, the files we want are in www, so
we'll start with that
as a relative path.
We only want the files
though that end in html.
So we'll use *html to specify that.
All right, so the complete
command is cp www/*html backup.
We're copying the files that end
in html to the backup directory.
Okay, so
in this second question we want to list
every file that ends in jpg or png.
We can list files with ls, but
matching just those two file name
endings is a good job for globbing.
Jpg and png are two options,
so we can put them in curly
braces with a comma in between.
To match the rest of the file name,
we put a star in the front.
This is another way that'll work.
This just lists all the jpgs and
then all the pngs.
And this is one more solution.
Since jpg and png both end in g,
we can factor out the g.
This is basically equivalent to our
first solution, but is pretty silly.
I wouldn't really use this in practice.
Okay, our final task is
to print short names
followed by all the one character
filenames in the current directory.
The glob pattern to match a single
character is the question mark, so
we'll start with that.
The command to print to
the command line is echo, so
that's what we'll begin
the command with.
The last part of this command is
the string to print, Short names colon.
You could put quotes around the string
if you want to, but you don't have to.
If this string had
funny characters in it,
though, you'd want to escape those
with a backslash or single quotes.