Bugs that don't crash your program can
be a lot trickier than the ones that do.
When the function calculates
an incorrect value, finding out where it
went wrong often involves splitting
the function up into smaller pieces and
looking at what the values or
variables are in each of these pieces.
One basic way to do this is to
introduce print statements that help
put the variables where
you can see them.
So here's a piece of code that removes
the substring from a longer string.
For instance, if we call remove on
audacity and a, we get udacity.
The way this works is it finds
the location of the substring
in a longer string and
the length of the substring.
And it uses those to extract the part
of the longer string before and
after the location of the substring.
And it glues them together
part_before and part_after and
it returns the result.
So this can remove a substring
from the beginning or the end or
in the middle of a longer string,
like so.
But sometimes it does
pretty weird things,
like remove do from ding and get dining.
Is this function just doomed?
Try finding out where it's going wrong.
Looking at the values of some of these
variables in the middle here might
be a good strategy.
Try adding some print statements
to look at these variables and
see what you can find.