Just like Firebase Realtime Database,
Firebase Storage provides a set of
security rules, so that you can
authorize access to storage.
Let's consider an example.
Friendlychat storage contains photos,
and these photos were meant
to only be sent to other Friendlychat
users and not the whole world.
What might happen if anyone
could see all of your photos,
maybe even change them?
What if you wanted to share a video
of your top secret prep technique for
your award winning recipe for peach
cobbler, and you wanted to only share it
with your family, but
instead the whole world got to see it?
Users expect that you
will protect their data.
Firebase Storage security gives you
the tools to keep their data safe,
as well as limit what kind
of data can be stored.
By now,
you know why data security matters, so
let's take a look at how
Firebase Storage rules work