So I told you before that nobody actually uses average intensity.
All right?
So what will we use?
Well, let's think a little bit about what it means to be a good function for
scale detection, all right?
Basically what you want is you'll be able to find these maxima as a function of
the region size.
Okay, so it would be bad if for
large variation of region side basically the function stayed flat.
That would be bad.
Another thing would be something that wiggled too much.
It's only three wiggles here.
Imagine, there were a lot of wiggles because we'd like to find the maximum and
we'd like to find really just you know,
one or a really key maximum that we can pull out.
So you know this becomes your ideal functions and it's sort of a, a,
a cartoon of the function there.
So, the functions that people use.
What you want is one that, you know, responds nicely to contrast.
Right? Because the idea is, you know, you're going to have edges at some scale.
Oh yeah, remember that?
Right, so edges occur at some scale.
And if you were operating at the right scale you'd get this nice sharp contrast.
And if you were, as you got away from that a little bit, it would fall, and
if you got too far, it would fall down on the other side.
So there's going to be something having to do with contrast, or
finding points of high contrast.
What are points of high contrast?
Remember edges?
Okay?
So in fact, some of the detector operators that people use are just applying,
remember kernels?
And these are the kernels like when we apply differential operator kernels.
We just apply a kernel to the image and use the output.
Now one that people sometimes use and we actually talked about this.
This Laplacian of Gaussian.
When we talked about edge detection we said well,
in the first derivative, there is two directions you could do.
You could do an x and a y.
And then we said, well if you have to worry about the second derivative there's
all sorts of challenges.
But we mentioned something called the Laplacian of Gaussian.
The Mexican hat operator, right?
And this was this one and the equation is written here.
I actually pulled out my own MATLAB here and
made a little 3D plot of what it looks like, and here this shows you.
It's an operator which essentially is a second derivative operator, and
we talked about zero crossings.
Go back and, and, review the property of what we did on edge detection and
you'll see it there.
So that's the type of operator that you could use.
Now, something that we didn't really talk about.
Instead of doing this whole Laplacian of Gaussian which involves these sort of
annoying second derivatives, there's a cute little trick you can do.
And that's called a Difference of Gaussians.
And that's what's written here, is basically if you take out of one Gaussian,
and you subtract from it another Gaussian with a slightly different,
or some factor different sigma, you get a curve.
And what's plotted here in the red is the difference of Gaussian, and
in the blue is the actual Laplacian.
And you see that the values are almost the same.
So if we're doing the work here,
it's a lot easier since you're completing these Gaussians anyway.
So just subtract things.
One of the things also is that these Gaussian the the difference of
Gaussians to solpacean is circularly symmetric.
So it's totally invariant with respect to orientation.
Okay so as you rotate your image, nothing changes.
And it says that it's invariant to scale.
What that means is if I, it's just like it's a scale and variant function
before, if I blow up the function and then I make my operator that much bigger.
I'll get back the same value that I had before.