So at this point you may be thinking, another middleman class?
Why would I want to take the time to create this?
Well, app developers create content providers for a few reasons.
Reason number one, as an extra level of abstraction,
they allow developers to change the underlying data source without needing to
change any code in the applications that access the content provider.
The second reason, some important Android classes such as SyncAdapters, Loaders,
and CursorAdapters use content providers.
So, if you want to use these classes,
you need the data accessible through a content provider.
But really the main reason that you use a content provider is to open up
the data source to other app developers so that they can access, use and
modify your data source, which, if you didn't use a content provider,
would otherwise be just limited to your app.
And while other apps are using your content provider to access your data,
they're doing it in a secure and
managed way because you chose to use a content provider.
So let's see how this helps in the business card example.
Here we have our business card.
Now, if we weren't using the contacts content provider,
we might store our data in a separate database.
This is no good because the default contacts app can't access your
data over here.
So instead, what we do is use the contacts content provider and
give the business card information to the content provider,
which then updates the data source for contacts and saves it to the database.
Then, when the default contact app loads up the contact information,
it'll get the information from your business card.
And really, all you had to do was pass off your business card information to
the content provider.
This whole process was black boxed from you, so it's easy.
As a developer, all you need to do is change a couple of app permissions and
add maybe one line of code.