For the first one, no.
Remember, micro-optimizations
really aren't that helpful.
For the second one, not quite.
While it may seem like a good
idea to execute JavaScript
on a 16 millisecond schedule,
this doesn't necessarily guarantee that
JavaScript is always executing at
the right time for each frame.
The third one isn't right either.
You need to make sure that JavaScript
is done as early as possible,
because it can lead to style
calculations, layout, and paint.
In fact, this answer doesn't
even really make sense,
because the frame is done
when the pixels are painted.
So, the last answer is correct.
The beginning of every frame is
definitely the best time to run
JavaScript because remember,
it can create style, layout, paint and
compositing changes.
And finishing JavaScript early means you
have as much time as possible to take
care of everything else.
In the next video, you will learn about
request animation frame which is an API
that will schedule your JavaScript to
run at the right point of every frame.