I created the brick warehouse
service with Yeomen,
then I injected the service
into both controllers.
Since both controllers now have
access to the warehouse service,
I extracted and combined each store's
brick data into the warehouse.
The Bricks A Bunch store
only sells red bricks, so
I connected the store's red
bricks with the warehouses.
The Lots O Bricks store
sells all bricks, so
I connected each color to
the warehouse's color.
I decided to keep these names so
that I don't have to modify
anything in the template.
Everything's the same now except that
the inventory levels are shared between
the two stores.
Now I need to add that
Add To Cart button.
In the Bricks A Bunch template, I added
a button that calls the controller's
addToCart method, passing in the size.
The controller just passes
this data to the service.
Since the service is shared
by both controllers,
when one controller changes the shared
data, the other controller sees
the change and its template is updated
to reflect the new stock level.
Services are a great way for
two different views to share
a common source of information.