All right,
let's look at this first pair.
In this case, cd../otter means go up
to the parent directory of the current
working directory and
then go to the otter folder.
So that means we go up a directory and
then to the otter folder.
So here we're actually just cding
to the directory we're already in.
The second cd command is cd /home/otter
which is just the absolute path.
So these two commands are equivalent.
Onto the next pair.
cd ./www, dot means the current
working directory and www means we're
going to look for a folder or a file
called www in the current directory.
So this one right here.
This next command, cd www just looks for
the file inside the current working
directory which is the same thing.
So this pair also matches.
Let's look at this pair, cd ../www.
This will look in the working
directory's parent directory for
a folder called www.
That's not even in the file tree though.
Compared to the second command,
cd ./www which is the equivalent
to what we just saw.
So these commands do not match.
This last pair of commands
are equivalent though.
Cd ../../usr goes to the grandparent
directory of the current
working directory.
And then heads down to /usr,
which is equivalent to using
this absolute path cd /usr.
In this case,
the relative path isn't any shorter or
more convenient than the absolute path,
but they're still equivalent.
So we'll check it off.