Awsome, so you have identified all the SQL
satements we need for the App, And once again,
there are first, creating, we need to insert a new pet into the database,
and we also need to insert dummy pet data into the database.
Next for the reading actions,
we'll need to read a list of
all the pets in the shelter.
As well as read a single
pet's detail by its id.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
As with update actions,
we'll need to update a single
pet's details by its id number.
And lastly for delete, we'll need to
delete a single pet using its id,
as well as delete all
the pets in the database.
Now in addition to these actions,
you will need to learn how to setup a
database and the tables within your app.
But luckily you've already
learned how to do this.
So as you learn about the statements,
I'll be highlighting them and
adding them to an SQLs cheat sheet which
you'll get at the end of this lesson.
Now you'll learn a few other
fact in the course, but
understand that the SQL code to do
these commands are the most important.
Now, let's dive in and
learn how to select and
insert pets into the database, as well
as view all the pets in the database.
So let's take a look.
So the first command we'll be
learning is the SELECT command.
And remember this is synonymous
with reading from the database.
Notice that we can specify
parameters such as which column and
which table we'll want to select from.
And here's an example of
that statement at work.
So we've updated the general
version of the selection statement,
to indicate which columns and
which table we want to select from.
So this command specifically
selects all the rows and
all the columns within
the pets database table.
Now let's break this apart and
see what it means.
So SELECT is what we're trying to do.
And this asterisk here,
sometimes called a wild card,
is a special short cut here
meaning all rows and all columns.
Next we have FROM which designates
what table we are going after.
And in this case, we want to
take a look at the pets table.
Remember, in more complicated scenarios
there could be multiple tables
within a database.
Just as there could be more
complicated spreadsheets,
when there are often multiple pages of a
spreadsheet within a larger spreadsheet.
So this command is analogous to
selecting a list of all the pets
in the shelter.
And I'll be adding that
to our cheat sheet that you'll
find later in the lesson.
So here I am in the Command Prompt
in sqlite3 program, and
I'm inside the shelter database.
And I have one table on that database,
the pets table.
So let's try using that SELECT
command that we just learned, and
select all columns from our pets table.
And with a semicolon and hit Enter.
And as expected, well there's
nothing in our pets table just yet.
So let's go ahead and add a pet.
So we can think of adding a pet like
adding a road to a spreadsheet.
And here's our new arrival, Tommy.
As you can see in this spreadsheet,
Tommy is a he, and
he weighs 4 kilograms, and
his breed is a Pomeranian.
So the command we need to put him as
a row in an SQLite database is this
right here.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So INSERT.
An inserting says that
we need to add a row
into the name of the table that we want.
So following that,
and the parentheses here are the columns
that we want to add data to.
And afterwards,
we have the keyword VALUES,
followed by the corresponding values
we want to insert into those columns.
So specifically, for our Tommy example,
we write it something like this.
So here I'm inserting into
the pets table, and for the column
id I'm inserting 1, and this is because
by default id's usually start by one.
And I'm inserting his name, Tommy,
breed Pomeranian, gender 1,
which corresponds to male,
and weight of 4 kilograms.
So now with this command,
we've added Tommy into our database.
Now here's an exercise to help you
practice using the SQL insert command
within the table.
In this scenario, Nina just
brought a cat named Garfield, and
entered his pet information below.
What I like you to do is to write
the code in your database to correctly
insert Garfield with
all of his information.
Two, go ahead and
change the mode to .ascii,
and then paste that result from
selecting all the pets and
all the columns from the database,
into this text box here.
And so this is given that Tommy from the
previous video has already been added
in the row id 1.