Step one for the findARestaurant
function was to geocode the location
into latitude and longitude coordinates.
Using the getGeocodeLocation
function I previously created,
I can simply call it here, and store the
coordinates in latitude and longitude.
I can now build the URL to
access the Foursquare API.
Passing in the necessary Foursquare
client ID, client secret, latitude,
longitude and
meal type to query the search.
I send off the request using the HTTP
library, like I did with geocoding, and
store the response in
the result variable.
By exploring into the result object and
then going into response and then
venues, and finding the zeroth item,
I found the first restaurant
of my query to Foursquare.
And then extract important information
about that restaurant as well, here.
I enclose this declaration inside
an if statement to make sure at least
one result was found.
The venue_id will be necessary
to find pictures taken in that
particular restaurant.
And the name of the restaurant
is always helpful.
The address of the restaurant
is a list that breaks up
each part of the restaurant,
such as the street, state, and
country into a different entry.
I want to make my address
one long string, so
I'm going to loop through the values and
catenate them into an address string,
separated by spaces and
then update my restaurant address.
Now I need to create another API
request to the photos API in Foursquare
in order to grab a photo
from the restaurant.
The venue ID gets passed in
along with the client ID and
client secret in order to
communicate with this API.
Some results can contain
multiple images, and
other results can contain no images,
so my code needs to account for that.
If images are available, I can
retrieve the first one by referencing
the zero index value of
this entry in my response.
As stated in the foursquare
documentation,
this image contains a prefix and
suffix string.
Between the two sub strings I can append
dimensions for scaling the image.
So I'm going to make it 300 by 300.
And save this as the image URL variable.
If no images were found,
I will just use this stock photo
of a cheeseburger in its place.
I'm now going to create a dictionary
that contains the restaurant name,
address, and image.
I'll print these results so
that they're in an easily readable
format from the terminal, and
also return the restaurant info.
Outside of my if statement,
I can now handle the case that
no restaurants were found.
I'll just make a print statement
saying no restaurants found, and
return a string saying
the same thing for now.
Now if I save and run my code, the find
a restaurant method is called on several
different meal types and locations,
which I can see from my terminal.
Code for this section is
available in the instructor notes.