Xcode is a very powerful integrated
development environment. And it may feel
a bit overwhelming at first, but that's
completely ok. Let me show you one of the
features of the interface builder part
of Xcode that will make your life a bit easier.
Here on the left side of the
interface builder is what's called the
document outline. Here I’m looking at a
completed version of Pitch Perfect just
so that you can see a full scope of what
the document outline can do. Your version
of the Pitch Perfect app won't have any
of these UI elements just yet. I’ll use
this bar to drag out a little bit more
space. And in the document outline, we can
see a View Controller called the Record
Sounds View Controller. And if I click
the disclosure triangle, we can see its
corresponding view and UI elements like
buttons and labels. Clicking any of the
disclosure icons will show you what's
contained within. If you're looking for
an easy way to find and work with UI
elements, the document outline is the
place to go. Here I’ve selected the
record button or I could select this
recording label and so forth.
Working with the document outline will
become extremely beneficial once your
app starts to have more than just a few
buttons and labels.