Welcome back.
So far we've talked about AI
as managing complexity and uncertainty.
We've seen how a search can discover sequences
of actions to solve problems.
We've seen how probability theory
can represent in reason with uncertainty.
And we've seen how machine learning
can be used to learn and improve.
AI is a big and dynamic field
because we are pushing against complexity
in at least 3 directions.
First, in terms of agent design,
we start with a simple reflex-based agent
and move into goal-based and utility-based agents.
Secondly, in terms of the complexity of the environment,
we start with simple environments
and then start looking at partial observability,
stochastic actions at multiple agents, and so on.
And finally, in terms of representation,
the agents model of the world
becomes increasingly complex.
And this unit will concentrate
on that third aspect of representation,
showing how the tools of logic
can be used by an agent to better model the world.