Next question is related to correctness,
and we know size and
correctness don't go together.
Larger the size, harder it is going
to be for us to do it correctly.
So, we sort of go back in time,
saying, start with MS Dos,
to the more recent Windows operating
system, they offer richer functionality.
They are much more complex as a result.
So the question is really rough estimate
of the multiplier, the lines of codes.
I'm going to assume that lines
of code in some sense capture
the complexity of a system and the
larger the system is more complex it is,
more lines of code it's going to have.
So, multiplier is x if
recent Windows OS is x
times the number of lines of code and
the recent Windows operating system is
x times that the lines
of code we had in DOS.