All right, so we're going to play
around a little bit with this idea of
contraction mappings, but
in a very simplified setting.
We're going to look at,
instead of Q functions,
we're going to look at just scalars,
just real numbers X.
So B is some operator that is applied
to a number and it spits out a number.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And I've defined 4
different kind of Bs here.
And some of them are contraction
mappings and some of them are not.
And we have to figure out by using
the definition of contraction mapping
which are which.
>> Okay.
So let me just make
certain that I have this.
So the way you defined
contraction mapping before,
you said there would be
these two functions.
And you basically want to see if they
get closer and closer to one another.
>> Yep.
>> As you apply the operator.
But here the function is just a thing,
instead of being a Q value with all
these indices, it's just a number.
>> Yeah, you can think of it at
being a single state, single action,
[LAUGH] right.
It's like an MDP that has one state and
one action.
So it's just a number.
>> Okay.
All right, and so I just want to see
if there's some gamma that I can choose
between 0 and 1, inclusive of 0, not
inclusive of 1, that as I apply these
operators X/2 X+1 X-1 and (X+100) *
.9 that will just get smaller and
smaller and smaller and smaller and
closer and closer closer together.
Okay I think I got it.
>> Okay.
>> All right let's do the quiz, go.