So, what are the other types of
video stabilizations available?
Now, of course, there has been a whole
lot of work of doing optical and
in-camera stabilization.
Of course, in this kind of stuff, people
have attempted to stabilize the lens
it's self or basically also adaptively
change the sensor as, for example,
motion happens on a camera.
And for example here, just showing
you two different pictures of how
we can actually stabilize the optics
itself or the sensor to the motion.
And these kind of are being
embedded into the cameras itself.
And again,
you see on high end SLRs and stuff,
they have these types of features.
Sometimes, it can also use the
accelerometer and a gyro, which actually
is becoming even more and more popular,
the newer hand held cameras.
Where actually you can use the fact that
there is a sensor built into the camera
which tells you how fast the camera is
moving and you can use that as a priori
information, a priori information
to remove some of the shutter.
But remember, one of the biggest things
with all of this is that they're
actually there to get rid of
the high frequency percolations.
The shake, because I'm moving the camera
too fast would be the ones that I'd
do it right there.
But basically, also means that they're
looking at a smaller temporal buffer.
In the case that we're talking about,
we'd like to also consider
post-process stabilization,
that is that removes the low
frequency perturbation, large buffer.
So for example, in the case of
the jogger that we saw in the marathon,
the head motion was relatively slow and
that's very kind of
low frequency motions.
And we'd like to get rid of that, that
means we need to keep a bigger buffer.
That can only be done as a post process.
That is after all the video is done,
uploaded or saved,
you run the process on it afterwards.
This can be done actively
in the camera itself.
Another part of it is that if you
do the post-process stabilization,
we can actually use a distributed
computing back-end.
Which basically means, we can actually
spend a lot of compute energy.
This is what I showed you
with the example on YouTube.
It goes to a cloud,
a whole lot of processing is done.
And actually, we get much more
accurate results afterwards.
The biggest advantage of
the post-process stabilization,
of course is can be
applied to any camera.
It doesn't care what,
where the footage came from.
And in fact, you can actually
apply to legacy footage.
Now, of course, stabilization is
something we want to accomplish for
the kinds of videos where we want to
get rid of some of the errors.
And whenever I talk about stabilization
and many people will come and say to me,
oh, and some artistic ways we actually
want to add shake and jitter.
I mean, movies like
Blair Witch Project and Cloverfield,
were ideally designed to actually show
you all of the kinds of motions and
jitters that the director wanted.
We don't want to get rid of
that kind of stabilization.
We're particularly interested
in stabilization of videos from
casual cameras.
So, our goal is to now focus on
this part of the process here.
We're going to talk about
post process stabilization.
But the kinds of techniques I'm going to
talk about with knowledge of more
information from the camera itself
can also be applied to in-camera
stabilization.