The problem with the existing code
is that in the MainActivity onCreate
method, we try to execute the network
request on the main thread.
Now we need to move these two
method calls into an AsyncTask.
The fetchEarthquakeData method call
should be run on a background thread,
whereas this updateUI call
should be run on a main or
UI thread after we received
the earthquake result object.
Okay, let's do some live programming.
First, I'm going to define a subclass of
AsyncTask called EarthquakeAsyncTask.
I'll also define it as a private
inner class of the MainActivity.
Now if the AsyncTask
isn't already imported,
I can use a quick fix shortcut
in Android Studio, Alt+Enter,
to automatically import the AsyncTask
class at the top of the Java file.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
As you can see,
it's been imported up here.
Now as you can see here via
this red squiggly line,
Android Studio is still reporting an
error, so I'm going to use the quick fix
again with Alt+Enter to autogenerate
the methods I need to override.
Go ahead and
select Implement methods, and
then I'll select OK here to implement
the stub for the doInBackground method.
Now let's review the generic
types used here.
I specified the string data type for
the input params
because the string usgs URL will be
the input to the doInBackground method.
I used void for the progress parameter,
because I don't need to continually
update the user on the progress
of this particular task.
For the result parameter,
I specified the event data type
because I want the result of the
background work to be an event object.
Now we can move the fetchEarthquakeData
call directly into
the doInBackground method, but
we still have a few more modifications.
Now, instead of hard coding this test to
only work for this specific USGS URL,
I'll use the input parameter by
accessing the zeroth element of
the URL's array.
That way this EarthquakeAsyncTask
can work for any string URL.
I'll also return the event object
as the return value of
the doInBackground method.
Now we'll also want to override
the onPostExecuteCallback method.
In it, we receive the event object
that was returned earlier here in
the doInBackground method.
Okay, great, we're done defining
the EarthquakeAsyncTask.
I also went ahead and added the comments
to the method and class as well.
Now back here in the MainActivity in
the onCreate method, I now can create
a new task and then call execute on
it while passing in the specific URL.
All right, so let's go ahead and
compile and run the app on a device.
All right, and now look,
our app doesn't crash any more.
Woo-hoo!
As you can see,
the app shows details about a 7.8
magnitude earthquake in Ecuador.
Now 183 people felt it, and on average,
they reported that it felt like a 9.1.
Wow, that's kind of a big earthquake.
Anyhow, if you want to check
out the code that I just wrote,
check out the link below for
the GitHub repository.
If you were able to complete
this exercise, congratulations.
If you weren't, no worries at all.
For someone who just started learning
Java and Android several months or
several weeks ago, making a network call
on a background thread by implementing
callback methods in a subclass of
a class that uses generic types, whoo,
that's a lot of concepts
coming together.
And you should just be proud
of how far you've come.