All right, so we're currently printing
the raw JSON data return from Flickr.
Now we need to deserialize it,
parse it, and
display an image and
it's title to the user.
This process should almost be
identical to what you did earlier in
the Sleeping In The Library app.
But before you dive in, I'm going to
provide you with a handy trick.
In the completion handler, I'm going to
go ahead and define a function for
printing and displaying an error
in case something goes wrong.
Now this function only exists
within the completion handler.
But it can save you a lot of time and
duplicate code for displaying errors.
Feel free to use it in
your implementation.
Now I'm going to leave
the rest up to you.
I know this might seem daunting, but
you should have all the tools to
piece together a solution for this.
To complete this exercise, you need
to take the steps necessary to finish
implementing the
displayImageFromFlickrBySearch method.
First, check if an error was
returned to the completion handler.
If no error is returned, then check for
successful response by looking for
code that begins with a 200.
Of course, if an error did occur,
you'll need to handle it accordingly.
Next you'll want to
deserialize the JSON data and
extract the values needed to select
a random photo, its URL and it's title.
If all goes well, your final
step will be to update the UI.
Remember to use
the performUIUpdatesOnMain
black box that we've given you.
If you get stuck at any point along
the way, you can always go back and
reference the code you wrote in
the sleeping in the library app, or
ask others for help on the forums.
When you're done, check this box.