So I'd like you to take five minutes and
teach me something I don't know yet.
You're allowed to ask me
what I don't know, or
whether I'd be interested in it,
>> Okay.
>> but once you get started I'm
going to watch the clock and
I'm going to cut you
off at five minutes.
>> All right.
>> And
you can use the board if you want.
Whatever you want to teach,
doesn't have to be technical.
>> It doesn't have to be technical.
>> Nope, anything you want.
>> Great.
Yeah, let me teach you about drumming.
Do you know anything about drumming?
>> I don't know anything about drumming.
>> And music, or musicality?
Actually, I used to play taiko.
So it's a Japanese art form,
thousands of years old.
>> Okay.
>> And taiko is actually a really,
really cool art form.
So how it got started, how it like,
pretend that this is Japan [LAUGH].
[CROSSTALK]
>> [LAUGH] Okay.
>> This is Japan here.
This drumming art form is called taiko.
This is a taiko drum and it is,
basically, it's a huge drum.
It's not like your drum kit,
where you find in a western rock band.
>> Okay.
>> It's not like a drum kit where you
have multiple drums.
It's just one big, gigantic drum, and
then you strike with these
big sticks called bachi.
So bachi.
And that is the main form of musicality
in taiko, and the origins of taiko
go back thousands of years and
the main use of taiko was more communal.
So let's imagine that you're a farmer
in a village, and that you need crops.
You need your crops to grow.
So, there's a lot of spiritual,
communal aspect of the taiko, where
actually the taiko player will actually,
during harvest season,
they'll play on the drum.
And they'll wish the gods to rain down
rain on the crops in order for that for
the people to have a bountiful harvest.
Also, if there were times of war, or
times of famine, or
times of when things weren't going well.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Usually,
Japanese people will actually have some
sort of festival to pray to the gods.
And they use these taiko drums to
actually communicate to the gods.
>> Okay.
>> So one god, in particular,
is called Susanoo.
And he's a very rambunctious,
kind of like a thunder god in Japan.
And if you worship Susanoo,
you basically play the drums like
you're really going all out.
The weather, usually the summer
festivals happen in the summer, and
it's very humid.
So you're playing all out
in 98 degree weather,
praying to the god to actually
wish good luck on your village.
And your city, and your people, and
your family to wish good health, and
good prosperity.
And Susanoo is a very rambunctious guy.
The faster and harder you play,
the better chance that you actually
get the blessing from the god.
>> Okay.
>> So,
that's the whole origin,
in a nutshell, of Japan.
So if, we then go into North America,
because I started playing taiko
when I was in college, UCLA.
And this is America now, there you go.
This is America,
>> All Right.
>> America.
And how this got transferred over was,
the history,
was in California here was
the nation of San Francisco.
>> Okay
>> So a man called
Tanaka-Sensei.
In the 1970s, 1960s he actually, sensei.
In the 1960s, 1970s, he went to a cherry
blossom festival in San Francisco.
He knows that this is a Japanese
festival, but there was no taiko.
There was no drum to wish people
good luck into whole people,
to pull the community together.
So, he was like, wait a minute,
this is not right.
So, he actually started his own troop,
own taiko group, and
actually brought the whole
musicality of taiko into America.
>> Cool.
>> And for the next 40 years,
other groups have popped up, and
the big ones are San Jose Taiko,
actually, San Francisco started it.
Number one.
San Jose Taiko started number two,
I think.
And then there's a Buddhist group in
LA started as well, number three.
I'm not sure, I think one,
could be two, could be three.
I'm not sure here, so
I'll need to research that.
But basically three taiko
groups popped up in
California within a span of two years.
And after that,
everything just went viral.
And that's the whole story of taiko
from Japan to America started.
>> Interesting.