We can also add attributes to our GrizzlyBear. And people often wonder how do
you tell the difference between a BlackBear and a GrizzlyBear? There's actually
an easy way, and the difference is based on their behavior. If a BlackBear is
chasing you, and you climb up a tree, the BlackBear climbs up the tree after you
and then, it eats you. If the bear that's chasing you is a GrizzlyBear, the
GrizzlyBear knocks down the tree and then, it eats you. Now, I should warn you,
don't take advice on bears from someone who's sitting in a dark room with
fluorescent lights on his hands. So, this means our GrizzlyBear does not have a
climb_tree attribute, but does have a knockdowntree and also has a chase. And
I should mention when I'm writing the methods here, I'm not including the self
parameter. There's always a self parameter so just to save space, I'm not
including it here. So, here's the code for our GrizzlyBear, which looks a lot
like the code for our BlackBear.