You've probably noticed by now
that we tend to talk about
the current working
directory as where we are.
And we talk about using the cd
command as moving around directories.
This is a really common metaphor.
It doesn't mean that the shell
is a file inside that directory,
it just means that's the part of the
file system that currently has focus.
So by now you've used cd a bit to
navigate around the file system.
But what happens if you try to cd but
give the name of a file
instead of a directory.
Like for instance, there's a file on
your system called ocean slash water.
What happens if you cd to that.
So try to cd to a path
that's not a directory like
the ocean slash water file.
What happens?
Does it create a directory
with the same name?
Does it show the contents of that file?
Does it do nothing?
Does it show an error message?
Or does it crash your Linux box?