So now we have, learned pretty much, all there is to know about Planning Under Uncertainty.
We talked about Markov Decision Processes.
We explained the concept of information spaces;
and what's better, you can actually apply it.
You can apply it to a huge number of problems
where the outcome of states are uncertain.
There is a huge legislation about robot motion planning.
Here are some examples of robots moving through our environments
that use MDP-style planning techniques;
and these methods have become vastly popular in artificial intelligence--
so I'm really glad you now understand the basics
of those and you can apply them yourself.