It's time for an exercise.
This time we'll explore indexes
in your app, and specifically,
we'll look at composite index creation.
We're going to deploy a query
that needs a composite index
without first running it
on the development server.
Then we'll fix it by running it
on the development server and
look at the index file and
deploy and see that it works then.
So, first, let's see what happens if
you deploy an application to app spot
that requires a new index,
but you don't have it.
So we're going to add a filter
to our app, asking only for
conferences in the month of June.
Number six is June.
Once you add this filter,
save your file and
go ahead and
deploy it directly to app spot.
In this case,
do not run it on local host first.
So don't hit the run button
just go straight to deploy.
And once the logs say that your
application has been deployed
go the API's explorer, make sure
that you're on the deployed app and
not local host.
Go to the filter playground method and
execute it.
What happens?