Let's first look at an example in which
we will consider two CPU bound tasks.
So, these are tasks that are mostly
just running on the CPU and
don't perform any I/O.
Let's assume their execution
time is ten seconds, and
in this system let's assume that
the time to context switch from
one context to another
takes just 0.1 seconds.
For this scenario now let's take a look
at what will happen when we consider two
different timeslice values,
timeslice of one second, and
timeslice of five seconds.
With a timeslice of one second, the
execution of these two tasks will look
something as follows, and
let's assume that the thicker vertical
bars are trying to capture this context,
which overhead in this case.
For the timeslice value of five seconds,
the schedule will look as follows.
In the context switch overhead is
only paid at this particular points.
That's in contrast with having to
context switch at every single one of
these vertical bars here.
Now if we compute the metrics for
throughput, average wait time, and
average completion time for these tasks,
we will obtain the following results.
To complete the throughput,
we calculate the total time that it
took to execute these tasks, and divide
it by two, by the number of tasks.
To complete the average wait time,
we look at the start
time of each of the tasks, and
divide that by two, the number of tasks.
And to complete the average
completion time,
we'll look at when each of the two tasks
completed, and then we average that.
And the detailed calculations for both
of these are in the instructors notes.
Looking at these metrics,
we see that for
throughput, we are better off
choosing a higher timeslice value.
For completion time, also, we're better
off choosing a higher timeslice value.
And then for
the average wait time of the task,
we are actually better off
choosing a lower timeslice value.
However, these are CPU bound tasks.
We don't really care about
their responsiveness and
the user is not necessarily going
to perceive when they started.
The user really cares about
when they complete, and
overall when all of the tasks
submitted to the system complete.
So this really means that
CPU bound tasks we're
really better off with
choosing a larger timeslice.
This is the winning combination for us.
In fact, for CPU bound tasks,
if we didn't know timeslicing at all, so
like the timeslice value is infinite,
we'd end up with absolutely the best
performance in terms of the throughput
and the average completion time, so
the metrics that we care for
when we run CPU bound tasks.
Yes, of course, the average wait time of
the task will be worse in that case, but
we don't care about that.
It's CPU bound task.
We won't notice that.
In summary, a CPU bound task
prefers a larger timeslice.