Now that we have discussed how thread structures are separated let's take
a look at an actual Linux kernel implementation in this quiz.
For each of the questions in this quiz we will be referencing version 3.17
of the Linux kernel.
The first one is,
what is the name of the kernel thread structure that's used in Linux?
We're looking for the name of a C structure, basically.
The second question is, what is the name of the data structure,
that's actually contained in the above data structure,
that describes the process that the kernel thread is running?
Again, we're looking for a name of a C structure.
Provide your answers in these text boxes and refer to
the instructor notes that reference the 3.17 version of the Linux kernel.