Okay, so let's say we have
a chain of pizza parlors and
want to put three of them in the city.
We make a study and
realize that the people who eat pizza
the most live in these locations.
So we've decided that we'd like
to put three pizza parlors and
we need to know where
are the optimal places to put them.
Well it seems that the houses
are nicely split into three groups.
The red, the blue, and the yellow.
So it would make sense to put one pizza
parlor in each of the three groups.
But a computer doesn't
know how to do this.
It can't just eyeball the three groups,
we need an algorithm to do it.
So here's an algorithm that'll do it.
Let's start by choosing three random
locations for the pizza parlors.
So they are here, where the stars are.
Now it would make sense to say each
house should go to the pizza parlor
that is the closest to it.
In that case, the yellow houses
go to the yellow pizza parlor.
The blue houses go to
the blue pizza parlor.
And the red houses go to
the red pizza parlor.
But now, look at how far the yellow
houses are from the yellow pizza parlor.
It would make sense to move the yellow
pizza parlor to the very center of its
clientele.
And the same thing for the blue pizza
parlor and the red pizza parlor.
So let's do that.
Let's move each pizza parlor to
the center of its clientele.
But now what happens,
look at these blue houses.
They're now much closer to the yellow
pizza parlor then to the blue one.
So it would make sense for
them to go to the yellow parlor instead.
Let's go ahead and color them yellow.
Same with these red houses over here.
They're closer to the blue
pizza parlor now.
So let's color them blue.
And now again,
it would make sense to move each pizza
parlor to the center of its clientele.
And again, look at this red houses here,
they're closer to the blue pizza
parlor than to the red one.
So let's go ahead and color them blue.
And again, let's send every pizza
parlor to the center of its clientele.
And now we have an optimal solution.
Iterating this process took
us from a random solution
to the ideal one where we have
one pizza parlor at the center of
each of the clusters of houses
where the clients live.
This algorithm is called
K-Means Clustering.
K-Means Clustering is useful when we
have an idea of how many clusters we
want to end up with.
Now I'll leave you with a question.
What if we don't know how many
clusters we want to end up with?