So just to conclude I just introduced a simple concept of pixel layer blending.
As actually you've seen now in the context of the videos that
you've been seeing.
But again, the bottom line is there are many different techniques like this,
widely in use in photography.
For those of you interested.
Just go in to Photoshop, open up the layer mode.
And then, in the layer mode, when you actually have multiple layers,
there is whole bla, you know, layer blending options that'll allow you to
kind of play around and see what the artifacts of each and
every one of them, and what effects you get from each and everyone of them.
again, showcase why some of those videos that you've been seeing.
Are looking up, and they will continue to look up for further information,
you can look at Wikipedia site on blend mods or you can actually look at
the pipeline of udacity videos producted from the blog site that I have listed.
Again,ah, you know start playing around with this kind of stuff using any of
the softwares that we have provided, you should be able to do this kind of
simple additions, and simple multiplications and other types of things.
Again this was an example of us opening a black box, and
that's what we just did for something you've been seeing.
Thanks