So let's do this with a simple example here.
I have two different images.
There are oh, basically two smaller images like this.
And if you notice, of course, there's a lot of similarity.
We want to now find, within these two images, find the overlapping regions that
would allow us to generate a smoother, novel image.
If I put these images next to each other with a little bit of an overlap,
I get a sharp boundary, a vertical boundary.
Of course, I want to get rid of this vertical boundary.
So, let's start looking at the regions.
So this is the overlapping region, between the two images.
I take the two source images and look at the same overlapping region.
This is the overlapping region between them that if I tried to do a simple cut,
that's what it looks like.
Let's look at these two overlapping regions.
If I was to take these two overlapping regions, and
my interest is to do basically looking at the difference between these.
What we can do is look at the, the squared difference between them.
So I take the difference and square it.
So take all of the pixel values from this region,
they're the same size small images, and compute a difference between them.
This would give me a, an image like this.
And within this, if I find the minimum values in this direction
the horizontal direction, I will get a region like this.
These are where the differences are the lowest.
So this basically kind of says,
is now I can take this, and generate a region like this.
And if this was the cut I put in through this overlapping region,
I would get as smooth as possible image like this.
Now if you notice, these two images, you can't see the seam.
So in essence, what we did is we took these two overlapping patches,
create a difference, squared it.
That started giving me a value of where things are.
With in this, I found the minimum error boundary.
Use that minimum error boundary to get enough pixels on the left and
the right, and the overlapping region, and generate a new image.
Okay? A new novel image that has the actual pixels but,
more importantly, now you cannot see the seam.