So now we can start to graphically illustrate this.
So on the left, I have an image I of x, y.
And on the right, I have the new function E of u, v.
Okay? So remember, E is the error.
Okay?
And what we're going to do is we're going to put 0,
0 sort of in the middle, right?
So this goes plus in u and minus in u.
This would be plus in v and minus in v.
All right?
So what if I just leave the square right in the same place?
What if I make u and v be zero?
How much error am I going to get?
Well, none.
Okay?
And so E of 0, 0 is 0.
I'm just subtracting the same image from itself and
that's what this E 0, 0 is meant to show.
Oh, and by the way, just showing you this little pixel here is black.
Why is that black?
Because that's zero, right?
There's zero error E of u, v.
Right?
Error because it's the sum of squares could only give, become more positive.
Right? So at zero, zero it's going to be an error of zero.
So now suppose I move my window just a couple of pixels,
like 3 in the u and 2 in the v direction.
Now my error going to be whatever it is, right?
And over here, right?
You notice this is just a gray value, right?
Because the value is gone higher, right?
So the error grows as I move away and just think for one minute,
suppose that picture were perfectly gray, every pixel is the same value.
That error would be zero at the middle, at zero, zero and
as I moved it, it would still be zero.
So that should give you some idea of where we're headed.
We're looking for points where as I move in u, v,
I get this nice change, no matter how I move in u, v.
Got it?
Cool.