In the last exercise,
we made GigaGal move, but
you may have noticed she
couldn't turn to the left.
Let's fix that.
First of all,
we'll add this facing enum to keep track
of what direction GigaGal is facing.
Then we'll update her facing direction
based on what direction she's moving.
Finally, down in render, we'll draw
either the right facing sprite or
the left facing sprite based
on GigaGal's facing direction.
When you're done,
it should look something like this.
By the way, I don't think she's
passing the cannon from hand to hand.
I think both of her gauntlets
are able to turn into cannons.
But feel free to interpret
that however you want.
Now it's up to you to set up GigaGal for
multi-directional mayhem.