Here's what I was looking for,
log base 2 of L.
By analogy to the size of the index,
reading L words should reveal
about log L bits of information.
Consider the block of L words.
The search key either goes between these
words, or to the left, or to the right.
So, you learn log L bits of the index.
The lower bound then becomes
something like log n over Log L.
You can also write this more
compactly using log rules.
This is the same as log base L of N.
Compare this lower bound against
the bound for nieve binary search.
Remember that was log N over L,
which is the same as log N minus log L.
So compared to the lower bound,
there's about a log L factor difference