Now lets talk a little bit more in depth about interruption signal handling.
Lets start with interrupts.
When a device like disk for instance wants to send the notification to
the CPU it sends an interrupt by basically sending a signal through
the interconnect that connects the device to the CPU complex.
In the past for this we used dedicated wires, but most modern
there's a special message called a message signal interrupter, MSI, that can be
carried on the same interconnect that connects the devices to the CPU complex.
So PC Express, for instance.
Based on the pins where the interrupt occurs or based on the MSI message.
The interrupt can be uniquely identified so we know, based on this information,
exactly which one of the devices generated the interrupt.
Okay, so now the interrupt interrupts the execution of
the thread that was executing on top of the CPU.
And now what?
Now, if the interrupt is enabled only,
based on the interrupt number a table is referenced.
For all the interrupt supported in this system, this table specifies what is
the starting address of the interrupt handling routines?
So, this is the interrupt handler table.
Based on the interrupt number, for instance, interrupt-N in this case.
We look up the starting address of the handler co.
And then the program counter is set to that starting address.
And the execution of interrupt handling link routine starts.
All of this happens in the context of the thread, which was interrupted.
Remember again that which exact interrupts can occur on a platform depends on
the hardware and how they're handled is specified by the operating system.