So, while the writer is executing in this write_phase,
let's say we have another writer that came in.
So this writer is now pending on the read_phase variable.
So, we currently have basically one writer here,
one writer pending on this write_phase.
And let's say we have another writer,
reader that came in and it's pending on this read_phase variable.
So we have two threads that are waiting on two different variables, and
then a writer that's actually in the critical section.
When this writer completes, it starts exiting the critical section.
So it will reset the resource_counter value,
doesn't make sense to decrement, only one writer at a time could,
could be in there so it's either negative 1 or 0.
And then here in this code, we did two things.
We broadcast to the read_phase condition variable.
And we'll signal to the write_phase condition variable.
We signal to the write_phase condition variable again because only one thread at
a time is able to proceed with our write operation.
We broadcast to those threads that are reading on the read_phase.
So potentially multiple threads will be woken up.
Because it makes sense, we allow multiple readers, we allow
multiple threads to be in a read_phase, it makes sense to use the broadcast.
So, let's say that we have multiple readers waiting on the read_phase when we
issued this broadcast.
Now, this phase here requires a mutex.
So, when these threads that were waiting on the read_phase are waking up
from the wait, they will one at a time acquire the mutex,
check is resource_counter negative 1?
No, it is not negative 1, right?
We just reset it to be 0.
So, I'll increment the counter.
So, incrementing the counter, when the first thread wakes up, the first,
the resource_counter will be 1.
And then the first thread of the waiting ones will release the mutex and
start reading the data.
The remaining threads that were waiting on the read_phase will also one at
a time come out of wait statement, check to see whether resource_counter is
negative 1, and now it will have some positive value.
And so, they too will increment the resource_counter and will come out.
So, the waiting threads which were woken up from the broadcast statement
will be coming out of this wait operation one at a time, but
ultimately, we will have multiple threads in the read_phase at the same time.
So, this is why broadcast is useful.
Yes, indeed, only one thread at a time can really be woken,
can really execute this piece of code.
But we do want multiple threads to be woken up so that multiple threads can
ultimately reach this read_phase once this writer completes.
The other thing that's worth noting is here we use both broadcast and signal.
Whether the reader's will be really the first ones to execute, or
the writers, that we really don't have control over.
It really depends on how the scheduler ends up
scheduling these various operations.
So, the fact that we first called broadcast versus signal, this is really just
implicit that the readers are given some kind of priority over the writers.
We have no control over that.