And the answer is, in the first question, two-third. In the second, four-fifth.
Let me explain: Probability of a loaded coin, given that we saw heads, is expanded by base roll in the probability of heads,
given the loaded coin times the prior probability of a loaded coin, divided by the same expression plus the probability of heads
given that we don't have a loaded coin times the probability of no loaded coin.
And if you plug in all the numbers from above, you find the probability of heads, given that it's loaded, is one.
The prior probability of picking that coin is 0.5, and the denominator becomes 0.5 plus the probability of heads with a fair coin
times the prior probability of the fair coin, which is 0.5 times 0.5, is zero 0.25.
And when you work this out, that's the same as two-thirds.
The final question is computed the same way, but using two-thirds of a prior for the loaded coin,
in which case we get one times two-third, as opposed to one times 0.5, divided by two-third plus one half for the probability of heads,
given that this is a fair coin, with a prior probability now just of one-third, because in two-thirds probability you already have a loaded coin.
If you work this out over here, it becomes four-fifth.