So what are the good properties of a Harris Detector?
One, a Harris Detector is rotation invariant.
In this case, basically what that means is that ellipses rotate, but
the shape and the eigenvalues remain the same, if this image is rotated.
And therefore, corner response function R is invariant to rotations.
So in essence, I could take the same thing, rotate it, it'll find the same
Harris Corners as it did when, you know, the image was not rotated.
Intensity invariant which basically means is that if the intensity of
the image changes because of photometric variations and
stuff it's actually not sensitive to it.
So it's basically partially invariance additive and melt, multiplicative
intensity changes because of thresholding that we can do with this.
And it actually supports us being able to deal with highly intense images.
Primarily also again, because we're only looking for derivative information,
that is the derivative change in intensity not just the absolute one.
So in essence, again, you notice, same image.
Now I've increased the intensity but find the same features.
Finally, scaling invariant.
Basically it's dependent on the size of the window we use for matching.
Of course, we can also use different types of
frequency domain analysis using pyramids to help us do matching of that type.