Now here I am in the PetPrvider class,
and let's take a look at the updated
query method. So here I've copy and paste
the query method from the gist, and then
go ahead and implemented to do for the
PETS case. So for the pets case, notice
that we don't use the selectionArgs to
select a single pet like we need to for
the pet ID case, that means we can just
directly call the sqlite database query
method like we do here, providing the
projection, selection, selectionArgs and
any other parameters. And that takes care
of it for the do in the PETS case. Now if
we take a step back,
we noticed that it will go down this path,
this PETS case here, when we call the
providers query method with a general
pet content uri.
Well, now we ask when does this happen
when we call that query method with a
general pet content uri. Now remember
this happens in the catalog activity, so
let's jump over there. From the catalog
activity, we'll grab a cursor of all the
pets like we see here, but currently the
catalog activity create method doesn't
take advantage of the provider logic we
just wrote. And knowing that, in the next
quiz, we'll update the catalog activity to
take advantage of this provider logic
that we just wrote.