So while we now know how a camera, or what's inside a camera,
let's go back to basics and begin understanding what is happening or
what we are trying to do when we take a picture.
What we're trying to do is capture a 3D scene and
create an image of something that can be displayed to a user and,
of course, what we're going to capture is the light in the scene.
In addition to that, what we also want to capture is the 3Dness of the scene.
For example here, there is a lot of geometry in the scene, right?
Which basically is shown in the perspective.
For example, these two train tracks are kind of converging at a point.
I mean this is actually something in the imaging field known
as the vanishing point.
All things like this, if I was to draw a line here on this train track and
another one on this train track,
you kind of see that they're converging far away at some point.
This is basically showing perspective, that is,
things that are farther away appear smaller.
Things that are closer appear you know, larger.
So this distance is large here but, of course, train tracks kind of get smaller.
So what we're trying to capture here is the geometry of a scene.
In addition to that,
we're also trying to capture from a scene varies types of light changes.
So here, of course, a scene just showing sand with water.
You see specularity, you see waves,
you see reflections, you see diffusity of an image and all that kind of stuff.
So, of course,
in this image what we're trying to do is capture all of the light variations.
Besides just the color, the specularities and stuff like that.
So in essence, what we are trying to capture is the light scattering.
So the two essential things we are capturing in a scene like this,
shown by these two images, is the geometry, that is the perspective changes,
the size of the space, the 3Dness of the space and
how the light is kind of reflecting off the environment across the board.
To achieve this, of course, that's what the camera is there,
it's trying to capture and depict the scene from 3D into a 2D representation.
Of course, available to us is a camera and again,
when we looked at the insides of a camera, we saw different things it has.
First thing is, of course, the optics and the lens of the camera.
Here I'm basically showing you that by just opening the aperture of the camera,
you can actually get more light into the camera.
More light into the camera is an important thing and also, how much of it will
actually get into the sensor is another part of the whole process we want to try
to understand because, in essence, what we are trying to do is capture light.
So the other thing available to us, of course, is the sensor itself and
the sensor itself could have a variety of different characteristics on how it
captures the color and the light variations that are captured from the scenes.
So, in essence, the light goes through this,
when it hits the sensor, and that's what we saw in one of the slides earlier,
it also kind of adds a variability on what we would capture.
So, in essence, going from 3D scene to a display, what we are going through is
a pipeline of wanting to capture perspective and light scattering from a scene
using the light opening and what the kind of sensor we used to be able to
create an image, a depiction of the 3D scene that we're trying to capture.