[Man] The first answer is yes, this is a good representation
of the sentence "Sam has 2 jobs."
It says there exists an x and y, and one of them is a job of Sam.
The other one is a job of Sam, and crucially, we have to say that x is not equal to y.
Otherwise, this would be satisfied and we could have the same job
represented by the variables x and y.
Is this a good representation of the member function?
No.
It does do a good job of telling you what is a member,
so if x is a member of a set because it's one member
and then we can always add other members and it's still a member of that set,
but it doesn't tell you anything about what x is not a member of.
So for example, we want to know that 3 is not a member of the empty set,
but we can't prove that with what we have here.
And we have a similar problem down here.
This is not a good representation of adjacent relation.
So it will tell you, for example, that square (1,1) is adjacent to square (2,1)
and also to square (1,2).
So it's doing something right, but one problem is that it doesn't tell you in the other direction.
It doesn't tell you that (2,1) is adjacent to (1,1)
and another problem is that it doesn't tell you that (1,1) is not adjacent to (8,9)
because again, there's no way to prove the negative.
And the moral is that when you're trying to do a definition,
like adjacent or member, what you usually want to do
is have a sentence with the equivalent or the biconditional sign
to say this is true if and only if rather than to just have an assertion
or to have an implication in one direction.