Let's talk about this class.
Most of the material is very basic.
It's the first class you would have in college if you're not a statistics major.
We teach you things like how to visualize data, how to summarize it,
how to run test, and even find trends.
But there are also a few nuggets in there that are challenges.
These are optional, and they're clearly marked as optional,
but I will let you prove some theorems along the way using little games that I play with you.
Most important, you'll be afforded the possibility to program the things you've learned.
Again, this is optional, because I don't expect you to have a programming background.
But give it a try.
I believe that through programming you learn the material much better than any other way.
It's optional. You can assimilate all the material without it.
But I would recommend to give it a try if you know how to program.