A good way to learn about Firebase
analytics, is to see it in action.
The app that I'm about to
show you is a sample app
that has gathered a little bit more
data than our friendly chat app.
And I'm using this so
that you can see what analytics can do.
Instructions for
following along are below.
Go ahead and open the analytics tab for
your Firebase project.
Analytics data takes
24 hours to show up.
So, if you're looking at your own
project and you don't see numbers,
you might want to wait until
tomorrow and come back.
Right at the top of the analytics
console is a breakdown
of active users by day.
First_open attribution shows me how
many times the app has been opened for
the first time.
Which gives you an idea of how many
devices have installed the app.
If we scroll down, and
select View First Open Attribution,
you can see more details
about this group.
If you scroll down further
on the main screen though,
you can see a breakdown
of user engagement.
User engagement gives a snapshot
of how users open your app, and
how long they spent using it.
If I scroll down a little bit further,
I see a chart for app version.
App version shows you how many users
are using each version of your app.
This could be a useful snapshot of how
a new version of the app is working out.
For example, has usage dropped
off since the new update?
Finally, at the bottom,
is some interesting demographic data.
You can see things like
the locations of your users,
as well as gender breakdowns and age.
You could use these demographics to make
new test groups for new features, or
to tailor your app for
your largest demographic groups.
You can also filter all analytics by
clicking on the Add Filter button,
which allows you to get even
more specificity in your charts.
If you're interested in knowing a little
bit more about how these demographics
are collected, check out the link below.
So, how can we actually use this data?
Well, image a scenario where,
after gathering some analytics for
Friendly Chat, you see that 70% of
your users are under 25 years old.
By adding a filter,
you can create a group for these users.
Do young people want
access to custom emojis?
With Firebase's remote config feature,
which you're going to be learning about
shortly, you could run tests to see how
custom emojis impact how many of your
users, between the ages of 18 to 24,
use your app.
You could then look at this
test data through analytics,
and make decisions about whether to
add emojis to the app permanently.
Now, you've probably noticed that
there's way more information collected
in this analytics section of
the console than we've talked about.
In fact, we could spend
a whole nother weekend, or
even several weekends just on analytics.
But for now, you have an overview
of some of the information
that analytics automatically collects
about events and user properties.
To check out a complete list of
automatically collected user properties,
I've provided a link below.
In addition, you'll also find
a link to the Firebase help pages,
which include more information about
adding other analytics to your app.