And not meeting
specifications is basically,
you don't do any of the things
that meets, that we've listed.
And exceeds here is where you, look at
this, you can add collectible items
on the screen, multiple vehicle types,
timed games, so yeah it will.
>> Levels.
>> Levels, yeah, you can do a lot there.
To meet specifications for the comments,
you need to have comments first of all,
and they should explain
the longer code procedures.
So you don't need to comment every line.
>> Please don't comment.
>> Please don't comment every line, yes.
If something is obvious, then there
might not be any need to comment it,
but if you can save reviewer some
time by reading something longer and
explaining anything that might
be a little complicated or
maybe describe a technique
that isn't obvious.
Then that's great to,
then please do include the comments and
they're necessary for
the larger pieces of code.
And then yeah we have a udacious
category that they are thorough and
concise and code is self documenting.
So basically,
saying code is self documenting is that,
the code is as readable as
it can be on it's own and
then anything that's maybe
difficult to understand you.
You add comments only in those cases.