At this point, we've completed
the settings activity and
we've made our first setting in
the Settings Fragment using DXML.
When we hit the check box, what Android
is doing is it goes into the file and
changes the value associated with
the key Show Bass, setting it to true or
false depending on whether
the box is checked or not.
What we need to do now is to read this
from the file to update the actual app.
We need to answer two questions.
How and
when should we read this from the file?
Here's what the code looks like
to read from shared preferences.
First, you need to get an instance
of shared preferences.
In the case of preferences,
set by a preference screen, you can
use the preference manager method
called getDefaultSharedPreferences.
There are other options mentioned in
the notes below, but only if you want to
make multiple Multiple preference files
for your app other than the default one.
But in our case, this is what we'll use.
Next, using that shared
preferences object,
we can use various get methods to get
data from that shared preference file.
Which Get method to use depends on
the type object stored in the file.
There is for example, Get Boolean,
Get String, Get String Set,
Get Flow, Get Int, and Get Long.
Once you've decided
which Get method to use,
you pass in the string which is
the key of the preference and
then you pass in the default value,
which is basically the result of
this call if that preference
was not found in the file.
Note that of course the default value
always matches the type of the return of
that call.
Also note that there's no type checking,
so
if you tell shared preferences to
get you a long when there's actually
a string stored in there which cannot be
converted to a long, the app will crash.
In our case, we want to use to get
boolean and we're going to pass in
the the key showbass and
we'll put in default value of true.
Now we won't be writing directly to
the shared preferences in this exercise
because this is all handled in
the background by the settings fragment.
That said, the code for
directly writing to the share
preferences is very similar.
Just as with reading you'll get
a reference to the share preferences.
You call the edit method
to get the editor object.
Then, on the editor object,
you can pass in the key value,
using the correct put type method,
such as putBoolean.
And then, finally, you save your
updates using the apply or commit.
Apply is usually the right choice
because it performs the update off
the main thread.
Now that we've got our code for
interacting with a sharedPreferences
where do I actually put it?
I'm going to load up
the preference of whether or
not to display the bass circle
right in the onCreate method.
So our onCreate method calls this
setupSharedPreferences method and
inside it,
I create the sharedPreference object.
This way I can pass this as the context
to get the object reference and
then I can use that to get
the boolean of the showbass settings.
And once I get it that boolean, I can
pass it into the video license view,
set show bass and
once I do that I'm ready to test this.
But there is one problem right now,
our videos will only update if
the activity is recreated and
hence the onCreate is called.
Something like a rotation would do, but
it won't reflect
the visual straight away.
Regardless let's just try this out,
and see if it works.
So I run the app,
go into the settings, and
I'll uncheck that and if we go back, you
can still see that the circle is there.
But once you rotate the phone,
the circle disappears.
That's because it only loaded
up the shared preferences
when the onCreate was called.