But there are many different
types of DNS records.
Literally, there are dozens of them.
A records, the ones we use to look up
the IPv4 address of another host or
just one of them.
Take out your favorite search engine and
see if you can find out what each
of these other record types is for.
First the CNAME type.
Does CNAME stand for common name, or
category name, or canonical name.
Second, the quad-A record type.
Which is spelled A-A-A-A.
Does a quad-A record stand for
a cluster address, an IPv6 address,
or an encryption key?
And lastly the NS record type.
Does that stand for a DNA name server?
Does that stand for an Ethernet switch?
Or does it stand for a network socket?