[Thrun] Let me talk about a really interesting special instance of Bayes net reasoning
which is called explaining away.
And I'll first give you the intuitive answer,
then I'll wish you to compute probabilities for me that manifest the explain away effect
in a Bayes network of this type.
Explaining away means that if we know that we are happy,
then sunny weather can explain away the cause of happiness.
If I then also know that it's sunny, it becomes less likely that I received a raise.
Let me put this differently.
Suppose I'm a happy guy on a specific day
and my wife asks me, "Sebastian, why are you so happy?"
"Is it sunny, or did you get a raise?"
If she then looks outside and sees it is sunny,
then she might explain to herself,
"Well, Sebastian is happy because it is sunny."
"That makes it effectively less likely that he got a raise
"because I could already explain his happiness by it being sunny."
If she looks outside and it is rainy,
that makes it more likely I got a raise,
because the weather can't really explain my happiness.
In other words, if we see a certain effect that could be caused by multiple causes,
seeing one of those causes can explain away any other potential cause
of this effect over here.
So let me put this in numbers and ask you the challenging question of
what's the probability of a raise given that I'm happy and it's sunny?