This is the property that we
would like to hold for Max.
Max needs to be,
I'm going to call it a non-expansion.
It looks just like the contraction
property except there's no
gamma multiplier here less than 1.
So it could be that we
have equality here, and
it could be that we have less than.
But we have this kind of non-expansion
sort of thing going on that
when we apply Max individually
to these two functions f and
g we get something that's going to be.
The difference between those is
going to be closer together than
if we actually just take the Max over
the entire differences between f and g.
So I don't know how
crystal clear this is but
I think it might help to
do a concrete example.
>> It is not crystal clear.
Wait, quick clarification question,
so you have max a f(a) max a g(a).
But just like before,
those are actually two different a's.
>> That's right.
In fact,
there could be three different a's.
because this thing on the right hand
side could be yet a different a.
>> A a a, okay.
>> So this is all very abstract.
So let's actually just write
down some concrete numbers.
And imagine this is,
we have two functions,
f and g defined over the same set of
a values, a1, a2, a3, a4, a5, a6, a7.
And I don't know,
just fill them in this way.
F of a3 is 1, g of a5 is 8 and so on.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Do you get that?
>> I do.
>> Good.
So, quiz.
Just fill in what these quantities are
in the case of these particular numbers.
Just make sure.
You know, we want to prove that this
holds for any f and g, for all f and g.
But let's just make sure that
it holds for this one first.
>> Okay.
I like this quiz because
this one I think I can actually do.
>> [LAUGHS] It's not hard but
it starts to make you think
about the relationships between
the numbers and the two functions.
>> Well,
you can try to make me think about it.
All right.
Go.