The first model is a One-to-One Model.
Here each user-level thread has a kernel-level thread associated with it.
When the user process creates a new user-level thread, there is a kernel-level
thread that either is created or there is available kernel-level thread,
then a kernel-level thread is associated with user-level thread.
This means that the operating system can see all of the user-level threads.
It understands that the process is multithreaded, and it also understands what
those threads need in terms of synchronization, scheduling, blocking.
So as the operating system already supports these mechanisms in
order to manage its threads, then the user-level processes can
directly benefit from the threading support that's available in the kernel.
The downside of this approach is that, for every operation we
have to go to the kernel, so we have to pay the cost of a system call,
of crossing the user to kernel boundary.
This we discussed already could be expensive.
This model also means that since we're relying on the kernel to
do the thread-level management synchronization, scheduling et cetera,
we are limited by the policies that are already supported at the kernel level.
So for instance if the kernel doesn't support a particular scheduling policy or
if the kernel has a limit on the number of threads that can be supported,
the process is restricted to operate within those bounds.
This basically affects the portability, so
if a particular process, a particular application, has certain needs about how
its threads should be managed, we're limited to running that kind of
process only on the kernels that provide exactly that kind of support.
The second model is the Many-to-One Model.
Here all of the user-level threads are supported,
are mapped onto a single kernel-level thread.
What this means is that at the user level there is
a thread management library that decides which one of the user-level thread will
be mapped onto the kernel-level thread at any given point of time.
That user-level thread, of course,
will run only once the kernel-level thread is actually scheduled on the CPU.
The benefit of this approach is that it's totally portable.
Everything will be done at the user-level thread library,
scheduling, synchronization, et cetera, and so
we don't rely on any specific kernel-level support.
Similarly we're not limited by the specific limits and
policies that are available in the kernel.
Also because all of the thread management is done at the user level by
the user-level threading library, we don't have to make system calls,
we don't have to rely on user kernel transitions, in order to
make decisions regarding scheduling, synchronization, blocking, et cetera.
So this is very different than what we saw in the one-to-one model.
The problem with this approach is, however,
that the operating system has really no insight into the application needs,
it doesn't even know that the process is multithreaded.
What the OS sees is just a kernel-level thread, so
the real danger is that when the user-level library schedules one
user-level thread onto the kernel-level thread, and let's say
this user-level thread makes a request for an I operation that's blocking.
The kernel level scheduler will see that the kernel-level thread block, and
it will basically block the entire process.
So the fact that there may be other user-level threads that have useful work to
do and the process overall can make some progress, that's hidden from
the operating system, from the kernel, and the whole process is forced to wait.
This is obviously going to have some implication on performance.
Finally there is the Many-to-Many Model.
The Many-to-Many Model allows some user-level threads to be
associated with one kernel-level process, others perhaps to
have a one-to-one mapping with a process, so sort of the best of both worlds.
The kernel knows that the process is multithreaded since it
has assigned multiple kernel level threads to it.
And also, if one user-level thread blocks an I/O, and
as a result the kernel-level thread is blocked as well,
the process overall will have other kernel-level threads
onto which the remaining user-level threads will be scheduled.
So the process overall can make progress.
The user-level threads may be scheduled onto any of
the underlying kernel-level threads, so they're unbound.
Or we can have a certain user-level thread that's basically mapped
one-to-one permanently onto a kernel-level thread.
We called this the bound mapping.
The nice thing about this is that if we have certain user-level threads that
somehow even the kernel should be able to treat differently, to ensure that they
have better priority or are more responsive to certain events that are happening
in the kernel, we have a mechanisms to do this by these bound threads.
For instance, if the kernel sees that there is some user input, and we have
a particular user level thread that's designated to run the user interface for
this process, the kernel has a way to
immediately schedule the corresponding kernel-level thread as a result of that,
also the corresponding user-level thread.
So this ability to provide this kind of one-to-one,
permanent mapping in the many-to-many model is another benefit of the model.
There are still some cons with this model.
And that's, in particular, because now we require some
coordination between the kernel-level thread management and
the user-level thread management, which we didn't see in the other cases.
In the one-to-one model, pretty much everything goes up to
the kernel-level manager, and in the many-to-one model, pretty much everything
goes up to the user-level thread manager that's part of the thread's library.
In the many-to-many model there's often the case where
we require certain coordination between the kernel and user-level managers,
mostly in order to take advantage of some performance opportunities.