Markers are used to indicate
a location on a map.
You're probably familiar with a typical
Google marker from using maps and
if not, you soon will be, or
if you prefer to customize it with
your own marker, well that's good too.
For the next few minutes,
I'll show you how to do exactly that.
You'll build an app that
has a map in it and
this map will have a set of markers for
specific locations.
You may have a business
that has many locations.
And you want your app to show your
users where these locations are, or
you could for example,
be part of a sports organization
that has a number of
locations where you play.
It's much easier to show this
type of information on a map.
And markers are the way to go here.
Let's take a look at an app like
that and we'll see how to build it.