You'll notice that we can handle
exceptions by at least logging
error conditions,
then at least we have some trace
left behind when an error happened.
It's better than catching
the exception and
doing absolutely nothing,
which is known as failing silently.
So in this task, I want you to make the
following modifications to Soonami app.
In the makehttprequest method,
I want you to log the HTTP response
code if the status code is not 200.
Also, log the IOException
if it gets thrown.
Notice that we disconnect
the HTTP connection and
enclose the input stream
the moment we're done using them.
And since we added the code to a finally
block, we know our code will get
executed regardless of whether or
not an exception is thrown.
So by disconnecting the URLConnection
and closing the input stream,
we're actually cleaning up and
we're releasing scarce operating system
resources that can now be used for
other tasks.
Now go ahead and complete these tasks.
If you need help, see the hint below
the quiz or you can reference the other
examples of try-catch blocks
in the Soonami app code.