And the answer is that any plan that
would work in the deterministic world
might work in the stochastic world,
if everything works out okay.
And all of these plans
meet that criteria.
But no finite plan is
guaranteed to always to work.
Because a successful plan has to
include at least one move action.
And, if we try a move action
a finite number of times,
each of those times the wheels
might slip, and it won't move.
And so, we can never be guaranteed to
achieve the goal with a finite sequence
of actions.
Now, what about an infinite
sequence of actions?
Well, we can't represent that
in the language we have so
far where a plan is a linear sequence,
but
we can introduce a new notion of plans
in which we do have infinite sequences.