Huh.
140 grams of fiber.
Why would you need that much?
[SOUND].
>> Hey.
Morning, Colt.
>> Hey, Chris.
What's going on?
>> How's it going?
>> I'm just recovering
from a long day yesterday.
I spent all day making this new app.
It's got a material theme, some
tasteful animations, a nice transition.
When I tilt the screen, look at that,
it subtly adjusts the color scheme.
>> Nice!
>> Pretty slick huh?
>> Yeah, it looks really good,
Chris, but
you know your application is
running really slow, right?
>> Yeah, for some reason,
Android feels a bit slow.
I mean, I think you guys might
need to tune it up a bit.
It would make our lives a little easier.
>> Ha ha.
I'm going to let that one slide.
Why don't you back up and
tell me what you're doing to create
this transcendent experience of yours.
>> Yeah, sure.
So
to get this nice color
blending happening here,
I have to layer a bunch of views, color
them, and then when I animate them,
I actually have to cut out circles,
redraw them back to the screen.
And as the user scrolls,
I apply this cool new animation to draw
the new content on top of the old.
I might even put an Easter
egg right there.
>> Okay.
Timeout, Chris.
I think you are violating some of
the principles of modern application
performance design.
Just because you can overlay 90
views that are animating and
transparent, doesn't
mean you actually should.
>> Okay.
But that's the user experience that
seems to be selling these days.
If it runs slow,
it's Android's problem, right?
Not mine.
>> No, you gotta remem,
put it this way, Chris.
You wouldn't use bubble sort on an array
that's got 20 million elements in it,
would you?
>> That's true.
I'd probably use some, something way
faster like merge sort or quick sort.
>> See exactly.
You gotta remember that the Android
system is doing a ton of work to make
things fast and look beautiful,
but you still have to live up to
your end of the bargain and
do a little lifting too, right?
All of those overlays and
transparencies are beautiful, but
they actually have an implicit
performance cost that comes with them.
This is why rendering performance is
one of the biggest pitfalls that most
developers fall into.
>> Right.
>> They spend so
much time making these
beautiful visuals.
They forget all of the performance
cost that comes along with it.
>> All right, well.
But, I still want to keep
this user experience.
So, how do I make it fast?
>> Huh.
That's the easy part, Chris.
You watch some videos.