Before I continue I want to make
one important comment to contrast
the message-based and the shared
memory-based approaches to IPC.
The end result of both of these
approaches is that some data is
transferred from one address space
into the target address space.
In message passing, this requires that
the CPU is involved in copying the data.
This takes some number of CPU cycles
to copy the data into the channel via
the port and then from the port and
into the target address space.
In the shared memory-based case,
at the minimum, there's CPU cycles that
are spent to map the physical memory
into the appropriate address spaces.
The CPU is also used to copy the data
into the channel when necessary.
However, note that,
in this case, there are no user to
kernel level switches required.
The memory mapping operation
itself is a costly operation.
However, if the channel
is set up once and
used many times,
then it will result in good payoff.
However, even for 1-time use, the memory
mapped approach can perform well.
In particular, when we need to move
large amounts of data from one address
space into another space, the CPU time
that's required to perform the copy
can greatly exceed the CPU time that's
required to perform the map operation.
In fact, Windows systems internally
in the communication mechanisms they
support between processes, leverage the
fact that there exists this difference.
So if the the data that needs to be
transferred among address spaces is
smaller than a certain threshold,
then the data is copied in and
out of a communication channel
via a port like interface.
Otherwise, the data is potentially
copied once to make sure that it's
in a page aligned area.
And then that areas is mapped into
the address space of the target process.
This mechanism that the Windows
kernel supports is called
Local Procedure Calls, or LPC.