So first, let's look at the Lightstage.
Lightstage is a system where a subject
is illuminated by a variety of
these controlled LED lights.
They're shone at different
res different times
to be able to kind of illuminate
the face from different directions.
Once, of course we can use this, and
we can capture all of the variety
of different lighting conditions.
The goal, really, is to then put
the subject in a different environment,
a CGR, computer graphic environment
which has different lighting.
And of course,
now we can relight the image
based on where the light sources
are in that environment.
>> In this video, we present a technique
from how to find the lighting and
reflectance of a live action
performance in post production.
By lighting the actor with a timed multi
flexed series of lighting conditions at
a high frame rate, we can simulate
their appearance in Nav illumination.
Or, we can modify their reflectance
functions to produce subtle or
stylized modifications
to their reflectance.
Our illumination device includes
156 white led light sources,
which can be run in arbitrary patterns
synchronized to a high speed camera.
The device also includes
a matting background,
allowing the subject to photographed
in silhouette to obtain a matte.
The system rapidly illuminates
the subject with a repeating set of
patterns, forming a basis for
the sphere.
Our camera requires up to
4,000 images per second,
which can cover the full set of
lights up to 24 times per second.
In this work, we explored using
three different lighting basics,
single lights, triples of lights,
and hadamard patterns.
Our paper discusses
the various advantages and
disadvantages we experienced
with each basis.
Here, we see a mosaic over
180 image sequence that
includes the triangle basis,
captured every 12th of a second.
We can produce a full motion film of
the subject with Nav illumination
by taking a linear combinations
of the basis images.
This lighting can be captured
from real locations, or
it can be designed by a cinematographer.
Unlike previous techniques, this
allow the lighting to be designed and
modified in post-production without
creating a digital version of the actor.
>> So here, you see an example
of how a camera system
coupled with a controllable light source
can be used to capture a subject.
And with ideal lighting conditions and
how we can take that control to generate
novel images and in case here,
video sequences.
And it's a technique that's widely
used in the movie industry at present.
I encourage you to look at the website
here, and also Paul Dubovick's webpage
and the paper that I'm also
citing at the end of this talk.
To look at variety of examples
of this kind of stuff.
And how, actually,
this whole technology, which is again,
a combination of cameras and
light sources,
can be used to generate
this new form of imaging.
That, basically now, as I said,
more importantly, takes the subject, and
then re-lights it in
the new environment.
Lightstage has gone through
a variety of developments.
And now, actually, let me show you
another video where they've taken this
whole concept of Lightstage.
And in the previous case, they applied
it only working with just faces, but
now they're actually done this to
allow it to work for walking subjects.
So here, you notice that, basically,
the same set up except that
they have a treadmill.
With a whole lot of led lights again.
But of course, in this case,
they can capture the motion
of the person walking.
And again, now,
using this kind of a scenario,
they can control the lights during
the action of a subject moving.
Generate the same kinds of lighting
bases as they did for faces.
This is equivalent to the mosaic
that we saw for faces.
And then, of course,
they can now re-light it, and this time,
the subject is walking.
They do a little bit of additional
work to align the subjects using
things like optical flow, and stuff.
But now, you basically see that
the subject could be put in
different types of environments.
And completely re-lit in that
environment, with a variety of different
lighting conditions, and
also different viewpoints.
So, of course, the motion is recreated
from the one that was captured
in the lighting stage,
at the light stage itself.
And of course, using this,
they can start replicating the subject,
different viewpoints.
I encourage you to look
at the website again and
also the paper that's
referenced with this.
But basically, the idea really remains
is by now taking cameras and lighting
sources, we can actually generate
novel types of images and videos.