One of the most important parts
of programming is understanding
how to use the documentation.
Unity has a wealth of
documentation available online.
It's organized into two primary
sections, the Manual and Scripting.
Let's talk more about
the manual scripting now.
The manual teaches you
how Unity is designed,
and it also shows you
how to use the editor.
The scripting section is all
about Unity programming.
This is the section we'll be
focusing on for this course.
Let's visit the Script API
documentation.
So go ahead and
click up here on Scripting API.
If you look over here,
you'll see that everything is
organized into a hierarchy.
Remember that we're writing
scripts in a language called C#.
C# determines how the scripts
are structured and
how the commands are called.
And C# has tons of ways to establish
relationships between objects.
The Unity Scripting Documentation
is divided into namespaces.
In this case,
Unity is using namespaces to establish
the groupings of related objects.
And the top two namespace
are the UnityEngine and UnityEditor.
The Unity Engine namespace is all that
stuff that happens when your VR app is
running.
And the Unity Editor namespace is all
that's extending the Unity Editor.
When you're just starting out,
you probably won't extend the editor,
instead, you'll use what in
the UnityEngine all the time.
Let's talk a little bit
more about UnityEngine.
You'll see using UnityEngine at the top
upon this every Unity C# script.
This is very important, because it
gives you the ability to access
all the objects in
the UnityEngine namespace.
So let's open up that namespace and
take a look.
So just go over here to the left,
click the + sign, and you'll see that
inside of the UnityEngine namespace,
there are more namespaces.
There's even one dedicated to VR.
Let's scroll down to Classes and
open that up.
These classes are the most important
objects to learn in Unity.
As a reminder, classes represent
what is common between objects.
For example,
all cameras have things in common which
are described in the camera class.
For now be sure to bookmark this page,
because you'll use it again and again.
Okay, now let's check out
the camera class documentation.
Scroll down to camera, and click on it.
Okay, now scroll down and
click on the backgroundColor variable.
See the example code?
Make sure you select C# at the top and
not JS.
JS stands for Java Script.
That's just a different scripting
language, but we'll be using C# here.
The background color variable is how
you change a camera's background color
using code.
Remember making cameras,
earlier in this Nanodegree?
Well, the background color, here, is the
scripting equivalent to the background
color on the camera component.
Let's go look at that.
So the documentation we
were just looking at,
tells you how to change
this color using code.
And while we're here,
here's a little trick for you.
There's a shortcut to jump directly
into a component's documentation.
In the Unity editor,
you can jump into the docs by clicking
on the question mark icon in the editor.
Check this out.
It took me directly to
the camera documentation, and
I can click here, and go directly to the
scripting documentation for the camera.
Pretty handy, right?
Okay, now you've seen where
the scripting documentation lives and
how to use it.
You'll use this again and again.
It isn't light reading for
the beach, but
it's incredibly valuable,
and worth studying.
Right, now let's move on and
learn about creating objects using code.