So, let's start coding this up.
First thing we need is to set up our
image cache in the service worker.
I'm going to create a variable to hold
the name of this new image cache.
And I'm going to create an array to
hold all the cache names we care about.
In our activate event
that we wrote earlier,
we're deleting any cache
that isn't the static cache.
That isn't good enough anymore as
we start losing our image cache.
Instead, we want to delete any
caches that aren't in our array
of caches that we care about.
Right.
Now, to handle those photo requests.
Over in our fetch handler, I'm going to
handle URLs that have the same origin
and have a path that starts
with slash photo slash.
When I see one of those,
I'm going to respond with whatever
returns from serve photo.
All we need to do now is
implement serve Photo.
I'm only wanting to store
one copy of each photo, and
photo URLs look like this.
They have width information at the end.
So, I'm going to create a storage
URL that doesn't have the size info.
I'm going to do that using a regular
expression matching on dash,
some digits and then px.jpg.
And I'm going to replace
that with nothing.
Now, I have the URL, but
missing the size-specific stuff.
This is the URL I'm
going to use in the cache.
And I reckon you can handle the rest.
Mike?
Come in, Mike.
>> You rang?
>> Yes,
we need to cache these photos in.
I figured the student could manage this.
>> I agree.
Let's do this.
>> To start, you'll want to catch
up with the code Jake just wrote.
Do this by running Git reset hard to
remove any local changes you have.
Then, git checkout task-cache-photos
to get the stubbed methods.
Now, head over to public/js/sw/index.js.
The service worker script.
Your task is to implement serve photo.
The aim is to serve photos from
the cache if they're there.
Otherwise, get them from the network,
but put them into the cache for
the next time.
Remember to use storageURL
when matching and
putting stuff into the image cache so
you only end up with one photo in
the cache no matter how many
different sizes are requested.
Once again, developing gets a lot easier
if you have Developer Tools open and
Force Update on reload checked so
you only need to refresh
once to see changes.
You know things are working when you
see a Wittr content images cache in dev
tools where the URLs are missing the
width and the ,jpg extension at the end.
You should be able to take the server
offline, reload the page, and
still get images.
To double check everything is working,
head to the settings page and
type cache-photos into the test
field and press enter.