One way to classify AI problems is
using properties of the environment and
components of state that
need to be captured.
>> An environment can
be fully observable,
like tic-tac-toe where you can see the
entire board, or it could be partially
observable like in Battleship, where you
can't see your opponent ship positions.
>> And the environment can be
deterministic, where you know for
sure the results of each action, or
stochastic where's
there's some uncertainty.
>> An environment can be discrete,
where there's a finite number of
states that the number can be in.
Or it can be continuous, where the
number of possible states is infinite,
typically due to some properties that
need to be stored as real numbers.
>> An environment could be benign, where
the agent is the only one taking actions
that intentionally affect its goal.
There could be other
random events going on.
Or adversarial where
there are one more other
agents that can take actions
to defeat it's goal.
Such environments are commonly
found in competitive games.
>> Now for
each of the problems listed below,
can you mark the appropriate
characteristics?