Theoretically for
a perfect consistency model,
we would like to achieve
absolute ordering and
immediate visibility of any state update
and axis, and we also want this to be in
the exact same manner as those updates
were performed in some real time.
With this model,
changes are instantaneous and
immediately visible everywhere, so even
if we had some read operations that were
immediately performed over here
to the locations m1 and m2,
they would have still returned
these values x and y.
So in P3,
regardless how far away from P1 it is,
P3 would always be able to
instantaneously see that P1 performed
this write operation to the memory
location m1 and that it wrote x there.
Furthermore, what's also really
important about the strict consistency
model is that it guarantees that
every single node in the system will
see all of the writes that have happened
in the system in the exact same order.
So, if we have the situation where
P3 is maybe closer to P2 than P1,
and these time intervals are really,
really small, in reality it's
possible that it took longer for
this message from P1 to get to P3 so
that P3 can see this x value.
That's not allowed with
strict consistency.
Strict consistency, every single update
has to be immediately visible and
everywhere visible, and the ordering
of these updates needs to be preserved.
In practice, even in a single shared
memory processor, there are no
guarantees regarding the ordering of
memory access operations from different
cores, unless we use some additional
locking and synchronization primatives.
In distributed systems, the additional
latency, any possibility for
the messages to be lost or
reordered make this not just harder, but
also even impossible to guarantee.
For that reason strict consistency
remains a nice theoretical model, but
in practice it is not something
that's sustainable and
other consistency models
are used instead.