In my own research, I've extensively used machine learning for robotics.
What you see here is a robot my students and I built at Stanford
called Stanley, and it won the DARPA Grand Challenge.
It's a self-driving car that drives without any human assistance whatsoever,
and this vehicle extensively uses machine learning.
The robot is equipped with a laser system
I will talk more about lasers in my robotics class,
but here you can see how the robot is able to build
3-D models of the terrain ahead.
These are almost like video game models that allow it to make
assessments where to drive and where not to drive.
Essentially, it's trying to drive on flat ground.
The problem with these lasers is that they don't see very far.
They see about 25 meters out, so to drive really fast
the robot has to see further.
This is where machine learning comes into play.
What you see here is camera images delivered by the robot
superimposed with laser data that doesn't see very far,
but the laser is good enough to extract samples
of driveable road surface that can then be machine learned
and extrapolated into the entire camera image.
That enables the robot to use the camera
to see driveable terrain all the way to the horizon
up to like 200 meters out, enough to drive really, really fast.
This ability to adapt its vision by driving its own training examples using lasers
but seeing out 200 meters or more
was a key factor in winning the race.