The characters property holds
the collection of characters that make
up a string.
You can use this property to loop
through all the characters in a string
like so.
Now, there's a lot going on to this
piece of code, so let's unpack it.
First, we have our variable declaration.
No problem,
you've seen lots of these before.
But on the next line,
we have this for in business.
What's that about?
Where you're looking at
your first Swift loop.
Loops provide a way to
execute a piece of code on
every element in the collection.
Or in this case,
every character in our string.
What's up with this animal.characters
part of our statement?
Well, this is called .syntax.
.syntax gives us the ability to access
properties and functions for a type.
And here the .syntax is used to
access the characters property
of the animal string.
A quick aside, if you want to see all
the properties and functions we have
access to for the animal string,
type animal, followed by a dot.
And then let Xcode's auto completion
show you all the possible properties and
functions.
We can delete that for now and
focus back on our loop.
The line that comes after
the opening curly brace,
it represents the heart of the loop.
The code that's going to be executed on
each character in the animal.characters
collection.
So this loop is printing every
character in the animal string.
If you click on this button in the upper
right-hand corner of your playground
window, it'll open up
the bottom console.
And then the console,
you can see the characters for
our string octopus,
are printed one by one.