So, we know that distortion
changes the size and
shapes of objects in an image,
but how do we calibrate for that?
Well, we can take pictures of known
shapes ,then we'll be able to detect and
correct any distortion errors.
We could choose any shapes to calibrate
our camera, and we'll use a chessboard.
A chessboard is great for
calibration because its regular
high contrast pattern makes it
easy to detect automatically.
And we know what an undistorted
flat chessboard looks like.
So, if we use our camera
to take multiple pictures
of a chessboard against a flat surface.
Then we'll be able to detect any
distortion by looking at the difference
between the apparent size and the shape
of the squares in these images, and
the size and
shape that they actually are.
Then we'll use that information
to calibrate our camera.
Create a transform that maps these
distorted points to undistorted points.
And finally, undistort any images.
Let's see how to do this all
using Python and Open CV.