And the answer is we have an unbounded solution
if every leaf in the plan ends up in a goal.
So, if we follow through the plan, no matter what path
we execute based on the observations--
and remember, we don't get to pick the observations.
The observations come into us, and we follow one path or another
based on what we observe.
So, we can't guide it in one direction or another,
and so we need every possible leaf node.
This one only has one, but if a plan had multiple leaf nodes,
every one of them would have to be a goal.
Now, in terms of a bounded solution,
it's okay to have branches but not to have loops.
If we had branches and we ended up with one goal here
and one goal here in 1, 2, 3, steps,
1, 2, 3, steps, that would be a bounded solution.
But if we have a loop, we might be 1, 2, 3, 4, 5--
we don't know how many steps it's going to take.