So what's up with all this
sequence number business?
What is it about the network
that makes it necessary for
TCP to put sequence
numbers on everything?
Well, for one thing the network
can fail to deliver a packet.
If we want to talk about whether
a particular chunk of data has been
received, we have to have
a way to refer to it.
But second, the network can also
deliver packets out of order.
Not going to go into all
the ways that can happen.
And that's honestly not as common
as packets getting dropped.
But if one end to sense.
h.t.t.p..
And the other one gets t.p.h.
t..
That's not going to work out very
well for the application level.
So how does this actually work.
Well, each end point in
the operating system.
Not in the browser or
a web server or other application
keeps a space in memory that it
fits the incoming data into.
And it uses the sequence numbers
as positions, like positions.
Just like in a big string or
array into that space.
So here's a quiz.
Rearrange these packets
into the proper order.
These numbers are sequence numbers.
And this is the buffer space into
which you can reassemble them.
Then put the message that you find here.
Note that packets may be
retransmitted or overlap.