Now these are all reasonable answers.
And in fact, they are all implemented
by different programming languages.
This first one is vector addition
as defined by linear algebra.
First, the first two numbers
were added to get 5.
Then the second two were added to get 7.
And finally the last two
were added to get 9.
This is also the behavior
you get when you add two.
The second result is the result of
something called list concatenation, and
this is what adding two
lists does in Python.
A new list is created with all
the elements from the first list
followed by all the elements
from the second list.
And the last option is very common.
Most languages do implement
list concatenation.
But in a lot of languages
you call a function or
use some different symbol
other than the plus sign.
So then using the plus sign with two
arrays or less would give you an error.
Since this first option is what Num Py
does that's the option we'll be focusing
on in this course.