Here we give you an intuition as to why
an optimistic heuristic function, h,
finds the lowest-cost path.
When a* ends, it returns a path,
p, with estimated cost, C.
And turns out that C is
actually also the actual cost,
because at the goal,
the h component is 0.
And so the path cost is the total
cost as estimated by the function.
Now, all the paths on the frontier have
an estimated cost that's greater than C.
And we know that because the frontier
is explored in cheapest-first order.
But if h is optimistic,
then the estimated cost is
less than the true cost.
So the path p must have a cost that's
less than the true cost of any of
the other paths in the frontier.
And any paths that go beyond the
frontier must have a cost that's greater
than that, because we agreed that
the step cost is always 0 or more.
So that means that this path, p,
must be the minimal cost path.
Now, this argument, I should say, only
goes through just as is for tree search.
For graph search, the argument's
slightly more complicated, but
the general intuitions hold the same.
[BLANK_AUDIO]