Great, so given what we've
learned in the last exercise,
now we have a diagram that we
can keep in our heads as we
continue implementing the various
parts of the Pets app.
So, you may have noticed that I've
been replacing Content Provider
with more specific providers such
as the Contacts Provider, or
in this case the Pet Provider.
And this is because Content Provider
is an abstract class.
So, this means the methods
aren't implemented.
So, in order to actually use it,
we'll need to subclass it and
implement our own logic.
So, once we get the Pet Provider set up,
this subclass here, will talk to our
PetDbHelper, which will help us get
access to the underlying database.
So, here we are back in Android studio,
and
let me show you what your code will
look like by the end of this quiz.
First, we'll be creating a content
provider for the Pets app.
And we'll call that
provider PetProvider.
So, the PetProvider class will be
a new Java file in the data package of
our app.
The PetProvider class will extend
from the ContentProvider class and
because of that it will need
to implement five methods.
Insert, query, update,
delete, and getType.
So, the first four methods map to the
CRUD operations that we've been talking
about since lesson one.
Now, next in the AndroidManifest file,
you'll need to
add that you're using a content
provider using this provider tag.
So, the code for this as well as what
I showed in the PetProvider class
are shown in the gist below.
So, this first attribute here, is the
name of the Java class of the provider.
Now, this next attribute is what
we call the content authority,
which uniquely identifies
the content provider on the device.
And usually, we can just use
the package name of the app and
we'll also be talking more
about the authority soon.
Now, the last attribute is exported and
this attribute can be either
set to true or false.
So, the export attribute
determines whether or
not your content provider is
visible to other applications.
So, say for example, we have another
app called Adopt a Pal, well,
maybe that app might want
to talk to our provider.
And in that case,
we need to set exported to true.
However, since in our situation,
we're only building the content provider
to be accessed by our own Pets app,
for now, we won't export the provider.
So, let's set exported equals to false.
Now, it's your turn to make
these changes to your app.
So, go ahead and create and
set up the PetProvider class.
And then after that,
add the PetProvider to the manifest.
Now, to make it easier,
like I mentioned, I've included a gist
in the link down below, where you
can access the code snippets for
the PetProvider, as well as what needs
to be added to the AndroidManifest file.
We're also providing you a template
of the ContentProvider class, so
that you don't need to write
your own from scratch.
And don't be alarmed if there are
keywords there that you're not familiar
with just yet.
I want you to focus on
what is familiar and
then follow along as we discuss
all of it in more detail later on.
So, now I want you to copy over
the PetProvider class, and
note that there is a TODO there
that you'll need to complete.
It's listed here in the onCreate method
and I've asked you to create and
initialize a PetDbHelper object in order
to gain access to the pets database.
And remember make sure
it's a global variable.
So, as a reminder, remember,
to do this TODO, when you're
setting up your PetProvider class.
Now it's your turn to make
these changes to your app.
So, here's what I'd like you to do.
First, create a PetProvider class.
This means copy over the contents from
the gist I've linked down below, and
add it to a new file
called PetProvider.java.
And inside this gist will be
a TODO that I'll like you to do.
The second task will be
to declare a PetProvider
as an application component of the Pets
app inside your AndroidManifest file.
And you'll do so,
using the XML tag.
So, to make these steps easier for
you, like I've mentioned,
I've linked to a gist down below, where
you can access the code snippets for
the PetProvider and what's needed
to be added in AndroidManifest.
Additionally, in this gist,
we're providing you a template
of the ContentProvider class,
which means you won't need to
write your own from scratch.
And don't be alarmed if there are
keywords in it that you're not familiar
with just yet.
I want you to focus on
what is familiar and
follow along as we discuss all
of it in more detail later on.
Also, in the PetProvider gist, like I
said, there's a TODO in the onCreate
method, asking you to initialize
the PetDbHelper class.
All right, so
after you've created these steps,
you're going to be ready to start
creating all the CRUD methods needed to
start interacting with
the content provider.
All right, so get on it.