So for Step 3, you're going to add the
click handlers for each of the buttons.
Now if you remember, there were three
buttons, sign-in, sign-out, and revoke.
So for sign-in, what you're going to
do is you're going to write text to
the label, which is just setting the
status, saying that you're signing in.
And then you're going to call this
function called resolveSignInError.
Don't worry,
you haven't written this function yet.
Then for sign-out, what you need to
do is disconnect the API client and
re-connect it.
And then for revoking access,
the Plus API has a method called
revokeAccessAndDisconnect.
You're going to call that, and
then you're going to build and
connect a new Google API client.
When you've done all of this,
check this box.