Here are the answers.
The first two equations
define the same line.
The second two equations
define lines with a unique
intersection, which is the point 1.173,
0.073.
The third pair of equations define
parallel lines which are not the same.
So there is no intersection.
Now here are the functions I added to my
Python module to find the intersections.
I have the function is parallel to
first, it leverages the function of
the same name we coded earlier for
the vector class.
It just returns whether the normal
vectors of the two lines self and
ell are parallel since this is how
we define lines to be parallel.
Next I added the function E.Q. which
checks whether two lines are the same.
Remember that we can check whether
two parallel lines are equal
by picking one point from each line and
looking at the vector connecting them.
If that vector is orthogonal to
the normal vectors of both lines.
Then the two lines are equal.
Here I first checked that the two
lines being compared are parallel.
If not then there's no
chance of there being equal
then I compute the vector connecting
the two lines base points.
Finally, I check whether that vector
is orthogonal to the normal vector of
the first line.
I don't need to compare it to
the normal vectors of both lines,
since I know the lines
are already parallel.
So being orthogonal to one normal
vector is equivalent to being
orthogonal to the other.
Here I've added some more code to deal
with the technical case that we haven't
encountered yet.
What to do if the normal vector
of a line is the zero vector.
This case will actually come
up later in the lesson.
But I want to go ahead and
put it into our code now.
Basically a normal vector of zero means
that the left hand side of the equation
defining the line is zero, since the
coefficient of each variable is zero.
In that case I check the constant terms
of the two lines to see whether they
are the same.
And if so
then I declare the lines to be equal.
If not then they are different lines.
You don't need to add
this to your code yet but
you may find it helpful
to come back to later on.
Finally, I added the function
intersection width,
using the formula from
earlier I compute the X and
Y coordinates of the point
of intersection.
However, the two lines turn out to be
parallel then I'll end up with a zero
division error when trying
to compute one_over_denom.
If this happens, then I check
whether the lines are equal.
If so, then I return self
since the intersection of the two
lines is a line object itself.
On the other hand,
if the lines are not equal,
then there will be no intersection
in which case I return none.
After coding the functions, here is
what I used to answer the questions from
earlier, and
here is the output when I run the code.