The answer to the first question is given by a simple algorithm.
Suppose you place the largest disk first,
which has three different locations.
And the next disk, on top of it,
which is another three locations.
the third disk and the fourth disk
Then for each disk, you have three possibilities,
and you have four disks, so it makes three to the fourth.
That is eighty-one.
The disks on the left side are an admissible heuristic,
because it takes at least that many steps
to move all the disks from the left-side to the right-side.
And finally the number of moves required,
is a little bit tricky.
And you have to know the solution here.
You will finally move the big disk once.
But to move it to the right-side, you previously moved the second largest disk
to the center. And then move it over the the right-side.
Which is two motions
for the second largest disk.
For the third largest,
you'll move it four times, by the same logic.
And the smallest is being moved 8 times.
The total is going to be fifteen.
That's the same as two to the n minus one,
if 'n' is the number of disks.