It's worth doing a quick refresher
on creating event listeners.
For this quiz, I want you to add
an event listener to this sample site.
See this red box here?
You can click and drag or
touch and drag it around the page.
There's also a P tag right about here.
I want you to change its inner HTML
to touch end only when the touch
end event occurs.
Here let me show you.
In device emulation mode when i let up,
you can see touch and pop up here.
And when i'm not in device
emulation mode, nothing happens.
And that's because me letting up here is
a mouse up event, not a touch and event.
Here's the general structure of
an event listener in plain old vanilla
JavaScript.
The target is the specific node you
want to actually listen to the event.
And this could be a dumb node,
it could be the document or the window.
The type is simply a string of whatever
type of event you want to listen to,
in this case, it'll be touch and.
The listener is a callback function
that will get past the event object
as the only argument.
And this gives you access
to the event itself and
whatever information it contains
from within this listener callback.
There's also this use capture boolean
which comes at the end of the method.
It determines whether you should
catch the event before or
after other elements have had the
opportunity to catch and interpret it.
If you're not sure what that means,
don't worry about it.
You actually don't need to use it for
this quiz.
Also, when you take a look at the code,
you may notice that you have the option
to do this quiz with vanilla
JavaScript or jQuery.
Both vanilla JavaScript and
jQuery are perfectly valid solutions.
But I want you to give it a shot
with vanilla JavaScript first.
Afterwards if you're adventurous,
try using jQuery.
Why not?
The two solutions
are actually pretty similar.
But you're only going to see me give
the vanilla JavaScript answer in
the solution video.
And as always there are links in
the instructor notes to help you out.
Good luck.