[MUSIC]
I'm Dan Galpin,
Developer Advocate at Google.
In this course, we're going to build
weather app together called Sunshine.
We chose a weather app because
it's easy to conceptualize while
touching most of the core
APIs we want to teach.
By the end of the course,
you'll be able to use those APIs and
concepts to build your own app for
your final project.
The main screen is a list of forecast
information with an emphasized
presentation for the forecast for
today's weather.
With just a quick glance, I can
decide if today is a stay inside and
code day or
if I should code from the park instead.
We have icons to indicate conditions
like snow, rain, fog or sunshine.
With the click on one of the forecast,
we bring up a detailed view containing
the rest of the weathery goodness.
This view also gives us the opportunity
to share the weather with our friends
hashtag Sunshine, hashtag Audacity.
We can go to settings and
change the units of measure
as well as the location.
The app will post system wide
notifications to let us know about
weather conditions without
even entering the app.