We've actually looked at this just a little bit before when we
introduced the notion of frequency.
So here we have a picture of this, this yeah, we did have this picture,
this man made scene, all right, and here what I did was, I took the,
inside part, and I set this all equal to 0.
So instead of tapering it off like a nice Gaussian, I was ruthless and
I set all of the, the frequencies outside a certain diameter to 0,
so there's no high frequency component at all.
And what you get, is this ugly looking thing called ringing, al lright, so
this actually has low frequency, but because of some slight variations in here,
it can't cancel them out with higher frequencies that it needs, okay so
what gets left over is what's called ringing, and
that's what happens when you clip the frequency precisely and
I'm going to make that a mathematically and better defined in just a minute.
The flip side of that, is if I remove, just those center frequencies,
and I think in the image processing world, this is what we call coring,
where you pull out that center, all that you get left with
is this high frequency bit, which is a lot like, what, the edges, okay,
we know that there's this relationship between frequency and
edges at the high frequencies is where you get these steep derivatives.
All right.