Magnus has talked to you about
querying by kind, and by property.
In the previous exercise, you practiced
querying for all entities of a kind.
The next step is to write the code to
filter the search results by property
values.
For example, you could find all
of the conferences whose city
property has the value London.
If we did that in code,
it would look like this.
Or if you want to be more
flexible with filters,
you can build a filter like this.
You can set a field,
an operator, and a value.
Build a FilterNode object,
using that field, operator and values.
And attach it to the query.
To practice filtering
queries by property,
you're going to add a function
to the conference API class.
You can call this function whatever
you like, maybe something like,
filterPlayground.
The name doesn't matter because
the function isn't called by the UI.
You're only going to use it
within the APIs Explorer.
You'll be using this method to
experiment and explore setting filters.
You can think of it as a playground
method for exploring queries.
FilterPlayground doesn't
take any arguments.
So the request type
will be void message.
And as for the response, well we're
returning multiple conferences, so
the response type will
be conference forms.
So, define this function to create
a query to get all conferences
where the city property
has the value London.
Run the app on local host, and
use the APIs Explorer to test it.
Look for the new function name in
the list of functions available in
the conference service.
You won't be able to test your new
function in the conference center UI
because nothing in the UI
calls your function.
You can also find sample code
in Lesson_4 > Additions >
TODO_4_conference.py, including some
detailed instructions on how to use it.
Now once you get this to work for
conferences whose city is London,
add another filter on
the conferences.topics field, for
the string Medical Innovations.
Check each one of these boxes as
you progress through this exercise.