To start off, let me actually go
back to the source, and actually,
show you the video that Noah Snavely,
Steven Seitz, and Rick Szeliski did with
the paper that actually, resulted
in the concept of Photo Tourism.
And how we can actually use this,
to now showcase photographs of space,
to showcase a variety of instances.
And specifically in this case,
they're going to talk more about how
we can actually, see popular sites,
where pictures have been taken, by
variety of people, not just by one-self.
>> Searching for a particular image
of a well-photographed object
using conventional tools, often results
in a large number of images that are not
ordered, in an intuitive way.
Finding the exact picture you want,
can mean browsing through page
after page of thumbnails.
How can we organize such large photo
collections, in a more intuitive way?
In this project,
we present a novel system for
registering large sets of photos,
and exploring them in a 3D browser.
Our system discovers the relative
positions of the cameras used to take
each photograph, situates the photos
in 3D space, and provides intuitive
controls for exploring the scene,
and finding interesting photographs.
Our system takes a collection of photos,
from the same scene as input.
We first find key points in
each of the input images,
then match keypoints between
each pair of images.
Next, we run an adjustment procedure to
estimate the parameters of each camera,
and the positions of
the observed 3D points.
Once the photos have been registered,
they can be browsed using our
photo exploration interface.
Our system provides standard controls,
for moving around a 3D scene.
In addition,
when the user selects a photograph,
the virtual camera is smoothly brought
into alignment, with that photo.
Information about the photograph appears
in the information pane, on the left.
Our system provides several intuitive
ways, to select new photos.
One is to select an object.
The user can highlight a region
of the current photo, and
the system automatically finds
a good photo of the selection.
And smoothly, moves the virtual
camera to the new photo.
During transitions we use
a simple plane-based morph,
to provide context as the camera moves.
A thumbnail pane along
the bottom of the screen,
shows other photos of
the selected object.
When the user moves the mouse over
a thumbnail, that photo is displayed in
the main view, projected onto a planar
approximation, to the selected object.
Here, the user selects a thumbnail to
see a different view of the statute.
We also provide tools for
viewing the scene, at different scales.
The user can step back from the scene,
with the zoom out tool.
This finds photos that display
a larger area of the scene.
The Show Me Similar Images tool finds
images of the scene with scale, and
orientation similar to
that of the current photo.
The Zoom In button finds details,
showing the user what
parts of the scene,
can be viewed at a higher resolution.
Here, the user selects a photo
of the in the upper left, and
the browser zooms into
the more detailed photo.
Our second example uses a set
of photos taken by one person,
over the course of two days.
We registered the photographs,
and reconstructed line segments,
as well as points.
We can align the reconstructed
model with the satellite image,
to situate in a geo-referenced
coordinate system.
We rendered the scene using
the reconstructed line segments.
We also project blurred, partially
transparent versions of the photos on to
the scene, to convey more information
with a non-photo realistic look.
An overhead map is displayed
in the upper right,
the user can select
a photo using the map.
Here, the user selects a building,
to see a photograph of it.
For this data set,
we can also move left, and right,
along a row of building facades.
We provide geometric controls,
for this type of interaction.
For each photograph, we pre-compute
a left, and right neighbor based on
the projected motion of the points
preserved by the image.
We also pre-compute a step back image,
so
the user can quickly
view more of the scene.
In this example, we explore photos of
the Notre Dame Cathedral in Paris,
downloaded from the web.
The user can select regions in the point
cloud, to find images of an object.
Our system also,
allows you to annotate photos.
These annotations are automatically
transferred to new images.
Here, these are labeled several
regions of the current photo.
As each is labelled we transfer
the annotation to the other photos.
The transferred annotations
are highlighted in the thumbnail pane.
So, as not to cover the photos,
we'll hide the panes, and
use the hot key to step to
the next photo, in the sequence.
As we move to each photograph,
the annotations appear.
Our system uses simple heuristics,
to determine if a annotated
region is occluded.
As in this example,
where one region is hidden.
We can also transfer annotations
from other sources such as,
annotated images on Flickr.
In this scene, we've also added
several other annotations by hand.
Our annotation transfer
algorithm is sensitive to scale.
If we look at photographs
taken at different scales,
we see different annotations.
Next, we explore a set of photos of
Half Dome in Yosemite National Park,
gathered from the web.
If the user finds
a view point they like,
our system makes it easy to find images
taken from a similar view point.
By selecting the Lock The Camera option,
we can generate a slideshow,
where an object remains
fixed in the view.
Now, we unlock the camera.
We can also register
historical imagery such as,
this photograph of Half Dome
taken by Ansel Adams in 1960.
Here's our estimate of where Ansel was
standing, when he took this photograph.
[SOUND] Here, we compare the photograph
to a synthetic rendering,
from the same location.
The port has been manually,
added for clarity.
Our final example is a scene created,
from about 80 photos of a walk
along the Great Wall of China.
We organized about 20 of the photos
seen here, into a slide show.
We have experimented with
an alternative morphing technique,
that creates a mesh from
the 3D point cloud.
Which is used as an imposter,
for the true scene geometry.
This methods often works well for
nearby view points, but
creates artifacts in cases
where the matching fails.
We hope you have enjoyed
our 3D photo tours.
>> So, for more detail,
visit the website that I
recommend you folks to look at.
And actually, there is
additional data on this website.
I wanted to show the entire video
because there's a lot of additional
stuff, in this work,
that is actually exciting.
And again, it covers a lot of things,
we've already kind of discussed.
I'm going to give you more details,
on some of them.
It builds on the concept of feature
detection, that we've looked at before,
and are using that extract
parameters of cameras.
And then, of course,
you heard the mention a little
bit about port morphing.
Where they actually use the point cloud,
as the proxy to help you do morphing,
between different types of images.
So now, let's dive in deeper.