Before we go on,
let me just show a simple example of what's happening in some of these things.
Here, basically we need to think about, again, rays of light, which were
the unique, the thing that we want to actually measure in photography.
But we want to also think about that rays of light have various properties,
one of them being the reflective property.
So for example, if I have a light source that's illuminating the scene right
here, and this is a some sort of a surface of an object in the scene.
Of course, light hits the surface, and
of course, if it's reflective, it's going to reflect in an interesting manner.
So if there is my light sensor, in this case, an eye,
it would reflect back into the eye.
But we have, we know one thing about surfaces, of course,
that not all light gets reflected from a surface if it has different properties.
So for example, this ray of light may also reflect back in this direction.
And this, in essence,
this kind of thinking about rays of light is referred to as light transport.
And we can actually start thinking about what happens with
light transport like this.
So in this case, reflects off here, comes in, reflects off here, and
then come back to the eye also.
So now, the same eye is getting this surface up here to it from direct and
also reflecting this way.
So, reflection of light depends on the kind of surface,
what kind of surface it is, could be a specular surface like a mirror, or
a diffused surface like a matte surface.
So this basically kind of says is that whenever a light hits a surface,
it could actually get to the sensor many different ways.
Question is, can we control it?
And then, of course, can we observe this controlled change?