Here are the answers.
This first sum is over all i,
j where i is not equal to j.
So these are off diagonals, and I'm
asking for the vertices that live in V+.
Since it's a sum over off diagonals,
lij will be -1.
And since all the vertices live in
V plus, Xi and Xj both will be one.
So this whole thing basically
counts the number of edges
wholly contained within V plus.
And it counts them twice.
And it's also negative.
In other words this thing is minus
two times the number of edges in V+.
So if you repeat this reasoning for
all of these sums and
you combine all the sums together, you
should be able to see how this product
is basically four times
the number of cut edges.