We've seen how to create new Gradle
tasks, and add task actions to them.
So far, task action
implementations have been simple,
such as just writing
text out to the console.
But what about more sophisticated tasks?
How might we go about implementing
a task action for, say, copying files?
We would first have to
define some way for
the users to configure which files
should be copied and to where.
We then have to write all the I/O code
necessary to perform the copy action,
handle errors, and
report status back to the user.
Thankfully, Gradle includes many
tasks which are preconfigured
to provide commonly
needed functionality.
We distinguish these tasks by their
type, such as copy, delete, or zip.
We refer to these kinds
of task as type task.
In contrast, tasks whose actions are
implemented inline in the build script
using gif first or gif last
are referred to as ad hoc tasks.
The syntax for creating a type task
is similar to that of an ad hoc task,
the difference being that we define the
type of the task as a name parameter.