We said earlier that the runqueue
is only logically a queue.
It could also be represented as multiple
queues, like when dealing with different
priorities, or it could be a tree, or
some other type of data structure.
Regardless of the data structure,
what is important is that
it should be easy for
the scheduler to find the next thread
to run, given the scheduling criteria.
If we want the I/O and CPU bound
tasks in the system to have different
timeslice values, we have two options.
The first option is to maintain
a single runqueue structure, but
to make it easy for
the scheduler to figure out easy
what type of task is being scheduled, so
that it can apply the different policy.
Another option is to
completely separate I/O and
CPU bound tasks into two
different data structures,
two different runqueues, and then with
each runqueue associate a different kind
of policy that's suitable for
CPU versus for I/O bound tasks.
One solution for this, is this type of
data structure that we will explain now.
It is a multi queue data structure,
that internally it has
multiple separate cues.
Let's say in the first round of queue
we'll place the most I/O intensive
tasks, and
we will assign with this round queue
a timeslice of 8 milliseconds.
Let's say for the tasks that
are of medium I/O intensity, so
they have a mix of I/O and
CPU processing, we have a separate queue
in this multi-queue data structure.
And here we assign with this queue,
a timeslice of 16 milliseconds.
And then for
all of our CPU intensive tasks,
we'll use another queue in
the multi-queue data structure.
And here we'll associate with this
timeslice, basically that's infinite.
So this will be like the first come,
first serve policy.
From the scheduler's perspective,
the I/O intensive tasks
have the highest priority,
which means that the scheduler will
always check on, on this queue first.
The queue that's associated
with the I/O Intensive Tasks.
And the CPU-bound tasks will be
treated as tasks with lowest priority.
So, this queue will be the last one to
be checked when trying to figure out
what is the next task to be scheduled.
So, depending on the type
of task that we have,
we place it in the appropriate queue.
And on the other side, the scheduler
selects which task to run next.
Based on highest priority,
medium, and then lowest.
So in this way we both provide
the time slicing benefits for
those tasks that benefit for
the I/O bound tasks, and
avoid the time slicing overhead for
the CPU bound tasks.
But how do we know if a task is CPU or
I/O intensive?
How do we know how I/O
intensive is the task?
Now we can use for
that some history based heuristics,
like slide the task run and
then decide what to do with it.
Sort of like what we explained with
the shortest job first algorithm.
But, what about new tasks, or
what about tasks that have dynamic
changes in their behavior?
To deal with those problems, we will
treat these three queues not as three
separate runqueues, but as one
single multi-queue data structure.
This is how this data
structure will be used.
When a task first enters the system,
so a newly created task will
enter it in the topmost queue.
The one that has the lowest
timeslice associated with it.
It's like we're expecting that
it's the most demanding task.
When it comes to these scheduling
operations that it will need
to be context which most often.
If the task stops executing before these
8 milliseconds, so whether it yields
voluntarily or it stops, because
it needs to wait an I/O operation.
That means we made a good choice.
The task is indeed fairly
I/O interactive, and so
we want to keep the task in this level.
So next time around,
when it becomes runnable,
after that I/O operation completes, it
will be placed in this exact same queue.
However, if the task ends up
using up its entire timeslice.
That means that it was more CPU
intensive than we originally thought.
So we will push it down the next level.
It will be preempted from over here, but
then the next time it needs to run, it
will actually be pushed into this queue,
so it will be scheduled from this queue.
If the task ends up getting preempted
when it was scheduled from this queue,
so it used up its entire
60 millisecond time slice.
That means that it's
even more CPU intensive.
So in that case it will even get
pushed down to the bottom queue.
So we basically have a mechanism
to push the task down these levels
based on its historic information.
Although we didn't know if a task
is I/O CPU intensive to start with.
We made an assumption, and
then we were able to correct it.
So we assume that it's I/O intensive.
And we were able to correct and
push it down these levels,
down to the lowest most level,
in case it's CPU intensive.
Now if a task that's in one of the lower
queues all of a sudden starts getting
repeatedly releasing in the CPU earlier,
then whatever the timeslice specifies,
because it is waiting on our operation.
There will be a hintto
the scheduler to say, oh, well,
this task is more I/O intensive
than I originally thought.
And it can push it up at one of the
queues that are on the higher levels.
This resulting data structure is
called the multilevel feedback queue.
And for the design of this data
structure, along with other work on time
sharing system, Ferdando Corbato
received the Turing Award,
which is like the highest
award in computer science.
It's the equivalent of
the Nobel Prize for computing.
I want to make sure you don't trivialize
the contribution of this data structure,
and say that it's equivalent
to priority queues.
First of all, there are different
scheduling policies that are associated
with each of the different levels
that are part of this data structure.
More uniquely, however,
this data structure incorporates
this feedback mechanism,
that allows us over time to adjust
which one of these levels will be place
a task, and when we're trying to figure
out what is the best time sharing
schedule for the subtask in the system.
The Linux, so called O of one scheduler,
that we will talk about next,
that uses some of the mechanism borrowed
from this data structure as well.
And we won't describe the Solari
scheduling mechanism.
But I just want to mention that that's
pretty much a multi-level feedback queue
with 60 levels.
So 60 subqueues.
And also some fancy feedback
rules that determine how and
when a thread gets pushed up and
down these different levels