Okay, let's review the answers.
You do need to request
permission in order to read or
write events in the user's calendar,
because it's private user data.
These article details how to interact
with the user's calendar on a device.
The permission section talks about how
you need to declare the read and/or
the write calendar permission
depending on your needs.
So going back to the quiz,
in order to play audio or
video in the app,
you do not need to declare a permission.
We implemented this feature
in the Miwok language app,
where we played audio files for
the pronunciation of each word.
And we didn't need to declare any
special permissions in the app.
You can verify this in
the media playback guide.
A little note, though.
This guide does point out that if
you stream music in realtime from
the Internet or
need to keep the screen from dimming,
you do need to request
special permissions.
Next, if you want to access the user's
location, which is highly sensitive and
private information, then you definitely
do need to request permission.
This guide explains how to get
the last known location of the user.
You can either ask for
coarse or fine grain location.
Coarse means a rough estimate for
user location, say within a city block,
whereas a fine grain location means
the very precise location of the user.
Last but not least, for
showing a notification on device, you do
not need to request special permission.
Any app can pop-up a notification,
but there are best practices
on when you should show on, so
you don't annoy your users.
This guide walks you through how to
pop-up notifications in Android.