There's one more important feature
with Firebase Authentication.
After a user has successfully
signed into the app,
we'd also like our user to be able to
eventually be able to log out as well.
Let's write the code for
this sign out button.
To do that, we'll modify
the onOptionsItemSelected callback for
the sign out menu button
from the main activity.
Let's scroll down to that method.
Okay, here we are.
I'm going to add
a switch statement here.
Okay, this is just the standard code
to react to menu button clicks.
Right here is the case if they've
click the sign out menu button.
FirebaseUI makes signing
out really easy.
Here, I'm going to do it for
you in one line of code.
All you have to do is call Auth.UI,
get an instance and
then call the signOut method.
You pass in an activity instance and
your user is signed out.
If you take a look at the FirebaseUI
authentication documentation,
you can see that this one line
handles signing out from FirebaseAuth,
from Smart Lock passwords and
from log in providers like Google or
Facebook if that scheme is used.
Okay, let's go ahead and
build the new app and try it out.
Okay, here I am, logged in to the app.
I just sent an authenticated message.
And now, I'm going to try to sign out.
Cool and
it takes me back to the log in screen.
We now have authentication
fully working in friendly chat.
Nice work.