A technique called Gibbs sampling,
named after the physicist Josiah Gibbs,
takes all the evidence into account and not just the upstream evidence.
It uses a method called Markov Chain Monte Carlo, or MCMC.
The idea is that we resample just one variable at a time
conditioned on all the others.
That is, we have a set of variables,
and we initialize them to random variables, keeping the evidence values fixed.
Maybe we have values like this,
and that constitutes one sample, and now, at each iteration through the loop,
we select just one non-evidence variable and resample it
based on all the other variables.
And that will give us another sample, and repeat that again.
Choose another variable.
Resample that variable and repeat.
We end up walking around in this space of assignments of variables randomly.
Now, in rejection and likelihood sampling,
each sample was independent of the other samples.
In MCMC, that's not true.
The samples are dependent on each other, and in fact,
adjacent samples are very similar.
They only vary or differ in one place.
However, the technique is still consistent. We won't show the proof for that.