>> Third grade math. 'Kay? Exactly right. However it's unlikely we're going to
have it, we're going to want to model a state machine that has 720 states in it.
With state charts, we can reduce this to two concurrent finite statement
machines totaling 72 states. One for the hour and one for the the minutes. But
even that seems little bit over, overkill here. Resi regardless of
which version we choose, the resulting state chart would still be crowded and
not all that useful. Instead, we will abstract the machine into a single node,
labeled clock time. And assume, that the underlying logic for
computing the correct signals to cause the lights to display.
There are 720 different possibilities work as expected. Deciding just how
to abstract the many possibilities for percepts is a key skill in state chart
model. We can do the same abstraction on the WakeTime and SleepTime displays,
giving us a simple three state machine that looks like what we're seeing here.
Note that we have not yet labeled the transitions between the states with
events, that step will come later.