To illustrate the structure
of the RPC system
I will walk you through an example.
Consider a client and server system.
The client wants to perform
some arithmetic operations,
let's say addition, subtraction,
multiplication, but doesn't know how to.
The server is the calculator process,
and
it knows how to perform
all of these operations.
In this scenario,
whenever the client needs to
perform some arithmetic operation.
It needs to send the message
over to the server that
specifies what is the operation it wants
performed, as well as the arguments.
The server is the one that has
the implementation of that operation.
So it will take those arguments,
perform the operation, and
then return the results.
To simplify all the communications
related aspects of the programming, like
creating sockets, allocating managing
the buffers, for the arguments and for
the results, and all the other detail,
this communication pattern will use RPC.
Let's consider in this example
the client wants to perform an addition.
It wants to add i and
j and it wants to obtain the results
of this computation in k.
The client doesn't have the
implementation of the addition process,
only the server knows how to do it.
However, with RPC the client is still
allowed to call something that looks
just like a regular procedure
k equals add of i and j.
In a regular program,
when a procedure call is made
the execution jumps to some
other point in the address space
where the implementation of that
procedure is actually stored.
So the program counter will be set to
some value in that address space that
corresponds to the first
instruction of the procedure.
In this example, when the RPC add is
called the execution of the program will
also jump to another location
in the address space.
But it won't be where the real
implementation of add is,
instead it will be in
a stub implementation.
From the rest of the client's process it
will look just like the real add, but
internally what this stuff does
is something entirely different.
The responsibility of the client's
stub is to create a buffer and
populate that buffer with all
of the appropriate information.
In this case, it's the descriptor of
the function that the client wants
the server to perform, the add, as well
as its arguments, the integers i and j.
The stop code itself is automatically
generated via some tools that are part
of the RPC package so the programmer
doesn't have to write this code.
So when the client makes the call at
here the call takes the execution of
the client process into a portion
of the RPC run time, and
by that we mean the system software that
implements all of the RPC functionality.
In the first step here is
that stub implementation.
After the buffer is created,
the RPC run time will send
a message to the server process.
This may be the TCP/IP sockets or
some other transport protocol.
What we're not showing in this
figure is that there is some
information about the server
machine like the IP address and
the port number where this
server process is running.
That is available to the client.
And that information is used by the RPC
run time to establish the connection,
and to carry out all
of the communication.
On the server side when
the packets are received for
disconnection they will be
handed off to the server stub.
This is a code that will
know how to parse and
interpret all the received bytes in the
packets that were delivered to the stub
and it will also know how to determine
that this is an RPC request for
the procedure add with arguments i and
j.
The servers stop once it sees that
it needs to perform this act.
It will know that the remaining bytes
need to be interpreted like two
integers i and j.
So it will know how many bytes
to copy from the packet stream,
how to allocate data structures for
these particular
integer variables to be created in
the address piece of the server process.
Once all this information is
extracted on the server side
these local variables are created
in the address space.
The stub is ready to make a call in
the user level server process that has
the actual implementation of all of
the operations, including the add.
Only at that point did the actual
implementation of the add procedure will
be called and the results of the edition
of i and j will be computed and
stored in a variable in the server
process address space at that point.
Once the result is computed,
it will take the reverse path.
It will go through the server step
that will first create a buffer for
that result and
then it will send the response back
via the appropriate client connection.
That will arrive on the client
side into the RPC run time.
The packets will be received.
The result will be extracted from
those packets by the client side stub,
be placed somewhere in memory
in the client address space, and
then ultimately the procedure will
return to the client process.
For the entire time while this
is happening, the client process
will be blocked on this add
operation will be suspended here.
It will not be able to continue.
Which is exactly what
happens when a client process
makes a local procedure call.
The execution of the client
process will continue
only once the results of that
procedure call are available.