This app was built in a very similar
way to the demo that switched map
types that you saw earlier on.
If you aren't familiar with the layout
in Gradle and manifest configurations,
check back to that video.
But I'm going to show
them a little bit here.
First, you can see in my bill.gradlel
file I've added the Services
library that gives me
access to the Maps SDK.
Then, in Android manifest,
I've added my open GL stuff.
And I've added the uses-permission stuff
for INTERNET, ACCESS_NETWORK_STATE, and
WRITE_EXTERNAL_STORAGE.
I've also added the metadata for
the Services libraries here.
And then finally, I've added
the API key configuration here.
Now, remember, every time you
create a new application on Maps,
you're going to configure the API key
on your Google developers console.
So for example as you can see here,
here's my API key that I'm
using in the application.
And because I've called my map
com.google.devplan.almarone.maps33,
I also have to have a setting for it in
the Android applications, using the SHA1
key for my debug certificate followed by
a semi colon, followed by the app name.
So, you should see a list of them here,
and if you recall the apps that we've
been building as we go along in
the course, I've been adding them here.
And that's why they're actually working.
Okay, let's take a look
at the layout next.
And here you can see in the layout,
I've done the same as I did
in the earlier application.
I have a vertical linear layout,
and the first child of that is
a horizontal linear layout.
This horizontal linear layout
contains three buttons.
These buttons are button Seattle,
button Tokyo, and button Dublin.
I've just set their text to
be the names of the cities,
I've hard coded the text in this case it
might make more sense to put that into
a string XML in a real application.
And then the second child is the end
of the horizontal linear layout, so
the second child of the vertical linear
layout course is the maps fragment, and
here's just the standard
maps fragment setting.
Where it's a
com.google.android.gms.maps.MapFragment.
So as you can see,
the layout is virtually identical
to the layout we had earlier on
in the application that allowed you
to switch the different map types.
Now let's take a look at the source
code in the main activity.
Here you can see the main activity, and
I've created four camera positions,
NEWYORK, SEATTLE, DUBLIN, and TOKYO.
Of course, I'm only using Seattle,
Dublin, and Tokyo.
But I've put New York in here in case
you want to build the application using
New York.
And here with the latitude and longitude
that I had showed in the slides for
New York, for Seattle, and for Dublin.
And if you didn't find out you're on for
Tokyo, here it is for
you and this is available in
the speaker notes, this source code.
So these are constant camera
positions that I've created for
the names of the four cities.
Then in my onCreate,
I just wire the button handlers and
I only have buttons for
Seattle, Dublin, and Tokyo.
So in each one of these on the onClick,
I'm going to call this helper method
that I wrote called flyTo, and
it's flyTo the city name, so
if you click the Seattle button,
flyTo(SEATTLE).
If you click the Dublin button,
flyTo(DUBLIN).
If you click the Tokyo button,
you flyTo(TOKYO).
And then to look at the flyTo
helper method, you can see it here.
And here's where I
call the animateCamera.
So on my map,
I'm animating the camera, the
CameraUpdateFactory.newCameraPosition(t-
arget).
Remember, a parameter passed into
FlyTo is a CameraPosition target.
So when I said flyTo(SEATTLE),
I'm just flying to the camera
position that I called Seattle.
I'm taking 10 seconds to do it,
which is the 10,000 milliseconds here.
And then I'm just doing a null, so
when the animation is complete,
I'm not going to trigger anything.
One thing to note with Android apps
that use maps, as you saw when I demoed
earlier, as the camera flies across the
map, it doesn't slow down by downloading
the tiles in between the cities,
so sometimes you'll see emptiness
when I manually panned around the map
in the areas between the cities.
Further transitions after
that looked a lot cleaner
because we were seeing
places in between.
Because while I manually panned,
I was caching those tiles.
Now that we have a good feeling for
how maps work and
we've seen how we build cameras
to determine how we view the map,
let's switch gears a little bit and
talk about markers.