Let's start by reading the first error.
It says on Line 1, the Tag Text,
is not a supported opening tag.
So if we look at the line numbers,
line 1 corresponds to this one.
And indeed we see that the view
name should be TextView
without a space there, and
it should be camel case as well.
So, the capitalization is correct, but
we need to get rid of the space, so
now it recognizes that TextView
is what we're talking about.
That reduces one error.
Cool.
So, now, three more to go.
The next error says that the tag
TextView should be self-closing.
This means it should end with a forward
slash and closing angle bracket.
So, if we check the code, there should
be a self-closing TextView tag, but
we only see the closing angle bracket.
It's missing the [NOISE] so
we add that in.
There you go.
And now we're down to two errors.
Cool.
So the next one says,
The attribute androidlayout_height
does not support the value 150,
which is on line 4.
So we go to line 4, and
then we see that this code is incorrect.
We may not know what's wrong with it,
though, so we can compare it
to the layout width line above since
width and height are pretty similar.
Here we set the width to be 150dp.
We remember dp from our
earlier discussion of it.
And indeed we're missing dp for
the height, so let's add dp.
Woo-hoo, and
now we're down to one error.
And the last error says,
The color @android:color/darker_groy
is not supported.
Did you type it incorrectly?
In my mind, darker groy is not a color,
but darker gray is, so that is a typo.
So I'm going to erase the O,
type an A, and
yay, our device now updates to
show a preview of the TextView.
Oh, there's one more thing.
This Happy Birthday text is
actually spelled incorrectly,
but there are no errors for
that misspelling.
That's because the text for TextView can
be anything inside these two quotes.
So you can misspell anything that you
want or you can spell it correctly.
It really doesn't matter and
it will just show up like that.
When you're creating your app,
we're not checking for
the rules of English, we're checking for
the rules of XML Syntax.