Tell me about a time when I failed and
how did I deal with the situation.
So the time that immediately
comes to mind was
at one time I'd built this
application called Wow Census.
It was an application that gathered
up in-game demographic data for
the game World of Warcraft.
Hugely popular and
I severely underestimated the amount of
data that the users would be sending me.
Not only did I program
the parsers completely wrong,
I used the wrong language,
I was parsing the files very poorly.
I wasn't thinking about how that
would impact the server and
very quickly,
killed my shared hosting provider.
Had to go buy a dedicated server.
And that's pretty much how I
got through it was, I went and
found a friend that knew
more about this than I did.
And I could go to him and
I could say, listen I messed up.
Here's the problems I'm having,
I believe this is the solution.
And bounce that solution off of him.
And he did say, yeah that's what you
need to do here I hope you with it and
I can learn from him.
He was a system administrator so
he basically did the, helped me get
the dedicated server up and running.
And beyond that I would just
turn to programming friends and
say listen, I'm trying to parse
these files you know these files
are 300 megs large, thousands of lines.
But I'm only interested in
100 lines out of each one,
so how do you think is
the best situation handle it?
And so really leaning on that
support network around me.
And just learning as much
as I could from them.
Was really helped me get through that
and turned it into a successful product.
Thanks.