Once we have audio focus, we need to
worry about audio focus state changes.
So in this documentation here, for
AudioManager.OnAudioFocusChangeListener,
it says that we need to implement
the onAudioFocusChange method,
where we expect to be given
the new audio focus state.
So in the description of the
onAudioFocusChange method, we should see
that there are four possible states
represented by these constants.
AUDIOFOCUS_GAIN, AUDIOFOCUS_LOSS,
AUDIOFOCUS_LOSS_TRANSIENT, and
AUDIOFOCUS_LOSS_TRANSITION_CAN_DUCK.
So as developers, we get to decide how
to handle each of these state changes,
according to the type of media that
we're playing in our app, and also,
what the user would expect.
So now take some time to click on each
of these to learn more about each state.
Now in this quiz,
I want you to fill out this table.
So describe in your own words what
each of these audio focus states mean.
Then, write down what you think
we should in our Miwok app,
when we receive this state change.
So I want you to think about what type
of audio that we are playing, and
what an ideal user experience should be.