Hopefully this should've been
a pretty easy exercise for you.
If you'd not already done it,
set a breakpoint to the addBugToView
controller method and
we'll add a breakpoint action to this.
So let's add an action
that plays a sound.
Here we go.
Select basso.
[SOUND] Maybe basso, I guess.
Maybe I've been saying
that wrong all along.
And I'll set the conditions, we want
debugs count to be greater than ten.
Let's run the application.
[SOUND] And so when we tap the screen,
we hear the sound and it stops and
we can see that we have 11
bugs in our bug's array.
So this is kind a cool.
I think, you could imagine that
if you have some condition,
you want to make sure that's not being
triggered, or should only be triggered.
Occasionally you could
play some custom sound,
that makes it sound like your
computers about to explode.
And it will definitely
catch your attention.
And it could be really useful
to use something like this,
if you have maybe a system or
an application that needs to run for,
say 30 minutes, before your actual
break point is going to get triggered.
So, you can have it
running in the background.
And then when you hear the sound,
you know that it's happened.