So if you're running a web app,
knowing that there are NAT,
some proxies out there, means you
can't assume that all the traffic from
particular IP address is coming from
the same computer or the same person.
For instance, if you want to know how
many users are accessing your site, it
won't do to just count the number of IP
addresses you're getting traffic from.
Because a single IP address
could have many users behind it,
especially in the case
of carrier-grade NAT.
So, how could a web app distinguish
users who are behind the same public
IP address?
Mark all of these that
you think would work.
Could have used a logged in user
identity, such as a user name.
Could have used the speed of
the user's network connection.
Could have used session cookies.
How about the ethernet or
wi-fi MAC address?
Could have used Geolocation.
Or is it that none of these will work?