So in summary, basically I've
talked about how we can combine,
again, the whole ideas of panoramic for
imagery with video textures to
generate panoramic video textures.
Again, you know,
you saw lots of examples of
generating these kinds of things.
It's a step towards trying to build
those types of active photographs that
again you've seen in movies
like Harry Potter and stuff.
Of course, displaying them reliably and
in large format, of course,
means an interesting challenge, which
some of you can think about on your own.
And again, basically it takes the whole
idea of video textures and panoramas and
extends it to this new medium.
Please do look at the paper by
the authors of this idea and
the two other papers again we had looked
at when we looked at video textures
earlier are also relevant.
And again,
this is the website of the authors and
there is all of this basic video,
including also some of the code and
also the data sets that they
collected for this work.