So, let's look at this a little bit more formally and talk about maximum likelihood.
Obviously, we're observing 8 messages: spam, spam, spam, and 5 times ham.
And what we care about is what's our prior probability of spam
that maximizes the likelihood of this data?
So, let's assume we're going to assign a value of pi to this,
and we wish to find the pi that maximizes the likelihood of this data over here,
assuming that each email is drawn independently
according to an identical distribution.
The probability of the p(yi) data item is then pi if yi = spam,
and 1 - pi if yi = ham.
If we rewrite the data as 1, 1, 1, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0,
we can write p(yi) as follows: pi to the yi times (1 - pi) to the 1 - yi.
It's not that easy to see that this is equivalent,
but say yi = 1.
Then this term will fall out.
It's not proficient by 1 because the exponent is zero, and we get pi as over here.
If yi = 0, then this term falls out, and this one here becomes 1 - pi as over here.
Now assuming independence, we get for the entire data set
that the joint probability of all data items is the product
of the individual data items over here,
which can now be written as follows:
pi to the count of instances where yi = 1 times
1 - pi to the count of the instances where yi = 0.
And we know in our example, this count over here is 3,
and this count over here is 5, so we get pi to the 3rd times 1 - pi to the 5th.
We now wish to find the pi that maximizes this expression over here.
We can also maximize the logarithm of this expression,
which is 3 times log pi + 5 times log (1 - pi)
Optimizing the log is the same as optimizing p because the log is monotonic to p.
The maximum of this function is attained with a derivative of 0,
so let's compute with a derivative and set it to 0.
This is the derivative, 3 over pi - 5 over 1 - pi.
We now bring this expression to the right side,
multiply the denominators up, and sort all the expressions containing pi to the left,
which gives us pi = 3/8, exactly the number we were at before.
We just derived mathematically that the data likelihood maximizing number
for the probability is indeed the empirical count,
which means when we looked at this quiz before
and we said a maximum likelihood for the prior probability of spam is 3/8,
by simply counting 3 over 8 emails were spam,
we actually followed proper mathematical principles
to do maximum likelihood estimation.
Now, you might not fully have gotten the derivation of this,
and I recommend you to watch it again, but it's not that important
for the progress in this class.
So, here's another quiz.
I'd like the maximum likelihood, or ML solutions,
for the following probabilities.
The probability that the word "secret" comes up,
assuming that we already know a message is spam,
and the probability that the same word "secret" comes up
if we happen to know the message is not spam, it's ham.