In the previous lesson you wrote
your very first unit test.
Congratulations.
If you recall,
your test looked something like this.
You were calling an expect function and
then chaining a matcher
like to be on to the end.
In this lesson, you'll be writing tests
against a variety of synchronous and
asynchronous functionality.
You'll predict and write the code
required to pass these tests and
confirm the suite of tests pass.
Unfortunately JavaScript
doesn't have these testing
functions defined by default, so
we'll need to use a library that will
provide this functionality for us.
There are a few different
testing libraries available.
But in this course we'll be
using one called Jasmine.
It's a popular and
easy to use library in use at companies
like Pivotal Labs and Helpful.
For this course, you'll want to
use the 2.2 branch of Jasmine.
I've included all of the sample code and
Jasmine 2.2 and
a get help repository for you.
You'll find the link in
the instructor notes below.
Go ahead and clone that repository and
let's get started.