So our purpose here is
to now start seeing is,
can we actually find this red box?
Can we actually find a crop
of the original image and
just keep that red box inside
the scope of this entire image?
So here you see the red box move.
And basically,
it's a cropped version of the original.
This one is the result,
this is the original video.
And what we basically want to do
is find the best possible red box.
But we want to keep this red box cropped
so that I don't have to look for
pixels outside.
I don't want to look for
those black borders, and
I don't want to be able
to fill in the holes.
So our solution is basically
constrain the crop
window to stay within the frame bounds.
And also, this allows us to guarantee
that basically we never go into
an undefined content.
You don't go outside the borders, and
therefore, we don't have to do things
like in-painting, that is figuring out
how to do the pixel and color them
pixels around to be able to make
sure that there is no black regions.
Remember, this is the kind of stuff we
looked at when we were doing filtering,
where we had to flip images and
start doing simple stuff.
But, of course, in a video like this,
we would have to do a lot more,
and technique usually used for
that is in-painting and
actually does always create artifacts.