Our new empty list is better, but
it's not telling the user any good
information about why they
aren't getting weather data.
There's something easy for us to check.
Let's look at improving the integration
point between the sync adapter in our
application and the server.
This integration point can go
wrong in one of two common ways.
And, it's vital to make sure
that we're dealing with both.
The first case is when
the user gives us bad input,
either an empty response or
a non-JSON response.
This can happen when there is
an error on the server side, or
when the user is behind
a captive web portal.
The other case,
which we'll be tackling first,
is when we cannot connect
to the network at all.
This will result in outdated data and
a bad user experience.
And it's part of the reason our
onboarding case goes so poorly.
In oder to address this,
we'll do two things.
An onLoadFinished in
the forecast fragment,
if we see that we have an empty cursor,
we will write a check to see if
the device is connected to the internet.
If the device is not connected to
the internet, we will alter the message
displayed in the empty list to
reflect the lack of connectivity.
Because Android uses a permission system
to allow apps access to certain parts of
the devices functionality, we'll
need to have a specific permission,
ACCESS_NETWORK_STATE in our Android
manifest in order to check whether
the device is connected to the internet.
This is a separate permission from
the internet permission we already have
in our app.
We use the connectivity manager
to check for this state.
I recommend creating a function in the
utility class that can do this for us.
We're going to update the empty view for
no connectivity.
First, we're going to add
the ACCESS_NETWORK_STATE permission.
Then, you're going to want to add an
empty view the sibling to the list view.
In onLoadFinished in the forecast
fragment, as we just went over,
check for an empty cursor.
If the cursor is empty, check for
the network state using
the Connectivity Manager.
If the network state is not connected,
update the empty view message.
Once again, we can test this
by uninstalling the app,
putting the device into airplane mode,
and running the app.