One thing you'll notice is that
to actually make use of this
new image resource ID variable we added,
we'll need to modify the constructor so
that this new field can be
initialized to a specific value.
Recall that initialize means to first
set up the value of a variable, so
similar to what we did here for
initializing the mDefaultTranslation and
mMiwokTranslation variables.
And also remember that
a constructor is used to create
object instances from
the class definition.
Hm, how should we go about this?
Should we modify the existing
constructor or just add an additional
one so that we have two
constructors with different inputs?
A healthy way to inform this decision is
to think about the other Java code in
our app that make use
of this Word class.
So we know that three of the four
categories screens have images for
each vocab board.
And the exception is a phraser screen,
which doesn't have images for
each phrase.
So because we have the phrase
a screen that doesn't use any images,
we can have it use our current word
constructor that takes in two inputs,
an English and Miwok translation.
And then we can create another
constructor that takes in three inputs,
so two strings and
one image resource ID, and
use that same constructor for
our remaining three activities.
So think of having different
constructors as different ways to arrive
at an object instance.
The only condition is
that each constructor
has to have a different
set of input parameters.
So for example,
one constructor can require two inputs.
And we could have another one
that requires three inputs,
taking in two strings and one image.
And notice the data type matters.
So if we had a third constructor
that also took in three inputs but
took in two integers and
one image instead,
this constructor is different from this
one that also took in three inputs.
Remember when we were looking at
the documentation for ArrayAdapter?
And in the public contractor section,
we saw that there are multiple public
contractors that we could call to
create a new ArrayAdapter object.
For example,
we could have used this constructor,
passing in a context, resource
layout ID, and an array of objects.
Or on the other hand, we could have used
this ArrayAdapter constructor that took
in a context, resource layout ID,
and an array list of objects.
So all these constructor
options will work.
It just depends on what inputs we have.
And they'll all still allow us to
end up with an ArrayAdapter object.
To help us better understand
multiple constructors,
let's take a look at how
we can declare them.
So I'm going to search for that online.
So after searching up multiple
constructors in Java,
I think I'm going to take a look
at this third tutorial here.
So this tutorial has a section called
Constructor Overloading, and it seems
to be the same thing as multiple
constructors for a single Java class.
So let's click on that.
Hm, so taking a look here, it looks
like this is a simple example, and
we have a class called MyClass,
and it has two constructors.
Now the only difference between
the two lines of declarations for
the constructors is what
arguments they take.
So this first one doesn't
take any input and
the second one takes in
an integer called theNumber.
This example is important to us because,
similarly, we want one constructor
that takes an image resource ID and
another one that doesn't.
So in this example,
it looks like the second constructor
can have different behavior
from the first one.
So here it's initializing
this.number to be equal to
the number that's passed
into the constructor.
So it turns out this is pretty
much the same process that we'll
want to use to add a constructor
to our Word class.
We'll need to write a second
constructor declaration
that takes in an additional input.
And within that second constructor
it's going to do all the same work
as the original constructor, plus
initializing our resource ID variable to
the integer that's passed
into the new constructor.
All right, so on to the exercise.
So for the first task,
I'd like you to add a second
constructor to the Word class.
Now if you recall,
we use the Word constructor to
create an array list of words.
Thus, we need to update each
line in each category activity
to call the proper Word constructor now.
So let me show you what that means
by going back to Android Studio.
Here I am in
the NumbersActivity of our app.
We can change the first word in
the list to include an image as well
by simply calling the new constructor
and passing in three inputs.
As you may have noticed, Android Studio
has a great auto complete feature.
They'll make suggestions for what
resources you might seem to be typing.
So this can be really helpful if you're
trying to refer to an image resource but
can't remember the exact
name of the file.
If you find the one you want,
just go ahead and hit Enter.
Now you will notice here that
Android Studio is throwing us an error.
That's because we haven't
created our new constructor yet.
But once that's created, we shouldn't
be getting this error anymore.
Note there will be no changes
in the appearance of the app.
That will happen in the next step.