fontFamily is the attribute that
you would use to set the font for
a TextView.
Since we want the actual
font to be Sans Serif Light,
sans-serif-light is the value that
we use for the attribute fontFamily.
To make that a little bit more clear,
let me show you in Android Studio.
Okay, I'm back here in my
lovely activity_main.xml and
let's add some more attributes.
I'm going to start with
the Happy Birthday, Ben TextView, and
the attribute I am adding
is android:fontFamily.
Okay, and the fontFamily that I wanted
to use if you remember from the last
slide is sans,
that's with an s, -serif-light.
And as always, it's nestled
between two quotation marks.
Now, this is a little bit hard to see,
but
the preview view has updated to show
us the thinner, San Serif Light font.
You can see it best if you click on
something that's not the TextView, and
sort of compare these two look like,
since this is the old font and
this is the new font.
A couple of things to notice, or
problems that you might have run into.
These things here are dashes,
they're not underscores.
So make sure you get
that absolutely right.
And make sure you spelled
sans-serif-light completely correct.
For example,
the computer won't recognize
sans_serif_light with underscores.
You can see here it has
reverted back to the old font.
Also note, that when you hover over
the text, you might get this message.
Attribute fontFamily is only used in API
level 16 and higher, current min is 15.
If you remember back to when we made the
project, we set the minimum SDK to 15,
or Ice Cream Sandwich.
What this is telling us is, to use this
attribute, you need one higher version.
This isn't a huge deal but
basically what it means is that on older
phones you're going to see the old
chunkier font and on newer phones you'll
actually see the Sans Serif Light font.
Okay, so I'm going to continue on and
add the attribute to my other TextView.
Let's scroll down.
android:fontFamily.
Okay, and now on the preview screen
everything looks correct, but
always run it on your phone.
I'm going to hit the green run button.
I'm going to wait a million years.
I'm going to hit the phone,
going to hit OK.
All right, and when you load it up
on your phone, you should be able
to see that you have a little bit
of a thinner Sans Serif Light font.
Excellent work, two down,
three more to go.