All right, the answer for this one.
Let's look at the correspondences.
I need this point.
I need that again also.
That will get me the translation.
But this time around,
I have to also model this.
So I'll actually also
need another point.
So basically, we would need 2 points for
correspondences.
And how many degrees of freedom?
Well I need to know tx, ty.
And if I know theta, I should be
able to compute all of these, right?
So the answers would of course, here
would be, I would need to know tx, ty,
and then of course the cosines and
sines would show up with the theta.
So I need to know theta, tx and ty and
I can actually fill this out,
to be able to get the answers I want.
And these would be 0, 0.