Let's explore how to do this in Altrix.
We're starting with daily sales data,
that runs from January 1,
2015 to December 31, 2015, and
we want to aggregate the sales value for
each month.
When we look at the data,
we can see that the date field is in
a date format not a string format.
This is important to recognize, because
if we want to aggregate by month,
then we need to create a new
field that has the month in it,.
Then we simply use the values in that
new field, to group the data by.
We can easily create a month
field by using the formula tool.
Make sure to change
the type to a string.
Go down to the functions,
choose Date/Time, and
we'll use the Date/Time format function.
If we browse through the help,
going to the Functions &gt; Date/Time,
we can find information
around that Date/Time format,
and find the format string
that we need to pull out
the three character
month value which is %b.
So going back to the workflow,
where it says dt we put
in the field date, and
where it says f we replace
this with "%b" in quotes.
We can see the month value
appearing in this field.
Then we can add the summarize
tool to aggregate the data
to the new month field, and
sum up the sales values.
However, when we run this, we see that
the data is sorted by month name, so
the months don't appear
in their calendar order.
To fix this,
we'll go back to the formula tool and
add one more month field,
that represents the month as a number.
We'll use the same function again, but
this time we'll use % lower case
m to pull out the month number.
When we add this to
our summarize tool and
move it to the top, the data will now
be sorted in calendar month format.