All right, so that ends totally our lessons on frequency.
I'll bet you're glad that's over, I know I am.
As I said when we started this,
if you're doing image processing as an electrical engineer, you would be
doing a ton of work analyzing images in terms of their frequency content.
And you'd be thinking about image processing operations in terms of
their frequency behavior.
We, however, will only do this a little bit because as computer scientists we
tend of think of images more as data structures than as signals.
But we're still going to have to worry about things like frequency content when
we try to do things like optical flow where it's necessary that the image not
vary very much over some distance of approximation that I make.
So you'll actually have to do a filtering that sort of
removes that high frequency.
So, hopefully you now have enough understanding of Fourier analysis and
frequencies to be dangerous.
And we'll go ahead and practice being dangerous in the lectures to come.