Before going parallel, let's review
a very common CS101 algorithm on trees.
It will seem very
sequential at first blush.
Why, I do declare I find sequential
algorithms so embarrassing.
Now suppose you want to compute
a post-order numbering of the nodes
of this tree.
The classic procedure is recursive.
You're given a root.
You want to assign each of the nodes
of the tree a unique value
starting at a given value, V zero.
You maintain the last assigned number.
I've shown that here as the variable V.
The last assigned number is
what you'll eventually update,
assign to the root, and return.
But before you do all that, you'll visit
and number all of the descendants.
Each recursive descent returns
the last assigned value.
The next assigned value is the last one,
plus one, which you then overwrite in V.
So let's trace the execution of
this routine on this sample tree.
We'll start with the root which
happens to be numbered zero, and
we'll assign values starting
at the initial value of zero.
The first part of the algorithm will
descend to, say, leaf number four.
This descent carries the initial value
of zero all the way to that point.
Since node 4 had no children,
it gets the initial value.
It also returns that value.
The parent caller,
which is node 1, will receive 0.
The next child will get the next
initial value, which is 0 + 1 = 1.
So continuing,
you should get this final numbering.
So how do you parallelize the scheme?
On the one hand, it looks sequential.
It looks like you have to number all
of the nodes' children before you can
number a node itself.
On the other hand, doesn't this look and
smell a little bit like list ranking or
list scan?
>> Quack.
>> If only you had an efficient
way to convert a tree to a list.