Let's now take a quiz in which we will
look at a hypothetical experiment,
and we'll try to determine if the
experiments we're planning to conduct
will allow us to make
meaningful conclusions.
A toy shop manager wants
to determine how many
workers he should hire in order to be
able to handle the worst case scenario
in terms of orders that
are coming into the shop.
The orders range in difficulty starting
from blocks, which are the simplest,
to teddy bears, to trains,
which are the most complex ones.
The shop has 3 separate working areas,
and
in each working area there are tools
that are necessary for any kind of toy.
These working areas can be
shared among multiple workers.
Which of the following experiments that
represented as a table of types of order
that's being processed and number of
workers that processes this order will
allow us to make meaningful conclusions
about the manager's question?
The first configuration
has three trials.
In each trial, we use trains as
the work load, so order of trains,
and we vary the number of workers,
3, 4, and 5.
In the second configuration,
again, we have three trials.
The first trial consist order
of blocks with 3 workers.
The second trial is an order
of bears with 6 workers.
And the third trial is an order
of trains with 9 workers.
In the third configuration
in each of the trials,
we have a mixed set of orders
of all the different kinds, and
we vary the number of
workers from 3 to 6 to 9.
And in the fourth configuration in
each of the trials, we use a set of
train orders, and we vary the number
of workers from 3 to 6 to 9.