Here's the send
notification helper method.
This method takes our string,
and turns it into a notification,
as we saw demonstrated earlier on.
I'm not going to through all the ins and
outs of creating a notification.
You should have covered that already
in the Android fundamentals class, or
you can just use this source code,
and check the Google developer
documentation for details on how to
built notifications for yourself.
The important thing to take
a look at here are as follows.
First of all you'll notice that the send
notification takes in notification
detail string as a parameter.
Then, when it creates the notification,
if I just scroll up a little bit,
we'll see in the builder for
the notification, the set content title
becomes our notification details.
Our set content text becomes click
notification to return to the app, and
our intent becomes the notification
pending intent itself, and
as a result this is all we have to do.
It's a standard notification
that we actually build.
We're just sending the text to this
of the notification details, and
the notification details is what
you just built earlier on where you
had a list of the action followed by all
of the IDs that triggered that action.
So, when I demonstrated it earlier on,
I had a geo fence called udacity, and
when I triggered that by entering
within one mile of udacity,
it just showed entered udacity, and
that's what was sent here in the sent
content title, the notification details.
So, this is all it takes.
It's a standard notification builder.
Again, if you're not familiar with this,
check the documentation on
notification builders, or check
the underwrite fundamentals courses, or
just use this code and dissect it.
You'll see the links in
the speaker notes below.