What if, over here I've got
something spinning and over here,
I've got something translating.
No, sorry, expanding.
I'm expanding.
What I've got is I've got
different motion regions and
I need to find those
different motion regions.
So, some nice work done, again,
a long time ago by, Ted and John Wang,
I'm going to call
layered representations.
The idea is,
what if we could break the image up into
a bunch of different motion regions?
Okay.
And in fact that is illustrated here.
So this is a, a figure taken
directly from their paper, so
the idea is we have a hand
that's moving across, and
it's against the background of checkers,
squares moving this way,
because we're always moving our
hands over, moving checkerboards.
I don't know, it's just what they did.
Okay?
So, here they're showing you each of the
frames, and clearly, what you'd like to
do is you'd like to be able to recover
those different elements that the front
part is moving this way, and
the back part is moving that way.
So, here's how we do it.
Here's our affine equations, again.
So we have these local flow estimates,
right?
So, compute some local flow some way.
Maybe you use straight Lucas-Kanade,
all right?
Notice that this one equation.
Let's just worry about the u,
for, for right now.
That's a linear equation in x and y.
That's just sort of a plane.
In fact, if we were just doing this
in 1D, it would be a line, right,
forget the y,
just say that u is equal to a1 plus a2x.
It would just be a, a, a, a line.
These are linear systems.
All right.
So, the way this works is the following.
And here's an example done from 1D,
again taken from that paper.
Suppose this is the velocity
as a function of x, so
we are only showing you the 1D version,
cause its a lot easier.
And lets suppose that this is the true
flow, and what we mean by the true flow
here is that the foreground region
is actually moving in some way and
its not a constant because its an affine
flow, that is it's a, it's planar.
And the background might
be moving some other way.
And what we want to do is,
we want to be able to find that.
So the first thing you do is
you do a local flow estimate.
Lucas-Kanade everywhere, let's say.
That gives you some vectors.
Now those vectors are not perfect.
They are what they are, okay?
Well, what you do then is,
you take a look at those values.
Where do I see big jumps?
I see a jump there, I see a jump there,
I see a jump here, I see a jump there.
And I break that up into those segments,
and then what I do is I take a look at
the segments, and I say, which segments
seem to be along the same plane?
And it's planar because
of this affine equation.
And when you do that,
you get to automatically separate
out the foreground motion from
the background motion just by
fitting it says line fitting but
essentially by fitting the affine
plane to what's going there.