The answer is here he's eaten 1, here he's eaten 0, and here he's eaten 1.
That's fine. The problem arises when we start backing up these numbers.
If these are max nodes, we've skipped the opponent's moves, which are the min nodes.
We're only looking at the maxes.
The max of 1 is 1, so this would also get an evaluation of 1.
The max of 0 and 1 is 1, so this would also get an evaluation of 1.
This final node would be the max of 1 and 1, so that's also 1.
But now when we go to apply the policy, if we're in this position,
using these evaluation functions, both of these moves are equally good.
The Pacman might choose this one,
choosing at random or choosing by some predefined ordering.
Then he'd end up in this state. So far he hasn't eaten anything.
But this state is just as good because he knows in two moves he can eat one particle
going this way just as well as in two moves he can eat one particle going this way.
Now he's in this state, but notice that this state is symmetric to this one.
On his next turn, if we did another depth-two search,
he might just as well go back one position.
He would be stuck going back and forth between these two states,
because either one of those, if you look ahead only two, is equally good.
You have to look ahead one, two, three, four moves to know
that one of them is better than the other.
This is known as the horizon effect.
The idea is that when we cut off search we're specifying a horizon
beyond which the agent can't see.
If a good thing or a bad thing happens beyond the horizon, we don't see that.
All we see is whatever is reflected in the evaluation function.
If the evaluation function is imperfect, we don't see beyond the horizon,
and we can make mistakes.