So let's work on the first
item in our plan,
modifying the list item
layout to include an image.
Notice in this screenshot, we're using
a placeholder image and each list item.
Later on, when we get the actual images,
we'll substitute it back in.
Now in this coding task, I want you to
make the appropriate layout changes.
We want the list item to look like this,
with the placeholder image on the left.
And remember, as a hint,
to use the basket icon as
a placeholder by referring to
it as @mipmap/ic_launcher.
Since we don't have the final set
of images from our designer yet,
let's make use of a placeholder image.
And we can use an image
that's already in our app, so
the basket icon that we used for
the app launcher icon.
And remember, that can be found
under res &gt; mipmap &gt; ic_launcher.
And there's a number of
different sizes here.
So as discussed in the hint here,
we can refer to an app icon by setting
the source of an image view
to be @mipmap/ic_launcher.
And it's called ic because
it's short for icon.
And launcher refers to
the Android home screen launcher.
So for your background information
on why we refer to the basket icon
by referring to it as ic_launcher,
in Android,
the launcher is the home screen.
And to get to the app store, we tap
here to see the list of all the apps.
So for our Miwok app, the basket
icon is our app launcher icon, and
tapping on it opens our app.
When you're done making those changes
to the list item layout XML file,
run the app on your device.
When you open up a specific category
activity, like the numbers activity,
each of these list items should look
like this, with a basket icon on
the left and the Miwok and English
word stacked vertically on the right.
So I know this might look a little funny
now with all these placeholder icons,
but this is just a small step
towards building the whole feature.
So making sure that the layout is
correct and appears on the phone,
even if it has the wrong image,
means that we're on the right path.
So when you're done making
these changes, go ahead and
check this box when you're done.