Now that we've touched on the three
most complex components of the camera,
let's talk about the rest.
Right after the Projection
property is the Field of View.
This controls the vertical angle
that the camera will capture
with a perspective projection.
Based on this value and
the screen size, Unity will calculate
the horizontal field of view.
By default, Unity sets this
field of view to 60 degrees.
Depending on the headset,
this value needs to change, but
this will usually be
taken care of by an API.
Since we talked about screen size,
let's jump to the Viewport property.
The Viewport property allows us
to control where on the screen
our camera image is rendered.
Normally, a camera renders
to the whole screen width.
But with this property, we can assign
what percentage of the screen to use.
This will be very useful in creating
a virtual reality camera system.
The property we skipped over is Clipping
Planes, which is primarily used for
efficiency purposes.
Unity defines two planes in front
of the camera called the near and
far clipping planes.
Anything inbetween those
planes will be rendered and
anything outside of it won't.
This is an optimization
called FRSs Num Calling.
And the closer the near and
far planes are to each other,
the better performance you will achieve.
There are a few more properties
on the camera, but for
the purposes of creating our own VR
camera system we won't need them.
If you want to learn more about other
properties feel free to play around with
them or just read the further reading.
For next up, let's learn how we can
use cameras to make VR a reality.