So in this case, the feature worked
great in development and testing, but
those environments
didn't match production.
The firewall rules are an important
part of the production system.
They're what's keeping it running, but
they aren't represented in
the development environment.
So that's one problem.
However, it wasn't really
a performance problem.
So this one's not a right answer.
Rather it was a bug that never got
addressed by developers because
an operational fix that was meant
to be temporary relieved the pain,
made it not urgent anymore.
Now, firewalls are actually
a pretty good tool.
So, number four here is not correct.
And properly fixing this
problem in both the short and
the long term required both ops and
dev skill sets.
So this last one isn't right either.
So to recap, the problem was that ops
correctly deployed a workaround, but
as a consequence the bug
was never actually fixed.
And the change that ops made to
the production environment was never
reflected in the development
environment.
So developers and
testers didn't notice that their new
feature wouldn't work in production.