Define something called discretionary
access control, it's called DAC.
In these kind of policies,
who has access to a resource
is at the discretion of
the owner of that resource.
So Alice owns a file, it's at her
discretion whether she's going to allow
Bob to read it or write it, or Bob is
going to be prevented from accessing it.
Furthermore, she can
actually say whether Bob can
propagate the access to somebody else,
access he gets from Alice.
So in this question we are saying,
Alice actually is going to grant read
access to this file foo, to Bob,
but she's not allowing Bob to
propagate this access to anybody else.
And that is discretionary
access control model
is basically an Access Control Matrix
that we have.
She is going to put a read
access in the cell or
the entry that we have for
Bob and foo, okay?
So the column for foo and
the row for Bob, if you look at ACM,
Bob,foo there's going to be
read access rights there.
So the question is asking,
does this ensure that a third user,
Charlie, will not be able to read the
sensitive data that is in this file foo,
or is there some way for
Charlie to gain access to this data?