So far we glossed over any discussion
of what is the appropriate page size or
how large is a page.
In the examples that we showed so
far, regarding the address formats,
we use 10-bit for the offset or
12-bit for the offset.
Well, this offset determined what is the
total amount of addresses in the page.
And therefore,
it determined the page size that we
were discussing in those examples.
So in the examples in which we had
a 10-bit offset in the address field,
that meant that these 10 bits could be
used to address 2 to the 10th bytes
in the page.
And therefore it meant that
the page size is 1 kilobyte.
Similarly, the examples that had
a 12-bit offset for the address format.
That means that they could have
addressed 4 kilobyte pages,
2 to the 12th.
But what are the page
sizes in real systems?
These are some examples
that we cooked up.
In practice,
systems support different page sizes.
For Linux and x86 platform,
there's several common page sizes.
4 kilobyte page size is pretty popular,
and
that's the default in
the Linux x86 environment.
However, page sizes can be much larger,
2 megabytes, 1 gigabyte.
The 2 megabyte pages
are referred to as large pages,
as opposed to the regular
4 kilobyte ones.
In addition, x86 supports huge pages and
these are 1 gigabyte in size.
In the first case, to address 2
megabyte of content in a page,
we need 21 bit for the page offset.
And in the case of a huge page,
we need 30 bits as an offset to
compute that physical address.
So one benefit of using these
larger page sizes is that
more bits in the address are used for
these offset bits.
And therefore fewer bids are used to
represent the virtual page number, so
there will be fewer entries that
are needed in the page table.
In fact, use of these large page
sizes will significantly reduce
the size of the page table.
Compared to the page table size that's
needed when we're working with 4
kilobyte pages.
Large pages will reduce the page table
size by a factor of 512, and then
switching to huge page sizes will reduce
the page table size by another 512.
So in summary, the benefits of
larger page sizes are the fact that
they require smaller page tables,
due to the fact that there are few
page table entries that are needed.
And we can have additional benefits,
often such as, for instance,
increased number of TLB hits, just
because we'll be able to translate more
of the physical memory
using the TLB cache.
The down side of the larger
pages is the actual page size.
If this large virtual memory
page is not densely populated,
there will be a larger unused
gaps within the page itself, and
that will lead to,
to what we call internal fragmentation.
There will be basically wasted memory
in these allocated regions of memory,
depending on the page size.
So because of this issue, smaller page
sizes of 4 kilobytes are commonly used.
There are some settings like databases
or in memory data stores, where these
large or huge page sizes are absolutely
necessary and make most sense.
I should note that on different systems,
depending on the operating system and
the hardware architecture,
different page sizes may be supported.
So, for instance,
on Solaris 10 on SPARC architecture,
the page size options are 8 kilobytes,
4 megabytes, or 2 gigabytes.