Another cool thing you can do is do some form of a hashing based method in
order to index.
So, what I'm showing you here is what's called Wavelet-based hashing done by
Brown, Szelski, and Winder in 2005.
It comes from Szelski's book.
you, you can see it.
And, and basically the idea is this, so here's our little neighborhood.
Okay?
And we apply what are called these Haar wavelets.
Now wavelets are just a self-similar form of filters,
may be applied different scales.
We didn't talk too much about them.
That's okay.
But basically these are the three filters.
And these filters are, you know, sum up plus here, minus there.
Plus here, minus there.
And then plus here, plus here, minus there, minus there.
Okay?
So, what you do is, that means you'll get three different numbers, right,
from each of the three filter outputs.
And what you do is, you can then quantize each of those into ten bins, or
maybe ten overlapping bins, all right?
So, you have 10 bins 3, that means you have 10 to the 3 different possible
values that you can get out for a single application to the neighborhood.
And because the bins overlap, you don't have to worry about well, maybe I got
out a 4 vs a 4.1 for some value, because the bins don't have a, a sharp border.
They have an overlapping border.
So then what you do is, you compute these three numbers quantized to over 10.
That gives you 10 to the 3 possible bins to pick from.
And you go and you get that.
So that has, that reduces the set of neighbors that you have to look at,
or the set of key points you have to look at by a factor of
something less than 1,000, because overlapping bins, but
on the, between, again, between two and three orders of magnitude.
Pretty cool.