Welcome back to computer vision.
today, we're going to continue talking more about filtering and
sort of finish up the basics about that, so
then next time, we can apply that to more complicated uses of filtering.
And we're going to start by developing some linear intuition.
And the reason linearity is important will become clear in a minute.
Let's do a little intuition.
So an operator, we'll call it H,
or a system, is called linear if two properties hold.
And for what I'm going to show now both f1 and f2 are going to be functions, and
a is going to be a constant.
So the first property is called additivity,
which is basically just that the things sum.
So if I have some operator, and I apply that to the sum of the two functions,
f1 plus f2, I just get the sum of the operator applied to each of the function,
looks a lot like the distributive law of addition and
multiplication, but that's additivity.
And the other one, which is sometimes called scaling property, but
is actually technical term I think is homogeneity of degree 1, is just that if
you multiply your function, in this case, f again, by a constant a, and
then apply H, what you get is a times H applied to f1, and so when you
multiply by a constant, that constant just propagates through in a linear way.
We do some multiplication, and then we sum them, and because multiplication and
addition both have these properties basically,
the filtering operations we're going to do are going to be linear.
And we're going to take advantage of that later.