So there's one D block row algorithm.
Is it good or bad?
Start by recalling the running time.
Now, it's the first algorithm we've
talked about in a long lesson, so
it has to be bad in some way.
Let's pretend to be more analytical.
Start by computing the speed up.
The best sequential algorithm
pays only for flops so
its time is just two
times tau times n cubed.
Next let's plug in the parallel time for
the 1D block row algorithm.
Let me massage it into
a different form for you.
Now this form makes it easy to see how
the speed up compares to our ideal,
which would be something
proportional to p.
That is, if you want to know when
the speed up divided by p is a constant.
In fact, this concept of speed up
divided by p has a special name.
It's called parallel efficiency,
which I'll denote by capital E.
So a parallel system is efficient if
its parallel efficiency is a constant.
And higher constants are better since
they correspond to higher fractions of
linear speed-up.
Now in order to have constant
efficiency you need the denominator to
be a constant.
So when will the denominator
approach a constant?
In this case when N is big omega of P.
Now think about what it means
to be efficient in this sense.
Let's say you want to double
the number of nodes In order to solve
the problem faster.
Then this condition you've just
arrived says you also have to
double the problem dimension.
But if you double the problem dimension,
the size of the matrices will
quadruple because they're N by N.
Even worse, the number of flops will
have to increase by a factor of 8.
In other words,
if you double the problem dimension,
you have to double the amount
of memory you need per node and
you have to spend more time doing flops.
Dang, that's huge.
Yes, thank you, that's hilarious Tiny.
Put another way, if you don't or
can't double the dimension, then you'll
quickly see diminishing returns as you
increase the parallelism of the system.
By the way, this function or
this relationship between n and
P has a special name.
It's called the isoefficiency function.
That is, the isoefficiency
function is the function of
p that n has to satisfy in order to
have constant parallel efficiency.
Now there's one other consideration,
which is the amount of
temporary storage space.
Remember, you need temporary storage for
these B twiddles.
So, you have to store the three local
matrix upper ends plus the B twiddle.
That gives you four times n squared / p.
Okay.
So, that gives us a pretty complete
analysis of the time,
speed up, efficiency and
storage requirements of
the one D block row algorithm.
Good job, you.