Let's take a second look at the sources of errors.
Mathematics can help us find and solve numerical issues.
We can use the computer to a evaluate our model concerning uncertainty
and sensitivity but what about the model as such?
The model that we are using is really myopic. It completely ignores external influences.
It doesn't cover spatial variation.
What's going to happen if I over fish these fishes but I'll leave these fishes alone for instance?
It doesn't include by-catch or if I try to harvest one species of fish,
I will almost invariably also find other fishes in the net including some of that effect is
one of homeworks, but the most drastic omission is that we don't think about food webs.
Consider for instance this situation, the purple species of fish feeds on plankton
but at the same time, these purple species is prey to the blue species.
If you harvest the blue species of fish, the purple species of fish will grow in volume
and may deplete the plankton and of course, there is a lot more of issues with this model.