All right.
You're done.
Let's take a look at my solution.
First, we create the attr's .XML file.
Then we add the declare styleable tag,
with the name
Location Edit Text Preference.
We create an attribute inside of that,
named minLength,
that takes an integer value.
Next, we created our
LocationEditTextPreference class
that extends EditTextPreference.
To really make sure things
are working correctly when we
read our styled attribute, we'll set
the default minimum length to 2.
We'll then call the obtained styled
attributes function from the current
theme, asking for
our LocationEditTextPreference style.
We can then get the integer value of our
attribute, passing in our default value.
Then, we need to edit our
preferences.xml file.
At the top of the file, we need to add
the name space of our custom attributes.
Then, we replaced our
edit text preference with
com.example.android.sunshine.app.Locati-
onEditTextPreference, and
set our custom attribute from min
link to the value we want, namely 3.
Finally, we need to test this.
Let's make sure our minLength
is being set appropriately.
And now we'll launch the application.
As you can see, minLength is set to 3,
being correctly read out
of our custom attribute.
But we're not using it yet.