So the second question, and I thought
Philip did really well on this,
was what happens when
you go to google.com?
And I think that's a great full-stack
question because a part of calling
yourself full-stacker, saying you're
full-stack is that you're able to
understand not just the different parts
of the stack, but how they connect.
So the way Philip explained
the networking layer to me well,
the way he explained how the browser
communicates with the server,
all those indicated that he is not
just a back-end candidate, but
a full-stack candidate, and
understands the full range.
I also really like it because
you can as deep as you want, and
show as much depth of knowledge as
you want in each specific field.
So yeah, those are the main reasons.