As you might have
anticipated from my hint,
the answer is of course that it depends.
So it could be more, it could be less or
it could be the same.
It all boils down to how you choice the
value of the tuning parameter, little s.
To see how, let's write down
an expression for the storage.
First, each node has to store
one block of A, B and C.
So that of course gives us
three n squared over P.
Now you also need buffers for
the two broadcasted strips.
The amount of storage depends on
the strip width, a little less.
So here are the cases.
S has to go between one and
N over root P, as you'll remember.
When S is less than one half N over
root P, then the total storage is
less than four N squared over P,
meaning less than the 1D algorithm.
Remember that the problem with a smaller
s is it increases the latency time.
Now if instead s is greater than 1/2 n
over root P then of course the storage
will be greater than 4 n squared over
P or more than the 1D algorithm.
In fact what happens when
s is its maximum value.
In that case the SUMMA algorithm might
need five times n squared over P worth
of storage compared to four times for
the 1D algorithm.
The interesting bit of course, is that
the strip width serves as a tuning
parameter which adjusts the relevant
importance of the latency term,
the bandwidth term, the overall
scaling and the memory requirement.
It's the overall simplicity
of a summa algorithm,
combined with this tuning parameter that
lets you trade off time and storage.
That made summa the gold standard for
dense linear algebra at least for
the better part of the last 20 years or
so.