The answer is obtained by counting plus Laplacian smoothing.
We find that there are 5 movies, 3 of which are old,
but thanks to Laplacian smoothing, we add 1 up here,
and because there are 2 classes, we add 2 down here,
so we get 4/7 for the probability of old under Laplacian smoothing.
Now for the next two questions, we need to understand how big the vocabulary is.
We have 1, 2, 6 different words in the movie title vocabulary,
so the dictionary size is 6.
In the category of old movies, "top" occurs twice.
Without Laplacian smoothing we get 2/6
where the 6 originates from the 6 words in the old category.
Now we add 1 on top and 6 on the bottom for the dictionary size.
We get 3/12, which is the same as 1/4.
Applying base root for the final question, the probability of old given "top"
given the probability of "top" given old.
It will be 1/4 times the probability of old, which is 4/7.
Now we have to normalize by the same expression over here
plus the expression for the new class.
The prior probability of new is 3/7,
and the probability of the word "top" given new is obtained as follows:
In the maximum sense you would get 1 word out of 4 in the new class to be "top,"
but because we apply Laplacian smoothing we add 1 to the top and 6 to the bottom,
which is 2/10 equals 1/5.
We plug in 1/5 over here, and then we work all these numbers together,
and they happen to be 5/8, which is the final result for this question.