Let's suppose I have two vectors so
I'm working from a point I've got two vectors.
I've got a vector S, that's in the direction of my source and
a vector N, that's in the direction of the normal of the surface.
All right.
Well those vectors are whatever they are.
Their unit vectors are sort of small s, small n.
So, remember I can project any vector up on the pq plain,
and that's what this is.
This is at the z=1 pq plain.
So I've got a pq for the normal, out of the surface and I've got like p sub s,
q sub s for the vector that is in the direction of the light source.
So when I write that I get the following, right?
Remember I said that our unit vector n is just p q one divided by
the magnitude of p squared plus q squared plus one squared square root of.
And likewise, the unit vector in the direction of
the source is this p s q s one divided by its magnitude, all right?
So far so good.
So we have an algebraic equation of both of those normals.
So let's suppose for a moment we have a Lambertian surface, then the only thing
that determines, in terms of the geometry here, the amount of brightness
that we see is just this angle i, which is kind of lost in this mess here.
But there it is, it's the angle between those two vectors.
And what I need to know of course, is the cosine of that angle, right?
That's the Lambertian surface equation.
Well, given all of this algebra, we can represent that cosine as follows, right?
The cosine of that angle is just the dot product of those two unit normals.
So it's the dot product of n, dot product of s.
Which is the dot product of these quantities which is written right there.
Okay?
So that, that is the representation in pq
space of what that cosine of that angle is.