SysV uses the following
shared memory API for
the high-level operations
we just discussed.
Shmget is used to create or
open a segment of the appropriate size.
And the flags include the areas
options like permissions.
This unique identifier is the key and
that is not actually magically
created by the operating system.
Instead it is explicitly passed
to the OS by the application.
To generate a unique identifier
the API relies on another operation
ftok which generates a token
based on its arguments.
If you pass to this operation
the same arguments,
you will always get the same keys.
That's like a hash function.
This is how different processes can
agree upon how they will obtain a unique
key for the shared memory segment
they will be using to communicate.
The following call attaches
the shared memory segments
into the virtual address
space of the process.
So we'll map them into
the user address space.
The programmer has an option to provide
the specific virtual addresses where
the segment should be mapped, or
if NULL is passed then the operating
system will choose and
return some arbitrary
suitable addresses that are available
in the processes address space.
The returned virtual memory can
be interpreted in arbitrary ways.
So, it is the programmer's
responsibility to cast that
address to that memory region
to the appropriate type.
The following operation detaches the
segment identified by this identifier,
so the virtual to physical memory
mappings are no longer valid.
And then finally the control operation
that the shared memory API supports
is used to pass certain commands
related to the shared memory
segment management to
the operating system.
Including the command to
remove a particular segment.
And that command is IPC.RMID.