In order to append a properly scaled
circle, we'll need to use three scales,
the x, y, and r scale that we
created throughout this lesson.
Remember, these scales let us input
a data value to output a pixel value.
Before I actually append the circle,
I want to make sure that the scales
that I've created are reasonable.
For China in 2015,
the life expectancy value was 77 years.
The income per person was 13,330.
And the population was 1.38 billion.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now, what's useful about this is that
we can preview where our circle will
show up.
The console.log function in JavaScript
simply prints the arguments to
the console.
So it takes this function
with this value and
evaluates it to get an output value.
So, we can expect our circle to have
a y value of 43 pixels or about there,
an x value of about 398 pixels and
a radius of 50 pixels.
Remember that this y value
of 43 pixels corresponds
to a higher portion of the graph.
We have a high data input value,
but a low white pixel value.
Because our y axis starts at zero for
the SVG canvas, and
increases as it goes down.
Let's try to append the circle
to the SVG element.
I store the SVG element into a variable,
so that way I can reference it later.
Now, I can append an SVG
circle by passing in
the string circle to
the append function.
Now, if I just ran this code a circle
would be added to the SVG element, but
it wouldn't be styled or
have any of its attributes set.
In fact,
we wouldn't actually be able to see it.
Let's go over to Mozilla to look at some
SVG elements, and what we can set for
their attributes.
So, I'm going to look at this list and
check out circle.
So, here we go.
It looks like, for a circle,
we can set cx, cy, and r.
If I scroll down a little bit,
I can get an explanation for
those specific attributes.
Clicking on cx, I see that this
attribute defines the x-axis
coordinate of the center of the element.
Which is basically
the center of the circle.
So cy would be the y coordinate for
the center of the circle and
r would be the radius of our circle.
Let's use D3 to set these
different attributes.
The first attribute that I'll set and
one that I didn't cover,
is the fill attribute.
This attribute sets the background
color for the circle.
The second attribute
allowed is the radius.
We want to use our radius scale here and
pass in our value of 1.38 billion.
And the last two attributes that I'll
set are the center exposition and
the center y position of the circle.
Again as you can see here
D3's chainable syntax
allows you to passes circle element
from one method call to the next.
You can keep adding different
attributes down the chain.
Running the code we see the red
circle appear on the page.
Now it's a little bit cut off and
that might mean that your radius
scale is a little bit too much.
So in that case we could go back and
change our r scale and then replot.
So first, I'm going to find the circle
and remove it from the page.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I'll just hit Delete, and
it removes it from our DOM.
I'll scroll back up to where
we created the r radius scale.
And I'll change the max radius
to a value of, say, 40 pixels.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now I'll rerun the code
to add our circle.
There that's better.
Sometimes you'll need to play around
with the radius scale in order to get
the proportions right for your graphic.
Now putting our graphic side
by side with the original,
we can see that China's red dot is
about where it should be on the page.
Nice work.
I hope you have a better sense of how
to learn and work with any new tool,
such as D3,
when you encounter it in the wild.
You can learn more about D3 JS by
reading through links that are included
in the instructor notes.
Or by taking a look at the D3
website and Mike Bostock's blog.
Next up, you can review all of the code
that we've gone through in one place.
So that way you can see which code
was used to create this graphic.
Then I'll hand it over to Jonathan,
who will recap and
walk you through one
last bar chart example.
Great work, and keep learning.