In this exercise,
you'll see the performance implications
of choosing suboptimal data structures
in containers when building an app.
To do this,
we use tools in the Android SDK
to identify performance issues related
to an inefficient data structure choice.
Now as developers, it's easy to overlook
the performance impact that comes with
writing code to store and manipulate
your app's data, so let's take a look at
a situation that explores this problem
and apply a performance mindset to it.
First, make sure you
download the compute and
memory sample application
linked in the notes below.
For this example, we focus on
the runtime of a method that generates
a list of numbers ranked
by their popularity.
For demonstration purposes, this method
is invoked when we press the following
button, dump popular numbers to log.
Now similar to previous examples, the
code seems to impact the frame rate of
our dancing pirate via slight stutter.
And if you take a look at logcat,
you'll see it running via the tag
popularity dump, like so.
Let's take a look at what is
happening under the hood and
learn to measure how fast
this code is running.
We want granular measurements of exactly
what's happening when we click that
button, so we use the trace classes,
begin section, and end
section methods to specify exactly where
we want the start of measurements and
where we want to finish them.
First, we zero in on the code that
is computing the popularity ranks,
which is this method right here.
See the instructor notes below for
the code stubs we'll use to instrument
the code and measure its runtime.
After the next two quizzes,
we'll run Systrace and
retrieve the running
time in milliseconds.