Handlebars makes it really easy to
create concise and expressive templates.
Pair that with dynamic data in a simple
handlebars template can handle a lot of
information.
We'll look at loading
dynamic data after this quiz.
But for now, I've done it for
you and saved the data to
a variable named model.
For this quiz you need to use
this model variable which has
all of this information and
build out a handlebars template that
displays all of it's information.
You'll need to use HTML, Handlebars
expressions, conditionals, loops,
the whole nine yards.
Make sure to build the template
in the stores.hps file.
I've already created this file for
you so
all you have to do is worry
about building out the template.
Here are the instructions
you need to follow.
One thing to be extra careful about
is to give everything the correct
class name.
Let me give you a quick
preview of the end result.
I have a section for red,
blue, and green bricks.
And each color has its
own set of bricks.
Some of the bricks are on sale and
I indicate that here.
Remember that all of this
information is already provided for
you in the model variable.
You just need to create
the handlebar's template.
A link to the starter code for
this project is in the instructor notes.
When you finished building the template,
the feedback extension
will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.
Ember uses the queue unit
testing framework, and
I've created a number of tests
that you need to satisfy.
These tests help guide you through
completing the assignment.
Once all the tests have passed, the
feedback extension will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.
You can find a link to this project's
test page in the project's read me file.