Believe it or not,
that's the end of this lesson about mapping from image to image.
It's a short lesson, I know, I needed a break, or you needed a break, or
somebody needed a break.
Anyway, what was happening was I had these lessons and
they were going on for like, 12 hours, and I said, that's probably not good.
So, in the interest of biobreaks everywhere,
we decided that we would shorten, some of these.
So, so that ends our sort of image to image transformation using
the projective, transforms.
And now, we're going to continue our conversation about projective geometry,
and, it'll get a little bumpy, so you know, take a breath; we'll charge ahead.
The cool thing is, the next thing we're going to do is make serious use of
homographies to, do something cool that will, wow and amaze your friends.
assuming, you have relatively nerdy and boring friends.
otherwise, their going to tell you to get out a little bit more often.
anyway, talk to you soon.