This time I start here.
And I go to the left,
because that is the positive gradient.
And I'm going to get to
the top of the global maximum.
>> But what's the chance that you're
going to get to the global maximum on
your second attempt?
>> Better than just
with my first attempt.
But I see what you mean.
We're computer scientists and
we have computer power to burn.
We can just do lots of random restarts,
hill climb until we reach the local peak
and then take the maximum
of all the durations.
>> How do you know you've
done enough examples?
>> Well, let's just do lots.
It's inefficient, but as our number of
samples goes to infinity it should work.
>> Well you could be more efficient and
keep track of the places on
the graph you've been before, and
restart the sample whenever
you've gotten to the same place.
That trick is called a taboo search.
As in, it's taboo to go
somewhere you've already been.
>> Well I could also just keep
a list of all the local maximum, and
try to get an idea of the general
shape of the problem and try
to predict where a new maximum might be,
given the areas I haven't explored yet.
>> That sounds like a variant
of the stage algorithm.
So what you are saying is that random
restart seems like a good idea
in general.
Given there are all these
improvements that have been made.
>> Yep.
Let's try a quiz on what
we've learned so far.