So now we found the intrinsic matrix.
And last time we found the extrinsic matrix.
So now we can combine them to get the total camera calibration that goes
from a world point all the way through the camera coordinate to the image.
So we write down our two equations here.
We have our intrinsic,
p prime is equal to K times the point in the camera frame.
And our extrinsic which relates the world point, to the camera point.
P in w is the world three dimensional coordinates transformed by
the extrinsic matrix, becomes the camera three dimensional coordinates,
which is used also in the intrinsic equation.
And then that's converted to pixels directly.
One thing to note here, is that our world coordinate system, is a four vector,
it's a homogeneous.
And we get out of four vector, but as we said before, for our K,
instead of using the three by four, we can use the three by three,
in which case we just use the x, y, z of the point in the 3D camera space.
We don't have to use the whole x, y, z, 1.
That's basically saying that this K can be thought of as a three by four or
a three by three.
And when it's a three by three we don't have to have that 1 on the bottom there.
So, putting these two equations together,
what we have is we take a world point here, we pump it through our extrinsic.
So, this is a three by four matrix, okay,
which gets us out of three dimensional vector.
And then we pump that through our intrinsic matrix, and
that get us our homogeneous image coordinates.
So this is a three vector.
Remember we said it was z times u, z times v.
Look at that.
My us and vs look the same.
Divided, and z, and then we convert it back.
And so this whole thing can be written as a single matrix M.
M for calibration in some language.
I have no idea why it's called M, but we call it M.