All right, so now it's time for
you to do this by yourself.
But I'll get you started off.
So head over to the data package and
create a new class
called PetDbHelper.java.
In that class we'll extend
our SQLiteOpenHelper class.
Now when you extend SQLiteOpenHelper,
remember that you'll need to
override the onCreate method and
the onUpgrade method.
And you should create constants for
the database name and version.
Also, don't forget the constructor for
the class.
So remember to also create
a string constant for
the SQLite command used
to create the table.
Now that we have this statement from our
cheat sheet, instead of just copying and
pasting it, we can use the constants
from the contract class.
And remember, these values here,
we've created constants for
those values as well,
so be sure to use them.
So, all the changes that you've
been making are hard to check.
So it’s hard to see and
know if they're correct.
We'll, I'm going to give you
two ways in order to see
if your database is working correctly.
So, the first way is a mysterious
method we've created
called displayDatabaseInfo.
And I like you to copy and
paste this code Into your code and
it will only work if SQL
is working correctly.
Now, the second way is actually
downloading the SQLite database file,
from your drive onto your computer.
And you can then through that examine,
if it was constructed correctly in
the terminal, using the techniques
that you learned in the last lesson.
So we'll discuss how to download
the database shortly but for
now let me show you the first option
of using the displayDatabase method.
So here is the code for
our displayDatabaseInfo method.
And I know we haven't
discussed it just yet, so
don't about its contents right now.
So by the end of this lesson,
you'll be able to understand
what all this code means.
And to follow along,
I highly suggest taking a look
at the full code link below.
I'd like you to copy over this
method into your CatalogActivity and
I want you to include it at
the end of the onCreate method.
Then run the application on your device.
And if you did all the steps correctly,
you should see some text outputted here,
in the CatalogActivity.
So you'll see number of
rows in pets database table
followed by a number which
I've covered up here.
So, if you don't see this sentence
on your catalog activity screen,
look over the steps above.
So, make sure that
the displayDatabaseInfo method
is correctly in the onCreate
method of our CatalogActivity.
And also double check to make sure
that your SQL statement is correct.
So finish up this exercise and
I'd like you write one number that you
see here, once you have the app running.
So if you find yourself
running to some trouble,
here's a little troubleshooting tip.
So Android will throw an SQLiteException
error when something is incorrect
in the SQLite statement.
So just maybe I've misspelled the word
create, leaving off the last e.
So if your app does crash and
you see an error output,
it most likely means something is
messed up with SQLite's string.
And it's just not
a valid SQLite command.
So don't worry if this does happen,
it just takes a little bit
of investigative work.
And Android is there to help you help,
giving you some tips
as to where to look.
So to iterate, here's what I'd like you
to do in order to create a database
with SQLiteOpenHelper class.
Follow these five steps for
the SQLiteOpenHelper class.
And I'd like you to log the SQL
statement string to make sure it matches
the SQL statement we've
listed on the cheat sheet.
Lastly, I want you to write the number
that you see when you run your code.
And write that number in right here.