To actually make this thing
work requires a lot of detail.
Finding those breaks is not trivial.
Clustering things is not trivial.
Fitting the lines, well that's pretty
trivial once you've found the clusters,
but you've got to find the right
clusters that belong to the right lines.
There's a lot of detail,
and you can take a look at the,
at the paper that we mentioned.
I just want to show
you the results here.
So here is again the flowerbed
sequence from mpeg.
And here what you can see is they've put
down what the different motions fields
they captured were.
One was the, the flowerbed.
And you can see that flowerbed is
kind of like a plane that's moving in
a particular way.
So that's one motion.
The house with the trees that are sort
of right by the house is another motion,
and the tree in the foreground
is another motion yet.
So it has done a motion
segmentation of the sequence.
So at the end of the day, it doesn't
tell you that all the points are moving
arbitrarily, like Lukas-Kanade does,
or even smooth Lukas-Kanade.
It doesn't tell you that they're
all moving the same way.
What it does is, it gives you this pa,
this broken-up pattern, or
this broken-up image sequence of saying,
this region is moving this way,
this region's moving another way,
and then this background region,
that's occluded by these regions,
is moving, yet, a, a third way.
And this is motion segmentation.
There's a lot of work lately
on video segmentation
it's an active area of research.
And there's always this, this question
of, you want to break it up into enough
pieces that you get out
the different elements, but not so
many pieces that you take something that
really should have been kept together,
and you break it into two parts.