One of the coolest deep learning
results from last year was
the Google Translate update.
They've been a leader in machine
learning for a while, but
implementing a deep neural network for
translation brought the service nearly
to the level of human translators.
With translation, the correct word
to use depends on the context, and
all the other words in the sentence,
and even in the paragraph.
Much of the information contained
in language is in the sequence of
the words.
So far, we've been working with what
are called feed forward networks.
The input is fed into the network and
it propagates forward through
the hidden layers to the output layer.
In feed forward networks, there is
no sense of order in the inputs.
Here's a simple idea then,
let's build order into our network.
First, we'll split up
the data into parts.
The text, this can be words or
individual characters like I've
done here with the word steep.
Going forward,
I'm going to borrow an example from
Andrej Karpathy because it's great.
Our goal here is to predict the next
character in the word steep.
To keep it simple, assume our entire
alphabet consist of S, T, E, and P.
Let's start with the normal
feed forward network.
We'll pass in the character S and
our desired output is T.
We pass in a T, we should get out E.
Now, we pass in that E.
In this sentence E is
followed by another E or a P.
The network, as shown here,
doesn't have enough information to
determine which character to predict.
To solve this problem,
we'll need to include information
about the sequence of characters.
We can do this by routing the hidden
layer output from the previous step back
into the hidden layer.
That box there means value from
the previous sequence, or time step.
Now, when the network sees an E,
it knows it saw an S and a T before, so
the next character should be another E.
This architecture is known as
a recurrent neural network, or RNN.
Now, the total input to the hidden
layer is just the sum of the layered
combinations from the input layer and
the previous hidden layer, ht minus 1.
We can view our recurrent network
as one big graph by unrolling it.
Now, we have a feed forward network for
each character but
connected through the hidden layers.
Each hidden node receives
inputs from an input node and
the hidden node from the previous step.
To make it a bit more understandable,
let's plug in some numbers here.
This diagram is borrowed from
Andrej Karpathy, with a few alterations.
Here, we're one hot encoding
the input characters.
So, 1000 is an S,
0100 is a T, and so on.
There are three units in
the hidden layer, and
the output layer is showing the logits.
You'd pass the logits into a softmax
function to get predictions and
train with a cross interview loss.
This is the basic architecture for
our character wise RNN, but
there are some improvements we'll need
to make, which I'll talk about next.