So what about this term
continuous deployment?
What's the difference between it and
continues delivery?
The continuous delivery process proves
that a specific code check-in
is production ready and
it then prepares it for deployment by
building and comprehensively testing it.
But there is usually a human
involved at the last stage.
It's usually a QA, or
operation sign off.
In some cases it's
a product order sign off.
And sometimes this is a step where the
pipeline will continue after some time
automatically, unless one
of these people interferes.
But with continuous delivery,
there are always one or
more possible manual interaction
points in the pipeline.
The converse of that is that
there are no manual steps and
the code can completely automatically
go from check in to the customer.
And this is called
continuous deployment.
Usually continuous
deployment is used for
stable software that has been around for
a long time.
And because it's stable, most of these
changes are small and bug fixes.
For software that's being actively
developed a lot of times the software
can change pretty dramatically.
If you're adding new features,
it's not particularly good to have
a completely automated process where
nobody manually checks it over.
It's also very hard to automate
user acceptance criteria for
software that's constantly changing.