um aquatics david ryan david used to
work at fort as a set of a kind near
before joining us today as an instructor
and ryan is a recovering astrophysicist
who was looking for a fun weekend outer
space couldn't find them and join us as
an instructor get exactly
awesome thanks Sebastian so the most
exciting part of this course is that at
the end of the course you'll be able to
put your own code on a real self driving
car in fact it's that car right there
behind us
that's right so welcome to the program
you and I are going to be learning
together to write code to drive a car
we're going to have David and Sebastian
looking after us and we'll be bringing
in industry experts to join us in the
classroom as well so let's get started
alright