We spend already quite a bit of time
talking about dealing with concurrency
in multi-threaded programs.
We explained mutexes and
condition variables,
both in generic terms based
on Birrell's paper, and
also their specific APIs and
usage in the context of Pthreads.
You're probably all safe and
well underway with writing your Pthread
programs using these constructs.
So you're probably
asking yourselves now,
why do we have to talk more
about synchronization?
We spent quite a bit of time
already talking about it and
gained experience with it.
Well, as we discussed mutexes and
condition variables we mentioned
a number of common pitfalls.
This included things like
forgetting to unlock the mutex, or
signalling the wrong
condition variables.
These issues are an indication
that the use of mutexes and
condition variables is not
an error-proof process.
What that means is that these
errors may affect the correctness
of programs that use mutexes and
condition variables.
And in general it will affect the ease
of use of these two
synchronization constructs.
Also, in the examples that we discussed,
we had to introduce some helper
variables when we needed to express
invariance to control a reader's
writer access to a shared file.
We also need helper variables to deal
with certain priority restrictions,
given that mutexes or
condition variables don't inherently
allow us to specify anything
regarding priority.
This implies that these
constructs lack expressive power.
We cannot easily express with them
arbitrary synchronization conditions.
Finally, mutexes and condition variables
and any other software synchronization
construct requires a lower
level support from the hardware
in order to guarantee the correctness
of the synchronization construct.
Hardware provides this type of low
level support via atomic instructions.
So these are some of
the reasons why it makes
sense to spend more time
talking about synchronization.
What we will do, we will look
at few other constructs, some of
which eliminate some of the issues
with mutexes and condition variables.
And also we will talk
about different types of
views the underlying
atomic instructions,
to achieve efficient implementations
of certain synchronization constructs.