We learned again when we talked about
video textures that we can actually find
loops in a video and
use that loops of similarity from frames
to the one frame to the other to
generate infinitely long videos.
Also, when we looked at video textures,
you may recall that we talked about
the concept of looking at videos,
specifically videos that have some
repetition, like this candle flame,
find similar features of similarity
between frames from one to the other,
use that now to generate
an infinitely long video.
In this case, of course, you see
the transition arch, which basically say
that I found a similar frame here and
I'm going to jump from one to the other.
That allows me to create
an infinitely long video of
something that actually has repetition.
Again, if you remember the previous
example, we talked about doing this for
flags, water, and
similar types of repetitious motion.
So now we have two
different ingredients.
So that, in essence, is what panoramic
video textures is all about.
Let's hear from the authors of this
paper as to how they actually kind of
facilitated this work.
>> Panoramic images are compelling
because they are immersive.
They communicate a sense of being there.
Panoramas show a wide field of view,
which lets us look
around within a scene.
However, panoramic
images are not dynamic.
So a panorama of this waterfall,
for example,
appears unnaturally frozen in time.
A video, on the other hand, can show
the motion of this waterfall but
still isn't immersive.
It isn't panoramic, and
it jars the viewer each time it moves.
Video textures, introduced by
Shodalosolve solve the looping problem
by creating a video that appears
to play continuously forever.
However, the result
still isn't panoramic.
In this paper,
we introduce panoramic video textures.
Panoramic video textures show dynamic
imagery for the entire field of view,
and can be seamlessly viewed for
any length of time.
Ideally, we would like to be able
to create panoramic video textures
without any special equipment beyond
an ordinary video camera and a tripod.
It would be nice if we could
somehow just pan the camera slowly
across a scene, and then create a
panoramic video texture just from that.
This introduces the key challenge.
The input video,
shown here at high speed,
only captures the dynamics of a portion
of the scene at any given time,
while the output must show dynamic
content at all times everywhere.
We begin by registering
the input video frames into
one global coordinates system.
Then, the user draws a single rough
mask that separates static and
dynamic regions.
We then create a static panorama for
the static regions.
Finally, we create a panoramic video
texture for each dynamic region, and
composite them into the static
panorama to create the final output.
Quite nice, huh?
So now, let's talk about different
stages that they go through
to build this.