Now that we've logged in with the API
it's time to create the session ID.
As seen in 's flowchart,
this is the last step necessary to
perform writes to user access data.
I'll help you out on this one,
the method that you're going to want
to use to get the session ID
is authentication/session/new.
This method is pretty straightforward.
It just takes the API key and
then the request_token.
It says that the request_token needs
to be approved by the user before being
used here, and that's what we did when
when we logged in through the API.
Now back in the completion handler for
loginWithToken, we need to go ahead and
call the getSessionID method.
This method's empty but
it describes the task at hand.
We need to get the session ID and
then store it in appDelegate.sessionID.
From there,
we can move on to get the user ID, and
we'll do that a little bit later.
So like before, implement the seven
steps and get the session ID.
Once it's received,
we can just print it for now.
When you're done, check this box.