So what are some examples
of good Kernels?
That become generals.
[LAUGH] Anyway.
All right.
Fine.
Well, the simplest kernel is actually
just the original linear space.
Right?
So if.
K of xi,
xj is just the dot product of xi, xj.
That's what I was showing you before for
the Dalal and
Triggs Pedestrian Detection.
Right?
You just have a great big long feature
vector and it, I don't even have to map
it into a higher dimensional space.
I'm just going to assume
that that's going to work.
Now and
the number of dimensions is what?
It's just N, where N was
the length of the feature vector.
So that's the lifting space.
Now something that I'm not going to
teach here even in some
higher dimensional space.
So when you pick, your system might
not be completely linearly separable.
Right?
And there's ways of learning support
vector machines in that situation.
I use what's called Slack Variables.
For those of you take
a machine learning class,
you learn a whole lot more about
how SVMs and Slack Variables work.
But basically what it does is it says,
let me try to find
the maximum margin possible.
Allowing for
the fact that some of my points
are going to end up on the wrong side.
Okay.
So that, that's how you handle that.
So even if you have this great
big long feature vector,
if things aren't totally
linear separable, you're okay.
So that's, when you have
a large input feature vector,
often its the case that
people use linear SVMs.
So heres another kernel.
Okay.
That people use, and
its very commonly used.
And it's a Gaussian kernel, sometimes
called RBF, Radial Bases Function.
So it's a kernel where just as,
as point moves away from
the support vecrum as xj moves away from
xi it just falls off like a Gaussian.
Just like a Gaussian bump.
Now, you might wonder, I did.
How is that exactly a kernel?
Well, and, and also because
that means that there is some
space in which this exponent,
exponential, is a docked product.
Okay?
And I realize I had learned this
before and I had forgotten it.
That this dimensionality of that
space is essentially infinite.
And there are a couple of ways of,
of thinking about this.
But the one that's the simplest is
it turns out you can write that
exponentiation or
that decay exponential this way.
Okay.
So here is my exponential the sigma
square rule, sigma square equals one.
And notice this is just some particular
value, so you just, the magnitude of x.
This is magnitude of x dot.
So for some x and x dot, it's fixed.
But notice that you're
taking dot products,
and you're taking
an infinite sum of them.
So it's the dot product,
raised to this j power.
Let me remove that.
Right?
So, it's the sum of, and the these terms
come out because they're constant.
It's the sum of this dot
product raised to the j power,
j equal to 0 equal to infinity.
Do you remember that e to the x was
an infinite exponential series?
Right?
So, way back in Mrs. McGillicutty's you,
maybe you didn't learn this in
McGillicutty's Algebra class.
Maybe you learned it in Miss Thompson's
Calculus class about infinite series
and, right, that an exponential, e to
the x squared, was x plus, x squared
over two factorial plus x cubed over
three factorial, in an infinite sum.
That's, see the factorial
here Here on the bottom.
That's related to the,
to the sum that's going on.
So the idea is that this Gaussian
kernel actually has infinite dimension
in its lifting space, but you know what,
we don't actually have to do that.
We can just use the Gaussian kernel.