This is the original XML
that we provided you.
It was a vertical linear layout.
And the items were appearing
in a vertical column.
According to the image in the quiz,
we want the item to look more like
a list item using a relative layout.
Here's the solution.
We've changed the layout so
that the photo is on the left and
the three text views are on
the right hand side.
In order to build this layout I changed
the root view to be a relative layout
instead of a linear layout.
Since this is the opening tag,
I also had to update
the closing tag at the bottom.
Between the opening and closing
tags we have four children views.
I also removed the vertical
orientation attribute
because that belonged
to the linear layout.
There's no orientation attribute
needed for the relative layout.
The photo was already
positioned correctly.
The first child of a relative layout
is always positioned by default in
the top left corner.
And that's what we want for
our list item, so this stays the same.
Next we have the TextView
that says Pebble Beach.
We want to position this TextView to the
right of the ImageView, so we need to
add the attribute layout_torightof and
then reference the image view.
In order to reference the ImageView
we had to add an ID attribute,
to the ImageView.
I just called it photo, but you can
call it something else if you wanted.
That correctly positioned the image,
and the first TextView.
The next TextView is for
showing the text California.
The California TextView has to be
positioned to the right of the photo and
must be below the Pebble Beach TextView.
So, first we add attribute
layout_toRightof and
reference the photo.
Then we add another
attribute layout below and
then we reference the first TextView.
That required also adding an ID for this
first TextView, we just called it name.
Cool, so that position,
the ImageView, and the two TextViews.
Lastly, we have the TextView that
shows the distance, 10 miles away.
It's positioned to
the right of the image and
below the California text view.
Thus, we had to add the attribute
layout_toRightof in reference
to the photo, and we also had to
add an attribute for layout below,
and then reference
the location TextView.
This involved adding the ID for
the location TextView as well.
I also added an ID for
the distance TextView.
Even though we're not
referencing it anywhere,
it doesn't hurt to add an ID to a view.
In the case that you do need to refer
to it later, it's already there.