In this next section, Peter will
teach us about logic and planning.
Peter, what important concepts
should our students look out for?
>> A logic is a way of
describing the world.
When we make logical statements,
we capture part of what we want to know
about the world, and ignore other parts.
Any description is only partial.
The beauty of logic is that once we've
made some statements about the world,
we can then reason completely within
the logic without having to go back
to reference the world to
come to some conclusions.
And were guaranteed that to the extent
the original statements correctly
represent the world so too,
will that conclusions be correct.
On the other hand, if you start
with something false then logic
will lead you to conclude
more false things.