In the makeHttpRequest method, we should
only perform the HttpRequest if the URL
is not null and it doesn't make sense to
make a connection into an invalid URL.
So at the beginning of the method,
let's check if the URL is null.
If it is, then we exit the method early
by returning a jsonResponse that simply
contains an empty string.
So now let's move on to
the core task in this quiz,
which is to check the response code.
After the connection
has been established,
you want to check the response code by
calling urlConnection.getResponseCode().
If you check the documentation,
you'll know that it returns an integer.
So in this test condition for
the if statement,
we check if the response code = 200.
If so we then proceed to read
from the inputStream and
extract the jsonResponse.
Otherwise, if we have
an error response code,
in other words not 200, we do nothing.
And we're going to go down here and
return the jsonResponse, that was
initialized earlier to an empty string,
which brings us to an important point.
If the return value of the make HTTP
request method can be an empty string,
then we need to make sure that
the method that takes the jsonResponse
as input is handling
that empty string case.
So lets look at
the extractFeatureFromJson method.
Before we proceed from extracting
information from the jsonResponse,
we should check if the info parameter
is either the empty string or
null by calling TextUtils.isEmpty and
passing in the string.
So I'm going to go ahead and
just jump to the declaration of this
isEmpty function to see what it does.
I do it by doing a shortcut
of the Cmd+click.
You notice here that in fact,
the isEmpty method within the TextUtils
class is checking for an empty string or
if the string is null.
So back to our code.
Now if this string is empty,
then this expression will be true and
we'll return early from the method.
Now we've returned null because
there is no valid event object from
the jsonResponse.
Notice how this extract feature from
JSON method returns an event data type.
We'll explain the full execution path
of the Tsunami AsyuncTask later in
the next lesson.
But if there is a null earthquake,
then we won't update the UI.
The key is that it's
okay to return null for
a method, as long as the null
case will be handled gracefully.
Now you know how to check
the HTP status code and
adjust the behavior of the app depending
on whether you receive a successful or
unsuccessful response code.