Now that we know that unity is able to
calculate intermediate points of our
animations with interpolation,
how can we control that interpolation?
To start out, let's first see how it
can control the length of our clip.
Unity assumes that the last
keyframe of our animation
marks the end of our animation.
By default, it is set to one second,
so, if we want our click to be faster,
we simply need to drag the last
keyframe to a different spot.
Say something like the 40th keyframe.
If we hit play and now, you'll notice
that the first half of our animation
moves slower than the speed
of the second half.
That's because we haven't
moved our middle keyframe, so
the animation is not evenly spaced out.
Let's move the middle keyframe to
the 20th one, so that now we get a nice,
smooth animation.
Now, let's take a look at a different
way to view our keyframes.
At the bottom left of our
screen there are two tabs.
One called dope sheet, and
the other called curves.
Let's go ahead and click on curves.
This gives us a view of our key
frames in a much more visual format.
If we click on the Z rotation in the
property list and then hit F to focus.
We'll see a linear line that represents
how our animation varies with time.
As you can see,
our rotation linearly changes with time.
However, if we want to change that, we
could just grab a key frame and move it.
Let's take the last keyframe and
bring it down to zero.
As you can see, we have a nice
smooth parabolic animation
that acts much like a sideways
pendulum right now.
It even slows down at the ends,
which is a nice effect.
But suppose we want
something a bit more linear.
For that we need to control
the tensions of our animation,
which we can do by right clicking
on our middle keyframe and
going to both Tensions and
clicking Linear.
Now if we look at our animation,
you'll notice that there's no smoothing.
And our hand immediately jumps back and
forth.
There's a lot you can do with tensions
and I encourage you to play with them on
your own, so you can get the effects
that match exactly what you want.
And if you want to learn more about
editing your own animation curves
check out the recommended reading.
But for now, let's go ahead and
reset our animation by changing
the last key frame to 360.
Let's quickly go ahead and
test our animation and
yap, working just as expected.