When you're working from example code,
though, you do have to exercise some
care, or you could inherit bugs from it.
Like, let's say that we want to print
out some text with a box around it.
We see that separator
calls bar with a number
to make a plaintext horizontal line.
So it seems like we could use that to
draw some horizontal lines of our own.
So we'll put a corner and then a bar of
length equal to the length of the text,
and then another corner, and then we
will put the text inside some vertical
lines then we will put another bar.
This looks like it should work.
Hm, well if that doesn't work,
what then?
Maybe we need to look more
closely in what these functions
that we're working with do.
Sometimes the example code you're
working with didn't actually
work very well.
In that case, basing your own code
on it never would have worked.
Maybe you can find out why it didn't.
Or else, find a better example.
So let's test out the bar function.
Ah-ha, bar is returning none.
So in this case, the bar function
would be a lot more useful if
it returned the string
instead of printing it.
That would let us use it effectively
in our box function, like so.
So now you've seen both sides
of working from example code.
When it's good it can be very, very
good, but when it's bad it's annoying.