If you've been playing
careful attention,
you will have noticed that the simplex
algorithm started with the basic
feasible solution.
Now in some cases basic feasible
solutions are easy to find just by
inspection.
But that's not always the case.
For these harder cases, we can create
an auxiliary program to help us.
First, we negate
the constraint equations so
that we have B is non-negative.
Then we create an auxiliary
program as follows.
We introduce artificial variables Y that
represent the slack between Ax and b.
We require these variables
to be non-negative and
then try to minimize their sum.
For this auxiliary program it is easy
to find a basic, feasible solution.
Just that x equal to zero,
and y equal the b.
Therefore we can start
simplex on this problem here.
If the optimum here is zero,
then we can start the simplex algorithm
on this problem at the value we found
for x, at the optimum to this one.
On the other hand,
if the optimum isn't zero,
then we conclude that our
original problem was in-feasible.
This is sometimes called the two phase
approach for solving linear programs.