Okay, great, so now we know about
how ViewGroups can contain views.
Each ViewGroup has specific rules on
how it will position the children
inside of it.
First, let's look at LinearLayout.
This ViewGroup can arrange children
in a vertical column like this.
Notice how we're not limited to just
one TextView and one ImageView.
We can put as many of them as we want in
here as well as other types of views.
So this is Tommy, and
this is his brother Timmy.
And this is Ivy and
her twin sister Irene.
Or the LinearLayout can arrange its
children views in a horizontal row
like this.
Hey, if you want to say no boys allowed,
that's totally fine with me.
This is Ivy, Irene, and Isabella.
Okay, and that's it for a LinearLayout.
Pretty straightforward, right?
You can arrange children in a vertical
column or in a horizontal row.
And then we have dad,
the RelativeLayout.
The RelativeLayout, again,
has its own rules for
how to position its children within it.
For example, it can position
children relative to the parent.
So if this is the parent ViewGroup,
we can have a child TextView aligned
to the bottom of the parent and
a child ImageView aligned
to the top of the parent.
This also works for
aligning to the parent's left and
right edge as well as the center.
The other useful capability
of RelativeLayout
is that you can position children
relative to other children views.
So, if this is the parent ViewGroup,
then you can position an ImageView
on the left edge of the parent and
then position a child TextView
to the right of that image.
And then, this child TextView is
positioned to the right of the ImageView
but also below this first TextView.
So you see how some of these children
views are aligned relative to the parent
or relative to each other.
That was a really quick overview of
LinearLayout versus RelativeLayout.
You can see how you might pick
one over the other depending
on the type of layout that you want for
your app.
Now let's look at the XML for
how a ViewGroup contains other views.
In this example,
we'll start with a ViewGroup that
contains two child TextViews.
This is a little more code
than we're used to, but
I want you to make some
observations about this code.
As a hint, the parent code is in red,
and the child TextView code is in blue.
We've linked that code below so
you can take a look at it and
then write down three observations here.