So we're going to use package sk learns knears neighbors implementation.
In the case of sk learn it is called k neighbors regressor.
For fun I created a knears neighbors model using five neighbors and
one using three neighbors.
Lets collect our training data.
And we'll use it to train our three nearest neighbors model.
Now let's create a list of values containing the error values for
the training data.
Here's a plot of the histogram of the signed error on the training set.
As you can see, it looks like performance on the training set is quite
good it had a mean absolute error of 1,876 seconds.
Although 50% of the time,
it predicts time correctly within eight seconds or better.
Let's look at performance on the test set.
As you can see, the model did quite well in the test set as well.
The predictor had a mean absolute error of 1,837 seconds.
Although 75% of the time.
It predicts time correctly to within 32 seconds or better.
As you can see,
our knears neighbors fit totally blew away our initial exponential model.
Just to put that in perspective, let's examine how far we've come.
As you can see, adding the additional features of text length and
mention distance and then using the updated model of
knears neighbors made a dramatic difference in our prediction accuracy.
We went from guessing 8585 and 1/2 seconds.
And being right to within about five minutes, half of the time to using a knears
neighbors predictor, that uses elapse time, length of the previous tweet.
And amount of time elapsed since the previous mention.
In order to predict the amount of time remaining until the next tweet.
Using that model.
Were able to guess within 32 seconds of accuracy 75% of the time.
Looks pretty good.
In the next video we'll think about some possible ways forward.