Well, a recipe is not an entity but
that's close.
An entity would be
an individual incident.
Something like a chocolate cake
recipe or a rhubarb pie recipe.
Those entities are examples or
incidences of a recipe.
But recipe itself isn't an entity.
Just as the ent type
isn't itself an integer.
So yeah that means that recipes
match the definition of a kind.
It answers the questions
of what kinds of objects or
entities are we going to make here.
And how do we represent kinds in code?
Well, kinds are just theoretical
concepts from the app engine data store
but classes are the blueprints that we
use in our code to make instances from.
So class is also a correct answer.
Finally we just talked about properties
above in our name, ingredients,
instructions, and so forth.
Those are properties so
recipe is not a property.