I began by searching for
AvAudioPlayer sample code and landed on this Stack Overflow page.
Here I found code that I could use to play audio file,
there was only one problem however.
The code was in Objective-C,
which is another programming language used to make iPhone apps.
Since Swift is a new programming language,
this sort of a situation will occur quite frequently.
When I will try and look for how to do something in iOS, and
will end up with code from Objective-C instead of Swift.
My strategy for dealing with this is to understand this code at
a very high level, and not worry too much about the syntax.
And see if I can deduce something from the code here,
that I can use in my Swift program.
So after reading this code I realized.
That the first thing that I had to do to try and
play an audio file, is to get a path to that audio file.
So here, for instance, they are getting a path to song.mp3 somehow.
Then I will need to create an instance of AVAudioPlayer somehow,
while using that file path.
And finally it seems like we can just simply play that file.
Now the following may be a little bit challenging, but
given that we have the pseudo code right here.
Why don't you give this a try, and see if you can in fact play a sound in Swift.
Feel free to use Google and stack all flow to find more help.
Here are your tasks one more time.
Select from any one of these options after you attempted this exercise