Now, back to the topic of contacts.
Why do we need them anyways?
So now I'll be discussing
three reasons why.
First off, the primary reason
developers need contracts is to have
one place to document the structure of
their database also known as a schema.
So this is the way to group
together all the constants
associated with our database.
So SQLite statements require a lot
of text and the Android APIs
can remove a lot of that writing for
you, but column and table names remain
as items that you need to reference
several times through the code.
Now the ability to abstract these items,
our table names and
column names, ints to constants,
reduces the potential for
spelling errors in our code and makes
future changes a lot easier to maintain.
So here's an example to
illuminate all that I just said.
Now here's one way we could write
our CREATE TABLE statement and
this is what we've been used to.
So we have our CREATE TABLE command,
followed by the name of the table and
then explicitly writing the names of
the columns and there data types.
But here's a way to do it more
efficiently using reusable Constance.
So notice, we're still using
our create table statement but
now our table name and our column
names are stored in constants.
So this leads us to our two other
reason for using contracts.
So first, when generating SQL commands,
remove possibility of
introducing spelling errors.
because when we're typing names
directly it's easy to misspell or
accidentally capitalize
letters that we shouldn't be.
For example reframe back to our
FeedReaderContract example,
we could have easily misspelled
entryid maybe capitalizing I and
D where we shouldn't or
maybe adding extra T.
And you can't do this with the constant
because the code won't run say if we
typed COLUMN_NAME_TITLE instead
of COLUMN_NAME_ENTRY_ID.
So our third reason is
that using the contract
makes it easier to
update the data schema.
So that means if you ever want to
change the actual column name,
we'll only need to
change it in one place.
So think about it this way: if you
have multiple statements throughout
your Android app that reference
the column name title but
you want to change it to
article title instead,
you'd only need to change it in
one place inside the contract.
Instead of going to every
single location and
updating the name of the column.
So it centralizes all the touch points
that will need to make with the code.
So to reiterate, the three reasons for
using a contract class are one, helps us
define the schema and have a convention
for where to find database constants.
Secondly, when generating SQL commands
it helps us to remove the possibility
of introducing spelling errors.
And lastly, it makes it easy for
us to update the database schema.
Now you might be wondering do
real developers use contracts?
Well, the short answer
is absolutely yes.
So the Android SDK alone uses
them heavily to document
all system wide data stores.
Such as calendar events,
contact and voice mails.
While the organization of those
might be a little bit different,
all of them still contain the essential
classes that we mentioned before.
With their filled in constants,
that define the schema for some data.
Now looking at the voice mail
contract here, we can see that there
are different column names or attributes
for voice mails, such as the date
the voice mail was sent, the duration,
and the phone number sent from.
And similarly we can dig around
in the calendar contract, and
we'll be able to see that there are also
constants for the different columns.
Now that you know a little bit
more about the reasons why we use
the contract class,
let's take a look at a contract from
the developing Android apps class.
So this contract is for a weather
application called Sunshine, and
that app shows users the current
weather in a specific location.
So in the code,
there'll be constants here for
data related to classes that
we haven't talked about yet.
But you should be able to
recognize three points
from the structures we saw before.
So we should be able to find
the outer class, the inner class, and
the string constants.
Now using what you know about
the structure of contracts
I'd like you to answer
the following questions.
So referring to the weather contract
from the Sunshine application,
first off, how many tables
are in that Sunshine database?
Secondly, for the table that is
represented by the WeatherEntry class,
what is the name of the table in SQLite?
Third, how many columns
does the table have, and
that's not including the _ID or
the _COUNT columns?
So lastly, what is the line of code, and
I want you to give me the number, that
creates a constant for the column that's
a description of the weather condition?