Looking back now, I wish I had
learned about databases earlier.
For some reason,
I had this fear of databases,
that it was this really hard topic.
And I think it was because it was
an optional class at my university and
the people who took that class
said it was really hard and
you just would have no
social life if you took it.
So I avoided taking that class.
And I delayed learning about databases
until my job actually required it.
I was on the Android apps team at
Google, on the Contacts app, where I
was assigned this feature that involved
doing a query on the Contacts database.
And honestly, I was a little embarrassed
because I didn't know about databases.
And it felt like I should know about it,
but
my tech lead was just
really nice about it.
And he took the time
to sit down next to me
to essentially give me a crash
course in databases on the spot.
We took the contacts database from
the app from the device put it on my
computer.
And then, we started using the command
line to try different queries.
He showed me how to query for
the list of contacts,
the list of favorite contacts,
even how to query for
the list of contacts that
started with the letter A.
And in hindsight it was
just a really cool way to
first be exposed to databases
by looking at contact data.
And through that experimentation I just
became a lot more comfortable with using
the syntax and just mixing and
matching the data to get
the results that I want back.
So my question to you now is,
can you think of a way to apply
databases to your own life?
In this reflection exercise, I want you
to think about how you can apply this to
a real life situation that you're in.
For example, if you are part of a school
or a workplace or media sports team.
Is there a use case where storing
data in a database would be helpful?
Share your thoughts on
the discussion forum and
we look forward to hearing from you.