In lesson one we'll build an app
called sleeping in the library
that uses the flicker
API to retrieve and
display images of people
sleeping in the library.
This will be our first exposure to a web
service, a core concept in this course.
To build this we're going to
learn all about networks.
In lesson two we'll create flick finder
an app that uses the flicker API
to retrieve and
display images except this time you
can search with a phrase or location.
Here we'll learn how to parse
data from the network and
then display it to our users.
Next in lesson three we'll build
the my favorite movies app,
by using the movie data base API.
In this lesson we'll learn
the difference between user and
anonymously access data.
Then, in lesson four,
we'll build on the app from lesson
three to create the movie manager.
This will require us to clean up
our networking code by using good
MVC design.
Then, in lesson five, we'll get started
on the course project called on the map.
This will let you showcase your
skills on the map with other
udacity students from around the world.
For instance, you can share a recent
blog post, your LinkedIn profile or
any of the projects that you've created.
So let's get started.