Last, let's talk about characterizing
systems with infinitely many solutions.
Which of the following
statements are necessarily true
about a system of equations
with infinitely many solutions?
And which statements are sufficient
to prove that a system will
have infinitely many solutions?
Again, let's assume we're only
talking about systems of equations
in three dimensions.
And we'll still assume that k
refers to a nonzero number.
The first statement,
there are 2 equations in the system
defining the same plane.
Second statement,
we encounter an equation of the form 0 =
0 while doing Gaussian elimination and
assume we don't find any 0 = k.
Third, there are fewer than
3 equations in the system.
And last, after reaching triangular
form, there's some variable which
isn't the lead variable in
any equation in the system.
Assume again,
that we find no 0 = k equations.
Check the appropriate boxes
next to each statement.