The first system has
the parameterization x equals
negative 1.346- t, y = t and z = 0.585.
The second system has
the parameterization
x = negative 0.301- 0.091t,
y = negative 0.492 plus 0.509T and
z = t.
The third system has a two
parameter parametrization.
X = negative 10.647 minus 1.882t
+ 10.016s, y = t and z = s.
And here's my code for
solving the problem.
I still use complete solution to
wrap my Gaussian elimination method.
Which I've now renamed to
do_gaussian_elimination_and_parametrize-
_solution to reflect the fact that
it now parametrizes a solution.
I no longer check for infinitely
many solutions as an exception
since that's what parameterizing
is supposed to handle.
But if a no solutions
exception is raised,
it is still handled at this level.
In the Gaussian elimination method,
I again first compute the rref of
the system and then I check for
contradictory equations.
Then I use two methods.
One to extract the direction vectors and
one to extract a base point for
the parametrization.
I then create and return
the appropriate parametrization object.
In my case, I still use this object
even if there is a unique solution.
In this case, the variable direction
vectors would just equal an empty list.
In the vector extraction method,
I determine which variables
are free variables by seeing
which aren't pivot variables.
And then for each free variable,
I construct a direction_vector.
The coordinate corresponding to
the free variable will be one
to reflect our setting
the variable equal to itself.
For example, z equals z or
y equals y in the parametrization.
Then for each equation in the system,
I determine the pivot variable,
find the coefficient of the free
variable in that equation.
And then I set the coordinate
corresponding to the pivot variable
equal to the negative
of that coefficient.
Since we have to subtract the free
variables from both sides of
the equation when we set
up our parameterizations.
For example, in x + y + z = 1,
we set x equal to 1- y,
one of the free variables and minus z,
another one of the free variables.
I do something similar for
computing the base point.
One observation is that only coordinates
corresponding to pivot variables
can be non-zero.
Looking again at our example, there are
no constant terms in the equations for
free variables.
So we can just set all
the coordinates initially to zero and
then just loop through
the pivot variables.
Since the constant term is already on
the right-hand side of each equation and
the variables are on the left-hand side,
we don't need to do any subtraction.
And now the moment of truth.
If I run the code down here,
we can see the nice output of
the parametrized solution sets.
The first and second systems,
since they only have one parameter
in their solution set will be lines.
However, the third system solution since
it has two parameters will be a plane.
This is because all the equations
in the system actually defined at
the same plane.
So their intersection is a plane
which is a two-dimensional object.