Okay, so something that we look for
in full-stack
engineers is that they have a basic idea
of how to protect our users' data and
make websites that
are relatively secure.
>> Okay.
>> So given that,
I was wondering if you could tell me a
little about what an XSRF attack is and
how you would protect against it if
you're building a website today?
>> Okay, so an XSRF attack is like
a cross-site request forgery.
And so, I guess that what that is,
is it's kind of abusing
I guess the browser's
storage of a user's credentials
to do some unanticipated things.
>> Can you give me an example?
>> For instance, you'll see example,
someone might buy an ad on a certain
page or something like that.
And so the way that that'll work is for
instance,
I'll get this content onto a page.
So that gets run as
the page is rendered and
that element they've added will make
some sort of request that wasn't
intended by the original
designer of this page.
And so that will do something like
using the user's credentials or
they might have in a cookie or a session
to access their user data on that site.
Or to make some request
that's outside of
the purview of what
they should be doing.
>> And so
how could someone use this maliciously?
If you knew a website was vulnerable
to cross-site request forgery,
how would you attack it?
>> So, for instance, maybe this
vulnerable site has a URL or an endpoint
that isn't properly verifying that users
are coming at it in a legitimate way.
>> Okay.
>> For instance, maybe-
>> Let's call this website monkeys.com.
>> Monkeys.com.
So maybe users at monkeys.com, they
have a user profile where it has their
credit card information for
ordering monkeys.
>> Okay.
>> Or whatever, and
maybe there's some URL endpoints
like monkeys.com/buyamonkey.
>> Okay.
>> And, ideally you could only
access the URL the normal way,
through the website, clicking on it.
But maybe someone records this URL,
and I guess they
distract users' browsers to this URL
from something that's non-standard flow.
>> So you're saying it's a different
website is making a request to
monkeys.com now?
>> Or its embedded elements or whatever.
>> Okay.
>> That somehow it's making this
site request to this URL in some
non-conventional sort of way.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, so.
So what was the original question?
>> Yeah, so how,
if you were to attack monkeys.com now.
>> Yeah.
>> How would you do it and
how can you benefit out of it?
>> Yeah, so what you could do is
you would design this malicious
element of the page to make some
sort of request to this URL,
like a JavaScript AJAXy-style
thing to this URL.
And you'd set it up with all the correct
parameters to initiate this action on
the server to, for instance, order 2,000
monkeys to your own address instead of,
or something like using
their saved profile.
>> I see.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
And now let's say you become the
director of engineering at monkeys.com.
How are you going to start
protecting against this now?
>> So security is really hard but
fortunately there's a lot of really
good documentation about how to
write secure websites and there's really
good libraries and stuff like that.
So depending on your stack,
you should research it and
see if you can find
the existing solutions.
So writing your own things from
scratch is generally insecure.
It's good to have the background
knowledge of how to write the solution,
but you should also use the existing
solutions because they're vetted.
But basically the way these solutions
work is you would kind of set up
a little session for
these important transactions.
Like the buy a monkey URL,
you'd kind of set it up so
that when the user gets to this
endpoint, on the previous page they
get a one time a random string so
that you can't just go to this URL.
You also have to have the knowledge
of this random string.
And the server supplies
the string initially, and so
it will know if it matches or not.
>> I see.
>> And
that way you're kind of like
re-wrapping this URL sort of.
So if you're not in the standard
flow of accessing this
URL-
>> Mm-hm.
>> You can't access it.
The server will recognize that this
isn't like a legitimate way to use this
use this endpoint.
>> Okay, that sounds a lot like
an XSRF token, so sounds right.
What about preventing that
kind of malicious JavaScript
from being there in the first place?
>> So I guess in that case, you'd need
to have a processor validating or
sanitizing these things before
they even make it onto your page,
before someone makes this post
on your website or whatever.
So there's obviously also libraries
to do that, they sanitize input.
And the philosophy, I guess,
is don't trust user input.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So
in any place where there is third party
content making it onto your servers,
you need to run that through some
kind of bleach or sanitizing.
>> I see.
>> Library.
>> Cool.
>> And how is it that this
malicious content has access
to our cookies in the first place?
>> Yeah, so because it is on your page,
for instance if it's a forum post,
because that code is being
executed from monkeys.com,
the browser loaded monkeys.com and
this code is on it.
That way it has access to the session
at that domain because it's being
run from that domain.
>> Okay, so let's take the case
now where I create gorillas.com.
And now I know that you have
a cross-site weakness and
I start making requests to monkeys.com
knowing that you'd be into
monkeys.com before you
come to gorillas.com.
Am I still going to be able to carry
out this attack and if not, why not?
If so, how can we prevent it?
>> Lets see.
So ideally, no, if it was the browser.
I mean so, the web server,
by default when you
make an AJAX style request,
when the browser makes that request,
it can't do it to a domain that isn't
the one that it's currently displaying.
>> If you look at how Google
does ad tracking and stuff,
they're never on google.com when they
send things to their own server.
And they definitely use cookies
to do those things, right?
>> Let's see.
I guess I'm not really familiar
with how that process works.
>> Okay, if you were to
design a policy on a cookie,
let's say you could make your own
cookie, the Phillip cookie, that would
protect against these kind of attacks,
what would you make that policy?
>> I guess it would have a whitelist of
domains that that request
could legitimately come from.
>> Okay, cool, what about
the case where let's say,
I have some JavaScript on gorillas.com.
And now I start using my
JavaScript to go through and
read all the cookies on
your your current session.
How would you design
a policy against that?
>> Let's see, I guess what you
could do is in your cookie,
you don't have to store all the user's
personal identifying information,
you could like store a key to
access things on your own server.
You don't put the critical
things in the cookie itself.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And that way, you don't have
the security on the browser itself,
you can do it on your own back end.
>> Okay, cool.
And a common way people do this is
through something called HttpOnly
cookies so that JavaScript has
no access to the actual cookie.
It's just that the browser is
the only thing that accesses it.
>> Cool, okay.
>> That's a common way that's done,
but you got the main points out of it.
>> Cool.
Cool yeah, I guess it's like a field
that I guess is evolving over time.
>> Right.
>> So that's good to learn.
>> Yeah,
security's always always evolving.
>> Yeah, cool.
>> Yeah very good.
>> All right thanks.
>> Cool.