All right, now we're going to take
everything you've learned and
make a simple birthday card app.
The apps going to look like this.
It's a digital card that you can
show and share with a friend or
family member.
Then at the end of the practice set,
you'll be making your
own custom holiday card.
So what I'm going to do for
you right now,
is breakdown the process of turning
a drawing like this into code.
And this is going to
take three easy steps.
And when you're designing
application layouts,
these are good steps to follow if
you're not sure how to get started.
Okay, so step one is to take the layout
and select the correct views to use.
Step two is to then take those views and
position them on the screen.
And basically, you do step two by
choosing the correct view group and
then selecting the correct
positioning attributes.
Finally, we add all of the stylistic
touches in step three.
This is where we take the views and
add things like color or
font related attributes.
One thing you'll notice is that this
card says Happy Birthday Ben, and
From Lyla.
Now your name probably isn't Lyla and
maybe you don't have a friend named Ben,
so you can feel free to change this text
around as we go through the example.
All right, so
we're going to go ahead and
jump right in, let's start with step
one, which is selecting the views.
Given this application,
what views do you think are included?