Let's try to implement a very simple approach for
matching corresponding regions from two image strips.
First, recall the find best match problem.
Given an image patch and
a strip, your task was to find the best x location for the patch in the strip.
You are free to use this reference implementation or roll your own.
Now, your task is to match two strips.
You're given the two strips, left and right, as well as a block size b.
Note that you are only to consider whole, non-overlapping blocks.
This means if your strip is 640 wide and the block size is 100,
then you only have six whole blocks.
The last 40 columns of these strips are unused.
Return a vector of disparity values, one for each block.
All right.
Here's some code to test with.
We use the same pair of flower images as before and
extract a strip from each image.
The top one here is from the left image and the bottom one from the right.
Now we should be able to call your function by passing in the two strips and
the block size.