This can be seen,
sort of simply in this one d k.
So we start off with a prior and
here it is as a Gaussian.
We have some measurement,
that's the evidence,
and here it happens to be tighter.
And then we get a posterior, all right?
And the posterior is narrowing because
it's narrower, it's also going to
be taller and then the prediction step,
we just take that posterior and
we do this shift and
we grow the uncertainty again.
So, so far, everything looks
like it's behaving really well.
So, let me show, give you a quiz.
Well, it's not a real quiz.
It's like a fake quiz.
All right.
Suppose this is your prior.
Okay?
Okay so you see it is this nice
white Gaussian lump over here.
And then suppose this
is your measurement.
Okay.
This nice tight green.
Where does the posterior go?
Well, first of all,
it's gotta go somewhere in between,
because in Kalman filtering,
your mean is a weighted average between
the priors mean and the measurement.
Okay?
So the fact that it's going to
go in the middle is okay.
But what might bug you is it's got,
again, that tight little uncertainty.
I've got this Gaussian bump here,
all right?
Now Gaussians go to zero,
really, really fast so
by the time we get out here,
it's like incredibly, un, unlikely.
But then all of a sudden there
is a measurement bump over here.
Okay.
So you know, what's poor Kalman to do?
Well, Kalman has to put them
somewhere in the middle,
because that's all it does.
And furthermore, it has to, it,
it has to reduce that uncertainty
because it's a slave to its model.
It really honest to God believes
that things are distributed by
these Gaussians and if they really were,
then that's the correct value to put in.
And the question is,
does this agree with your intuition?
And the short answer should be, yeah, I
don't think so because Megan, over here.
Over here, okay.
If I've really got a Gaussian lump
over here, then the idea that
something will now be over here, the
probability is so infinitesimally small
that what's probably the problem
is that our model is wrong.
We really should be trying to
abandon the model at that point
as opposed to doing the integration.
And in some sense, that's the, the, the,
the, the part of the message
of Kalman filter.
You're actually a slave to
the model you really believe in.