Alright, first if we had a complete series of snapshots
from a nondeterministic RAM solving SAT on his formula.
Well, a nondeterministic RAM can solve SAT in polynomial time,
so we can check those in polynomial time as well
since we just have a list of these.
So once we have those, we can definitely verify that his formula is satisfiable.
Now if we had a list of satisfiable clauses,
this actually isn't enough to verify that Bob's formula is also satisfiable.
To see this, let's take a look at the formula in somewhat pythonic form,
X and not X.
Now clearly X is a satisfiable clause and so is not X,
but the entire Boolean formula is definitely not satisfiable.
So a list of satisfiable clauses actually isn't enough
for us to believe Bob.
Now if we had a satisfying assignment for all of the variables in the formula,
then sure, we can just plug them into the formula
and check on a deterministic RAM,
and that occurs in polynomial time.
Similarly, if add all calls to if_better on the Boolean formula,
well, if_better is the only difference
between a nondeterministic and a deterministic RAM,
so if we had all the calls to if_better,
we wouldn't actually have to simulate if_better,
we would know what the algorithm did at each step of the process.
So we could also check Bob's formula using just this.
Not even a complete series of snapshots is necessary
just the calls to if_better.
Now let's say we had a satisfying assignment for 90% of the variables.
Well, 90% of the variables still leaves 10%,
and 10% of exponential is, well, exponential.
So we would still have exponentially many variables to check.
So this actually doesn't work.