So far, all the probabilistic
objects that we've talked about
have been events.
Things that either happen or
don't happen.
As we go further in
our analysis however,
it will be convenient to talk
about other random quantities.
What is the value of a random die roll,
or how many times did we have to
repeat that procedure before
we got an acceptable outcome.
For this, we introduce
the idea of a random variable.
A random variable is just a function
from the sample space to the reals.
For example, let's let x be
the sum of two die throws.
Then the sample space is the set of
all pairs of numbers between 2 and 6.
And the function x just adds
the two numbers together.
If I roll a four and a seven,
then the total is 11.
We use the notation x
equals some constant a,
to indicate the event
that x is equal to a.
Thus is the set of elements s from the
sample space, for which x is equal to a.
In our example, the event x equals 3,
is the set consisting of the samples 1,
2 and 2, 1.