Sorting is great, but
sometimes you need more than sorting.
For example, what if you need to
section off pieces of data querying
on all of the shopping lists which
were edited in the last 30 days only?
Or only show shopping list items
bought by a specific user.
When you need to make
this type of query,
we use what are called range queries and
Firebase.
To use these,
we take one of three methods.
startAt(), endAt() and equalTo(),
which allow you to grab only
a specific section of our data.
startAt() will create a query
at a specific starting point.
Only child nodes that exactly
match the starting point and or
greater will be returned.
endAt() is similar child node
they have a value less than or
equal to the given
value will be returned.
Going back to the desserts example,
maybe we only want desserts
that are exactly 322 calories.
So, we would use this statement.
equalTo() will filter range queries
based on exact matches, either returning
child nodes which match a specified
value or a specific key value pair.
Maybe we were on a diet and only want
desserts that are 200 calories or less.
In this case,
we would use the following.
Let's say we're trying to
eat everything we can.
Maybe we're training for a marathon.
So, let's say we're not interested
in any low fat desserts.
We only want desserts with
358 calories or more.
Unlike sort by criteria,
you can combine startAt() and
endAt(), and you will get what
is in between these values.
For example, if we had very
strict dietary requirements,
perhaps we only want to eat
dessert between 200 and
400 calories,
we could use the following code.
Notice how in all cases we
start with a query by child.
This allows us to specify what
exactly we're looking for
when we say startAt() or endAt().
And startAt() and endAt() our inclusive.
So now that you are familiar
with these range queries,
let's practice what you've learned.
These questions are about the shopping
list plus, plus database.
Don't forget that you have to
specify query by child and
which child you are querying.
How do you get all the users who joined
after September 30, 2015 at midnight?
How do you get the items
in a shopping list
bought by a user with the email
address Laila@gmail.com?
If shopping list items include
a property price, how would you find all
items with a price equal to, or
greater than to, and less than $10?