You could make a case for
many of these methods.
For example, you could choose to
use the list name as the key here.
Then you could use setValue and
pass in the list as an object to add
a new list, much like we do here.
You could generate the URL
location like this.
You'd make a new Firebase
reference at the base URL.
Then you go to the child activeLists,
and then you make a new child,
which is the name of the current list,
so
setValue is definitely
possibly an option.
Now, updateChildren will only edit
the key value pairs that you pass it, so
it's a little bit clunky for
creating a new list.
You'd have to convert your object into
a hashmap, so it's really good for
editing a couple items, but in this
case, we probably don't want to use it.
runTransaction doesn't make
a huge amount of sense.
You don't need to worry about two
people both editing a previous
version of a list.
Since we're making
a completely new list,
two users are not trying
to edit the same data,
and the order that people make their
lists in isn't extremely important.
So the actual answer is a combination
of both push and setValue.
How do you use this combination,
and why is it superior?
Well, push creates a new key for you,
so instead of relying on something like
the list name, you can allow
push to make some sort of key.
Push creates the key for you,
and then setValue actually sets
the shopping list at that location.
Now you might be wondering, why do we
really need to use this push thing,
and why's the key so important?
Well, let me tell you why.