I just wanted to have you look at this concept a little bit more in detail,
I've given you, basically, three different signals, A and B and C.
And this is the original signal.
And in essence, what basically this is a 600 by
600 image which has basically a white bar in the middle and black.
So this is black, white, black, and I have only showed the signal as I this way.
And of course, there is filtering going on, so there is a ramp from black to
white, so you've noticed 0, goes up to 1, and then comes down to 0.
The same image, I've basically then given 0.1 of the magnitude noise in there,
you can see a lot of you know,
noisy pixels coming in, and of course I've increased the noise.
I just want you to look at these three and
figure out, which is the right derivative for each one of them?
Just put the no, the character of the choices A, B and
C in the appropriate boxes.