After all that practice, hopefully
you understand how to identify JSON
components and
how to traverse the JSON object tree, so
you can extract that
the values that we care about.
Transforming a string of JSON
into a live JSON object or
JSON array requires parsing.
Now parsing is a deep part of computer
science and it basically means that
the computer reads some text
written in a language it knows, and
then transforms it into another more
useful representation like a JSON object
that we can call methods on, and then
extract the data that we need from it.
Now we know how to
parse JSON in our heads
by identifying the key value pairs and
traversing them, but
we need to learn how to apply that
same process in our Java code.
So, let's talk about it.
So, I've switched over
to my web browser and
I'm looking at the official Android
documentation at developer.android.com.
Fortunately, there's
a class called JSONObject.
That makes it easy to convert
a simple string of JSON into a much
more intelligent object, an object that
knows about the keys it contains and
how to access their accompanying values.
If we scroll down to the summary
section, we can review the available
constructors that can be used
to create an instance or
object of the JSON object class.
Here we go.
This is the specific
constructor that we want.
It allows us to construct a JSON object
by passing in a single string of JSON
containing the raw JSON.
Now, we see that we have a rather large
set of getter methods that we can call
in a JSONObject instance to retrieve
the values associated with certain keys.
Now as you already know,
there are various JSON components
ranging from basic data types
like integer to larger data types,
like JSONObjects and JSONArrays.
So for example, if you wanted to extract
an integer you could call the getInt get
in method passing in the name
of the key here as a string.
Now, we have a similar pattern for
getting a double or getting a string.
For the larger JSON components, you
could call something like getJSONArray.
So, you get the JSON
already mapped by its key.
Notice that the data type returned by
the getter method is a JSONArray type.
And likewise, you can call
getJSONObject to get a JSONObject back.
Notice again, that the data type
returned here is a JSONObject.
Let's click in a little deeper.
Now note that any time we try
a get request on a JSONObject,
the requested key might not exist.
In which case, the request will
actually result in a JSONException,
which we'll need to catch and deal with.
Alternatively, there are these
opt methods that can be called on
a JSONObject where opt stands for
optional key value pair.
These methods get the corresponding
value for a given key, but
return null if the value doesn't exist.
Let's parse this little snippet of JSON.
We've got this root object
with one key called candies.
The key corresponds to an array here,
because of those square brackets,
which contains another JSON object
here within this curl braces.
Now, this inner object
contains two keys.
One of which is name, which correspond
to the string value Jelly Beans and
another key called count, which
corresponds to the integer value of 10.
Now let's review what
the traversal parse will look like,
if we want to extract out
the data mapped by these keys.
So for the data Jelly Beans, we want to
start at the root of the JSON payload
here at the root, then we're going to
go and index in using the key candies,
which is going to be
returning us a JSON array.
Then we want to get the first
element of the array,
which is going to be
this single JSONObject.
And then we simply get the string
value for the name key,
which in this case is jelly beans.
Now, the traversal path to
get the value for count.
Similarly, we start at the root,
then we're going to go and
key value index using the key candies,
back into the JSON array.
And then we want to get that
first element out of the array,
which is a JSON object.
And then we going to key guide you index
to grab the value represented by the key
count, which in this case is
an integer with the value 10.
Now, we want to take this
traversal path process and
map it to statements that
we can write in job code.
So, let's go and take a look.
So let's say, we were given a string
containing this JSON here on the left.
Well, actually more likely, we'd receive
a compacted version, which is exactly
the same just with all the white space
removed and all the quotes escaped.
What do we mean by escaped?
It means by adding a backslash character
in front of it since you can't have
quote marks in the middle of a string.
Otherwise, how would you know
when the string was done?
Now we can turn this candy JSON string
variable into a live JSONObject by
passing the string into
the JSONObject constructor.
Now, this JSONObject has done all the
work of parsing the JSON string for us.
It now knows what keys it contains and
all sorts of useful methods, for
instance, on this route object.
Let's call getJSONArray to find the
array nested within the root object with
the candies key.
Now, we can store this in a variable
named candiesArray with data type
JSONArray.
Now, the JSONArray
class exposes a method
called getJSONobject to access an object
at a specified index position.
So we can get this zero
JSON object in that array,
which means the very first in the list
and then we can store this first element
in the firstCandy variable
of type JSONObject.
Since we want to find the attributes
within the firstCandy JSONObject,
we can call the method getString to
extract the primitive value associated
with the key name.
In this case, "Jelly Beans".
Similarly, we can call the getInt
method on the firstCandy JSONObject
to extract the primitive integer
value with they key count.
In this case, the value 10.
In this next quiz,
I'd like you to read through the linked
tutorial on JSON parsing in Android.
Now this example will be a little more
complicated than the candies example we
walked through together,
but I want you to try and
understand as much as you can.
Specifically, trying to read and
understand the MainActivity.java code.
Check here when you're done.