Let's review how to import and
run a libgdx project.
Open up Android Studio and
close any open projects until
you get to this splash screen.
On the Quick Start pane
select Import Project.
If you click on this button,
second from the left,
you'll jump straight to your desktop.
There, hopefully you can
find the ud406 folder.
If not, go ahead and
press these blue circle arrows, and
that should refresh the file picker.
The folder you want is
2.1.01-Demo-importAndRunAProject.
And hit OK.
Now that the project is imported,
let's get it fired up.
The easiest way to run the desktop
version is to open the terminal down at
the bottom left of Android Studio.
And then execute the command
gradlew desktop run.
There we go,
it looks like everything's working.
Instead of using the terminal, we can
also set up a run configuration so
that we can use the Ctrl+R
shortcut to run the game.
To do that, we can go to this
run configuration drop down,
select Edit Configurations,
hit the plus button, select Gradle.
We'll call this new run
configuration Desktop.
We'll hit this button, and
select the root project.
And then for
tasks we'll say desktop run.
Then if we just hit Ctrl+R or
hit the green arrow, we'll run the app.
Unfortunately, you'll have to do this
with every project you import as these
run configurations are stored in
the same place as user specific stuff,
like the theme you use, which doesn't
make sense to check into Git.
Finally, to run the Android version, you
can just switch the run configuration
back to Android, and
hit the screen button, or hit Ctrl+R.
Hopefully, all these steps are familiar
to you from a previous course.
But you might want to run through them
again just to refresh your memory.