The correct answer is the second option.
The second option is selling just one
thing, gold, the in-game currency.
But it does a great
job of showing value.
It has the percentage bonus of
buying more gold displayed right in
front of you.
The value is clear and you're
encouraged to buy higher priced items.
The first option to buy stars in fruit
ninja has a great layout really clear
but the value is not clear
until I do some math.
It'll be helpful to have bonus
markers like in this one.
So this store could improve especially
if you wants players to go for
the more expensive packs.
And the third option for
candy crush has high price points and
doesn't describe the items at all.
So I probably wouldn't buy from this
store without more information.