Okay.
We gave you a link to the XML Visualizer
with this initial layout.
From the device preview we can
see that Natalie, Kagure and
Amy are positioned incorrectly.
First let's try to position
Kagure in the right place.
She should be located
to the right of Ben and
aligned to the top of the parent.
So I'm going to search the XML for
the Kugare TextView.
Here it is.
Currently it's aligned to
the parent top which is correct.
But this is incorrect, we don't want to
align her to the parent's right edge.
Instead we want to position her
to the right of the Ben TextView.
So now she's located
to the right of Ben.
Notice that I use @id/ben_text_view.
There's no plus symbol because the Ben
TextView ID was already created up here.
Next, let's position Natalie.
She should be located above Lyla and
along the left edge of the parent.
Here's the Natalie TextView.
It's located by default on the top
left corner of the parent.
Let's move her so that's she's
located above the Lyla TextView.
And the reason why I use this name is
because it was defined as Lyla's view ID
name up here.
Okay, great, so Kunal, Ben and
Kagure are positioned correctly now.
And so are Natalie, Lyla and me.
Next we just need to move Amy
from here over to here, so
that she's above the Omoju TextView.
Here's the Amy TextView.
Currently she's aligned
to the parent bottom.
But instead we want to align her
to the right edge of the parent.
So, let's change that.
Then we want to position her
above the Omoju TextView.
The reason why we know to use this ID
is because it was defined as the ID for
the Omoju TextView.
Cool and now it's in the right place.