So for the first task, we should
add the second word constructor.
Now here my word class,
I'm going to copy and
paste the existing constructor, and
work off of that one as my base.
Remember to copy the comments as well.
So copy and paste.
This second constructor
will take in a third input,
which will be the integer
image resource ID.
Remember that every time you modify
the parameters for a constructor, or any
other method in that case, it's always
good practice to update the comments.
So, I'm going to do that here.
So I added that the image resource ID,
is the draw-able resource ID, for
the image associated with the word.
So here in the body of the second
constructor, I'm going to initialize
the global image variable that
we called mImageResourceId,
and initialize it to the value
that's passed into the constructor.
So it's going to be given
the value ImageResourceId.
All right.
So once this variable's initialized,
any outside caller
can access that variable through this
public method, getImageResourceId.
All right, so
that completes the first task.
Now for the second task, we're supposed
to update all the category activities
to now use the proper word constructor.
Now let's take a look at what
the activities look like.
So, heading over to
the numbers activity.
This is what it looks
like when I'm done.
Here I'm referencing the images
that we added to our app, so
calling number underscore one,
number underscore two, so on and so on.
And I also want to call the Android
Studio does a good job of pulling in
the images.
So, you have a preview of
what image you're calling in.
Let's take a look at
the colors activity.
I notice here, that I use a similar
pattern to create the list of word
objects for the corresponding images.
And the same thing applies
to our family activity.
So the same code is used to
create family word objects
with their corresponding images.
And I just think it looks really cute
with all these little faces here.
Now last but not least,
is our phrases activity.
So taking a look at this, we noticed
that the phrases activity is unchanged.
And that's okay, because we created
each word object using the English and
Miwok translations for the phrase.
But we don't provide the third
input to the word constructor,
because we don't have an image for
each phrase.
So in this case,
we're using our word constructor
that only takes in two inputs.
So after making those code changes,
I want to make sure the app still
works by testing it on my device.
So let's tap into a category.
And we see that there's no
visible changes just yet, but
that will come next.