So one thing that I have noticed with
a lot of project submissions so far have
that a lot of people have been taking
the interactive resume to another level.
And they are adding different layouts,
they are adding charts,
they are adding all these
different things, a menu bar.
And what I've noticed is that
these students are going in and
playing around with the CSS,
maybe adding things to the HTML.
And applying maybe things that
they've learned in the first project,
so with the HTML CSS layout for mock-up?
>> Yeah.
>> So using that information and
then going in and
playing around with the CSS
with their interactive resume.
And then the end result is
you get something that A,
looks completely different
from all your classmates.
So it makes you stand out.
But also you can see them processing
the information they've learned and
really understanding it.
And so it really builds on
what you've learned so far.
And, I would recommend doing that.
>> Yeah great.
Thanks for the tip and
like can you elaborate more?
Why should someone just really
concentrate not just on the job
descrip but also to see CSS?
Why would it help them later on in,
when they're applying for jobs?
>> Well part of front end as we know,
is HTML and CSS.
And for a front end developer, they need
to have a good grasp of HTML and CSS.
Know how to adjust the page,
add functionality,things like that.
And so on top of that I mean,
with programming practice makes perfect.
>> Mm-hm.
>> The more practice you have.
The more experience you have.
The better programmer you are.
So you can learn all
these different concepts.
You can read, you can take classes.
But at the end of it all if
you don't actually do it.
And if you don't put it into practice
you're not really retaining it.
And so I mean going back to that you
should definitely as a developer.
>> Yeah I think so.
It gives you, if you're coming
from project one to project two.
Just don't forget that my God.
I don't need to use HTML or CSS anymore.
It's actually, this is still
part of your core foundation.
You're building your foundation and
we're just adding
JavaScript on top of it.
And also if you really just, my
recommendation too would be to really,
really make this project your own,
make this resume.
Just assume that you're
making this resume and
you're ready to show
this to an employer.
You know that's all.
And that big bit of extra care
makes a whole world difference.
>> To in this section it would be
wonderful if you were to add additional
interactivity.
Floating palmer components or
a navbar or.
What else have we seen?
I've seen a skills chart.
It takes the skills that
you've listed out and
kind of adds some kind
of a proficiency level.
It would based on what you input.
What have been some of the fun
things that you've seen for this?
>> Yeah, you can change the layout.
Right so as part of the navbar, you can
make different sections sort of appear
with different kinds of-
>> In different kinds of.
>> Yeah, with yeah.
Or with different sort of,
different CSS transitions.
So you can have fun with
the [COUGH] [INAUDIBLE].
>> Yeah, this is the project where
you start playing around a lot
more with creativity.
And then this last portion of the rubric
is indeed artistic creativity,
and the meet specification
is all CSS is default.
Basically, you do not touch
the CSS file or index.html and
change anything In there.
But do exceed specifications and
be audacious.
We do need you to change the layout and
the color theme and actually make
the project completely yours.
And these are the projects
that impress us a lot.
I would definitely say go to the
provided github repo that you have and
go through the read me that is there for
that project.
That is definitely going to help
you get started with project two.
The associated class, JavaScript basics,
also is very, very helpful.
It helps you get started
with the project.
So to exceed specifications in CSS,
we want to see a lot more than
just changing font and colors.
I actually all of us agreed on how the
length of the the page should change.
Or even exceeds the specification for
that.
>> So I think when people see
whether you change the CSS or not.
They go in and might change the font,
might change the font size, colors,
things like that.
But what we really want to see for
CSS, artistic creativity
is we want to really get in there and
play around with the CSS.
Not just go in and modify what we have
to really but really get in there.
Add Bootstrap, because you worked
with that for project one.
>> Or go in there, and
just move things around.
Maybe instead of having each,
it has a list.
>> Yeah.
>> So, the bioheader section.
And then you've got work, education or
work, projects, education.
>> Education, and then the map.
>> And the map, so it's very linear.
It's like a list.
Maybe you can go around and
use a grid system, or
some other framework to say,
you know what.
I kind of want to have
it in like squares.
So let's say we have bio at the top and
then we've got work, education,
projects comes at the bottom.
And there's a lot of different ways
that you can play around with and
we want you to get creative.
This is a project that I had
the pleasure of grading and
I'm still blown away by this project.
She took your basic files that we
gave her and then came up with this.
So, she has percentages,
different languages that she
might be proficient in, the map.
And, you can see that
the layout is very.
She even has this graph, which I think
is really cool, to show off skills.
And so it just, she went in and
she played around, put in extra images,
played around with structure,
she moved things around.
It was a great project and definitely
something that we're looking for.
>> This is a real student's
submission and we have.
Don't worry,
we've masked identification.
>> Yeah, it's hidden your identity.
>> Hidden this person's identity just in
case this person is sensitive about his
contact information.
But basically this is resume project and
if you look at the code,
the structure is the exact same
structure that you all have.
The HTML structure's the same,
the JavaScript code is basically the
same that you're going to be writing.
He's using all those templates and
helper.js and
he' s inserting all of
his information inside
this HTML file dynamically
via JavaScript.
And there is a section on the rubric
that says, to be audacious.
We highly encourage you to just
play around with the CSS and
this is basically all CSS.
Like the difference you see here is,
mainly on the CSS.
He structured things a little
bit differently to be able to
create the layout that he wanted to.
But it's a good example of
like how you can really,
really make this resume project your