Let's check out how to use
Shape Renderer to draw some points.
I don't just want to show things
off of my computer, though.
I want you to follow along
on your own machine.
Let's walk through loading up
a libgdx project one more time,
just to make sure you
got the hang of it.
So we'll open up Android Studio,
close everything until you
get to this flash screen.
Go to import project.
We'll navigate to the ud405
folder that you downloaded
earlier and
then open up 1.3.01-Demo-DrawingPoints.
Now Android Studio and cradle will
think about things for a bit.
All right, there we go,
we're all loaded up.
Now let's set up our desktop
ring configuration again.
We click on the right
configuration drop down.
Hit edit configurations,
hit the plus button, select Gradle,
give our new run configuration
the name Desktop and
then give it the task, desktop run.
Then one more thing so
we can see the files we're working with,
we'll open up the project pane.
Then switch this drop down
from Android to Project.
Awesome, now we're ready to get started.
Walk through these steps again and
we'll get to some actual drawing.