For this question an always
on activity is ideal here.
You want to be able to glance
at the stats during the run and
don't want the activity to go away.
But you can dismiss it
when you finish the run,
returning to your standard watch face.
For this question it's notification.
Stock prices can change slowly and
there's no need to keep
checking the watch.
The best strategy is to show
notification when the threshold has been
exceeded so
the user doesn't have to keep looking.
This one, it's regular activity.
If you want to look at some detailed
information, a regular activity is fine.
Once you're done, the activity
will automatically dismiss itself.
For this one,
notifications are the best way to find
out if there are new emails or messages.
The notification will vibrate when
something interesting happens.
There's no need for the user to keep
checking the display themselves.
For this one, probably a watch face.
Watch faces run 24 hours a day.
So if you want to track the steps
you take everyday of your life,
having this on your watch face
is probably a good place so
you don't have to keep
starting up another activity.
For this one,
it's probably watch face as well.
Watch faces run 24 hours a day.
So if you're the kind of person who
wants to see your calendar all the time,
a watch face might be a good idea.
You could use a color coded ring around
the edge to indicate your busy and
free times over the coarse of the day.
Or some other kind of non visualization
that doesn't involve showing
text everywhere