Now that we have our project deployed,
let's run through some scenarios
where we could run into problems.
So let's go back to our app.yaml file
and let's change our application ID.
Let's save this, and let's try and
redeploy it and see what happens.
All right.
So, in the pop-up window, it says,
Error 403 begin server output.
You do not have permission
to modify this app.
So this is what you can expect if
you try to run your project with
an incorrect application ID.
So, now let's try a different scenario
where we have a typo in our script ID.
So, let's change this to say helloword.
Typically this should match
the name of your Python file.
So our Python file is
named helloworld.py,
but instead we have helloword.
So let's save that.
And now let's deploy it again.
So, according to the pop-up window,
it looks like it ran properly.
So, let's check our web
browser to see what happened.
So, here is our updated web browser,
and it says Error: Server Error.
So, it looks like, since we had a typo,
it didn't deploy properly.
And if we go back to our localhost, and
this is also a refreshed page,
you can see that nothing shows up.