In the first exercise you also
saw string interpolation.
In other words,
inserting the values of variables and
expressions directly
into string literals.
Let's say we have a statement about how
much food my roommates dog Mia eats per
month.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
If we use a variable for
the dog name instead of Mia,
our statement becomes more versatile.
Here I'm declaring dog name and
pounds per month as variables.
So now, if I insert the variables
dog name, and pounds per month,
into my doggy diet string,
then I can print out that string,
and we will see that our
string has the same value.
Now let's say instead of Mia,
we want to know how much Zebedee
the Samoyed eats per month.
So we'll just go up here, and we'll
switch out the values for our variables.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Print it again, and voila,
we've got a statement about Zebedee now.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We can also use string
interpolation with expressions.
Zebedee is a pretty wordly pooch.
Let's say we want to know how much
Zebedee eats in kilos instead of pounds.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay.
So now we're making a new string
called metricDoggieDiet, and
we are inserting our
two variables in there.
But instead of pounds per month,
we're using an expression that
represents kilos per month.
And then of course we change pounds
to kilos here in the string.
And then this expression for kilos,
which includes the conversion rate, can
be evaluated as this string is built.
So now let's try printing out
our metric DoggieDiet string.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Uh-oh.
Okay, let's look at this error.
Binary operator cannot be applied to
operands of type "Double" and "Int".
Okay, I think I know
what's going on here.
Our kilos in a pound is double, but
our pounds per month is
probably defaulting to an Int.
So, let's make that a double, and
see if that fixes the problem.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
All right, here's our
metricDoggyDiet string for Zebedee.
And then if we want a statement for Mia,
we just change our dog name variable,
change our pounds per month variable.
Run it again.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And there's our statement about Mia.
And we are good to go.