[Thrun] Here is our 1-dimensional localization example again,
this time with particle filters.
You can see the particles initially spread out uniformly.
This 1-dimensional space of forward locations you're going to use as an example
to explain every single step of particle filters.
In the very first step, the robot senses a door.
Here is its initial particles before sensing the door.
It now copies these particles over verbatim but gives them what's called a weight.
We call this weight the importance weight,
and the importance weight is nothing else but the measurement probability.
It's more likely to see a door over here than over here.
The red curve over here is the measurement probability,
and the particles over here are the same as up here,
but they now attached an importance weight where the height of the particle
illustrates the weight.
So you can see the place over here, the place over here, and the place over here
carry the most weight because they're the most likely ones.
This robot moves and it moves by using its previous particles
to create a new random particle set that represents the posterior probability
of being at a new location.
The key thing here is called resampling.
The algorithm works as follows.
Pick a particle from the set over here and pick it in proportion to the importance weight.
Once you've picked one--and sure enough, you pick those more frequently
than those over here--add the motion to it plus a little bit of noise
to create a new particle.
Repeat this procedure for each particle.
Pick them with replacement.
You're allowed to pick a particle twice or 3 or 4 times.
Sure enough, you pick these more frequently.
These are being forward moved to over here, these to over here.
You see a higher density of particles over here and over here,
than you see, for example, over here.
That's your forward prediction step in particle filters.
It's really easy to implement.
The next step is another measurement step,
and here I'm illustrating to you that indeed this nonuniform set of particles
leads to a reasonable posterior in this space.
We now have a particle set as nonuniform.
We have increased density over here, over here, and over here.
You can see how multiplying these particles with the importance weight,
which is copying them over verbatim but attaching a vertical importance weight
in proportion to the measurement probability,
yields a lot of particles over here with big weights,
some over here with big weights, lots of particles over here with low weights.
They got copied over, but the measurement probability here is low and so on and so on.
And if you look at this set of particles, you already understand
why the majority of importance and weights resides in the correct location
given that we had a measurement of a door and motion to the right
and another measurement of the door.
The nice thing here is that particle filters work in continuous spaces,
and, what's often underappreciated, they use your computational resources
in proportion to how likely something is.
You can see that almost all the computation now resides over here,
almost all the memory resides over here,
and that's the place that's likely.
Stuff over here requires less memory, less computation, and guess what?
It's much less likely.
So particle filters make use of your computational resources in an intelligent way.
They're really nice to implement on something with low compute power.
Let me move on to explain the next motion.
Here you see our robot moving to the right again,
and now the same what we call resampling takes place.
We pick, with replacement, particles from over here.
Sure enough, these are the ones we pick the most often.
And then we add the motion command plus some random noise.
If you look at this particle set over here, almost all the particles sit over here.
It doesn't really show it very well on this computer screen,
but the density of particles over here is significantly higher than anywhere else.
There's occurrences over here and over here that correspond with these guys over here
and these guys over here and over here, correspond to this guy over here,
but the vast majority of probability mass sits over here.
So let's dive into how complicated this algorithm really is.