We can now, summarize a spectrum of
Firewall locations and Topologies.
The first are the host-based firewalls
that include, also, personal firewalls.
These can be placed on servers or
personal computers.
We can place a network firewall on
a router to protect the internal network
from the external network.
Or, a network firewall can also
be placed on a dedicated device,
such as a bastion host.
A bastion host can also have
a third interface through DMZ.
We can also have an external
firewall on a bastion host and
a separate internal firewall
on a different bastion host.
We can then put the DMZ in
between these two firewalls.
All the external firewall bastion host
can have a third interface to the DMZ.
We can also use a distributed
firewall configuration
that includes network firewalls,
and host based fire walls.