Here's how I solved the problem.
Since I know the settings
view is an instance of
the breakpointsettingsviewcontroller,
I'll start by examining that swift file.
And if I look over the class,
my guess is,
is that the problem could be occurring
in both the dismissSettingsTouched or
even the bugTypeSelected methods.
One of these two.
But to be sure, let's set a breakpoint
in each of these methods to make sure
that they are actually
being called first.
Set the breakpoints and I'll go back
to the app > run it > breakpoint
debugging > go to settings > and
I'll tap the red spider.
And we dropped right into
the bug type selected method.
So, it's a little strange.
If this methods being called, then why
is the view itself not being dismissed?
because it has it's call to
dismiss view controller animated.
Well one thing I do know is that if
this method dismiss view controller
animator is being called,
it's not causing any type of crash.
So it's being called
without any side effects.
So that's not the worst
thing that can happen, but
by the fact that we're not dismissing
the view, we still have a bug.
So let's read a little bit
more about this method and
see if it tells us anything.
If I hold down the option key and
then click the methods name,
then Xcode will display
a pop-up describing the method.
And it says that the method dismisses
the ViewController that was presented
modally by the receiver.
That sounds reasonable, but
we can dig a little bit further.
I will click the UIViewController
Class Reference to open up the docs
about this particular class.
And here I can search and
read more about this particular, where
are we, dismissViewControllerAnimated.
Now while I'm searching for this, I also
want to make sure that everyone knows
you can find this information online or
your could use a documentation
tool like Dash.
Dash is a wildly used
documentation viewer.
It's useful for other languages
other than just Swift and frameworks
like the IOS frameworks and such, and
I posted a link to the Dash website, and
the instructor notes
if you're interested.
Now if I go to the dismiss
view controller and
scroll down to the Discussion area.
You can see that it mentions that
if you call this method on
the presented view controller itself,
it automatically forwards the message
to the presenting view controller.
Now this kind of makes me curious.
Which view controller is actually
presenting the settings view?
So we'll go back to our code, and we'll
look at the self in the variables view
because self is what we're using to make
this dismissViewControllerAnimated call.
In the Search box of the variables view,
I'll type in the word viewController
to filter our results.
Here if we click through the drop downs,
we can see that it has a parent view
controller, maybe that's it,
it says UI navigation controller.
But, I also know based on the quick
description that we read,
it mentioned something about
presenting things modally.
And our parent modal view
controller is currently set to 0X0,
which is really just a special
address meaning null or nil.
So let's go over to the story board and
see how this thing is being presented.
Zoom out a little bit, and if we look
at the breakpoint bug view controller,
see that it has a segue here.
And the segue that's presenting this is
a show segue which is not quite right.
This should be a modal segue
based on what we're reading.
In order for
it to work correctly with the self
dismiss view controller
animated method that we saw.
So let's try changing this to modal.
You may have caught on too if you can
see the icons here are different.
So like the icon for the previous
one which worked fine was modal or
we can assume that it's because
of this present modally.
If we made it show and made it modal.
There we go.
So this seems like it may be our fix,
and we'll go ahead and try it.
So now, if I go to settings,
I'll tap one of the bugs.
What has happened?
Okay, we still have one of
our breakpoints actives, so
let's make these inactive.
Sorry, I'm hiding a lot
of different things here.
Just try to get my environment
the way I want it.
And we'll click continue.
And it looked like it
dismissed just fine.
Try that again.
And it looks like we've found and
fixed our problem.
Now, before we move ahead,
I want you to ask yourself how hard is
might've been if we used
only print statements.
You'd see that breakpoints and also
a good skimming of the documentation
can give us a lot more power and
flexibility to solve our problems
than the print statements
that we use by themselves.
Also, anytime you're
handed a new project,
using breakpoints like this to
step through each line of code
is a really good way to
understand how something works.