So far we've covered these two steps,
and now we're going to look at providing
alternate translations
in another language.
So in Android Studio there's
actually a neat little tool
called the translations editor.
You can access it by clicking
on open editor, or you can
right click on the strings.xml file and
then click on open translations editor.
There's a column for
the name of the string resource and
then the default value, which is
the English translation right now.
Each row corresponds to another string
resource that we defined in our
strings.xml file.
If we click on the globe icon
here we can add a new language.
I'm going to type Spanish and
add Spanish.
You can click on the cell here to
provide the Spanish translation for
the string resource, thank you.
I'm going to type in gracias,
which means thank you,
in my terrible Spanish accent.
We can do the same for
our toppings header and
this is the Spanish translation.
I'm not even going to
try to pronounce that.
Now let's rebuild our app.
My device still has Spanish as a default
language, and when I open up our app,
now I see that the toppings
header is translated in Spanish.
The rest is still in English
because I haven't finished it yet.
And then when I click on the order
button, then I see gracias.