In the onReceive that you've just
implemented, you got a context and
an intent.
Now remember earlier when you
broadcasted the detected activities,
you created an array list
of detected activities and
you put them into the intent.
See now if you can create a new array
list of detected activities and
get them out of the intent.
And here's a hint, you can use the get
parcelable array list extra method.
On the intent to do it.
Check out the documentation for that.
But that's the key.
Now, once you've done this, you're going
to easily iterate through this array
list of detected activities, and you
can get their type using the getType.
Once you've done this you can iterate
through the DetectedActivity objects in
the ArrayList.
Getting their type and the confidence
for this type using the getType and
getConfidence methods.
Note that getType will actually
return a code and not the string for
the activity.
You can find these codes on
the DetectedActivity class.
Go ahead now and write a helper function
that turns this code into a string,
and then implement
this on your onReceive.
When you're done, check this box.