So to drill down one step deeper, the next step in analysis is to determine,
what stage, each percept can be in. Each percept will in general, be modeled
with a finite state machine, and these finite state machines can be though of,
as executing concurrently. That is a state chart in this particular situation
is going, the models of clock radio is going to be carved up into different,
different, concurrently executing state machines, in which,
each state machine is, going to, or most of the state machines are going to
correspond to the states of the particular perceps. For example, the mode switch
can be in four states. And when the user sets the switch to one of these states,
this naturally affects the device's behavior. Let's see how this works for
one of the clock radio's percepts, its time display. How many different states
can the time display be in? For the moment ignore the two accompanying lights,
the AM/PM light and the alarm indicator.
Just the rest of the display, how many different states can it be in.