So, now moving on from programming,
I wanted to go next to more like
a practical application of data science,
maybe something like machine learning.
>> Okay.
>> So, it's really more of a thought,
it's a thought process that I
want to go with you right now.
And yeah, so,
this is when we work for Google, and
we are trying to build this spam
classification algorithm for Gmail.
>> Okay.
So, the first question, I guess,
is what features would you think,
would you put it into this?
It's algorithm, right?
So, a user receives an e-mail, and now,
we decide whether this email is spam or
not.
>> Mm-hm.
>> I want to see, if you could like,
come up with some numerical
features that we could eventually
feed to a machine learning algorithm.
>> Okay, so
an email comes with some things and
we'll figure out what we can use.
So, inside an email,
we've got a sender address.
I guess we've probably got some kind of,
I'm not very good on how email works.
>> Okay.
>> But there's a metainformation,
like maybe some.
>> Yeah, like IP addresses or
something like that, it might be there.
We've got the subject.
I guess we've got time and date.
>> Yes.
>> We've, obviously,
we've got the body of the email.
We've got attachments.
I'm trying to think what
else we might have.
I guess, what's the name?
Recipients.
So, it could just go to this one person,
but it could go to others as well.
I guess it's kind of in the subject
line, but whether it's a reply or
a forward, or something like that.
>> Okay.
>> That's about all I can think
of right now, I think, so.
>> Yeah, I think that's
a great list to start with.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
how can we start deriving some
nice features from this list?
>> So, I think a common thing you'll
see with spam is subject matter.
It's probably adverts for things that
you don't want or some kind of scam.
So, there's words in it that
you might not talk about a lot.
So in here and in here, like you've
got text, you've got text and
you can break that down into words and-
>> Okay.
>> look at what words are in there.
So, maybe there are some words
there people never, in general,
never talk about.
I guess, at the first thought,
I wouldn't do this but
maybe later on, like might look at
what that particular user talks about.
>> Okay.
>> So, but
they're also kind of in general things.
>> Okay.
Yeah, let's try to make something,
some similar features that I think might
be, because going without the text
is a little more complicated for
right now but, or
something like actually straight off the
bat, like very simple features that you
could even ask right out of
the sender side, for example.
Let's look at the first one.
>> Okay, so, sender address, they could
be in the person's address book or
have received an email
from that person before.
So, known or unknown to the,
I guess, to the Gmail account.
>> Okay.
>> Also,
there might be a known spammers list.
So, they could have been
marked in Gmail as spam,
in the past by another user or
by this user.
>> Okay.
>> And the same could kind of go for
this, as well, I guess.
>> IP addresses, okay.
So, let's go to known and
unknown addresses.
So, I think that's a great feature,
right.
So, if it's someone that
you have sent an email to,
it's more likely to not be a spam,
right?
What about unknown, right?
So, there's a lot of unknown email
addresses that are not spam.
>> Okay.
>> So, do you think there might be other
things about the email address
that might help us see unknown?
I guess there might well be
a whitelist of known email providers,
so if it was from a Gmail address,
you might trust it more, or
if it was from a known company,
you might trust it more.
And whether the address,
I don't know how to explain it,
but whether the address
actually matches, the address
shown is matching the address
underneath, do you know what I mean?
>> I know exactly what you mean.
>> Like spoofing, I guess it's called.
>> That's a great,
that's a great feature too, yeah.
>> So, we've got, within the unknowns,
we've got spoofed or not.
That's a big red flag.
We've got maybe known email provider.
I would be tempted to say something
like whether the words in there
make any sense as dictionary words,
but I think that's kind of a bit far,
because people's names and people's
online identities can be kind of
different from the normal
dictionary words.
>> Yeah, and then, so yeah,
I think that's a great set of features
from the sender's address list.
Let's look at the IP address.
>> Okay, so,
I guess I don't know too much
about how that all works but I, is there
a sense, is there a way of like-
>> Let's
say we can map the IP
address to a country.
>> Okay, let me.
So, country.
So, I guess, whether it's the same
country as the person is in, or
the same country as other people
who send this person emails like,
I'm not from the country I live in so.
>> Yeah.
No country for
recipient.
I guess that maybe also
fitting the language,
because whilst I haven't
written it down,
I imagine that's pretty easy to extract
from the subject line in the body.
Not too hard, so whether the country and
the language match or
not might be relevant.
I guess they're are kind of
when spammers send emails,
they route them around all
kinds of funny places.
But I don't know how would you,
how would you do,
how would you do that without
just putting a bias, right?
because if you said there are lots
of spammers in x country,
there are also lots of people in
that country who send valid emails.
>> Yeah, so to a certain degree right,
that's where the machine learning
algorithm eventually may be
able to come with, right?
So they,
there's a higher likelihood that someone
from a certain country is a spammer,
relative to other countries, not because
the person is from that country.
It only means there's
going to be a spam.
>> Okay, so
prevalence of spam in that country.
>> Mm-hm.
Yeah, so you'd have like a conditional
probability of whether somebody from
that country is-
>> Yeah, that sounds perfect.
>> I guess,
knowing a little bit about Google,
I know that they really try and
avoid bias.
So, they would not want to be biased,
[LAUGH] but
they obviously need to make
spam filters that work.
Okay.
>> Yeah, so actually I think this is
a great list of features we can start
fitting into an algorithm, right?
So, let's look at our algorithms, right.
So what, what we feed it to?
Let's say we have, let's say
you're Goggle, right, you have,
you have millions and
millions of users you need to be able to
train an algorithm with all that data.
>> Okay.
>> And this is a more philosophical
question more than anything,
because there's no right answer.
Yeah, so what are your thoughts?
>> Well, so
this is a binary classification problem.
So, I think that one thing that can
work well with large data sets for
this kind of problem and
even with text is Naive Bayes.
So, the problem with
Naive Bayes would be
that it treats everything as separate.
So, especially around these things.
You've got some kind of interactions
between, I remembered the word, [LAUGH],
interactions between the features
that you would lose at Naive Bayes.
But you can get good performance.
I guess there are other ways too,
so what else could I use?
So, I guess support vector machines-
>> Support vector machines
>> Can split things into categories
which might work too, actually.
>> So, what are maybe some pros and
some cons, I guess,
of using a support vector machine for
a case like this?
>> I suppose, I'm not super comfortable,
in real life, I would be going away and
looking it up.
I think,
my understanding is that they can be
a bit slower at least to train things,
at least to train on large data sets.
I'm not quite sure,
are they are they okay with
testing new data or
are they going to be slow there?
>> They take a lot of memory,
so that one is pretty fast, but
it's slow in the training,
very slow at training,yeah.
>> And I can imagine with something like
this, you're going to want to retrain or
reinforcement kind of
idea all the way through,
because people are clicking
this is spam, all the time.
>> Yeah.
There's going to be also come about so.
Your current thoughts were support
vector machine on these base algorithms.
Are there any other algorithm that maybe
is just more standard, more simple?
Some type of regression maybe?
>> Well, a logistic regression would
separate things into parts, I guess.
That could, yeah,
I guess that could work.
Yeah, I don't know tons about
logistic regression, so
I don't want to say
things that aren't true.
>> Okay.
>> But I can see how that would do
the classification that we might want.
>> Yeah, that's great.
That's great, so yeah, and now we are
ready to, you know, go work for Google,
and no just kidding.
We want to.
>> [LAUGH]
>> [LAUGH] Then go with them.
Yeah, great.