One mode of IPC that operating system
support is called message passing.
As the name implies, processes create
messages and then send or receive them.
The operating system is responsible for
creating and
maintaining the channel that will be
used to pass messages among processes.
This can be thought of as some
sort of buffer or FIFO queue.
Other type of data structure.
The operating system also provides
some interface to the processes so
that they can pass
messages via this channel.
The processes then send or
write messages to this port.
And on the other end the processes
receive or read messages from this port.
The channel is responsible for passing
the message from one port to the other.
The OS Kernel is required to both
establish the communication channel,
as well as to perform every
single IPC operation.
What that means is
that both the send and
receive operation require a system call,
and a data copy as well.
In the case of send,
from the process address base
into the communication channel.
And in the case of receive,
from this channel into
the receiving process address base.
What this means is that a simple request
response interaction among two processes
will require four user kernel crossings,
and four data copies.
In message passing IPC, these overheads
of crossing in and out of the kernel and
copying data in and out of the kernel,
are one of the negatives
of this approach.
A positive of this approach
is it's relative simplicity.
The operating system kernel will
take care of all of the operations,
regarding the channel management,
regarding the synchronization.
It will make sure that data is not
overwritten or corrupt in some way, as
processes are trying to send or receive
it, potentially at the same time.
So that's a plus.