The first distributed file system
mechanism we will look at is caching.
Caching is a general optimization
techniques in distributed systems,
where the clients are permitted to
locally maintain a portion of the state.
In this case,
portions of the files or file blocks.
And also the clients
are permitted to perform some
operations on that cached state locally.
For instance, some of the open or
read or write operations
can be issued against the locally
cached files or file portions.
This can be done potentially
without contacting, and
overloading the actual file servers.
Keeping the cached portions of
the file consistent with the on server
representation of that file, requires
that we have some coherence mechanisms.
For instance, in this illustration,
clients one and
two both cache a portion of the file F.
However, Client 2 has
subsequently modified that file,
F prime, and has also updated the file
server to reflect those changes.
The question then is, how and
when will Client 1 find out that
Client 2 has performed these changes?
The problem here is similar to
maintaining cache coherence in shared
memory multi processors.
There we said that we use mechanisms
like write-update and write-invalidate,
and these mechanisms get triggered
whenever a particular variable, or
a particular memory
location gets written to.
What this would mean in the context of
this example that whenever Client 2
performs any kind of update to some
portion of file F in its cache,
that, that would be
propagated to Client 1.
Either as a write-invalidation
message or
a write-update,
the actual change will be visible here.
But given the very different
communication costs, and also latencies
that exist in distributed systems,
achieving this may not be realistic.
And also, it may not even be necessary,
given the ways that
files are being shared.
Instead for distributed file systems,
things that make sense would
be to trigger some of these coherence
mechanisms on demand when the client
needs to access a file or periodically
whenever the client is open.
And when exactly get executed will
also depend on whether the coherence
mechanism is something that is client
driven so the client initiates.
I need to find out if
the file is updated.
I need to see the new
version of this file.
Or, server-driven,
where the server notifies the clients
who have cached the file, in this case,
Client 1, that something has
changed about their cached state.
The exact details of how and when the
coherence mechanisms are executed have
to be such so that the file system
can maintain consistence guarantees.
However, what those details will
be will depend on the file sharing
semantics that this distributed
file system needs to support.