So let's talk a little bit
about scene reconstruction.
The whole purpose of scene
reconstruction is to automatically
estimate the position, orientation and
focal length of cameras.
We also then want to
be able to model and
extract 3D positions of feature points.
I'm not going to get into a lot of
details about basically how we can get
to focal length of cameras in fact,
Noah Snavely, on his website,
has a very nice tool to bundle our.
That actually let's you do this kind of
stuff with variety of different types of
methods and
pictures that you upload to it.
I will actually make available to
you some other resources to look at
how to do this kind of
camera calibration.
But we, kind of, skipping that for now,
because the kind of stuff we
need to do would be basically,
we'll be able to move forward without
getting into those types of details.
So what we really want to do to be able
to automatically estimate is first we
want to do feature detection,
something we have talked about before.
Then we basically want to do a little
bit of matching of features, something
again we have looked at before,
and we will talk about again now.
Using this we want to be able
to find correspondences.
Remember we talked about correspondences
a lot when we talked about stereo.
We needed to find two points in an image
that allowed us to then actually compute
a disparity map, which would be
then used to create a depth map or
a depth image that we can actually use
the extract depth arrange of an image.
Same concept, now we want to do this not
just with two images but a lot more.
And again, we want to run to something
called structure from motion,
I'll talk a little about that next,
in a few minutes.