So, if a client asks you to
develop an application that should
display the temperature
in several cities
in both Celsius and Fahrenheit,
both as text and as a graph.
Just a color or a line graph, whatever.
How would you go and design it?
And by designing mean,
the architecture of the application,
not graphical design.
I'm thinking with model view controller.
>> Okay, yeah.
Use the whiteboard.
So, I like to start with the model
when I'm thinking about
applications like this.
And when you said graph, I kind of
quickly thought about data points.
So in this case,
maybe like a temperature point.
So, we'll just say struct for now, and
let's say it needs
a temperature reading.
I'll just, let tempReading.
So, something like this and
I'll put it as a double.
I don't know exactly what
system we need to be in.
But whether we want to do the readings
in Celsius or Fahrenheit, but
don't worry about that for now.
>> Okay.
>> And then maybe a timestamp.
>> I want just to show them in
several degrees Celsius, Fahrenheit.
It doesn't really matter
how you do the reading,
as long as the user can see it in both.
>> Okay.
Okay, so this will work then, I think.
Maybe I'll just call it temp,
make it more simple.
So we'll have a temperature.
And then since,
if we're going to display it on a graph,
in a graphical format, it'd be nice
to have a date when it was recorded.
I can use a date of maybe
some information about
the region in the locality or something.
So, region.
And for this, are we going to display
them based on maybe city, or does it?
>> A city.
City is enough.
>> Okay.
We'll do more precision.
Okay, I guess what I'm trying to ask,
is it a small set of places potentially,
or?
>> Yes, a small one.
>> Okay.
I would just use a string for now.
What I'm thinking is,
if you're say, displaying cities,
maybe there's a quicker way to filter.
Like, if we wanted to filter which graph
we're looking at other than just using
a string, but we'll go with this.
So we'll say this is the model,
it's a simple model right now.
And then for our views, let's think
about how we're going to display it.
So, it's a very rudimentary iPhone here.
You said, a graph and then just maybe
like a single temperature reading or?
>> Yes.
The temperature in Celsius and
Fahrenheit, both,
and the user might switch
from a text to a graph or-
>> Okay, so I'm just trying to,
in my head,
think about what it might look like, so
we might have something like this.
Show the time it was recorded.
So maybe we should use
something other than NSDate.
Just add time, we need some time for
this potentially.
We'll say it was like 10:53 PM central
standard time, since I'm in Alabama.
Assume it's going to be
central standard time.
And then of, maybe something
that talks about where it is.
So I'll just say Alabama.
If we want to be able to show both
Celsius and Fahrenheit at the same time,
it might be nice to have
like a calculated property.
If this is recorded, say in Celsius.
We could have temp F double and
then return, whatever that
calculation is to Fahrenheit.
And then for our graph,
I don't know if there's actually
a built-in graph display within
UI Kit or something like that.
>> There's core plot, which is not
built in, but a lot of people use.
But with, what I meant a graph,
it's enough to have kind of a bar,
that displays the temperature
with a slightly different color
maybe if it's getting hot, this would
be red and over here would be blue.
Nothing too-
>> So you're saying, plotting like,
if it's like we have
a little temperature.
>> Yeah, something like that.
>> Plot.
I have a little, like a beaker here.
Will we have multiple
points on the same?
Okay, so I mean, at some point, this is
going to be backed by a controller and
this controller, whatever it is, is
going to need to have an array of these.
We never name this.
We'll call this TempReading.
Reading structs.
>> So, if this is your model and
these are going to be the views.
Where is the controller in this?
>> The controller kind of
lives in between.
So, imagine somewhere kind of here
in the middle of these two things.
We have a temperature, we'll call this
something like temperature graph.
The view controller.
And we may have the single temp,
new controller.
And these two, since they're going to be
displaying essentially the same thing.
Maybe this is displaying one particular
element in an array of these structs.
These can probably be backed
by the same data source.
So, they could have a property
that is that potentially.
So, we'll just say,
it's temp data source,
or we could have these two classes.
Let's just say, we'll call this.
No, actually, that works fine, I think.
What I was thinking is maybe we
have them inherit from an object
that has the data in it.
So, we can have like a temp
data store or like that.
And then this particular class-
>> Mm-hm?
>> Gives us options for
like, add reading.
Get reading at index for
these particular one we want
to split a single one,
or something like that.
>> Okay, makes sense.
>> Yeah, so
it's a little rough but I think-
>> Yeah, but
I just want to have a broad
overview of if you understand what
are the responsibilities of the model,
the view, and the controller.
>> Yeah.
>> So that's our main focus.
>> Yeah, I mean my main goal with
these would be to try to keep them
as small as possible.
And just make sure that they're doing
the task they're dedicated to do.
>> Okay.
Okay, thank you.