In this quiz, you'll be thinking
about this hypothetical news app.
Inside the app, users will be
reading articles like this one,
about how California's in a drought.
They'll be looking at images
like this one in London,
where they actually do get rain.
And they'll be watching videos like this
one, where a Golden Retriever is writing
some JavaScript because that's
definitely something that could happen.
You've booched up the app to render
content above the fold pretty quickly.
You also know from your analytics
that most people look at a page for
a couple of seconds,
before they start interacting.
So, with that in mind,
what kind of tasks should you handle
during this post-load idle state?
Should you load the text for
news stories like this one or that one?
Should you load image assets like
this one, this one, or that one?
Should you load videos like
the web deb Golden Retriever?
Should you load the app's
basic critical functionality?
Or should you load the comments section?
Check all that apply.