Now that we've got the daily
special working in our app,
we can use Google Analytics
to to see how people use it.
For the Show Daily sSpecial activity,
we'll send our tracking
data to Tag Manager.
And then Tag Manager will
forward it to Google Analytics.
You already saw that you can put data
into the dataLayer using the push
method, specifying the key and
the value.
When we used it, the push values into
the dataLayer, keyed by food pref.
In this case vegan is a value,
food pref is the key.
Put an event in the dataLayer
is very similar.
You can call dataLayer.push,
specifying event as the key.
And then you'll need to
pass a bunch of other stuff
to pass the parameters for the event.
In this case the key absolutely
must be exactly "event," however,
it's easier to use
the pushEvent method instead.
This method makes it easier to
pass parameters for the event.
You need to pass the eventName, and
you pass extra data using the mapOf
method, specifying key value pairs.
Now, each of these keys corresponds to
a dataLayer variable in Tag Manager.
Let's see what this means
in practical terms.
In the code for our app,
in the main activity,
in the method that gets called
to show the daily special,
we can add the code to put in
an event in the dataLayer.
Get the dataLayer and
push an event onto it.
In this case, we're pushing the event
open screen and we're setting
Show Daily Special as the value of
the screen name key, and this means
that the screen-name dataLayer variable
will get the value, Show Daily Special.
So, go ahead and add the code to your
app to push an event into the dataLayer
when the user clicks
the Show Daily Special button.
In Main Activity you're going to update
the method startShowDailySpecialActivity
to push the openScreen event
into the dataLayer, and
you need to set the value
of the screen-name kry.
You'll create the new screen-name
dataLayer variable in tag manager
in the next section.