Here is the block device stack figure
from the previous morsel, as we said,
it has well-defined interfaces among the
applications and the kernel level file
system and this is what makes it easy to
change the implementation of the file
system that we want to use without
making any changes to the applications.
In the same way we can also change what
is the particular type of a device that
a file system uses without really
making changes further up the stack.
However, what if we want to make
sure that the user applications
can seamlessly,
as a single file system, see files that
are distributed across multiple devices?
And, if on top of that, different types
of devices work better with different
file system implementations,
or what if the files
aren't even local on that particular
machine, on some of the devices?
What if they need to be
accessed via the network?
To deal with these differences,
operating systems like Linux
use a virtual file system layer,
the virtual file system will hide from
applications all details regarding
the underlying file system.
Whether there is one or more, whether
they use one or more local devices or
a file systems they reference remote
servers and use remote storage.
Applications continue to interact
with this virtual filesystem
using the same type of API,
for instance the POSIX API and
the virtual file system will
specify a more detailed set
of all system related abstractions that
every single one of the underlined file
systems must implement, so that it can
perform the necessary translations.