[Thrun] The reason why I went through these different invariances
is because they are really crucial to computer vision.
These and a number of other invariances really matter.
When you want to recognize objects, you want to write software
that is invariant to scale and illumination and so on
and that it retains the important information in the image
regardless of the present rotation and occlusion and deformation.
If you succeed in eliminating the effects of those changes
and build a truly invariant computer vision algorithm,
I will be very impressed with you.
You will have solved a major computer vision problem.