Now did you get something maybe like
this, with a right angle bracket?
That'll happen if you type something
with a single quote mark, or
with a parenthesis, or brace.
In order to get your shell prompt back,
with an arrow message,
you have to type the matching quote
mark, or parenthesis, or brace.
Then you'll get a command not found and
you get your show prompt back.
Now, if you typed exit, or
if you type Ctrl+D, you logged out.
No worries, you can just log right
back in like you did before.
And if you got into some other sort of
weird state where you're not sure what's
going on,
you can usually type Ctrl+C or look for
instructions on how to
exit back to the shell.
In any event, errors are okay.
Weird stuff is okay.
If you get a message from the shell
that doesn't really make sense,
you can try looking it up in
your favorite search engine.
And if that doesn't work,
post about what you did and
what you saw in the discussion forums.