[Norvig] Let's show an example of where a backwards search makes sense.
I'm going to describe a world in which there is one action,
the action of buying a book.
And the precondition is we have to know which book it is,
and let's identify them by ISBN number.
So we can buy ISBN number B, and the effect is that we own B.
And probably there should be something about money,
but we're going to leave that out for now to make it simple.
And then the goal would be to own ISBN number 0136042597.
Now, if we try to solve this problem with forward search, we'd start in the initial state.
Let's say the initial state is we don't own anything.
And then we'd think about what actions can we apply.
If there are 10 million different books, 10 million ISBN numbers,
then there is a branching factor of 10 million coming out of this node,
and we'd have to try them all in order until we happened to hit upon one that was the right one.
It seems very inefficient.
If we go in the backward direction, then we start at the goal.
The goal is to own this number.
Then we look at our available actions, and out of the 10 million actions
there's only 1 action schema,
and that action schema can match the goal in exactly one way,
when B equals this number, and therefore we know the action is to buy this number,
and we can connect the goal to the initial state in the backwards direction in just 1 step.
So that's the advantage of doing backwards or regression search rather than forward search.