How about, just an easier way.
Once again, to the rescue, is going to come homogeneous coordinates.
And, we're just going to assume that we have a rotation matrix, okay.
So here, I took that top equation,
that the p b is the rotated version of p a, and now,
instead of the identity matrix in the top left, and the offset in the right,
we have the rotation matrix here, and that's a three by three.
So this is zero vector is a three by one of zeroes, so transposed is just zero,
zero, zero, this is zero, zero, zero this way.
Okay.
And that makes, rotation a matrix multiplication.
And again, we, we're using homogeneous coordinates.
And to remind you, unlike translation, rotation is not commutative.