So here the instructions with a quiz.
First, I like you to open up
the court counter app and
you can download it from the the
instruction notes below if you need it.
Next, enter some
information to the app and
then afterwards,
close the app off completely.
So these means going into the all
app screen and then swiping it away.
Lastly, reopen the app and
see what happens.
After you've tried these instructions,
go ahead and answer this question.
Did you notice anything strange?
Perhaps, the data you entered initially
was missing after you reopened it or
maybe the colors of the application
has changed slightly.
Or maybe even the menu
bar has disappeared or
perhaps the buttons in the app
are no longer responding to touch.
Give these instructions a try and
then move on to the next video and
we'll see what strange things are afoot.