So in quick summary, for the things we covered so far.
What I discussed was Computational Photography, the basics of it and
how it computationalizes the entire workflow photography.
Basically we talked about rays of light being the crucial element.
And of course, we're still trying to get pixels.
But pixels could have different types of meanings now.
In essence, we're generalizing the control.
How elements of different elements of photography, elimination optics,
apertures, sensor, processing, display and
sharing can be actuated by computation.
And that's the key.
Of course, the goal is all of this would enhance the photographic process to
let you generate more novel images.
In the next class I'm going to provide a specific example of
computational photography, in fact I'm going to give two different examples.
These will allow us to do a deeper dive into what
computationalizing the different elements of photography are all about.
And help us create both a vocabulary and
kind of an understanding of what are the aspects of computational photography.
And again, those examples, the two examples we used extensively, the rest of
the term to kind of situate different technologies we're going to be studying.
And just a quick thanks to people like the for
example the camera 2.0 paper and I also borrowed some ideas from
other people who have been working in the area of computation photography.