Whenever I ask you that the answer is always partially explain how and
here's why.
Yes, normalize correlation is powerful if you happen to have the template.
And in here for Waldo, we have the exact template.
How do I know? I actually cut it out of this picture to begin with,
then I made a template out of it.
But if I don't know what Waldo's going to look like.
All right?
So he's got that same dumb hat and the striped shirt, but
he could be bent over, et cetera, whatever.
I don't have the exact right template.
But now think about stepping back and blurring it just a little, so there's
kind of red stuff up here and reddish, whitish, pinkish stuff down below.
So your template is sort of close.
So you might actually be able to get some candidate examples.