We'll start with a naive attempt to implement our tracking
application. This digitized procedure here,
represents the producer method and the
tracker is the consumer one. This if statement is intended
to stop the digitizer from wrapping all the way around the
queue and overriding a frame before the tracker has had
a chance to process it. This if statement is intended to
stop the tracker to work all the way around the
queue to a frame it has already tracked again. Try to
see if you can find the problem with this code. Is it that we
can't write to the same memory more than once in a threaded program? Is
it that the threads will go into an infinite loop? Is it that this
bufavail isn't updated atomically? Or is it
that each thread has its own bufavail variable.