In this section, you'll add the files
to your app to include functionality
to display the daily special.
And it'll update daily of course,
being a daily special.
These all sound so tasty.
And you'll learn how to use
container from Tag Manager to update
the daily special.
To get ready though, you need to add
the daily special activity to your app.
You'll add the Show Daily Special
button to the main activity.
Then you'll need to add
the button in the main layout.
And then you'll need to add the on
click code in Main Activity, so
that when the user presses the button,
they see the daily special.
So you'll need to add the Java class for
ShowDailySpecialActivity.
It's very similar to the other
classes such as ShowRecipeActivity.
It shows the info box, and
also we're going to have it
include an Order Online button.
And you can hardwire the value
of the daily special for now.
Don't forget to update
the Android manifest.
I always forget that,
and then I get an error.
You'll need to add the layout file for
the Show Daily Special activity screen.
It's much like the other screens,
such as, show recipe or
show dinner suggestion.
And in this case we just have
this one button, Order Online.
And of course, don't forget to
run the app and try it out.
I encourage you to write the code and
create the config files yourself.
But if you're not in the mood for
it, we've provided predefined versions
of ShowDailySpecialActivity and
the new layout files that you're
going to need to add to your code.
So go ahead and do these steps, and
check the boxes when you're done.