Right.
so, I'm a very strong believer that given time and
open source like analytics stack and
the pieces of that will emerge as the standard in the valley.
And it's really determined by like,
companies and the problems that they're aiming to solve.
When I think of analytics I think primarily of-
[CROSSTALK].
>> Mm-hm.
So, I've spent a lot of time looking at,
like, what Twitter's architecture looks like.
And, I know for at least processing, stream, for
stream processing, you guys are a very big storm shop.
>> Mm-hm.
>> In terms of scaling out your infrastructure, I guess,
I know you guys use like, me cells a lot for, like, resource management.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Resource scheduling.
I'm kind of curious about the query side of things, and, and
I guess maybe the event the event handling side of things-
>> Mm-hm.
>> where, oh, sorry, event delivery side of things.
So, how you guys are solving that problem.
Yeah, I think like, I mean if you look at all of the [INAUDIBLE]
I mean some of the talks that they have given you here.
>> Right.
>> So I see you all know like the [INAUDIBLE] plane.
>> Yes >> As well as [INAUDIBLE] plane >> Yes.
>> And, the [INAUDIBLE] has turned into a lot of [INAUDIBLE] which is more of
a scribe, which kind of taps the data whenever the data,
the moment, instant data is produced.
And, from Scribe the data moves to a Scribe application systems,
from a Scribe application system it goes.
>> Okay. .
>> Into data loop.
It also goes to two cluster and cluster.
Andm at Kafka, we use it quite a bit.
>> Mm-hm. >> And it has been there for historic reasons.
>> Okay. >> And, the apologies kind of feed on those us data.
>> Mm-hm.
>> In order to produce the analytics and
the similarly passes bunch of back jobs.
And, the bad jobs are able to turn in the peg or
even scholarly because scholar is very popular.
>> Mm-hm. >> So, we use one of those two major things.
And, you can make your jobs like that or
on the real time you either directly express your data.
Sorry, you analytics using EPA, all of them are using some Hummingbird.
Again, Hummingbird is open source as well.
And these analytics are done in parallel or
in tandem, and will read the difference between the between the two.
And, once analytics is done,
then the output of these analytics are either turned into.
Some kind of key values [INAUDIBLE] cache,
depending upon the requirements of how long that [INAUDIBLE] has to be.
Either it has to be persistent or it's okay for
it [INAUDIBLE] then it's up to the [INAUDIBLE] writer to choose that.
Once it is written, then, then whoever is interested in
consuming analytics from what he called from an application point of view.
Then, they used appropriate API in where to get the data from.
Then, they had to obviously refresh the logic cache port.