Okay, it's now time to take this show
on the road by taking an Euler tour.
You know I'm bad, I'm bad, you know it!
Oh!
In your life, or maybe in this lesson,
you've observed that some tree traversal
tasks, like computing pre and
post-order numberings, look sequential.
Yet, they also seem
eerily like list ranking.
What you need is a way to
view a tree as a list.
Let's start with
the following observation.
You can take every undirected
edge of this tree and
represent it by a pair
of directed edges.
Now, notice that at every node,
the number of incoming edges equals
the number of outgoing edges.
For example, look at node 1.
It has four incoming edges,
it also has four outgoing edges.
This fact makes this
particular graph Eulerian.
Yee-ha!
That's Eulerian with an E-U,
as in Leonhard Euler, the famous
Swiss mathematician and physicist.
Now for any Eulerian graph,
there exists a directed circuit.
A directed circuit is a round trip
path that goes through every edge
exactly once.
I hope you can easily see
the Euler circuit in this example.
Now the point of all this is that
this circuit gives you a linked list.
So how does this help you do
something like, I don't know,
compute a post-order numbering?
Let's try to do a scan, or
a prefix sum, on this list with a very
clever choice of initial values.
First, start by recalling
the post-order pseudo code.
In the recursive call, it just
passes along the current value of v,
upon return it adds 1.
Aha, so what if you did the following?
First, assign a 0 to the head node.
Then consider any sink
node that's a child.
This sink is an example, it's the end
point of a parent-to-child edge.
So go find all the sinks and
mark them with a 0 also.
Now what about the remaining list nodes?
Notice that they're all sinks for
edges that go from children to parents.
That corresponds essentially to
returns from the recursive call.
So at all the remaining nodes,
let's put the value of 1.
Now notice what happens when you
do a scan along this circuit
starting at the root.
Take a closer look at all of
the child-to-parent sources.
Together with the final end point,
these values are exactly
the post-order numberings.
That's the basic idea behind
the so-called Euler tour technique.
Here's a summary of the technique.
Again, step 1 is to take the tree and
convert it to a list.
The list is the Euler circuit.
You then mark the nodes of the list, and
these are operations that can
be done in constant time.
Lastly, you apply a list scan or
list prefix sum.