Now that you've seen how to use
an existing content provider
in this lesson you'll build your own.
This will not only give you the ability
to share data with other apps but
also because content providers are part
of the Android framework, this will let
you work with other framework classes to
most efficiently load and display data.
You'll be building a content
provider for a to do list app
that lets you create and display a list
of prioritized tasks to complete.
You'll add new tasks,
query the data, and
delete tasks all through
the content provider.
After working through this app,
you'll then update the way
data is managed in Sunshine.
And you'll add a provider to act as
a layer between the database that stores
weather information and
the UI that displays it.
Since you've already learned
a lot about SQLite and providers,
we'll start off by taking a quick look
at the to do list app,and the code you
will be starting with, then we'll jump
straight to into building a provider.