Let's talk a little
bit about binding now.
Binding is the mechanism
that's used by the client
to determine which is the server
that it needs to connect to.
Based on things like the name of
the the service that it needs perform,
the version number of that service.
And also it's used to determine how
to connect to that particular server
to basically discover the IP address or
the network protocol that need to be
used for
that connection to be established.
To do this, to support binding,
the system software needs to support
some form of database of
all the available services.
And this is often called a registry.
You can think of the registry as the
Yellow Pages that you need to look up
based on the service name that you
require and then find the best match
based on the protocol,
the version number, the proximity.
Some other information.
That match will then provide you
with the contact details for
that particular service instance,
so the address, the port number,
the protocol that needs to be used.
At one extreme this registry can be some
distributed online service may be called
something like rpcregistry.com,
that any RPC server can register with.
And the clients then have
a well-known contact point,
how they can find information
regarding the services they need.
At the other extreme,
the registry can be a dedicated process
that runs on every single server machine
and knows only about those services
that run on that particular machine.
That means that the clients have
to know the machine address,
when they need to request
some particular service.
And the registry still
provides useful information.
It will tell the clients
what is the port number
that they need to use when they try to
connect with the particular server.
Regardless of how the registry's
implemented, it will require some sort
of naming protocol,
some sort of naming conventions.
For instance, the simplest approach
could require that a client has to
specify the exact name and version
number of the service that it requires.
Or a more sophisticated naming scheme
could consider the fact that words
like summation and sum and
addition are likely equivalent
to the use of the word add.
And so any service that uses any one of
these function names or service names is
a fair candidate to be considered
when trying to find the best match.
Allowing this kind of reasoning for
required supports for
things like oncologists or other
cognitive for learning methods, and
we will not discuss this in this course.