We will discuss later some of the implications on implementation that
are there because of the interactions between the user-level threads and
the kernel-level threads.
But for now, you need to understand that there are different levels at
which multi-threading is supported, at the entire system or within a process.
And that each level affects the scope of the thread management system.
At the kernel level we have system-wide thread
management that's supported by the operating system-level thread managers.
What this means is,
that the operating system thread managers will look at the entire platform we're
making decisions, as to how to allocate resources to the threads.
This is the system scope.
On the other end at user level, a user-level thread library that's linked to
the process manages all of the threads that are within that single process only.
So the management scope is process wide.
Different processes will be managed by different instances of the same library.
Or even different processes may link entirely different user-level libraries.
To illustrate the effects of having a different scope,
let's take a look at the following situation.
Let's say the web server has twice as many threads as the database.
If the user-level threads have a process scope,
the operating system doesn't see all of them.
So at the operating system level, the available resources will be
maybe managed 50/50 among the two different processes.
That means that both the web server and the database will be
allocated equal share of the the kernel level threads, so two each.
And then the OS level scheduler will manage these threads by
splitting the underlying CPUs amongst them.
The end result of that however,
is that the webserver's user level threads, will have half of
the amount of the CPU cycles that's allocated to the database threads.
Now if we have a System Scope, the user-level threads all of them,
will be visible at the kernel level.
So the kernel will allocate to every one of its kernel-level threads.
And therefore, to every one of the user-level threads across the two
applications, in equal portion of the CPU.
If that happens to be the policy that the kernel implements.
As a result, if we have a situation in which one process has
more user-level threads than the other, this process will end up
receiving a larger share of the underlying physical resources.
Since very one of its user level threads will get equal share of
the physical resources as the user level threads in the other process.