And the answer is only this outcome,
with A = -5, B = -5, is an equilibrium point
because if A switches, it gets -10.
If B switches, it gets -10.
Neither player wants to switch away from keeping with that strategy.
Over here, the Pareto optimal solution is not an equilibrium point
because if B switches, it will do better,
and A will do worse.
This is where the game turns out to be a dilemma
because there's an equilibrium point that it seems like
if both players are rational, they're bound to end up
in this outcome,
whereas the Pareto optimal solution is over here in the other corner.
And yet, being rational, neither Alice nor Bob can see a way
to get to this preferred outcome.