They can target you in phishing
attacks that are highly sort of,
we call it spear fishing.
Which is highly targeted,
the information about you
that'll come with the phishing.
They try to look like a bank.
They know something about the last
transaction you may have done or
something like that.
The way you did it or things like that.
So, if they can get hold of this
information, then they know about you,
and that information that they know
about you can be used to craft
a targeted or spear phishing attack,
which makes poor privacy good for
them, because it enables
them to get access to
information about you that can be used
in these kind of phishing attacks.
They know about where you
went to high school, or
where you live, certain age,
things like that.
Maybe they can come up with
correct questions about,
correct answers for security questions.
And that information, again, can be
used to gain access to online accounts.
So, poor privacy is basically
something that you know, or
you are what you do, or
something you know, or something you do.
That information leaks out to
the bad guys, and of course,
that information can be abused by
them for doing these kind of things.
So poor privacy is good for bad guys
and, of course, it is bad for us.