Here you can see how I've edited
my onCreate where I had previously
set up all of my different markers,
renton, kirkland, everett, lynnwood,
etc, by creating a new marker options
and setting a position and a title.
But now as well as the position and
the title, I'm setting the dot icon.
And the dot icon is set to
bitmapdescreptorfactory.fromresource.R.-
drawable.ic_launcher.
If I was using a different icon,
of course, I would just put the name of
that icon here, but for simplicity
I'm just using R.drawableic_launcher.
And you can see it's on
every one of these markers.
And that's it.
That's all I needed to do to
create the custom markers.
So if I've run the application you'll
see what you saw earlier on, where
instead of the standard Google Maps pin
I had the little Android pin instead.
And we you zoom in and out of
the application the icon will scale
automatically so
that it's always appropriate.
Now that we've seen markers for
locations and
how to customize them, let's look next
at another great feature of Maps and
that's the ability to
actually draw on the map.
You'll have a number of functions
that will let you do this.
We'll look into them next.