So putting those equations we just saw sort of into some simple pictures.
Our frequency in general can be thought of
going from minus infinity to infinity.
And the real part is the cosign part and its impulses that look
like this the imaginary part is the odd part that's the sin looks like that.
And as we said before typically we're only going to worry about the magnitude of
the power.
And so you just take the sum of the squares screw it up and
this would be the power.
When I combined the real part and the imaginary part to make power,
I can take a look at the power spectrum from different kinds of signals.
So here's some and I apologize for sort of the terrible picture.
So here we have just a sinosoid and
our sinosoid just has power there's two peaks right the regardless of the phase
the sum of the squares square root of is going to give us those two peaks.
And also here we have that square wave and
you can see that the power falls off as frequency goes up.
And that's what we we showed before and one of the interesting things also is if
you take a signal out of some sort of typical natural image, or
typical natural signal, you take a whole bunch of them.
You also tend to find these spectra falling off, and
that's just is a property of what,
of how images are formed by looking at things, in terms of, natural images.