So what's the issue here
with rolling shutter?
Let's look at the concept
of electronic shutters.
Here we're going to talk
about a global shutter
which is basically
what's in a CCD sensor.
Again, there are no photo sites with
an amplifier reading things are there.
Everything is first gotten onto the
photo sites and then read off and CCD.
That image is red at
one instant in time.
So, if I was to take this camera and
move it this way,
as I've shown by this arrow here.
What would happen is basically you would
get a full image every time I move it.
So, I basically have three different
images, because what's really happening
is, it's really efficient in how it
scans from the top down here as I move.
And it basically captures everything
in a global manner completely, so
nothing is actually moved
as I move the camera.
In contrast to this, let's take what
happens when I have a cellphone.
Again, very thin and a very small
sensor and a lens associated with it.
What happens is basically an image
is read one scan line at a time.
So now, if I was to take this camera and
move it this way.
What's really happening is
the first part got captured.
By the time the next scan rate comes in,
the camera is moved a little bit.
Similarly, when I move to the third one,
move,
the camera is moved a little bit more.
So, I keep going.
If you notice the camera is moving,
which basically means this straight
line, which would've been down this way,
is now curved or at least slanted.
So this whole scene has
been slanted a little bit,
because I moved the camera this
way while I was taking the video.
So the global shutter in this case
would have kept line straight,
the rolling shutter has created the
small angle that you can see from this
line here from this one.
And that is basically,
I'm moving this in this direction.
This gets much more complicated if I
was to move this in that way, right?
And that's why you saw the nonrigidity.
because if I had gone this way and
come back,
this line would have curved this way.
I'm just showing simple motion,
that's why I'm seeing a slant.
So that's a problem and
partly it is again, as I said,
as we go down in the scan in time,
we get a refresh rate like this.
The problem with this is we don't
know exactly what it is because it's
proprietary known for each and
every camera by each and every camera
manufacturer, we need to figure this
out pretty much from the data itself.