Signing an app gives you a cryptographic
way to associate your app
with a secret key that you control.
To sign this app,
we need to do three things.
First, we need to create a keystore and
a key.
Second, we need to create a signing
config in our build.gradle file.
The signing config basically
describes where to find and
access the keystore and key.
Then finally, we need to assign the
signing configuration to a build type.
You can do the entire signing
process via command line tool,
so don't think there's
anything magic happening here.
We have here a completely
stock android project and
note, that there is no
install release task.
That's because we haven't assigned
the release build type a signing
configuration, so
it can't yet be installed.
Let's go ahead and
generate our keystore.
We can do that by navigating to
Build > Generate > Signed APK,
up in the toolbar.
We'll say yes, we want to generate
the signed APK of the app module.
And now we'll create a new keystore.
We can choose to put the keystore in
our project directory just by clicking
this button.
So we're creating a keystore called
keystore in the root of our project.
We're giving it a password, password.
Then inside the keystore we're
creating a key with the alias udacity,
also giving it the password, password.
Then we're specifying some demographic
information in our certificate.
If we just want to create
a one-off signed APK,
we can continue on
through this dialogue.
However, we'd really like to
configure automatic signing.
So we'll go ahead and use a different
wizard to get that setup.
To configure automatic signing, we'll
right-click on the app directory and
select Open Module Settings.
Then in the Signing tab, we can
create a new signing configuration.
Go ahead and enter in
the information about the key alias,
the keystore locations,
and the passwords.
Now we can open up the Build Types tab,
select our release build type, and
assign the config, Signing Config.
Now you'll not that that
wizard actually added some
configuration to our build.gradle file.
We had the sign and configs block and
then the config, Signing Config
with that information we entered.
Also, down in the build types block,
our release build type now has
a signing config assigned to it.
And after we sync our gradle files,
you'll note we now have
an install release task.
Note that the store file field
is using an absolute path,
which isn't very portable.
There are various issues you might want
to consider regarding the security of
checking your keystore and passwords
in the version control, but the most
expedient thing to do is use groovy
string interpolation and the rootdir
property on the product object to
make this a relative path instead.