The answer is c. We are indeed allowed to write
to memory more than once in a threaded program, so its
not that. The threads will indeed go into an infinite
loop, but that's intentional. We want our tracker to run continuously.
Actually since bufavail is a global variable, it's shared among
the threads. So that eliminates this option. The real problem is
that bufavail might get out of sync. Going back to the
code, observe that these two lines might get executed at about
the same time. Our fear is that something
like the following might happen. The Incrementing line might
take the value currently in memory 3, load
it up, but then gets suspended. And then control
goes to the Decrementing line which loads the
value 3 into memory and then decrements it, turning
that value in the CPU register here to 2.
And then copying that back to memory, making this
2 as it should be, and when the increment
finishes, it should restore it back to 3. But it
doesn't, because it's already done its load. So instead when
it goes to do its increment, it changes the value
to 4 and then writes that value into memory, meaning
that we have a value one higher here than we
should. And as you can imagine, this might through our
queue out of sync if this happened too many times.