So now your app have the code
to send hits to Analytics
when someone views a product.
In this case, a dinner.
And we're using the Order Dinner screen
as equivalent of the view dinner screen.
Let's take a look at
the Analytics dashboard.
Make sure that the date is set to today,
or at least include today.
I recommend just setting it to today.
So, I'll start out by going to
Behavior and looking at the events.
So I have some events.
Let's look at what they are.
So, I have two event categories.
You'll probably only have one,
I kind of played ahead a little bit so
I have my add to cart.
Don't worry about that,
focus on the shopping steps, so
you should have the shopping steps
event category and you can drill down.
And you see we've got the view
order dinner screen action.
And then we see all
the different event labels.
So that's cool, but you already
knew how to send event hits, right?
So why did we do that extra work of
creating a product and a product action?
Well, it was so
we could get some e-commerce data.
Let's take a look at Ecommerce
screen in the dashboard.
Go down to Conversions, and Ecommerce.
Let's look at product performance.
So here we see the dinner
product showing up.
You can drill down into it.
This is the product SKU,
which is the product ID that you set.
We haven't had any
purchase transactions yet.
So this product hasn't
completed any revenue yet.
But, hey, that's to be expected.
Now let's take a look at
the Shopping Analysis.
Go to Shopping Analysis and
then Shopping Behavior.
So here, I see that my app has
a total of three sessions, and
one of those had
a product view activity.
Sessions with product views.
By attaching the product and
product action to the hit
that got sent to Analytics,
we were able to tell Analytics that
users took part in the shopping process.
So far, all our users have done is view
products, but that's a good start.
Gotta view them before I buy them!
So go ahead and
look at the product performance and
the Shopping Behavior Analysis in
your app in Analytics dashboard, and
then come here and
fill in these check boxes right here.