So let's look into a little bit more carefully the scale invariant features that
we are interested in.
The Harris-Laplacian is one type of scale invariant feature.
Basically, it finds local maximum of Harris corner detection in space and
Laplacian in scale.
What that basically means is, I have x and y, we've got the translations or
transformations scale.
In essence, if I have something in space here,
this feature could also be measured in different scales.
Laplacians, again, remember all of our work on Laplacian pyramids and
Gaussian pyramids that suggests how we could do this kind of stuff.
So, in essence, we can actually find the feature in different scales.
Which means that, now, the same feature, if you zoom into an image,
the feature got bigger, we should be able to detect it with this approach.
So, in essence, the Harris space is here, and the Laplacian is in scale.
So Harris is x and y, and Laplacian is in scale.
Another scale invariant detector is SIFT, and we'll cover this again in
a lot more detail, but I just want to introduce this very briefly here.
It attempts to find local maximum of difference of Gaussians in space and scale.
And the difference of Gaussian is simply a pyramid of differences of
Gaussian within each octave.
So this accounts for
our idea of different things that are in the frequency domain, and, again,
we're looking for these difference of Gaussians in both space and scale.
Again, looking at our simple example,
our simple schematic here, looking at variations in space.
But when we go up in scale, we can actually start looking for information.
The difference of Gaussians, both in x and y, and
also difference in Gaussians in scale.
Again, we'll cover this a little bit more in detail in a later lecture.
So SIFT in essence refers to a scale-invariant feature transform,
which allows us to look for changes in orientation, and
basically allows us to find features within it.
So it allows for
us to compute the best orientation for each keypoint region in an image.
And also captures keypoint description,
where we basically use local image gradients and selected scale, and
also look for rotation to describe each keypoint region.