And strongly typed languages attempt to
pass data that is not of the right type.
Remember we said strongly typed,
just make sure that when
you passed it for example, what you're
passing has to match the expected type.
Or the target type where
this data is going.
An attempt to pass the data
would either be called.
This shouldn't be allowed by
a strongly typed language.
Okay?
Because of typed mismatch.
So either it would be caught
at compile time statically, or
it gets caught at run time,
leading to an error.
So a strongly typed language will
actually detect that mismatch and will
catch any attempt to pass incompatible
type of data if you try to do that.
So this is possible in strongly typed.
Okay, strongly typed languages
don't allow you to access
array data beyond it's,
outside of the range of the array.
So the second one, we have to perform a
bounce check to make sure that you don't
spill into memory where some
other data type lives or
some other data item lives.
So you shouldn't be able to access
this other data time by just
sort of overflowing the bound,
ray-bound, that we have here.
So this checking has to be done in
strongly a type line which is weakly
typed actually may not do that and
as a result of that they may
allow something like this.
A W would be the answer.
Pointer arithmetic basically says,
pointer is an address in some sense,
isn't it?
Arithmetic allows you to move up and
down from some point or
value into various parts of memory,
and depending on how you manipulate
the pointer, you can get to sort
of arbitrary area of memory.
So this is allowed by languages like C,
by weakly typed languages, but strongly
typed languages do not allow it.
So they would not allow you
to do point arithmetic, and
it's going to be impossible.
And so the answer is it's impossible for
strongly typed.
So the answer here would be S.