Let's return to this equation, which we use to show how to do inference by enumeration.
In this equation, we join up the whole joint distribution
before we sum out over the hidden variables.
That's slow, because we end up repeating a lot of work.
Now we're going to show a new technique called variable elimination,
which in many networks operates much faster.
It's still a difficult computation, an NP-hard computation,
to do inference over Bayes nets in general.
Variable elimination works faster than inference by enumeration
in most practical cases.
It requires an algebra for manipulating factors,
which are just names for multidimensional arrays
that come out of these probabilistic terms.
We'll use another example to show how variable elimination works.
We'll start off with a network that has 3 boolean variables.
R indicates whether or not it's raining.
T indicates whether or not there's traffic,
and T is dependent on whether it's raining.
And finally, L indicates whether or not I'll be late for my next appointment,
and that depends on whether or not there's traffic.
Now we'll put up the conditional probability tables for each of these 3 variables.
And then we can use inference to figure out the answer to questions like
am I going to be late?
And we know by definition that we could do that through enumeration
by going through all the possible values for R and T
and summing up the product of these 3 nodes.
Now, in a simple network like this, straight enumeration would work fine,
but in a more complex network, what variable elimination does is give us a way
to combine together parts of the network into smaller parts
and then enumerate over those smaller parts and then continue combining.
So, we start with a big network.
We eliminate some of the variables.
We compute by marginalizing out, and then we have a smaller network to deal with,
and we'll show you how those 2 steps work.
The first operation in variable elimination is called joining factors.
A factor, again, is one of these tables.
It's a multidimensional matrix, and what we do is choose 2 of the factors,
2 or more of the factors.
In this case, we'll choose these 2, and we'll combine them together
to form a new factor which represents
the joint probability of all the variables in that factor.
In this case, R and T.
Now we'll draw out that table.
In each case, we just look up in the corresponding table,
figure out the numbers, and multiply them together.
For example, in this row we have a +r and a +t,
so the +r is 0.1, and the entry for +r and +t is 0.8,
so multiply them together and you get 0.08.
Go all the way down. For example, in the last row we have a -r and a -t.
-r is 0.9. The entry for -r and -t is also 0.9.
Multiply those together and you get 0.81.
So, what have we done?
We used the operation of joining factors on these 2 factors,
getting us a new factor which is part of the existing network.
Now we want to apply a second operation called elimination,
also called summing out or marginalization, to take this table and reduce it.
Right now, the tables we have look like this.
We could sum out or marginalize over the variable R
to give us a table that just operates on T.
So, the question is to fill in this table for P(T)--
there will be 2 entries in this table, the +t entry, formed by summing out
all the entries here for all values of r for which t is positive,
and the -t entry, formed the same way, by looking in this table
and summing up all the rows over all values of r where t is negative.
Put your answers in these boxes.