Let's see what it takes
to load up a nine patch.
So first of all we just load up the
texture that we're going to be making
into a nine patch, and then the nine
patch constructor just takes the texture
and how much to chop of the top,
left, bottom, and
right to define the nine patches.
In this case, the edge of our
scalable image has size eight.
So for instance the top left corner
is an eight by eight square.
The top edge is eight pixels deep and
so on.
Drawing a texture versus drawing with
a nine patch is almost identical.
The only difference is you call
batch draw passing in a texture, but
with the nine patch, you call draw and
then pass in the sprite batch.
And here we can see the results of
drawing with a nine patch verses drawing
with a texture.
If we draw a texture at a small size and
then at a larger size,
the screw heads get all tiny and
it doesn't scale very beautifully.
With a nine patch on the other hand,
the size of the screw heads is
always identical, regardless of
the scale of the overall nine patch.
Time for you to load up the texture,
chop it into nine patch, and
draw it out at a couple different sizes.