Another example is basically
we can get depth cues
basically by illuminating
the scene with a structured light.
In the past case,
the light was the intensity of the light
that will basically being put up and
how it shaded the image was used
to kind of reconstruct a shape.
Here, just by figuring out the stripes
and how well it's lit and using that
information and, again, you notice
that these stripes are very useful,
because I can, now I can trace the curve
to get the shape of this statue here.
And this can be used to model 3D
environments or 3D scenes like this.
This is a widely used technique for
doing range scanning of rooms and,
or people and statues,
and stuff like that and sometimes they
even use laser lights to do this.
Another method is shape from texture.
Here, I'm basically showing an example
where basically just looking at
the texture as a change knowing
that this is a regular texture.
We can actually compute
the shape of a cloth like this.
Also something we've played
around a little bit so far and
talked about cameras.
We can actually even get shape the focus
that is by being are to focus and
defocus an image.
In this case focusing on this one and
that one,
you can actually compute depth.
So here basically showing you the two
images, focusing and defocusing.
You can actually use this to compute
a depth image like the one shown here.
A very well known method is also
using structure from motion
in this case by moving the camera along,
around this building and
taking multiple pictures and then
actually doing things like we've looked
at already feature detection and
stuff, making sure that these features
are actually then matched
across these images.
I can actually construct
the geometry of the scene.
In this case, these cloud points
are being used to used to create a model
of the building that is there.
It's a widely used technique,
we'll actually see another example
of this in a future lecture