I love reading, I try to read every day.
Most of the time,
it's article about video games but
I like reading the newspaper, too.
Usually, I'm reading digital words.
However, I wanted to have something
tangible to talk to you about how
content is laid out.
Regardless of the medium,
digital or print,
any visual design follows a few simple
principles and it all starts with boxes.
Here, check this out.
Take this newspaper,
it's actually just a bunch of boxes.
The most obvious is the heading,
but you have smaller headings and
columns which are also boxes.
Then you can look at
the page as a whole and
it's just a big box with
smaller boxes inside.
Here, look at this page,
it has tables on it.
These are obviously boxes because
they have borders around it.
But what about this?
These don't look like boxes but
of course they are.
Really there are two points I
want to make about visual design.
First you can take basically any
design and turn it into a box.
And second, there are many kinds of
boxes with many different purposes.
HTML works the same way.
Here, let me show you.