I think one advantage that we may have is because all of
the different parts are sharing the memory, sharing the data.
The porting may be easier, or like the interplay between components might be
easier, but it seems like maintaining any kind of change for
the system in the long run is going to be more difficult than if you had
the components kind of isolated and the functionalities isolated.
>> So, [COUGH] we have shared data, it's all in memory.
That's going to be quite simple for
all the components to get out the information.
It's also going to be very efficient.
Okay.
There's no there's no function calls involved in getting that data,
you just go and get the data, okay.
On the other hand, if we wanted to change the way that that data is represented,
every one of the components would break,
all right, because they all have to know how to get the data out.
So we have a plus with respect to efficiency and simplicity, and
we have a negative with respect to resilience to changes in representation.