So let's think about how we can
get those same values from data.
Instead of you knowing in advance what
the model of this particular markoff
chain is.
So let's imagine that in fact,
what happens is we're going to do a
series of simulations starting from S1.
It's going to hop around and
with some probability it's going to hop.
It's going to go S1 to S3 and
then either S4 or S5 and then to SF and
then it stops.
And so let's imagine that we've done
that and these are the episodes.
These are the sequences
that come out of it that.
So the first time we run it it
goes from S1 to S3 to S4 to SF.
The next time it goes
S1 to S3 to S5 to SF,
then it goes S1 to S3 to S4 to SF,
and so on.
So what I'm interested in is
how we would actually estimate.
Develop an estimate of
the value of state one.
Given just this data after say
the first three episodes, or
the first four episodes.
The fifth episode doesn't involve S1 so
presumably it shouldn't.
Well, we'll get to what happens then.
But first I want to think about after
the first three or after the first four.
That makes sense?
>> Sure, I can do that.
>> Excellent, all right, so do that.
>> All right, go.