Here are the transitions I used.
Let's take another look at our state
diagram to see the correspondence
between these transitions and
the arrows in the diagram.
For the set of transitions
following the initial action a,
we only have one possible action,
going from state 1 to itself.
There are two transitions that
come out of initial action b.
Going from state 2 to state 4 and
then vice versa from state 4 to state 2.
Finally following initial action c we
have a single transition from state
3 to state 5 captured here and
then another transition from
state 5 to itself captured here.
Notice that all of these
transitions are deterministic.
So we have probability one for
all of them.
Also notice I used action id 0 because
it's the first action coming out of
each of these states.
For state 0 we had three actions which
is why we had action id 0, 1, and 2.
If you're interested in seeing how we
checked your code, please take a look at
the first MDP grader ex4.java file in
the downloadable section on this page.