So how did you do with this quiz?
I know that the whole variables and
triggers thing can be a bit confusing,
with variables depending on triggers,
which depend on variables, anyway.
So the first one,
the value of a data layer variable
is set by code in your app, is true.
So if you remember,
we set the food_pref value in our code.
The value of a value collection
variable is set by you
in the Tag Manager interface,
and that is correct.
So if we look at one of our variables,
Value Collection variable,
and this is where we set
the value of that variable.
And it takes a series of key and
value combinations.
We've only been using one key
value combination per variable.
A value collection variable cannot
include a key that any other value
collection variable uses.
Well that's just wrong.
We've been using
the daily special key and
a bunch of different variables,
not just this one.
The value of a key in
a value collection variable
can be triggered by the value
of other variables.
And that's true, but of course it's
done through the use of triggers.
Here again, in our daily-special-fish
variable, we have the fish trigger, and
the fish trigger depends on
the value of the food pref variable.
So here we have a variable influencing
the value of another variable.
A value collection variable can be
triggered by at most, one trigger?
Wrong.
So we look at, for
example, daily-special-vegetarian,
you can add multiple triggers.
I can add another one if I wanted.
It's important to understand
that any of these triggers
will set the value of this variable.
They don't have to all trigger.
Just one of them has to trigger.
And yes, you can create a trigger that
fires when the data layer variable
has a certain value.
So, if you look to our
vegetarian trigger,
this here food pref is a data layer
variable and when it has this value,
vegetarian, then this trigger will fire.
And you can create a trigger that
fires when the app is running on
a device with a specific
screen resolution.
You can create triggers that fire based
on any of the built-in variables,
of which screen resolution is one.
And a trigger can have multiple
criteria that determine when it fires.
You can add multiple
conditions to a trigger.
Just keep pressing the plus button.
It's important to notice though,
that the trigger will only fire when
all of the conditions are true.
This is not an or thing,
this is an and thing.
So they must all be true for
the trigger to fire.
So how did you do with the quiz?
Have you got your triggers and
variables straight?