Another useful way to add consistency
and distinguish different views in your
app is through text and
its different font and sizes.
The default text for
Android is a font called Roboto,
which is designed to work across
a range of differently sized platforms.
And it comes in a variety
of font families.
Font-families are groups of fonts that
share similar design characteristics,
like serif or sans serif.
Sans serif is the default in Android,
and
there's also sans serif thin, medium,
and condensed, to name just a few more.
The Android material design site
has recommendations for sizes and
font families to use for readability.
And a link to that site below.
It's typically good to stick with one
phone family throughout an app and
change the color, weight, or size when
you need to make some text stand out.
It's also good practice to have
only a few consistent styles for
different text components and
not just change the style at random.
For example, when you're displaying the
text for a headline of an article, it
should be bigger or bolder than subtitle
or body text since it's more important.
One thing to note about text size
is that it will be in units of sp,
which stands for
scale independent pixels.
Most views will be in units of dips,
or density independent pixels,
which we'll learn more about later.
Both dips and scale independent pixels
will stay the same physical size
across different resolution screens.
So text on newer screens
with lots of pixels and
on older screens with fewer pixels will
appear to be the same physical size.
Unlike dips, scale independent
pixels are also used for
accessibility purposes.
For example, if someone changes their
text size settings to be larger for
visibility, then Android will enlarge
any view whose size is in sp,
accordingly.
So using units of sp for text makes sure
that the text in your app will respond
to accessibility settings and
will be readable across devices.