On it's core, Remote Config is a key
value store for public perimeters in
your app that you want to be able to
tweak from the fire base console.
Key value may remind you
of the real time database.
But Remote Config is
meant specifically for
values that control the behaviors and
the appearance of your app.
But just because Remote Config can
update your app on the fly without
going through the regular
app update process,
doesn't mean that you should be
putting all your parameters in there.
Here are three things that you should
not be using Remote Config for.
First, parameters should not
require user authorization.
Remote Config parameter should be wholly
controlled by you, the App developer.
If you configure parameters that should
have been authorized by your user first,
it can make your app
untrustworthy to your users.
Second, confidential information
does not remain in remote config.
That means no server keys or
any other secrets that you don't
want anyone else to know about.
Since there are no security
rules on Remote Config,
anyone can access the parameters.
Lastly, Remote Config should
not be used to work around
policies of your app's platform.
For example, don't add a Remote Config
parameter that hides the figure
while the app is going
through app review.
And then remotely activate the feature
only after the app has been published.
Let's take a look at how we can
enable fire based Remote Config
in friendly chats.
We'll check out the fire
based console first, and
then implement code in the app.