We're now going to move to
a class of AI problems,
where it's not as easy
to find a solution.
In search,
we generally have a few correct routes.
And we have a few algorithms
that help us find that route,
in a fairly straightforward way.
However, in some problems,
the state space is so large
that we need other techniques to search
the space and find optimal solutions.
In this lesson we'll look
at simulated annealing,
one such technique to navigate
a potentially large space.
In particular, we'll use simulated
annealing to solve the n-Queens problem.
A puzzle where we try and
set up n-Queens on a board, in such
a way that they can't attack each other.
Let's get started.