For a generalized Hough transform, it was easy when we had a specific shape,
because based upon, our equations for a single point in an image or
a single feature or single edge line, we would know how to vote, we would
essentially solve for the equation that would tell us how to vote in the bins.
But if you have an arbitrary shape, how do you know how to vote?
Well, the way you do this is, you build what's called a Hough table.
It was actually called an R-table in the original article but
I think of it as a Hough table.
The way it works is as follows, for each boundary point, and here we have our
first one P1, what we do is, we compute a displacement or an r vector from that
point to, here I've got it as the center, but it's some reference point,
this is the point that we're going to use to locate the object, all right.
And we measure that r, that's a displacement vector.
The next thing we do is, we compute the gradient, and edge orientation.
And what, and what we do is, we take that r, and
we put it into a table that's indexed by theta, all right.
So if we had some other point, that had the same theta,
it would also add its r to exactly the same table location.
So you would have multiple displacements, and
I'll show you an example of that in a minute.
But the idea is that you create the r based upon the offset, and
then you index it by theta.
Here's our second point P2, it has a different theta, and
there would be a different r entered into that table.
So we store the displacements in a table indexed by theta.
At recognition, we essentially go backwards.
What we do is, at every boundary point, we compute the theta that's there.
By the way, for
now we're assuming that the orientation of the object doesn't change.
In a minute, I'll show you how to solve it when, well more than a minute,
I'll show you how to solve this when the orientation does change.
So at every boundary point, here's P1, we figure out the orientation, we go
into our table, we find all of the displacement vectors that are associated with
that orientation, so there's going to be this one, maybe there were some
others as well, but we're definitely going to vote with this one for this point.
Then later at P2, we find its orientation,
we find all the displacement vectors that are associated with that orientation.
That one's going to, definitely has this one, so this votes as well.
And the whole idea is that the,
the correct reference point gathers a whole bunch of votes.
So what you're doing is, you're using this table, this R-table or Hough table,
in order to tell each, found each point in the new test image how to vote.
This was originally done by Dana Ballard, and
I'll point out that this is back in 1980, 30 plus some odd years ago.
And that's just a way of showing you that what goes around sometimes comes
around, even in computer vision.