A good way to validate your model's
ability to make a good forecast,
is to use a holdout sample.
Holdout sample is a subset
of the time series,
usually the most recent data points,
that you withheld and
then used to check the accuracy
of predictions from your model.
In our construction of the ETS and
ARIMA models from the previous lessons,
we withheld the last six months from
our time series from model validation.
We then built the model
using the remaining data and
now we can test the results of the model
against the data in our holdout sample.
This gives us actual observed
values to test against.
The size of the holdout sample will
depend on how long the time series is
and how far you would like to forecast.
Ideally, the size of the holdout sample
should be at least the amount of
periods you are forecasting for.