Constraint layout allows you to
create a complex layout without
having to nest view
groups inside each other.
It's very similar to a relative
layout in that older views
are laid out relative to each other,
or to the parent layout itself.
But the underlying structure of
a constraint layout is much simpler.
And hence, it usually
outperforms other layout types.
In this lesson try app,
you're going to implement and
design a boarding pass application.
Something similar to the paper one that
you get when you're boarding a plane.
A typical boarding pass tells
you important information
about where to go inside the airport,
which terminal and which gate number.
It also tells you what seat
number inside the plane.
They also usually contain a barcode that
will be scanned as you board the plane.
The cool thing about smartphones is
that you can get live information and
updates to your phone straight away.
Like gate changes, or
approaching boarding times, so
that all that can be integrated in
your boarding pass application.
We will use a constraint layout to
build this design from scratch.
But before that, let's start and
make sure that you've got the constraint
layout libraries set up
in your Android Studio.