[Thrun] And the answer is yes,
although, technically speaking, to reach the absolute global minimum
we need the learning rates to become smaller and smaller over time.
If they stay constant, there is a chance this thing might bounce around
between 2 points in the end and never reach the global minimum.
But assuming that we implement gradient descent correctly,
we will finally reach the global minimum.
That's not the case if you start over here, where we can get stuck over here
and settle for the minimum over here, which is a local minimum
and not the best solution to our optimization problem.
So one of the important points to take away from this is
gradient descent is universally applicable to more complicated problems--
problems that don't have a plausible solution.
But you have to check whether there is many local minima,
and if so, you have to worry about this.
Any optimization book can tell you tricks how to overcome this.
I won't go into any more depth here in this class.