And the answer was: This is a positive point,
and this is a positive point.
These 2 points over here are negative.
So let's define k-nearest neighbors.
The algorithm is really blatantly simple.
In the learning step, you simply memorize all data.
If a new example comes along with the input value you know
but which you wish to classify, you do the following.
You first find the k-nearest neighbors.
And then you return the majority class label as your final class label for the new example.
Simple, isn't it?
So here's a somewhat contrived situation of the data point we wish to classify
where the label data lies on the spiral of increasing diameter as it goes outwards.
Please answer for me in this quiz what class label you'd assign
for k = 1, k = 3, 5, 7, and all the way to 9.