When we try to decipher
this cipher text,
other than trying all possible
26 factorial number of keys,
we can leverage our knowledge
of the English language.
In particular, the most common
word in English is the, T-H-E.
There are two three letter words here,
but the odds are good that the word
the is not at the end of a sentence, so
most likely this would be the T-H-E.
In other words, T was not to W,
H was not to A, and E was not to S.
Therefore this four letter
word start with T H.
From here we can use some guess work and
use our knowledge of the English
language to determine which guess
is most likely to be correct.
So if you follow this process of
combining the knowledge of the English
language, in particular the most
commonly used word in English and
plus some guess work, you should be able
to get this answer, this is the end.