You've got quite a few new tools in
your forms tool belt at this point.
You've spent a lot of time thinking
about forms as a whole, so
I want you to put your skills
to the test with this check out.
I'm going to give it to you in its
current state, which is a bit ugly.
This skeleton of a nice form is here but
that's about it.
You can tell that there
are definitely way too many inputs.
Clicking on the labels isn't working and
not to mention the color scheme
isn't really looking that great.
What I’d like you to do is
turn this into a simple,
beautiful form using everything
that you've learned so far.
This is an open ended exercise in that
there's really no correct answer.
I want you to apply what you've
learned about inputs, labels,
simplification, auto completion,
validation and form design.
You may find that you can make some
small tweaks to improve this checkout,
or you may want to just blow it up and
start from scratch.
It's up to you.
In the next video, you'll see me discuss
two different versions of my check-out.
One will use native HTML elements,
while the other will take
advantage of Polymer.
Polymer includes a set of
elements called gold elements
that I found to be really
helpful with e-commerce.
As this is totally up to you to create,
feel free to take advantage of whatever
framework or library you like.
Doesn't matter if that's Polymer,
Angular, React, or
something else entirely.
It's up to you.
The point of this quiz is to give you a
chance to think through a checkout flow
from start to finish.
I want you to make decisions and build
something that you're proud to show off.
I also want you to think mobile
first while you're designing.
You'll learn more about this in a bit.
But for now i just want you to do your
best to think about what it's like for
your mobile users first.
It'll be a big help.
Prioritizing for mobile devices
will only help simplify and
expedite your checkout flow.
When you're happy with your checkout,
share in the forums.
And while you're there,
peruse your classmate's forms and
give them some
constructive feedback too.
I'll leave a few helpful links for
you in the instructor notes.
When you're happy with your checkout and
ready to continue, check this box.
Good luck.
I know you can do it.