Out app can create
a notification on command.
But that's not super useful, after all
the whole point of our hydration app is
to remind us when to drink water.
And it's supposed to issue these
reminders automatically without
requiring the user to
actually do anything.
So our end goal for
this notification here is to have
it shown every 15 minutes or so.
These notifications should also only
show when the device is plugged in
like this, meaning that the user
is hopefully near a water source.
We could easily do this using by
creating a scheduled service using
a class called Firebase JobDispatcher,
which you'll be learning about next.