Let's put an end to this spam nonsense.
We need to make sure that the data
in the content column will always be
treated as having the same meaning,
as text, not as JavaScript code.
As it turns out,
there's a really good Python library for
doing this called bleach.
It's installed on your VM already, so
you can import it right into your code.
Have a read through
the bleach documentation,
which is linked in the instructor notes.
Once you do that, you can use bleach
to stop unsafe HTML from ever
getting from an attacker through
your database back to a user.
Go ahead and
make that change to the forum code,
but here's something to think about
when you do, do you think it would be
better to clean bad stuff out of posts
before we store them in the data base?
Or should we store whatever
the user sends us and
then clean the bad stuff out before
we display those posts in the forum?