Okay, I just created a new project in
Android Studio using the project wizard.
When I run the app on my device,
it just says, hello world.
Now I'm going to remove
the onCreate method.
I select the whole method
from the method declaration.
To the opening and closing braces,
as well as the @Override text here.
Then I run the app on my device.
Hm, interesting.
Now I see that the app is blank.
The hello world text is gone.
If I hit undo, then I can take
a look at the onCreate method again.
It appears that by
overriding this method,
we're actually causing the hello
world text to appear on the screen.
And that makes sense, because when we
call set content view, this is actually
setting the activity main xml layout
onto the content view of the activity.
So now we're starting
to see why it's useful
to override the default
behavior in the super class.
When we override the onCreate method,
then we can actually use
the layout that we want.
Okay, let's leave this deleted.
That was the second task.
Moving on to the third task,
I asked you to delete
the onCreate options menu method.
So we can select all of this here and
then delete it.
And now I'm going to
run it on my device.
Okay, it looks almost the same.
The content area is still blank,
and there's still an app
bar with the app title.
It's kind of subtle, but
you may have noticed that the three
dots here actually disappeared.
The three dots were for
the overflow menu of the app.
And apparently, if I hit undo,
then the onCreate options menu code
was actually controlling those
three dots showing up here.
To show you what I mean, I can add that
code back in and then run the app again.
Okay, so if we override the onCreate
options menu within the main activity,
then these three dots appear again.
And then I see a menu item
in there that says settings.
So again,
in the MainActivity it's valuable to
override the onCreate options menu,
because then we can provide our own menu
items, instead of just having no menu.
Even though we're altering and
overriding some of the behavior
from the AppCompatActivity class,
it's still extremely valuable
to inherit from this class.
It has a lot of complexity behind the
scenes, but we don't have to worry about
any of it, we just have to specify a few
lines of code to customize our activity.