Once you've looked at some
of the surprising points,
it's time to fix any
problems that you find.
Of course, you won't always see
the problem at first glance so
more investigation may be necessary.
Often though, you will find a problem or
two just by looking at some of
the surprising points, or you might find
that there actually wasn't even
a problem in the first place.
In this case, I saw that a student had
cancelled within one day of joining,
and that's not really a problem, and
it does explain why that student was
missing from the engagement table.
This is a good thing to be aware of,
though.
Depending on the analysis I do later,
I might want to exclude students like
this, or I might just need to know these
students exist in case they
cause an edge case in my code.
At this point, the process repeats.
Once again, I need to identify any
remaining surprising data points.
Of course there might not be any more
surprises at this point, since a student
who cancels the same day as they
joined no longer counts as surprising.
But it's still important to check
in case there are other problems I
haven't found yet.
Go ahead and
figure out whether there are any
surprising enrollment records left.
That is, rows in the enrollment
table where the student is missing
from the engagement table but
they stayed enrolled, at least a day.
Enter the number of surprising
records you find in this box.
It could be zero.