Let's look at how firewalls should
be deployed to protect a network.
Here's a figure that illustrates
a common firewall configuration, that
includes an additional network between
the external and internal firewalls.
An external firewall is placed at
the edge of the local area network,
just inside the boundary router.
The boundary router connects
the complete network to the Internet.
One or more internal firewalls protect
the bulk of the enterprise network.
Between the external firewall and the
internal firewall is typically the DMZ,
systems that are externally accessible,
but
need some protections
are usually located in the DMZ.
These systems require or
foster external connectivity, such as
the public facing corporate web server,
an email server, and a DNS server.
The external firewall provides some
basic or first line defense, but
allows access to these
public facing systems.
The internal firewall provides
additional protection.
In particular, it protects traffic from
a DMZ to the internal trusted network.