Now that we've created the set
of states, let's designate
one of the states in our domain to
be the initial state for the MDP.
At the moment, we haven't defined
any transitions between states.
So our choice of an initial
state is arbitrary.
But for grading purposes,
let's call State 0 the initial state.
Here I added in initState; field which
has the type of the Burlap object state.
Now let's initialize this
field in our constructor.
Take a look at the Burlap documentation
for graph defined domain again.
Using this documentation I'd
like you to fill in the blank
in this new line of code.
So that it initializes this.initState to
the 0th state in the domain
we created earlier.
Using this.dg.generateDomain();