Open ended questions like these are a
great way to demonstrate what you're
passionate about.
Lorenzo did a fantastic job by
describing his interest in music and
how he brought that and combined that
with machine learning to produce
a final product,
like a mobile application.
I was really impressed
by the work he did and
the way he explained how he got
the line per data and the challenges
he went through in order to put it
into a machine running context.
And then what he did with the result of
office machine learning pipeline
was also really interesting.
You have to keep in mind that machine
learning solutions are often sitting
in between a larger eco-system
off activities that are going on.
For instance, here there is
some audio input coming in and
then the machine learning algorithm
is predicting what song and
what portion of the song
is being played.
And then that information is being taken
by another component which then plays
back that same song using different
instruments accompanying the singer.
This is really important to
understand the overall ecosystem.
And was demonstrated
very well by Lorenzo.
You can also take a cue from Lorenzo and
go out there and
do projects that interest you.
Try to pick a hobby of yours or
some other field that interests you and
see how you can apply machine learning.
Projects like these are really
useful when it comes to interviews
because you can use them very well
to connect with the interviewer, and
to demonstrate how passionate
you are about machine learning.