We already looked at this before but
basically, now I want you to recall the whole pipeline of how rays of
light are converted into novel forms of images.
Basically have a 3D scene, which is emitting lights.
Of course, now we can put our own light sources in that scene.
We can control it with generalized optics and aperture.
So this now scene is lit by lights that we control.
And of course these are rays of light coming in and hitting the scene now.
We refer to this as basically a newer form of illumination.
Course these rays of light are then being captured by a Novel camera.
This Novel camera already has, also has optics, aperture, and
of course a sensor.
And out comes various forms of information to generate a novel image,
a standard one of course is pixels, but
it could be any different types of things like a light field or
other types of information to regenerate new images for somebody to see.
So this is the pipeline.
Now, in this example we're going to look at how we
can basically do both this novel camera and novel illumination.
And both of these things would be much different in how they are thought of than
traditional photography pipeline would be.