Let's look at this simple spinlock
implementation we showed earlier in this
lesson that uses
the test-and-set instruction.
In this one and in all of the other
examples that we will show, we will
assume that the lock initialization
step sets the lock to be free, and
that 0 indicates free and 1 indicates
busy, that the lock is locked.
The nice thing about this lock is that
the test-and-set instruction is a very
common atomic construction that
most hardware platforms support it.
So, as code, it will be very portable.
We will be able to have the exact
same code run on different hardware
platforms.
From a latency perspective,
this spinlock implementation
performs as good as it gets.
We only execute the atomic operation and
there's no way we can do
any better than this.
Note the lock was originally free.
Say it was 0.
And then as soon as we execute
this spinlock_lock operation,
we make an attempt to
execute test_and_set.
The lock is free, so this will return 0.
As a result of that,
we will come out of this while loop.
And also the test_and_set will
change the value of lock to 1, so
the lock is busy.
So at that point, we have clearly
come out of the while loop.
We're not spinning,
and we have the lock,
and we have marked
that the lock is busy.
Regarding delay,
this particular implementation
potentially could perform well
because we see that we're continuously
just spinning on the atomic instruction.
As long as the lock is busy,
test_and_set will return a 1,
will return busy, so
we will remain in this while loop.
However, whenever the lock does become
freed, this test_and_set will, or
at least one of them,
will immediately detect that and
will come out of the while loop.
That single successful test_and_set
operation also will again set the value
of lock to 1, so any other test_and_set
attempts will result in spinning again.
Now, we already said there is a conflict
between latency and delay and
contention, so
clearly this lock will not perform
well from a contention perspective.
As long as they're spinning,
every single processor will repeatedly
go on the shared interconnect,
on the shared bus to the memory
location where the log is stored,
given that it's repeatedly trying
to execute the atomic instruction.
This will create contention,
delay the processing that's
carried out on other CPUs.
It will delay the processing that
the lock owner needs to perform,
who's trying to execute
the critical selection.
And so, therefore,
it will also delay the time when
the lock actually becomes freed.
So it's just bad all over.
The real problem with this
implementation is that it continuously
spins on the atomic construction.
If we don't have cache coherence,
we will really have to go to memory in
order to check what is
the value of the lock.
But with this implementation,
even if we do have coherent caches,
they will be bypassed because
we're using an atomic instruction.
So in every single spin,
we will go to memory regardless
of the cache coherence.
That clearly is not the most
efficient use of atomics or
of hardware that does have support for
caches and cache coherence.