To better understand and apply these
methods, we'll examine a business
problem surrounding how management at
Bates Hotel, a mountain resort walking
distance from the best slopes in town,
are able to prepare for
their year by forecasting the number of
room bookings they expect each month.
This information can help management
make informed decisions on staffing,
hospitality arrangements,
and pricing for rooms.
They have tasked their business
analysts, you, to forecast bookings so
they can make the necessary
preparations.
Historical bookings data contains
monthly data from the past ten years,
and the forecast should contain monthly
bookings for the next six months.
Your job will to be use to the
historical bookings data from years past
to one, investigate and clean the data.
Two, determine trend and
seasonal components, three,
apply findings to an ARIMA and
ETS model in Alteryx,
lastly, forecast bookings for
the next 6 months.
That's quite a lot to think about.
But don't worry, we'll be taking
a closer look at time series
forecasting methods and
what they all mean.
First let's take a quick quiz to
review what makes a set of data
a time series data set.