Here, we can assume that we can
only observe network traffic, and
cannot examine the botcode,
or the malware yet.
So the first game,
a Gmail account is used for C&C,
email address is hardcoded in botcode.
This is not hard to detect.
In particular, with system and
send Gmail, or even your local network,
they may be able to notice that an email
account is receiving short emails for
C&C from all over the internet.
And it is easy for
them to disable the Gmail account.
The second scheme,
a P2P protocol is used for C & C, and
the query string is
hardcoded in botcode.
This is not hard to detect.
In particular,
in enterprise network where P2P
traffic is typically not allowed.
That is a C&C based on P2P protocol,
can easily stand out in
enterprise network traffic.
In addition, if the hardcoded
query string is identified,
then it is easy to disrupt
the P2P communication, as well.
The third scheme,
a news website has been set up for C&C.
For example, commands can be
parsed from news articles.
The website and the parsing logic
have to be hardcoded in the botcode.
This can be quite hard to detect,
because reading news would
appear to be a normal traffic.
On the other hand,
if this is ever detected,
then disrupting it will not be hard,
because the website can be blocked.
Therefore, in conclusion,
none of these schemes can satisfy
all of these requirements.