I've created a sample project
in angular using Yeoman.
The link for
this project is in the instructor notes.
To complete this quiz, you have to
take this hard coded template and
change it so
that it gets its data from a controller.
So you'll need to create
a brick controller and
add it to the module, add the controller
to the template with the name brick,
add properties to the controller
with the data from this template,
replace these hard coded
values in the template
with expressions that get their
value from the controller.
In the end, nothing will look different
in the browser, but that's okay.
The app will now get its starting
data from the controller.
When you finish setting
everything up correctly,
the feedback extension
will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.