I chose to do a general programming
question because we definitely want to
see that she's able to code, for one.
It's very important that she has
this general coding skills and
that is why we test little bit
of basic SQL understanding and
also basic byte on scripting.
And both programming questions
just aim to do exactly that.
The first SQL question is
a very basic question which
just test general knowledge the SQL and
there's not there's not very much to it.
Just want you see to be
able to get to a solution.
The second question which involved
a finding the maximum difference in a in
a list of integers.
It has two purposes write one to
test general by conscripting and
the other one is to help to see how
you think again like like everything.
I think I Shirley did a great job
in both of them the first one she just
knew of the bad leg that we expected.
In the second one, she did something
that is very important as a candidate.
There many ways to solve
a problem usually when you get
a programming question.
You really just want to go ahead and
get to a solution first.
They, she knew
that the solution she had come up with
wasn't the most optimal solution and.
She recognizes of the better equipped
recognize this off the bat but it went.
Went ahead and wrote it, which is
exactly what you're supposed to do, you
can say this is the first thing I came
up with and then you go ahead and do it.
And that is completely acceptable,
I definitely don't expect her to come
up with the most optimal solution
in 10 seconds and
that along with me staring at her.
So I think she did a very good
job in answering that question.