So, all these different Bellman
Equations, since they all come from that
same infinite sequence, they can all be
related to each other, like by blood.
>> Whose blood?
>> Well, [LAUGH] I'm hoping not yours.
So, and this is why.
So what I want you to
do is actually fill in,
how do you express the V function In
terms of here, say the Q function.
How do you express the V function
in terms of the C function?
In each row here,
it's how you express that function
in terms of the other three.
The Q in terms of the three,
and the C in terms of three.
And I'll do some to get you started,
ta-da!
>> Oh, that's really cool.
So why can't I just do
that in every single box?
>> No, because you have to
express the Q function in terms
of the V function for this box.
>> Okay, that's fair.
>> Should I write the equations
up there again or
do you know them well enough by now?
>> I think I'm okay without
the equations being up there.
I can always just go back
to to the previous video.
>> Good point.
>> Anyway,
I've been taking notes all along
as have all of our students
who are watching this now.
>> I don't doubt that for a minute.
>> Good.
>> I doubt it forever.
>> [LAUGH] All right, okay.
So I think I understand.
I'm going to now I have to write
V in terms of Q using magic.
And V in terms of C and Q in terms of V,
assuming that's possible.
And Q in terms of C,
and so on and so forth.
All right.
So, let's go.