There's some variety in the way
that terminal programs look,
but the actual contents of
the terminal don't change much.
It typically shows
informational messages,
output from previously run commands,
and a prompt for entering new commands.
Command prompts can be configured
differently on different systems, but
it's common for prompts to include
the login user's name, the host name, or
name of the computer you're logged into,
and maybe some other information too,
like the current time or
what folder the user is in.
You can enter new commands
after the prompt, and
after hitting enter your command runs
and the output is printed to the screen.
After the output is printed,
a fresh prompt is added at the bottom of
the terminal, ready for
your next command.
In this quiz, see if you can identify
the parts of the terminal interface.
Label the interface
elements of this terminal.
The items to label are a shell command,
that command's output,
a current prompt, a previously used
prompt, the cursor, and a login message.
Enter the number that corresponds
to each label in the text box.