So let me show you an example.
This example comes from Andrew Moore and
it's a really nice example.
Suppose my vector x is just
two-dimensional to start with, and
I, I need to be able to say
exactly how many there are, so
I can show you the whole
thing written out.
Okay?
Let me define my kernel
function as this.
Okay?
So my kernel function is just
xi transpose xj, 1 plus that squared.
Okay?
This is referred to as a polynomial
kernel, because I take 1 plus the dot
product of xi and xj and I raise it to
a power squared, so this is a quadratic.
Let's write out what that actually is,
okay?
So, we need to show that this function,
in order for it to be a kernel that we
can use for the SVNs, it has to be a dot
product in some high dimensional space.
I don't actually care
what that space is, but
it must be a dot product in some space.
So, just for this, th, demonstration
we'll actually show what that space is,
but in general we, we don't, we tend
not to worry about that, all right.
So, here I just wrote out K, so
it's one plus xi transpose xj squared.
Multiply this whole thing out, okay, so
just using the fact that x is only
two-dimensional and it's x1 x2.
You get this, you know,
big, ugly expression.
And that's only squared.
Imagine if it's raised to
a higher power or imagine if x,
instead of being just x1 x2 was,
you know, x1 through x5, right?
You get all of these terms, all right?
Here, we only have, one, two, three,
four, five, six, six terms, okay,
because it's squared.
But that expression can be
written as the following, okay?
And you have to, sort of work
this out for yourself, right.
So let's just take a look at this term,
okay, well, 1 times 1 is what?
One, very good.
So here I have x i squared, x j squared.
Well, if I put xi squared and
xj squared here.
xi squared times xi1 squared times xj1
squared is xi1 squared xj1 squared.
This sounds like a Dr. Seuss thing okay.
What's going on here is now let's
take a look at this term here.
Right?
These two, times each other,
is that, and so on.
Basically, this big expression is just
this term,
which is made out of the xi components,
dotted with, transpose, the same
term made out of the xj components.
Okay?
So the way of thinking about that is
that's a dot product
between the phi of xi and
phi of xj,
where phi of x is just defined by this.
So here the idea is, we went from being
a two dimensional space to being a one,
two, three, four, five,
six dimensional space.
Now, we don't actually
need to know that space.
We're just going to use the Kernel
function in our SVM and
the way we're going to do that, is we're
going to use that, that kernel trick.
As, so instead of computing explicitly,
that high dimensional space,
right, we just define
some kernel function,
which we know is a dot product
in a high dimensional space, but
we don't actually even look at it,
we just know that it is.
In which case, we convert our xi.x for
testing our new vector x
to just the kernel of that.
All right?
And so we don't actually have to do
the thing in the high dimensional space,
we just compute the kernel in
the lower dimensional space.