P and not-P is valid.
That is, it's true when P is true,
because of this, and
it's true when P is false,
because of this clause.
P and not-P is unsatisfiable.
A symbol can't be both true and
false at the same time.
P or Q or P is equivalent to Q is valid.
So we know that it's
true when either P or
Q is true so
that's three out of the four cases.
In the fourth case,
both P and Q were false and
that means P is equivalent to Q and
therefore in all four cases it's true.
P implies Q or
Q implies P that's also valid.
Now, in ordinary English,
that wouldn't be valid.
If the two classes or the two symbols,
P and Q, were irrelevant to each other,
we wouldn't say that either
one of those is true.
But in logic, one or
the other must be true, according to
the definitions of the truth tables.
And finally, this one's more
complicated, if Food, then Party.
Or if drinks then Party implies,
if Food and Drinks, then Party.
You can work it all out, and
both sides of the main implication
work out to be equivalent to not Food or
not Drinks or Party.
So that's the same as
saying P implies P.
Saying one side is
equivalent to other side.
And if they're equivalent,
then the implication relation holds.
[BLANK_AUDIO]