All right, now stationary policy,
which sometimes in the literature is
referred to as the universal plan,
is actually
what we talked about in the context of
MDPs, so mapping from states to actions.
And this is a very
powerful sort of thing
because it can handle
stochasticity really well.
Every time you take a transition, you go
back to your table, you go back to your
policy to say, all right,
here's the state that I ended up in.
What's the right thing to do from here?
It is kind of hard to convey
these to people, though.
Do you see why that might be?
>> Yeah, so
one way it might be is because,
I will claim that a stationary policy or
universal plan is just
a conditional plan where you have
an if at every single possible state.
>> That's true but it's actually
a little bit more constrained than that.
Which is it's the same if
at every possible state.
>> Right.
>> So no matter where you came from,
no matter what you were in the middle of
doing, once you discover where you are,
that's going to determine what
your next step's going to be.
>> Right, and
that's a lot of if statements.
>> It's a lot of if statements, yeah.
And right, so if you try to convey it,
you have to actually tell someone
what all those if statements are.
It's sort of like if I want to
give you directions to my house.
A plan might say go left,
go right, go left.
Go down until you get to Maple Street,
make a right.
A conditional plan might say
something like, go to the highway.
If you get there and it's crowded,
then go these back roads, otherwise,
go on the highway.
[LAUGH] And a policy would say
something like, for every location
in my neighborhood, here's
the direction that you should turn.
And yeah, and
that's going to be very large.
>> Right.
And in some ways not very useful.
>> Well, [LAUGH] define useful, right?
So it's very useful in the sense
that it is very powerful and
it can handle any kind of stochasticity.
And there's always an optimal
stationary policy for any MDP.
>> Okay.
>> So that's a really nice property.
You never have to look beyond the
stationary policies to find something
that's optimal.
>> Okay, so
then I take back what I said.
It's not that it's not useful,
it's that, in fact it's very useful.
It's that it's not very compact, or
as you have up there, it's very large.
>> Very large.
>> So you have to say a lot.
>> Yeah, so that's exactly right.
All right, but now for
the learning algorithm, it could
mean that it has to learn a lot.
It has to discover what a reasonable
thing to do is in every one of its
possible states.
So that could actually make
the learning problem difficult.
But anyway, I just wanted to
at least raise this issue.
We're going to be focused, almost
entirely, on these stationary policies.
Because they do allow for
the possibility of expressing
that optimal behavior.
>> Cool.