In case A, the gradient is negative.
If you move to the right in the X space,
then your loss decreases.
In B, it's about zero.
In C, it's pointing up; it's positive.
So if you apply the rule over here,
if you were to start at A as your W-zero,
then your gradient is negative.
Therefore, you would add something to the value of W.
You move to the right, and your loss has decreased.
You do this until you find yourself
with what's called a local minimum, where B resides.
In this instance over here, gradient descent starting at A
would not get you to the global minimum,
which sits over here because there's a bump in between.
Gradient methods are known to be subject to local minimum.