Having obtained a strong
foundation in classical AI,
in term two you'll enter
the cutting edge of AI.
In particular you'll get a chance
to build amazing agents using deep
learning, with leaders
from the industry.
For instance, you can work with the team
behind Amazon Alexa to build a recurrent
neural network based
speech-to-text system
that converts your human
speech into real text.
Or, you can work with
the team behind IBM Watson to
build a deep learning based system,
to extract meaning from example
sentences that we will provide you.
Or finally, you can work with
the MIT PHD team behind Affectiva
to build convolutional neural network-based computerization systems,
that automatically classify and
detect objects.