All right, that concludes the,
the boosting discussion and
also the context of face detection.
Like I said, it's rare that a single
paper can influence a field so much,
like this one did.
But but it did.
And not only influenced the field,
it influenced the people sort of
learning and thinking about the field.
The representation,
the classification method and
then the whole cascade, it just worked.
It just worked really, really well.
And, as I said, unlike SVM methods,
which we'll learn about lex, next time,
you can actually just
write the code yourself,
both boosting and random forest.
By the way, random forests are sort
of related because it's this idea of
adding these weak eh,
this consensus of weak learners.
So, for those of you who want to
think about random forests,
because you know about them, you can
think about them in that context.
These boosting algorithms,
these consensus algorithms, are just
much simpler to implement yourself.
And therefore they sort of
become fun to play with.
Next time we'll talk about support,
support vector machines,
which are not fun to implement,
but just work really, really well.