A lot goes into implementing
authentication systems.
As you're creating your own
restaurant menu application
it's important to consider
the following aspects of web security.
Requiring strong passwords from users
prevents a hacker from simply guessing
a password and
gaining access to private information.
We use strong encryption by
implementing a mathematical algorithm
to make information virtually
impossible to decrypt by someone
who doesn't have the right key.
Ensuring secure communication between
client and server to make sure your
private information does not become
public at any point along communication.
Securing password storage
in an encrypted database,
such that no one can gain access
to your users' passwords.
Implementing password recovery, so
that if a user forgets their password
there's a way to create a new
one quickly and securely.
Adding two-factor authentication,
a highly recommended extra layer of
security that requires a password and
a special key to access private data.
And including protection against
man-in-the-middle attacks to make sure
there is no malicious system interfering
with the data being transmitted or
pretending to be a trusted website.
From the problems listed here, what do
you think are the three most important?