Business has been really good, so
the bricks a bunch stores expanding.
The existing Lots O Brick store
currently only sells blue and
green bricks.
Management wants the Bricks A Bunch
store to still sell only red bricks.
While the Lots O Bricks store
should sell its blue and
green bricks, and red bricks.
These two stores need to share
the same number of red bricks.
For this quiz, you need to create
a brick warehouse service.
Both stores should have
access to this service.
Brick information should be extracted
from each store, combined, and
put into the service.
Here's the specific information
that you need to follow.
The link to the starter code for
this project is in the instructor notes.
When you finished, the feedback
extension will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.
Ember uses the queue unit
testing framework, and
I created a number of tests
that you need to satisfy.
These tests help guide you through
completing the assignment.
Once all the tests have passed, the
feedback extension will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.
You can find the link to this project's
test page in the project's read me file.