The course instructs you to divide
learning between building our
weather app and a series of simple or
toy apps designed to illustrate
key android concepts.
The first of the applications
is literally a Toy App.
The app displays a scrolling list
of generic toys with what we hope
are non-copyrighted names.
A sort of toy wish list.
We start by using the new project
wizard in Android studio.
The wizard will create
all of the files for
us to get a simple,
functional Android application.
Lets call it favorite toys.
Next, we provide
a corresponding domain name,
which generally should be the name
of the internet domain you own.
As you can see in the wizard,
Android uses the Java standard of using
the elements of the domain in reverse
order to construct
the application package name.
For distribution purposes on Google Play
and elsewhere, this package name must be
globally unique across all
packages installed on Android.
Since we're not planning to publish
FavoriteToys, and it will be helpful if
it matches the GitHub repository, please
use android.example.com as your domain.
Finally, choose a location for
your Project.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Next, we'll select the form factors that
Favorite Toys will run on, phone and
tablet.
One of the great things about learning
Android development is that this
knowledge applies to apps written for
phones and tablets, TVs, watches,
and almost certainly other form factors
we or others haven't created yet.
In this class, we're going to be
focusing on building applications
optimized around phones to keep things
as straight forward as possible.
Then we select empty activity.
There are lots of choices here, though.
Android studio contains templates for
many different kind of activities.
Including common types, such as a basic
activity with a floating action button.
A navigation drawer activity,
or even a Google Maps activity.
We then can customize
our new empty activity.
Since we want backwards
compatibility and
that initial layout file,
we'll leave both of the options checked.
Click Finish and we'll have the shell
of an Android app to start working in.
[BLANK_AUDIO]