Just to keep us going, here is a simple quiz.
Here is that, you know, two images.
And I just want you to simply play around and do the computation to be able to
generate another image that actually has these types of processes.
So of course what that would mean is, first I would, to get the value here,
multiply the number 36 by 2 then subtract 36.
In this case of course, the answer would be 36.
So imagine doing this across the board for all of them.
24 times 2, that would be 48 minus 78.
That starts kind of getting interesting again.
So, one of the things I want you to do when you do this kind of stuff
is also do the truncation, so you keep the values from 0 to 255.