Now I want to do a little quiz,
and ask you: True or False,
which of the following are possible
weaknesses in this TD learning
with a passive approach to reinforcement learning?
One: Is it possible that we would have
a long convergence time--
that it might take a long time to converge to the correct utility values?
Secondly, are we limited by the policy that we choose?
So remember: in passive reinforcement learning,
we choose a fixed policy
and execute that policy;
and any deviance from the policy
results from the stochasticity.
We may visit different squares
because the environment is stochastic,
but not because we made different choices.
So there's that elementation.
Third, can there be a problem with missing states?
That is, could there be some states that have
a zero count--that we never visited,
and never got a utility estimate?
And fourth, could there be a problem with a poor estimate for certain states?
So could it be that, even though a state didn't have a count of zero,
it had a low count, and we weren't able to get a good utility estimate for that state?