All right, Sam. We've got a pretty cool app going.
>> Yup.
>> We can automate stuff on the day of the
festival. Problems are going to come up and they're going to get addressed
[SOUND]
like that.
>> Yeah.
>> Because you've got all these slick workflows and approvals going.
>> Nice.
>> I'm pumped.
>> I'm pumped too. But the things we've been working on
so far have mainly been focused on, like, what are you going to
be doing? Or what's that guy going to be doing? But there's nothing,
you know, connecting everyone and getting
them to collaborate, do stuff together.
>> Mm hm.
>> like, like a team want.
>> Okay.
>> So, I mean, think about just first of
all, if there were multiple people working at the stage
>> The udacity stage.
>> Yeah.
>> That totally could be.
>> How would they be able to communicate between each other around things
that need to happen or things that
have been happening or scheduling or whatever?
>> Email.
>> Email. Sucks, right? I gate getting a million emails.
>> It sucks yeah.
>> So what if you could add something like a Facebook
feed to the top of this record so that people could collaborate
right from this record and it would all be limited to this
screen. So then I don't have to check emails, save stuff, whatever.
>> What if?
>> Well.
>> Let's do it.
[LAUGH]
>> Yeah
[LAUGH],
no ifs.
>> Okay.
>> Right. Yeah.
>> Okay, so, I assume we can do that.
>> We can and that's using Chatter.
>> Okay.
>> So, what we can do is go into the
Set Up and add or enable this object for Chatter.
>> So, I should not just click on Chatter over here.
>> No, because that's going to take you to your Chatter profile.
>> All right. So, I'm going to edit this object. What are we doing?
>> So you could edit the object,
which would remember that little third checkbox that
we hadn't checked yet?
>> Yeah.
>> That would enable us to be able to use chatter on this.
>> Okay.
>> But since we're going to want to do a little bit more than
just enable it, let's just go into the setup and configure chatter completely.
>> Okay. Cool.