To use a semaphore in this manner,
you should initialize the semaphore so
that it is a non-process
shared semaphore.
So, this argument to
the initialization call should be 0.
And so that its initial count is 1.
So this argument will be 1.
Then, when the semaphore
wait operation is called.
It will decrement this counter and it
will allow exactly one thread at a time
to enter the critical section and
posting to a semaphore will increment
the counter and it will be
identical to a mutex being freed.
Note that most operating systems
textbooks will include some examples on
how to implement one synchronization
construct with another
including mutexes or
condition variables with semaphores.
And there are many other examples.
So you're welcome to experiment on
your own with these kinds of examples.