Hi, Michael.
>> Hey, Charles, how's it going?
>> It's going fantastically well.
How are things going with you?
>> I've been told I can't complain.
>> You could always complain Michael.
>> [LAUGH] I'd rather not.
>> Okay, well fair enough.
Okay, well guess what we're
going to talk about today?
>> I'm reading Decision-Making and
Reinforcement Learning.
>> That's correct.
>> Is that the name of our class?
>> Sure.
>> [LAUGH] I feel like
the class has an actual name.
>> Yeah, decision making and
reinforcement learning,
how do you feel about that?
>> Awesome, I like it a lot except there
is kind of an extra hyphen in there.
>> Where?
>> Between decision and
making you only put that in if
it's modifying another noun.
>> Wait,
haven't we had this conversation before?
>> It does seem vaguely familiar.
>> Hm.
>> Oh, you know what it was?
When we did our introduction in
the machine learning class for
decision making and
reinforcement learning as a sub-piece,
we had a very similar conversation.
>> Oh, so why are we doing it again?
>> Well, I mean do we need
to cover the same material?
>> Yeah, absolutely important
that we cover some of the same
material in the beginning.
>> So maybe we shouldn't do it again,
maybe we should kind of cut and
paste from the other class.
>> Oh, I like that,
we can fix it in post.
That's fantastic, let's do that.
So why don't we just
pretend that somebody's
put all the right video stuff in
the right place and go do that.
How's that sound to you?
>> That sounds like it saves
everybody a lot of time, except for
the people actually watching the videos.
>> That works for me.
Okay, so let's do a flashback.
You want to do the flashback sounds?
>> Sure, I know how to do that.
Okay, let's go.
[NOISE]