In our discussion about
memory management so far,
we saw that our operating
systems rely on the hardware,
on the memory management unit hardware,
to perform address translations and
to also validate the accesses to enforce
protection in similar mechanisms.
But the same hardware can also
be used to build a number of
other useful services and optimizations,
beyond just the address translation.
One such mechanism is called
Copy-on-Write, or COW.
Let's consider what happens
during process creation.
When we need to create a new process
we need to recreate the entire
parent process by copying
its entire address space.
However, many of the pages are static,
they don't change.
So it's not clear why we
should keep multiple copies.
In order to avoid unnecessary copying,
on creation the virtual
address space of the new process or
portions of it at least, will point,
will be mapped to the original page that
had the original address space content.
The same physical address of the
physical memory may be referred to by
two completely different virtual
addresses from the two processes.
We also have to make sure to write
protect the physical memory so
that we can track
concurrent accesses to it.
If the contents of this page
are indeed going to be read only,
then we're going to save both on memory
requirements, as well as on the time
that would have otherwise been
necessary to perform the copy.
However, if a write
request is issued for
this memory area via either one of these
virtual addresses, then the MMU will
detect that the page is write protected
and will generate a page fault.
At that point the operating system
will see what is the reason for
this page fault.
We'll create the actual copy.
So the copy will only be performed then.
We'll update the page tables of
the two processes as necessary.
So basically the page table
of the faulting process.
And will in this manner, copy only
those pages that need to be updated.
Only those pages for
which the copy cost is necessary.
We call this mechanism
Copy-on-Write because
the copy cost will only be paid when
we need to perform a write operation.
There may be other references to this
write protected feature so whether or
not the write protection will be
removed once this one copy is performed
will depend on who else is
this page is shared with.