While we´re on this topic, I'd like
to talk about local beam search.
Because we'll use it
later in the course.
>> Okay, it's your show after all.
>> The local beam search,
instead of just using one position,
which I'll call particle,
just because that's how I think of it.
We'll keep track of K-particles.
At each time frame,
we'll look at the randomly generated
neighbors of each of these particles.
And keep the k-best ones for
the next iteration.
If ever any of these particles have
reached your goal, we terminate.
Now you'd think that this outer
limit's just like random restart.
>> But it's not, because we are
comparing all the neighbors of all of
the particles to each other.
There is information being
passed to each position, right?
Normal random restart doesn't share any
of this information between iterations.
>> That's correct.
>> Okay, that seems fine.
But I've heard you talk about stochastic
beam search before as being more useful.
How is that different?
>> Stochastic beam search
is the same thing.
But the successors are chosen not just
based on their fitness, but with some
randomness, which helps ensure that we
don't get stuck in a local maximum.
This idea has some similarity
to simulated kneeling.
As in the class of algorithms to
which genetic algorithms belongs,
which we'll tackle next.