This is a famous problem called the monkey and bananas problem,
described in the language of classical planning.
There are six actions. The monkey can go from location x to y.
It can push some object from x to y. It can climb up an object. It can grab something.
It can climb down from an object, and it can un-grab something.
Initially, the monkey is at location A. The bananas are at location B.
The box is at C, and the monkey is at a low height, as is the box,
but the bananas are at a high height,
but the box is pushable and climbable.
Now, assuming that we execute this plan--go from A to C, push the box from C to B,
climb up on the box, grasp the bananas, and climb down from the box.
What I want you to do is look at these definitions of actions,
tell me how the state unfolds from this initial state here to the final state,
and then click off all of these instances that are going to be true in the final state.