We talked briefly about CPU
scheduling in the introductory lesson
on processes and process management.
We said then,
the CPU scheduler decides how and
when processes access
the shared CPUs in the system.
In this lesson, we'll use the term task
to interchangeably mean either processes
or threads, since the same kinds of
mechanisms are valid in all context.
The scheduler concerns the scheduling
of both user-level processes or
threads, as well as
the kernel-level threads.
Recall this figure that we used when we
talked originally about processes and
process scheduling.
The responsibility of the CPU scheduler
is to choose one of the tasks in
the ready queue, a process or a thread.
We said we'll just use the term
task to refer to both, and
then to schedule that
particular task onto the CPU.
Threads may become ready so
they may enter the ready queue
after an I/O operation they have
been waiting on has completed or
after they have been woken up from
a wait on an interrupt, for instance.
A thread will enter the ready
queue when it's created, so
when somebody has forked a new thread.
And also a thread that, maybe, was
interrupted while executing on the CPU
because the CPU has to be
shared with other threads.
That thread, it was ready,
it was executing on the CPU.
So, after it has been interrupted,
it continues to be ready so
it will immediately go
into the ready queue.
So to schedule something,
the scheduler will have to look at all
of the tasks in the ready queue and
decide which is the one that it
will dispatch to run on the CPU.
Whenever the CPU becomes idle,
we have to run the scheduler.
For instance, if a thread that was
executing on the CPU makes an I/O
request and now it has to wait in the
I/O queue for that particular device,
the CPU's idle, what happens at that
moment, we run the OS scheduler.
The goal is to pick another task to run
on the CPU as soon as possible, and
not to keep the CPU idle for too long.
Whenever a new task becomes ready,
so a task that was waiting on an I/O
operation, or was waiting on
an interrupt, or some kind of signal.
Or whenever a brand new task
was created for the first time.
For all of these reasons, again,
we need to run the scheduler.
The goal is to check whether any of
these tasks are of higher importance and
therefore should interrupt the task
that's currently executing on the CPU.
A common way how schedulers
share the CPU is to give
each of the tasks in the system
some amount of time on the CPU.
So, when a time slice expires, when
a running thread has used up its time on
the CPU, then, that's another time
when we need to run the scheduler so
as to pick the next task
to be scheduled on the CPU.
Once the scheduler selects
a thread to be scheduled,
the thread is then
dispatched onto the CPU.
What really happens is we
perform a context switch
to enter the context of
the newly selected thread.
And then we have to enter user mode,
then set the program counter
appropriately to point to the next
instruction that needs to be executed
from the newly selected thread.
And then we're ready to go.
The new thread starts
executing on the CPU.
So in summary,
the objective of the OS scheduler is to
choose the next task to run from
the queue of ready tasks in the system.
The first question that comes to mind
is, which task should be selected?
How do we know this?
The answer to that will depend
on the scheduling policy or
the scheduling algorithm that
is executed by the OS scheduler.
We will discuss several
such algorithms next.
Another immediate question is,
how does the scheduler accomplish this?
How does it perform whatever
algorithm it needs to execute?
The details of the implementation of
the scheduler will very much depend on
the runqueue on the data structure that
we use to implement this ready queue.
That's called the runqueue.
The design of the runqueue and
the scheduling algorithm
are tightly coupled.
We will see that certain
scheduling algorithms,
they demand a different type of
runqueue, different data structure.
And also that, the design of
the runqueue, it may limit in certain
ways what kinds of scheduling
algorithms we can support efficiently.
So, the rest of the lecture will focus
on reviewing different scheduling
algorithms and runqueue data structures.