Welcome back to intro to computer vision.
Today we're going to start a section that's really on mapping from multiple,
across multiple images.
Image to images.
And so I'll refer to it as n views.
Mostly we're going to think of about two views, but
a lot of this stuff extends to having multiple views.
Today what we're going to do is talk about image to image projections.
because last time we talked about calibration.
And calibration was all about going from the world to the image, and
we made a stop.
We go from the world 3D coordinate frame, to a camera coord,
3D coordinate frame, and
then we do a projection from a 3D camera coordinate frame to a 2D image frame.
And we built that m matrix, and
we talked about if I gave you 3D points in the world and I gave you 2D
points in the image, how you could figure out that that relationship is.
For the next several lessons,
we'll be talking about mapping from one image to the other.
And this is going to be important both for stereo and for
other applications where you have multiple views of, of the same scene.