So remember what happened when we're
talking about smashing the stack for
fun and profit, you overflow the buffer
and go down where the return address is
stored and then you change that if you
going to alter the program execution.
So actually had to do two things,
you had to change the return address and
then you had to send the return
should happen to your shellcode
where the exploit code is.
So you overwrite that, the return
address, so this is going to be true.
It's correct.
The second says pushing data onto
the stack to overflow the stack
into the heap.
The heap and
stack are sort of separated,
the buffer overflow, although the heap
overflows and stack overflows,
but going from stack to heap is not what
we discussed, so that's not correct.
And popping data off the stack
doesn't do anything for you either,
because you need to actually alter the
return address and go to exploit code.
Neither of these two, second and third
options are going to let you do that.
So, the way to think about this
is overflowing the buffer to
change the return address.
So essentially what you're doing
now write into a location.
So keep that in mind.
Where is this location?
On the stack.