But suppose you don't know the radius.
Okay?
Megan sent the postcard to the wrong place.
You moved, because you wanted to upscale your apartment and
now you know you shouldn't have, because you're left without a radius.
So what do we do?
Well, let's think about it this way.
All right?
Now our Hough space has three dimensions, a, b and r,
because we don't know what the radius.
All right?
So now if I have single point, what happens?
Well, now if we knew the radius, let's say, the radius was, I don't know, seven
over here, then it would be some sort of a circle centered about this point.
Right? Just like that we did before.
And if the radius was let's say, three,
it would be another circle centered about the same point, but smaller.
So I hope you can start to see that what we're getting in here is
actually a cone, okay?
So with unknown radius, each point votes for an entire cone in this 3D space.
So the surface of the cone, right?
Not a filled in cone, but the cone that's a surface.
And the next point, what does it do?
It votes for another cone and you can sum these all up.
Now I will tell you this is pretty painful.
And in fact, if any of you end up doing a problem set for some random course
like this one, we're going to to tell you in terms of looking for circles.
If you try to vote in a great big 3D space, it's not going to work so well.
And in a whole bunch of lectures later when we teach you about ransack,
it'll sort of overcome this dimensionality.
But for now, just know that we have this little problem of growing the size of
the voting space.
So it can be done, it's, it's just a little bit painful.
But remember before, one of the ways we got rid of the number of
votes you had to do was by using the gradient direction?
Okay?
So because if like, I had a point and
I knew the gradient, there was only one possible line it could be.
Well, we can do the same thing with circles.
All right? So now we have an unknown radius, but we have a gradient.
All right?
So again, our Hough space is a, b and r.
But this time, our one point here, it has this gradient.
Okay?
Well, now if we knew the radius,
we would just have one possible circle it could be.
Right?
So if you tell me that this is a point and that this is the gradient that I
know the radius, that's the only place the center can be.
But if the radius was half that, then the center would be there.
Or the center, I guess it also could be on the other side.
So it's just this single line of voting that can happen when you
have the gradient and that's drawn like that.
So in the Hough space, even though it's a three dimensional Hough space,
you would only vote along one line.
Okay?
And so that's a little bit better, at least it makes the voting easier.
You still have this problem when you have this three dimensional Hough space.