When a user first taps inside the emoji
text field any existing text clears.
If you are able to discover that
the text field did begin editing method
is called as soon as the user taps
inside a text field you probably guessed
that this method is being implemented
in the emoji text field delegate.
Both the emoji text field and
the colorizer text field
are manipulating user generated text.
So we can guess that their
delegates both implement,
should change characters in range.
We also know that in the colorizer the
keyboard dismisses upon pressing return.
So we can guess that the colorizer
delegate implements text field
should return.
The text field id end editing
element is a good place to save
text once editing is finished.
Notice that neither the emoji nor
the colorizer text field does anything
with the text after editing is finished.
Let's take a look at the emoji delegate.
If we look inside the text field
did begin editing method down here
at the end of the file, we can see
in this line of code that as soon
as the user clicks into the text
field the text is cleared.
So what about the rest of
emoji delegates functionality,
lets scroll up to the top of the file.
Up here we can see a dictionary
that maps animal words
to emoji symbols to
replace those words with.
By the way, don't worry if you've
never seen a dictionary before.
We're going to discuss swift
dictionaries in the next lesson.
Most of the action is happening in
this should change characters in
range method.
Whenever the text changes,
the delegate is told.
Then it proceeds through these steps.
It constructs a new string.
It looks for each emoji string, and
then replaces emoji strings
with emoji characters.
If we replace a string with
an emoji we return false here.
And if not, we return true.
And let the text field modify the text.
Now let's see how the colorizer works.
Remember the colorizer closed
to the keyboard on pressing.
Which is probably the user
experience we're after.
So let's take a look
at how this was done.
You'll want to scroll down to where
the text field show return method is.
And here in the text field show return
method you can see this call to text
field resign first responder.
Anytime a keyboard starts editing, we
say that it becomes the first responder.
That's why touches to the keyboard
only show up in the current text view
instead of all of them.
Resigning this first responder
status dismissed the keyboard.
So what else is going
on in this delegate?
If we scroll up to the top we can
see just like the emoji delegate.
This colorizer delegate
also has a dictionary.
This dictionary maps color
strings to UI color objects.
Whenever the text changes,
this loop finds all of the color
words in the new string.
It creates an array of color objects
corresponding to the color strings, and
then passes that array into a.
Helper method, which blends the colors.
You can see this blend color array
helper method down here, and here you
can see the text color of the text field
is being set to the blended color.