Let's implement two more functions now.
The first will compute the dot product
of two vectors and the second will
compute the angle between two vectors,
both in radians and in degrees.
Use your code to answer
the following questions.
Remember that like with
the normalization function earlier,
if one of your vectors
is the zero vector,
there may be a special case
you have to deal with.
For the first question,
please find the dot product
of the vectors 7.887,
4.138, and -8.802, 6.776.
For the second question
please find the dot product
of -5.955, -4.904, -1.874,
and -4.496, -8.755, 7.103.
For the third question,
please find the angle
in radians between the vectors 3.183,
-7.627, and -2.668, 5.319.
And for the last question,
please find the angle
in degrees between the vectors 7.35,
0.221, 5.188, and
2.751, 8.259, 3.985.
As before, please enter your solutions
within an accuracy of at least three
decimal places.