currently our process for
entering data in a system we utilize
software system called Shelter Buddy and
as animals
are brought into the shelter they are
manually input into our shelter system.
As they go through the different
processes within our organization,
their medical assessments,
behavior assessments, those are all
entered into our system as well and
then at that point they're
made available for adoption.
Whenever we have adopters,
the adopters information is
also put into that system and then
linked up with the animal profile for
whichever animal they've determined
was the best fit for them.
So this is Jacob.
He is a twelve-week-old
maltipoo mix puppy.
He's really energetic, really really
playful, loves other dogs and
loves everybody that he meets.
If you could see his tail
right now it would be wagging.
So Jacob is a really great example
of how we do our rescue runs
which means we go out to other shelters
and rescue animals from those city and
county shelters and
bring them to our organization.
He was originally found as a stray in
the city of San Jose off of Story Road.
His owners never came and
claimed him if he had owners.
And so
then he was brought into our system.
It would have been really fantastic if
at the time he was brought in we could
have utilized a mobile app to input
all of his information at the previous
shelter rather than waiting until we got
him back here because then we could have
already started the process of moving
him through the different channels.