Now that everyone has to write shorter
messages I'm going to ask again about
going to the movies.
So far so good.
I'm liking the app better already.
And if I ever decide that I want to
tweak the message length again,
I can easily return to
the Firebase console and
try out different message lengths
until I find one that works.
For now I'll wait a few days again and
then check analytics to see if my
changes will increase my number
of users or my user engagement.
Now this was not a true AB test.
If you'd like learn more about to write
a proper AB test using remote config and
Firebase analytics, I've provided
a link below to get you started.