Great job completing the Twitter word count topology.
Hopefully you were able to access live tweets using your own oath,
oath credentials using the Twitter 4AJPI and run your visualization.
I'll walk you through my solution here.
First after entering my credentials I asked you to
simply run topology using mvn package.
And once you had a build success, you could look at your structure,
here's your TweetTopology and your jar-with-dependencies.
And submit using storm jar target/udacity,again using tab.
And we have udacity .storm.TweetTopology.
Finally I asked you to update the topology.
First in part one we attached the parsed tweet bolt with a parallelism of 10.
I also asked what grouping is needed.
Remember our builder syntax is builder.setBolt.
We want this to be the parse-tweet-bolt.
And that's a new ParseTweetBolt.
And a parallelism of 10.
Finally, the grouping that's needed in the parse tweet bolt is
simply a shuffle grouping.
And we connect that to the tweet spout.
Using the component ID tweet-spout.
And remember to end with a semicolon.
Next, we want to attach the count bolt with a parallelism of 15, and again,
what grouping is needed?
Syntax here is, builder.setBolt.
This is the component ID,
count-bolt, a new CountBolt, and a parallelism of 15.
Next, the grouping nets needed is a field grouping,
because we want to parse each word coming out of the parse-tweet Bolt.
And hash it on the unique word that's coming in order to be counted.
So we have fieldsGrouping.
Connect to the parse-tweet-bolt.
And for our fieldsGrouping,
we need to declare the new field with the name of the field.
The name of the field is something that we need to check.
Let's go to the ParseTweetBolt now.
I'm doing that by searching ParseTweetBolt.
And we can scroll down to the declare output field where I
declare the output field, tweet word.
That's the field we need.
Let's jump back to our topology and enter in the new field, tweet word.
And finally end with a semicolon.
In part three we want to attach the report bolt with a parallelism of one, and
again I ask what grouping is needed.
Here we have builder dot set bolt.
Report bolt is our component I.D. It's a new report bolt.
Parallelism of one.
Again the question is what grouping do we need?
We want all of the streams coming from the count bolt to go one
report bolt in order to connect with our visualization.
Therefore we need a global grouping and
the syntax here is simply to connect to the count bolt.
With the component ID component ending with the semicolon.
Let's check our solution by maven package.
So notice I get a build failure and it turns out that I have a syntax error.
So I'll leave this in just because this is very common.
In maven it's a good check for your syntax and simply put.
I have an extra parentheses, right there, in the ParseTweetBolt.
So, I want to declare the ParseTweetBolt, but have the parallelism of 10,
and that's how I can tell that my topology was incorrect.
So, let's clear this, and repackage.
And I leave this one in too because we see another build failure, and
it's new FieldsGrouping, with s.
let's repackage again, and finally we have a build success.
Now let's submit our program using storm jar target again using our tab, and
this is udacity dot storm tweet topology.
Finally as our program's running, we can bring our visualization.
And we see that as the tweets are coming in through our live tweet spout,
the tweets are parsed, counted and displayed using our visualization.
The longer the topology runs, we see that the words grow in size.
We can hover over a word, and we see that there is 158 instances of.
This http word.
We'll clean this up in further exercises using different filters.
But, for now, it's pretty cool to see that our tweet topology
is counting words correctly in real time.
Great job.
And, hopefully, you're able to take a screenshot or video and
post this to the forum.