So let's create the family
activity in the same way.
If we go to
the AndroidManifest.xml file,
there's a lot of xml that we
haven't talked about yet.
However, you may have
noticed that there's an extra
activity XML element here
with the name FamilyActivity.
And I can create the ColorsActivity and
the PhrasesActivity in the same way.
Since we made code changes,
we should run on the device to make
sure that there are no errors.
So let's try that.
Cool it works!
However, as expected, clicking on
the categories doesn't do anything yet.
Let's answer the quiz question.
When I check the AndroidManifest.xml
file I see new activity XML elements for
ColorsActivity and
the PhrasesActivity too.
Looks like each activity in our app
is listed in the AndroidManifest.xml.
So here's the answer to our question of
how does the AndroidManifest.xml file
change as you add more
activities to the app?
So we noticed that a new activity
XML element is automatically added
to the AndroidManifest.xml file for
each new activity created.