So I just noticed that the maximum
number of minutes spent by
any student during the first week is
actually greater than the number of
minutes in a week.
My process for debugging problems
like this is similar to my process
tracking down the missing
engagement records before.
I'd like you to follow
the same steps here.
First, you'll need to decide which
data points count as surprising.
Then, print some of those out and
see if you can find anything wrong.
Were you able to find a problem?
Describe any problems you found here.
The bug is actually in some of
the starter code that I gave you.
So if you can't figure out exactly
what's causing any problems that you
find, don't feel bad.