Hey, Charles.
>> Hey, Michael.
>> We're going to talk about
exploration.
>> Alright, I like exploration.
>> Yeah, it turns out to be
a really important property,
or topic in reinforcement learning.
I think there are some people who have
said exploration is the topic that
separates reinforcement learning from
other kinds of machine learning.
So it's kind the thing
that's special to us.
>> Yeah, I think I would argue it's
part of a fundamental trade off of
reinforcement learning.
>> Okay, I'll tell you who said it.
It was me.
>> [LAUGH]
Fair enough, Mike.
>> Let's dive in and
see what some of the subtopics are.
So ultimately, we're going to work our
way up to regular old stochastic MDPs
and what it means to do exploration and
learning in those settings.
>> But by way of warm up,
we're going to look at two other classes
that illustrate other aspects of it.
We're going to talk about bandits that
don't have any state transitions at all.
>> Okay.
>> And we're
going to talk about deterministic
MDPs which have state transitions but
don't have any stochasticity at all.
>> Okay.
But the bandits do have stochasticity?
>> Bandits are all about
the stochasticity, yeah.
>> Okay.
And so once we've kind of mastered
those two, it's kind of combining
the union of those that gives us the
general ability to handle general MDPs.
>> Combining the union?
>> Taking the union of the topics and
then integrating them into
an algorithmic whole.
>> Hm, sounds promising.