Before we move on to more advanced
debugging tools, I want to talk about
what you can do when you're facing
a bug that you can't solve.
And there are a couple possibilities.
It could be the case that there's
actually a problem with Apple's code and
this can be especially true when you're
using SDK's that were recently released
or changed.
And if this happens, you'll want
to file a bug report with Apple.
Developers in the community will
commonly refer to this as filing
a Radar.
And Radar is Apple's
bug reporting system.
I've posted a link in the instructor
notes with instructions on how to
use Radar.
Besides Apple's code, there can also
be problems with third-party frameworks
you're using in your application.
If there are problems with a third-party
framework, then you're going to have to
contact the third-party framework that
you're using to resolve any issues.
And this can be difficult depending
on the level of support and
responsiveness of the third party.
That is why it's so important that you
make sure that you use well-trusted and
well-maintained third-party frameworks.
So before you get started
even using a framework,
that's why it's a good idea to go
take a look at their repository,
see if it's been updated recently,
see if people are talking about it.
If it looks like they have
a good support system.
If they have maybe a website that
you can go to and request help or
file a bug report.
Those are the types of things
that you want to look for.
Another possibility is that the problem
you're trying to resolve is a result of
poorly designed code, or
a case when you're trying to solve
a problem in a less than ideal way.
And this occurs actually more often
than most of us are willing to admit.
But if you do find yourself in a
situation like this, it's probably best
to either rewrite or refactor your code
so that the problem is avoided entirely.
At any rate,
if you're stuck on bugs like these,
you may find yourself needing to explain
a bug to someone else that can help.
But that should be your last resort.
The more bugs that you
can solve on your own,
the less time you'll spend debugging and
the more time you'll spend developing.
But, if you do need help, one common
place you can go is Stack Overflow.
If you've not use Stack Overflow before,
it's a question and
answer site for professionals and
enthusiast programmers.
I posted a link in the instructor
notes if you need to go check it out.
When you're sharing a bug on
Stack Overflow or anywhere else,
you want to be as specific as possible.
Make sure that you're using all
the correct terminology, and that you
avoid being ambiguous or confusing
in any of the wording that you use.
It's also extremely useful to
provide a list of explicit steps for
how to reproduce the error.
This can be as textual scriptions or
even gif images.
And personally I enjoy gif
images where possible.
If you're interested, I've posted
another link in the instructor notes for
a tool that you can use to easily
create gif images on your own.
Either way, the key thing to remember
is that when you're sharing a bug,
you want to empower somebody
to reproduce the error.
If they can't reproduce the error,
then they'll be very limited in
the type of help that they can provide.