The box model defines an HTML
element space on the screen and
you can visualize it with the dev tools.
Hovering over an element shows
its entire box model and
by using the diagram
in the Styles panel.
You can highlight each component of
an element's box model individually.
I mean, come on, you have to admit,
that's pretty cool.
Every box model is made
up of four components.
The content, the padding, which is
the space between the content and
the border, the border and the margin.
Margin is the space between this
element and any neighboring elements.
Most people think of margin as being
the space on the outside of elements.
While everything from the border to the
content is on the inside of elements.
Now before we go any further,
I want to point out this chunk of CSS.
It changes the default way
the sizes of boxes are calculated,
the default version is content box and
it's a little weird.
Because most people
look at the box model.
And assume that the margin is
the space on the outside and
everything else is
the space on the inside.
It would make sense for the area on
the inside to represent the width and
the height of an element.
And for margin to not be
included in this measurement, but
that's not the case.
With content box, width and
height don't include padding or
border, that's what makes it weird.
For example, if you were to set
the width of an element to be 800px and
then add padding and border.
Then the actual width of the element
is 800px, plus whatever padding and
border is added to the element.
This is confusing, because the width
only includes the content.
It doesn't include the padding or border
which are parts of the box model that
most people think of
as inside the element.
This is often unexpected behavior, with
border-box you don't have this problem.
Both padding and border are included
in the width and height of the element.
So you can be safe as thinking
of content, padding and
border as on the inside of the element
and as margin on the outside.
>From here on out when we're
describing the way box sizing works.
We'll assume that you're using
border-box, instead of content-box.
Anyway, there's a bit more to the box
model than what I've given you so
far, but this is more than
enough to be dangerous.