Travis, I'm really glad you
could join us for the course.
Can you tell us a little bit about
yourself and the movie database?
>> Yeah sure.
So I started TMDB seven years ago.
Just as a side project to help serve
images to the media center community.
And what started off as literally
just a website sharing zip files.
Has turned out to be one of the most
popular movie databases on the Internet.
>> Awesome, so what exactly can
we do with the movie database?
>> So yeah, I'd like to mention
you know, seven years ago,
when I started TMDB we
were just sharing images.
And since then, obviously our database,
our service has evolved a lot.
And some of the cooler
things we've added is,
goes way beyond just you know,
searching for
movies and finding you know, the
filmography of an actor or an actress.
We wrote, wanted to make it as
easy as we could to let developers
on any platform, you know,
mobile or even just other websites.
To plug in, you know, sessions and
account features without ever
having to worry about the back end.
And that's exactly what most of
our service, account service does.