Now some people like manipulating trees.
And some people like a more sort
of formal mathematical notation.
So if you're one of those, I'm going to
give you another way to think about
whether or not we have a solution.
And let's start with the problem
solving where a plan consists of
a straight line sequence.
And we said, one way to decide if this
is a plan that satisfies the goal is
to say, is the end state a goal state?
If we want to be more formal and write
that out mathematically, what we can say
is, what this plan represents is
we started in the start state.
And then we transitioned to
the state that is result of
applying the action of going
from A to S to that start state.
And then we apply it to that
the result of starting in that
intermediate state and applying
the action of going from S to F.
And if that resulting state is
an element of the set of goals,
then this plan is valid.
This plan gives us a solution.
And so that's a mathematical
formulation of what it means for
this plan to be a goal.
Now in stochastic,
partially observable worlds,
the equations are a little
bit more complicated.
Instead of just having s prime
as a result of applying some
action to the initial state,
we're dealing with belief states,
rather than individual states.
And what we say is our new belief
state is the result of updating
what we get from predicting
what our action will do and
then updating it based on our
observation, O, of the world.
So the prediction step is when
we start off in a belief state,
we look at the action, we look at
each possible result of the action.
Because they're so caustic, to each
possible member of the belief state,
and so
that gives us a larger belief state.
And then we update that belief state by
taking account of the observation, and
that will give us a smaller or
same size belief state.
And now that gives us the new state.
And we can use this predict and
update cycle to keep track of
where we are in belief state.