You've just seen some tricky situations
involving multiple variables and
interesting ordering.
Here, hand stimulating to figure
out what the computer does is key.
Now let's talk about scope.
I've linked the video on scope if
you don't remember what I mean by
variable scope.
Scope is what differentiates a local
variable from a global variable.
A local variable is stuck in the block
of code that it was defined in,
usually a method.
Whereas a global variable has a little
bit more freedom to go to different
parts of the program.
Let's look at a few different questions
to see if you understand the difference.
In these exercises we're going
to look at longer code examples.
All of these examples will
either have no errors or
it will have an error involving scope.
Here's the first example.
In this scenario let's say you're
a market researcher, and you've made
an app to figure out which sugary drink
consumers prefer, UdasiCola or Pepcity.
You'll talk to people on the street and
hand them two drinks.
And then ask them to vote with the app
to say which one they like better.
Let's look at the code
that goes with this.
These ellipses here and
here mean that there's more
code that I'm not showing you.
But I'm showing you the important
code that has to deal with voting.
When you click the Udacicola button,
it'll call the voteUdacicola method,
which adds one to udacicolaVotes,
a variable that's meant to
keep track of how many people
have voted for Udacicola.
In the same way, let's say that
you've programmed the XML so
that when you click on the Pepcity
button, it call the votePepcity method,
which also adds one, but
instead to the number of Pepcity votes.
Then, for the sake of argument,
let's say that there's a third secret
button which only you can use.
Which will show the votes.
That button will call the showMeVotes
method, which will show the udacicola
votes versus the pepcity votes, so you
can compare the two for your research.
Okay.
So let's start thinking about
the scope of some of these variables.
We'll look at the udacicola
votes variable first.
From what you see here
in the code right now,
is udacicola votes a local variable or
a global variable?
Now this doesn't mean should
it be a local variable or
should it be a global variable.
Look at the code and tell me,
is it instantiated and
defined as a local variable or
as a global variable?
After you answer this there's going to
be one more additional question.