So the right place to put the commit,
is immediately after the execute
in this particular code.
By adding commit, you can make
sure that your changes get saved.
By the way,
one nice thing about transactions and
rollbacks, is that if your code crashes
in the middle of a database transaction,
you can be sure that it won't have
written half-finished changes.
This is an important database
principle called atomicity.
Atomicity means that either
a change happens as a whole,
atomically or it happens not at all.
On the next page,
we'll be switching gears a bit.
Remember that software I asked you
to install at the end of Lesson two?
I hope it hasn't had time to get dusty,
because you're going to use that next.