Well then why not just
keep the step size large?
>> A couple of reasons.
First, with a really large step size,
we can miss sharp hills completely.
Going back to our first starting place.
If my step size is this big, I would
skip the hill I intended to take.
And would start going up
the next hill instead.
>> Well, that seems obvious, but
you said there were a couple of reasons.
What's the other one?
>> In certain situations, the algorithm
could get into a infinite loop and
never terminate.
For example,
look at the hill with a global maximum.
If I start to the left of it,
above the shoulder.
And have a step size this big,
I'll skip to the other side of the hill.
Now the gradient is going
to go back the other way.
So, I step back in
the direction in which I came.
End up close to where I started.
The algorithm can oscillate and
not converge on the answer.
>> But it should be easy to check for
that in our code.
Maybe if we see oscillation,
we could just do smaller steps.
>> You've hit upon a key idea.
We can start with a large step size and
decrease it over time.
To better ensure,
that we reach the global maximum.
However, we'll get the same result with
something called simulated kneeling.
Which is one of the big
concepts of this course.
>> Before we continue,
I'd like to experiment a bit
with these hill climbing ideas