A cool thing in perspective projection and something that, that you already know
is that parallel lines in the world almost always meet at a point in the image.
So here's an example of that's two parallel lines out on the ground plane and
they project to two lines in the image.
And you can see that they meet at this point,
sometimes called the "Vanishing" point in the image.
And the, the canonical example of that is always railroad tracks, where the,
the tracks themselves all converge to some point.
So we can sort of intuitively think about that.
But what's really cool is you can see that directly from the mathematics of it.
So let's think about what a line in 3-space is.
So a line in 3-space can par, parametrized by a single value a single parameter.
So in this case, we're going to use t.
So we have x of t, y of t and z of t and
the idea is as t changes from maybe minus infinity to infinity or
zero to however you want to do it, you would move along that line.
And a line in 3-space starts at some point in 3-space.
I'm saying here, x0, y0, z0.
And then its moved along some vector.
So right now, we're using the vector a, b, c.
So a, a in the x direction, b in the y direction and
c in the z direction, scaled by the value of t.
So now, let's take a look at where all the points on the line lie in
the image plan.
All right? So that's for every x, y, z,
what's the x prime and y prime for the given t?
Well, we learned that the equation of the projection from x,
y, z to x prime is just fx over z and for y, it's just fy over z.
So here, we just substitute it in the expressions from the other side
in terms of t.
So that's where all the points on the line go, but
what happens as t gets really big?
In the limit as t goes to infinity and I'm going to assume for
now that c is not zero, we'll talk about that in a minute.
Okay?
The limit of x prime is just fa over c.
The limit of y prime is just fb over c.
What's missing?
What's missing is x0, y0, z0?
In other words,
it doesn't matter which point in the world this line starts from.
I can start from here.
As long as the points are all moving in the direction to a, b,
c, they're all going to converge at this point in the image.
And that's what were,
that's why it's the case that all parallel lines in the world, so
it's lines that are parallel in the world will all converge to a single point.
So the railroad tracks and a sense along the railroad track, since they're all
parallel in the same direction, they all converge to the same point.
So what does it mean that c is zero?
So c is zero means that the z value doesn't change.
So assuming I'm holding my camera like this, so
my image plane is a, a vertical plane, so that z is perpendicular.
If the z value doesn't change,
it means the line in the world is parallel to my image plane.
Doesn't get further away or
closer, it stays parallel and those lines will all stay parallel lines.
And that's why I said that almost all pairs of parallel lines in
the world converge to a point.
If you have parallel lines that are vertical or
aligned with the image plane, they don't converge.