Now it's your turn to put
these operations into code.
I'd like you to please implement
the addition, subtraction and
scalar multiplication functions
in a language of your choice.
Use your code to find the answers
to the following questions.
After the quiz, I will show you
the solution I used based on the python
module I introduced
earlier in the lesson.
For the first question please compute
the vector 8.218 minus 9.341 plus
the vector minus 1.1229 2.111.
For the second question,
please compute the vector 7.119,
8.215 minus the vector, -8.223, 0.878.
For the third question
please compute the scalar
7.41 times the vector,
1.671, -1.012, -0.318.
Please enter your solutions
within an accuracy of at least
three decimal places.