Let's try updating the empty view
in the location status changes.
First, we'll add a function to utility
to get the location status, and then
we'll have forecast fragment implement
on shared preference change listener.
Registering and
Deregister it in onResume and onPause.
Finally, we'll make the empty view
function update based upon the location
status and the network state.
I've given you two strings that you
can use in the instructor notes.
The string for the invalid server error
case, recommends if user check for
updates of Sunshine.
This is designed to handle
the case with a server,
is outdated in a way that is no
longer compatible with our app.