These points are called vanishing points.
Here's it demonstrated that each set of parallel lines,
that means they're all in the same direction, meet at the different point.
Another thing that's true is that parallel lines that are all on the same plane,
they all converge to colinear Vanishing points.
And you know this as the horizon.
So here is one set of parallel lines in the world.
And they converge to a point here.
This is another set of parallel lines.
And they converge to a point there.
If I had parallel lines going away from the camera,
they would converge like this, all right?
And the horizon is this line right there.
And that's because all of those parallel lines that I drew, they were all
in ground plane, so they all converge at vanishing points on the horizon.
By the way it turns out
getting the vanishing points consistent, when you're putting together an image.
Like, you're taking a piece of a building here, and
putting something else together there,
as opposed to actually taking a picture, is actually kind of hard.
So if you want to try to find a fake image.
That is, something that's been Photoshopped, put together.
Go to your local supermarket tabloid.
You can often find pictures where the vanishing points don't seem to
do the right thing, and
that's because it was made up of parts of an image that weren't taken with
a camera aligned with those parallel lines all in the same way.
A little bit more, maybe some of you actually took an art class,
before you decided to lose your soul and become an engineer.
And maybe they taught you about 3-point perspective.
Well and here's a drawing of 3-point perspective.
And basically what they're talking about is if I've got a cube in the,
in the, in the air.
That defines three sets of parallel lines.
Like the left face, the right face and then underneath.
And you could see that drawn here and that's where it comes from,
is that parallel lines converge to different Vanishing Points.
Here's another example I think, I think this is a Zisserman product,
I'm not sure, so just a really quaint old building.
And there's Vanishing point from the right, from the power lines there,
another Vanishing point on the left.
And without talking about others,
you can see where the horizon is, okay, right across there,
that's where all the lines for example, on the ground would converge.