Recall our basic sketch of a work
optimal list ranking algorithm.
The idea is to first shrink the list,
then run the sub
optimal list ranking algorithm, and then
expand the list back to the original.
The key step is shrinking the list.
So how do you shrink the list?
Let's use Parallel Independent Set.
This process is similar to Pointer
Jumping except you'll only jump over
the independent set elements.
Let me sketch this idea by example,
first, let's maintain a list of ranks.
Initially, let's assign a temporary
rank of zero to the Head and
one to each of the other nodes.
To shrink the list,
first identify an independent set.
Remember the two steps.
The first is flipping coins.
The second is removing double heads.
Here's the independent set.
Now remove it.
Removing it entails removing
the vertices for one and eight.
It also means rewiring
seven to point to three.
That should remind you
of pointer jumping.
Let's start by removing
four in the four two edge.
In addition to removing four,
you should push it's temporary
rank to the neighbor two.
In this case,
the temporary rank is zero,
so two's rank will remain the same.
Remember, that you did the same
operation in pointer jumping for
list ranking.
So that's it for vertex four.
Now, let's move to vertex one.
You should push its temporary rank
of one to its neighbor three.
Now let's look at the jump
from seven to three.
Jumping means updating
seven's next pointer.
These are the basic steps.
You do them over and over until you've
removed the entire independent set.
Now you might have to repeat
the independent set process
because remember.
Your goal is to get to a list
that has a size of n/log n.
For example,
let's say you haven't gotten there yet.
So you'd flip coins again.
In this case, five and
seven are in the independent set so
we need to remove them.
Let's start with seven which
requires a jump from two to three.
So here's the jump.
So we should also push sevens
temporary rank to three, and
you repeat the process for vertex five.
Now let's suppose that this point
the list has the right size.
Then we can run list scan on it.
The temporary ranks or
the ranks to scan, so
running the scan gives
you the following result.
Now let's compare these computer
ranks to what they're supposed to be,
based on the original lists.
They're exactly what they need to be.
Neat.
Now what about these other ranks?
You basically need to run the process
that you just ran to contract the list
in reverse.
It's not hard, but
it's a lot of bookkeeping, so for
the sake of clarity,
let me skip those details and
refer you to the downloadable section
for my detailed notes and pseudocode.