One thing that we didn't explain is what
actually ends up in the buffers that
are being passed for transmission
among the client and the server.
For instance, the server can
support multiple procedures.
It is important to not just pass the
arguments but actually to include an RPC
header that will uniquely identify what
is the procedure that's being called,
the version number,
something about the requests so
that we can detect repeated
requests on retries.
Similar type of information will be
sent from the server back to the client,
again, as part of the RPC header.
So this is one component
of what actually goes on
the wire in the packets
that are being transmitted.
Then, clearly we have to put the actual
data, the actual arguments or
results on the wire as well.
However, as opposed to just directly
copying from memory into the packets,
we have to first encode all of
the different data types for
the arguments in the results into
a byte stream to serialize them
in a way that depends on
the actual data type.
It is important to have a specific
agreement on how this encoding is done
so that the server has the ability
to interpret the byte stream and
recreate the appropriate data
structure in the server address space.
In order for
the server to actually call the
procedure that implements the service.
it needs to have the arguments
present in the server memory.
That's why this step is necessary.
Similar kind of requirement,
we have also on the return when
the result is passed to the client.
The client needs to be able to
look at this byte stream and
figure out how it needs
to take that information
in populated data structure
in the client memory.
In some cases there may be
a one to one mapping between
the in memory representation and
how the data is encoded in the packet.
But in other cases that
may not be the case.
And finally when all this information
is placed in a packet that needs to be
preceded with the transport header with
the networking header that will specify
the protocol, the destination address
and will make sure that on the client
and on the server, all of the protocol
specific operations take place.