I think the most important realization that I had when I got into computer
science. Or the best advice that I got, was just somebody telling me, you're
not bad at it. And by it, I mean programming. It's really hard because
programming is a completely new way of thinking. It's like learning a language.
And, it's really easy to struggle and people always seem like they know what
they're doing. because some people have been programming since they were like
three in the basement with their little like calculators and stuff. And I
wasn't one of those people. And so, it took me a long time to just sort of
realize that I could do it just as well as anybody else. And just sticking to
it is the best thing that you can do. And there's so much help out there
between, you know, online courses. just sort of forums on the internet or your
friends, anything. And just being vulnerable and asking for help is the way
that I've gotten through it.