The process of improving application
performance can be a daunting task, but
it's actually much simpler than that.
Once you shift gears into
focusing on performance problems,
you've now entered what we call
the performance improvement life-cycle.
It's a very small set of tasks you must
perform, to find and fix a problem.
It namely consists of three steps.
Number one, gather information.
When someone says that your app is slow,
you have to go and figure out why.
This means you need to
run the profiling and
feedback tools to collect
information about your app.
What you can measure,
you can optimize, right?
Which means that in the beginning of
optimizing any of your applications,
the process hinges on being
able to measure its state and
then evaluate it after you make changes.
Step number two, is to gain insight.
The data that you gather
is not always obvious.
Now, most of the time,
the content is a big collection of
floating point numbers, which then,
if you're lucky, gets turned into
some snazzy visualization by a tool.
But even then, chances are that
you're still at a loss for
what all those colors, lines,
and charts actually mean.
This is where developers
become performance gurus.
Now you see interpreting a sheet
of floating point numbers and
then realizing that you're spending too
much time serializing XML, is the modern
equivalent of a shaman reading
chicken bones to predict the future.
And honestly these first two
stages of gathering data and
then gaining insight,
happen in a really tight loop.
You may use one tool,
gain some info from it, and
then realize that the problem is
in another part of your pipeline.
Which then you'll need
a separate tool to diagnose.
But of course that leads us to
the third step, take action.
This is often the most difficult part
of the loop this is where you take all
the numbers and all the insight,
and know where the problem is, and
then you have to go convince the other
programmers the right way to fix it.
Of the three stages,
this has the most human component to it.
Because solving
the problem isn't enough,
you need to solve it in a way that
meets your coding standards for
your complexity or your company or
takes in account libraries or
a particular module or
a platform that you're running on, or
other crazy restrictions that
your code base might have.
Before your solution is accepted,
you usually have to take all
of these things into account.
But before you run off into the weeds
and become a performance engineer I have
one small piece of warning
about performance.
Throughout this course we'll be teaching
you what's going on under the hood of
Android and
teaching you how to use the tooling to
gain insight into some of those actions.
Some of that content is going to be
prescriptive like if you see this,
it means this, so do that.
But in honest,
that might not always be the case for
every application sure something
may be inefficient but
if it's not impacting your performance,
it's not worth stressing over.
This is why we like to say,
tools not rules,
while it's important to understand the
rules and the flow of things, you need
to validate the true real issues by
trusting what your tools say first.
It may not make sense for you to solve
a problem that you actually don't have.
Always go back to the data and
validate the true nature of a problem,
decide if it's a problem, before
moving on to the optimization process.
You've been warned,