[Thrun] I should warn you this question is hard.
If you're new to computer vision, you likely won't get it.
I'd like to ask it to you anyhow just to see how close you can get
and whether you appreciate the answer I'll be giving you.
Suppose we have m camera poses.
That means m directions from which we take an image.
That's called the motion.
And suppose we have n 3D points, which is called the structure.
Then it's quite obvious that we have 2 times m times n constraints
simply because in each of the images we see all the n points
and we get an x and a y coordinate for each of the points,
which makes 2-m-n constraints.
We also have unknowns.
Specifically, each camera position is a 6D unknown
about the rotation and translation of the camera,
and each point itself has a 3D coordinate.
So the total number of unknowns is 6m plus 3n.
At first glance, to solve the structure from motion problem you would want 6m plus 3n
to be smaller or equal to 2mn.
And of course if m and n is big enough, this equation will be satisfied.
But my question is if you run the structure from motion problem,
how many of these unknowns can you actually recover?
Or, put differently, how many of those unknowns can you not recover?
If you think about it, for example, you won't be able to really recover
the absolute coordinates of our system, because you can move the entire system
1 meter to the right and you'll still get the same answer.
So there's going to be a number over here that I want you to enter
that specifies the number of parameters that cannot possibly be recovered
in this structure from motion problem.