Before you can import and
run a LibGDX project, you'll need to get
Android Studio set up and
get your phone talking to your computer.
If you haven't already done this,
then setting up Android Studio
is your side quest for today.
Now, I know what you're thinking.
Isn't this a cross-platform
game development class?
Why are we using Android Studio?
Well, Android Studio is actually based
on another integrated development
environment called IntelliJ Idea, which
is a powerful general purpose Java IDE.
That means you can build all sorts of
stuff in Android Studio that has nothing
to do with Android, like for instance,
the desktop backend of our games.
And of course,
Android Studio will make deploying the
Android version of our games super easy.
And it doesn't even blink at deploying
the iOS and HTML versions as well.
For specific instructions on
how to install Android Studio,
I'm going to hand you off to Lyla,
another one of our course developers,
who made an awesome lesson all
about Android Studio installation.
You can check it out at
udacity.com/ud808 or
by following the link in
the instructor notes below the video.
Install Android Studio, and get to
the point where you can go ahead and
deploy a test app on your phone.