In this lesson we will be talking
about another distributed service,
specifically distributed shared memory.
Now recall that in a previous
lesson on memory management,
we made a visual analogy between
the memory contents of a process and
the parts used by workers
sharing a single work space.
Holding off of that analogy,
managing distributed shared memory
is like managing the toy parts or
even the tools across all
the work spaces in a toy shop.
As you can see from this image, it is
very similar to the one that we used for
the distributed file systems because
we want to show that there are multiple
distributive nodes that are working
together towards providing a service.
The service that's provided is
the sharing of the tools and
the toy parts among workers that are
working on multiple such work benches.
So you imagine even in a single location
like this, there will be multiple such
workbenches with multiple workers using
certain toys and toy parts and tools and
this is what we want to facilitate,
the sharing of those tools and parts.
For the management of tools and
toy parts in a toy shop there are three
major decisions that must be made.
The first one is how are we going
to place all these resources
in the distributed environment.
Next we must decide how and when to
move tools around the different shops or
the different work benches in those
shops, and finally we must establish
some rules how those toy parts and
tools will be shared.
For instance,
regarding placement we would probably
decide to place those resources close
to the workers that are currently
needing them to perform their task.
When a worker on one work bench is
done with a particular resource and
another worker on another workbench or
potentially in another location
needs that resource we should
move it as soon as possible.
And finally we must have policies on how
long can a worker keep a tool on their
desk or when and how workers should
let others know that a tool or
a toy part is ready and
is available for use by others.
Or for instance when should the tools or
the toy parts be placed into a storage
facility that others can access as well.
For managing distributed shared memory,
we must make similar types of decisions
however clearly the details
are going to be very different.
For instance, when deciding placement,
we should typically place the contents
of memory or the contents of a page
in a physical memory that's
close to a particular process.
This would be the process that
either created that content and or
will be using that content.
When a process needs access to memory
that's stored in a page param on
a remote node,
we should come up with some policy
how to migrate that
content to the local node.
For instance, we can copy
that content that memory page
from the remote to
the local physical memory.
Since the memory page may be
concurrently accessed by multiple
processes, and in addition since we
may have multiple copies of that page
in different locations in the system,
it's important to establish some rules
how the different
operations are ordered.
How they're propagated across
the different copies, so
that there is a consistent
view of the entire memory.