Now that you understand the AVAudioRecorder,
it's time to get the code into
Pitch Perfect. I’m currently open to the
RecordSoundsViewController.swift file.
Add the import statement for AVFoundation
right below the import
statement for UIKit. Inside the
RecordSoundsViewController class,
let's add a AVAudioRecorder property
called audioRecorder. While we're at it,
I’m also going to remove the
didReceiveMemoryWarning function, we don't need it
right now. In the recordAudio function,
add these lines of code for creating the
audio session and telling the AVAudioRecorder
to start recording audio.
You can find all the code that I have here
directly under the video. At this point,
our code is able to record the audio and
save it to the recordedVoice.wav file.
But what about when we want to stop
recording? That should be handled when
the Stop Recording button is pressed, and
you've already wired up that button to
fire the IBAction stopRecording.
Let's go there. In the stopRecording
function, add these three lines to stop
the recording. These lines both stop the
audio recorder and set the shared
AVAudioSession to inactive. And that's all
it takes, Pitch Perfect should now be
able to record your voice. To check that
things are working, let's print out the
file path when we start recording audio.
Let's go ahead and run our app. When we
click the Record button, we can see a
file path to the recordedVoice.wav
file.