Everything you see on your computer
screen is just a rectangular grid of
colors.
This makes perfect sense for
some things.
For instance,
a digital photo is captured
using a rectangular sensor grid.
So, the color samples you see on your
computer are just the colors that were
captured by the camera.
But what about something else,
like a line drawing?
A smiley face is made up of circles and
arcs, it's not made of
a rectangular grid of colors.
So, how do we draw it to the screen?
It seems impossible, right?
To draw shapes like lines,
triangles, circles,
and other polyhedra,
they have to be rasterized.
To draw a black arc on a yellow
background, we have to determine for
each sample on the raster, whether
that sample is part of the arc or
part of the background and
then color that sample appropriately.
If you want to get super fancy,
you might determine what percentage of
the sample is part of the arc, and what
percentage is part of the background,
and then mix the two colors to
get your final output color.
Doing is this is called antialiasing for
reasons beyond the scope of this course.
Anyway, only once we know
the color of every pixel,
can our shape be drawn to the screen.
This process is also called rendering.
This presents a huge challenge though,
which we'll explore by way of a quiz.
So, how much work is rasterization?
Let's say our raster is 1080 x 1920,
so that's standard HD.
And let's say we're drawing
20 shapes to this screen.
Let's then say for each pixel and each
shape, it takes 10 processor cycles to
determine if the shape changes
the color of that particular pixel.
Then, since we want
a silky smooth frame rate,
we need to do all of this 60 times
a second, so here's the question.
How many processor cores
running at three gigahertz
would we need to render this screen?