The easiest way to do this
is using cumulative sums.
You can call cumsum with a matrix and
a dimension specified.
Here 1 tells it to sum up rows.
So the first row gets
added to the second.
And then that result gets
added to the third and so on.
Let's see what this looks like.
I'll comment out the rest of the code,
since it's of no use right now.
You can see the effect
of rules being summed.
Getting brighter and
brighter as you go down.
Here is the original image for
reference.
And here is the row-wise
cumulative sum result again.
All right, so this takes care
of summation in one dimension.
As you might have guessed, we can take
the cumulative sum along the other
dimension of this intermediate result
in order to get our integral image.
Let's clean up and do that.
So, as we said, the first cumulative
sum is an intermediate result.
Now we summed this up
along the other dimension.
That is, along the columns.
The first column gets
added to the second and
that result gets added to the third,
and so on.
And that's it.
This is our integral image.
Lets see what the result looks like.
You can clearly see a gradual
monotonic increase in
brightness from top
left to bottom right.
That is to be expected, isn't it?
Lets check if the two computed
values were the same.
And yes, they are indeed.
Okay.
So what about this crazy formula?
Within the larger image, we've
defined a window using x1, y1, x2, y2.
The top left corner has coordinates x1,
y1.
And the bottom right has x2, y2.
The first value, I(y2, x2),
is the integral image value here
in the bottom right corner, which
is basically the sum of the original
image from the top left till that point.
We call this A.
Remember B was this rectangle up here?
Note that it needs to go to
the column value x2 on the right.
But needs to stop one short of y1,
otherwise the values at row y1 will
get subtracted from our final result.
This is why you have a minus 1 here.
Again this was B.
Similarly for c,
it needs to go down to y2.
But needs to stop one short of x1.
Hence, x1 minus 1.
Note that the region d that
has been subtracted twice
is only up to x1 minus 1, y1 minus 1.
And that's exactly what we add back in.
Clear?
Now think of an edge case
where x1,y1 equals 1,1.
That is the top left corner
of our desired region
is at the top left corner
of the image itself.
These minus 1s can then
result in invalid indices.
To overcome this problem, Matlab for
instance, pads 0s on the left and
top, that is a single row of 0s.
It increases the resulting width and
height by 1,
and it requires you to change
the final computation expression.
But this is just
an implementation detail.
Overall, I hope you can appreciate how
vastly significant integral images are.
Once you've computed an integral image,
you can replace each of these summation
operations, which involves probably
hundreds or thousands of additions,
with just two subtractions and
one addition right here.