Some good ways to create competition is
by letting players compare their high
scores or
achievements with other players.
So for example, I might choose to keep
track of the level a player gets to and
how many aliens they shot.
And make a leaderboard to show who has
the highest score in these categories.
You can also keep track of who
maintain the least amount of damage or
any other competitive
measures you can think of.
You could also build an option for
a two-player game.
So that two players compete
to shoot the most aliens.
The important thing is that you create
competition by involving a larger part
of your gaming community and letting
them compare their game performance.