You now have a scheme for
searching across the image for
possible detections, but you'll notice
that your classifier is not perfect.
In some cases,it will report multiple
overlapping instances of the same car or
even report cars where there are none.
These are known as duplicates and
false positives, and
you'll need to filter them out.
In correctly combining
duplicate detections and
rejecting false positives, you are
performing the task of identifying where
vehicles are on the road.
But equally important
where they are not.
False positives that are not properly
filtered out can lead to taking actions
like emergency breaking when it's
not necessary and potentially,
to causing an accident.
In order to avoid running into another
car, you would like to get the best
estimate possible for the position and
size of the cars you detect.
That means whether it's a single
detection or multiple detections on
the same car, a tight bounding box for
each car is what you're aiming for.
These bounding boxes are ultimately
going to be used by your path-planning
or motion control algorithms,
to try to cause the steer is
clear of the other vehicles.
In this next exercise, you'll write
code to handle multiple detections and
false positives.