There are lots of ways to loop
over arrays in JavaScript, and
each way has its pros and cons.
For loops are very versatile and
give you complete control
over the looping process.
You can explicitly define
where to start and
stop in the array, whether you want
to skip over values in the array, and
even whether you'd like to break out of
the loop early, using a break statement.
When it doubt, you can probably
use a for loop to do it.
forEach gives you a concise
way of looping over an array
if you know you are going to be looping
over every element from start to finish.
You have less versatility than
you do with a regular for loop.
But you can access each element
directly, which is nice.
And you don't need to use an index
of an element to do that.
Map is one more ray method you'll
want in your Java Script tool belt.
Similar to forEach, you can define
a callback function that performs
an operation on each
element in the array.
The difference here is
map returns a new array
with the new values to
your function calculated.
So there you have it.
There are tons of ways to
iterate over a data in array.
And you can check out even more of them
by reading the Mozilla documentation.
But for now,
you've got three you can pull from,
depending on what you
need to accomplish.
For loops, forEach, and
now map, if you need to create
a new array using our function.