To solve this problem, I started where
attach event listeners gets called.
It's generally it occurs inside an event
listener for dom content loaded.
When attach event listeners gets
called there is a flag that's set for
sliding and that indicates whether or
not the toggle's actually sliding.
I'm going to take advantage of this
flag to figure out when I should use
events on the window to move the toggle.
You'll see,
inside attach event listeners
I set the touch start event
listener on the toggle itself.
This is because I wanted to make sure
that sliding starts when somebody is
actually touching the toggle,
not some random place on the screen.
Inside the event listener I set sliding
to true because at this point the toggle
should be able to slide.
And I added the first movement
to the toggle tracker.
Remember add movement is expecting
the x position of either a mouse or
a finger on the screen, so in order to
get that I'm using the event object.
The event object contains a touches
array and there's only one touch.
And it has a property pageX which
is exactly what I'm looking for.
Next up, here comes the move.
So on touchmove, I look for
if the toggle is (sliding) already.
I need to look for (sliding) because I
attached touchmove to the whole window.
And that's because somebody's finger
can pretty easily slip off the toggle.
And so if the toggle should
actually be (sliding),
I add the movement
the same way I did before.
And then i request an animation
frame using the slide callback.
And this is what actually
makes the toggle move.
And lastly, I want to watch out for
any touchend events, whether or
not they occur on the toggle itself.
So, in that case,
I add toucnend to the window.
It doesn't matter where the finger
gets let up on the screen.
In that case, sliding is done.
I then did basically the same thing for
mousedown, mousemove and mouseup.
The only difference is now I don't have
a touches object on the event objects
and I can simply go straight to pageX.
Cool, okay, that's enough code.
Let me show you what this looks like.
Just like before,
touch events seem to be working and
mouse events work as well.
I can slide off and keeps going but
as soon as I let up, no more sliding.