Congratulations on building your
first artificial intelligence agent.
For most of you,
your Sudoku agent is by no means the
first AI agent you've interacted with.
In fact, If you've ever
played a modern video game,
you've almost definitely interacted
with an AI agent before.
But how do these game agents work?
How do they learn to play a game and
beat humans with such consistency?
In the following lessons, Tad Steiner,
a professor at Georgia Tech.
And one of the leading
researchers at Google X,
will introduce us to artificial
intelligence in game playing.
By the end of these two lessons,
you'll build your own game playing AI
to win at the board game of Isolation.
You will also get a chance to see how
these same techniques are used both
in Deep Blue,
IDM's AI that beat Garry Kasparov.
And Alpha Go, Google's AI that
beat Lee Sedol in the game of Go.
Let's get started.