You're now ready for
the final lesson in the course.
In this lesson,
I'm going to prepare you to build
the course app called On the Map.
Here's the app in action.
First you login with
your Udacity credentials.
And then you're going to
be presented with a map
that shows the locations of other iOS
students that are in the program.
So you can see these pins here.
And I'm going to go ahead and
submit my location.
Which is Mountain View, California,
that's where we're located.
So I'll paste it here and
I'll find it on the map.
And them I'm going to share the link for
the iOS nano degree.
And I'll submit this and
you can see my pin's posted on the map.
As well as these pins for
the other iOS instructors.
This is pretty cool.
And without further ado,
it's time to go to the final lesson and
build On the Map.