Consider this graph.
Suppose you want to coarsen two subsets
of vertices into super vertices.
That is, suppose you want to merge these
two vertices into a super vertex, and
you also want to merge these three
vertices into a super vertex.
Structurally, you would get
the following coarsened graph.
Here's what I want you to do.
I want you to compute
the weights of the vertices and
the edges in the coarsen
graph representation.
Type your answers into the boxes.
These red boxes are for edges,
and the brown boxes are for
the two super vertices.
Assume that all vertex and
edge weights in the original graph,
on the left, are equal to 1.