Let me now showcase a simple example of
how we can actually applied what we've
learned about with images, that is
sometimes it's not better to fade or
blend, but to cut images except,
now this will do this cutting in time.
Let me show you this video here,
if you notice that basically we
have two videos of you know,
waterfalls, but rather than actually
fade, and you know, cut or fade it.
We basically finding a surface
between both of them, and
using that to figure out
which pixels to show.
Let me actually, now explain this here,
so what's basically happening here is we
have an input video and we have an
output video, we basically put both of
them on top of each other, and
find the best possible seam in time.
And use that to find the best pixels
between them, and use that to now
generate a video, that also, is crossing
over the two video volumes, but
allowing us to create a much more
crisper version, as we did with cuts.
Here you see this example in this
case of this simple video of,
of blowing, when, you know, blown grass.
This is my original video sequence,
can notice, of course, when it loops,
and you see a jerk,
this was actually the earlier method.
Of course, when we do it with that,
there's a little bit
of blending going on.
And the new method, which is a graph
cut method which is also for me and
my students, of course,
can generate this much, much better,
and much more cleanly.
Same thing again, for
the waterfall example that we looked at,
original video sequence.
Much crisper, with graph cut if you
notice, we can actually generate this.
Really crisper, and of course,
this can go on infinitely long.
So, that's what actually you come in, in
the case of using cuts because what they
again do is they provide you
with the right pixels, and
not blending between pixels.
Again, something we looked at
when we talked about images.