In this exercise,
you'll create a Word Cloud.
Now we've created a lot of the
infrastructure for you, but this is kind
of a complicated exercise, so
I wanted to walk you through it a bit.
So we've already set up
the SpriteBatch and the BitmapFont.
And we've also created this array,
Array words,
where the words
are a static inter class.
If we jump down to the bottom of this
file, we'll find the word class, and
you see it has five member variables,
the x and
y position, The scale in which to draw
the word, the color of the word, and
then what letters are actually
contained in the word.
So, for each of these word objects,
you need to set the font's scale.
Set the font's tint and then,
actually draw that word.
All right, check out the to-dos
in the course quota and
let's see if you can draw a Word Cloud.