After watching this clip, you should know the background and reasoning for the
study. For the purposes of this next example, we'll simplify it a little bit.
We just want to know if the wording of a question influences how well people
remember details. So let's get started. In an experiment to see how wording
affects people's memory, 150 students from the University of Washington were
shown a one minute film clip of a car accident. After the students watched the
clip, they were separated into three groups. Group one was asked, how fast were
the cars going when they hit each other? Group two was asked, how the fast were
the cars going when they smashed into each other? And group three was asked
nothing about the speed of the cars. After one week all the students were
asked, did you see any broken glass? There was no broken glass in the film, but
seven out of 50 students reported seeing broken glass in group one. 16 out of
50 in group two. And six out of 50 in group three. Let's summarize our results
in a table. We know that 50 students were assigned to each group making 150
total. But fill in the frequencies for the number of students who said no, they
did not see broken glass. And the marginal totals for the yes and no responses.