So, what are the benefits of using
a panda series instead of a numpy array?
I mentioned before that panda
series have some extra functions
not available for numpy arrays.
For example, the describe function.
However, the main difference
between panda series and
numpy arrays is that a panda series
has something called an index.
Let's take a look at an example.
Throughout this lesson,
we've been looking at data for
a bunch of different countries, and
I've been creating one array to hold
the actual data points and
one to hold the country names.
In pandas,
I would only create one series, and
I would use the data points
as the values of that series.
Then I would use the country names
as the index for the series.
Now I'll delete the numpy array code and
print out the series.
You can see here that pandas is
matching up each index value
to the corresponding data point.
I've said before that numpy arrays are
like souped version so of Python lists.
Similarly, a pandas series is like
a cross between a list and a dictionary.
In a list, elements are stored in order
and you access them by their position.
And you've just seen that
that's true for a series also.
These values are stored in order, and
you can access them by their position.
In the dictionary, on the other hand,
you can have a key such
as a country name, and
a value such as a life expectancy,
and you can look up values by keys.
You saw earlier that
the code life expectancy
at zero will give the life expectancy
at position zero in the series.
Pandas also has an attribute
called walk that lets you look up
values by their index.
If I run life_expectancy.loc Angola,
then I'll see the life expectancy for
Angola, without needing to know which
position Angola is In the list.
So, what happens if you create
a series without specifying an index,
like we did earlier?
Well, then the numbers zero, one,
two, and so on get used as the index,
by default.
So, before, when I accessed
elements using square brackets,
it wasn't clear whether I was
accessing by index, or by position.
At this point, it should be clear to you
that the square brackets are accessing
elements by position,
since there is no value in our life
expectancy series with index zero.
I prefer to be a bit more explicit
when using a series though.
Pendas has an attribute
corresponding to the lock attribute
call iloc to access
elements by position.
These two lines of code
do the same thing, but
the version using iloc is just
a little more clear in my opinion.
By the way, here's a terminology note.
In this numpy array,
many people will say something like
the country Albania is at index zero.
And they'll call using square
brackets to access an array element
indexing into the array.
I've been trying to avoid
this terminology, and
call this position zero rather than
index zero, since in a panda series,
the index and
the position are not the same.
But be aware that you might hear
the term index used inconsistently
elsewhere.
On the next screen,
I want you to rewrite the max_employment
function that you wrote at
the beginning of this lesson.
Which finds the highest employment
rate in some given data, and
the country name with
that employment rate.
This time, the input will be a single
series, rather than two numpy arrays,
and the index of that series
will be the country names.
Try using the pandas argmax function.
There's a link to the documentation
in the instructor notes.