If you completed the previous task,
your copy of the project is in
the right shape to take on this task.
Otherwise, you can run git reset --hard,
to remove any local changes you have.
Then, git checkout page-skeleton
to get up to speed.
As you saw, we’re working in
different script for this exercise.
So head over to
public/js/idb-test/index.js.
Here, you can see all the code
that Jake was writing.
And you can see it working in
the browser in local host port
8888/idb-test, by working,
I mean you get a blank screen.
But also a couple of
messages in the console.
And you'll see the database
appearing in dev tools.
You've already seen how to add and
remove items from the key val object
store, but your task is to set
the favorite animal key to the name of
your favorite animal, whatever that is.
Once you've changed the code,
refresh the page and
check dev tools to see if your
favorite animal has appeared in IDB.
To double check everything is working,
head to the settings page.
And type idb-animal into
the test field and press enter.