One air system that does do visual
spatial reasoning is called Galatia.
It was developed by Jim Davies here
at Georgia Tech, about 10 years back.
Which is why it looks black and
white and has this particular form.
We provide a reference to the paper and
in notes.
There is a very famous problem and
a logical reasoning
called a Duncke problem.
The Duncke problem goes
something like this.
First I'll tell you a story.
And then I'll give you a problem.
And you should try to find
an answer to the problem.
Let me begin with the story.
Once there was a king and not a
specially good king who ruled a kingdom.
There was an army.
That was trying to overthrow the king.
But the king lived in a fortress and
it was very hard to overthrow.
Moreover, the king had mined the roads,
so that when the army went over
the roads, it would blow off, and most
of the soldiers in the army would die.
The leader of the army decomposed
the army into smaller groups, and
these smaller groups then came to
the fortress from different directions.
Because each group is small enough,
the mines did not blow off and
each group was able to reach
the fortress at the same time.
They are able to overthrow the bad king.
This was a story,
now let me tell you about the problem.
There is a patient with
a cancer tumor in his body.
There is a physician with a laser gun.
She can use the laser gun on this tumor
to kill this tumor and cure the patient.
However, the laser light is so
strong that it will
also kill all the healthy tissue in
the way, and the patient can die.
What should the physician do?
In most computer models of this problem,
this problem is solved using
propositional representations.
So an example for
proper surplus reduction for
the original story might
be that if there is a goal,
and there is a resource, there is
an obstacle between the resource and
the goal that split the resource into
many different smaller resources and
bring them to the goal all at the same
time but from different directions.
Most composition models or decomposition
problem extract some causal pattern.
The causal pattern might be
that if there is a goal and
there is a resourcable level, and
your resource can achieve the goal but
there is an obstacle in the way.
Then decompose the resourcing
to many smaller resources and
bring them to the goal in the same
time from different directions.
The important part here is that
this is the causal pattern
extracted out of the first story.
Once this causal pattern
has been extracted,
it can be applied to this new problem.
So the physician may decompose
the laser being into smaller beams and
focus them on the tumor at the same
time, thus curing the tumour.
Jim wanted to ask whether one could
do the same kind of problem solving
without extracting
these causal patterns.
Could one use simply
visual spatial knowledge?
So this is visual spatial knowledge
because there is both a sense of what,
the fortress, as well as where,
in the middle of the figure.
Notice there is visual spatial knowledge
is represented prepositionally.
There are words here like fortress, and
right road, and top road, and so on.
But there is no causality
that is explicit.
You and I can infer the causality but
it's not explicit.
His Galatea program was able to
find a solution to the new problem
by transporting the visual spatial
knowledge to the new problem,
one step at a time.
Thus it would map this top
body part to the top rod.
One here, the left body part,
the left rod here, and
therefore beside that,
this can be decomposed.
This resources, denoted by this arrow,
can be decomposed into
smaller resources.
And then the smaller resources
can arrive at this central tumor
from different directions
at the same time.
In this way, Galatea was able
to solve the addition problem
without abstracting any
causal pattern from it.
Of course, one might say that the causal
pattern is implicit here, and
that is indeed true.
But the entire point of a visual spatial
knowledge here is that the causal
pattern is not being obstructed, but
as long as it is a problem-solving
procedure where each step is
represented only visually spatially.
It is possible to transfer this
problem-solving proceeded
to the new crop.