So, by now you may be a little curious as to why are we trying to do this?
So, let's look an example that we have looked at before.
You may recall this image that we looked at before,
where we generated a panorama.
And if you look at this carefully, you'll see,
again, that there are different subimages in this image.
So for example, you can see some of the boundaries of different images here.
And of course, each and every one of them is a separate image of their own, and
what we're interested in now is taking all of these images and
merging them together so you would have a full panorama.
So this, of course, is the output.
Now you cannot see any lines across the whole spectrum of this panorama.
All different images have been merged together.
I will flip back to the previous one again.
So just looking at these flips,
you should be able to see that the basic boundaries between
different subimages have vanished to generate a complete smooth image.
And that actually is what, the output we were looking at.
So in this lecture we will look at is how to go about coming at
various techniques we can to be able to blend images so
these types of edges that exist when you merge two images together vanish.