Up until this point, you've been working
mostly with primitive data types.
This types have been strings, numbers,
booleans, undefined, and null.
If you type the following code in
the JavaScript console, predictably
the console will return string because
hello, is a primitive string data type.
No surprises there.
But if you instead ask for
the type of this array,
you'd expect it to display array, right?
Well instead it returns object.
So what is this mysterious object?
An object is a data
structure in JavaScript
that lets you store any
kind of data value.
And you can keep track
of the data using a key.
Before we dive into the syntax of
defining an object, let's think about
what information an object that
represents a person might need.
A variable containing just
the person's name is not enough.
A person also has an age,
parents, siblings,
favorite colors, and the list goes on.
So instead of defining all the data
about a person in isolated variables,
objects allow you to
group this information.
Like the information shown here.
Into a meaningful structure.
Here is an object that's stored
in a variable called sister.
And the object's data,
information about my sister,
can be stored as a list of key
value pairs inside curly braces.
You might be noticing that this code
is a bit hard to read at first.
It's common to format objects with each
key value pair on its own
line to improve readability.
Note that the syntax hasn't changed,
we just added a new line after
each comma and indented each pair.