So, what'd you get?
I got 70 microns.
One round trip, from center to corner
and back, is l square root of 2.
Recall that your goal is to do
three trillion of these round
trips, per second.
So how do you get to 3 trillion
operations per second?
Each operation is a round trip,
each round trip is l root 2,
units of distance.
So think of this distance, l root 2,
as being in units of, say, meters.
You can travel this distance
at the signaling speed,
which is the speed of light,
by assumption.
Solve this equation for l.
Assuming I did the math right,
you should get about 70 microns
to one significant figure.
That is really tiny.
In fact,
it's about the width of a human hair.
Here's the point of this exercise.
To hit the target compute speed,
assuming information propagates
at the speed of light, a sequential
computer has to be really, really tiny.