Now I want take a second to convince ourselves
this is indeed the maximum likelihood estimate
of the mean and the variance.
Suppose our data looks like this--
There's "M" data points.
And the probability of those data points
for any Gaussian model--mu and sigma squared
is the product of any individual of data likelihood--x,i.
And if you plug in our Gaussian formula, you get the following--
This is the normalizer multiplied "M" times
where the square root is now drawn into the half over here,
and here is our joint exponential.
We took the product of the individual exponentials
and moved it up straight in here where it becomes a sum.
So the best estimates for mu and sigma squared
are those that maximize this entire expression over here
for given data set X1 to Xm.
So we seek to maximize this over the unknown parameters
mu and sigma squared.
And now I will apply a trick.
Instead of maximizing this expression,
I will maximize the logarithm of this expression.
The logarithm is a monotonic function.
So let's maximize instead the logarithm
where this expression over here resolves to this expression over here.
The multiplication becomes a minus sign from over here,
and this is the argument inside the exponent
written slightly differently,
but pulling the 2 sigma squared to the left.
So let's maximize this one instead.
The maximum was obtained where the first
derivative is zero.
If we do this for our variable mu,
we take the "log f" expression and
complete the derivative for spectrum mu,
we get following--
This expression does not depend on mu at all, so it falls out.
And we can still get this expression over here, which we've set to zero.
And now we can multiply everything by sigma squared next to zero,
and then bring the Xi to the right and the mu to the left.
The sum over all "E" of the mu is mu equals sum over i, xi.
Hence, we proved that the mean is indeed the maximum likelihood estimate
for the Gaussian.
This is now easily repeated for the variance.
If you compute the derivative of this expression over here
with respect to the variance,
we get minus "m" over sigma, which happens to be the derivative
of this expression over here.
Keep in mind that the derivative of
a logarithm stresses internal argument
times by chain rule--the derivative of the internal argument,
which if you work out becomes this expression over here.
And this guy over here changes signs
but becomes the following.
And again, you move this guy to the left side,
multiply by sigma cubed, and divide by "m".
So we get the following result over here.
You might take a moment to verify these steps over here,
I was a little bit fast,
but this is relatively straight forward mathematics.
And if you will verify them,
you will find that the maximum likelihood estimate
for sigma squared is the average
deviation of data points from the mean mu.
This gives us a very nice basis to fit
Gaussians to data points.
So keeping these formulas in mind, here's a quick quiz,
which I ask you to actually calculate the mean and variance for a data sequence.
So suppose the data you observe is 3, 4, 5, 6, and 7.
There is 5 data points.
Compute for me the mean and the variance
using the maximum likelihood estimator I just gave you.