To conclude, I want to make sure you understand that in our work right now.
In this example, the kinds of stuff that you're seeing on a screen.
You're seeing lots of example of darken, because we want to be able to kind of
show you everything on the screen, especially since our base screen is white and
we do have lots of text and images.
We have chosen or at least Aaron has chosen, to actually apply the darkened
process between the two layers, the top layer coming from the camera and
the bottom one coming in from the screen capture from the tablet.
And this allows us to kind of showcase the best possible image that
actually shows all the information that's in combination of these two screens.
Yes, in doing so sometimes.
Unreal artifacts like this will show up and you can see why
that's happening again there is a little bit of a dark blue color here.
Which when you go into the RGB space with the skin color of my
hand actually does have a little bit of this artifact or
getting a little bit of darker values.
So again remember, this is done for each and every channel RGB separately.
So hopefully, you won't be minding these kinds of artifacts but
hopefully, also using that as a learning experience.