We've looked at two search algorithms,
one Breadth-First search,
in which we always expand first the
shallowest paths, the shortest paths.
Second, Cheapest-First search,
in which we always expand first
the path with the lowest total cost.
And I'm going to take this opportunity
to introduce a third algorithm,
Depth-First search, which is in a way
the opposite of Breadth-First search.
In Depth-First search, you always
expand first the longest path,
the path with the most links in it.
Now what I want to ask you to do is,
for each of these nodes in each of
the trees, tell us in what order
they're expanded, first, second,
third, fourth, fifth, and so on,
by putting a number into the box.
And if there are ties,
put that number in,
resolve the ties in left to right order.
Then I want you to ask one more
question, or answer one more question,
which is, are these searches optimal?
That is, are they guaranteed
to find the best solution?
And for Breadth-First search, optimal
would mean finding the shortest path,
if you think it's guaranteed to
find the shortest path, check here.
For Cheapest-First, it would mean
finding the path with the lowest
total path cost, check here if you
think it's guaranteed to do that,
and we'll allow the assumption that
all costs have to be positive.
And in Depth-First, cheapest or optimal
would mean, again, as in Breadth-First,
finding the shortest possible path
in terms on number of lengths,
check here if you think
Depth-First will always find that.
[BLANK_AUDIO]