Going back to D3's documentation, there
are a few more methods that we can use
in order to transform or
change DOM nodes.
Now, you've already seen the style
function, but there's also others,
like text, html, and append.
Also, notice that some of these
methods are both getters and setters.
You set a value by passing in
a second parameter to the method,
just like we did with
the style function.
And back in the console,
remember that you can always figure out
what functions or methods are available
by using the autocomplete feature.
We can save a selection to a variable,
and
then quickly see which methods
are available on that selection.