Now, we're going to add two
more checkbox preferences for
allowing users to toggle on and off
whether they see this treble triangle or
this midrange square.
Now this process is very similar
to the one that we just did for
the base circle checkbox preference.
So if you'd like some less guided
practice, go ahead, pause this video,
and try this one out on your own.
Otherwise, you can follow along with me.
I'm going to start off here in
this preference visualizer XML.
And I'm going to add two
new check box preferences.
Now that I have these
two new preferences,
as per best practices, I'm not going
to hard code any of these values.
Instead, I'm going to go
to the strings.xml file and
the bools.xml file to add
all of these new values.
So let's do that now.
Here are all of the new string values.
I have one for the label and
key for both of the preferences.
I'm also going to want to add two new
Boolean values for the treble and
the midrange.
To see some difference in
the default state of the app,
I'm going to set these two to false.
Now back at my XML, I can actually
start adding these values.
Okay, now that's done, my preferences
should show up on the settings screen.
And they do, but
this isn't affecting the app yet.
To do that, I'm going to need
to change my code in two places
here in the VisualizerActivity.
The first is onCreate.
Scrolling down,
in the setupSharedPreferences method
which is called from onCreate.
I'm going to change this setShowMid
call to look at sharedPreferences.
Here, I'm taking sharedPreferences and
calling getBoolean from it.
Passing in the key and
the default value.
I'm going to do the same for
setShowTreble.
All right, so
now when the app first loads,
it should have the correct preferences.
The other place that I need to
change the code is down here in
the onSharedPreferenceChanged listener.
I'm going to make two
additional if statements.
These if statements check
which preference changed.
And then the update the VisualizerView
in the exact same way that it was
updated up here,
instead of sharedPreferences.
And that's it.
Let's try running it.
This is looking good.
It looks like it's reading
the initial preferences.
Then here, if I change these,
it updated the preferences.
Awesome.