Now life gets uglier, rotation.
What I have here is a figure, or I think this is also from four-side composite
slides, and what I'm showing you is two coordinate frames, A and B.
And you'll notice that A has an I vector, a J vector and a K vector.
And B has an I vector, a J vector, and a K vector.
And one of the important things to realize is that this P value,
the vector from the origin, is, can be expressed in two ways.
It can be expressed as some components in the a frame times the x, y,
z components, or some components in
the B frame with the components in the x, y, and z frame, right?
They're the same vector, right?
And what's key is understanding that there are these basis vectors and
we need to know the amount of component that multiples each of them.
What we want to be able to do is say we're going to rotate the frame from A to
B, and that's what this says.
What this says is given my point described in A, I'm going to have a rotation
operator that would give me the P now expressed in the B frame.
And R A to B means describing frame A in the coordinate system of B and it says,
so if you gave me the location of a point in terms of the components of A,
this is and it's only a rotation after applying R,
I get the components in the frame B.