We just made our app write
messages to the database.
It's cool to see the messages showing
up in the database console, but for
friendly chat to work, our friends need
to be able to read those messages.
Right now,
our table of messages is empty.
It's as if our messages just disappear,
somewhere off into
the ether of the cloud.
Now in reality,
they are in the database.
But unless we visit the database and the
Firebase console, we're not seeing them.
We need to add code to the app so that
it not only writes it to the database,
but reads and
displays data from the database.
Reading data in Firebase works a little
different than the traditional method.
Traditionally if you
want to read some data,
you'd send individual request or queries
to read data from your data base.
If you think this data
might change often,
such as the contents of
the chat message list.
You need to keep requerying
the database to get new messages.
Firebase real time
database is different,
because it tells you
when the changes occur.
Instead of repeatedly asking whether
there are changes made to the data,
our code will be automatically
informed when data is updated.
With just a little work, we can handle
both downloading the existing database
as well as syncing any
future updates in real time.
We can do this by creating listeners
that are tuned in like a radio station
into specific locations in the database.
The listener is triggered once for
the initial state of the data and
again any time the data changes.
And once the listener is triggered,
it completes any task that you specify.
So let's see what this listener
looks like in Friendly Chat.