Now lets go into the specific things and
implement a banner ad in our app.
Here are the things we will do.
In android manifest, we will add
an activity called AdActivity.
Then its time to add code to
our Banner Activity to actually
display a banner ad.
Then, we will add our banner
ad to banner activity.
This involves adding a banner
ad to our layout file and
then adding code to display that ad.
Okay, so let's start to look at how we
add the AdActivity to our manifest file.
So if we open the manifest file,
this is how we add the AdActivity.
So you got the name of
the activity right here.
And then you have another attribute
called configChanges that you should set
to the following string.
So what is this activity doing?
Because, as you can see, it is not an
activity that we have created ourselves.
This activity is used in banner ads
to actually launch the ad viewing
in case the user clicks on the ad.
And it's used in interstitial
ads to actually display the ad.
So where we press the Show
interstitial Button here.
It is what makes this screen appear.
All right, so that's how we add
the AdActivity to the manifest file.
Let's now look at how we add
the banner ad to our layout file
in Banner Activity.
So if we open up the banner
activity layout file,
you can see that we've created
the standard relative layout.
And the thing that we've added
to display a banner ad is this
AdView element here.
This is the definition of the banner
ad that will appear in this
relative layout.
And as you can see,
we have many standard android
attributes here to control the layout.
And then we also have two
specific attributes here
that controls the banner ad.
First we have ads:adSize which
controls the size of the ad.
There are many alternatives you can
specify for the size of the ad and
you can look these up
in the ad size class.
We're going to use
a constant called BANNER and
then we have something
called adUnitId here.
So what is this?
We'll adUnitId is the ID
of an ad placement.
So if we go back to this picture,
the ad unit ID is something we
define in the AdMob interface.
So when our app is requesting
an add using a specific ad unit ID,
then AdMob will know which type
of add to serve to your app.
With an add unit ID,
you can also specify the media type
that the add should be in, if it should
be an image, a text or a video clip.
But wait a minute, you may say now.
We haven't set up any account in AdMob
yet, and we're not ready to display and
get paid for real ads yet.
We're just in development and
testing phase right now.
And that's correct.
So before we show you how to
move your app to production,
we will be using a test ad unit ID.
Let's go back to Android Studio.
So here's our definition
of the ad unit ID.
It's set to this string here.
And this particular adUnitId
is an ad unit ID for
banner ads that will serve test ads.
So this is the string that you
should use in your application now.
And as you can see, I've actually
not hard coded this string, but
it's a string resource.
So, in line with android best practices,
I've defined this string
resource over here in strings.
Here it is.
So now it's very important that you
enter exactly what it says here.
Otherwise this is not going to work.
All right,
let's go back to the layout file now.
And now there's only one little thing
left before we can start coding.
Notice that these things don't
have the usual android prefix.
They have ads as the prefix.
Well by default, the ad's name
space is not included here so
we also need to add this line up here.
This line gets the ad:namespace
into the layout file so
you have to add that
otherwise this won't compile.
All right.
That's it for the layout file.
Let's now switch to Java and
see how we code the banner ad activity.
And you may be amazed
how simple this code is.
The first thing we need to do is declare
this member here, which is an AdView.
And after setting our layout, we
retrieve this view using findViewById.
We then create an AdRequest
using a builder and
finally we load the adRequest,
into the view.
That's it.
With only those steps, we're able to
write an app that talks to AdMob and
gets us connected to a huge
advertising network that are eager for
you to show their ads and
are willing to pay for it.
So now it's your turn
to do these things.
Remember, add the AdActivity
to the manifest file.
Then, in the banner activity,
add the banner ad view to the layout and
then add the code to display the ad.
Check here when you are finished.
Good luck.