Given the non-optimality of depth-first search,
why would anybody choose to use it?
Well, the answer has to do with the storage requirements.
Here I've illustrated a state space
consisting of a very large or even infinite binary tree.
As we go to levels 1, 2, 3, down to level n,
the tree gets larger and larger.
Now, let's consider the frontier for each of these search algorithms.
For breadth-first search, we know a frontier looks like that,
and so when we get down to level n, we'll require a storage space of
2 to the n of pass in a breadth-first search.
For cheapest first, the frontier is going to be more complicated.
It's going to sort of work out this contour of cost,
but it's going to have a similar total number of nodes.
But for depth-first search, as we go down the tree, we start going down this branch,
and then we back up, but at any point, our frontier is only going to have n nodes
rather than 2 to the n nodes, so that's a substantial savings for depth-first search.
Now, of course, if we're also keeping track of the explored set,
then we don't get that much savings.
But without the explored set, depth-first search has a huge advantage
in terms of space saved.
One more property of the algorithms to consider
is the property of completeness, meaning if there is a goal somewhere,
will the algorithm find it?
So, let's move from very large trees to infinite trees,
and let's say that there's some goal hidden somewhere deep down in that tree.
And the question is, are each of these algorithms complete?
That is, are they guaranteed to find a path to the goal?
Mark off the check boxes for the algorithms that you believe are complete in this sense.