Let's think about the first point.
Our pendulum example is one where x and
y are different quantities.
However, this is not a strong argument.
Here our state can be precisely
computed using the observation.
It is merely a more
efficient representation.
However, there are other cases where
the difference between state and
measurement is more important.
You're looking at a clown juggling three
identical balls that you want to track.
You have an excellent detector that,
given any video frame,
spits out three x, y coordinates that
are the centers of the three balls.
This is your raw observation.
x1, y1, x2, y2, and x3, y3.
There is no guarantee that x1, y1
refers to the same ball across frames.
Clearly, you need something
more in your state model.
How about velocity?
Including direction and magnitude.
That would help you
predict better which x,
y belonged to which ball in each frame.
There are many other situations
like this where directly observable
quantities do not suffice
as the system state.
Therefore, the first point is valid.
More importantly, you need to
realize that detection techniques,
especially dealing with real world data,
are not always 100% accurate.
Noise can be introduced into
observations, due to various reasons.
Sometimes just the discrete nature
of digital images results in
observations that are not smooth.
It is best to take observations
with a grain of salt.
Remember the video where that
guy walked behind the pillar?
That's a missing observation.
If you didn't have anything
more in your state,
where would you say the person was?
Well you could say that is highly likely
that the person is nearby where they
were last seen, therefore the last
point is also a valid reason for
modeling these as
probability distributions.