Now that you've set up
the content provider,
it's time to build it up further.
You already know what
the task data looks like and
next you'll need to tell the counter
provider how to access that data.
Earlier, when you communicated with
the provider in the quiz example app,
you saw how you always needed to make
data request through a content resolver.
You'd call the correct action audit and
pass in the URI for
the data you wanted to access.
In general,
URIs tell content resolver two things.
First, which provider they
want to talk to, and second,
what specific data is being requested.
So when you build your
own content provider,
it's up to you to define URIs that both,
first identify your provider, and
second, identify each different type of
data that the provider can work with.
Now, for the To Do List app, we want to
access two different types of data.
The first is a directory of tasks,
and the second are individual tasks.
This way, we can do things like
display all of the tasks, and
we can also modify a task one at a time.
So we'll define URIs to distinguish
between these two types of data.
Now, there are guidelines for
how content URIs are constructed.
You've already seen a few
examples of this structure.
For example,
you see that all content URIs
start with a base that includes
a scheme, followed by an authority.
Then after that is the path,
that indicates the specific
data that you're interested in.
This is the portion of the URI that will
help the provider select the correct
data.
And this is the part
you'll need to define.
So let's define the URI for
accessing all of the task data.
This directory is a SQL
like table named tasks.
For consistency,
when you define the path for
this specific URI,
you should define it with the same name.
And the final URI should look like this,
the content scheme, authority, and
then the tasks path at the end.
A lot of providers will have multiple
directories of data to work with and
will therefore need multiple URI paths.
One example of this is
the CalendarContentProvider.
The CalendarContentProvider keeps
track with what's happening throughout
the year.
The provider works with
a number of separate tables.
There's a table for different calendars,
a table for the events themselves,
and a table to keep track of attendees,
just to name a few.
And it uses different URI paths to
distinguish between these directories.
This seems simple enough, but how
should we define the URI structure for
an individual item in a directory, or
for maybe a smaller subset of
rows in the large directory.
Well, in these cases,
you need to include more
information in the URI itself.
For example, in our tasks directory,
we might want to see the data
in the priority column only.
Or perhaps we want to point to
one row by its specific ID.
If I want to look only at the priority
column, I might to find the URI
that points to data by pending
the name of the column to my path.
This path tasks/priority has
the name of the task directory and
the column name priority.
So it includes all of the information,
a content provider would need,
to select data from the priority column.
Similarly, if I wanted to design
a URI for looking at a single task,
I could decide to have a URI that points
to that row by appending its unique ID.
This is a fairly common practice.
So if I wanted to access the second task
in this table, I'd append the ID 2, and
my path would be tasks/2.
If I wanted to access the row with id 3,
I'd use a URI like tasks/3,
row 4, /4, and so on.
For the task content provider to respond
to a single row of data like this, I'll
actually want to tell it when any URI
is pointing to a single task by its ID.
So potentially,
I could define a bunch of URIs,
a single URI for every row in my table.
But this would quickly
become pretty unmanageable.
What I could do instead
is to find a URI for
a single task using something
called a wildcard character.
This is the hash symbol seen here.
What this hash symbol stands for
is any integer number.
So as long as the URI has
a integer ID after its tasks path,
it will be recognized as a URI
that points to a single item.
Let's look at a few more examples of
URI structures that use these wild
card characters.