When data is placed in shared memory,
it can be concurrently accessed by
all processes that have access
to that shared memory region.
Therefore such accesses must be
synchronized in order to avoid
race conditions.
This is analogous to the manner in which
we synchronize threads when they're
sharing an address space, however it
needs to be done for processes as well.
So we still must use certain
synchronization constructs,
such as mute accessor
condition variables, for
processes to synchronize when
they're accessing shared data.
There are a couple of options
in how this interprocess
synchronization can be handled.
First one can rely on the exact same
mechanisms that are supported by
the threading libraries that
can be used within processes.
So for instance two pthreads
processes can synchronize amongst
each other using
pthreads mute access and
condition variables that
have been appropriately set.
In addition, the operating system
itself supports certain mechanisms for
synchronization that are available for
interprocess interactions.
Regardless of the method that is chosen,
there must be mechanisms to coordinate
the number of concurrent accesses
to the shared memory region.
For instance, for support for
mutual exclusion,
mutexes provide this functionality.
And also must, to coordinate,
when is data available
in the shared memory segment and ready
to be consumed by the peer processes.
This is some sort of notification or
signaling mechanism.
And condition variables are an example
of a construct that provides this
functionality.