Now it's time to create an ad unit Id.
So let's start by creating a banner ad
unit Id, by clicking on banner here.
So let's look at
the configuration options here.
The first thing we have is the Ad type,
which can either be text or
an image or both.
So in most cases,
we want to select both,
to have the highest probability
of finding a matching ad.
A text ad is typically
a clickable title with one or
two lines of text beneath it.
You can actually see
an example of it here.
An image hack includes graphic.
And you can specify multiple different
sizes when you define that in
the layout file.
Then we have the refresh setting.
This specify how often a new ad
impression should be generated.
You can select no refresh.
Or a refresh rate between 30 and
120 seconds.
The recommended is to use a refresh
rate between 45 to 60 seconds.
The text ad style allows you to
customize how text ads are displayed.
So they look good in your app.
You can choose a standard layout but
you can also customize it.
With your choice of colors.
I'll just choose Standard for now.
And finally, we have the Ad unit name.
This is just a name that helps
you find the Ad unit ID later.
Now we click Save.
And as you can see,
this gives you an ad unit ID.
That you can use in your application
to display real advertising.