The first code snippet will print 2,
3, 4, 5.
I haven't shown you the plus
equals operation before, but
it will modify the existing array.
So, before you run this line, both a and
b will point to the same array which
contains the elements 1, 2, 3, and 4.
Running this line updates
the values to 2, 3, 4 and 5.
So now if you print a or if you print b,
you'll see the same result,
the array 2, 3, 4, 5.
The second code snippet, on the other
hand, will print 1, 2, 3, 4.
Once again, a and
b start off referring to the same array.
1, 2, 3, 4.
However, the plus operator without
an equal sign first creates a new array.
The values in the new array are 2,
3, 4, and 5.
Then setting A equal to this new array
updates A to refer to the new array.
B still refers to the previous
array which has not been modified.
So when you print B you
get the output 1, 2, 3, 4.