Hopefully the lesson one, stage one wasn't too difficult, but
let's work through the solution here.
First, in defining your execute method, scroll down to the execute method,
uncomment the line that takes in a tuple, gets the string at position zero,
and names it word.
We check if the word is present in the map.
If it's not present add the word with the count of one.
Countmap.put(word,1) else the word is already there, hence get the count.
Integer val equals countMap.get(word) and increment the count and
save it to the map.
With countMap.put, word, and increment the value by one.
After countMap is updated, emit the word and
count to the output collector by uncommenting the line, emit collector.
That takes in the values, word and countMap.get, word, which is our count.
Once that's completed in part two of three, we need to scroll down to our
declareOutputFields method and simply uncomment the outputFieldsDeclare,
that calls method declare with new fields word and count that we just emitted.
Finally, for part three of three, scroll down to our topology builder section
and here we have our builder.setBolt, with an ID report bolt,
which is a new report bolt with a parallelism of one.
Finally, remember from our quiz that we want a global grouping, so
we have .globalGrouping.
Which takes in a component ID, CountBolt.
To visualize this, this is our Spout, here is our CountBolt and our ReportBolt.
Using the same color scheme as our quiz.
Note we have our field grouping connecting the Spout to our Bolt,
CountBolt and finally a global grouping.
Which takes all streams from the count bolt to the report bolt, and
finally our report bolt connects to our visualization.
With your Flask microserver running, go to your command line, lesson2 stage1.
Do a mvn package.
Once you see build success, I'm going to clear this.
Submit your topology using the command storm jar target/udacity hyphen.
Remember that we, and hit tab.
Remember we want the dependencies in our jar.
Udacity.storm.WordCountTopology with camel case.
And we see as our storm topology runs, we switch to our visualization, and
we see that the name and size are linked to the count.
So as our topology runs longer, the count increases and the names get bigger.
Great. Congratulations on finishing stage 1.
Your coach now match stage 2.