So for this exercise, since the UI stay
the same, it will show all the rows
in the pets table and all the columns
for each pet and then the cursor return
by the query method should contain all
rows and all columns of the pets table.
So starting from the beginning
in our catalog activity we're
going to delete our raw query method.
Now next I'm going to
define my projection.
Remember that my projection is a string
of array with the column names that I'm
interested in.
And then this case,
it's going to be all of them.
I'll then pass the projection
into the query method.
So, let's setup the call
to the query method.
So, in this case no selection is needed.
So, I'll set these values to null and
the remaining parameters
will also be set as null.
So, those are the three
changes we needed to make.
And as you can see, the query
method well return back our cursor.