Testing takes time, so why do it?
The testing process has a few goals.
The first is that the software matches
whatever requirements it was supposed to
meet, these are usually outlined
in the specifications document.
Second, testing is meant
to ensure software quality.
And finally you test software so
that if you find a bug and
you resolve it, you know that
it's not going to come back.
Unfortunately for all of these, they're
actually impossible to guarantee.
It's not actually possible to test all
ways to use an application, for example,
to test in all environment settings.
You also can't prove that
a program is bug free.
What is possible is that you can
show the existence of a bug, and
then once you've found that bug,
remove it.
The first goal when deciding
any sort of testing suite
is to make sure that the desired
functionality works correctly.
Given that you can't test everything,
you first focus on testing
a positive scenario.
This is a scenario where everything goes
as expected and there are no errors.
Because of that, this is called testing
a happy path through the software.
But of course, it's also important
to test what happens when
incorrect inputs are given.
You never know what users are going to
input into your system, so
you have to test this as well.
Another important
testing methodology idea
is to ensure that once you
fix a bug it doesn't return.
It gets annoying for both users and
the development team to keep fixing
the same bug over and over again.
So, if a bug is found in
the manual testing process once,
the developer should come along and
fix that bug.
The developer should then also add test
cases to the automated testing process.
This way you know that the bug will
not be reintroduced at a later time.