Previously we'll learn about compression
resistance and content hugging.
Let's look through them again.
Content hugging means how much
a view will resist being stretched
beyond its intrinsic content size?
Since the text field was
the one that gave in and
stretched, it probably means it has
a lower content hugging than the label.
Compression resistance,
on the other hand, is how much
a view will resist being squeezed.
Again, it was a text field.
This probably means it has a lower
compression resistance than the label.
Let's make sure our
assumptions are correct.
The text field has a compression
resistance of 750,
and a content hugging of 250.
So it's obvious why
the text field stretched,
but why did it shrink later on?
Both views have the same
compression resistance.
The reason why auto layout shrunk
the text view is because doing so
wouldn't make it smaller than
its intrinsic content size.
The label is at its
intrinsic content size,
while the text field is much bigger.
It still has space to spare, and
therefore, the text field
is the one that shrinks.