Three.js gives you a bunch of ways to form rotation matrices. Here's what one of
them looks like. A rotation around the z axis. The Greek letter theta is the
angle of rotation. The cosine and sine of this angle are used to form a somewhat
symmetric piece of the matrix here. The rest of the matrix is left alone by
leaving these values in the third row 0 and this value here being 1 this has the
effect of leaving the z coordinate untouched. This makes sense since when you
rotate around the z axis the z values shouldn't change. Here's a real rotation
matrix around the z axis. For rotation angle of 53.1 degrees. As an example the
coordinate 1, 0, 0 transforms to the coordinate 0.6, 0.8, 0, the coordinate is
rotated counter clockwise around the origin. One way top look at things is the
rotating a point from one location to another. Another way to look at it is that
you're changing the frame of reference. The rotation transform can also be
thought of taking original point. I'm looking it up to see what value it has on
these two new axis. For example on our new x axis the point's coordinate is 0.6,
on our new y axis the point's coordinate is 0.8, on the left we're rotating
coordinate with respect to the axis. On the right we're rotating the axis and
then seeing where the coordinate lies with respect to these axis'. Either
interpretation is correct and both have their strengths. If we rotate the first
interpretation so that the x and y axis are aligned with the second, we see that
the transformed point is in the same orientation to the axis in both cases. This
second interpretation is the one that helped me understand how a dot product is
rotating a point. And in earlier lesson, we've talked about how the dot product
between two normalized vectors gives us the cosine of the angle between them.
Rotation is a similar use of the dot product. We use the cosine of the rotation
angle to give us two new axis, both of which are normalized, that is the links
are both one. The dot product between our test point coordinates, and each
rotation axis gives us the coordinate of the new location. For example, 0.6 is
here, and 0.8 goes over here. A dot product projects one vector onto another,
which is what gives us these coordinates. That was a simple test case where the
vector to our test point was of length one. If we do the same analysis for
another point, we get the same result with both ways of thinking. Here's a new
point, which has the same location on both of our graphs. On the left, we rotate
the point to its new position. Then read the coordinates off of its axis. On the
right, we rotate the axis and read the points coordinates with respect to these
axis. For example, here's X's and Y's. The way we read off these coordinates is
to take a dot product between each axis and the vector to the point. So here's
our x axis and here's our vector. And we take a dot product between the two to
get this value here. This is what a matrix does. It computes a dot product. When
we use the dot product for materials both vectors were normalized. Here our axis
is normalized, but the vector to the point is not. The vector here could be of any length.