This final question is motivated by structure from motion,
and it's not the full-blown structure from motion problem,
which is hard to do on a piece of paper here.
But it's a variant event for which I know the motion but not the structure.
Suppose we are given two cameras,
and we happen to know there are three features in the scene.
All three features can be scene by both cameras.
This camera will see a feature on the left, in the center, and on the right--L, C, R.
This camera is camera A.
One camera B, we also see a feature on the left, center, and right,
but I don't know the identity of those features, which I will call 1, 2, and 3.
Suppose in camera A we see from left to the right the following sequence: 1, 2, 3.
These are the features numbers.
So in the left camera we notice that the left-most visible feature is feature 1,
the center feature is feature number 2, and the right feature is feature number 3.
I'm going to ask what is the order of those pixels in camera B,
assuming that the features are located as shown over here and so are the cameras.
Please give the index of the features over here that clearly have to be 1, 2, and 3
in some order which you have to determine.
For a different configuration let's now assume we get to see 1, 2, 3 in camera B,
and we care about the feature indices we see in camera A
that corresponds to those features over here.