You can think of the terminal as an
alternative interface to your computer.
The terminal interface uses
text instead of graphics,
but that doesn't mean it's
fundamentally less capable.
Many of the things you
use a computer for
don't really require a graphical
interface, it's just that graphical
interfaces are the most common
interfaces for desktop programs.
And some things are even
easier to do in the terminal.
So, given what you've seen thus far,
which of the following activities do you
think can be done readily
using the terminal?
Can you edit and run a program?
Is it possible to find files on your
computer that have particular names?
Do you think it's possible to download a
file from the web, if you know its URL?
Could somebody edit a major motion
picture using the terminal?
Could you start a web server
on your own computer?
Could you start a web
server in the cloud?
And lastly,
could you break the entire Internet?
Mark the boxes for the ones of these
things that you think could be
reasonably done using the terminal.