The two most important
kinds of objects in
a Linux server's filesystem
are files and directories.
You've been working with files
already throughout this course.
So files are probably nothing new.
And directories are almost exactly
the same as folders that you've probably
seen on a Windows or Mac system.
They're named containers
that can hold files and
can also be nested inside
other directories.
Every object in the file system
has a name or a file name.
The rules for file and directory
names in Linux are pretty flexible.
You can have spaces and filenames,
you can have dots, you can at signs or
accent marks or whatever.
The only thing you can't
have is the slash character.
And in the shell, when you write a file
name that contains spaces or certain
punctuation marks, you have to put
the file name in quotes, or else precede
each one of the special characters
including spaces with the back slash.
So for instance,
if you had a file whose actual file
name was Great space Filename!
When you're talking about
that file in the shell,
you would write it either
as 'Great Filename!' or
as Great\ Filename\!
This is called Quoting and
this is called Escaping.
The reason for this is that these
characters all have special meanings to
the shell, and putting a backslash in
front of them tells the shell to treat
them as ordinary characters.
Directories are nested inside
each other, with the outermost or
topmost being the file system root or
root directory.
It's very common for
there to be multiple discs or
disc partitions on a Linux system.
Unlike on Windows, there aren't separate
roots for each disc, like C: or
D: drives.
There's just one filesystem root
at the top of the filesystem.
This means that no matter what directory
a file is in, you can unambiguously
refer to that file by giving the full
path which starts at the root and
lists each directory on the way
down to the individual file.
The directory names
are separated by slashes.
So, for instance,
here's a file called auth.log,
which is inside a directory called log,
which is inside a directory called var,
which is inside the root directory.
So to give the full path name,
we start at the root /var/log/auth.log.
Now if you're coming from Windows,
be careful.
Linux uses the forward slash
to separate directories,
whereas Windows uses the back slash.
The forward slash is the same
one that you see in URLs,
like https://udacity.com, or for
writing fractions like 2/3,
or in various other uses.
So now it's your turn.
For each one of these other files,
fill in the full path name based on
the directory structure and
the filename itself.