Let's revisit the example from
the beginning of the lesson, and
try to put in the context what's
happening using JavaScript code.
Now if you don't remember,
the scenario we had was whether or
not to purchase an item from the store.
To make this a little more realistic,
let's say the store I'm purchasing
the item from is JD's Department Store.
Let's say the item that I want to
purchase is a hammer, and
let's say it costs 15 bucks.
I'll update this flow chart and, okay,
there we go, that looks a little better.
We've got purchased hammer
from JD's Department Store.
If we got enough money,
yes, buy the hammer.
If we don't, don't buy the hammer.
So the real question here is, do we have
enough money to purchase the hammer?
And to answer that question,
we need to know two things.
We need to know how much
money do I have, and
how much money does the hammer cost.
Now we already know that
the hammer costs $15, so
in code, I can store that value
in a variable called price.
So let's do that right now.
Okay, so I've got my text editor open,
and we'll say var price = $15.
And that's going to be the price
of our hammer, all right.
And let's say, I have $20 on me, and
we'll store into another code called
money, and set that equal to the $20.
So this is how much money I have, cool.
This gives us enough information
to answer whether or
not I have enough money
to purchase the hammer.
But in order to represent that question
in code, we'll need to use a comparison.
If you remember back to
the last lesson of data types,
we can use a comparison that
compare two strings or two numbers.
So for this situation, I'll write
my comparison to see if my money
is greater than or
equal to my price of the hammer.
Now by itself,
we know that this expression will
either evaluate the true or false.
If it evaluates to true,
then I know I've got enough
money to purchase the hammer.
If it evaluates to false, then I'm out
of luck and I can't buy the hammer.
But this code doesn't really
do anything for us by itself.
So here's where things
get really awesome.
We can actually represent
this question and
both possible results using
an if else statement.
So let me type that out, and
then explain what's going on.
Okay, so the way this code reads
is if money is greater than or
equal to price, then we'll want to
print out, buy the hammer.
Otherwise, or else, we'll want to say,
don't buy the hammer.
So what this actually means is,
if our money is greater than or
equal to the price,
run the code inside these curly braces.
Otherwise, run the code
inside these curly braces.
Now pay attention to the curly braces
here, because they're super important.
Whatever code is written inside of these
things is going to be the code that's
executed when our condition is either
true, like it is up here, or false.
Also, notice how I've
indented the code over, so
you can tell what part of our
code belongs to which block.
The code here belongs
to our if statement.
to our else statement.
So to show you this code working,
I'm just going to copy and
paste it over the JavaScript console.
We paste it in, awesome.
That's what we expect to see.
So our money, which is $20 is
greater than or equal to the price.
So it hits this conditional statement
because it's true, and it prints out,
buy the hammer.
And just to show you that it
can work the other way around,
let's redo the same code, but let's say,
it's $10 that I have instead of 20.
Awesome, then it prints out,
don't buy the hammer.