All right.
That ends, the lesson on RANSAC, the subunit on
fitting models based on features, and in fact, the entire unit on features.
This kind of work, finding features, figuring out how they match,
is, pervasive in sort of geometric computer vision.
The computer vision that talks all about how cameras align, and scenes, and
depths, and, and, and points.
And, so they, they, they use a lot, these days,
because of the, just how ubiquitous, imagery and, and video is.
and, because these, these methods are sort of powerful and
real, and not just myth, they are used in lots of real applications.
So, I expect that if you end up doing any work,
that involves dealing with multiple images and
trying to figure out something about the relationship between them,
that you will actually see things like, PARIS detectors,
things like the SIFT descriptors and certainly things like the RANSAC alignment.