We've seen how to put
a reference in our scripts.
Now, let's use that reference
to create new objects.
We're going to use the reference
as a placeholder for
any object we want to drag
in from the Unity editor.
Our script will use this
placeholder to create new objects.
Okay, let's do it.
Go to the start method and
write the following code.
Great, now save your script and
go back to Unity.
Go ahead and press Play,
and you'll see that
a new cube appeared with
the position of 2, 4, 6.
That's 2 in the x-axis,
4 in the y-axis, and 6 in the z-axis.
What's happening here is that
your code is creating a copy
of whatever object you dragged
into the object create slot.
And it's placing that
copy at position 2, 4, 6.
Pretty cool, right?
If you don't see the second cube,
then go back and double check your code.
Make sure you created a 3D cube and
dragged and
dropped it into the object create slot.
Also, you can see the full
code in the text notes below.
All right, let's take a look
at the code and break it down.
We start with Object.Instantiate.
This means that you're calling
the instantiate method on the object
class and if that doesn't make a lot
of sense, don't worry about it.
Methods in class are just
programmer jargon and
you'll need to learn them, but,
for now, let's do a quick review.
Remember the classes from
the Unity Scripting Manual?
We found the classes by going
to Unity Engine &gt; Classes.
Well, you can find the object
class inside the manual
by doing a quick search.
There it is.
When you scroll down you'll
see the instantiate method.
It's right here.
You can see that this
method clones an object.
In our case, it's cloning the reference
object that we drag and dropped in.
Okay, let's look at the next part
of our script, objectToCreate.
Well, that's just the name of
the reference you created.
You're telling Object.Instantiate to
create a new object that is just like
the one you picked in the Unity Editor.
Okay, that's simple enough.
The next part is new Vector3, 2_4_6.
Okay, now this might look a little
strange, but it's not that bad.
This is just how you code
positions in 3D space.
Let's talk about Talk
a little bit more about this.
Vector3 objects hold three numbers,
an x coordinate, a y coordinate,
and a z coordinate.
You almost always need to create a new
vector3 whenever you want to specify
a location in 3D space.
So, going back to the code,
this code here just says,
place the new object at position 2,
4, 6.
The last part is quaternion.identity.
Which I know sounds very strange,
but this part is just telling Unity
how to rotate the new object.
And let's talk a little bit
more about Quaternions.
Unless you're a math expert, you've
probably never heard of a quaternion.
But you're probably familiar with
rotating things using degrees and
radians.
Well, quaternions are just another
way to think about rotations,
and Unity uses them because they're
way better for 3D simulations.
Unity hides all the complicated
math from you, but
you do need to know rotations are all
handled internally using quaternions.
Let's go back to the code.
In this case, quaternion.identity
just means no rotation at all.
The identity quaternion is the rotation
that keeps the object identical.
So this line tells Unity to create
an object with no rotation at all.
Okay, well, that's how it all works.
And it may seem like a lot of
work just to create another cube.
But once you understand the principles,
you can do amazing things
with these simple tools.
Okay, next up, let's start doing
more powerful stuff with code.