It's time to make sure the new Recording
Label and Stop Button stay in the
correct position and size at all times.
Much like the original Record button,
we need to add constraints to these two
interface elements. Before we get started,
I'm going to hide away our debug area and
go back to our standard editor view mode.
Now we have to think about what we
actually want, which is three UI elements,
one beneath the other, centered on screen.
They should always be centered, regardless
of running the app on a small iPhone or
on the new iPad Pro. Now we already have
the Recording Button centered on the
main UI view of our View Controller. So we
can anchor the other two views off of
the recording button.
let's start with Recording Label.
Remember, the Recording Label is the one
that's with the text Tab to Record.
In the document editor, with the Recording
Label selected, let's control drag
diagonally to the Record button. So I'll
hold down the control key and I'll click
drag diagonally to the Record button. And
let go. The menu that pops up is context
sensitive to the direction of the drag.
If I was just to have done a straight up
or down or left or right drag, you're
only going to get a subset of the
constraint options shown here. Now with the
shift key held down, let's select
Vertical Spacing and Centered
Horizontally. And then add the
constraints.
This means that we want to maintain the
vertical spacing from the recording
button to this label and that we want
the label to be centered horizontally to
the Record button.
How does AutoLayout know where the label
needs to be on screen.
Well it's going to check where the Record
button is, and then it places the label
based on that using the two constraints
that we've just set up. If you remember
back earlier, how I mentioned that there
are two constraints needed for each axis.
Two for the x and two for the y. You're
correct. However, the label, much like the
button, has an intrinsic size.
So AutoLayout can figure out the height and
width of the label
based on the text and font of the label.
All we need to do is provide where to
place it along the x and y axes, or in
other words, just one constraint for the
x and one constraint for the y. Ok let's
set up the constraints for the Stop
Recording button against the Recording
Label. Once more, in the document outline,
select the Stop Recording button and
then we want to hold down the control key
and click drag diagonally to the
Recording Label. Again we’ll select
Vertical Spacing and Centered Horizontally.
And then add our two
constraints.
Now in the document outline, if we click
the disclosure triangle next to
constraints, we should see that there are
six constraints defined for our view.
If I select one of our Vertical Spacing
constraints and then I look into the
utilities panel, I can see the amount of
spacing between the two controls where
the constraint was made, in this case 8.
Your constant number may not be eight,
but that's perfectly okay. It's based
upon where you place the UI elements in
the storyboard when you initially drag
them in.
Ok let's see if our constraints worked.
I’ll click the Run button or you could
press command+R. And we should see the
Pitch Perfect app running in the iOS
simulator. Great, our controls are
centered. And if we change the
orientation, they remain centered in the
simulator. They should also be the case
if we were to run the app on a different device.
Great job
It seems like a lot of work for a small
payoff, don't stress. The more that you
use AutoLayout, the more comfortable
with this process you’ll become.