So far, we have learned a lot of
different fun things to do with images.
Now let's get to an even more
interesting topic, and that is how to do
similar kinds of things of both analysis
and synthesis, but apply to video.
The simplest way of thinking
about it is, images over time,
a sequence of images forms a video.
In this lesson, I'm going to
introduce a variety of methods or
representations that will let us do
the same kinds of things that we've done
with images, but the constraint of time
or sequence of time will be added to it.
But look at the representations and
actually start thinking about how we can
apply some of the things we have learned
in respect to images applied to video.