The algorithm you've analyzed for
reductions and
broadcasts is a tree-based scheme.
You showed that it was
sub-optimal in the beta term.
What that really means is that
it's a perfectly fine algorithm,
as long as the messages are small.
But what if you care about
the case when n is very large?
After all,
if beta is much smaller than alpha,
then you can utilize a network bandwidth
better by sending larger messages.
Let me turn this question around on you.
Why is the beta term so large?
That is, can you explain to
me intuitively in English,
what is the problem with the algorithm
that leads to this extra factor of log P
communication?
Type your explanation here.
Note that the question is somewhat open
ended so I'm not necessarily looking for
a fixed answer.
Well actually, I am looking for
a fixed answer, but
I want to see what you come up with.