So can we extract
the general rule from this?
So if we have a learning rate sequence
that looks like one over T to the K.
This is going to work for
some range of K's right?
>> Right.
>> So we saw that with K is too big then
it fails because everything
sums to something finite.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And
if it's too small, then it fails because
everything sums to something infinite.
So what's the range of Ks
that's going to work here?
>> Right, so there's two things.
So we should be able to back into this,
right.
So we know that the exponent will go
to infinity, which is what we want for
K, if it is one or less, right?
So K has to be less then or
equal to one.
>> Good.
>> We want one over T to the K squared,
also needs to be greater than one.
>> Hm-mm.
>> So since it's an exponent,
that would be two K, so
that would be two K greater than one.
Is that right?
>> As long as it's bigger than
a half it's going to work.
But if it's equal to
a half it actually fails,
because then when we square it we get
one over T which has an infinite sum.
>> Right.
>> So we have to have,
it has to be strictly greater than
a half, but it can be less than or
equal to one.
>> Okay, any particular reason why
you'd pick one over the other?
Some particular value
of K over the other?
>> That's a good question actually.
The, for the purposes of what
we're talking about now, no but
there are actually some interesting
results in the literature where you can
run into trouble with things like K
equal one, that it's a little bit too
unstable and you want something a little
bit lower to smooth things out better.
>> And
where does that instability come from?
Its just come from,
it's just close to the edge.
>> Yeah, I think so.
>> And so if you're very unlucky in the
things that you see, it might blow up.
Is that the problem?
>> Well it's not a practical issue.
It's just that there are some formal
cases where you can show that one over T
has some bad properties.
>> Okay.
>> But in practice?
Well interestingly in practice,
it's very common to use
things like this last line.
[LAUGH] Alpha T equals one over 100.
So even though that doesn't
really work with the theory,
it tends to learn faster and
you don't have to tweak it to figure
out well how fast should it decay?
You just you know, pick a number so
that things move around a little bit and
then you just kind of
be content with it.
>> Okay, so why would that work?
Why would one over 100 work then?
>> So there's a sense in
which it doesn't, right,
because it will cause
this to not to be true.
The limit ST goes to infinity of this
sequence of estimates that we get.
Doesn't go to V.
But it does go to something you know,
okayish.
So here's one way to think about is,
if you put, make a little plot.
Time is going this way, and
this is our estimate of the value.
And here’s V, what we want to go to.
What these conditions guarantee is that
we hone in on V, as we go to infinity.
If we don't do this, if for example,
we use a learning rate like
one over 100, then we can get
a different kind of behavior where it
doesn't actually decay enough over time.
So it's going to stay in some
kind of neighborhood of V, but
it could wiggle up and
down you know, by some amount, and this
amount doesn't necessarily get smaller.
So we're kind of wobbling around
inside of, here it's an interval, but
kind of in general,
a ball around the target value.
>> Okay does it get there faster or
anything?
Is there any reason why that's okay?
Is it just that you know,
the ball's small enough.
>> I think that in practice what happens
is it's hard to guess exactly you know,
the ideal way of decaying it and
so if you don't decay it,
it does tend to pretty quickly get
inside the ball and then wobble around.
Once you're inside the ball and
you're sure you're inside the ball,
then you can imagine doing a decay.
You can like switch over to you know,
one over T to the two third or
something.
So that it actually decays
out a bit more of the way.
But if you do that prematurely,
it still will converge in the limit.
It just could take a very,
very long time.
>> Okay, that makes sense, cool.