The, the answer for this one is simple.
If you look at it here, there is a gradient change.
So, if I'm going up there,
all of a sudden there was a big change and then back to zero.
This one, again, shows a negative.
So, this one is A.
B has a lot of noise.
But, it's not enough, and
you can actually kind of see a replica of this thing, except with a lotta noise.
There is signal, there's a little bit of hump, end coming up,
and there's a little bit of hump coming down.
So, while there is significant noise here, it's not enough, and
you can most probably detect it, but it's going to be hard.
But if I really increase the 0.25, all of a sudden you notice,
there is just no information here that allowed me to kind of look for
a sudden gradient change, which is where, perhaps, an edge would be.