Of course, the correct answer here is 8 bits.
And the way to think through this in the binary world is 2 raised to the n,
where n is equal to 8.
Would give you a value of 256,
which basically will allow us to have values from 0 to 255.
Different types of images do have different ways or different number of bytes or
bits of information we would use.
We could actually imagine a binary image
which bit allow only basically looking at values of 0's and 1's, and
that would be a binary image or a black and white image.
Of course, we can imagine also having images 2 raised to the 24,
where a lot more information is stored beyond just 0 to 255,
and I"ll actually be showing an example of that a little later.