All right, welcome to Computer Vision.
We're going to talk today about perspective imaging.
Before we talked about sort of different geometry and configuration of cameras.
And today what we're going to do is we're going to do the math behind that.
In particular, even though we talked about all these different problems and
different ways lenses work, etc, today we're going to sort of retreat to
the pinhole model, sort of take the academic route of take a simplified model.
So we are not going to talk about things like focus or
other non-pinhole effects.
Remember pin-hole camera, all the rays are in focus.
At some point we might talk about fixing lens distortion,
which is something you don't get in a real pin-hole camera.
But the reason we're doing that is to try to make our images be more like they
were generated from just some really uber pin-hole camera.