Yeah, it's quiz time.
So here is pseudo code for
an algorithm that I claim will gather
all elements that are less than or
equal to some pivot value, extracting
them out of this input array A.
The algorithm stores the output in
another array L, returning it here.
Take a minute to ponder this algorithm
and then answer the following question.
So if I take this for and
I replace it with a par for,
will the computation be both correct and
efficient?
Your choices are yes, the algorithm
will be both correct and efficient.
Or, the algorithm will be
neither correct nor efficient.
Actually, if it's not correct you don't
care whether it's efficient or not.
So no just means it won't be correct.
So choose one.