We've gone through backbones
template function,
now I want you to write
your own template function.
Your function must have a set of default
delimiters, allow for custom delimiters
to be passed in, handle simple
replacement and return a function.
The returned function should be
called with data to be inserted into
the template.
And the number of times the template
should be logged to the console.
For example if I have this template,
I should be able to pass this
string into your template function.
Your template function should
then return a function.
I should be able to call that
function passing a data for
each one of these variables.
The last argument to your function
is the number of times it should log
the completed template to the console.
So let's see how it should work,
I'll pass the string to the template
function and get a function back.
Then calling the function with data and
a number, logs the message to
the console that number of times.
Don't forget that your template function
needs to be able to handle custom
delimiters.
This is definitely a challenging quiz.
Filling out your own templating function
will help nail down how this works, and
it lets you build up a collection
of code that you've written,
that you can use later.
If you're ready to tackle it,
click the next button.
If you need a hint stick around for
a second.
Still here?
Okay, I didn't use any regular
expressions in my solution.
Instead I use a combination
of JavaScript split and
indexOf methods to search for
a delimiters.