All right. If you had actually been here while we were recording this,
you would have seen that I just walked around the room 17 times trying to get my
act together.
because I started to talk about this and my, my tongue just [SOUND].
But, but here goes, okay?
Couple things, all right?
So, this relationship here,
that's the relationship that happens algebraically between corresponding points.
p and p prime are the image points of the same point outside in the world.
Now, we remember from our epipolar geometry, so like that's over here, that if
I've got some point let's say it's right here in the image, I know that that's
on this ray somewhere and therefore that point must be on that epipolar line.
That was the geometric constraint that we had derived earlier.
So the p transpose Fp prime equals 0 is the algebraic one.
The drawings that the epipolar lines is the geometric one.
But clearly, they relate.
So you'll remember from our projective geometry little tutorial that we
said that the equation of a line, right, could be written a couple ways.
I'm going to write it this way, p transpose l equals 0.
All right?
Remember l was the, that normal to the plane, and all the points p
had to be on that in that plane, and would be perpendicular to it.
So notice, here we have p transpose, here we have this p transpose,
here we have this l.
Here we have that l, that it here we have that Fp prime, okay?
These equal 0's align, that's the constraint that has to equal 0.
What this means and that's what's written here is that this l,
which is Fp prime is actually the epipolar line in the p image, okay.
So remember it's mol, I'm going to to erase this, right?
It's going to be multiplying a point in the p image.
So l equals Fp prime is the epipolar line in the p
image associated with the point p prime.
Also just reversing this, that means that F transposed p is the epipolar
line in the prime image, the p prime image associated with the point p.
All right?
So what the fundamental matrix does is it
gives us the epipolar line constraint between two views.
So if I know what F is I can compute the epipolar lines.
In fact, you can just for a given point I just take F transpose p and
that's the epipolar line in the other image.
And that makes sense because the F is what we said deri,
takes all of the, goes through the intrinsics of one,
through the extrinsics, the intrinsics of another.
And so the only thing I don't know for some point that I'm seeing in the,
in my left image is well, since I don't know its depth along that ray, I,
it has to be along this line, that was the geometry.
So, the fundamental matrix equation reduces that
geometric constraint to an algebraic one.
The great thing about video's you can go back and take a look at this.
We'll also, in the class notes,
there'll be some pointers to some texts where you can look at it and
learn it from people who are way more articulate than I am.
But that's relationship between the fundamental matrix.
And the epipolar lines.
Go back and look again.
Do it again. Okay, so now you're here and now you're really got it,
you understand it all, so you should really teach this class but I'm stuck here
on this side of the screen, you're stuck there so I'll keep going, okay?
Great.