One common way that developers go from a
starting concept to a polished final app
is to have a visual model
in mind as they go.
To create a cohesive design for
your app, it's a good idea to draw out
a model of what you want
your final app to look like.
In fact, it's often the job of
a designer to create these models,
which are referred to as mock ups.
A mock up is a model of an Android app
that's used for design evaluation.
It's usually a picture or
animation of the final app.
And detailed mock ups include
specific colors to use, and
markings called keylines.
Keylines are used to
specify the exact size and
spacing for components in an app layout.
Then, for every detail that's
provided in a mock up,
it's your job as a developer to
implement that in the app code.
You might be wondering how a designer
makes these decisions about layout and
which colors and fonts to use.
And in general, they follow something
called material design guidelines.
Material design for Android is
a set of principles and guides for
creating useful and beautiful visuals
and interaction across platforms and
devices.
And next, we'll go over these
guidelines for choosing color and
fonts that work best for you app.