Let's say we have a bright edge
that we can see at time t.
The same edge at time t plus 1
has clearly moved to the right.
Now when analyzing the optical flow
here, you might think, what aperture?
Is there a magical green donut
that is forcing you to look at
small parts of the image at a time?
Well no.
It's because with the brightness
constance equation,
we're trying to analyze
each pixel at a time.
We look at the image intensity
at that specific location x, y.
How that changes from
time t to t plus 1.
The horizontal and
vertical image gradients again,
at that specific location, and
we try to compute the displacement u,
v, for that particular pixel.
Since there is no actual
approacher limiting your view,
how would you improve this approach
to get the correct optimal flow?
Think about what additional
constraints you might be able to use.
For instance, do you think nearby
pixels move together, that is,
in the same direction and
roughly the same amount?
And can this be used to optimize
our optical flow computation?
Similarly, can we say that motion over
an entire image should be consistent?
Or should we just look at
distinct regions, like corners?
Select the choices that you
think are valid and useful.
Anything else?
Mark other and enter it in the box.