We'll look at the problem of scheduling a series of tasks, each of which has duration.
We'll show a task network which has a start and a finish date,
and then has a sequence of tasks, which have to be completed
and arrows to indicate precedence of which ones have to go before other ones.
This task has to occur before this one,
but there's nothing said about the relationship between this task and this task.
We'll list for each task their duration.
This one takes 30 minutes, 30, 10, 60, 15, and 10.
Scheduling then is a process of figuring out a schedule under which
we specified the times at which each of these tasks starts
such that we can finish as soon as possible.