First, upload the malware
disguised as an app
without authorization bypassing
the review and check process.
We know that's not possible
given the restricted
app distribution model by iOS.
Second, uploading an app that
after it passed the review process
morphed into malware.
This is possible and, indeed, this is
the method that the researcher had used.
In the spirit of full disclosure,
I was one of the researchers.
A link to an article about the research
can be found in the instructor's notes.
Third, uploading an app that led users
to a site that contained malware.
This is not the method
that the researchers used.
In effect, iOS would prevent malware
from being downloaded from a site and
run on the device.