Okay, so now you're well on your
way to use ads in your app.
And the time has come to implement,
an interstitial ad.
So to implement the interstitial,
here's what we'll do.
We will implement the interstitial
activity that will contain two buttons
for the initial text, Load Interstitial
and Interstitial Not Ready.
The Load Interstitial button
will have a call back method
called loadInterstitial.
When this method is called,
we will disable the button and
then change the takes to
Loading Interstitial.
The other button will have
a property in interstitial activity
called mShowButton.
It's callback method
will be showInterstitial.
And for the first part of this we
will leave that implementation empty.
As you can see, when the activity
is loaded, this button is disabled.
Therefore, we will set it
to disabled in onCreate.
And finally for this first step,
we will create a string
resource called interstitial_ad_unit_id.
This string resource we will
set to the following value.
And as you may have guessed, this is the
test ad unit ID for interstitial ads.
So let's look in more detail how
these things are implemented.