Before moving on with the discussion
of the spin lock alternatives that
are presented in Anderson's paper,
let's do a refresh on multiprocessor
systems and
our cache coherence mechanisms.
This is necessary in order to
understand the design trade-offs and
the performance trends that will
be discussed in this paper.
A multiprocessor system
consists of more than one CPU.
In some memory that is
accessible to all of these CPUs.
The shared memory may be
a single memory component that's
equidistant from all of the CPUs.
Or there will be multiple
memory components.
Regardless of the number
of memory components,
they are somehow
interconnected to the CPUs.
And in this figure, I'm showing
an interconnect based connection.
And this is more common
in current systems.
Or a bus-based connection, which
was really more common in the past.
Also note, here I'm drawing
the bus-based connection to apply to
a configuration where there is
only a single memory module.
However, the bus-based configuration can
apply to both of these situations and
vice versa.
The one difference is that in
the interconnect base configuration,
I can have multiple memory
references in flight.
Where one memory reference is
applied to this memory module and
another one to the other memory module.
Whereas if I have a bus-based
configuration in this case,
the shared bus, only one memory
reference at a time can be in flight.
Regardless of whether these references
are addressing a single memory module or
are spread out across
multiple memory modules.
So the bus is basically shared
across all the modules.
Because of this property that
the memory's accessible to all CPUs,
these systems are called
shared memory multiprocessors.
Other terms used to refer to shared
memory multiprocessors are also
symmetric multiprocessors,
or for short, SMPs.
In addition, each of the CPUs in these
kinds of systems can have caches.
Access to the cached data is faster so
caches are useful to
hide the memory latency.
The memory latency is even more of
an issue in shared memory systems
because there is contention
on the memory module.
Because of this contention, certain
memory references have to be delayed.
And that adds to the memory
latency even more so than before.
So it is as if the memory is
further away from the CPUs
because of this contention effect.
So when data is present in the cache,
the CPUs will read data from the cache
instead of memory, and
that will have an impact on performance.
Now when CPUs perform a write,
several things can happen.
First, you may not even allow
a write to happen to the cache.
A write will directly go to memory and
any cached copy of that particular
memory location will be invalidated.
Second, the CPU write may be
applied both to the cached
location as well as directly in memory.
So this technique is
called write-through.
We write both in the cache,
as well as in memory.
And finally, on some architectures
the write can be applied in cache.
But the actual update to the appropriate
memory location can be delayed and
applied later.
For instance, when that
particular cache line is evicted.
We call this the write-back.