Handling the Intent in
the Intent Service requires a few steps.
First, you'll get the activity
recognition result from the Intent.
Luckily enough,
that can be easily extracted using
the .extractResult() method
on ActivityRecognitionResult.
This result will give you an array
list of detected activity objects
when you call the getProbableActivities(
) method on it.
Once you have this,
you need to create a new Intent on
which you're going to send the results.
It's good to give it a name
with the package of your app or
something like that added to it,
something that's easily recognizable.
You should set this up as
a constant in a constants file.
Once you've got this new Intent,
you can then add the detected
activities array list onto it.
And finally, use a LocalBroadcastManager
to broadcast the Intent so
that it can be picked up.
Go ahead and
implement the on handle Intent override
now, doing all of these steps.
You'll see the solution to
this in the next video.