So here's what your
code should look like.
In your onCreate method,
you're just going to create
a StreetViewPanoramaFragment.
You're going to initialize this by
calling
getFragmentManager().findFragmentById,
very similar to what you do for
typical controls.
And then you just pass it the ID of the
fragment, earlier I called my fragment
streetviewpanorama, and
that's the ID that I pass in here.
Now once you get your
streetviewpanorama fragment, you then
call the getStreetViewPanoramaAsync,
passing it this class.
And this will setup
the asynchronous callbacks for
whenever the streetviewpanorama
is ready.
And then the callback you @Override,
and you just call it
onStreetViewPanoramaReady, and it takes
a StreetViewPanorama as its parameter.
And here you can see I've
just called that panorama.
On panorama, you then call .setPosition,
and you pass it a latitude and
longitude.
This is the latitude and
longitude of the Grand Canyon.
You then create a camera, and
very similar to mapping applications,
you create a StreetViewPanoramaCamera
using a Builder.
And then you just set its bearing and
other parameters that you like, but
I've just set its bearing to
be pointing at .bearing(180).
Once you have the camera,
you then animate the panorama to
that camera with a duration, and
here you can see, it's 1000
milliseconds, it's as simple as that.
If you want to have a little bit of fun,
here's a couple more locations
you can take a look at.
This location on the left, at 41.89
12.49, is the Colosseum in Rome.
And this location on the right, at 51.17
and -1.82, is Stonehenge in England.
And this is all it takes, implement this
code if you haven't done so already,
and you'll have a street view app
that allows you to virtually hike
in the Grand Canyon,
in the Coliseum, or in Stonehenge.
What types of scenario
could you use this in?
The possibilities are endless and
I would love to see what you build.