The last paper talked about threads in a generic way.
It described multithreading concurrency synchronization in more generic terms.
In this lecture, we will talk about PThreads, which is a very concrete
multithreading system, and it's the defacto standard in UNIX systems.
First off, PThreads stands for POSIX Threads.
POSIX stands for
Portable Operating Systems Interface, and it basically describes the interface,
the system call interface, that operating systems need to support.
And its intent is to increase interoperability among OSes.
Within POSIX, PThreads describes the thread and
correlated API that operating systems need to support, in order for
creating and usage and management of threads.
And this includes both the threads themselves, as well as the synchronization
and concurrency related construct such as new texts and condition variables.