Here's an example of spelling correction in action.
Take the word w equals "thew,"
and we want to find the correction c
that maximizes the probability of w given c times the probability of c.
We start searching for the possible corrections c
that are close to our target word "thew" in terms of added distance.
That is, first we start with all possible c that are one letter away,
replacing one letter, swapping two letters, inserting one letter, or transposing two letters.
And here we have a list of a few of those possible corrections.
So it could be "the" by deleting the "w.
We could do no correction at all; we have to consider that as one of the possibilities.
We could replace the "e" with an "a."
We could add a "r."
We could transpose the "w" and the "e."
Then we look into our spelling correction tables,
and again we reduce them from a word-based to a letter- or edit-based,
and we say what's the probability of inserting a "w."
Here we've conditioned the insert not just absolutely of inserting a "w" anywhere,
but for insertions and deletions, we condition them on the previous letter.
So what's the possibility of inserting a "w" given that the previous letter was an "e?"
It turns out that's what the probability is,
and then we go through the list.
Here's replacing an "e" with an "a."
That's one of the most common edits made in English,
one of the most common spelling corrections.
A 10th of a percent of all spelling errors are mistaking an "e" for an "a,"
and similarly down the list.
So we get this probability for the probability of w given c,
and then the probability of the correction word c,
that we just get by looking up in our corpus how many times we have seen this word
and applying whatever smoothing we're getting.
Then we multiply them all out, and I've scaled these by a factor of 1 billion.
It turns out with the model I've built that "thew" is most probably corrected to "the."
And that makes sense.
It's easy to imagine your finger slipping off the "e" key and going over to
the "w" since they're next to each other,
and "w" is a very common word in English.
But it's troubling that the second possibility,
namely leaving "thew" alone and keeping it as is has such a high probability.
Now, it turns out "thew" is a word.
It's rather archaic. It does show up in the Shakespeare corpus.
It has to do with muscle tissue,
but it's a fairly uncommon word,
and how high it ranks depends in large part on the probability that we assign
to this edit of doing nothing at all.
Here I've assigned it a probability of 0.95.
That is, I've said for my probabilistic model,
I've made this choice to say I think that about 95% of the words are spelled correctly
and 5% are spelled incorrectly.
You have to make that choice in order to have a complete model.
The probability distribution has to be spread out over all possible,
and they have to sum up to one, so I've got to put it somewhere.
If I had made another choice, then these two could have been swapped around.
So the answer you get depends on the assumptions you make.
Still, we can have spelling correcters that are highly accurate.
This very simple model of just looking at unigram possibilities
and looking at the edits achieves accuracy in the 80% range.
If we go beyond that and start dealing with Markov assumptions
and looking at multiple word sequences, then we can get up into the high 90%.