Good work.
At this point, you've made your first
preference and read it into the app.
Now, I did take you through the shortest
path to get something working and
appearing on the screen.
Why don't we now try to clean up
the code with some best practices?
The first thing is that we should
have been using string resources from
the strings.xml file for
all of our preferences.
So, in our strings.xml file,
I'll add those two new strings.
One for the key and one for the title.
Notice that I've set the translatable
to false for the key string,
because if I ever do localize my app,
I don't need to waste the translator's
time translating keys that
are never even visible to the user.
Also, I don't want changing the language
to affect what name the keys are saved
under.
Next, I'll go into our
preference visualizer XML and
start using those strings.
I'll do that by just replacing
the hardcoded strings
with the ones that we've created
in our strings resources.
Now let's do the same for
the summary off and on.
The first thing is we just add
them to the strings resources.
And then we can replace those hardcoded
values to the string resource values.
And finally, make sure that you
use the string resource for
whenever you refer to this key,
show_bass.
Like for
example in the visualizer activity,
you should replace this string
literal with our new resource.
What this does is it allows me
to reference the string resource
inside the code, which foolproofs
the code against sloppy typing, and
it makes changes in
the future a lot easier.
Now, for the default value,
I'm still using this literal true.
We can actually define boolean constants
the same way we define string constants.
Let's create a new bools.xml file
under the values resource folder.
This file will be used to store
constants that I can refer to later.
So, inside that XML file,
I'll put a constant for
whether the bass should be
shown by default or not.
I'll go to our preference visualizer and
change that default value,
replace it with the bool resource.
And then in the visualizer activity,
also replace this hardcoded true
with the resource we just created.
And then finally,
I'll just run the code to make sure
there weren't any regressions.
[BLANK_AUDIO]