The next step is to have a way to turn
off the recording once you started
recording something. For that, you'll need…
you guessed, the Stop Recording button.
Will also need an IBAction from the
Stop Recording button to the View
Controller code. To create this action,
make sure you're in the assistant view
with the storyboard and the
ViewController files open. Control drag
from the Stop Recording button to the
ViewController.swift file.
Select the option to create an Action
and let's name this action stopRecording.
In this action, let's add a
print out so that we know the button was pressed.
We should be able to run the
Pitch Perfect app now. And if we press
the Stop Recording button, we’ll see our
print out in the console.
Let's give it a try. And there's our
print out. We're almost there, the next
step is to add constraints to our new
label and button, and then to wire up
some more IBOutlets so that the
recording and stop recording buttons are
not both enabled at the same time.