So at this point, you might be thinking,
another middle man class?
Why would I want to take
the time to create this?
Well, app developers create content
providers for a few reasons.
Reason number one,
as an extra level of abstraction,
they allow developers to change the
underlying data source without needing
to change any code in the applications
that access the content provider.
The second reason is that some important
android classes such as loaders and
cursor adapters use content providers.
So, say you want to use a loader,
you need make your data accessible
through a content provider.
But really, the main reason
you use a content provider,
is to open up the data source
to other app developers so
that they can access, use,
and modify your data source.
If you didn't use a content provider,
this data would be
limited to just your app.
And when other apps are using your
content provider to access your data,
they're doing it in a secure and
managed way.
This is because the content provider
is a single class through which
all data requests can be made.
So you can add a code to
that class to sanitize and
protect your data as needed.
So let's see how this helps
in the business card example.
Here, we have our card.
Now, if we weren't using
the contacts content provider,
we might store our data
in a separate database.
This is no good because your
phone's default contact
app can't access the data over here.
So, instead what we do is use
the contacts content provider and
give the business card info
to that content provider,
which then updates the data source for
contacts and saves it in the database.
Then when the default contact app
loads up the contact information,
it'll give the information
from your business card.
So, instead what we do is use
the contacts content provider and
give the business card info
to that content provider,
it then updates the data source for
contacts and saves it in the database.
Then on the default contact upload
of the contact information,
it'll give the information
from your business card.
And really, all you had to do was pass
off your business card information to
the content provider.
This whole process was black
box from you so it's easy.
As a developer, all you need to do here
is change a couple of app permission and
a few lines of code.