If we know that a quadratic equation has some number of solutions with an
imaginary component, then it has to have two of those kinds of solutions. So, in
other words, it has to have two complex solutions neither of which has a
coefficient of b equal to 0. Let's look at the quadratic formula to think about
why this is true. And the quadratic formula gives us solutions that are in this
form. Let's write out the two solutions separately for the time being. Written
out like this, we can see what may have seen hidden to you little bit before.
The only difference between this solution and this one is that there is a plus
here between the negative b and this part, and there is a minus here between the
negative b and this part under the radical sign. Now, since we know the
imaginary part of our solution has to come from this part with the radical, and
what will happen, of course, only at the discriminate under here is negative.
That means, that these signs that are opposite one another are separating the
real component of either solution from its imaginary component. That means, that
any time we find imaginary solutions, or complex solutions with nonzero
imaginary components for a quadratic equation, those 2 complex numbers are going
to be complex conjugates of one another. This is super powerful, super potent.
We're going to continue to think about this concept through many of the coming
lessons.