To show how probabilistic games work,
I've invented a version of
isolation called sloppy isolation.
In this game, players may not
actually move where they intended.
For example,
if our player is trying to go to here,
he only has an 80% chance of
hitting the square intended.
There's a 10% chance that the player
will undershoot its goal.
And there's a 10% chance, the computer
player will overshoot its goal.
But suppose a computer player is in a
place where moving is very constrained.
For example,
here If the computer player is moving to
the right it can't go beyond the border.
In that case, there's a 100% chance
it'll land on the intended square.
If the computer player is trying
to move to the last square here,
there's a 90% chance of it
hitting it's intended square, and
a 10% chance of it falling short.
Similarly, if our computer player is
just trying to move over by one, There's
a 90% chance it'll hit the square at
once, and a 10% chance it'll overshoot.