Here's where the code starts.
There's a select tag here indicating
that this is a drop down and
there are a few options inside.
And this is what it looks
like as a datalist.
The differences are pretty minimal.
Starting right here you can see that the
select tag turned into a datalist tag.
I added a list attribute to the input
with the same ID as the data list.
And I changed all the option values
from inert HTML text to values.
And once again here's
the finished data list.
I like it, these are super useful.
All right, well next up,
you're going to watch the next
part of the interview with Luke.
This time, he'll be talking
about what makes a perfect form.
Let's watch.