Before we saw that you can include
information from a sequence of data
using a recurrent connection
on the hidden layer.
This connection goes
through these weights, Whh.
If we enroll the network,
we see that the hidden layer sub t
is a function of the previous hidden
state multiplied by those weights.
And the output from that layer
is again multiplied by Whh.
For every step you have in the network,
you're multiplying by
the weights again and again.
And when you're doing backprop,
that's even more multiplications.
This leads to a problem where
the gradients going through the network
either get really small and vanish or
get really large and explode.
This happens because if you're
multiplying by some number a bunch of
times, you're going to get two results,
except in a couple special cases.
If that number is less that 1,
you'll end up at 0.
If it's greater than 1,
you'll head towards infinity.
This happens to gradients
in a normal RNN.
They'll either vanish or explode.
This makes it difficult for
RNNs to learn long range interactions.
Luckily, there is a solution.
We can think of recurrent networks as a
bunch of cells with inputs and outputs.
Inside the cell you have
your network layers,
such as the sigmoid layer
labeled with a sigma here.
To solve the problem of
the vanishing gradients,
we can use more complicated cells called
long short-term memory, LSTMs for short.
Okay, LSTM cells are pretty
complicated at first glance.
But if you break it down into parts,
they aren't too difficult to understand.
The key addition here is the cell state
labeled C, I'll get into this next.
In this cell, there are four network
layers shown as yellow boxes.
Each of them with their own weights.
The layers labeled with
sigmas are sigmoids.
And tanh is the hyperbolic
tangent function.
tanh is similar to a sigmoid
in that it squashes inputs.
But the output is between -1 and
1 instead of 0 and 1.
The red circles are point-wise or
element-wise operations.
That is, they operate on
matrices element by element.
The main improvement here
is through the cell state.
The cell state goes through the LSTM
cell with little interaction,
allowing information to flow
easily through the cells.
The cell state is modified only
through these element-wise
operations which function as gates.
And the hidden state is now calculated
from the cell state, then passed on.
The first gate is the forget gate.
The values coming out of the sigmoid
layer are between 0 and 1.
Then, they are multiplied
element-wise with the cell state.
So values from this layer close to
0 will shut off certain elements in
the cell state.
Effectively forgetting that
information going forward.
Conversely, values close to 1 will allow
information to pass through unchanged.
This is helpful, because the network can
learn to forget information that causes
incorrect predictions.
On the other hand,
long range information that is helpful
is allowed to flow through freely.
The next bit updates the cell state from
the input and previous hidden state.
The tanh layer output is
added to the cell state,
again, gated by a sigmoid layer.
In this way, the cell state
can be updated in the step and
passed along to the next cell.
Here, the cell state is used to
produce the hidden state which is sent
to the next hidden cell as
well as to higher layers.
It's the arrow pointing up here.
The cell state is passed through
another tanh then gated again with
another sigmoid layer.
All these sigmoid gates let the network
learn which information to keep and
which information to get rid of.
Putting all this together, the LSTM
cell consists of a cell state with
a bunch of gates used to update it,
and leak it out to the hidden state.
This is just the basic LSTM.
There are multiple variations and
a lot of ongoing experimentation
into improving these.
They are also easily
stacked into deeper layers.
You just send the output from one
cell to the input of another.
Okay, so now you might be wondering how
all of this fixes our gradient problem.
Since the cell state is allowed to flow
through the hidden layers with only this
linear sum operation.
Gradients can easily move through
the network without being diminished.
You also get gradients added into
the network through the LSTM cells but
they're just added to
the gradients flowing through.
I'm not going to get into
the math behind all this.
I'll link you to some resources such
as a great lecture by Andre Carpathy to
help you out there.
LSTMs are the basic unit of
recurrent networks these days.
You don't have to completely
understand the inner workings.
But knowing how they work
conceptually will be important.