Right, my next question is
about support vector machines.
Let me draw a two dimensional
support vector machine scenario.
Our data samples are laid
out on this 2D space.
I'm going to use + signs for
the positive examples.
And - signs for the negative examples.
And as you might know support
vector machine tries to find
like a boundary that
separates these two classes.
Now my question for
you is what is the value or parameter or
function that the support vector
machine is trying to optimize for,
either minimize or maximize?
>> The support vector machine is,
thank you,
trying to operate on a boundary.
And saying based on this
boundary on either side of where
I decided to draw my division.
I want to minimize the number
of misclassifications.
Based on the training set,
where's the line I can draw such that
I minimize the number of positives
on this side of the boundary, and
negatives on the other
side of the boundary.
>> That's a very good starting point.
As you can see in this example, the
support vector machine still have a lot
of freedom, in terms of where
it places the decision boundary.
What else is it trying to look for
or strive for?
>> Okay, so since there is a little
bit of freedom of movement like
this line could have been drawn,
anywhere in sort of this space and
still correctly classify all of
the data that we have in this set.
We're going to try and
draw the line such that
the distance between the classification,
between these labels
is sort of optimal for
all of these samples.
>> Would you say that the algorithm is
trying to minimize these distances or
maximize these distances?
>> It's trying to keep the distance
from either side about the same.
>> Okay, that's a very good point.
In essence, the decision boundary
that comes up is sort of in between
opposite examples that
are fairly close together.
Cool, do you know what
the samples that are close
to the decision boundary are called?
>> No, I'm not familiar with that term.
>> Okay.
It's that's where sort of the term
support vector machine comes from
because these points are referred
to as support vectors.
In some sense they are supporting
the decision boundary.
The other examples that you see
are not really affecting where
the boundary lies.
>> Okay.
>> Cool, so one follow up
question would be what are some
domains in which support vector
machines could be useful?
>> Yeah, definitely, so support vector
machines have multiple use cases.
Especially when your data clusters
around a certain value and
it is easy to create a boundary between
multiple classifications of data.
If this were, let's say,
an image classification and
these were pictures of dolphins and
these were pictures of cats,
we might see some very apparent
differences between the two.
And the support vector machine
could easily determine
the difference between the two.
But let's say we were looking at
wolves and we're looking at dogs.
We can imagine cases where
there is some very, there's
dogs that look a lot like wolves and
wolves that maybe look a lot like dogs.
There would be a lot of
misclassification along the boundary.
And a way to work around that,
you could possibly see if you can tweak
the kernel of your SVM such that instead
of let's say like a straight line,
it can have some curvature to it, or
try and use a different machine
learning algorithm completely.
>> That's a very good point.
SVMs, although they're very popular
in machine learning are still they
can't be directly applied
to all scenarios.
Very good.
>> Thank you.