For continuous integration
to work effectively,
there are actually several requirements
that have to be met first.
Now, these requirements fall to two
categories, technical and behavioral or
cultural.
Let's take a look at
the technical requirements first.
The first requirement is that the code
has to be in some sort of version
control system.
Version control allows your team
to track changes as well as
easily roll back to
a previous version if needed.
In the context of continuous
integration, it also allows us to
automatically trigger a build
phase after a change is detected.
And speaking of the build phase, there
must be an automated build process for
continuous integration.
The purpose of integrating changes for
different developers is to make
a working piece of software.
If it doesn't even build,
it's not exactly working.
To be able to test whether code builds
automatically when the code has been
changed, the build process has to be,
well, automated.
The build process also serves
as the starting point for
the next step, testing.
And speaking of which,
this means that you also have to
have automated tests in place.
As a minimum, your developer
should be writing unit tests.
Preferably, you also
have acceptance tests.
All these together allow for
regression testing which basically means
that the functionality that the app
currently has doesn't break
when you submit a new change.
Now testing is a pretty large
topic in and of itself, so
we're going to talk about
this in more detail later on.
For now, just think of
the testing in general terms.
If there are no tests, it's impossible
to know if the software actually works.
You could do manual testing, but
manually testing every functionality
after every code check-in
would be very time consuming,
inefficient, and pretty boring.
Finally, it should be easy to see the
build and test results for each commit.
The feature in many continuous
integration systems is a dashboard
that will show all builds and
their status as well as detailed logs.
Everybody who's involved in the process
should have access to the dashboard.
This also manifests in
another common approach
which is to have the build
status visible in the office.
For example, your team could consider
putting up a big TV with build
statistics on it, or
even having a colored light or sign.
And this sums up the technical
requirements for continuous integration.
But beyond that,
there are also cultural requirements
that you should be thinking of.
And these are requirements that
have to be true about the team and
people that you're working with.
The first of which is that changes
have to be checked into a code
base frequently.
This is preferably happening
several times a day or
at the very least once a day.
If developers have a habit of working
on separate feature branches for
a long time without
committing their code,
it will make it that much harder to
integrate back into the code base.
And therefore, continuous integration
in general is going to be difficult.
When developers
are integrating code back in,
they should also be including tests.
Another important cultural requirement
is what happens when a build is broken.
So if a developer breaks a build,
either the build process itself or
the automated tests,
it has to be the priority for
the whole team to fix the build
before any other work can be done.
A broken build is a reason for
developers and
testers to communicate,
figure out, and fix the problem.
Your team should see this as an
opportunity to improve the quality for
the entire product, and not a reason to
blame someone for breaking something.
Now sometimes, a build won't be able
to be fixed in a timely manner.
In this case,
the change has to be rolled back.
And rolling back essentially means that
you go to a previous working version.
What it's hardly better means
is dependent on the team.
But the rollback time should be
standardized for the team and
it's usually between 10 and 30 minutes.
Finally, the team needs to
agree that commenting out or
deleting a broken test just to fix
a build is not acceptable behavior.
If a test is broken,
it's either because the code is wrong or
the test is wrong, and
that has to be fixed properly.
If these requirements, both technical
and cultural, are not met for
a project,
they have to be implemented first.
For example, you could try to
run contiguous integration
if you didn't have automated tests.
But it wouldn't be nearly as effective,
and that's because the only thing it
would guarantee is that it's
possible to build the app.
But sometimes you might be
missing a lot of requirements for
continuous integration.
And in this case, you can start the
implementation process by just having
an automated build and then working on
adding something like tests later on.
In addition, there are also some
nonfunctional technical requirements
that should be taken into account.
And those are that
the builds have to be fast.
The build takes a long time to finish.
Developers are not going to want
to check in their changes often.
Checking in the changes will either
mean waiting a really long time or
being pulled back to fix a build after
they've already invested time working on
the next feature.
And similar to builds, the test
also have to be reasonably fast.
Test can be run in parallel for speed.
They can also be subdivided into stages
so that faster tests, like unit tests,
can run first while longer running
acceptance tests run later.
Once your project gets
sufficiently large,
it might make sense to take a step back
and see if you need to optimize for
build and test speed optimization.