self-driving car engineers today used
two distinct approaches to autonomous
development a robotics approach and a
deep learning approach the robotics
approach uses output from a suite of
sensors to directly measure the vehicle
surroundings and then navigate
accordingly self-driving car engineers
have been working on and perfecting the
robotics approach for many years
more recently engineering teams have
begun to use deep learning as a
different approach for developing
autonomous vehicles deep neural networks
allow self-driving cars to learn how to
drive by mimicking human driving
behavior both the robotics and deep
learning methods are actively being
pursued today in the development of
self-driving cars so in this nanodegree
program you'll be working with both
approaches that way you as an engineer
will be prepared to work anywhere by the
end of this program will be teaming up
with other students to actually write
both robotics and deep learning code to
control a real self driving car pretty
cool along the way you work through
several modules with each one focusing
on a different layer of the self-driving
car technology stack and after each
module you'll build a project to
demonstrate what you've learned and
you'll get real human feedback on your
work this first module that you're going
through now is smaller and should only
take a week or so to complete later
modules will be longer and may take up
to a month in addition to receiving
human feedback on your project you'll
also have access to the forums where you
can ask questions and get to know your
fellow students and of course our team
is here to help you succeed so be sure
to reach out and keep in touch