Shorter's job considers the execution
time of the tasks in order to decide how
to schedule tasks, and
when to preempt a particular task.
Another criteria for
driving those decisions may be that
the tasks have different priority.
Tasks that have different
priority levels,
that's a pretty common situation.
For instance, we have certain operating
system level threads that run OS tasks,
that have higher priority than
other threads that support,
maybe user-level processes, or
even within a user-level process,
maybe certain threads that are intended
to run when there is user input.
Such threads may have higher priority
compared to other threads that just do
some background processing for
long running simulations.
In such scenarios the scheduler will
have to be able to run the highest
priority task next.
So clearly it will have
to support preemption.
It will need to be able to stop a low
priority task and preempt it, so
that the high priority one can run next.
So, let's look at now at
the same example from before,
except now we're going to
use priority scheduling.
And we need to know
the task's priorities.
And in this particular example,
the priorities P1, P2, and
P3 are such that the first thread,
T1, has the lowest priority.
Followed by the second thread,
so it's Priority, P2.
And then finally, the third thread,
P3, has the highest Priority, P3.
Again, we start with
the execution of T2,
since it's the only
thread in the system.
Now however, when T1 and T3 become
ready at this particular point in time,
when time is doom, we'll have
a very definite execution compared
to the shortest job first
with preemption scheduler.
So when we look at the priorities,
we see that T3 has the highest priority,
P3.
So when threads one and
three become ready and
they arrive at this particular moment,
thread two is first going to be
preempted and the execution of
the thread three will start.
So thread three has
the highest priority.
When thread three completes, at that
point thread two has the lower priority.
So we'll have to give
the CPU to thread two.
And now it's pretty unfortunate that for
thread 1 we'll have to wait for
all this time before it can execute.
But a priority based scheduling is only
going to look at the priorities of
the threads.
So thread 1 is not going to really
start running until the 11th second
in this time graph and
then it will complete at time
T12 as the entire schedule will
complete at that time as well.
In this example we were looking at this
table, but in principal, our scheduler
if it needs to be a priority based
scheduler, it will somehow need
to quickly be able to assess not just
what are the runnable threads in this
system that are ready to execute,
but also what are their priorities?
And it will need to select the one
that has the highest priority to
execute next.
We can achieve this by having
multiple run queue structures.
Different run queue structures for
each priority level.
And then have the scheduler
select a task
from the runqueue that corresponds
to the highest priority level.
In this case that was the P3.
Other than having per priority queues,
another option would be to have some
kind of ordered data structure.
Like, for instance, the tree that
resolve with the shortest job first.
However, in this case,
with priority scheduling,
this tree would need to be ordered
based on the priority of the tasks.
One danger with priority-based
scheduling is starvation.
We can have a situation in which a low
priority tasks is basically infinitely
start in a run queue just because
they're constantly higher priority tasks
that show up in some of the other
parts of the run queue.
One mechanism that we use to
protect against starvation is so
called priority aging.
What that means is that, the priority of
the task isn't just a fixed priority,
instead, it's some kind of function
of the actual priority of the thread.
Plus one other factor, and
that is the time that the thread or
the task spent in the run queue.
The idea is that the longer
a task spends in a run queue,
the higher it priority should become.
So eventually the task will become
the highest priority task in the system,
using this priority aging mechanism,
and it will run.
And in this manner,
starvation will be prevented.