The concept of stereo photography has
actually been around for a while.
And when we talked about cameras,
first we talked a lot about
different types of cameras.
Here is basically an initial type
of a viewer, invented in 1838.
Basically you would put
a stereo pair here.
You would take two pictures
of the same subject from
two slightly different locations.
And then use a viewer like this
that would only show to each eye,
the most appropriate view point from
that image, one that of, of the pair.
So this is a stereo pair image,
we'll talk about that in a bit too.
In this view where actually you'll
start giving you sense of depth.
Again, if these two images are captured
from approximately the same distances as
the two eyes would be.
This is earliest forms of stereo
viewers, and I'm sure by now there
are loads of additional types of
viewers out there in the market.
And again, just another example
of importance of stereo or
early 3D photographs, I mean here is
case of a stereo pair of our president
Abraham Lincoln he can
again as a stereo pair.