So, much like our ordered function
that we talked about earlier,
I don't think there
is a precondition for
this because we could take any kind of
vector whether it's empty or non-empty.
>> Okay.
So assuming that we got the type
checking handled for us, then as long
as we have that vector of integers
coming in we could always ask the
question whether or not it's ordered,
and expect to get
a boolean results back.
Does raise the question, though,
of whether a empty vector is ordered or
not.
Have any thoughts on that?
>> That seems like something, if it
wasn't stated in the requirements for
our system,
we could come up with a distinction for,
but-
>> Well,
our job here is to state what we
intend by this particular function.
We are essentially giving
instructions to the developers,
and we certainly wouldn't want
the end user to try to use this and
get some surprising results on
an empty vector for ordered.
So, what is your natural
feeling about whether the empty
vector is ordered or not?
>> I feel like it's ordered.
We don't have anything, so it's ordered.
>> Sure, sure.
And in fact, when we think about what
Jared was saying earlier about all the
elements are greater than, less than, or
equal to the one that comes after it,
well, that's true of an empty vector.
Okay?
So, we're going to hope that
our post condition for ordered,
when we write it down, will,
if we plug in an empty vector,
we'll get out a value of true for that.
Third step is the post condition for
ordered.
And this is going to turn out
to be the trickiest one, and,
but it is a pure program.
And for all pure programs what you're
really saying is what the relationship
of the output is to the input.
And I'm going to give you a couple
of hints on this one, okay?
One is you're going to
have to use a quantifier.
And what you can say about the value
of the ith element of the vector,
that is a typical element of the vector,
in what can you say about that in
relation to the value of
the ith plus first element?