The answers are, yes, the monkey has the bananas.
No, the box is not at C. It has been pushed to B.
Yes, the monkey is at B. Yes, the bananas are at B.
No, the height of the monkey is not high, because he climbed down,
which means that that the effect was that he is at height low.
But, yes, the height of the bananas is high, according to these definitions.
You would think once the monkey grasped the bananas and climbed down
that the height of the bananas should be low,
but if we look at the operator for climb down, it doesn't say that.
It refers to the monkey, but it doesn't refer to anything that the monkey is holding.
That kind of thing is difficult to express in the language of classical planning.
You could say that's a weakness in the definition of climb down.