The answers.
For P and P implies Q, we know that
P is true in these bottom two cases.
In P implies Q,
we saw on the truth table for
P implies Q is true in the first,
second, and fourth case.
So the only case that's true for both
P and P implies Q is, the fourth case.
Now, this formula,
not the quantity, not P or not Q,
we can work that out to
be the same as P And Q.
And we know that P and
Q is true only when both are true.
So that would be true only in the fourth
case and none of the other cases.
And now, we're asking for
an equivalence or
bi-conditional between these two cases.
Is this one the same as this one?
And we see that it is the same,
because they match up In all four cases.
They're false for each of the first
three and true in the fourth one, so
that means that this is going
to be true no matter what.
They're always equivalent,
either both false or both true and so,
we should check all four boxes.