Filling in the intermediate
values of this circuit,
I want you to notice something.
The first step produces sequences
where the first half increases, and
the second half decreases.
In fact, this observation leads to
a nice algorithm, so let's run with it.
Here's a sequence of 32 values
as shown schematically.
Notice how it starts increasing,
and then decreases.
Such a sequence is called bitonic.
Note that the word bitonic
contrasts with the probably
more familiar monotonic, or
even the more familiar gin and tonic.
Feel free to pause and
grab one of those if it will help
you get through this lesson.
But only in moderation.
Here's a more formal definition.
A sequence of values is bitonic
if it goes up and then goes down.
To be a little bit more precise,
the less than or equal to signs and
greater than or equal to signs indicate
that a bitonic sequence is initially
non-decreasing and
then becomes non-increasing.
Now that's not the complete
definition of bitonic.
There's one more condition.
If this up and down property holds
not for the original sequence, but
it does hold for
some circular shift of the sequence,
then the sequence is still bitonic.
Now that was a lot of words, so
let's look at some examples.