[Thrun] And the answer is 3, 2, 1. Let's just go through this.
Clearly the leftmost feature in camera A is 1, which corresponds to this point over here,
the center will be 3, and the right one will be 2,
as indicated in the table over here.
If we now look into imager B,
we find that the leftmost projection comes from feature number 3,
the center projection from feature number 2,
and the rightmost projection from feature number 1.
This is not the full structure from motion problem,
but it's a good exercise to understand how feature indices under known position A and B
and under known locations of the target features map to each other,
and it's good to understand the complexity of the structure from motion problem.