So Cameron, I think a lot of
the students who are taking the intro to
programming m degree may be
wondering why they should
begin their journeys as programmers
with this course which we designed for
somebody who is specifically looking
to be a front-end web developer.
>> That's a great question.
And first off,
I want to say that front-end web
development is just a lot of fun.
So I think it's a great
place to start off.
But it's also one of the few
areas of programming that is just
inherently visual.
Which means that anything you do,
any code you write,
any changes you make, will automatically
be visible inside a browsers.
And, for instance, later on in
the course you'll be learning Python.
And Python's great, but if you want to
show off Python, you're going to have to
show it to somebody who knows
what that code does because
otherwise it's just going to look like a
jumble of letters, numbers, and symbols.
But with web development, it's really
easy to share a website with somebody.
So it's a fantastic place to not just
get immediate feedback on the code that
you're writing, but also give you
a chance to share what you're doing.
>> Cool, I totally agree.
Front-end web development is really fun.
Lots of immediate, early rewards.
Cameron, can you talk a little bit about
what the students are about to see in
the very next video?
>> [LAUGH] Sure, so
in the next video you'll be learning
about the purposes of HTML,
CSS, and JavaScript which are the three
languages that go into web development.
And don't worry.
You might hear some terms you
aren't quite familiar with.
But really what you need to take
away is that HTML, CSS, and
JavaScript have different purposes
when you're developing a website.
And really for this course, for
this next part of the Nanodegree all you
need to worry about are HTML and CSS.
>> Right, we're not going to do any Java
Script in this Nanodegree, but what you
should take away is that awareness
that we were talking about earlier.
Knowing that Java Script exists,
means you know what to search for
if you decide to pursue front-end
web development in the future.