So what, really,
is a panoramic video texture?
As I stated, it's a combination of
two things we have looked at before.
Let's look at a specific example first.
This is actually a work that
was done by Agrawala et al and
it was published in SIGGRAPH in 2005.
So here you see this video, and
in this video you basically see in
the camera is being panned and,
of course, you can see the panning shows
that it basically is now a panorama but
if you notice, in this panorama,
it's not a static panorama.
The flags were moving,
and now, actually,
when you see here,
you also see the water is flowing.
When you get to the boats, and you look
at it carefully because of the wind,
the boats are also kind of
moving a little bit and
if you look at it very carefully,
the background, the traffic is moving.
So yes, it is a wide angle view but
each and
every element that is a dynamic
element in this wide angle view,
is actually dynamic, it's no longer
a static scene, those things are moving.
So a panoramic video
texture basically is
a video that has been stitched
into a single wide field of view.
As you noticed in this case,
I was moving the camera around, it's a
wide field of view image, or a video but
of course, the dynamic parts of
it are now video textures and
that's why they continuously play and
can play on infinitely long.
So now you actually have a view
that's dynamically evolving and
all the dynamic parts of
it are moving but still,
it's a much more wider field of view
than a single video would have been.