We're going to do our best to
layout exactly how LibGDX works and
how to build these games,
but we do have to start from some
baseline level of knowledge.
Or else, as Carl Sagan would almost
certainly not say, if you wish to make
an Android game from scratch,
you must first invent the universe.
Specifically, we assume you've
got a good handle on Java and
object-oriented design.
We won't do anything super crazy, but we
will be extending abstract classes and
implementing protocols
pretty much off the bat.
You'll need to be comfortable looking
up documentation and code snippets.
This course will teach you a lot
of the basic libGDX API, but
mostly this course contextualizes
the official documentation.
It doesn't replace
More practically,
you'll also need a computer where
you can install Android Studio, and
the computer literacy required for
that installation process.
If you want to test your
games on Android or
iOS, you really need
the corresponding physical device.
Games don't tend to
work well on emulators,
since they're relying on specific
hardware to make drawing fast enough.
Also, we'll be using the accelerometer,
and
that's awkward to use on an emulator for
obvious reasons.
That being said, we will do most of our
prototyping on the desktop build, so
you can definitely do this
course without a mobile device.
Finally, some real talk here.
I know that people take online
courses for all sorts of reasons and
in all sorts of different ways.
Hey, I make online courses for
a living, and even I don't finish
the vast majority of courses I start.
If you're just here to get the flavor
of game development, that's fantastic.
But if you're here to complete
the course from beginning to end, well,
you're going to have to write a lot of
code, learn a ton of new things, and
display some real resilience and grit.
You ready?