Okay so if you've followed all the
previous steps correctly you're going to
end up with source code
that looks like this.
First of all in your build.gradle file
you should see the entry here for those
services libraries, as we've discussed
and as we've been using all along.
Next in your AndroidManifest file
you should see a number of things.
First, you can see where I've
added the OpenGL libraries.
Second, you can see where the service
libraries have been added and
it's the same as you've been doing all
along when building applications that
use the services.
Third is the API key.
And if you remember from the early
example you created API key and
you were able to put the API key
in your meta data as shown here.
Now before you run this application, you
have to associate this application with
the same API key in the developer's
console, and I'll show that in a moment.
And then finally is
the user's permissions.
As you can see here,
we have INTERNET, ACCESS_NETWORK_STATE,
and WRITE_EXTERNAL_STORAGE setup.