To add actions to our notification, the
first step we'll need to do is inside
the NotificationUtils, to create
a method called clear all notifications.
This will basically dismiss any
notification that we've created
with our hydration app.
To do that,
we just call the getSystemService to
get the notificationManager again.
And then inside,
we can call the cancelAll method
provided by the notificationManager.
Inside ReminderTasks, we've
previously created this string here
which represents the action of
incrementing the water count.
We can reuse this action string
to handle when the user clicks on
the I DID IT action and that will
increment our water count for us.
But we still need to create a new action
for when the user clicks the NO THANKS.
So, let's create a new string
called ACTION_DISMISS_NOTIFICATION
to represent this new task type.
And then inside executeTask,
we can add this else if to handle this
new task type and clear all
the notifications if that was the case.
And then let's also clear
all notifications inside
the INCREMENT_WATER_COUNT method
to dismiss the notification after
we're done.
Now, to handle the action
buttons in the notification,
let's create two static helper
methods that will create and
return the appropriate action
instances for each button.
IgnoreReminderAction takes in a context
and starts by creating an intent using
IntentService class to relaunch the app
and execute a task in the background.
Since this is the ignore action,
we'll set the action of that intent
to dismiss the notification task.
And then, let's wrap this
intent with a pending intent so
it can be triggered by
the notificationManager.
And finally, let's create the actual
action instance from the intent,
along with a cancel icon,
and the label NO THANKS.
And then, we can return that
action we just created.
Now that we have a helper function for
ignoring the reminder action,
we'll create a very similar one for
the drinkWaterAction.
The only differences would be,
that we're setting the action
to ACTION_INCREMENT_WATER_COUNT.
Using a different ID for our pending
intent, along with the intent that we
just created, and we've also changed
the label and icon for this action.
Now the very final step is to add those
two new actions into our notification
builder.
One for the drinkWaterAction and
the other for the ignoreReminderAction.
Perfect, now it's time to test it and
see if everything works.
And now if I click
the TEST NOTIFICATION,
I did it seems to increment
the count perfectly.
And NO THANKS just dismisses it,
well done.