We will now summarize one
more time the steps involved
in developing RPC applications.
And this figure here will
serve as an illustration.
We have to write the .x file in XDR and
pass it through the rpcgen compiler.
That will generate a number of files.
The header file, the stubs.
It will generate even the skeleton for
the server.
And it will also generate an underscore
XDR file that has a number of helpful
marshalling routines.
For the server-side application,
the developer has to provide
the implementation of
the actual service procedure.
The square.proc_1, for
the first version, _svc.
This is the naming convention.
On the client side, the developer has
to develop the client application and
whenever necessary,
call the wrapper procedure squareproc_1.
This is what will actually invoke all
of the communication with the server
process and the execution of this
particular service implementation.
The developer has to make sure
that he includes all of .h file,
particularly the auto-generated
ones from the rpcgen compiler.
And also that it links the client and
the server code with the stub object.
The RPC runtime that is called
from the stub things, provides
all other functionality, including
interactions with the operating systems,
creating sockets, managing connections,
and everything else.
I should point out that, that rpcgen,
when used only with the flag -C
generates code that's not thread safe.
The output of the compilation results in
a function that will need to be called
with something like this.
And the problem with this
function is that internally,
the implementation of this operation,
as well as at the runtime level, there
are a number of statically allocated
data structures included for the result.
And this leads to race conditions when
multiple threads are trying to make RPC
calls to this routine, concurrently.
To generate thread safe code, the code
must be compiled with the -M option,
and M stands here for
multithreading safe.
This will also create a wrapper
function squareproc_1, however,
it has a different signature and
its implementation differs, for instance
it will dynamically allocate memory for
the results of this operation.
So some of the issues that are coming up
with the previous implementation will
not come up in this case.
>> Using the -M flag doesn't actually
create a multithreaded server,
the implementation that's provided,
that generated in the _svc file.
That won't be multithreaded.
On Solaris platforms there's another
option, -a, using this option,
that actually generates
multithreaded server code.
But in Linux,
this option is not supported and
any multithreaded server
has to be created manually.
Of course, with using the multithreaded
safe routines as a starting point.