I have to tell you this
worked extremely well.
These are some examples taken both from
their original paper and some others, so
they were showing it running on
all of these different images.
Some of which are shall we say,
you know, typical computer vision images
where the face is right there,
some of them are much harder, right?
Now you'll notice, and we'll get to this
in a minute, that this guy is missed.
You know why he's missed.
It's not, because he's not good looking.
I have no idea whether he's good
looking, that's up to you guys.
It's because he's turned this way, and
the thing was trained on frontal faces.
Here's some more examples.
You know, I love the Star Trek one
that it worked really well, but for
some reason Scotty there, James Doohan,
I don't know if it's the mustache,
whatever it is.
This thing likes Vulcan's more
than it likes Scottish people,
can't explain why?
But basically the idea is the thing
was able to work, extremely well.
It also dates it a little bit, because
here's a picture of the Seinfeld Cast,
so that tells you something
about when this work was done.
Some interesting errors.
Notice this one down here, okay?
So we got all the faces on
the soccer player, football for
those of you not in the states.
All right?
But,
take a look at the ball at
the bottom there, right?
Now if you kind of squint
at that a little bit, oh,
I'll just take off my glasses and
look at that and say,
oh yeah, it's George and they say,
no, that's a soccer ball.
The distribution of the pattern was
kind of close and it labeled it.
Here's some more examples.
And again, you'll see that this profile
was not done so well, so what do you do?
Well, how about training some profiles?
Again, train the classifier using the
same types of rectangular features and
now all of a sudden you
can find faces site,
you know, these faces here and
those faces there.
Couple of cute things
that were done by folks.
They found faces in video.
That was done easily, but the video came
from broadcast video that had annotated,
subtitles, including characters, and
they started to be able to associate
different faces with
different characters.
So eventually, as you can see, it would
recognize Buffy the Vampire Slayer,
because after all who would be
complete without recognizing Buffy
the Vampire Slayer, but
the work was very cool.
So here's an article pulled out 2007, so
most of you used Google's Street View.
Well, when Google's Street View
first came out,
there were people's faces in it.
Actually it's not totally true
because they knew this was
going to be a problem.
But as you could imagine, people didn't
want their faces, and by the way,
not just one.
In the United States you can push
back a little bit in terms of faces.
In Europe, you have a much greater
right to your own face, or
I should say to the image
of your own face.
So it was very important that
Google be able to remove,
the faces of people
from their street view.
So to remove them,
you have to detect them,
and they're not going to pay 9 million
undergraduates to sit there and
click on all the faces, so
that you run the recognizer.
Here's a thing pulled out from iPhoto.
Most of you have an image in
our introduction you know,
on the back of your camera
where it finds all the faces.
Many of those systems use either
the Beulah Jones method or
some version of it.
I do like the, Lana had this picture
of things that iPhoto thought was face.
Here's a picture of a sort of a teddy
bear made in chocolate chip cookies, and
iPhoto thought it was a face,
because the pattern is about right.