Welcome to the homework assignment on computer vision.
I will first ask you a few questions about perspective projection
in which you will exercise the math that we explored
that relates the size of an object in the scene, uppercase X,
with the depth for the range to the pinhole camera Z, the focal length f,
and the size of the projection, small x.
Remember from class the following equation.
I'm literally dropping the minus sign. I want all numbers to be positive in this example.
So please don't worry about the minus sign that might not occur
in this specific version of the equation.
I'll give you three values for X, Z, f,
and would like you to understand what the missing value is.
X is measured in meters and the same with Z.
f is in millimeters and so is lowercase x.
Here's my first question. Suppose X is 10 m in size.
It's 100 meters away. Suppose our focal length is 10 mm.
How large is our projection lowercase x in millimeters?
Now we're asking you what is the focal length if an object of size 20 m that is 400 meters out
if we observe it to be 1 mm on our projection surface.
Suppose we have a 2 m sized object that with a 40 mm focal length
appears to be 1 mm in size. What is the distance of this object to the camera?
Finally, say a known object is 300 m away.
Our focal length is now 100 mm, and the object is again 1mm.
How far is this object away in meters?