This is one of my favorite parts
of user research, because it shows
just how much of the process you can
go without, if you're in a rush.
Of all these options, the only two that
we thought were going to critical when
we started, was whether the user
can create a new event, and
whether users can easily find
a way to check off tasks.
Once we identified that you had trouble
finding the way to check off a task,
that also elevated the question of
whether users would like to be able to
check off tasks on the home
screen to critical.
There are a couple of informational
questions which you may consider
critical, as well.
Knowing how to make the check boxes
stand out as well as figuring out where
to put our delete buttons
are important parts of the story.
Given all this feedback and
that we have data on every critical
question, the main task of our app.
And the things in
the way of those tasks.
It looks like our
prototype was a success.
We haven't decided whether our
design was a success though.
To do that,
we need to be sure we have enough data