For the moment I'm going to call the length of our flight path just the letter
d. That will make dealing with it in equations much simpler. The Pythagorean
theorem says that because this is a right triangle, we can say that 200 squared
plus 700 squared equals d squared. Simplifying that gives us 530,000 equals d
squared. In order to get d by itself, what do we need to do? Just take the
square root of both sides. Taking the square root of d squared, just leaves us
with d. The square root of 530,000 gives us a number with a ton of decimal
places, but when we round it, we get 728, which, since we're rounding, I will
say is about equal to d. Since our flight is really kind of approximate any way,
we can add to it that this length from Grant's hometown to Udacity is about 728
miles.