You made some good observations in
the last quiz about the XML that
we showed you.
Now we're going to talk more
formally about the XML syntax.
Syntax means the rules that
define what valid XML is.
If you write invalid XML, then it
won't even show up on your phone.
This is the code for
the XML element called TextView.
We always start with an opening angle
bracket, followed by the view name.
This could be image view, button,
or any other type of view.
Then we have a list of attributes here,
one per line.
And then we have a forward slash and
a closing angle bracket.
There's a lot of symbols and
characters here.
To help you remember it, you can
think of an opening angle bracket.
[SOUND] And then the view name.
[SOUND] And
then the attributes [SOUND] and
then the forward slash [SOUND] And
then the closing angle bracket.
[SOUND] So all together it's [SOUND].
If you miss any of these symbols,
then you're going to get invalid XML.
Here's the reasoning behind what
seem to be arbitrary symbols.
For every XML element,
when you start or open up a tag,
you always need to close it.
It's kind of like putting a period
at the end of a sentence, but for
XML Instead of a sentence, you need
to make sure you close each tag.
Because we start the tag here and
then close it right away,
this is called a self-closing tag.
Instead of a self-closing tag,
you could have a separate opening
tag and a separate closing tag.
Here's an example where it'd be useful.
This is for the LinearLayout
view which is what you going to
learn later in this lesson.
But just know that this is the opening
tag and this is the closing tag.
The closing tag is the same,
except it has an open angle bracket,
a forward slash, the name of the view
and then a closing angle bracket.
So the difference
between the opening and
the closing tag is this forward slash.
And you'll also notice that in between,
we have two TextView XML elements.
These are also called children XML
elements within the parent LinearLayout.
You can imagine that if you had
a self-closing tag up here for
LinearLayout, then you would have no
idea how many children it contains.
But now that the closing
tag is down here,
you know exactly that
you have two children.
In our case, for the TextView,
there are no children XML elements, so
we can just do a self-closing tag right
away because that saves us from having
to write open angle bracket slash
TextView closing angle bracket.
You notice that we have a bunch of
additional text inside this tag.
These are called attributes.
Attributes are characteristics
that determine the behavior or
the appearance of the view
on the Android phone.
For example,
we can think of it with this analogy.
A person have attributes like
black hair, and brown eyes.
A text too has attributes like width,
height, background,
text among many others.
Looking more closely at
the format at each line,
we have the attribute
name the left hand side.
Underlined in yellow here.
And on the right hand side,
we have the actual value.
It's important to note
that the attribute values
should be put in quotation marks
as part of the syntax for XML.
Then we have an equal sign in the middle
to say that the attribute name on
the left is set to
the value on the right.
So the text for
the TextView is Happy Birthday!, and
the height is 75 density
independent pixels.
All of these attributes
have default values,
and there's attributes that
we didn't even list here.
That's because the TextView has default
values for all of it's attributes.
If you're okay with the default values
then you don't need to set them here.
You should only write lines of code
here that you want to be
different than the default values.
For example,
the default background color for
a TextView is the transparent color.
But, we want to set it to
be a darker grey color, so
that's why we have
this line of code here.
One more important note.
Humans are pretty smart, if I write
phrases like this, you probably know
what I mean, even if I'm not using
proper English punctuation or
grammar, or even real words.
However, computers are not as smart, so
you need to use the precise symbols and
names that they recognize, otherwise
they won't know what you mean and
there will be errors in your code.
Here's an example.
For the name of the view,
we can't spell it TxtView, or
Textview with a lowercase v, or
text view with a space in it.
These are all incorrect and
the computer won't know that
we actually mean TextView.
if we want TextView we need to
spell it exactly the same way
with a capital T and
a Capital V for camel case.
Attribute names need to be spelled
out this exact way with a colon
after the android.
We need to have an equal sign and then
we need to put quotes around the values.
One more time so
you don't forget its [SOUND].
Now that we've gone over
the syntax rules of XML,
can you answer these questions for
this XML element?
First, what is the name
of this XML element?
Then, can you list all the attribute
names separated by commas?
Not the attribute values.
Then, on what line number
is the tag closed?
To help you, I've written down the line
numbers on the left hand side.