So what we're going to do is in order to figure how to
go from an image to the shape we're going to talk about this reflectance map.
So the reflectance map relates the brightness I of (x, y).
And again I'm just going to talk about sort of the brightness in the image
assuming that the image is linear with respect to the light that is hitting it.
So I'm not going to talk more about radiance or irradiance etc.
I'm just talking, talking about the lightness or
the brightness of the image, all right.
So the reflectance map relates the image brightness to the surface orientation.
Remember (p,q).
For a given source direction and a given surface reflectance, okay?
So this assumes for the moment that you know the source direction and
you know the surface reflectance.
Let's first consider the Lambertian case, all right?
So here we have our same math again.
We're going to assume that we've got some source brightness,
which we'll just call k here.
We have some surface albedo row.
And we're just going to use our same equation as we had before
that row times k times the cosine of the incident angle, right.
That's the angle between the source and
the normal, is what's going to determine how bright our image is.
And what we're going to do for the next little bit,
is we're going to assume that just row times K equals one.
Or another way of saying it is,
we're just going to assume that our image intensity is the cosine of the angle.
You could make it proportional to the cosine of the angle, but
the idea is that it's a fixed number.
In fact, later we are going to assume that it's proportional.
Clearly what matters in the brightness that we see is this angle,
the incident angle between the normal and the light source.
Alright, so here is the mathematics of our Lambertian system,
and in order to try to keep everything straight, I've sort of color coded.
The normal is pinkish, purplish.
Magenta, is that fuchsia?
Yeah, I don't know.
I don't really know my colors.
And this sickly green bluish I don't know, some color.
So we got sickly purple and sickly green.
But just keep them straight, all right?
But the idea is the purple is the surface normal,
the green is the direction towards the illuminant.
So the dot product that we showed before is just
p times ps plus q times qs plus 1 over the normalization.
And we refer to that as R of p,q.
And this is the reflectance map in this Lambertian case, okay?
So this R of p,q.
So what is that going to look like in pq space.
Well to take, figure that out, we can actually just do it algebraically.
But it's actually kind of cooler to do it geometrically.
All right.
So here we have our light source.
And we have some vector pointing up to our light source.
Now if I have, if my normal is some theta i away from it,
that means that it is in some cone.
Around that that light source direction, right.
So for that constant cosine of I, or some constant theta of I,
that's a cone around the illumination direction, alright.
Well, I can project, remember, pq space allows me to map any direction,
any surface orientation, to a PQ location, right?
So I'm going to project that constant cone up into PQ space and
I'm going to get this, this elliptical.
It's not really ellipse.
I'm just going to get this cone sliced by a plane.
And the idea is that everywhere along that curve
is the same cosine angle between the surface-normal and the source direction.
So that means that it's equally bright.
Those are referred to as iso brightness contours in pq space.
That's a lot to say, but basically, along that curve in,
in pq space, I get the same intensity.
Because that curve represents the set of
possible angles that are the same cosine theta away from the source direction.