I will now talk about fitting Gaussians to data or Gaussian learning.
You may be given some data points, and you might worry about
what is the best Guassian fitting the data?
Now, to explain this, let me first tell you what parameters characterizes a Gaussian.
In the 1-dimensional case, it is mu and sigma squared.
Mu is the mean. Sigma squared is called the variance.
If we look at the formula of a Gaussian, it's a function over any possible input X,
and it requires knowledge of mu and sigma squared.
And as before, I'm just restating what I said before.
We get this function over here that specifies any probability
for a value X given a specific mu and sigma squared.
Suppose we wish to fit data, and our data is 1-dimensional, and it looks as follows.
Just looking at this diagram makes me believe
that there's a high density of data points over here
and a fading density of data points over there,
so maybe the most likely Gaussian will look a little bit like this
where this is mu and this is sigma.
They are really easy formulas for fitting data to Gaussians,
and I'll give you the result right now.
The optimal or most likely mean is just the average of the data points.
There's M data points, X1 to Xm.
The average will look like this.
The sum of all data points divided by the total number of data points.
That's called the average, and once you calculate the average,
the sigma squared is obtained by a similar normalization
in a slightly more complex sum.
We sum the deviation from the mean
and compute the average deviation to the square from the mean,
and that gives us sigma squared.
So, intuitively speaking, the formulas are really easy.
Mu is the mean, or the average.
Sigma squared is the average quadratic deviation from the mean, as shown over here.