Now, what value should E choose for P?
Remember, you've got an infinite number of choices
for any value for P.
Well, if E chose a value of P
such that this value here
was larger than this value here,
then O would know to always play 1,
and similarly, if this value was larger,
then O would know to always play 2.
So, it seems that what E wants to do
is choose the value of P such that these 2 are equal.
So, how much is that? Well, let's see.
This is 2P - 3 - P.
That's 5P - 3,
and we want to set that equal to -3 + 4 - P.
That's -7P + 4.
And let's gather the terms together.
So, that would be 12P = 7
or P = 7/12.
So, if E chooses the value of P = 7/12,
so 7/12 of the time play 1,
5/12 of the time play 2,
then O doesn't know what to do.
No matter whether he chooses 1 or 2, he gets the same result.
And you can do the same calculation over here,
and it turns out that Q also equals 7/12.
Now, let's take this strategy of P = 7/12, 1,
and feed it back into the matrix for the game,
and if E plays this strategy of 7/12, 1, 5/12, 2,
then no matter what the strategy O plays,
the value of the game to E, the utility to E is -1/12.
And then we can do the same computation over here.
If Q has the strategy 7/12, 1, and 5/12, 2,
then we plug that back into here, and no matter what strategy E chooses,
the value there is also -1/12.
And so now we've shown that the utility to E
is greater than or equal to -1/12
and less than or equal to -1/12.
In other words, the utility to E
is exactly -1/12, so we've solved the game.