Now that we know our test is failing,
let's start iterating
on our implementation and
get this test turned green.
We'll need to first edit our
source/AddressBook.js file and
start writing our
implementation in there.
If we look back at our spec
runner we'll see the error
AddressBook is not defined, and
that error resides on line 3 of our
AddressBook spec where we were
instantiating our object.
This is an easy error to fix,
we'll just write a constructor function.
If we refresh our spec runner, we'll see
a new error; Contact is not defined.
To resolve this error, we also need
to write a contact constructor.
To keep everything organized,
I created a new file called Contact.js,
in my source directory.
And once again,
I wrote a quick constructor function.
I also had to add this file to my
spec runner, so that it gets run.