Let's look at the answers.
The first one says we can exclude
a query that we run to derive
the data from a table that we have
in the database, could exclude
certain sensitive attributes like social
security number or something like that.
And users can only be given access to
the view where this sensitive data
is not there.
This is a new derived virtual table
we're talking about, so it doesn't have
all the attribute values,
in particular the highly sensitive ones.
So this answer is the correct one.
The next one is not correct because
it says view can only be accessed by
a single user.
We actually didn't talk about that,
doesn't have to be.
Have a virtual table, or, it depends on
what sort of access control you have in
place, but it doesn't have to
be accessed by a single user.