So how would version spaces be useful to answer Raven's progressive matrices?
Like with the incremental concept learning,
think first about what concept you're trying to learn. Are you learning
transformations? Are you learning types of problems? What are the increments?
Are they individual problems? Are they individual figures?
Are they individual transformations in a problem? Second,
what are you converging onto? For example, you could use version spaces within
one problem and converge down onto a correct answer, or you could use it for
learning how to solve problems in general and converge onto adoptable algorithm,
or you could use it for learning an ontology of problems and converge onto
a single type of problem you expect to see in the future. So what are you
converging onto if you use version spaces for Raven's progressive matrices?