What's really interesting
in this representation is,
that the edges embody
the rules of the game.
For instance,
you can only go to a finite number of
next states from each current state.
>> Hm, you're right.
It limits the number of moves
we might need to consider,
especially later in the game,
when the board is more full.
But I can see that there are still a lot
of nodes here that need to be expanded
right at the beginning.
How do we address that?
>> That's true.
On a three by three board,
the very first move has nine different
possibilities, and then,
eight for the opponent and so on.
>> But some of these are pretty
clearly wasteful moves.
So for example here, it's o's turn,
but it doesn't make sense to go here.
Because there's one x in that row and
one in the same column.
This move will never contribute
to a winning combination.
>> Yes, that's a great observation.
Being able to ignore moves based on easy
to evaluate conditions like this is,
known as pruning the search tree.
Can you think of any
other search indicators?
>> Maybe.
How about the fact that we're
playing against a human opponent
that's also trying to win?
>> You're on the right track.
>> Okay so
I know that if I put an O here,
the opponent is definitely going to
try to close this and win the game.
So, maybe that's not a good
move to play either, yes?
>> And
that is the gist of adversarial search.
We'll learn how to formulize these
intuitions using the mini-max algorithm.
Where you are trying to maximize your
chances of winning on your turn.
And your opponent is trying to minimize
your chances of winning on their turn.
This approach is so effective, because
when you rule out a move as being bad.
You are actually getting rid of it's
potential successors from consideration.
>> So, that seems like this is a better
definition of an intelligent agent
to me.
It's able to anticipate and plan around
expected changes in its environment.
Including, those introduced
by other agents.
But game playing is one thing,
I wonder how AI handles
the complexities of the real world.