Today I have the great, great pleasure
to teach you about hidden Markov models and filter algorithms.
The reason why I'm so excited is in pretty much all of my scientific career,
hidden Markov models and filters have played a major role.
There's no robot that I program today that wouldn't extensively use hidden Markov models
and things such as particle filters.
In fact, when I applied for a job at Stanford University as a professor many years ago,
my job talk that I used to market myself to Stanford
was extensively about a version of hidden Markov models and particle filters
applied to robotic mapping.
Today I will teach you those algorithms so you can use them in many challenging problems.
I can't quite promise you that once you have mastered the material
you will get a job at Stanford, but you can really, really apply them
to a vast array of problems in places such as finance, medicine, robotics,
weather prediction, time series analysis, and many, many other domains.
This is going to be a really fun class.