Okay, so, I guess to preface this,
I feel like in English I
know what it means.
Mathematically, I'm not-
>> Let's just start with English.
>> So we're going to start with
the top of the handle to represent
the first line in our sequence.
>> Okay, you mean the position
of the top of the handle?
>> Yes.
>> Okay, with respect to the
>> The tray.
>> Huh.
>> Okay.
So if it's halfway down,
you'd expect to be
halfway down the file.
>> Correct.
>> Okay.
>> And then, for the rest of the lines
in the sequence how many more lines do
we need is based on the handle size.
>> We don't even have
to be that complicated.
>> Okay.
>> We can just say the number of lines
that fit in the view port.
>> Okay.
>> Right?
So if the view port has 50 lines,
we can expect to get the next 50 lines.
>> Okay.
>> Ultimately we would have to translate
this into mathematics or express
the mathematics on OCL but for now our
expectation is that that percentage of
the way down in the tray indicates the
percentage of the way down in the file.