Welcome back.
This is my solution to the sentiment
analysis with TFLearn exercise.
I'm going to walk through it and
show you how I implemented this network.
First off, the bag of words.
I started by creating
an empty Counter object,
this is where I'm going to
store the word counts.
Here, I'm iterating through the rows in
the data set with iterrows, this returns
the row index, which I don't really care
about which is why it's an underscore,
and the row data itself.
Row[0] here, returns the review text and
then I split it into words, then I use
these words to update the counter.
This will count up each
word in this review, so,
this will go through each review and
count up all the words.
And we get 74,000 and
74 total words in the dataset.
Then, keep the most
frequent 10,000 words, and
this is what it looks like for the first
60, mostly it's a bunch of small words.
But there's also movie and
film, which is to be expected,
because it's a bunch of movie reviews.
Okay, onto the word to index part.
Here's how I built my
word to index dictionary.
If you haven't seen this syntax before,
this is a dictionary comprehension.
Here, I'm sending the dictionary
key to the word in vocab and
the value to an integer i.
The words are coming from vocab and the
integers from the enumerate function.
enumerate iterates through vocab and,
at each step,
also returns an incrementing integer.
So 0 the first time,
1 the second time, and so on.
Comprehensions are amazingly useful,
and if you get the hang of it,
you'll wonder how you
ever lived without them.
Okay, now on to
the text_to_vector function.
First, I start off by creating
the empty array of zeros for
keeping our word count.
Then here, I'm iterating
through each word and text.
>From the word2idx dictionary,
I get the index for the word.
If the word didn't exist,
then I'm just going to skip it, so,
if idx is None, continue.
This goes straight to the next iteration
of the loop, if the word does exist,
I increment the value at the index for
that word.
Once it goes through all the words,
it returns the array.
Now, onto the network.
Here I created the input layer, our
input vectors are 10,000 elements long,
so we need 10,000 input unit,
that's pretty straightforward.
Then I added a couple hidden layers,
one with 200 units and another with 25.
You could probably have a quite accurate
network with just one layer, but
I wanted to get fancy.
For the output layer I have two
units with the softmax activation.
And here I set the training
parameters with regression.
I set the learning_rate as 0.1, this
is typically a good rate to start at,
if the network has problems training,
then, I'll load it a bit until
the training looks good.
Finally, create the model and return it.
If you're wondering about this
tf.reset_default_graph function here,
it fixes the problem
tflearn has in notebooks.
I'm not sure why it happens but if you
try to reinitialize the model after
training, if there was an error, and
you have to restart the notebook kernel.
reset_default_graph clears out
all the internal variables and
parameters tflearn stored and
allows you to reinitialize
the model without any problem.
Finally, time to train this thing.
At first, I trained for 200FX, it got
the validation accuracy to around 75%,
but I thought I could do better,
so I trained it more.
And eventually,
as you see I got to around 89% on
the validation set, this is pretty good.
Of course, I could have kept training,
but I thought this was good enough.
Now that I'm happy with
the validation accuracy,
it's time to write it
on the testing set.
Here, I got 85.5% accuracy,
you'll notice that this is a fair
bit lower than the validation score.
Since you set the network
hyperparameters using the validation
set, you're actually overfitting
the network to the validation set.
The test data is completely unseen
by the network and by you, so
it's the best way to get
a completely unbiased measurement
of the network's performance.
All right, that's it for my solution,
how well did your network do?