We've learned about the standard shader
and we've coded our own shader, but we
need to know one more thing about Unity
shaders before we finish up this lesson.
Let's open up Unity and
check out some different shaders.
First, create a new material and
name it Unlit- Super Fast &amp; Pretty Ugly.
[LAUGH] I know that's a long name.
And then go to Shader, and
then change the shader to Mobile and
then Unlit (Supports Lightmap).
Now over in the hierarchy right-click,
go to 3D Object &gt; Cube.
And now drag and
drop your unlit, super fast, and
pretty ugly material onto the cube.
See how it's completely white and
doesn't respond to light at all?
If your object doesn't need shading
from a light source then this is
one of the fastest shaders you can use,
and you totally should if you can.
This shader will use lightmaps,
which you'll learn about later, but
it doesn't have any real-time lighting.
But, lets say your object
does need to be shaded.
Go ahead and select your Super Fast
material and press Ctrl + D, or
Cmd + D on the Mac, to duplicate it.
Now rename your new material to
Mobile Diffuse- Pretty Fast
&amp; Attractive.
And then switch its shader
by going to the Shader
drop-down box &gt; Mobile &gt; Diffuse.
Now go up to your cube,
press Ctrl + D or
Cmd + D to duplicate it and then move
that new cube a little bit out of
the way and drag and drop your mobile
diffuse material onto the new cube.
You can see that the cube
responds to light and
it's shaded, but it doesn't look
quite as good as the standard shader.
The big difference between
the mobile defuse and
standard shaders is that the diffuse
shader is much, much faster.
It's a great choice if your 3D objects
need to be shaded by light sources.
Check out this chart.
You can see that fast shaders can have
a huge benefit to your frame rate, but
it's often at the expense of realism.
Now you know which shaders
to pick most of the time
when developing mobile VR in Unity.
It's your job as a VR developer, or
content creator, to achieve the best
possible graphics in a given context.
You'll have to make hard choices.
Dropping frames is not an option in VR,
you need to keep the frame rate.
If your project runs too slow, shaders
are a great way of making it faster.
Play with them, and select the most
appropriate one for you, given how many
objects there are in a scene and
on what hardware your app runs.