So as I said these operations are easy in 1D and a little trickier in 2D, and
of course it doesnt work at all if you have sharp shape variations.
So here is a shape example I think also done by Ted Abelson.
So here we have this sharp shape boundary right here, and
the question is what is the relationship between these, this square and
that square and actually you can take a look at these edges.
Right? Well, you realize that these two are the same.
And yet this square probably looks darker to you than that square.
And in fact, here we go again.
You can see that there's not boundary here, and there's no boundary there.
These two squares are the same intensity,
which by the way are the same intensity as that.
All right?
So rednex would fail here because it would assume that this sharp boundary
was due to change in an object and not due to change in an illumination.
because when you have a sharp shape change you have
a sharp illumination change and rednex doesn't deal with that at all.
So what's going on here is refered to as sometimes as color constancy or
lightness constancy.