All right.
So each of these cd commands
changes our current directory.
The first one, cd .., goes to
the parent of the current directory.
So after running this first command,
we go to the parent of otter.
The second command is
cd with no arguments.
Cd with no arguments returns
us to our home directory.
So, we go straight back to home/otter.
The next command in
the series is cd www.
This takes us to the www directory
inside of our current directory,
which is down here.
The fourth command, cd stuff,
takes us to the stuff directory
inside of the www directory.
This last command, cd .,
doesn't change anything.
., refers to our current directory.
So we wind up in /home/otter/www/stuff.