[Thrun] What's shown here is the tour guide robot that I showed you earlier,
but now I'll talk about the what's called localization problem--
the problem of finding out where in the world this robot is.
This problem is important because to find its way around the museum
and to arrive at exhibits of interest, it must know where it is.
The problem with this problem is that it doesn't have a sensor that tells us where it is.
Instead, it's given what's called range finders.
These are sensors that measure distances to surrounding objects.
It's also given the map of the environment,
and it can compare these range finders measurements with the map of the environment
and infer from that where it might be.
The process of inferring the hidden state of the robot's location from the measurements,
the range sensor measurements, that's the problem of filtering.
And the underlying model is exactly the same I showed you before.
It's a hidden Markov model where the state is the sequence of locations
that the robot assumes in the museum
and the measurements is the sequence of range measurements it perceives
while it navigates the museum.
A second example is the underground robotic mapping robot
which has pretty much the same problem--finding out where it is--
but now it is not given a map; it builds the map from scratch.
What this animation here shows you is a so-called particle filter applied to robotic mapping.
Intuitively--what you see is very simple--
as the robot transcends into a mine, it builds a map.
But the many black lines are hypotheses on where the robot might have been
when building this map.
It can't tell because of the noise in its motors and in its sensors.
As the robot reconnects and closes the loop in this map,
one of these black what we call particles in the trade--
one of these black hypotheses are being selected as the best one,
and by virtue of having maintained many of those, the robot is able to build a coherent map.
In fact, this animation was a key animation in my job talk
when I applied to become a professor at Stanford University.
Here is one final example I'd like to discuss with you which is called speech recognition.
If you have a microphone that records speech
and you want to make your computer recognize the speech,
you will likely come across hidden Markov models.
This is a typical speech signal over here.
It's an oscillation for the words "speech lab" which I borrowed from Simon Arnfield.
And if you blow up a small region over here, you'll find that there is an oscillation,
and this oscillation in time is the speech signal.
What speech recognizing systems do is they transform this signal over here
back into letters like "speech lab."
And you can see it's not an easy task.
There is some signal here.
The E, for example, is a certain shape.
But different speakers speak differently, and there might be background noise,
so decoding this back into speech is challenging.
There's been enormous progress in the field
mostly due to hidden Markov models that have been researched for more than 20 years.
And today's best speech recognizers all use variants of hidden Markov models.
So once again, I can't teach you everything in this class, but I'll teach you the very basics
that you can apply to things such as speech signals.