Okay, so let's see what our app
should look like with a banner ad.
So here I've started the app, and
I can now click on the banner ad button.
And when I do that,
you can see that the test banner ad
is displayed at the bottom here.
And remember,
the reason why you see a test banner
ad Is because we use to test banner
ads unit id that we talked about.
And if I click on the banner ad
you'll see that it brings me to
the details for the ad.
And remember the reason this
is happening is because we've
added the ad activity
to our manifest file.
And of course I can go back
to our app by clicking here.
And that's it for our app so far, but
let's take this one step further and
actually hook into the different
activities that can be triggered when
you use ads in your app.
Let's look at add listener.