Here's what I was looking for,
for the reads and
the writes a total of n/L transfers.
For the comparisons, n log Z.
Let's look at the transfers first.
The reads and writes involve
about Z/L transfers each and
of course you repeat that for
all iterations.
So that's a total of n/L transfers.
Now what about comparisons?
An optimal comparison based sort will
incur about Z log Z comparisons.
Doing that for
all n/Z iterations gives you n log Z.
The good news is, so
far your scheme is giving you something
proportional to n/L transactions.
That's good because it means you're
doing a good job utilizing each
transaction.
Good job, you!
Here's a candy bar.
You're nuts for HPC.
>> [SOUND]