After completing stage one to connect a simple split sentence bolt
using Java and
Python, you are now ready to use python for something a bit more interesting.
Python packages can be used to speed up development especially for
computations that might be more difficult in Java.
In this section we will use the beautiful suit package to parse tweeted URLs and
emit text.
In step zero, navigate to lesson three stage two, and
remember to add your twitter credentials into the tweet topology file.
In part one, we installed Beautiful Soup in Ubuntu package in
Python by using the apt-get command.
You can copy and paste sudo apt-get install python-bs4, into your terminal.
This stands for super user do, apt-get is the install command for
Ubuntu, and Python-bs4 is the Beautiful Soup package in Python.
Running this the first time will give you a build success but
if it's already installed you won't see any build.
Also after our hackathon, a number of students asked us
about how to install different Python commands using the vagrant file.
So in lesson four if you're interested, we walked through how to
add this command to your vagrant file, that prevision through virtual machine.
In part two, modify your tweet spell to omit only the first URL contained in
a tweet, remember to check if the URL is empty before admitting.
And we used the Tweeter 4JEPI which can be found here,
remember that Tweets are called status.
On the Twitter4J.org site, if you search for
your URL, you'll see the method getURLEntitites.
And getURLEntities has a method getURL that returns a string.
And I've given you a few syntax hints that states just that,
status.getURLEntities, remember we're getting only the first
URL at position zero.getURL that returns a string.
Next its time to create your own python file in part three,
create a new python file in the resources folder called urltext.py.
In part four use the urllib2 and
BeautifulSoup libraries, to define a new class, URLBolt.
An important hint is to wrap your procedure in a try/accept statement to
avoid connection errors, connection errors will actually crash Storm,
due to the implementation of Python in Storm.
Here's a documentation for your reference, and
if needed, a few syntax hints in Python.
In part 5, create a Java bolt URLBolt.java, and
remember that this is located in the storm folder and not the resources folder.
And finally in part 6,
update your Topology to visualize URL words using a Python bolt.
And finally, in part 6,
Notice that your word cloud is now a parsed word cloud of URL
words from webpages that were processed using beautiful soup in Python.
Remember as well that your code should match less in three stage three, so
if syntax errors or
problems occur, please look ahead for the solution or review the solution video.
Good luck.