In general, what your brain has to do is to make a whole variety of
assumptions in order to disambiguate, between different possible solutions.
That is different possible interpretations in order to come up with one that it
really likes.
And in fact your brain does this so
well you don't even notice that it's doing it.
A college of mine, Ted Adelson is sort of a master at exploring these kinds of
thing, and he's put together some really compelling demonstrations.
Of your brain making assumptions, in order to determine lightness.
So one of them is here, right?
So this is a relatively simple scene.
You can see the two squares marked a and b.
And if you look at it real carefully you'll say oh, yeah.
A is a dark square and B is a light square, right?
And this is so mind blowing because.
Even though I look at this all the time, I can't believe it, all right.
You're ready? So here's this gray bar.
Nothing up my sleeve, okay.
And you'll notice that gray bar,
is at constant intensity all the way along, right.
It's the same intensity.
It's not like it's lighter and darker.
And now we're going to move that gray bar, and it's lined with square A and B.
And yet there's no edge here, and there's no edge there.
See I'll remove those lines.
So A and B are actually the same intensity, okay?
And when you look at it, you swear they're different intensities.
In fact, here you can, I put two gray bars there, right?
And now.
Depending upon how far away I if I kind of squint and I ignore all
the rest of it, I can see that all of these squares are the same intensity.
But it's just, you know, incredibly hard to see that.
So, what's going on there?
Well clearly what's going on, a couple of things.
One is, my brain is compensating for this shadow, right?
So it's seeing the shadow cast by the cylinder.
So it says, okay, wait a minute.
If there's more light here than there is there, then this thing, if it's
the same intensity coming off the, the image, it must be a lighter square.
The other thing is that the idea of this being a lighter square,
is consistent with this interpretation that this is a checkerboard.
And these are nice light squares, and the repeated pattern.
And generally the way I like to think of it,
as your brain likes consistent interpretations.
So this is sort of compensating for the shadow.
You're brain is saying okay, I see that shadow, I understand that shadow.
So the thing underneath it must actually be lighter, even though the,
the image intensity coming up at you is the same between A and B.
So here's another example, also from TED,
that your lightness perception can be influenced by 3 dimensional cues.
That is, your belief about the underlying shape.
All right so here we have two squares there, and
those probably look like they're the same intensity to you.
And in fact they are, as the grade bar there shows you.
But now we get to blow your mind again.
You ready?
Here we are.
Okay, those two squares, and now you're saying no, not possible.
It cannot be that those two squares are the same intensity.
Well, here comes my bar.
And there it goes.
I love this.
And son of a gun, it's the same intensity.
In fact, let me back that up, right?
So this square and this square, are the same brightness.
And when you look at it just like that you just don't really want to believe it.
And then when you put it next to the grey bar you realize that it's true.
So that's, your brain again interpreting that okay,
this area is in a more shaded area than that area.
So, this square even though it has the same intensity as that,
because it has less lighting falling on it, it must be brighter.
Okay, so again its your brain making these kind of assumptions.
And there's a very simple definition of this called simultaneous contrast, so
if you're looking at this it may depend a little on the setting of your monitor.
You probably see this square, as darker than this square,
even though, of course they're the same intensity.
And, the idea is,
that your, your brain, sort of focuses on these, these contrasts.
So, your brain is doing all these kind of things in order to
figure out what lightness is.