0.1, which is the difference between 1 and 0.9.
Let's assume the probability of the test coming out positive
given that we don't have this cancer is 0.2.
In other words, the probability of the test correctly saying
we don't have the cancer if we're cancer free is 0.8.
Now, ultimately, I'd like to know what's the probability
they have this cancer given they just received a single, positive test?
Before I do this, please help me filling out some other probabilities
that are actually important.
Specifically, the joint probabilities.
The probability of a positive test and having cancer.
The probability of a negative test and having cancer,
and this is not conditional anymore.
It's now a joint probability.
So, please give me those 4 values over here.