So, this was an idea behind this very nice paper on dual photography that
was presented at the Siggraph Conference in, 2005, and
I'm going to basically now just talk about it.
As I said, this was led by a bunch of people at Stanford with a bunch of
collaborators also at different places.
It's a very nice piece of work, and for those of you interested more,
please go to this link here, and you can see more details about this paper.
Just to showcase this example I'm going to play the video from this.
>> Our technique allows us to interchange cameras and projectors,
thereby enabling us to take images from the point of view of a projector.
Suppose for example we had the following experimental setup.
Here we have a scene that is imaged by a camera on the left and
illuminated by a projector on the right.
This is the image taken by the camera,
which shows the scene flood illuminated by the projector.
In our paper, we refer to this as the primal image.
After measuring the light transport between the projector and
the camera, we show that the flow of the light can be effectively reversed using
Helmholtz reciprocity.
This means that we're able to generate an image from the point of view of
the projector as shown here.
This dual image shows the scene from the perspective of the projector,
while the lumination is coming from the position of the camera.
Note that this is the image synthesized by our technique.
Dual photography is the process of measuring the light transport to
generate the dual image.
A simple example will help us understand how dual photography works.
This scene is illuminated by a projector and
the outgoing light will be measured by a photo sensor.
Suppose we light up a single pixel at a time in the projector and
store the value measured by the photo sensor as a function of pixel location.
We do this for all the pixels in the projector.
Helmholtz reciprocity specifies that the light transfer will be
the same along a light path, regardless of the direction of the flow of light.
This means that the same value would be measured whether the light starts off at
the projector pixel and goes to the photosensor, or
if it starts from the photosensor and arrives at that projector pixel.
The transfer of energy from one to the other will be the same in
either direction.
Thus we can transform our projector into a virtual camera and
the photo sensor into a virtual light source.
By putting back the measured values into the correct position so
the camera image array,
we can form the picture that would have been taken by the virtual camera.
The resolution of this image will be that of the projector.
Replacing the photo sensor with a camera, allows us to capture the four
dimensional transport between the pixels of the projector and
the pixels in the camera.
However, scanning the projector pixel by pixel is very slow,
since there are millions of pixels in a standard projector.
To accelerate this process, we must identify pixels whose contributions unto
the scene can be later separated and illuminate them in parallel.
Our adaptive algorithm subdivides the projector image recursively to
determine which pixels can be lit simultaneously.
This allows us to capture the transport between a projector and
camera significantly faster than with the brute force scan.
On the left, we show the projector pattern and on the right,
we show the image captured by the camera.
So now you noticed how this whole pipeline unfolds, and
how basically what the projector is illuminating, and how camera captures
the whole concept of dual photography results in a new work type of an image.
Let's look at one of the more interesting applications of this,
again there are other applications that are mentioned by the authors in
that paper that I encourage you to look at.
Finally, we perform an experiment to demonstrate that we can capture subtle
diffuse interaction.
The projector's set up in front of a standard playing card, while the camera's
placed so that it can see the back of the card and the diffuse page of a book.
In this case, the light going from the projector to the camera had to
undergo a diffuse bounce at the card, and another at the book.
The image on the right is what the camera can see under ordinary room lighting.
It seems impossible that we could ever identify the card by simply changing
the incident illumination.
However, our framework shows that this is indeed possible.
By scanning the pixels of the projector, we can generate the dual image.
Here we see that the color of the book changes depending on the point on
the card we're illuminating.
After the complete transport has been acquired,
we can generate an image of the card from the perspective of the projector.
So now you see we can actually use this approach to, well,
see things that were not directly visible by a camera, but again by looking at
how the light transport impacts the surfaces around it and just observing those.
So this is one of those instances where both the illumination from the projector
and the capture device, the camera, both are being controlled by a computer, and
used that to now actually generate a newer form of an image.
That's an important part that I want you to kind of understand,
because that will lead to the basics of computational photography.