Image classification is a pretty
common task in machine learning.
But large scale image classification can
be computationally pretty intensive.
You need to realize that although
images are like vectors with
thousands of elements, the values of
these vectors can be highly correlated.
They can have patterns that you can
exploit, and condense the data.
Lorenzo came up with one scheme which
was taking the Fourier transform of
the image, which would reduce
the dimensionality of the input data.
Another method, probably a slightly
more applicable method in this case,
would be to take
the principal components and
the top few principal components for
each image.
That would help to reduce
the dimensionality even further and
retain the information from the image.
Now, you need to realize that these
same transformations can be applied
in slightly different domains as well.
And this was something that was nicely
pointed out by Lorenzo, saying that
Fourier transform can be applied, for
instance, in the audio domain as well.
So when you're talking
about a particular data
transformation algorithm or machine
learning algorithm, you should be able
to answer questions about what domains
or fields they can be applied in.