The answer is log, log n.
Here's a quick and dirty analysis.
Remember that each time
you run independent set,
you expect to pick about and
over four notes.
That means that the length of the list
will be about three-fourths N
on average.
Now suppose you run parallel
independent set k times.
Then the expected length of the list,
after k calls,
will be three fourths to the k, times n.
And remember your target list length.
It's n over log n.
So to determine the number of times you
need to call parallel independent set,
just solve for k in this inequality.
What you should get in log, log n.
Uh-oh!
This result means that I lied a little.
We were hoping to arrive at
a Work-Optimal Scheme, but
we're actually off by a little bit.
The good news is that this log,
log n factor doesn't grow very quickly.
For instance, when n is 10 to the 18th,
log log n is about 4 or so.
In other words, you only need to run
parallel independent set a few times.
That's terrific news.
Woot!
Now
there are a couple
other details to check.
The first one has to do with the fact
that this was kind of a rough,
average-case analysis.
That's not entirely satisfactory.
You don't only want to know
what happens on average.
There's going to be some
distribution around the average.
You want to know, is that
distribution skinny or is it fat?
And how much mass is in the tail?
So that's one detail.
The other detail is how much bookkeeping
is necessary to implement steps
one and three?
I'm going to claim it's doable, but
you shouldn't believe me unless
you can work it out yourself.