The best way to understand
the Soul is to see it in action.
Let's create a simple
example in Android Studio so,
that we can see all the parts, and
how to build and install them.
Android Studio includes templates for
all the popular Android platforms and
so we can create one very easily here.
In Android studio select File > New
> New Project, and you can fill in
whatever you want as the defaults
because we're not using this for
anything important.
Click Next.
We select Phone and
Tablet with the defaults and
we also select Wear with
a minimum SDK of at least API 21.
Click Next.
For the mobile activity just select
the default blank activity and
leave everything with
the default activity names.
Now you'll see we have the option
to select a wearable activity.
In this example we'll
use Blank Wear Activity.
But you'll notice that you can also
create a notification or a watch face.
Those will come in handy later on.
Once again you can leave the activities
with the default names and
than click Finish.
So, now I want you to
replicate the same steps.
After the project is fully created,
how many build.gradle files do you have
appearing in your project browser?
Choose one of the answers,
one, two, three, or four.