First, I'm going to change the app so
when you hit the Order button,
it's going to show Amount Due $10 or
whatever the price is.
Since there's going to be a lot of
combinations where I'm going to need
the price, I'm just going to create
an integer variable to hold the price.
Notice that the int is lowercase i
because it's a primitive data type.
Now I can just refer to the price
variable whenever I want
the price number.
Now, I need to change the string so
it says Amount Due.
So, I'm going to write "Amount Due ",
add a space,
and then concatenate that
with the price variable.
Oh, and
I forgot the dollar sign as well.
The dollar sign should be part
of this string literal, and
I want it to be after a space,
so I'll put it right here.
Now I'm going to run it.
If I change quantity to three and
then hit the Order button,
then it correctly shows Amount Due $15.
First one done, that wasn't too bad.
Next, we want it to say
that would be $10, please.
I'm going to change this text to
start with That would be, and then
I want a dollar sign, the price, and
then I want some more text after that.
I should say " please" and a period.
I add a space here because I
want a space after the price.
Let's check to see what that looks like.
On the device,
if I change quantity to three,
hit the Order button,
it says That would be $15 please.
Now the second one's done.
We're on a roll.
The third one says,
You owe 10 bucks, dude!
I'm going to change the start of
this string to be You owe, and
then I'm going to remove the dollar
sign because we just need the price,
and then we're going to add " bucks,
dude!".
That looks correct.
Let's run that.
I'm going to hit the Order button.
It says, You owe 15 bucks, dude!
The fourth one is a little tricky.
We want to say 10 dollars for
2 cups of coffee.
Pay up.
I see a need for two variables here,
the price variable and
the quantity variable.
We're going to start with the price,
which is ten.
And then we're going to
say " dollars for ", and
then I need to put the quantity and
then " cups of coffee.
And then Pay up.".
Let's run that.
If I hit the Order button, then it
says 15 dollars for 3 cups of coffee.
Pay up.
That looks really good.
This was tricky because we
had two variables here,
concatenated with two string literals.
Fortunately, we added spaces
in the right place so
that it would look
like a normal sentence.
That was the hardest one, and now we can
do the last one, that says Total: $10.
I'm going to erase this
whole thing here, and
say "Total: " and then the price.
Oh, but I also need the dollar sign, so
I'm going to put that
inside the string literal.
Oh, and I forgot the plus sign, too.
There, now let's run the app.
I change quantity to three, hit Order,
then it correctly says Total: $15.
Woo hoo!
You got through all of these different
combinations of string concatenation
with variables.
Now move on to the next video for
your last coding task of this lesson.