We have a fully
functional recycler view.
But you can't really tell
that it's recycling views or
if they are all allocated when
they are first displayed.
Now we're not going to ask you
to implement this step, but
we've left the instructions for
you if you're interested.
With these next changes,
our GreenAdapter is finally
living up to its name.
I've changed the Viewholder to be
assigned a shade of green when it is
created.
And added another text view to
the item to hold the Viewholder
number to better illustrate
what's getting recycled.
Note that the shade of green doesn't
actually change when the view is
recycled.
To make it even nicer, the next exercise
and solution adds a reset button.
Since we've already learned
about toolbar buttons,
we're not going to ask you
to do this exercise either.
One thing to note is that we reset
the adapter by creating a new one, and
replacing it in the recycler view.
This is something you'd probably only
do in the context of an academic
discussion about recycler view.
But it does cause the recycler
view to refresh nicely.