Starting from the top, a file editor is likely not a part of
an operating system because the users interact with it directly, and
it's not involved directly in managing hardware.
Next, the file system is likely a part of an operating system.
It's directly responsible for hiding hardware complexity and for
exporting a simpler, more intuitive abstractions.
A file, as opposed to block of disk storage.
Device drivers are also likely part of an operating system.
A device driver is directly responsible for
making decisions regarding the usage of the hardware devices.
Cache memory is a little bit tricky.
Although the operating system and the application software utilize cache
memory for performance, the OS doesn't directly manage the cache.
It's really the hardware that manages it itself.
Web browsers are also not part of an operating system.
Again, just like in the file editor case, it's an application that
users interact with and does not have direct control over underlying hardware.
And finally, the scheduler.
This is indeed a part of the operating system because it's responsible for
distributing the access to the processing element, the CPU,
among all of the applications that share that platform.