The first option should be checked.
If it is attractive because you're not
just getting information about a few
people, but lots of people.
Finally, query languages that
are used to access data can be abused
to gain unauthorized access, okay?
So we talked about software security and
vulnerable software and
things like that.
And, actually, we're going to see
that I mentioned that SQL is used
to write the programs for the queries
that we run against databases,
and people exploit the way we
formulate those queries for
example, and I will again
access to databases via that.
So the attack rectors, and
if they make it easy for them to
gain access to the data, of course
that makes the target attractive
because it's easy to get to it.