in 2014 google published its own network
in the image net competition and in
homage to yawn lagoon and Lynette google
name their network
wait for it goog lennette it's spelled
like Google met but it's pronounced
google and that go figure in the image
net competition google Annette performed
even a little better than VG 6.7 percent
compared to 7.3 percent although at that
level it kind of feels like we're
splitting hairs google and that's great
advantage is that it runs really fast
the team that developed googling that
developed a clever concept called an
inception module which trains really
well and is efficiently deployable do
you remember inception Vincent explain
the concept earlier we're going to show
it again here in case you forgot it's
called an inception module it's going to
look a little more complicated
the idea is that at each layer of your
cognate you can make a choice have a
cooling operation have a convolution and
then you need to decide is it a
one-by-one convolution or three by three
or five by five
all of these are actually beneficial to
the modeling power of your network so
why choose let's use them all
here's what an inception module looks
like instead of having a single
convolution you have a composition of
average cooling followed by one by one
then a one-by-one convolution then one
by one followed by three by three then a
1 by 1 followed by a five-by-five and at
the top you simply concatenate the
output of each of them it looks
complicated but what's interesting is
that you can choose these parameters in
such a way that the total number of
parameters in your model is very small
yet the model performs better than if
you had a simple convolution as Vincent
says the inception modules create a
situation in which the total number of
parameters is very small this is my
google and that runs almost as fast as
Alex net and of course Google annette
has great accuracy like we mentioned
earlier it's imagenet error was only
seven percent google Annette is a great
choice to investigate if you need to run
your name
work in real time like maybe in a
self-driving car