So if you follow
the instructions in the quiz,
you would have created the word class.
And Android studio helped us out by auto
generating some code for us already.
All right, so first in our word class,
we declare it as publicly accessible.
That way other classes like the numbers
activity would be able to access and
use it.
Also here, I've added the Java.comment
already above the class declaration.
To explain how the work class is meant
to represent of a vocabulary word, so
notice that it contains an English
default translation, and
a Miwok translation for each word.
Hence we'll need two fields for
the state of the word object.
mDefaultTranslation, which is the word
in a language of the users already
familiar with, so for example English,
and secondly, mMiwokTranslation.
Which is a word in the Miwok language.
So both of these here, notice,
are private, because we only need them
to be accessible from inside the class.
So by convention, since they are private
member variables of the class,
we add a lowercase m to indicate that,
and
the m is added to the start
of each variable name.
So next,
we need to create the constructor which
takes in two string parameters.
The defaultTranslation and
the miwokTranslation and
then set these values for
our two fields.
So in order to create a new word
object the color has to pass in
these two required inputs.
Remember that the constructor has to
look like a at method declaration.
But the name has to match the class name
exactly, which in this case is Word.
And remember that it has no return type.
So lastly we'll add two methods
which will be marked as public, so
that classes outside of the Word
class can access these methods.
So first is the getDefaultTranslation
method, which will return the default
translation of the word
whose return type is String.
So it won't accept any parameters,
because its sole purpose is
just to return information.
Our second method is
getMiwokTranslation,
and I'll follow a similar format.
So notice that it returns in
Miwok translation of a word
which is a string data type.
Now remember to add comments above
each method to help people who
are reading your code better understand
what to expect from each method.
So we could of added two setter methods
to allow the two strings to be changed
by an outside color.
However for the purpose of this app,
once we create the word object,
we don't expect the English or
Miwok words to change.
Hence we won't provide setter methods
to modify the state of the word object.
So when you create a class it's entirely
up to you to decide what methods you
want to expose to the outside classes.
All right, so there we have it.
Here is the word class defined in its
entirety with the declaration, state,
constructor and methods.
Now great work on defining
your first custom class.