Let's talk about the powerful
capabilities of the database, so
you can see why we use it.
Our database synchronizes data,
so that every time data changes,
all connected devices receive
that change within milliseconds.
A message sent by one
person in friendly chat.
Quickly show up in their friends app and
this makes for
a seamless user experience, and
simplifies the code for you.
Firebase apps also remain responsive
even when the user is offline, because
the database can cache your data in
the app using only a few line of code.
That means if a client makes a change to
the data that change is stored locally,
so the app continues to working
even when the device is offline.
When the user reconnects to the network,
the app will automatically synchronize
with the Firebase servers.
So similarly, any data even shown
in the app will still be there.
So, the user won't suddenly open to an
empty screen and none of us likes that.
The database aligns perfectly to
apps that use chat functionality
like friendly chat, but there are so
many other use cases for the database.
The database could be, for example,
used for mapping applications.
So the MapSwipe app uses
the database to store and
update information about locations
that need to be mapped, so
that humanitarian organizations could
find people in need during a crisis.
The database also works
with travel data.
Skyscanner is a travel search site
that uses Firebase to store data about
flights, hotels and car rentals.
And since this kind of info
is almost always changing,
the real-time database provides
a way to keep all of it up to date.
An Instacart is a shopping service
where you select groceries
to be delivered to your door
in as little as an hour.
It uses the database to show what food
is available to order right now and
keep track of what's in your order.
All of this is just to say, these apps
are multi-user, collaborative and
real-time and
the Firebase real-time database
meets these requirements nicely.
In order to understand how
the database could serve so
many different purposes, let's now talk
about the structure of the database.