In problem 4, we’ve given a list of n numbers
and our task is to find the mode, within time
Theta (n). And there’s a lot of different ways to
do this and – so, what I’ve done is, I’ve gone
through and basically written five different ways
of doing it. All variations of the theme really. In
the first case, what we’re going to do is, we’re
going to use a dictionary and when we iterate
through the dictionary, keeping track of the
element that has been seen the most often. So,
here we’re just doing initialization, if we haven’t
seen this value before we’ll create a key value
pair and set its value to 1. If we have seen this
key – this value before, we’ll just increment the
value associated with it. As we’re going along,
we can keep track of what the value – what
value we’ve seen the most. So, if the value that
we’ve just updated is higher than the previous
maximum value, we will set the current
maximum value to be this current key value
pair. As a result, by the time we finish this loop,
which is 1 pass through the list, we will know
the mode or we’ll know one of the values in the
mode, if there’s more than one value that has
the same number of appearances and we’ll just
return that. There’s a lot of different ways you
can do this and a slight variation of that, that
let’s us shorten our code a little bit is when you
can use the default dictionary that Python has.
And what we’re doing here is, we’re saying
basically that the first time you see a key, you’re
going to give it an initial value using this int
function, and it’s going to give it a value of zero.
So what that allows us to do, it lets us get rid of
this little bit of code here, that check to see
whether or not the value existed already, which
is a single look-up in a hash table basically. So,
what we do now is we just increment the value
by 1 regardless, and so the first time it sees it,
it’ll use the default dictionary value of zero, add
1 to it and give us the value of 1, so it’s
basically the same as what we’ve done before.
And the rest of the code is the same, just
keeping track of the maximum value and
returning it. Another thing you could do is you
can use the – the built-in max feature of Python
and again when we’re just doing incremental
changes, we’re going to use the default
dictionary again, we’re going to increment the
value, but instead of keeping track as we go
through, what we’re going to do instead is do
see this max at the end, with a little lambda
function that basically returned the number of
appearances that a given value had in the list
and then returning the maximum key. And to
show you that you can make it even more
compact, you can actually use the set feature of
Python. Pick our initial value, our initial list, turn
it into a set which removes all duplicates and
then use the same max function. And then if
you want to be even more compact, you can
even do it as a one liner, if you wish, and here
what we’re doing is everything in one line, using
the max function, we’re creating a set from our
initial list, so that gives us all the unique values
that we want. And then we’re using the lambda
function to say, give us a count of the number
of times this value appeared in our initial list,
and then return that value. Now, we talked
before – in class, we’ve talked before about
performance. And this is great, this is one-liner
code and that’s fairly understandable, but it’s
actually not nearly as fast as some of the other
things that we’ve done. There is a lot of repeat
passes through the list that occurs because of
the way that we’re doing this. And actually –
probably the fastest one that I’ve seen so far is
this one. Now there are some people on the
forums that may have faster ones and we’ve
been using the comparison functions done by
Anthony Pace to run test on it and this is – it’s
fun to play with. So anyhow, any of these things
work – there’s lots of different ways to find the
mode and a simple and straightforward pass
through a dictionary is a nice way to do it.
And it clearly finishes in time for Theta(n).