Let's look at the simplest
example of a light-field.
Here is a two-dimensional
light-field which basically,
same viewpoint, we never change.
And the best example of
this would be a panorama,
something we have looked at quite a bit
in detail in this class so far, right?
I put camera at one point.
I rotate it around to be
able to traverse the whole
spherical region around it,
and that can be used to generate an
image like these two types of panoramas.
And again, we have looked at
a variety of things like Google Maps,
Google Street Views and
also other types of panoramas and
stuff like that that we have looked
at including photo and stuff.
They also use geometry,
as we have looked at.