Like in the previous lesson,
this app, the Movie Manager,
has increased in complexity again.
And this is all the more reason for
us to check out the code base ourselves.
At work, I find myself diving into
unknown code bases all the time to get
up to speed on a new project.
Okay, so first you'll want to
download the starter code project for
the Movie Manager app.
I've posted a download link
in the instructor notes.
And then, you'll want to answer
the following questions.
Which class is used to handle
Step 2a of the movie database's
authentication flow?
Which class is the only
view class in the project?
What is the name of the file containing
constants for the movie database?
And finally,
based on the movie database constants,
how many methods of the movie
database API will this app use?
You can write your answers in
the boxes next to each question.