Okay, so we're ready for a quiz now.
We talked about sort of system mode and
user mode or
previous level that is needed when
you're in the kernel, and user mode.
So in this quiz we're going to talk
about a couple of different functions.
These functions could be executed
either in the operating system, so
you have to figure out if this function
belongs in the operating system,
or it could be executed in
application code that is running
outside of the operating system,
and that would be in user mode.
Depending on what this function is,
if it can only be carried
out in the operating system,
which is kernel mode,
then you should check operating system.
If you think it doesn't belong
in the operating system and
can be done at the user level,
then you should check user.
Okay, so
there are four different functions In
this quiz that you are to think about.
And for each, decide if it's OS,
system mode, or user mode.
Goes in that system portion of
the address space, one we provide at
the top, or can it be executed in
the user part of the address space?