So let's say we're studying
the housing market and
our task is to predict the price
of a house given its size.
So we have a small house
that costs $70,000,
and a big house that costs $160,000.
We'd like to estimate the price of
this medium-sized house over here.
So how do we do it?
Well, first we put them in a grid where
the x axis represents the size of
the house in square feet and the y axis
represents the price of the house.
And to help us out,
we have collected some previous data
in the form of these blue dots.
These are other houses
that we've looked at and
we've recorded their prices
with respect to their size.
In here we can see the small
house is priced at $70,000.
And the big one at $160,000.
Now, it's time for a small quiz.
What do you think is the best estimate
for the price of the medium house,
given this data?
Would it be $80,000,
$120,000, or $190,000?
Submit your answer below.