An interface definition
language is used to describe
the interface that
a particular server exports.
At the minimum, this will include
the name of the procedure and
also the type of the different
arguments that are used for
this procedure as well
as the result type.
So you see this is very similar
to defining a function prototype.
Another important piece of information
is to include a version number.
If there are multiple servers
that perform the same operation,
the same procedure,
the version number helps a client
identify which server is most current,
which server has the most current
implementation of that procedure.
Also the use of version
numbers is useful when
we are trying to perform
upgrades in the system.
For instance, we don't have to
upgrade all the clients and
all the servers at the same time.
Using this version number however,
the clients will be able to identify
the server that supports exactly the
type of procedure implementation that is
compatible with the rest
of the client program.
So this is basically useful for
so-called incremental upgrades.
The RPC system can use an interface
definition language for the interface
specification that's completely agnostic
to the programming languages that
are otherwise used to write
the client and the server processes.
SunRPC which is an example
of an RPC system that
we will look at later in this lesson,
uses an IDL that's called XDR.
External data representation.
And XDR is a completely
different specification from
any other programming
language that's out there.
We will describe XDR in more detail,
but here is an example of something
that's described with XDR.
And you can notice that
the definitions of things like
the string variable with
these angular brackets,
that's not really something that's
used in other programming languages.
It's very XDR specific.
If you would like, by the way, to read
ahead and examine a SunRPC example and
look at XDR in more detail, there are
links provided in the instructor notes.
The opposite of
a language-agnostic choice for
an IDL is to choose a language- specific
IDL to describe the interfaces.
For instance, the Java RMI,
which is a Javaequivalent of
RPC uses the actual, the same,
programming language JAVA.
To specify the interfaces that
the RMI server is exporting.
Here is an example of an interface
specified for Java RMIs.
Those of you that know Java will
immediately recognize that this looks
just like Java.
For programmers that know Java,
use of a language specific
IDL is great because they don't have
to learn yet another set of rules to,
how to define data structures or
procedures in another language.
For those that don't know Java
that are not familiar with
the specific programming language that's
supported by the server for instance.
Then this becomes irrelevant if you have
to learn something they might as well
learn something simple and
that is one of the goals that XDR has.
Now let me iterate one more time
that whatever the choice for
the IDL language, this is used only for
specification of the interface
that the server will export.
The interface, whatever is written
with this IDL language will be
used by the RPC system for tasks like
automating the stop generation process.
Generating the marshalling procedures.
And to generate information that's
used in the service discovery process.
The IDL is not actually used for the
actual implementation of the service.