A completely different way to organize
the address translation process is to
create so-called inverted page tables.
Here, the page table entries
contain information, one for
each element of the physical memory.
So, for instance, if we're thinking
about physical frame numbers,
each of the page table elements will
correspond to one physical frame number.
Today on the most high-end platforms,
we have physical memory that's on
the order of tens of terabytes,
whereas the virtual memory of an address
space can reach petabytes and beyond.
Clearly, it would be much more efficient
to have a page table structure that's on
the order of the available physical
memory versus something that's on
the order of the virtual memory
that a process can have.
To find the translation, the page table
is searched base on the process ID and
the first part of the virtual address,
similar to what we saw before.
When the appropriate pid and
p entry is found into this page table.
The index,
the element where this information is
stored, that will denote the physical
frame number of the memory location
that's indexed by this logical address.
So then,
that is combined with the actual offset
to produce the physical address that's
being co-reference from the CPU.
The problem with inverted page tables is
that we have to perform a linear search
of the page table to see which
one of its entry matches the pidp
information that's part of the logical
address that was presented by the CPU.
Since the physical memory can be
arbitrarily assigned to different
processes, the table
isn't really ordered.
There may be two consecutive entries
that represent memory allocated to two
different processes, and
there really isn't some clever search
technique to speed up this process.
In practice, the TLB will catch
a lot of these memory references so
this detailed search is not
performed very frequently.
However, we still have to
perform it periodically, so
we have to do something to make
it a little bit more efficient.
To address this issue,
inverted page tables are supplemented
with so-called Hashing Page Tables.
In most general terms, a hashing page
table looks something as follows.
A hash is computed on
a part of the address and
that is an entry into the hash table
that points to a linked list of possible
matches for this part of the address.
So, that allows us to basically speed
up the process of the linear search
to narrow it down to few possible
entries into the inverted page table,
as a result,
we speed up the address translation.