Alright, so let me try to get to this concept
of cross validation. So, imagine that we've got our data,
this is our training set. We can, again, picture geometrically
in the case of regression. And, ultimately what we're trying
to do is find a way of predicting values in
the testing set. So, what we imagine is we do
some kind of regression and we might want to fit
this to a line. And, you know, the line is
good, it kind of captures what's going on and if we
apply this to the testing set, maybe it's going to do
a pretty good job. But, if we are, you know, feeling
kind of obsessive compulsive about it we might say well in
this particular case we didn't actually track all the ups and
downs of the data. So what can we do in terms
of if we, if we fit it with the line and
the errors not so great. What else could we switch to Charles?
>> We could just use the test. No, sorry. What, what I mean
is if we fit, we fit this to a line and we're sort
of not happy with the fact that the line isn't fitting all of
the points exactly. We might want to use ,uh, maybe a higher order polynomial.
>> Oh, I'm sorry, totally misunderstood you.
>> To fit this better. So if we, we can fit this with a higher
order polynomial and maybe it'll hit, all these
points much better. You know, so we have
this kind of, kind of other shape, and now it's doing this, it's
making weird predictions in certain places. So, really what we'd like to
do is, and what was your suggestion? If we trained on the
test set, we would do much better on the test set, wouldn't we?
>> Yes.
>> But that, that, that's definitely cheating.
>> Why is cheating?
>> Is there some, why is it cheating? Well, if we
exactly fit the error, the, the test set. That's not a function
at all, is it? [LAUGH] If we exactly fit the, the test set, then
again that's not going to generalize to how we use it in the real world.
>> So the goal is always to generalize. The test set is just
a stand-in For ,what we don't know we're going to see in the future.
>> Yes, very well said. Thank you.
>> Actually that suggests something very
important, right, it suggest that ,um,
nothing we do, on our training set or even if we cheat and use the test set
.Actually makes sense unless we believe that somehow the
training set and the test set represent the future.
>> Yes, that's a very good point, that
we are assuming that this data is representative of
how the system is ultimately going to be used. In
fact, there's an abbreviation that statisticians like to use.
That the data, we really count on
the data being independent and identically distributed,
>> Mm-hm.
>> which is to say that all the data that we have collected,
it's all really coming from the same source, so there is no, no
sort of weirdness that the training set looks different from testing set looks
different from the world but they are all drawn from the same distribution.
>> So would you call that a fundamental assumption of supervised learning?
>> I don't know that I'd call it a fundamental of supervised learning per se,
but it's a fundamental assumption in a lot
of the algorithms that we run, that's for sure.
>> Fair enough.
>> There's definitely people who have looked at, well
what happens in real data if these assumptions are violated?
Are there algorithms that we can apply that still do
reasonable things? But the stuff that we're talking about? Yes,
this is absolutely. A fundamental assumption. Alright, but here's,
here's where I'm trying to get with this stuff. So
what we really would like to do, is that we'd
like to use a model that's complex enough to actually
model the structure that's in the data that we're training on,
but no so complex that it's, it's matching that so directly that
it doesn't really work well on the test set. But unfortunately we
don't really have the test set to play with because that again,
is going to, it's too much teaching to the test. We need
to actually learn the true structure that is going to need to
be generalized. So, so how do we find out. How can we,
how can we pick a model that is complex enough to model
the data while making sure that it hasn't started to kind of diverege in
terms of how it's going to be applied to the test set. If we don't
have access to the test set, is there something that we can use in
the training set that we could have it kind of act like a test set?
>> Well, we could take some of the training
data and pretend its a test set and that wouldn't be cheating because its
not really the test set.
>> Excellent. Indeed, right, so there's nothing magic
about the training set all needing to be
used to fit the coefficient. It could be that we hold out some of it ,as
a kind of make pretend test set, a test test set, a trial test set, a
what we're going to say cross validation set.
And it's going to be a stand in for the
actual test data. That we can actually, make
use of that doesn't involve actually using the test
data directly which is ultimately going to be
cheating. So, this cross validation set is going to
be really helpful in figuring out what to
do. So. Alright, so here's how we're going to do
this, this concept of cross validation. We're going to take
our training data, and we're going to split it into
what are called folds. I'm not actually sure why they're
called folds. I don't know if that's a sheep reference.
>> Why would it be a sheep reference?
>> I think there's a sheep-related concept that is called a
fold. Like, You know, we're going to bring you back into the fold.
>> Oh.
>> It's like the, it's like the group of sheep.
>> You are just trunk full of knowledge.
>> Alright so what we're going to do is train
on the first three folds, and use the fourth one
to, to see how we did. Train on the [LAUGH]
second third and fourth fold and check on the first
one. And we're going to we're going to try all these different
combinations leaving out each fold as a kind of a,
a fake test set. And then average these errors. The
,uh, the, the goodness of fit. Average them all together,
to see how well we've done. And, the model class,
so like the degree of the polynomial in this case that
does the best job, the lowest error, is the
one that we're going to go with. Alright, so if
this is a little bit abstract still let me,
let me ground this back out in the housing example.