So it's helpful to think
about how we would use this
potential function idea in
the context of Q learning,
instead of just solving Bellman
equations like we had a moment ago.
So in the setting of Q learning,
we're going to be keeping
some Q function, Q(s,a).
And each time we get a state
action reward next date quadruple.
We're going to update our state action
pair for this state action pair we just
left to be the, you know, little bit
more in the direction of the reward
plus the discounted value
of the state we end up in.
And this reward, now we're
going to use the real reward, but
now we're going to shift it around, mess
it around with this potential function.
So we're going to take the actual
reward, subtract the potential for
the state that we're leaving and
add the discounted potential for
the state that we're arriving in.
And so this is going to
be how we do our updates.
And so
if we run this version of Q learning,
what should happen in the limit?
>> The right thing.
>> Yeah.
So
it should actually solve the original
MDP, the one with just R here.
And it should ultimately
ignore the size.
So there's a sense in which we don't
really care what the size are.
So what if we choose like this one?
What if we say psi of s is
the max over all actions
of the optimal Q function Q*,
for that state action pair.
>> You mean the actual true
value of being in the state?
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, well first off, if we choose psi
to be that then we're already done.
>> Well so, yes and no, right?
We only can do this if we've
already solved the problem.
So admittedly this is an unrealistic
thing to be able to do.
But what does it do to Q?
What does Q end up being in this case?
>> Zero.
>> Is that obvious?
QSA Is going to be Q*(S,a)-
psi(S), right?
That's what we figured
out on the last slide.
And this psi(S) is
exactly -max a Q* (S,a).
>> Which is Q* (S,a).
>> Not exactly, right.
So Q(s,a), for
the optimal action, is zero.
>> Oh, you're right, I'm sorry.
What I just said is true for
when you take the optimal action.
It is zero.
>> Right.
So Q(S,
a) in this case is going to
be 0 is a is optimal.
>> And it'll be less than 0 otherwise by
a consonant for each action otherwise.
>> Right,
by the amount that it's suboptimal.
>> Yes, that's exactly right,
>> So this is kind of cool.
So if you think about initializing your
Q function to 0, which we often do,
because what do we know.
Then it should start off
actually doing the right thing.
It should maybe take some of the
non-optimal actions, discover that they
have a value less than 0, and
then after that just take the best ones.
So this give you an incredible
leg up on the learning problem.