Hello, and welcome to your
orientation for the iOS nanodegree.
In the next few videos,
we're going to make sure you have all of
the information and tools you need to
get started working on your nanodegree
and focus on your learning.
We're going to assume from here on
out that you've taken the readiness
assessment, and feel like you're
prepared to start the program.
>> It's super important that you go
through this orientation from the very
beginning to the very end.
We'll talk about everything from
how the program is structured,
to what we're expecting from you, to the
support you'll get through the program.
So let's get started.