So some of these you
probably already knew, but
I hope you looked up some of them too.
jpg is the most common
file name extension for
the jpeg image format which is
the most common format for photos.
LICENSE in all caps is a really common
name for software licenses on Linux and
other systems.
It's a plan text file.
Well, it's usually written in legalese
but technically that is plain text.
Now if you've used GitHub,
you've probably seen a file
called README.md before.
It's a text file in markdown format.
This next one is one
that surprised me a bit.
A lot of crypto keys are stored in
files with names ending in pem.
The keys for ssh for SSL web
servers are usually in pem files.
What does pem stand for?
It turns out this format was created for
an old project called
privacy enhanced mail.
That project didn't go much of anywhere
but the file format stuck around and
we still use it.
And for the last one, install.sh,
whenever you see a .sh file,
you're looking at a shell script.
A shell script is just a text file
consisting of shell commands.
Pretty much anything you can
do from the command line,
you can do in a script, too.