Here's a game that we've seen before.
We call this a single-player deterministic game.
We know how to solve this.
We use the techniques of search through a state space--the problems solving techniques.
We draw a search tree through the state space,
and I'm going to draw the nodes like this with triangles rather than with circles.
In any position--in this position here--there are three moves I can make.
I can slide this tile, this tile, or this tile.
So I have 3 moves, and that gives me 3 more states.
I keep on expanding out the states going farther and farther down until I reach one
that's a goal state, and then I have a path through there that gets me to a solution.
What does it take to describe a game?
Well, we have a set of states S, including a distinguished start state S0.
We have a set of players P that can be our one player, as in this game, or two or more.
We have a function that gives us the allowable actions in a state,
and sometimes we put in a second argument,
which is the player, in that state-making action,
and sometimes it's explicit in the state itself whose turn it is to move.
We have a transition function that tells us the result of,
in some state, applying an action giving us a new state.
And we have a terminal test to say is it the end of the game.
That's going to be true or false.
Finally, we have terminal utilities saying that for a given state and a given player
there is some number which is the value of the game to that player.
In simple games that number is a win or a loss, a one or a zero.
Sometimes it's denoted as a +1 and a -1.
In other games there can be more complicated utilities
of you win twice as much or four times as much or whatever.