[Norvig] There's one more type of search for plans
that we can do with the classical planning language
that we couldn't do before, and this is searching through the space of plans
rather than searching through the space of states.
In forward search we were searching through concrete world states.
In backward search we were searching through abstract states
in which some of the variables were unspecified.
But in plan space search we search through the space of plans.
And here's how it works.
We start off with an empty plan.
We have the start state and the goal state, and that's all we know about the plan.
So obviously, this plan is flawed. It doesn't lead us from the start to the goal.
And then we say let's do an operation to edit or modify that plan
by adding something in new.
And here we're tackling the problem of how to get dressed
and put on all the clothes in the right order,
so we say out of all the operators we have, we could add one of those operators into the plan.
And so here we say what if we added the put on right shoe operator.
Then we end up with this plan.
That still doesn't solve the problem, so we need to keep refining that plan.
Then we come here and say maybe we could add in the put on left shoe operator.
And here I've shown the plan as a parallel branching structure
rather than just as a sequence.
And that's a useful thing to do because it captures the fact
that these can be done in either order.
And we keep refining like that, adding on new branches or new operators
into the plan until we got a plan that was guaranteed to work.
This approach was popular in the 1980s, but it's faded from popularity.
Right now the most popular approaches have to do with forward search.
We saw some of the advantages of backward search.
The advantage of forward search seems to be that we can come up with very good heuristics.
So we can do heuristic search, and we saw how important it was to have good heuristics
to do heuristic search.
And because the forward search deals with concrete plan states,
it seems to be easier to come up with good heuristics.