Now that we've created
the food_pref variable
we can use it in other triggers too.
Your next task is to create
specials of the day for
each kind of food preference.
For this you'll need triggers for
each food preference.
An easy way to create the triggers,
is to go the Trigger screen,
copy the existing trigger, and
modify it to suit your needs.
I'm going to create the fish trigger.
And then don't forget to
change what the food pref is.
So for the fish trigger, obviously,
the food pref equals fish.
And save the trigger.
After you create a new trigger,
you can use it in a variable.
So this is how I'd create
the fish variable.
Copy the existing vegan special
variable, make sure you copy it,
don't edit the existing one.
Rename it.
Make sure you set a value.
It's got to be a fishy value.
And you'll have to change the trigger.
It's not vegan, obviously.
And pick your new trigger.
So if you've pre-created the triggers,
then this list of triggers
will be pre-populated.
And then that makes it quick,
and create the variable.
Now I have my daily
special fish variable.
So go ahead and create specials of the
day for each kind of food preference.
Create the triggers that you need.
And you already have the vegan trigger.
And create variables.
And again, you already have
the vegan special variable.
So go ahead and do these steps.
Create the triggers,
create the variables.
Handle the case where users don't
specify a food preference, and
publish and check the boxes as you go.
And then test out the app.
So we'll need to start and
stop your app, to make sure
the latest container downloads.
Go to, Show Daily Special,
pick one of these, go Vegetarian,
veggie pie with sauteed donut,
sounds delicious.
And all the other options
should work as well.