Casting relies on smoothly
coordinating two or more screens.
The users should never feel
like they're doing work.
Successful cast apps
have a familiar UI and
controls that minimize
the user's learning curve.
The receiver UI should be smooth and
cinematic and
feel as uncomputerlike as possible.
To help you build the best
possible cast experience,
Google provides a visual
design checklist.
Although following this checklist
is optional to publish your app,
it's highly recommended and
required if you'd like your app to
be featured at chromecast.com/apps.
To make it easier to build a UI
that follows these guidelines,
Google provides
the Cast Companion Library for Android.
This contains ready built features and
components you can reuse in your app,
also samples are available for
all platforms supported by Cast.
We'll cover both of these
later in the course.
For now, let's take a look at
the key points from the checklist.
Once your app is Cast enabled,
you'll want to let your users know.
A great way to do this is to show
a one time Cast Introduction Screen.
This is useful both to alert experienced
users to the new capabilities and
also to teach novices.
You can find a link to
this particular screen,
which you can reuse in your app,
in the instruction notes.
Next, it's important that users can
start and control casts at any time.
We recommend that the cast icon should
always be visible in the upper right
corner of your app whenever
a cast receiver is available.
When a receiver is not available,
don't show the icon at all.
And the color of the icon should
change to reflect the connected state.
Users should be able to easily control
the Cast device at any time and
from any place in your app.
It's important to always show playback
controls when you're casting.
These can either be full screen, or you
can show a persistent mini-controller
when the user is navigating
elsewhere in your app.
It's also important to show playback
controls when your device is locked, and
here's how it looks on
Android 5.0 Lollipop.
The task companion library makes doing
this very easy on any version of
Android, although the appearance might
differ slightly from version to version.
It's also important to show
playback controls via notification
when your app is out of focus.
If you use the task companion library,
you can also startup the notification's
service, so this notification will
show even if your app is killed by
the operating system, so
the user can always control the cast.
Also, make sure that users can always
disconnect from the device, and
they can bring up this disk
menu from the cast menu.
And keep in mind that if
multiple users are connected,
only stop the actual cast when
the last user disconnects.
In the event the connection
to the cast device is lost,
automatically reconnect users
when they're in your app.
Connections can drop for
a couple of reasons, for
example the WiFi could go out of
range or the users battery could die.
Also keep in mind that if your app
is killed without gracefully exiting
the cast session and the user
restarts your app, you can try and
rejoin the existing session
if its still running, and
the cast companion library will
make this task very easy for you.
Now a user can start
casting in one of two ways.
They can connect to the cast device and
then begin playing media, or
they can start playing media and
then connect to the cast device.
Either way,
once the user starts casting,
whatever they play in their act should
automatically be cast to the tv.
At this point, the phone is going
to allow the users to browse and
control the cast while the tv
displays the streaming content.
Remember the sender always
shows the action and
the receiver always shows the state.
It's very important that your Receiver
UI should never appear touchable, and
you should definitely not re-use
an existing phone or tablet UI.
If you do so this is going to confuse
your users and make them very unhappy.
On your Receiver UI it's important
to keep the users' content
front and center.
If they pause playback be sure to fade
away your controls after about five
seconds so they can see the full screen.
Let's recap with a quick quiz.