All right,
you're ready to answer these questions?
>> Yes, I think I am and
I think I know the answers.
I think they're yes, no, no, yes.
>> Great.
That's actually correct.
You want to tell us how you
can actually argue that?
>> Well, no but I'll do it anyway.
So let's take the ones that I
think are pretty easy, two and
three so
without even coming up with an example,
I think it's pretty easy to see
that those are contraction mapping.
And here is why.
So let's Imagine I started
out with two functions.
Let's say they were six and eight.
>> Okay.
So, we are going to say X equals 6 and
y equals 8.
>> Yes, but Y is the other function.
Well, what's the difference
between them?
It's 2.
>> So just let's make sure we
are applying this in the right context.
What we want is that the distance
before we've applied any operator to
them is going to be bigger than or
equal to the distance between them
after we've applied the operator.
>> Right.
And it has to be
the gamma's less than one.
This actually becomes important.
>> That's right.
All right, so you did x-y is 2, uh-huh?
>> Right, well x-y is 2, well when I
add 1 to both of them that'll just
become 7 and 9, but
the difference is just 2.
>> Okay, so
I do buy this, that adding one to
something shouldn't be a contraction.
But it seems like subtracting one from
something should make them smaller.
>> Right.
Except it makes both of them
smaller in exactly the same way.
And so, you're basically keeping
the distance between them constant.
>> Good point.
And in fact the same example works here.
So, 6 and 8 are 2 apart.
6 minus1 and 8 minus 1, or 5 and
7, are still exactly 2 apart.
So, 2 is not less than or
equal to any gamma less than 1 times 2.
>> Right.
>> So, yes,
I agree that these are not
contraction mappings and
the proof basically involved showing
a particular value of X and Y such that
they're not getting any close together,
they're staying the same distance apart.
>> Right and I think you can even prove
that by just basically writing down
the equation that relates X and
Y together.
Y is equal to X + 2, if I subtract
a constant from both sides or
add a constant to both sides
it doesn't change anything.
>> Very good.
>> All right.
So for the first one, x over 2.
Here's my thought process, and kind of
the proof that I ran through in my head,
and then the realization that I had
that made four actually easier as well.
Okay, so why don't you erase that?
And I'll give you an example
of what I was thinking.
All right.
So the x over 2 thing,
I thought are you going to
just keep dividing by two.
So let me come up with
an example in my head.
And I thought, oh,
I should use a power of two because
then I can keep dividing by two.
>> Hang on.
Hang on.
Well okay we'll let
you step through that.
But that's not going to
get us all the way there.
>> No it's not, but-
>> Okay, let's do it anyway.
>> Well I was just going
through my thought process.
Okay.
>> Great.
So just for
the sake of thinking out loud,
let's say x is 16 and y is 32.
So what's the distance between them?
Well it's 16.
>> Good.
>> Now if I divide both of
them by 2 I get 8 and 16,
>> Right.
>> And the distance between them is 8.
>> Good, all right, and
8 is definitely less than 16.
>> Right, but then I realize, oh,
this is actually pretty simple,
I'm glad I chose a power of 2.
That basically the distance between
x and y at any given, let's say,
time step, I chose x to be some 2 to
the n and y to be 2 to the n plus 1.
And then if I divide both of them by 2,
then the new distance will be 2
to the n minus 1 and 2 to the n.
>> Sure, but
this is only showing that it works for
things that are like consecutive powers
of 2, which is not what we need.
We need it to hold for all x and y.
>> Right, but that was the process that
I went through in my head to kind of
show that this will keep working.
And then I realized what's really
going on is I'm taking my value X and
making it smaller.
>> Sure.
But that's true of number three also.
>> That's true, but I'm making
it smaller in a geometric way.
>> [LAUGH] Okay.
>> You don't like it there?
>> To me, the easiest way to step
through this is to do the algebra,
to say that Bx is x over 2,
By is y over 2.
>> Yeah.
>> So the absolute difference
between them is actually equal to
1/2 of the distance between X and Y.
>> Yeah that's fair.
>> So I'm just factoring that.
And that gives us exactly what we want,
which is to say that the difference
before compared to the difference after
applying the operator is less than or
equal to some less than one value
multiplied by the old distance.
>> Yeah, that makes sense because
that's exactly what I was
doing when I went from 16 to 32 to 8 and
16.
>> Exactly, yeah.
>> I noticed
the distance was cut in
half every single time.
>> Right.
>> Okay, but
that general thing is going to work for
number four as well, right?
So the first thing to do to make that
really easy is to realize that although
you've written it as X
plus 100 times 0.9, so
I could rewrite that as
X times 0.9 plus 90.
>> Good.
>> Right.
So the X times 0.9 part is going to
keep reducing by exactly the same
argument that you did before.
I could take out the 0.9 and show that
it's just going to keep getting smaller.
So that parts going to get smaller and
since I'm adding a constant
every single time, it's not going to
change the actual distance.
>> Good.
>> So it will continue to get smaller.
>> Yeah, that's right.
And so algebraically,
if we have whatever X and y were before,
after we applied this operator, as you
just pointed out, it's actually going to
be 0.9x minus 0.9y, plus 90 plus 90, but
then they're going to get subtracted.
Ans so
this quantity is equal to .9 x minus y.
You just factor that out.
So whatever the distance was before
is actually contracting a little bit,
it's getting a little bit smaller, nine
tenths the size of what it was before.
>> Right.
And so, there are two things there.
One is, adding a constant, whether
the constant is positive or negative,
doesn't change the distance, because
they're going to cancel each other out.
That's why two and three don't work.
And then multiplying your
function by a number that is
less than 1 will make them get
closer and closer together.
Which suggests that if we were instead
to multiply them by a number greater
than 1, or actually 1 or
greater, you would end up with
something much much much worse.
If we get bigger and bigger and bigger
it would be an un-contraction mapping.
>> [LAUGH] Expansion mapping.
>> Yes, so expansion mapping,
I like that.
>> Great, okay nicely done.
>> Cool.