In this task, you're going to
set up a database for Wittr, and
add posts into it.
Some of the methods have
been stubbed out for you, so
you want to check out that code.
To do that run, get reset hard to
remove any local changes you have.
Then, get check out task-idb-store,
to get the stubbed methods.
We're back to editing Wittr, so
ahead over to
Public/js/main/indexcontroler.js.
In the constructor we're
creating a promise for
our database by calling openDatabase.
This method is incomplete, your task
is to return a promise for a database
called wittr that has a objectStore
called wittrs that uses id as its key,
and has an index called by-date,
which is sorted by the time property.
The idb polyfill has been imported
at the top of this script, so
it's ready to use.
Once you've done that, you need
to add messages to the database.
Down in _onSocketMessage,
the database has been fetched.
Your task, is to add each of
the messages to the Wittr store.
Note that we're not using
the entries in the database yet,
we'll do that in the next chapter.
This is a lot to cover, but
you've done most of this
already earlier in the course.
The code in public/js/idbtest/index.js
should act as a good reference.
Also, if your database gets into
a bad state, go into dev tools and
run indexedDB.delte-database,
and pass it a parameter of Wittr.
This will remove the database and
let you start afresh.
Once you've created the database,
refresh Wittr in the browser
to run your code.
Developing gets a lot easier if
you have developer tools open and
force update on reload checked.
So you only need to refresh
once to see changes.
If everything's working, you should
see the Wittr database and dev tools.
A Wittr's object stored,
a by date index, and some messages.
To double check everything is working,
head to the settings page, and
type idb-store into the test field,
then press enter.