If you we're writing code
to control this umbrella,
you would first create an object
to represent the umbrella.
One way to define an object
is to create a variable and
assign it to a pair of empty
curly braces like this.
You can verify that umbrella is
an object by using the type of operator.
The type of operator will return
a string that tells you the data type.
However, an empty object
is not very interesting.
Objects have properties and
things they can do.
To add this information, you can define
key value pairs for each piece of data.
Here, we've defined a property
key called color, and
it's value is pink,
since it's a pink umbrella.
This umbrella also happens to be closed,
so
you can add a property called isOpen and
set its starting value to false.
Now you have an umbrella object,
it's pink and it's closed.
Opening the umbrella is a task you
want the umbrella to be able to do.
It's not a property which is an
attribute that describes the umbrella.
Something the object can do is a method.
A method is just a function
that's associated with an object.
You've actually seen methods before.
Back when you used push and
pop with erase.
Push and pop are methods to add and
remove elements from an array.
Here is a method that
opens the umbrella.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
If you're a little confused right now,
it's okay.
Objects can be tricky to wrap
your head around at first.
But be patient.
We're going to go into more
detail in how to create objects.
Define property, and methods, and
use these objects in your code.