The answers are the first sentence has erroneous syntax.
We're using an and here between 2 terms, but you can't do that.
An and can only be used between sentences and predicates in first-order logic.
The second sentence does correctly encode the English sentence
Paris and Nice are both in France.
Similarly, the third sentence does correctly encode
there's a country that borders Iran and Syria,
but the fourth one incorrectly encodes it.
Here we have an existential. There exists a C.
And then an implication, and that's usually the wrong thing.
The problem here is not if C represents a country,
but what if C represents something that's not a country, say my dog.
My dog is not a country, so there does exist a c,
which is my dog, such that this implication is true
because whenever the antecedent of an implication is false,
my dog is not a country, then the whole thing is true.
For the final sentence in English, no 2 bordering countries
can have the same map color, both of these are correct encodings.
The first one seems more obvious,
and the second one we've just manipulated things a little bit.
We know that A implies B is the same thing as saying not A or B,
so here we've just taken the left-hand side and negated it
and then put those all together with an or,
so these 2 sentences represent the same thing,
and they're both correct.