So before we do think about how we are going to do this in machine,
what about humans?
How do humans see in 3D, all right?
And frankly, we can actually do this using just one eye before we
even get to two eyes because we in it, we look at these different cues.
So here's an example.
So, when you look at this picture, in fact,
when you look at any flat picture on a piece of paper or on a single screen,
there is only flat real depth, and you see the depth that was in the scene.
So, here we have perspective effect.
You assume that those houses are all the same size, and
their fading off into the distance is what makes them smaller.
So you perceive depth from this perspective effect.
Shading, here's a picture on the left and b and c are some of
the recovery of using an automatic method to try to recover the depth.
And it's using just the shading information.
You assume that the skin has a particular type of reflectance and
your brain figures out the, the depth in it.
By the way, this is why certain kinds of makeup is used, right?
By changing the shading on the cheeks,
you change the apparent shape of the face.
Even though, of course, you didn't change the face,
you just changed the reflection.
Texture, here you see a wall and
you can tell that the wall is sort of curving around.
And that's because the texture elements on it are changing.
Those circles with the little lines on them,
that's an early attempt at being able to recover orientation from texture.
A more recent piece of work done by Loh, here you have a picture.
You see the strawberry and you see the texture.
And the texture changes as the surface tips away from you.
And the system actually works on trying to recover the, the surface height or
the orientation from the change in texture.
And here's a really cool one.
Remember, we talked about that in real lenses there's a single focal plane
of depth.
That is, there is some plane out there in the world that's a depth, that,
that's in, that's in focus on the image plane.
And, the more you're away from that particular location,
the more out of focus you become.
So you might be able to take how an image changes focus as you
change the aperture.
Remember, a very tiny aperture, everything's in focus.
And as you open up the aperture, the depth of field shrinks.
And that means that things that are further away from that
focus plane get fuzzier faster.
So you could actually take multiple images from that same point, change the,
the aperture and figure that out.
So it's a little bit of a cheat.
because yes, it's one eye, but it's multiple pictures, all right?
Here's an image of them recovering a 3D to shape and depth from a de-focus.
And a last one, and
this is something we're actually going to look at a little bit later.
And in fact, it's actually related to stereo,
is the idea that from a single eye, if something moves, you can tell the shape.
Now, here's a picture of a statue.
And it's pretty hard for you to figure out the motion that you would use.
Mostly, you're looking at the shading.
So here's a simpler example, all right?
Now, if all our video gods are working right and
the web is working correctly, and you've got decent bandwidth, and
the moon is in the sun with the seventh house of Ju, whatever that is.
Anyway, you should all be seeing a rotating cylinder.
Now, some of you are going to be seeing it rotating counter-clockwise and
some are going to be seeing it rotating clockwise.
And that's because you can't be sure whether the pick, the, the dots moving to
the right, are in the front of the cylinder, or in the back of the cylinder.
But the idea is, purely from motion, you are seeing this cylinder rotate.
It's pretty amazing actually if you think about it,
and we'll talk a little bit about structure from motion later on in the class.
But the idea is from a single image, but the thing moving, you can get depth.
We're going to come back to that in
a minute because it's a single image with the thing moving.
Well, we can also have two images where the thing stays the same.