So, the correct answer is 0.1698 approximately,
and to compute this, I used the trick I've shown you before.
Let me write down the running count for cancer and for not cancer
as I integrate the various multiplications in Bayes Rule.
My prior for cancer was 0.01 and for non-cancer was 0.99.
Then I get my first +, and the probability of a + given they have cancer is 0.9,
and the same for non-cancer is 0.2.
So, according to the non-normalized Bayes Rule,
I now multiply these 2 things together to get my non-normalized probability
of having cancer given the plus.
Since multiplication is commutative,
I can do the same thing again with my 2nd test result, 0.9 and 0.2,
and I multiply all of these 3 things together to get my non-normalized probability
P prime to be the following: 0.0081, if you multiply those things together,
and 0.0396 if you multiply these facts together.
And these are not a probability.
If we add those for the 2 complementary of cancer/non-cancer,
I get 0.0477.
However, if I now divide, that is, I normalize
those non-normalized probabilities over here by this factor over here,
I actually get the correct posterior probability P of cancer given ++.
And they look as follows:
approximately 0.1698 and approximately 0.8301.