Welcome back again to computer vision.
Today we're going to continue a little bit,
on we did SIFT feature descriptors last time, descriptors in general.
And today, we're going to talk about matching them,
but we're only going to talk a little bit ab,
abou, matching, because actually there's only a little bit you need to hear.
So, okay, so where are we?
We, we know how to detect points, right?
So we detect, feature points.
And we now know how to describe them, this little, notial picture showing you
that we get the little feature descriptions, using, the, the, the sift, meth,
method we talked about where you get a 128-long vector as a descriptor for
each one of them.
So now the question is, how do we go about matching them?
Which is kind of a, sneak here cause I started off with this slide last time
that said we were going to do matching, we didn't do the matching,
we just did the descriptor.
I'm not even going to tell you about matching again,
I'm going to tell you about how to search for a match this time.