And so, here's our, here's our exercise.
Assume that you had to implement quick.
Or, more accurately, to design and implementation of it quick.
And to start doing that, you want to break it up into pieces.
I realize this is a small problem and maybe doesn't really warrant having
pieces, but assume that you want to break it up into component pieces, okay, and
we're going to represent the architecture you come up with as,
with a diagram called a box and arrow diagram.
And the boxes are going to correspond to the pieces or
components that you come up with.
And shoot for something like three to five or
six, different, different pieces, components, okay.
And come up with a label for each one of those components.
After you've done that, decide how the comp,
components are going to communicate.
And [COUGH] have line between two boxes saying how it's going to communicate.
And in particular there's two typical kinds of communication.
One is a flow of control, typically A calling B or A passing control to B and
the other is a sort of data, data communication that is
that one component uses the data in another in another component.
Indicate in your diagram which kind of communication,
whether it's a data communication or it's a flow communication,
control flow communication, and you can do that by using different line style or
whatever, or wanting a textural label.
And the trip of the exercise is I
want you to come up with at least two solutions.
>> Okay. >> Okay?
And so take, take a minute and see if you can't sketch out a couple of box and
arrow diagrams.
>> Do I need to be worried about assigning words to
talk about the relationships between the boxes and arrows?
>> So there's only going to be two kinds of relationships.
Okay, there's going to be, think of A calls B.
Okay?
And so you could just have one kind of line a solid line with
an arrowhead indicating that and the other is, A uses the data in.
Okay, you can think of that as a dash line or something like that.
Okay?