The next element of the MDP that we
need to include is the RewardFunction.
Burlap comes with an interface which
we can use to implement a custom
RewardFunction in our code.
First, we'll need to import
the RewardFunction and
then we'll add a RewardFunction
member to our first MDP class.
Now within the first MDP class,
let's make a static class that will
implement the RewardFunction interface.
I'm going to call it FourParamRF, since
the rewards will be based on the four
parameters P1, P2, P3 and
P4 we have in our state diagram.
P1 through P4 will be member
doubles of this FourParamRF.
And the constructor for
the FourParamRF will just initialize
these members based on the inputs.
We can then go ahead and add a line
to the end of the constructor for
the first MDP.
It assigns a new FourParamRF object
to the first MDP's new .rf member.
Now in order to implement
the RewardFunction interface,
we need to override the reward method.
This should match the reward
scheme from our state diagram.
This will be your test for
the next exercise.
Make sure to look at the documentation
for the RewardFunction interface for
the appropriate signature for
the method.
You might also find the getNodeId method
from Graph Defined Domain
helpful in writing your method.