We're going to use this quiz question
actually to reinforce the idea that
mandatory access control applies
in nonmilitary setting as well.
So hospital is found to be lax.
Unfortunately, there
are examples like these that you
read about in the newspapers
almost on a regular basis.
So they were lax in securing access to
patient records and they have a breach.
And a breach means basically
someone who's not authorized to
access those records is able to do that
or is able to gain access to them.
That's not a good thing.
So the hospital has violated
some kind of a policy.
And that policy, really, we talked
about in healthcare regulation,
is what requires that you handle
data with care or in a certain way.
So this quiz question basically is what
policy may the company have violated?
And there are two options.
Think about each one of those and
then we'll discuss the answers.