So the next step is to create the list
of geo-fences that you want the app to
actually trigger upon the user
entering or leaving them.
You're going to do this
using a final class.
So create this final
class called constants,
in which you're going to
store the constants.
Here's some starter code for you.
In this class create a HashMap.
And the hash map's key will be a string
and it's data will be of type LatLng.
Give it any name you like.
I'm just calling it Bay_Area_Landmarks.
And then, in this HashMap,
just create the list of entries based
on their latitude and longitude.
And you just saw how to find
out latitude and longitude.
So when you're done creating this class,
check this box.