And by the way, I happen to be
estimating position, velocity.
I could also estimate acceleration.
Right?
So, here my state position, my,
my state vector is position,
velocity and acceleration.
All right.
And I'm just including that to show you
that that's a choice that
you make as the model maker.
You're going to build a model for
doing this tracking, and this, and
this is what we're going to do.
And, again, I can write this out as
a linear system, using matrix notation.
But now we have, instead of a two by
two matrix, We have the 3 by 3 matrix,
which includes the components
having to do with acceleration.
By the way, the other choice,
you also have when you do this, and
I just mention this for
completeness, is you can assume
that there's noise in here or not.
You can make those be 0 and just have
the noise be in the acceleration.
It's not that you're assuming
your model is perfect.
That is,
that your estimates are perfect.
You're just saying, well I'm actually
going to believe that the velocity
that this is how
the position's really moving,
and this is how the velocity's
really changing.
And the only place that I'm putting
in any change is in the acceleration,
and you can, you can do that either way.
If you didn't understand what
that meant, don't worry about it.
Our measurement can still be the same.
It can just be position only.
And you might ask well,
if it's just position,
how do you ever get velocity and
acceleration?
These equations that we'll set up, will,
whether you sort of do the invert to
solve for things, it figures out that
you have to take the differences between
the positions,
divided by delta time velocity and
the difference between velocity is
divided by delta time for acceleration.
Even if we're only measuring position.