So now let me take a moment to tell you a little bit about the class.
This class is about computational photography,
which is actually nowadays also considered a discipline.
This discipline is about building the computational technology, and
the tools to basically figure out
how light from the environment is used to generate images and photographs.
We will be concentrating on the computational aspect of this pipeline,
how computation impacts photography.
It's an interesting discipline because if you really hard think about it,
the computation is impacting an artistic and
aesthetic aspect of what photography is.
But again, I emphasize,
we'll be spending time on trying to understand the technology that impacts this
whole pipeline of how light is used to generate images and photographs.