So what makes VR actually VR?
If you look closely at a VR headset,
you'll notice some common features.
They have two lenses for each eye.
And there are one or
more display panels behind those lenses.
Sometimes the headset has tracking
hardware built into the frame.
But is that all there is to VR?
A headset?
Well no.
Virtual reality is all about creating
a synthetic, believable, virtual world.
And that requires the precise
interplay of several hardware and
software systems.
Not just a headset.
This lesson is going to dive into
the major components of virtual reality.
Now we're going to touch on displays,
optics,
tracking, performance,
and even a bit of history.
It's pretty cool right?
Okay, let's start right into
the principles of virtual reality.