Before we get started, you may have noticed these cute,
wooden blocks on my desk.
They belong to my daughter, but I'm borrowing them for this course.
And during each lesson, I will illustrate some more complex concepts related to
operating systems using a metaphor that's based on toys and a toy shop example.
To give you a high-level idea of how this will work, we will think of
the hardware in computer system as the toy shop with its tools and
work spaces and storage areas.
Then we will think of all of the processes and applications that execute on
hardware as all of the toys that are being produced in the toy shop.
And then central to this course will be that we will drawing be
analogies between operating systems and
the toy shop manager that oversees everything that's happening in the toy shop.
This will become much clearer in the following classes.
For now, this concludes the introduction.
I sincerely hope you will enjoy this class.
Good luck and have fun.