One last thing about the fundamental matrix and we'll look more at this later.
The fundamental matrix is actually a three by three, right, because this is the,
homogeneous coordinate of an image point, so it's a three vector, okay.
But I will tell you we're going to show this in a little bit,
that the F matrix is actually singular.
And the reason for that is if it wasn't singular, it would map
between points and points, but, in fact, it maps between points and lines.
So it maps from a 2-D point to a 1-D line, and that's what, we sort of
requires that it be singular, we'll do a simple algebraic proof of it later.
But it makes sense, because when you give me a fundamental matrix and I give you
a point, you can't tell me the point over here, all you can tell me is the line.
So we're go from something that has zero degrees from a single point to
something that has another degree of freedom, and
that's because the rank of the fundamental matrix is only two and not three.
Like I said, we'll show that to you in just a minute.