Here are the answers.
Breadth-first search, as the name implies, expands nodes in this order.
One, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7.
So, it's going across a stripe at a time, breadth first.
Is it optimal?
Well, it's always expanding in the shortest paths first,
and so wherever the goal is hiding, it's going to find it by examining
no longer paths, so in fact, it is optimal.
Cheapest first, first we expand the path of length zero,
then the path of length 2.
Now there's a path of length 4, path of length 5,
path of length 6, a path of length 7, and finally, a path of length 8.
And as we've seen, it's guaranteed to find the cheapest path of all,
assuming that all the individual step costs are not negative.
Depth-first search tries to go as deep as it can first,
so it goes 1, 2, 3, then backs up, 4,
then backs up, 5, 6, 7.
And you can see that it doesn't necessarily find the shortest path of all.
Let's say that there were goals in position 5 and in position 3.
It would find the longer path to position 3 and find the goal there
and would not find the goal in position 5.
So, it is not optimal.