So this is the end of the, the lesson.
Mostly what we've just talked about is so
you understand more about correlation and convolution.
Remember, correlation we take the filter straight, convolution is it's
the 180 degree rotation so it's both left, right and up and down.
Most of the time if we're using symmetric,
when we're using symmetric filters it doesn't matter.
But if we're taking derivatives, right, so the derivative in the x direction,
there's actually a positive direction versus negative direction.
That's when you do have to
worry a little bit about correlation versus convolution.
And most importantly, filtering is going to be an important tool, sort of, in
your toolbox for how to deal with images and get out the elements that you need.
And we'll do more of that over the next time.
And then again, much later, when we're trying to compute features over images.