It's called an inception module, it's
going to look a little more complicated.
And you can skip this
section if you'd like,
it's not essential to
the rest of the lecture.
The idea is that at each
layer of your convnet,
you can make a choice have a pooling
operation, have a convolution.
And then you need to decide,
it is a 1x1 or a 3x3 or a 5x5.
All of these are actually beneficial to
the modeling power of your network, so
why choose?
Let's use them all.
Here is what an inception
module looks like.
Instead of having a single convolution,
you have a composition of average
pooling followed by 1 x 1,
then a 1 x 1 convolution then
a 1 x 1 followed by 3 x 3.
Then a 1x1 followed by a 5x5.
And at the top, you simply concatenate
the output of each of them.
It looks complicated.
But what's interesting is that you can
chose these parameters in such a way
that the total number of parameters
in your model is very small.
Yet the model performs better than
if you had a simple convolution.