Hi, my name is Patrick Nussbaumer, and
I'll be your instructor for this course.
I work for Alteryx, a leader in
self-service data analytics, and
I've worked with data acquisition and
analysis for over 20 years.
Imagine that you work
at a large bank and
you're contemplating changing operating
hours at all of your bank branches.
You're not sure if the change will
lead to better performance and
want to run an experiment to determine
if you should proceed or not.
It would be great if you could change
the hours at a few branches and
then base your decision on all branches
on the limited data that you gathered.
This is exactly the type of scenario
that is a perfect fit for AB testing.
Using AB testing methodologies, you
can design an experiment where you can
determine if the performance of a group
of branches with the modified hours have
statistically significant results
over the control branches.
And you can use this information
to guide your business decision.
In this course, we'll learn how
to set up and analyze AB tests.
AB testing is a type of experiment
with two variants, A and B,
which are the control and
variation in a controlled experiment.
You can use AB testing to
help solve business problems
when you don't have enough data
to use modeling techniques.
The two types of experiments that
will be discussed in this course
are randomized design and
matched pair design.
The first lesson in this course will
walk you through the fundamentals of
experimental design, then we'll
cover the two types of AB tests.
Lesson two will focus on
randomized designs and
lesson three will focus
on matched pair designs.
We'll then build upon what we've
learned in lesson four and
address a slightly more
complicated business problem.
To get started with experimental design,
let's introduce a business problem that
we'll reference throughout the course to
give some context to the terminology and
processes that you'll learn.
You've recently become the brand
manager for a large candy manufacturer.
The product development team
has been hard at work coming
up with a new line of products for
your brand.
As this is a new product and the company
is unsure if it will be successful or
not, you're being asked to
predict the effect on sales
if the new product is introduced so
management can determine if the product
should go into full distribution.
In this situation, we have no past
information to help us build a model and
predict what will happen in the future.
Being in this data-poor situation, we
have only one course of action to help
us with our business problem,
set up an experiment.