Now that you've seen all
the parts of a function,
let's put those pieces together.
We'll write a few function definitions,
and then call those functions.
We'll start with a description of the
task the function should accomplish and
go from there.
Here, our goal is to write a function
that takes in a string and
returns the first
character of that string.
We'll start with func,
and then we need a name.
I'm going to call this
one firstCharacter.
In general,
don't shy away from long names.
Especially in the age of code
completion, it's more important to be
descriptive than to save yourself
a few milliseconds of typing.
So we have our name, next comes
the parameters between parentheses.
Let's call the string we're
going to pass in word.
word will be its local parameter name,
and then we specify its type, String.
Next comes an arrow and the return type.
Our return type in this
case is a character.
And finally,
we get to the meat of the function.
In between curly braces here, we'll
put the statements we want to execute.
And I'm just going to add
a return statement here so
the compiler stops complaining.
There are a few different ways to
get the first character of a string.
I'm going to use subscript syntax
with the index startIndex.
And of course, once we get that value,
we want to return it.
Now, since this function doesn't
belong to any particular class,
it's a global function.
So in order to call it,
we just write its name, firstCharacter,
and next we'll pass in
a parameter between parentheses.
Now, notice that we didn't specify
an external name for our parameter.
We only gave it the local name, word.
If you don't specify
an external parameter name,
the external name matches
the local name by default.
So here we'll type word, and
then the string we want to pass in.
What if we did specify an external
name for our parameter?
I'm going to suggest that we
use the preposition of as our
external parameter name.
In general, it's nice to choose
parameter names such that
the documentation reads
like an English sentence.
Now, our function definition will
read firstCharacter(of word:).
And now that we've specified
an external parameter name,
we switch out the external parameter
name in our function call.
And we can see here in the side bar
that the function is evaluating to M.