I'll go ahead and stop because I
want to show you one more thing.
Let's disable this break point
in the handle single tap method,
and let's go ahead and
add a break point if we scroll up
a little bit to the- here we go,
add bug to view method on line 33.
And I'll run the app again.
I'll tap the Breakpoint Debugging scene,
and then tap on the screen.
Now this time, our stack trace
includes stack frames for
both addBugToView(),
here at the top, and handleSingleTap.
And you'll notice again as I
click through these stack frames,
the information that's available
in the variables view changes.
And that's because each stack
frame contains different state,
which was available to it
at the time it was reached.
So in the handleSingleTap,
we have the recognizer and self, and
then the add bug to view.
We just have self and
then this new bug, and remember,
you can always switch this view
mode to see additional information.
So let's go ahead and focus on self,
which is an instance of the break
point bug view controller.
If you click the dropdown, we can
see that it has a reference called
bugFactory, it's a reference
to a BugFactory object, and
that it has a value for
maxBugs, which is currently 0,
moveDuration, a disperseDuration,
and then our array of bugs.
And that's an array of UIimageviews.
We also see our current values.
And if you look closely, you may already
see what's causing some of our problem.
Currently, max bugs is set to zero and
the bugs array also
contains zero values.
This means that this if block
will not execute because account
of the bugs array is zero, and
that is not less than the value
of max bugs, which is also zero.
This sounds like a valid hypothesis.
But how can we be so sure?
Well with breakpoints,
we can actually test the hypothesis.
Breakpoints not only allow us to
pause the execution of our apps, but
we can actually run our apps
step by step or line by line.
And this is going to allow us to see
if the if block is actually being
entered or not, and we'll do this next.