So let's look at the convolution theorem and
its relationship to the Fourier transform.
So imagine if we were to do a convolution of two filters or two functions here.
We'll also want to do or compute a Fourier transform of it.
Basically that's a to the product of the individual Fourier transform.
So if I want to do a convolution of, of g and h, well what I can always do
is convert each one of them to their Fourier transform and just multiply them.
The inverse Fourier transform of the product of two Fourier transforms.
So here basically is the two Fourier transforms.
And we have inverses of them.
basically, it's a convolution of two inverse Fourier transforms.
So to compute this, I would just basically compute the inverse Fourier
transforms with both of them and just do a convolution.
And that will result in the answer for this one.
The other thing to note is the convolution in the spatial domain,
that is the amplitude and time domain.
Is equivalent to the multiplication in the frequency domain.
Again, these are simple examples.
We'll see many practical ways of actually using that