[BLANK_AUDIO]
One of the warnings I give people
who are looking to participate in
competitions is that it can
be incredibly addictive.
[LAUGH] If you think about how you
approach machine learning use case or
something that you're drawing outside
of Kaggle, you might go to it,
take a quick stab at it,
evaluate your results and say okay,
I did a decent job of that and
then move on to something else.
However, if you're competing
in a Kaggle competition,
you download the data,
write code on it to create
a bench mark on it as you would
starting a normal problem, however,
the difference is you're making
a submission to our leaderboard.
And when you make that first submission,
almost inevitably,
you're not going to be doing very
well in that first submission.
And you see everyone above you, and then
that makes you ask the question what
are these guys above me
a doing that I'm not getting?
Or how can I do better than them?
And that question keeps striving you
to try to do better and better at our
problem and it really forces you to
explore the scope of supervised machine
learning and the different methodologies
and approaches that you can use.
So it means that you're not just
attacking a problem in one or
two different ways but
trying to throw a thousand
different ideas at a problem and
figure out the couple that make a really
big difference in the model performance.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
There's many different ways that
Kaggle's users engage in our platform.
Some of them only ever work solo and
work on their machines,
don't really interact very
much with the community and
use their own entirely
locally developed approaches.
Others are very much into Kaggle for
the social aspect as well.
They have a set of people that
they really like to team up with,
and many of which they
met through Kaggle.
Then they work very cooperatively as
part of the team to do the competition.
We don't really see much of
a pattern who wins competitions.
Sometimes it's someone
that's working solo,
other times it's a large team that
wins it and everything in between.