The algorithm just described,
which we call approximate metric TSP, is
a polynomial-time factor 2-approximation
algorithm for the metric TSP problem.
The process for building the minimum
spanning tree is order v squared for
dense graphs and the depth for
a search process takes time proportional
to the number of edges in the tree,
which is the same as being proportional
to the number of vertices.
That takes care of
the efficiency of the algorithm.
Now for the two factor part.
Consider this example here and
let H star be a minimum
cost Hamiltonian cycle.
This is what an exact solution to
the traveling salesman problem
might look like.
Well, the cost of the minimum spanning
tree that the algorithm finds
must be less than the total cost
of the edges in this cycle.
Otherwise, just removing
an edge from the cycle
would create a lower cost
minimum spanning tree.
Remember that all the cost
here must be non negative.
Now let's draw a minimum
cost spanning tree.
The cost of the depth for a search
traversal, found by the algorithm,
is twice the cost of the sum
of the edges in the tree.
This traversal starts and
ends at the same vertex.
The trouble, however,
is that it's not Hamiltonian.
It might visit the same
vertex more than once.
It's simple enough,
however, to simply count only
the first time a vertex is visited.
This is what ordering vertices by
their discovery time achieves.
By the triangle inequality,
skipping over intermediate vertices
can only make the path shorter.
So the cost of the cycle returned by
the algorithm is at most twice the cost
of the sum of the edges in the minimum
spanning tree that we found.
This recall, however, is at most
the cost of the optimum cycle,
giving us a two-factor approximation,
that's the proof of the theorem.
It may be useful to view the argument
on a scale like this one, with zero at
the bottom and maybe the cost of
the most expensive cycle at the top and
the minimum cost cycle
somewhere in the middle.
As we argued,
the cost of a minimum spanning tree
must be less than the cost
of the optimum cycle.
We can just delete one edge from
the cycle and get a spanning tree.
A depth-first traversal of this spanning
tree uses every edge twice, and
is therefore twice the cost of the tree.
Shortcutting all but the first
visit to a vertex in this traversal
gives a Hamiltonian cycle,
which must have lower cost than
the depth-first traversal because
of the triangle inequality.