Now let's define a function value of S,
which tells us how to compute the value for a given state,
and therefore will allow us to make the best possible move.
If S is a terminal state, then the value is just the utility of the state
given by the definition of the game.
If S is a maximizing state, then we'll return something called max value of S,
and if S is a minimizing state, then we'll return min value of S.
Now we can define max value to just iterate over all the successors
and figure out the values of each of those.
We'll initialize a value m equals minus infinity,
and then we'll say for all pairs of actions and successors states in successors of S,
we'll say the value is--and let's call this S-prime so we don't get confused--
the value of S-prime and M for keeping track of the maximum so far and the new value.
Then when we're all done we return the M with the maximum value.
This will compute the maximum at a maximum node over all the states
that we have from all the possible moves.
The definition for min value is roughly equivalent but just reversed,
taking the minimum instead.
With these three recursive routines--value, max value, and min value--
we can determine the value of any node in the tree.
Now to do that efficiently, you'd want a little bit of bookkeeping
so you aren't recomputing the same thing over and over again,
but conceptually, this will answer any two-player, deterministic, finite game.