I'm here with Jarrod Parkes, who is
a course developer here at Udacity.
Thanks so much for
talking with us today Jarrod.
>> Absolutley.
>> I'm going to talk to
Jarrod today about games, and
using games in learning.
So let me start by asking Jarrod,
what experience do you have
with using games in learning?
Do you have any projects
you've worked on in the past?
>> Yeah before projects,
as a gamer at a young age,
a lot of the games that I played were
ones that had like a really strong,
I wouldn't necessarily say educational
skew, but they were developed to a point
where they taught some concepts
that I was learning in school.
And I was like hey, I'm learning
the same things playing games as I
am in class, and
I felt that effectiveness there.
But in terms of projects, yes I've
worked on a couple projects that used
game engines to teach science and
biology specifically.
And those seem to reach a certain
group of students pretty effectively.
>> Very interesting.
So when you're talking about using game
engines for that, is it building a game
for it, or is it just kind of
using the physics simulation, or
something like that for
the learning process?
>> It's more using the physics engines,
and
the other different components
that game engines have, and
presenting something that looks and
feels like a video game but
in terms of maybe game logic, or
other types of game objectives.
Those may not necessarily exist.
There's different ways
to I guess classify.
You also have technology.
There are apps that
are using game technology,
that are more like gamified learning.
As opposed to something that's more of
like a full in depth 3D experience,
where maybe you're walking around in
an environment that is historically
relevant and doesn't exist today.
And you're seeing it and experiencing
it, as opposed to something that's kind
of like quiz games, or something like
a brain game trivia style type stuff.
>> So, talking about a spectrum that
runs from, giving students badges or
achievements for
completing the kind of work they
probably would have been doing anyway.
All the way to building kind of these
more robust, exploratory environments,
where students can actually experience
playing with some real system.
>> Right, and systems and
also things that are telling stories.
For me history was the thing that
really I learned through games.
A lot like you might learn through
movies, or other media where you're able
to portray something in a interesting
way in something that's engaging.
>> So do you think that kind of
teaching approach is inherently better,
is it always better, are there
certain fields it works better in?
>> I think it's better for
certain cases,
I don't think it is the all in one
solution, it's not the silver bullet.
But for certain mediums,
that maybe classically aren't
interesting in a classroom setting
I think it's great to explore ways to
bring in game tech to make learning fun.
>> Yeah.
Does it apply to everybody or
does it appeal to everybody, or
do we need to be aware sometimes
of the type of audience we're reaching
with some of those interventions?
>> I think you have to be very aware.
I think for certain students,
you can approach them with
some learning application that's
using game technology, and
they would tell you
themselves that they love it.
And to those students I say,
let's give them more of what they like.
For the students that
you're not engaging,
I think you take an alternate route.
>> So, is the main purpose of
that approach engagement, or
is there something more to it?
Is it to get them interested?
Or, is there some fundamental learning
that's easier to do through this kind
of arrangement?
>> I think for
things that are visually based,
they're hard to conceptualize on
a whiteboard, or just extract from text,
than things that are in a video game
setting using physics or other things.
Yeah it would probably be easier
to teach in a game way, for
certain things no, though.
Math maybe not, that's I think
the chalkboard has been an effective
way of teaching math for a long time,
but I think some of those things where
you get to say games are getting better.
Engines are getting better in
terms of what they can do and
what they can simulate.
>> And I agree,
I think that when we're designing games,
there's an authenticity there we really
need to pay attention to that when
we're able to use those engines to
create an authentic experience,
then the learning kind of follows that.
That it might be more engaging sure but,
even if it's not inherently
more engaging if it can build
a closer experience with whatever that
system we're going to explore is.
That's the old better.
So what are the new coming horizons?
What are the new frontiers in using
games in educational environments?
>> I think there's a lot of interesting
things that are being re-thought
about and rehashed in computer AI.
Oh man.
Systems that respond more
intelligently and more realistic, and
those types of things, I think, will
be more prominent in the coming years.
I know there's a lot of
research being done there.
And I'm happy and excited to see
how that's going to translate from
something that's maybe purely academic
to something that's more in games.
>> One of my favorite topics that, it's
covered a good bit here at Georgia Tech
is game AI for story telling,
for narrative story telling,
because it creates a kind of nice
experience where not only students,
in human history for example.
Not only are we putting them in
a environment where they can
look around and see what it looked
in some historical time period, but
we might actually be able to create
a world that they can interact with.
And, that actually has
the kinds of stories and
kinds of experiences we want to teach
them, as something they can just find,
and just emerges out of some
system that they interact with.
So it's very personal to them but it's
also very authentic to whatever system
we're, or
whatever time period we're exploring.
>> Yeah.
>> So for
any of our students who want to use
games for teaching, do you have any tips
on things they should be aware of,
things that they should look in to?
>> Yeah, I think it's important
to start with an idea, and that
idea needs to be something, that maybe
the motivation isn't games at first.
And really sit down and think about
is how I'm using this game technology
an effective mechanism,
as opposed to something else.
Don't just go, I like games,
let's figure out how to take what I've
learned in classroom and make it a game.
It should be approached with
a little bit more caution.
>> And I agree, I think that there's
some theory about motivation that says
that when we kind of gamify
the traditional educational experience,
we actually risk hurting it,
especially down the road.
So I agree with you that I think,
what we really need to pay attention to
when we're building educational games is
building the game out of the authentic
portions of the material,
as opposed to just attaching a game
onto what students are doing anyway.
>> Right, consumers of games and
of technology in general can see when
something feels cheap, and
if the experience feels cheap I
think you're going to lose more students
then the ones you're going to help.
>> Great.
Well thank you so much Jarrod for
talking to us today.
>> Absolutely.
>> And thanks you all for watching.