Welcome back to Intro to Computer Vision!
The last time we talked about homogenous transforms, and
said how they were a form of a projective transform.
And we showed for a high chromographies are your best friend.
They allow you to map from one plane to another and to be able to map image
planes, and that allowed us to do panoramas and other kinds of cool things.
Today what we're going to do
is we're going to get a little heavier in the projective geometry stuff.
It's actually a short lesson.
And we're doing this for two reasons.
Well three reasons.
One is no self respecting computer vision person should not
know something about projective geometry.
So, you can say you know something about projective geometry and
impress your your parents.
More importantly.
Or, or maybe significant others if you're dating a nerd.
More importantly we're going to use in a little bit when we
talk about the relationship between multiple views.
Because projector geometry is just a very convenient way
of representing the projection operator.
Which after all is how images are made.