Once we get into that kind of concept, we will now move to
more advanced ideas of how actually we do computational photography.
So for example, learning how to build panoramas.
This is a panorama I took of the Georgia Tech basketball team,
the Yellow Jackets at their arena a few years ago.
Or also how do you play around with high dynamic range imagery like this one
,where you can actually see the snow, and also the insides quite clearly.
We'll learn more about how to do image editing, but more importantly,
you'll get to play around with all of this, by doing some simple coding and
programming will lead you to things like HDRs and panoramas.