And, not surprisingly, the answer is
all of those companies and many, many, many more
use massive machine learning for making decisions
that are really essential to the businesses.
Google mines the web and uses machine learning for translation,
as we've seen in the introductory level. Netflix has used
machine learning extensively for understanding what type of DVD to recommend to you next.
Amazon composes its entire product pages using
machine learning by understanding how customers
respond to different compositions and placements of their products,
and many, many other examples exist.
I would argue that in Silicon Valley,
at least half the companies dealing with customers and online products
do extensively use machine learning,
so it makes machine learning a really exciting discipline.