Activity diagram. Well that's the one that's, of course, there's a flow
of control from activity to activity. As far as the sequence diagram, that's
an interaction of classes in terms of message exchanges. Communication diagram.
That's object interaction in terms of numbered messages. Interaction overview.
Synthesis of lower level behavioral diagrams. Timing diagram.
Well that's the rotated sequence diagram.
That's also going to have specific time laid out on it. The use case diagram,
well that system functionality provided to its external actors.
And the state diagram, that's dynamic behavior in response to stimuli.
[BLANK_AUDIO]