Here's the answer I was looking for,
log P for
the alpha term, and
log squared P for the beta term.
The exact calculation isn't hard, but
it does have some tedious algebra.
So what I'll do is just walk you through
the setup, if you want the details,
see the downloadables section for
this video.
The key question is where
does communication happen?
Recall that the bitonic sort network is
a sequence of bitonic merging stages.
These stages start small and
grow larger.
Let's number these
stages from 1 to log n.
Now pick some stage and call it k.
What is the size of each bitonic merge?
Well, it's 2 to the k.
Now, suppose you use a block
distribution with P processes.
Notice that you only need to communicate
when the size of the merge exceeds
n over P,
which is the amount of data per process.
In other words,
there's no communication here, and
you only start communicating
at this stage.
Now, in one of these
stages where the merge
is spread across multiple processes,
how many processes are interacting?
Here's one way to express the number.
As a sanity check,
notice that when k is equal to log N,
then this thing simplifies to just P,
the total number of processes.
Now, bitonic merge of
size M on P processes,
takes this much time to communicate.
We just need to sum this time over
all the stages in which communication
happens.
Remember you only communicate when
k is greater than log n over P.
The tedious algebra part is
just plugging this into this.
So if you plug in and
simplify you should get this.