Okay, so now we're going to do
something slightly different here.
We have a set of views that
will be our header, and
at the bottom there's another
set of views, the footer.
Right in the middle we have a text view,
although it could be
any other kind of view, whose job
is to keep header and footer apart.
Sounds easy as pie.
Let's give it a try.
Before we start,
remember the guiding principles.
Start small, and
work from the inside out.
So first of all, let's create the header
with two labels and two text fields.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now let's apply the second
commandment and
put these two guys inside of stack view.
By now you should understand
why the text field shrank.
Let's create another one for
the last name.
Put them inside a stack view.
Let's combine them both using the second
commandment and create the header.
Select both stack views, and
put them inside of another stack view.
Now let's make a row of buttons for
the footer.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Let's put these guys
inside a stack view and
now we'll create the text
view in the middle.
Let's finish up by combining
everything into our main stack view,
and add the constraints needed
to make it stick to the edges.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay, so this is easy to fix.
Update frames, fix misplacement.
And this is what we get.
Well, it did seem easy, but
it didn't turn out very well.
Take a deep breath and recall
the last principle of auto layout.
Don't panic.
Pause the video and make a list
of everything that went wrong.
We'll be fixing it in the next video