Another property of a network that
you should really care about is its
bisection width and
there's a related concept which
is the bisection bandwidth.
The bisection width is the minimum
number of communication
links that you have to take out in order
to cut the network into two equal parts.
Equal is measured by
the number of nodes.
For simplicity, lets assume that
the number of nodes is even so
that bisection is well defined.
Eep!
For linear network, cutting this
link will break the network into two
approximately equal size pieces.
Again equal is measured in
terms of the number of nodes.
In this case, you only need to break one
link, so the bisection width is one.
I'll denote by section
widths by capital B and
in general they'll be a function
of the number of nodes.
What's the bisection of a 2D mesh?
Here's a cut that breaks the network
into two equal size pieces.
In this case each half
has eight nodes a piece.
This cut goes through four links.
In fact, there is no cut with
fewer than four links, so
the bisection width is four.
For instance,
here's another cut that breaks
the network into two equal sized pieces.
However, this cut is not a bisection.
It goes through one, two,
three, four, five, six links.
Now in general, a mesh with P nodes,
will have a bisection
width of square root of P.
So, why do you care about bisection?
Well, one really important communication
pattern is something called an all to
all personalized exchange.
An all to all is a collective,
where every node wants to send
a piece of data to every other node.
Sort of like a bunch of nodes
shouting at each other.
And what this means is that every
node in one half of the network
will want to send messages to every
node in the other half of the network.
So all message traffic will have
to go through the bisection.
Of course networks with larger bisection
widths will have a better capacity for
carrying all that traffic.
Now, for the fully connected network,
we said there were about P
squared over two links in total.
Remember that every node has
a direct link to every other.
So to cut in half,
you'd have to take about half the links.
That yields a bisection width
of about P squared over four.
Now, related to the concept of
bisection width is the concept of
bisection bandwidth.
Let's explain this by example.
Suppose you have a 2D mesh.
Let's say the speed of every link is
beta measured in words per unit time.
If all the links have the same speed,
as in this example, then the bisection
bandwidth is just the product of the
bisection width with the link bandwidth.
In other words, the speed across
the bisection is the bisection width
times the speed per link.
What if you have links
with unequal speed?
In that case, you would look for a set
of links that cut the network in two and
have a minimum total bandwidth.