So here's the first property.
First property says that for
all Q functions,
U1 and U2, and
see I used a Q function and U together.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Just because you thought it was funny
that I kept saying Q function and Q.
So now I said Q function and U.
>> [LAUGH]
>> All right,
for all
>> Q functions U1 and U2 and
state action pair SA.
This is true, all right, what the heck.
What's happening here,
we're taking this B operator,
applying it to U1 to get a new
operator that we apply to Q star and
we compare that to that same
Operator Bt applied to U2.
Whatever operator we get out of
that we also apply to Q star.
What has to be true,
what we need to be true,
is that this is going to be less than or
equal to one minus the learning rate,
times the difference
between the U functions.
So this is a non-expansion
property again.
Right, that the update rule, the
>> Right,
that the update rule, the operator
that we're using to modify the inner
value function at the B, is going to
have this averaging property to it that
what we're ultimately doing is
computing the expected value.
It's not exactly what this says, but
that's how it's going to be used.
>> Okay.
>> So the important thing
here is this just doesn't make
things get farther apart.
Okay, by the way, I just want to
say I really appreciate your proper
use of farther instead of further.
It makes me very happy.
>> I try really hard
when I'm talking to you.
>> Thank you, I appreciate that.
>> All right, so here's the second
condition that has to be true.
That for all Q functions Q,
Q functions U, and state S action a,
we need another kind of, well in this
case, contraction property to hold true.
There's a, our gamma is sitting
in there, gamma is less that 1.
See.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And what we're saying is that
if we hold fix this U value,
this value that plays this
role in the operator, and
the other 1 is Q* and Q
>> That we actually get a contraction of
Q towards Q* by applying
this operator in both cases.
All right, so
[LAUGH] we're almost there.
Lastly, we're going to need our standard
condition on the learning rates to hold,
right, which is that they
sum up to infinity and
the square sum of less than infinity
>> But
there's something hidden
in this definition.
It took me a long time when I read
the first proofs of this, like,
no this can't be true.
In fact, what's happening here is that
given that we set the learning rate
to zero, when there's state-action
pairs that we're not visiting.
The only way that this sum of learning
rates for state-action pairs is going to
be infinity, Is if we visit every
state action pair infinitely often.
So not only is this saying something
about the learning rates have to change.
It's giving an additional constraint on
how we have to visit state action pairs.
>> Wait, so then if that's true that
gives you infinity why doesn't that give
you the squared?
Why does that still get you
the square less than infinity?
>> So the infinity and
the square less than infinity is here,
because we're going to be doing the
standard kind of averaging trick, and
we need the learning rates
to decay the right way.
But what I'm pointing out is that in
addition to that condition that we
generally we need when we're doing
convergence of stochastic things.
We also have an additional
constraints that's hidden in here.
Which is it's saying, we have to visit
all state action pairs infinitely often.
If we don't,
then the sum of the learning rates is
not going to be infinity,
it's going to be something finite.
Oh, I see.
No, no, no, that's right,
that makes sense, that makes sense.
Oh, so cool.
So
basically our algorithms
will converge so
long as we take an infinite
amount of time.
>> [LAUGH] Well,
convergence is an infinite amount of
time kind of thing, just to be fair.
>> Mm-hm, mm-hm, no,
that's very, very satisfying.
Later in the class we'll talk about
some results that actually hold,
believe it or not, infinite time.
But this, yeah, this result is
intended to hold in infinite time.
>> I'll believe it when I see it.