Now you'll learn how to run queries to
find conferences that were created by
a specific user.
Remember that each conference
has an ancestor and
that ancestor is the profile
entity of the user who created it.
So here's how you create
a query to get all entities
that have a particular ancestor.
You just add an ancestor argument to
the query with the key being the profile
of whichever user it
is you're looking for.
This kind of query is
called an ancestor query.
But you can also think of it as a
descendant query because it lets you get
all the descendents of
a particular entity or
all the descendants that
match a particular kind.
So for conferences, this will get
all of the conference objects
that were created by a particular user.
Now you already dealt with the response
classes for conferences, so all you'll
need to do is define get conferences
created in the conference API.
It doesn't need to accept
anything from the request so
you can use void message there.
But since this query, query's for
conferences created by the logged in
user, you need to make sure the user
is logged in, and if not, throw
the endpoints unauthorized exception.
That's your task for this exercise,
define the endpoint,
test it, then deploy and
create some conferences.
The sample code is in lesson four
editions to do three conference.qy.
Once you're done adding
getConferencesCreated to the conference
API, test your code on localhost,
deploy it to appspot,
create several more conferences, and try
querying them, and put your app ID here.