So I've got the site open on my mobile
device, and I will start tapping.
Okay, so did you see that?
It goes aqua then pink.
So Aqua is active, and pink is actually
HotPink, and that means hover.
Notice that no matter what you do,
you don't see FireBrick showing up.
But that was on an iOS device.
I wonder if it's any different
on an Android device?
Let's see.
Okay, so it goes Aqua,
then FireBrick, interesting.
Last time on the iOS device,
I didn't see FireBrick.
I wonder if HotPink is there?
If I press down on a button and
then slide my finger off,
the HotPink shows up.
Which means that hover
is actually there too.
So on Android you have all three.
So the correct answer is, actually,
none of them because different mobile
devices behave slightly differently.
It's worth keeping this in mind as you
develop your sites to look good on
any device.
You're starting to think
about forms with touch,
which is a distinctly human interaction.
In the next video,
watch Luke describe how the human body
becomes a factor with mobile devices.