So, the question was in the Swiss
system, if there are 16 players,
how many rounds does it take
to find a champion, and
how many total matches will be played?
Even though players aren't eliminated
from the tournament by losing a match,
one loss means they can't
become the unbeaten champion.
In fact, if we look at this subgraph,
of this Swiss system tournament,
it looks an awful lot like
this elimination tournament.
This means that the Swiss tournament
takes the same number of rounds,
as the elimination tournament
to find a champion.
So if there are 16 players,
it would take four rounds.
In the total number of matches, it's
just the number of rounds multiplied by
the pairs of players in each graph.
Since no players are eliminated, each
of the 16 players are in each round.
16 players is eight pairs and
multiplying this by four rounds, tells
us there are 32 total matches played.