[Thrun] And the answer will be 0.6, 0.44, and 0.376.
It's really an exercise applying probability theory.
In the very beginning we know to be in state R,
and the probability of remaining there is 0.6, which is directly the value on the arc over here.
On the second state we know that the probability of R is 0.6
and therefore, the probability of sun is 0.4,
and we compute the probability of rain on day 2 using total probability.
The probability of rain on day 2 given rain on day 1
times the probability of rain on day 1 plus the probability of rain on day 2
given it was sunny on day 1 times the probability of sun on day 1.
And if you plug in all these values,
we get 0.6 times 0.6 plus rain following sun which is this arc over here, 0.2,
times 0.4 as the prior, and this results in 0.44.
We can now do the same with the probability of rain on day 3,
which is the same 0.6 over here, but now our prior is different--it's 0.44--
plus the same 0.2 over here with the prior of 0.56, which is 1 minus 0.44.
And when you work this all out, it is 0.376 as indicated over here.
So what we really learned here is that this is a temporal Bayes network
of which we can apply conventional probabilities such as the total probability
which was also known as variable elimination in the Bayes network lecture.
All these fancy words aside, it's really easy to evaluate those.
So if you want to do this and you ask yourself given the probability of the certain time step
like 1, what's it related to time step 2,
you ask yourself what's the durations that I encounter in time step 1.
There are usually 2 in this case.
What are the transition probabilities that lead me to the desired state in time step 2
like the 0.6 if you started in R and 0.2 if you started in S,
and you add all these cases up and you just get the right number.
It's really an easy piece of mathematics if you think about it.