So in these two cases,
the first story is one
where Google decided because of the EU,
or the European Court of Justice ruling,
decided they would not
return a link to it.
The second one, public still should
be able to know some history about
this doctor if they want
to use his services,
then we reasonably can agree that
this stuff should not be forgotten.
So I think you know Google, these kind
of requests have to be reviewed and
Google is going to decide whether
they're going to comply with it or not.
And this is only for EU.
If you live in the US you can't ask you
don't have the right to be forgotten.
So they will return
what they can return.
Obviously they don't want to have or
all the head of having to
review these and so on