So let's say the readers, our readers start finishing the accesses.
So as they finish the access they will first log the counter_mutex and
this is why it was important that the writer release the mutex,
because otherwise none of the readers would have been
able to basically exit the real critical section, the reading of the files.
So to perform these updates to the proxy variable, and
to reflect the fact that nobody's currently reading the file.
So reader exists the read phase.
So it will lock the mutex.
It will decrement the counter.
And it will check the value of the resource_counter.
So, once the reader decrements resource_counter,
it checks to see whether it's the last reader.
So, this really should be it checks whether resource_counter is,
has reached the value 0.
The very last reader that is exiting this
read phase will see that resource_counter has reached 0, it's the last reader.
And then it will signal the write_phase condition variable.
It makes sense to generate this signal and to notify a potential writer that
currently there are no readers performing read operations.
And given that only one writer can go at a time,
it really doesn't make sense to use a broadcast.
So, this write_phase will be received ultimately over here.
And the one writer that was waiting on that write_phase condition of
the area above will be woken up.
What will happen internally, that writer will be removed from
the wait queue that's associated with the write_phase condition variable.
And the counter mutex will be reacquired before we come out of
the wait operation.
Now as we explained earlier, the very first thing that we have to do is,
we have to go ahead and check the statement resource_counter one more time.
So we, we go out of the wait statement, but we're still in the while loop.
We have to check whether resource_counter is indeed still zero.
The reason for this is that internally in the implementation of
this wait operation, removing the thread from the queue
that's associated with the write_phase condition variable, and
acquiring this counter_mutex mutex, are two different operations.
And in between them, it is possible that another, either another writer or
another reader has basically beat the writer that was waiting to the mutex.
And so when we come out, yes we have the mutex, but
somebody else has already acquired it, changed the resource_counter value to
reflect the phase that maybe there is a reader or
a writer currently accessing the file, and then released the mutex.
But it, actually, there is another thread that's currently in one of
these code blocks that we wanted to protect in the first place.