So I've opened up the Parallax
demo from before.
And I've got DevTools open.
I'll click on show paint rectangles and
now I will scroll.
And you can see that the entire
page is lighting up in green.
Which means that there is
a lot of painting happening.
There must be a problem with this demo.
To understand why there's
a lot of painting happening,
I've opened up the source code for
for the Parallaxing site CSS.
You can see that there are a lot
of elements that have will-change
transform applied to them, but
it must not be everything.
Something Parallaxing has not been
promoted using will-change transform.
So for this quiz I want you to
find the element that should have
been promoted with will-change.
Use DevTools to fix it and
then to finish this quiz simply type
its ID into this box right here.