Let's look at dynamic programming again.
Specifically let's look at environment that has a loop.
Here's the environment.
The environment possesses 14 states,
and here is the loop as indicated, and there is a big intersection in the middle over here.
Let's assume this is our start state in the very south, and we're facing north.
We we reach to the goal state in the west, and here we will be facing west.
Obviously, there are two ways to get to the goal.
We can go north 3 steps and then turn left to the goal,
or we can take the entire loop over here, avoid left turns,
but eventually find ourselves at the goal as well after more steps.
Let's assume there are different costs attached.
The cost of motion is -1 per red cell.
The cost of right turns is -2.
Why would be penalize right turns?
Well, as you turn right, you might have to yield for pedestrians.
That might cost you some time.
Let's assume an expectation that -2 accounts for the time relative to the motion of -1.
What I'd like you to know is a tricky question.
What is the max cost of a left turn?
If we avoid left turns altogether, we'd much rather take the loop over here.
I want the solution where you turn left to be distinctly more expensive, or more negative,
than the solution where you turn right.
When I say "max", we're dealing with negative numbers.
So if you would were to look into positive numbers, what's the minimum cost of a left turn?
But I want you to enter the negative number over here.