So you've seen that
the APIs Explorer lets you try out
the API that your application
exposes through endpoints.
Google uses the APIs Explorer in the
same way to let you investigate the APIs
that are publicly available for
the services that it provides.
For example, let's consider
Google's translation service.
You can go to tranlate.google.com
to translate some text from one
language to another.
However, you could also write
applications that do translations using
the Translate API.
And you can try out the Translate API
using the APIs Explorer.
It's easy to find the APIs Explorer for
Google's public APIs.
Just search for it.
When you go to the APIs Explorer,
you'll see a list of all of
the APIs that Google provides for
developers to use.
Search or scroll down to
the Translate API and click on that.
You'll see the functions of the
Translate API exposes through endpoints.
These are functions that you,
as a developer,
can use in your own application.
Now a task for you.
Go to the APIs Explorer for
the translation service to find out the
meaning in English of the name Gundega,
the name of the instructional
designer for this course.
Using the Translate API, find
the language.translations.list function.
Use a target language of en and
then try to find out what
Gundega means in English.
Then from the returned message, find out
what the detected source language was.