First, can malware disable
a software firewall?
The answer is yes, because if the
malware gets into the operating system,
then it would have the privilege to
disable software-based firewalls.
Likewise, a malware can
disable an antivirus checker.
Because if the malware gets in the OS,
it would have the privilege to
disable the antivirus checker.
Can a malware disable
a hardware firewall?
Typically, no, because malware typically
cannot control hardware settings.
Can firewalls stop pings?
Pings are ICMP packets, and
they can be stopped by firewalls
because the firewall can look at the IP
header and
know that this packet is an ICMP packet.
Second one, packet sniffing.
Typically, this means that
the attacker has a malware
in the internal network that passively
records traffic on the internal network.
And so there's no activity that
can be seen in the firewall unless
the attacker is sending a huge amount
of decoded traffic out to the Internet.
But typically the attacker would have
a malware performing the analysis of
the decoded traffic in
the internal network.
And only sends the small amount of
valuable data out to the Internet.
So it would be hard for
the firewall to stop this.
Outbound network traffic.
Yes, the firewall can control outbound
traffic, because firewalls can inspect
and control traffic both inbound and
outbound.