So our Catalog Activity
is looking pretty good.
So now we want to tackle one of the big
remaining functionalities which is
implementing the detail screen.
So instead of adding a brand
new activity to your app,
we can actually go ahead and use our
existing Editor Activity for this.
What's the modifications?
So one way to think of this, is that
the Editor Activity will have two modes.
So the first mode will
be inserting a new pet
which is triggered when
you press the FAB button.
So from this mode,
the title will say, Add a Pet and
the fields will be all blank and
then pressing the save button will
insert this new pet into our database.
The second mode is an edit mode
where we allow to edit a pet and
this will be triggered when one of
the pets in list view is clicked on.
So in this mode, the title will say Edit
Pet and the fields will be pre-populated
with the existing pet's information and
pressing the Save button here
will update the pet's info instead
of making a brand new pet.
Now our Insert Mode Is already done.
So that means we just need to add logic
to differentiate between these two modes
and then add code for
the edit-mode function.
So building this out will
require quite a bit of code, but
let's start off with
a small coding task.
So for this small coding step,
I just want to focus on pressing
one of the list items and
then have it open up the EditorActivity.
In addition, I want it to display
whether the editor is in edit mode or
the insert mode via what's in the title.
Right now, there's no need to
populate these fields just yet,
just changing the title.
So populating these fields will involve
more than just triggering an intent
that's opens up a new activity
because the intent to do so
we'll need to include some data
which shows the fact that the user
has clicked on a list view item.
So to help us eventually build out so
that the edit mode of the editor
activity will eventually show
the information about the existing pet,
we can add the URI to
the data field of the intent.
So the URI will contain
the ID of the pet and
we'll pass it along to
the EditorActivity.
And so we can use the data field of
the intent because it's meant for
storing URIs.
So to sum it up, by the end of this
coding step, the user will be able to
press any of the pet list view items and
the URI for that pet will be sent
along in an intent data field to
the editor activity in edit mode.
Now here's how you would implement code.
So first you'll need to add an on item
click lister onto the pet list view.
Now inside of it,
you need to create an instance
of a new on item click listener.
Now remember the reason that
it's thrown an error right now,
is that there's a method that
we still need to implement.
So to help us with that, go ahead and
click on this red light bulb.
Go to implement methods,
and it will pull in the on items click
method that we need to implement.
So go ahead and select that, click OK,
and then it pulls in a template
of the method for us.
Now remember on item click is the method
that's triggered when the list view
item is clicked on.
So by default,
we're given these parameter names, but
I'm going to change a couple of
them to be more useful to us.
So first we have the adaptor view,
and this is just the listview.
Next is view, which is
the particular view for the item.
Following is integer, which is the
position of the item in the listview.
So let's go ahead and
change this from I to position.
And lastly, is the long parameter.
So long here is the ID of the item and
let's change this from L to ID.
So this parameter will be particularly
useful for us since we'll
be generating the URI for the pet In
order to pass along as an intent extra.
So we'll need this ID to identify
which item we've clicked on.
So here are two hints for accomplishing
this inside the onCreate method.
So once you receive the intent
from the CatalogActivity,
you have to use the getIntent method and
the getData method in order to get
the associated URI from the intent.
Now once we have that information,
you have to set the title of the editor
activity depending on
which situation you have.
So the two situations, remember,
are if the editor activity
were opened from using the list view
item, then we'll have the URI for
the pet, so we should change
the app bar to say Edit Pet.
Otherwise, if we are coming from a new
pet, that means the URI is null, so
the app bar title should
change to Add a Pet.
So given these hints and
the flow of information, go ahead and
complete the quiz.
So for this coding step, I'd like
you to modify the editoractivity so
that it accommodates editing pets.
So to do so, add the functionality so
that when you press a list item view
from the catalog activity, it, 1,,
opens up an Editor Activity,
2, has a title of Edit Pet and
then 3, passes the selected Pet's URI
by setting the data of the intent.
As a hint, remember you can always
log the URI in the log statement
in order to test if the URI
was passed along correctly.