So in essence, what has happened in this process is we've generated a pyramid
where we can do coarse computations here at the top of the pyramid and
fine computations at the bottom of the pyramid.
Again, by just doing this recursion using this to compute this one,
using that and going up the pyramid.
And, of course, we can move down and
up the pyramid, do whatever kind of processing we want.
So now we know that given any g0,
I can compute g1 using the reduce function in a recursive manner.
So replace this by g0, and I can get g1.
Now the question is, if somebody gave me g1,
could I actually compute something equivalent to a g0, or
some application that could be used to generate something similar to it?
Basically, there is a function called expand which lets you
take any value from here, or information that is from here, to generate this.
Let's look at an example of that and we'll talk about in a bit.
Now I'm going to show you what the output would be from this function if you
were just given g1 to create a version of g0.
Of course, we will call that g0,1 and that's what the image looks like.
Which basically implies that it's g0, but
actually expanded once, from here to get there.
Now for those of you looking carefully you may see, oh not much of a difference.
Just to see what the difference is, what I'm going to do is I'm going to take
the expanded version of this image, and subtract it from the original image.
So this is what you see now here, and
this is basically, of course, showing you where the differences are.
You notice a lot of high frequency information is much more visible.
The eye-lines and all that kind of stuff are much nicely defined.
And in basically you can see that this is the output of which actually is
basically showing you the error in reconstructing it backwards.
Remember, g0 was the original image, g1 was the one we got by using reduce.
Then we basically said let's come up with a function that takes the reduced
image, and expands it back to the original which is g0,1.
We did this from the original one, that's why this is g0,1.
And of course, when we subtracted it, this is what the image we got.
So in essence, the expand is the inverse of the reduce.
As basically attempts to add new values between known ones.
Again, remember the example when we went by an eight by eight simple one to
generate a four by four.
In essence, what we are trying to do is go from a four by four to an eight by
eight, in essence meaning we will be adding new values.
Of course, there will be error, and we want to be able to measure it.
In this case again just to get the notation correct.
G, g0, 1, was basically attempting to
keep the value from g0 just being able to expanding once, in essence,
in general terms gj, n is gj expanded n times.
Remember, we could even go from g2 to g1 all the way to g0.
So, recursion is possible this way, where we go from g0 all the way to gn.
Or, or, g, you know, a larger numbers.
Or, we can go now from our gn, the level that we are at, back all the way here.