So we've talked about how your code
could be slow because the type of
hardware that's executing underneath it,
remember the whole floating
point branching issue problem?
Well, that's mostly a non-issue for
today's hardware.
There's one set of issues that you
still need to worry about, that is,
the performance of the primitives
in the language that you are using.
Take a fundamental
algorithm such as sorting.
Now there are many
ways in which to sort,
and some are better than others,
depending on the circumstances.
For examples, quicksort is generally
faster than bubble sort except when you
have a fewer than a thousand elements or
take searching for
objects in a large sorted list.
Generally, the best way to do
this is with a binary search.
But completely different is finding
objects in an unsorted array.
Now instead of in comparing each object
for the value you're looking for,
you can use a hash function
to find it immediately.
Now this is all basic canon of modern
computer science and data structures.
And thankfully, modern languages like
Java supply these containers and
algorithms on your behalf, so that
you don't have to rewrite the Murmur
3 Hash function or a quicksort over and
over and over again.
But let me reveal something here.
In all of my years of programming,
the one problem that consistently
bites performance of your project
has to do with the performance of these
language-provided container objects.
I mean, it's awesome, right?
Java's providing you with
an implementation of a vector class that
you can push, pop, add, and
remove objects as you see fit, but
in order to get that flexibility, it has
to use a linked list structure under
the hood, which has a unique set
of performance characteristics.
As long as you are only operating on
the front of the list, it's super fast.
But if you're trying to insert or
remove in other places, it's going to
default to the worst possible time.
The point is that just because
the underlying system provides
these containers doesn't mean
that they're performant with
respect to how your program is
going to actually be using them.
James Sutherland published a series of
microbenchmarks on the performance of
specific data structures provided
by the Java framework and
found that there's some differences
in performance versus functionality
that people need to be aware of.
For example,
he found that Hashtable performance
was about 22% faster
than HashMap performance,
depending on how you're actually
using the containers themselves.
The point is this.
Have you profiled your container
classes that you're using in your code?
Are you confident that they are using
the absolute fastest container for
what your code is actually doing?
Mm, yeah, that's what I thought.
But the good news is that you can gain
visibility into the performance of these
containers with some handy
profiling MPIs in Android.
So let's see if Chris's code
stands up to our scrutiny.