[SOUND] Learning about all those
e-commerce steps was a bit complicated.
Now let's do something a little easier.
Let's time something
that happens in the app.
You can send hits to Analytics
to record timing information.
To be clear,
Analytics won't do the timing for you.
You need to write
the timing code yourself.
Once you've recorded the timing,
you can set that in hit to Analytics.
The easiest way to time things is
to record the timestamp before and
the timestamp after
the things you want to time.
And you can use System.nanoTime to
record elapsed time between the start
and the stop time in nanoseconds.
So to send a timing hit to Analytics,
use TimingBuilder
to build the hit and set the value
to be the time that you recorded.
The other parameters are the same as for
the events that you've
already sent hits for.
There's the category, the value,
the label, the variable.
It's important to put
the time value as the value.
Now you may find that the developer
documentation says that some of
the parameters are optional.
But I found that the hits didn't show up
unless I supplied all the parameters.
To see the timed values in
the Google Analytics Dashboard,
you go to Behavior > App Speed.
And here you see I had some
sessions with timing hits.
And I timed how long it took to list all
the dinners, and it was really fast.
Now it's your turn to add
timing hits to your app.
Go ahead and
add the code to time how long it takes
to display the list of dinners and
then enter that value here.
And we want the value as
reported from Google Analytics.
No fair popping up
a toast to get the data.