Welcome back to computer vision today we're going to continue talking about
features, or interest points interest point operators key-points,
in particular last time we talked in fact last couple of times we
talked about how to find interest points, how to detect them.
And we talked about the Harris operator and other kinds of ways of finding them.
And here, for example, typical picture of finding interest points.
In two images, and so this is like about a 500 points extracted with
a Harris detector, and you can see that, well there are a bunch of points found.
And what's good is that a lot of points, like here on this turret here,
is also found on this one, there.
So one of the things that we're looking for
is remember we talked about reliability, that points that you find on one.
Should be found on the other.
But now the question is,
given that we found points in two images, image one, image two.
Image a, image b.
Alpha bravo, take, pick your favorite.
The question is, how do we match them?
How do we determine which points in the left image are the same as points in
the right or multiple images.
So to do this, we need what's referred to as a descriptor.
A descriptor is a description of the neighborhood.
Where the interest point is, and then we're, that's going to allow us to match.
Now, we need a couple of properties of the descriptors, and
what's important is that these properties sort of trade off.
The first is that we want these descriptors to be what we call invariant.
That is, they should be.
Almost the same from one image to the next.
So why do I say almost?
Wouldn't it be great if they were exactly the same?
Well it would be great if they were exactly the same but
also there were no duplicates.
Remember that silly example I gave a couple of lessons back which maybe you
just watched now or maybe you watch eight months ago.
I have no idea.
Where I said, you know,
if we name everything George then it's easy to match them.
Except not really.
Because everybody matches perfectly.
But you don't know which George is the right George.
So the way we say that is,
we also want our descriptors to be distinctive, all right?
Distinctive means that.
One point, you know, some particular point here has the same at the,
corresponding location as the other image has one descriptor.
But a different point would have a different descriptor.
And the reason that's challenging is because these two
images are a little bit different,
it means even the same point like the top of that Diet Coke cap that you
guys can't see that Megan's been drinking because she drinks a lot of Diet Coke.
Anyway ,.
When I move a little bit, the image changes a little.
So, th, the neighborhood is not exactly the same anymore.
So the descriptor is probably going to change a little bit, but
we don't want to change so much that I can't tell that they're the same,
but on the other hand, there's another cap nearby.
That I'd like it not to have the same descriptors so
that they can be, you know, unambiguously matched.
So we have this tradeoff between being invariant, found each time, and
being distinctive, one is different from the next.
So you might say, look I've got a solution.
>> I've got a simple solution.
>> We know that the Harris detector.
Gives pretty good detection and
remember we did that whole thing to talk about how to find the right scale.
Right so we even know sort of the scale of the window.
So, why don't we just do this?
Why don't we for every feature we have here, we pick a window whose scale has
been determined and we'll just do correlation against all of the feature points.
Over here, using their appropriate scale, and then we
just pick the best matches, and we go through and through that all the way.
That would be a great solution, right?
Well, no.
If it was, then I wouldn't be here telling you all this.
So why isn't this so good?
Well, first of all.
Just remembering about correlation.
We have these two pictures and we might have a different picture over here,
a camera over here, and the, fe, features could have rotated.
Right? And correlation is not rotation in variance at all.
Remember we talked about how.
Harris detectors are very robust with respect to the de,
the rotation for detection, but
to do the matching, we have to be robust with respect to rotation as well.
Correlation also is pretty sensitive if I made things brighter or
dimmer, et cetera, I would actually change the values.
So remember we introduced this thing called normalize.
Correlation, well that's not really your savior either,
because it sensitive to non linear changes.
And actually very slight geometric distortions,
can cause your normalized correlation to get pretty bad.
So as I move and
that bottle cap changes, it's appearance to me just a little bit.
The normalized correlation could become problematic.
And also this idea that I'm going to take one and I'm going to compare it
against all of the others, and then the next one, all of the others.
That would be very expensive, so
we'd like to do something that's a lot smarter than that.
So, this lesson, and the one next,
is about, sort of, essentially overcoming these problems.