So if you remember from the last lecture--value propositions,
what we're really trying to do is find the right product market fit
between what you're building and who wants to buy it.
Again, we call this relationship between value proposition
and customer segment, simply product market fit.
Today in customer segments, in this lecture, we're really going to ask
what job are we getting done for the customer, that is what functional or social jobs
are we going to get done, what emotional jobs, what problems or needs are we solving,
what gains are we providing the customer, what pains, how does market type affect this,
and at the end, what we're going to come up with is a deep understanding of the persona and archetype
who are they, why would they buy, why won't they buy, what do you need to say to them,
and if you spend your energy out of the building doing customer development
and customer discovery, it will make your company incredibly efficient
and actually figuring out how to market and sell to them.
So remember, the goal is now to connect the value proposition
with what you're going to know and learn outside the building about customers.