If an error occurs here in this line,
then the next reject function
will get called, which is here.
So once again the first number is 1.
Then the recovery function happens,
and things get back on track.
So, the next number is 3.
After that, there's no more
log in here so that's it.
Next step.
If there is an error with this recovery
function, now this is an interesting
one, because this is only going to
get called if there is another error.
So in this case nothing
will show up in the log.
And then for this one, if something
goes wrong with the async function,
then this next reject
function will get called.
In that case, the number 4
should end up on the screen.
So, these can be kind of tricky,
but just keep in mind that if
something goes wrong, the next
reject function will get called.