I'm going to hook up the delete
function in main activity, so
that we can swipe to delete.
Okay, so I'm going to scroll
down in my on create, and
here you're going to see some code
that's similar to the wait list app code
that you made for the SQL Lite lesson.
Basically, we have a item touch
hopper which we create and
then attached down here
to the RecyclerView.
Now, the important function here is
on-swipe which you can probably see
from this to this.
On-swipe is called whenever a user
swipes left to right of the screen.
In here I'm going to start
by getting the ID for
the item that's being
swiped in our RecyclerView.
The value of this tag was set in the
adapter class to be the ID of the view,
which is why this works.
Then we're going to construct the uri
that points to the specific task.
And I'll do that by turning
the ID into a string and
then appending it to
the content URI of task entry.
Okay, so now we have this uri that
is pointing to the specific item so
let's delete it.
We will delete it by colleague or
ContentResolver and
telling it to delete
the item using that uri.
Remember that these two selection
arguments here will be null.
This is because we construct them later
on in the content provider code and
we do it based off of the URI path.
Now because we've deleted the task,
the task director is changed.
So we're going to need
to reload all that data.
So I'm going to call
getSupportLoaderManager and
I'm going to restart the loader.
This will handle the query at the
background turn, which is what we want.
And then after you've completed this
UI code, you could go ahead and
run the app.
Okay, moment of truth, let's see if
I could swipe something off the list.
Cool, and it updated.
Now, I can swipe left or
right to delete any task.