Now we'll learn a technique
called only choice.
Let's focus on this unit here,
this three by three square.
If we apply the elimination technique,
we get that the only possible values for
each box in this unit are these.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So for example, for
this box here with a 4 and a 9,
we've concluded that the only values for
that particular box are 4 and 9.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
1, for example, can't be a value since
it's here below in the same column.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now something peculiar happens here.
Let's look at this value 1.
It must go somewhere in
the three by three square.
But only one box would allow it,
which is this one.
Thus, we conclude that the box
must have a value of 1.
This is called the only
choice technique.
You'll have the chance to code it below.
[BLANK_AUDIO]