So welcome to Sunday of
your Firebase weekend.
Yesterday we learned all about
the Firebase Realtime Database, and
we set up Friendly Chat to send and
receive messages that were
stored in the database.
>> Right, right, and we talked about
security rules for the database.
And then we set up authentication
to control who can access messaging
in the Friendly Chat app, right?
So right now we have
an app that can send and
receive messages, which really is
amazing for just a day's work.
>> Yeah, it really is.
And today, we're just going to add some
more features to enhance Friendly Chat.
We'll look at some things
such as Firebase Storage.
And we'll use this to
store photo messages, so
we're not just sending
text to each other.
And we'll make Friendly Chat
that much better.
>> That sounds great actually.
Then next we're going to examine
the security roles for Firebase Storage.
>> Okay.
>> Right?
And then finally,
we're going to round out the weekend
by adding some other Firebase features.
Let's do analytics, notifications,
and how about remote config?
>> That's a lot, but
I know we can do it.
So let's dive in.
>> Cool.