Now that we have a database
that supports creating users,
let's write up some codes
to interact with it.
For this project, I want to point out
that our back end code will look up
a user based on his or her email
address associated with their login.
So logging in with a Google account and
a Facebook account tied to
the same email address will provide
the same level of authorization.
To get started,
open up your project.pi file and
be sure to import the user
model that we just created.
I want to walk you through three methods
you should add to your project.pi file
that may help you deal with
getting user information.
The first is createUser.
It takes in a login_session as input and
creates a new user in our database,
extracting all of the fields necessary
to populate it with the information
gathered from the login_session.
It then returns the user
ID of the new user created.
The next one is getUserInfo.
If a user ID is passed into this method,
it simply returns the user object
associated with this ID number.
And, finally, is getUserID, which will
take an email address and return an ID
number if that email address belongs
to a user stored in our database.
If not, it returns none.
In your code,
you should also add the user ID field
when you create a new restaurant or
menu item, like so.
In the instructor notes,
you'll find a version of project.pi
that contains these new code additions.