Earlier, we discussed how
you don't always touch
every part of the rendering pipeline.
In fact, the workload depends
very heavily on exactly
which properties you change.
>> Right, and often people ask me
whether they should animate styles
with JavaScript or CSS.
Which one is faster?
And honestly, it rarely matters.
Most of the time the speed is the same.
The reason is that changing,
say, width incurs the cost of
layout no matter how you do it.
That's true whether you did
it in JavaScript or CSS.
If you change width, height, top,
left, you're going to trigger layout.
If you trigger layout,
you're going to trigger paint.
Or maybe you just change
box shadow on an element.
That's not going to trigger layout.
But it will trigger paint, and
paint is super expensive,
especially on a mobile device.
And you can't trigger layout
without triggering paint.
>> You need to be careful about
what styles you change and when.
In the app life cycle,
which if you recall was RAIL,
response, animation, idle, and load,.
You can afford to do these expensive
style changes in the load, idle, and
response times but
not during animations.
>> Right, during animations
you'll want to avoid layout and
paint if at all possible.
Just because they're normally too
expensive to fit into the short time
you have available.
Now if you can't do that,
you're going to have to find
a way of limiting your effects.
Let's get on to the next lesson,
where we'll discuss just that.