A common term for the behavior
you just saw is that plus equals
operates in place while plus does not.
That is,
plus equals is storing all the new
values in the same places the original
values were stored rather than
creating a new array to store them in.
Operations that are not in place
can be a lot easier to think about.
Like you just saw,
when you do in-place operations,
variables can be modified even when it
doesn't look like they will change,
such as the variable b
in the previous example.
In this course we'll mostly be using
operations that are not in-place.
I prefer to use just plus for
vectorized addition, not plus equals.
Here's another place where
this concept comes up.
Read through this code snippet, and
decide what you think
the output will be.
Again, if you're not sure, either
try it out, or take your best guess.