A critical component in the planning and
implementation of a firewall is
specifying a suitable access policy.
So what does the policy say?
Simply put, the network access policy
specifies what types of traffic
can pass through the firewall.
The types of traffic are typically
defined by the address ranges, meaning,
what are their machines, the protocols,
the applications and the contents.
We will give some examples
of access policy, later.
How do we decide on the policies?
A policy should be developed
through the security and
risk assessment on the organization.
The topic of risk assessment is
discussed in another lecture.
Essentially this risk assessment and
policy exercise will tell us what types
of traffic the organization
must support.
And what security risks
are associated with these traffics.
And therefore how the firewall should
be implemented to mitigate such risks.