Let's start with this one, finishing order in a race. The first person crosses
the finish line so he or she is number one. The second person might cross 30
seconds later, let's say. That person is number two. The third person might
cross immediately after the second person. But it doesn't matter that person is
still number three. It doesn't matter the spacing in-between when they finish
the race. They'll still be assigned that rank. Therefore there are not equal
intervals between the rankings and their is no absolute zero because their
can't be a zeroth ranking. Let's go to percentage correct on a test. If one
student gets a 100%, another gets 90%, another student gets 87%. Then their
definitely be some kind of rank. The person that got a 100% scored first place
in the class. But there are also equal intervals. A person who scored 100%,
scored one percentage point more than a person who scored 99%, and so on. Their
score on the test makes sense in relation to each other. We know how much
better one students did than another. Unlike finishing order in a race, we just
know the ranking but we don't know how much faster one runner finished the race
than another. And there's also an absolute zero. A student can score 0% and get
nothing right. But here she can't score any lower than that. However
temperature and degree Celsius can be zero and it can be lower. Zero is kind of
an arbitrary value that we've assigned to a particular temperature. But just
like percentage correct on a test, there are equal intervals between the
values. The value by itself makes sense in relation another value in this data
set. We call this type of data with just ranks ordinal data. There's a clear
order to the data but the distance between the first and the second is not
necessarily the same as between the second and the third. Or the third and the
fourth, etcetera. Temperature and degrees Celsius is an example of interval
data. The spacing between the values are equal but there is no real zero. The
kind of data that has ranks with equal intervals and an absolute zero is called
ratio data.