Welcome back to Introduction to Computer Vision.
I'm Aaron Bobick still by the way.
I normally when I introduce something I'd say, who I am, but I guess you know.
Okay.
So last time we talked about projective geometry and sort of this relationship
between lines, points and planes and, and using sort of the projective relation
and homogenous coordinates as an easy way to describe these things.
Today, we'll use this a little bit to talk about the relation between two
calibrated cameras.
Next time, it will be uncalibrated.
Just ta contextualize it again a little bit,
we have these projective transforms that are these matrices.
These are 3D matri, three by three matrices that operate in
two-dimensions that can transform from an image in a variety of ways.
For 3D we talked about it being four by four.
We also talked about transformation that are called Homographies that would map
between planes.
This is going to become very important not in this lesson, but the next one.
Because we're, we're going to be talking about recovering homographies that map
between image planes.
We also introduced projective lines and
we talked about that a line in an image plane was just the intersection of an,
the image plane and a plane through the center of projection.
That plane would be defined by a normal l and that's why both a line and
a point are 3-vectors in this homogeneous or, or projected space.
And we showed some really cool things, we showed how the equation of
a line is represented by the normal components in this projective space.
And then a little bit of some cool operations that if I gave you two points,
defined in terms of projective coordinates,
you could find the line that connected them by doing the cross-product.
Likewise, if I gave you two lines,
you could find the point of intersection by doing their cross-product.
And these are some tools that we're going to make use of going forward.