If you look around the flickr
documentation you'll see there's a bunch
of different methods.
And looking around the documentation
to see what methods are available is
actually a really good practice.
This is something that developers do all
the time once they've picked an API.
You know once you know
that the API has for
instance image information you
want to know how can I access it.
So as an exercise I'm going to give
you a couple different things that you
might want to do with the flickr API and
then I want you to tell me
which method I should use.
So which method should I use if I want
to get a list of photos for a gallery?
What if I want to get a list of public
photos for the given user, how about
the number of views comments and
favorites on a photo for a given date?
And finally, to get the URL for
a user's photos?
For each of these questions,
I want you to write the name of
the method in the text box next to it.