Speaking of building things,
let's talk about projects.
>> My videos offer a really great
high level overview of deep learning,
but through this awesome
partnership with Udacity,
you get to apply what you learn
in a unique, hands-on way.
GitHub is the new resume and by the time
you're done with this course, you'll
have an awesome portfolio of projects
to show companies what you're made of.
>> And you're not just submitting
projects into the aethyr.
You'll get in-depth code review from
Udacity's deep learning experts.
>> Real humans, not bots.
>> So you can iterate and
truly master these concepts.
The first project, which you'll be
able to start in just a few minutes,
will have you building
your first neural network.
You'll use it to predict
daily bike rentals.
>> In the second project,
you'll build a convolutional neural
network that will be able to detect and
recognize objects and images,
like vampires and Shia LaBeouf.
>> In the third project, you'll use a recurrent neural
network to generate new scripts for
your favorite TV show.
So, you can live in a world where
Firefly was never cancelled.
>> In the fourth project, you'll build
a chatbot that can translate text in
realtime and tell you moderately
funny jokes in French.
>> And finally,
you'll use a generative adversarial
network to create novel human faces.
>> And we'll be coming at you
with problem sets between each.
>> Some of the content may be familiar
if you've taken our self-driving
car Nanodegree program or
other deep learning courses.
If you've seen it before,
feel free to skip ahead and
go straight to the project.
We have a large corpus of
material to pull from, and
we'd like to utilize our most effective
materials when teaching select concepts.