So the first question to ask is, well, why multiple views?
Obviously, structure and
depth are fundamentally inherently ambiguous from a single view.
Remember, we're projecting from 3D to 2D?
When we do that, we lose information.
So here's an example of a man pushing the Leaning Tower of Pisa over to make it
lean even further.
And either he's very large, the building's very small, or
there's an ambiguity when you project from 3D to 2D.
Or how about, so those of us who grew up in the States who were a fan of,
It's a Great Pumpkin, Charlie Brown.
So that might be a picture that looks like this.
Which would be really a great pumpkin.
But of course, what's really going on here is that the location of the camera
makes it such that this picture just appears like the pumpkin is very large.
And what's fundamental problem?
Well, the fundamental problem comes for, from perspective projection.
Here we have an optical center.
All right.
And we have several points such as P1 and P2 projecting along the same ray.
And of course, because they project along the same ray,
they land in the same spot P1 prime P2 prime.
And so that's where the ambiguity comes from.
And the question is how to figure out where P1 and P2 really are.
And the trick, of course, is going to be the look at a different camera.