Clustering is an unsupervised
learning problem.
And unsupervised learning does not
get as much attention as supervised
learning.
In addition, using text data in
the form of documents is even rarer.
So, this was, in fact,
a pretty challenging problem.
I was impressed with how
Lorenzo identified very
early on what kind of transformation
needs to be done to those documents
in order to feed them into
a machine learning algorithm.
He glanced over briefly, mentioning
TFIDF and I had to probe him a little
bit to figure out whether he understood
what that transformation was doing.
And he demonstrated that he did.
So, keep in mind that it's not enough
to simply throw out the name of
an algorithm or a processing technique,
you might be put on the spot and
asked, explain how this works,
or what its output format is like,
and you should be prepared to do that.
Overall, I liked how this
problem progressed from
a simpler implementation using
TFIDF to end grams which
captured better context of the words
that the students were using.
And, finally, to natural
language processing which would
alleviate a lot of other problems with
the previous approaches, including,
as Lorenzo correctly mentioned, if
a student modifies a few words here and
there, the previous two methods
might be affected by it.
But, natural language processing would
capture the overall sentence structure
and be able to produce
more faithful results.