What we've learned about today is,
how to deal with images that have, large scale differences between them.
Frankly, if you have two images that are translated, rotated, made brighter,
darker etc.
Stretched a little, skewed a little.
The scale may not matter as much, but if you had a large scale difference,
then what you do is you try to find the same scale around the interest points by
that scale-invariant function, and you search for these maxima.
All right.
So where are we?
So we know, how to detect interest points.
Here's a whole bunch of them.
The next question is how to match them.
So I've got points on my left and points on my right.
How do I find the match?
To do that, I need what's called a descriptor.
I need to describe each of those points by looking at
the little region around it, and look for that in the next image.
And that's what we're going to do next lesson.