Now a couple of other things that we can
also talk about is, that window that I
showed you, the crop window also
gets bigger and smaller on its own.
So here, we are basically
showing you a very long video.
Again, this is a very difficult
case if you think hard about it.
It's snow, not a lot of features.
You see the red crop getting bigger,
smaller and also,
you know, for example sometimes.
I mean, it does crop out some things.
It doesn't know anything
about where the skier is.
We've actually added algorithm that can
actually improve the quality of this by
constraining it to where
the person would be.
There's motion in this one
except camera motion, and
after a while another
skier with come down.
And one of the other things we've added,
and
there is ability to actually deal
with very long video sequences.
On of the more important advantages
of her approach is that,
if actually doesn't find anything stable
it reverts back to the original video,
so basically the all times
we actually do get a result.
So it does have a graceful failure mode.
Now, I'm giving you very specific
perception of the approach that
is specific to this method here.
I do encourage you to look at
other methods out there, and
in fact even professional
softwares like Adobe Premier and
After Effects now have stabilization
tools, much more detailed, and
with a lot more controls than ours does,
because in this one you just click.