You just saw that the PetDbHelper
provides a connection
to this SQLiteDatabase object.
This object let's you manipulate
the underlying database.
That means you can execute any
statement from our cheat sheet
on this underlying database
using the SQLiteDatabase object.
Note, if you do want to create,
update or
delete, you'll need to call
the getWritableDatabase method,
instead of our
getReadableDatabase.method.
However, for read or select type
actions, you can go ahead and
use the getReadableDatabase method.
Here's our cheat sheet with
all our CRUD operations.
And from the tutorial
I showed you before,
we can see that there are examples
with the Feedreader app
showing how to create, read,
update, and delete information.
And in this lesson,
you're just getting a taste of what
using SQLite in Android is really like.
What we're doing now, won't be the final
code that we'll be using in our app.
And so for now we're just inserting
some data and then reading it out.
First, let's take a look
at how to insert data.
First, let's take a look at the INSERT
statement from our cheat sheet.
When you insert data, you won't be
able to see it on the screen just yet.
Because right now,
we're just inserting it, and
not selecting
the information out to read.
But, if you do download the database,
you will be able to see that the new
data was added to the database.
To help us visually see that the
information was added to the database in
the app, we can use our handy dandy
display database info method which
displays the number of
rows in our database.
This is an easy way for us to get
quick information about whether or
not the database was updated with
the information that we insert in.
Writing the SQL might seem like
a good idea, but that's actually very
prone to typos and errors, so actually
a much better way to write this.
Looking at this section in the Android
documentation in Saving Data
in SQL Databases under the Put
Information into Database section,
I can see that this example is using
a class called Content Values.
Now Content Values is a class that
stores a bunch of key value pairs,
where the key is the column
name in the database and
the value,
is whatever value you want insert in.
Here's an example of that.
Say we have a pet with the name
Garfield, of the breed tabby,
of the gender male and
weighing in at 14 kilograms.
These are the associated key and
value pairs for all of that information.
Using Content Values is super easy.
All you need to do is make
a ContentValue object and
then call the put methods with the
associated column name and column value.
Note this chunk of code here,
doesn't actually insert anything
into our database just yet.
All this is doing is creating an object,
with the column rows and
associated values.
Now to actually create
a new row in the database,
we'll need to use the insert method
from the SQLiteDatabase class.
Now, from the developer documentation
for the SQLiteDatabase class,
we see that the insert method
takes the name of the table,
secondly an optional parameter which
we'll always be setting to null, and
the content values that you create in.
This null parameter here,
will only be used if you're inserting an
entirely empty row into your database.
And a final thing to note
about the insert method,
is that it returns the ID
of the newly inserted row.
And if there was an error,
it will return back negative 1 to us.