Let's start by looking
at the Firebase site.
Sometimes UI's for websites change so
if anything seems out of place,
check out the instructor nodes for
the most up to date information.
We're going to create a free account,
so let's first see what's included.
As you can see here, the free account
gives you a good amount of included
storage, unlimited users and
some static hosting.
That last part might be useful
later on if you ever want to
make a web app in addition
to your mobile app.
Now to create a free account.
Click on Sign Up, and
enter an email address and password.
Once you're account is created you
are redirected to your account page.
This page shows you all
of your apps in Firebase.
But what is an app in Firebase?
In Firebase,
an app refers to a Firebase app backend.
This backend includes a database and
support for authenticating users and
tracking if they're logged in.
But, for shopping list plus plus,
we also have our client
code which runs on Android.
So to be clear as we continue through
the course, here's what we mean.
When we say your app, we're referring
to the shopping list plus plus app
you'll be helping me create in Android.
When we talk about your app's backend,
we're referring to one of these
online Firebase app backends.
So now,
looking at your account page, you will
see the card titled My First App.
This is a starter Firebase
app backend available
when a user creates a new account.
If you're just playing
around with Firebase,
this is where you'd go to
explore the functionality.
However, for our purposes we are going
to make a new Firebase app backend for
our shopping list plus plus app.
First click on the gray card
to the left of My First App.
You'll need to name your new app.
I will go ahead and
type mine in the app name field.
Notice that the app URL is populated
with the base URL for his app.
Every app has a base
URL associated with it.
And this URL is where you'll go when
you want to access or edit your data.
URLs must be unique.
So now, since I've just taken that URL,
you'll need to use something
a little bit different.
You could use any name that
is 20 characters or less.
Containing alpha numeric characters and
hyphens.
For example, you could name your app
like I did, shop list plus plus hyphen,
and your initials or
something else if you prefer.
Select create new app.
You should now see a card for
your Firebase app backend here.
Click on the URL, or
manage app button and you'll be
taken to your Firebase app backend.
Notice how the URL is
what we originally typed.
As long as you're logged into your
account you can go to this URL
to get a view of what's
going on with your data.
Right now there's not a lot going on.
Your entire database is equal to null.
Now we could manually
type some data in here.
But instead, let's start with making
a new Android app, hooking it up to this
Firebase app backend, and writing
your first data from the Android app.
I'm getting ahead of myself
a little bit, though.
I'll give you a moment to
make an account now, and
when you're done, copy and
paste your app's root URL here.
The root URL is just
the base URL of your app.
You will need this for
the next step, when we hook up
the Android app to the Firebase.
So paste or type your URL here.