So how do we compute the fundamental matrix from corresponding points.
All right, so here I wrote the fundamental matrix equation.
And you notice that each point gives us one equation.
And that's written here like this.
So u prime, v prime, one.
That's the projective similarity of the point in the prime,
times the fundamental matrix, times uv 1,
that's the other point in the original image, equals 0, okay?
That's a single equation per point, all right?
So, copy it here and I can just multiply this whole thing out, and
I still have my one equation per point.
And, on the left-hand side.
These are my knowns right, so I take the u primes and the u's or
the v primes or the v prime and the u or just this individual etc.
And here are my unknowns right,
the unknowns are the elements of the f matrix okay.
So one point, one equation.
Well, I just collect n of these.
Right? And it's however many number of points that I have.
And then I'm going to solve the thing.