Before we go any further, it would be
great if our View Controller where the
recording happens was called something
other than just ViewController.
In writing your app, there are times when
you might want to rename classes and it
takes just a minute. Let me show you.
For renaming this View Controller, it's going
to take three steps. We want to change
ViewController to RecordSoundsViewController.
The first step is to select
the ViewController.swift file
in the navigator with a single click.
When you do a single click,
Xcode gives us the ability to modify the
file name. Ok change the name to
RecordSoundsViewController. With the file
still selected, we want to change ViewController
in the code itself to
RecordSoundViewController. We also want to
change it in the comments at the top.
There we go. Now it's changed in both places.
Changing the name in the comment
isn't exactly required for our code to compile,
but if someone else is looking
through your code, it won't make any sense if
the old name is still reference there.
Alright let's make sure we save this, so you
haven't already you can press command+s
and that will save the file. And then the
last step is we have to tell the
Main.storyboard that the View Controller
we've configured our buttons with is no
longer called ViewController, it's
called RecordSoundsViewController.
So open up the Main.storyboard, select
the ViewController for our first view.
Make sure you have the utilities panel shown,
and then we want to go to the
identity inspector. That's the inspector
whose icon looks like a little ID card.
And here with the name of classes ViewController,
we want to change it to
RecordSoundsViewController and make
sure you press Enter for the changes to
take effect. We’ll know that it worked
when the module changes to current - PitchPerfect.
That indicates the class
name we provided here is indeed part of
our project, so it knows where to find it.
And that's all it takes to change the
name of a class. Next let's add the
AVAudioRecorder code that you saw earlier.