So to quickly summarize, talked a lot
about how we can extract shapes,
structure, geometry, range and
depth from a variety of methods.
Specifically, talked
about stereo imaging and
also how do you compute depth or
disparity from a stereo image pair.
A lot of information exists.
I just put one paper for you to look at
in terms of what can be done with image
based rendering types of things.
That the Szeliski book has
a lot of information stereo.
There's a whole chapter dedicated to it.
If you really get more interested
in 3D computer vision,
the most classic textbook in this
area is by Hartley and Zisserman.
While dated, it still has
the most foundational methods for
trying to reconstruction or
geometry construction from images.
Just to finish up, of course,
there are, you know,
lots of nice stereo cameras
available in the market these days.
Here's the one that I have.
Basically, if you notice
it has two cameras and
basically can be used
to generate 3D images.
And have,
you know can show you this one actually.
I just took a picture of
the scene that I am at.
I don't know if you can see
this when I rotate this around.
But it should show you that this
basically has also got a display that
shows the scene in 3D.
Again I'm going to let you folks spend a
little bit of time learning about these
types of cameras and stuff like that.
There are some cameras.
And of course,
there's a long history of 3D cameras,
even with film are coming out.
And there are these days,
of course, game devices and
a lot of cell phones that
have multiple cameras
that could be used to generate 3D
images by just doing stereo pairs.
Here is actually just using this camera,
I took the images left and
right pair of Daniel and
they can be used in this instance
to generate anaglyph image here.
There are lots of other different types
of ways you can display 3D images
like this.
For more information, please look at
some of the other sites and thank you.