Jake did you work this one out?
>> Yeah, I did.
I'll walk you through it.
To open the database I'm
going to call idb.open.
Passing in Witter is the name,
one is the version number.
And now I'm going to write my
upgrade function to set it all up.
Since I'm on version one, I'm not going
to do the whole switch statement thing.
I'll introduce a version
two if I have to.
To set up the database,
I'm going to create an object store
named witters with a key path of id.
That means it will treat the id
property of objects in the store
as the primary key.
I'm also going to create an index on
the store called by-date which indexes
on the time property of stored objects.
Over in the browser, I'm going to use
force update, reload the page, and
now in the resources panel,
I can see the new witters database,
along with the witters store and
the by-date index.
Now, we need to get
items into the store.
I'm going to start by creating a read
write transaction for the witters store.
Then I'll get hold of the store.
And then loop through these messages and
put each one into the store.
Back to the browser, I reload the page
and then the resources panel,
I can see messages in the database.