Looking at the documentation, we can
see that if the user mistypes their
password, that would be
a INVALID_PASSWORD error.
The specified user account?
INVALID_PASSWORD error,
which occurs when the specified
user account password is incorrect.
Meanwhile, if they mistype their email.
And again, we're assuming that
it's not somebody else's email and
that they didn't mangle it so
badly that it's not an email anymore.
In that case, they will get
a USER_DOES_NOT_EXIST error,
because it will look like a valid email
account, but it's not in the system yet.
Okay, cool?
Good luck with handling
both of those errors, and
I'm sending this back over right now.