So let's just think for a minute.
Suppose we wanted scale invariance.
How could we do that?
So to think about this, let's consider some regions, and I'm going to use
circles, it's easier to think about, of different sizes around some point, okay?
So here on the left, I've got a curve that is the zoomed in version of
the curve on the right and I've got some circles around this.
You know, when I look at the part that's in this circle and
the part that's in that circle, I say, no,
that curve doesn't really look the same.
If I make the same circle a little bit bigger,
no it doesn't really look the same.
How about now, no, not yet.
Then I say, oh, wait.
Now with this bigger size,
this piece of curve looks a lot like this piece of curve.
All right?
So the regions of corresponding sizes will look the same in both images.
It's not the same size, I, I call them corresponding sizes.
It is, it spans the same amount of the image.
So the problem, of course is, we have to choose the circles independently,
because I'm dealing with this image and
I've gotta figure out what scale to do things.
And I'm dealing with this image, I've gotta figure what scale to do things.
And I want it to be the case the way the, the red circles are indicating here,
that the scale I picked for the left-hand image is this nice big circle and
the scale I picked for the right-hand image is this small circle.
So, that's what we want to do.
We want to be able to do this independently on the, in the images.
So, how might we do that?
Well, here's a solution.
Okay.
And graphically, it'll be a little bit easier to see.
What we're going to do is, we're going to design some function, okay?
And it's going to be a function over that circle, and
this is a little bit tricky, we're going to call it scale invariant.
And what we mean by that is,
the function doesn't actually care how big the circle is, it just cares about,
say, the distribution of the values of the pixels within that circle.
So a simple example, not one that we're going to use, but
it's simplest to understand is imagine average intensity.
All right. If I just take the average intensity over a circle,
that function doesn't care how big the circle is.
It's just going to compute that function over whatever size circle you give it.
And in fact, if there were a constant grey value,
if you kept making the circle bigger and bigger and bigger, it wouldn't matter.
The, the function would stay the same.
If you have a function that changes over different corresponding regions,
then that function would go up and
down as you've looked over those different regions.
And if I zoomed out of that thing, it would go up and down again.
But now it would go up and down faster, because as I grew my circle,
I would be covering more, more of that picture as I move that circle out.
Now, I know that was clear as mud, so let's take a look at a picture.
All right.