Let's dive into the firebase
real time database structure.
All data is stored as JSON objects.
You can think of the database
as a Cloud hosted JSON tree.
This means that your entire database
is stored as a single JSON object.
The quicker side we are going to
be spending the rest of this video
talking about JSON as it relates to
the firebase real time database.
So if you would like
more practice with JSON,
you can check out the course
works links in the notes.
All right, back to the main topic.
When you add data to the JSON tree,
it becomes what I'll call a nodes.
The existing JSON structure.
Nodes has keys and values.
You can provide your own keys such
as user IDs or semantic names.
Keys are always strings and they must
be unique within their contexts.
As you can expect from JSON,
node values can have different types.
They can be integers, like the answer
to the ultimate question of life,
the universe and everything.
Or there can be floats
like the golden ratio, or
it can be a Boolean like true or false.
Like whether there's
fog in San Francisco,
okay, that one is mostly true.
Failures can also be strings
like this tasty palindrome, and
failures can be other message
objects like this messages object.
The key is messages and
it contains a list of search objects.
Each representing a single message.
So, here we see keys.
Message one and
message two which we created
manually to enumerate each message.
But this can cause conflicts.
If two users are trying to write
to the database at the same time.
Which of these users is
the one adding message three?
That's why Firebase can create unique
keys, to avoid these name conflicts.
But they are still ordered
like numbered message keys.
These unique keys are called
Push IDs in Firebase.
Because they are generated
with the push function or
when your on iOS,
the function corp chow by auto ID.
We'll talk about a push function later,
and
we'll work with push ID's
in the friendly chat app.
If you have extra time this weekend,
you can learn more about push ids
in the Firebase blog posts The 2 to the
120th ways to ensure unique identifiers.
The link is in the notes.
JSON also supports arrays
in square brackets.
But arrays are not recommended in
the Firebase Realtime Database,
only JSON dictionaries are.
Let's go over a few more terms that
are good to know when you work with
a realtime database.
We'll focus on one message here,
for the sake of explanation.
And when we navigate the database,
we'll do so
by walking down the path of children.
In this case, the node for the message
is the child of the messages node.
And if we go back up,
the messages node is the parents
of the specific message node.
We can refer to a specific part
of the database in the path.
A path look just like urls on the web.
We like a path to a file on
your computer's file system.
A full path starts with a forward slash
which means that is starts
at the root of the database.
And then each following path segment
is the key that walks us
down a tree child by child.
The path we see here refresh
with specific chat message.
In this case, the note is an object
with two key value pairs,
name, Person and text Hello.
Now that you've seen the characteristics
of the Firebase Database structure,
let's apply them.