So now in relation to this, what is computational photography?
Well, one thing you may actually want to start thinking about now is,
that these days cameras are pretty complex devices.
So if you buy any kind of camera, doesn't have to be a high-end based DSLR, that
is the, you know, digital version of the older SLR cameras, single lens reflex.
But there is a lot of computation involved with it.
But we want to actually start thinking it, a little bit more.
Imagine that there is a relationship now,
much more symbiotic one, between a camera and a computer.
What can happen when I really bring a much more powerful computer and
attach it to a camera?
Well that's the kind of things computational photography's attempted to do.
And a example of this is a camera 2.0.
Sometimes also referred to as a Frankencamera which is
a research attempt done a while ago.
Building a camera like this with a lot of computation so you can
actually change things like put multiple flash, that's multiple light sources.
Also control various aspects of how the light is captured.
That's one example of what computational photography would be.
But more and more, if you look in your pockets you have smartphone cameras.
These phone cameras have computation built in where the camera is, so
computational photography can impact even devices like the ones you have in your
hands, or even the computers these days all come with cameras attached to them,
perhaps for things like you know, teleconferencing applications.
But if you noticed, camera and, and computers are now becoming integral parts of
each other, which basically means that now, we can actually take computation and
impact the entire workflow of how light is captured,
to generate an image or a video.
And that's what computational photography really is about.
The whole entire workflow of how light is captured to generate an image,
photograph or video.
How can computation actually impact that whole workflow all the way to
sharing the images or the videos that you have at the end.
Well that's what computational photography in the simplistic matter is.