Hi, welcome.
I'll be guiding you through
the coding lessons in this class.
The first thing you'll do is deploy a
simple app engine application that uses
endpoints.
You'll learn how to define
endpoint functions.
You'll learn how to call an endpoint
function from a webpage using
the JavaScript client library.
You'll also learn how to use the APIs
Explorer, which is a cool tool for
exploring publicly
available Google APIs, and
which also lets you test out
your own application's API.
The main coding project
that you'll be building in
this course is an application
called Conference Central.
It let's users schedule conferences and
also register to attend conferences.
You'll be focusing on implementing
the backend functions.
Just like on a cooking show
where some of the cakes
are already baked ahead of time,
we've written some of the code for you,
so that you can get straight to work
implementing the more interesting bits.
You'll start out by downloading
a skeleton version of the conference
central application.
Then, you can keep working on it,
from lesson to lesson.
But, at any point, if you don't complete
the exercises in a lesson, don't worry.
We provide new starting code for
each lesson.
Okay, let's go write
some endpoint functions.