Great. So, hopefully, you found stage six not too difficult and
pretty straightforward.
So, the first step would be to go to your TweetTopology and
enter in your OAuth credentials.
And, here, you'll need to comment out, comment out the earlier credentials.
I would suggest at this stage, package, and run.
And once you get a build success, submit your topology and make sure it runs.
And if you submit your job,
you'll actually see nothing, as we don't have a topology yet.
So let's go back to our topology.
In part zero now,
we need to attach the tweet spout to the topology with a parallelism of 1.
So, here we have builder.setSpout.
Let's call this a tweet spout with a parallelism of 1.
Notice that our syntax tweetSpout is simply calling the tweetSpout object that
we named with our credentials.
At this stage, we package again.
And once we get a build success, we can use the up arrow, submit our job again.
And now, we see the twitter4j TwitterStream.
Let's go on to part one.
Similarly to stage five, this is simply builder.setBolt parse-tweet-bolt new
ParseTweetBolt with a parallelism of 10.
And again, we want a shuffleGrouping that connects our
tweet-spout component ID to the tweet-spout.
In part two, we want to attach the count bolt with a parallelism of 15, and
the grouping here is the fields grouping.
The one difference is that our parse tweet bolt is now its own file.
And to figure out the fields grouping needed, let's go to the parse tweet bolt.
And now we scroll down to our declareOutputFields and
we see that we have the tweet-word.
We copy the tweet-word, go back to our topology, and
enter this in the new Fields tweet-word.
And finally, in part three,
we attach the report bolt with the syntax builder.setBolt with a component ID
report-bolt, new ReportBolt parallelism of 1.
And again, we want a globalGrouping to send all streams from
the count-bolt down to one bolt in the globalGrouping report-bolt.
Finally, the component ID to make that connection is count-bolt, listed there.
Remember, to save the program, we'll mvn package.
And finally, once we get the build success, we can look at a tree structure.
Now we have individual classes, and our TweetTopology.
Remember again, that we want our jar with dependencies.
Here, the structure is udacity.storm.TweetTopology.
storm jar target udacity.storm.TweetTopology.
Finally, as storm runs, we come back to our visualization.
And we see as the Tweets are being parsed, we saw our visualization count grow.
And again, we can hover over a word and see that 150 HTTP splits were occurring.
And again, we'll clean this up using filters in later exercises.
And, congratulations on finishing on the Tweet word count.
The complete topology.