Here’s the answer.
Let’s see where it comes from.
Remember that each output is
computed from a dot product.
So, for example, let's take this output.
There are two missing values, so
let's give them some arbitrary symbols.
How about w and x?
The dot product is just this equation,
basically,
the element-wise products summed
together equaling the output, and
we can repeat this for
each of the other output elements.
For each blank,
I introduced a new symbol.
As you can see, we have four
equations and four unknowns, so
we should be able to find a solution.
Let's start with the third equation,
which only has one unknown.
Solving for z, we get the value 2.
We can then plug this
into the fourth equation.
Solving for y, we get 7, so
that eliminates the fourth equation.
Since we know y,
we can solve the second equation for w.
You'll get w equals 1.
Eliminating the second
leaves us just the first.
You'll find x equals 30.