So that ends this lesson on finding, matches for SIFT, descriptors.
And it's really all I've really talked about was some clever indexing and
hashing methods that have made it,
much more effective as a way of describing and finding, matches.
As I said earlier,
if you have a really fast computer, you might just do full nearest neighbor.
Or, if you had all day to do a problem set,
you might just do the nearest neighbor.
But if you actually have a real time device that needs to do something a little
more clever, then you need something that accelerates that pace.
Going forward, what we're going to talk about is to use a small number of
local matches, to determine a best global solution.
And this should remind you of something we've done before, where we take,
sort of, a modest number of local events and find a global solution.
Remember that whole voting thing?
Well, what we're going to show you is another way that's more appropriate for
doing things like I've gotta sum SIFT features.
Some of the matches are good, some are not so
good, I'd like to find the best global, match, what's the way of doing that and
we'll talk about that the next times.