So one of the first, to me at least,
it seems like obvious problems
with this approach is that if we come
back later and have the Mark 5 come out,
there doesn't seem to be any real
ability to reuse the components that
we've already created.
For instance, if our warmer plate is
described here as just this warmer
plate and we flush it out with
functions and attributes and
then the Mark 5 comes around and we
have this completely new warmer plate.
There doesn't seem to be any way for
us to share some of the things that
might be similar between those?
>> Well, we have a play heater class and
a boiler heater class.
Why can't we use those?
>> Well, I don't know.
The heater, I guess,
the parts of it that are general about
the heating element doesn't
seem to be specified here.
Like, the boiler heater and the plate
heater, they're both heaters, but
I don't know what they're sharing.
>> So, am I hearing that you'd
like to see a separation between
the classes that,
a class that describes in general,
the property of things, and
then the specifics from Mark 4?
>> It seems it should be defined more
about how the heating is accomplished
instead of just this general
classification of it being a heater.
>> If we're heating elements by this
particular function, all the heaters or
types of heaters that do
this particular function,
they should extend from
that type of heater.
So it's more of a functional approach,
as opposed to this
kind of general put everything
in a box because it's a heater.
>> Okay.
So there's
a couple of things going on here.
Let's see what Martin
had to say about this.
So, Martin came up with
four primary problems
associated with this
approach to doing the model.
The first is that, obviously,
we haven't paid much, if any,
attention to the operations
that are going on.
And, in fact, many of the classes that
we have here have no state at all.
So they don't have any
attributes either.
If you have a class without state,
it probably should
be an interface instead
of being a class, okay?
Second, what Martin labels
as imaginary abstractions
that even though the heater and
sensor are base classes,
they are not going to have
much to share between them.
Third is a term from the objectorian
role called the God class.
The only substance of class left, when
taking account these the other problems,
is the coffee maker class.
And it contains all
the interesting code.
When you have that sort of situation,
you probably haven't done
a good job at your OO design.
And so, we want to address that.
And then even though
we have the button and
the light, we don't really
have a user interface class.
And so
we need to represent that as well.
>> So I have a quick question.
Is the term here, god class,
is there some carry over to that in
the invariance maintenance strategies
that we talked about earlier,
where you have kind of this central
node that seems like it's controlling
everything instead of distributing
that responsibility out
amongst the rest of
the components in this system?
>> So I hadn't thought about that.
One of the guidelines for
OO design is to break things up
into very small pieces, okay?
There's reasons to centralize, okay,
both at the architectural level,
where you'd like to have knowledge
concentrated because you want to
control effectively where you might want
to do things with respect to safety or
security, things like that,
but also at the object level.
If there are things that might change
separately, you probably want to
have those in separate places, so you
can change just what you need to change.