While the center position has
16 spaces in which it can move,
most other positions have 12 or less.
As the game plays, we will have less and
less spaces our player can move.
>> That means we can make
a better estimate on how many
nodes we have, right?
>> Yep.
Okay.
We know we cannot have more
than 25 moves in a game.
That is the maximum depth
our tree is going to be.
And we already know how many moves
can be done in the beginning,
which leaves 23 moves left.
We know that each move after the first
two are generally going to have 12 or
fewer moves available.
We'll call this the branching factor.
In worst case, we can expect 25 x 24 x
12 to the 23rd n nodes in our game tree.
Shelly, how many is that?
>> More than 10 to the 27th power.
>> Ouch.
Okay, that really didn't help.
Perhaps we can improve
our estimate more.
>> Well, we know at the end of the game,
there have to be progressively
fewer moves available.
There are zero moves in the end,
one move before that,
a maximum of two before that,
three before that, and so on.
>> You're right.
So for the last few moves, assuming a
branching factor of 12 is way too much,
that would be around
10 to the 13th nodes.
But the maximum it could be is 12
factorial, or about 5 x 10 to the 8th.
I guess, we could redo our
estimate as 25 x 24 x 13
12's in a row x 5 x 10 to the 8th.
That's approximately equal
to 3 x 10 to the 23rd.
That is better than 10 to the 25th or
the 10 to the 27th.
But still seems like a gross
overestimate as most branches will have
much less than the maximum
branching factor.
>> Let's see if the students
have a better answer than we do.