Reviews are an early step in an organization's effort to improve the quality of
it's products it produces.
A more sophisticated step is to review the review process itself.
That is, to collect data on the effectiveness of the reviews and
use it to improve the review process.
Among the data that might be collected are the following.
What was the artifact being reviewed and
at which stage of the development process does the review take place?
What was the date and time of the review and how long did it last?
Who were the participants and how much preparation time did they spend?
How many issues were raised, how many of them turned out to be defects,
what were their types, and what were their severities?
Organizations can also collect subjective data
by distributing post review effectiveness questionnaires to the participants.
Finally, for large organizations, it makes sense to store this data in
a database for aggregate analysis over time.