Other interesting management interactions between the user
level threading library and the kernel level thread management occur when we
have a situation where we have multiple CPUs.
In all of the previous cases we've discussed, we only had a single CPU.
So all of the user level threads ran on top of that CPU, and
then whatever changes,
in terms of which of the user-level threads will be scheduled, were made made by
user-level threading library were immediately reflect on that particular CPU.
In a multi-CPU system, the kernel level threads that
support a single process may be running on multiple CPUs, even concurrently.
So we may have a situation when the user-level library that's
operating in the context of one thread on one CPU
needs to somehow impact what is running on another thread on another CPU.
Let's consider the following situation.
Let's say we have three user-level threads that are running, T1, T2, and T3.
And their priorities are such, so that T3 has the highest priority followed by
T2, and then T1 has the lowest priority.
Let's say the situation is such that T2 is running in the context of one of
the kernel-level threads and currently holds a mutex.
T3, the highest priority thread, is waiting on that mutex, and so it's blocked.
It's not executing.
And therefore, the other user-level thread, T1,
is the one that's running on the other kernel-level thread on the other CPU.
Now, at some later point, T2 releases that mutex, it unlocks it.
And as a result of that ,T3 becomes runnable.
Now, in all three threads, T1, T2, and
T3, are runnable, and so we have to make sure that the ones with
highest priority are the ones that actually get to execute.
What needs to happen is T1 needs to be preempted,
since that's the one with the lowest priority among the three.
And we're making this realization while running in the context of the T2 thread.
When T2 performed the unlock operation,
that's when we invoked the user-level threading library.
And that's when we determined that we need to schedule T3
on top of the other context.
We need to context switch T1.
However, T1 is running on another CPU, and so we somehow need to notify
this other CPU to do something to update its registers and its program counters.
We cannot directly modify registers of one CPU when executing on another CPU.
What we need to do, instead, is to send some kind of signal,
some kind of interrupt from the context of one thread and
one CPU to the other thread on the other CPU.
And to basically tell this other CPU to go ahead and
execute the library code locally because the library needs to make some kind of
scheduling decision and change who's executing.
Once that signal happens, the user-level library on the second CPU will
determine that it needs to schedule the highest priority user-level thread, T3.
And thread T1, which has lowest priority, will be the one that's blocked.
So basically, once we start adding multiple CPUs and have multiple kernel and
user-level threads in the process, the interactions between the management and
the kernel and the user-level becomes a little bit more complex than what
the situation is when there's only one CPU.