So the answer is A and D.
Let's first take a look at why B and
C wouldn't work.
For B, because the button overlaps
the toolbar and the content view below,
you can't really use a linear layout.
Because in linear layouts,
children can't overlap.
You see, because the button needs
to appear above the toolbar,
it can't be the middle child.
It would need to be last.
Now A works well.
All three children of the frame layout
are anchored to the top of the screen
with varying offsets.
They're also in the right drawing order.
First the content, then the toolbar,
and then the button.
And D works great at well.
The toolbar and content are arranged
in a vertical linear layout.
We wrap the linear layout
in the frame layout,
so that we can place the button at
any arbitrary location on the screen.
In this case, along the right edge and
offset from the top of the screen
by a fixed number of DPs.