In this introductory lecture,
we will provide a very high-level view of operating systems.
We will explain what is an operating system and
what is the role that it plays in computer systems.
Then we'll look at some of the key components of operating systems,
design principles, and organizational structures.
The following lectures in this class will provide you with
a much more in-depth understanding of what any of the terms and
mechanisms that come up during this lesson actually are.
In simplest terms, an operating system is a piece of software that abstracts and
arbitrates the underlying hardware system.
And in this context, abstract means to,
to simplify what the hardware actually looks like.
And arbitrate, it means to manage, to oversee, to control the hardware use.
We will see throughout this course that operating system support a number of
abstractions and arbitration mechanisms for
the various types of hardware components in computer systems.