To generalize from the example
that we saw in the previous video.
We will now summarize the steps
that have to take place
in an RPC interaction between
a client and a server.
The first step, a server binding occurs.
Here the client finds and
discovers the server that supports
the desired functionality.
And that it will need to connect to.
For connection oriented protocols,
like TCP/IP
that require that a connection be
established between the client and
the server process, that connection will
actually be established in this step.
Then, the client makes the actual
Remote Procedure Call.
This results in a call
into the user stub, and
at that point the rest of
the client code will block.
Next, the client stub will create
a data buffer, and it will populate it
with the values of the arguments that
are passed to the procedure call.
We call this process,
marshalling the arguments.
The arguments may be located
at arbitrary non-contiguous
locations in the client under space.
But the RPC runtime will need to send
a contiguous buffer to the sockets for
transmission.
So the marshal link process
will take care of this and
replace all the arguments into a buffer
that will be passed to the sockets.
Once the buffer is available,
the RPC run time will send the message
in the sending will involve
whatever transmission protocol that
both sides have agreed upon
during the binding process.
This may be TCP, UDP, or even shared
memory based IPC if the client and
the server are in the same machine.
When the data is transferred onto
the server machine, it's received by
the RPC runtime and all of the necessary
checks are performed to determine what
is the correct server step that
this message needs to be passed to.
And in addition,
it's possible to include certain access
control checks at this particular step.
The server stop will unmarshal the data.
Umarshalling is clearly
the reverse of marshalling.
So this will take the byte stream
that's coming from the receive buffers.
It will extract the arguments and
it will create whatever data structures
are needed to hold the values
of those arguments.
One of the arguments are allocated and
set to appropriate values the actual
procedure call can be made.
This calls the implementation
of this procedure that's part
of the server process.
The server will computed the result of
the operation, or potentially it will
conclude that there is some kind of
error message that needs to be returned.
The result will be passed to
the server side stub, and
it will follow a similar reverse path in
order to be returned back to the client.
One more step is needed for
all of this to work.
Here we have as the zero initial step.
That the client will need to find or
discover the server, so
that it can bind with it.
But before that can happen somehow
the server needs to do some things so
that it can be found.
The server will need to announce
to the rest of the world
what is the procedure that
it knows how to perform,
what are the argument types that
are required for that procedure.
What is its location?
The IP address, the port number,
any information that's necessary for
that server to be discovered and
so that somebody can bind with it.
What that means is that the server
also executes some registration step
when this operation happens.