Now that we've talked
about the WayPoint system,
let's also talk about
that speed parameter.
So by default, it's set to 0.05.
And we also have
the ability to change it,
to change it from being
really slow to really fast.
&gt;&gt; Right, and this effects
an important topic in virtual reality,
which is motion sickness.
Moving really slow can be okay and
teleportation can be
a little disconcerting.
But moving quickly between
places can make you motion sick.
This script allows you to change
the speed from slow to instant.
And exploring that will help
you understand this topic and
see what works for your scene.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so our task for
you is to basically play around with
this parameter and try it out in VR.
And let us know what you
think is really comfortable.
&gt;&gt; Right,
just don't make yourself too sick.