Now, see if you can take that quantified expression we had before.
>> Mm-hm. >> Okay, as far as the post condition is concerned and
play with it a little bit to get a post condition.
And this one, I'll give you a hint, is going to be different.
Okay, it better be different.
>> Mm-hm. >> Or otherwise we're specifying ordered again.
See what you can do with it.
>> So, very much like our other post condition, we will start by saying for
every element i.
That of, is index of, of a integer y from one all the way to the element
one less than the cardinality of the vector y.
It better be the case that, if we're looking at Y sub i
that it is greater than or equal to the element that-
>> Succeeds it.
>> Succeeds it, sorry.
[LAUGH] >> Comes in, comes [INAUDIBLE], okay?
That's precision is, is what this is all about.
>> Mm. >> So exactly right.
In fact, the only change is that instead of a less than or
equal, we have a greater than or equal, okay?
And notice that we could've done this same thing with j.
The exact letter that we use, doesn't make any difference.