If you'd like to follow along, you can
find the data set in the Resources tab.
You see here a small data set of
super heroes and super villains, and
we're trying to make conclusions about
differences between the two groups.
First, let's take
the average intelligence and
strength of both groups and
compare them.
As you can see, it appears that villains
are quite a bit more intelligent,
while heroes are stronger.
So now let's check the t-test results.
You can do this in Excel
using the T-TEST function.
This function has four fields.
The two data arrays you're comparing,
whether the test is one or
two tails, and
what type of t-test you're using.
For now, select the two-tail test and
an unequal variance test.
You can read more about
these options below, but
we won't go into detail in this lesson.
The formula will return a p-value.
The p-value will tell you how likely
it is that the two means are in fact
the same, and that there is no
difference between the treatment and
control groups.
The closer the p-value is to zero,
the more likely that the two
means are different.
In this example, though the observed
difference in means seems large,
the sample size is too small to result
in statistically significant results.
You can see this clearly because
neither of the p-values are below 0.05.
In order to get to
statistical significance,
you'd have to increase the sample size.