In the next set of quizzes,
I am going to be showing you how
variables are actually used.
All the programs that you are about
to do in part 2, will compile.
Which means that the computer can
understand the code that's been written
for them, and
we'll be able to create an app.
Now, while the programs will
be able to run on the phone,
there's a chance that they might
not do what the intended goal was.
This is something known
as a logical error.
A logical error means that there's
something wrong with the logic which you
used to write the code.
Let's look at a short program and
an example scenario and I'll walk you
through how you solve one of these.
Okay, so here's an example.
Each of these programs will have a goal,
which will be written out here.
The program itself will
be in the green box.
Okay, so the goal of this program is to
calculate something called sleep debt.
Now, how much sleep you need varies
a little bit by age, but on average,
people need about eight
hours of sleep a night.
So what this program is trying to do is
calculate the sleep debt in one week.
The user of the program will go ahead
and estimate how much they sleep on
an average weekday, and how much they
sleep on an average weekend day.
For this example, we're assuming the
user sleeps five hours on a weekday and
nine hours on a weekend.
The code for
this task is here in the green box.
And the first thing that you're trying
to do is read through this code and
decide whether or
not the goal was accomplished.
Then what you're also going to do is
go through each of the statements that
happened in the code and decide what
was actually displayed to the screen.
Assume that these method calls here,
the things that look like display and
have parentheses and
something in between them,
will display content to the screen.
Now, some of these problems will have
multiple pieces of content that they
need to display, so you might see
display1, display2, display3.
Okay, so
if you're still watching this video,
you're probably wondering how
to solve one of these problems.
This isn't the first time you're
interacting with multiple variables,
the values of which might change
a few times during the problem.
So let me do the first one with
you before I set you loose.
Now I'm going to use a technique called
hand simulation and what this technique
involves is trying to figure out
what the computer is doing, but
without just sticking
it to the computer.
For us really it's just an organized way
to keep track of what's going on with
the variables.
Okay, now you're going to go line by
line so let me start this with you.
In the first line here I see
a declaration of a variable, so
I'm going to go ahead and write
the variable name which is weekday.
It's also initialized
to a value which is 5,
so under weekday I'm
going to put the value 5.
This is representing that the variable
weekday currently stores 5.
Okay, so that was the first line,
I'm going to move to the next line.
We have a variable called weekend,
so I'm going to write that out,
and the value of that variable is 9.
Okay, so that's looking good so
I'm going to move on to the next
line which is a declaration and
instantiation of the variable
optimalHours, so I'll do the same thing.
Okay, so
I'm not going to write the value 7*8.
I'm actually going to calculate
that out because that's
what gets stored in optimalHours.
So, with a little bit of mental math,
7 times 8 is 56.
Okay, we have another declaration here.
We make a variable called actualHours,
so I'll write that out.
Well, it's equal to
the value of weekday, and
this is the current value of weekday.
It's not some past value of weekday or
future value of weekday.
Now, we're keeping track of what the
current value of weekday is over here.
And so I could just look here and
see that it's 5.
So I should really think
about this as the number 5.
So it's saying int
actualHours is equal to 5, so
I'm going to go ahead and
write that there.
OK we'll move on to the next line.
So now we're changing actual hours
again to be equal to the current value
of actualHours plus weekend times 2.
So I can look over here, the current
value of actualHours is 5 and
the current value of weekend is 9.
And now I have this
little equation here.
So, I do the multiplication
before the addition, so,
9 times 2 is 18 and then I add 5.
And with a little bit more mental math,
18 plus 5 is 23.
Okay, so this all equals 23.
And what I have to do is cross out
the old value of actual hours, and
write in the new value of actual hours.
Okay, so that's done.
Let's move on to the next line.
We have n solution, so
that's a variable declaration.
And it's being set equal to something,
but
I'm going to write out
the word solution first.
And solution is equal to optimal
hours minus actual hours.
So let's go over here, optimal
hours is 56 and actual hours is 23.
Now it's okay to use your calculator,
I happen to do that earlier and
I know that 56 minus 23 is 33.
Okay, and
then we move on to the next and
final line which says display solution.
So, we can look over here to see what
the value of solution is, which is 33.
So it is going to display the number 33.
So that is how I, or you, or
anyone, could figure out
what this program just did.
But the real question is,
did it do the right thing?
Is there a logical error
somewhere in here or
is somebody who sleeps five hours on
a weekday and nine hours on a weekend
night going to have thirty three hours
of sleep debt at the end of the week.
And I want to know what you think.
All right, quick side note, now you've
created this practice set 2 app, so
I'm just going to show you how you could
also put the code into the practice
set 2 app if you wanted to test it out.
I really recommend
hand simulating first,
because it's going to give your brain
a better grasp about what's going on.
But it's also go to be able to put
the code into Android Studio and
play around with it a bit.
So my suggestion is that you copy and
paste the code for the problem,
which will be provided in the instructor
notes, into the onCreate method.
That's the first method you'll see
in your main activity class here.
Okay, just to be very clear,
here's what your onCreate looks like
before it's modified and then you can
paste over the code, like I've done.
Okay, the other thing you're going to
need to copy and paste over,
which will make this line of code work,
is down here.
It is this code, and I've also
included this in the instructor notes.
The one final thing that you'll
need to do is go to your XML, and
make sure your that your text
view has an Id/display_text_view,
and this should exactly
match what's shown here.
Ok, as long as those two
things match when you run this
code, you'll get the value
printed out to the screen.
It's a little bit hard to see but
it says 33 right there.
Okay, and with all of that,
then I'll try to hand simulate and
some help with getting it up and
running on your phone.
Go ahead and try to figure out is this
program doing what it's supposed to do.