Now, some people like manipulating trees
and some people like a more--sort of formal--mathematical notation.
So if you're one of those, I'm going to give you another way to think about
whether or not we have a solution;
and let's start with a problem-solving
where a plan consists of a straight line sequence.
And we said one way to decide if this is a plan that satisfies the goal
is to say, "Is the end state a goal state?"
If we want to be more formal and write that out mathematically,
what we can say is--what this plan represents
is--we started in the start state,
and then we transitioned
to the state that is the result of applying the action
of going from A to S, to that start state;
and then we applied to that, the result of starting in that intermediate state
and applying the action of going from S to F.
And if that resulting state is an element of the set of Goals,
then this plan is valid; this plan gives us a solution.
And so that's a mathematical formulation of what it means for this plan to be a Goal.
Now, in stochastic partially observable worlds,
the equations are a little bit more complicated.
Instead of just having S Prime is a result of applying some action to the initial state,
we're dealing with belief states, rather than individual states.
And what we say is our new belief state
is the result of updating what we get from predicting what our action will do;
and then updating it, based on our observation, O, of the world.
So the prediction step is when we start off in a belief state;
we look at the action, we look at each possible result of the action--
because they're stochastic--to each possible member of the belief state,
and so that gives us a larger belief state;
and then we update that belief state by taking account of the observation--
and that will give us a smaller--or same size--belief state.
And now, that gives us the new state.
Now, we can use this to predict and update cycle
to keep track of where we are in a belief state.