Before we start connecting outlets and
actions let's apply some of
our diagramming strategies.
Let's think about how the views and
the view controller will interact when
the user starts tapping the screen.
Here's the sequence we expect.
The user touches one of the switches and
the switches turn those taps into
events, this triggers
target actions that we set.
An action method will be invoked on
the view controller, and in that method,
the ViewController looks at the state
of all three of these Switches.
That determines the background color,
which the ViewController will
then set on the colorView.
So we'll need outlets to get the state
of each of these three switches,
we'll need an outlet for the colorView.
And we'll also need to set actions for
each Switch.