A method like this is sometimes
referred to as a Call Back Method.
We configure the button so that it
will call back when an event occurs.
We're not changing the code in
the button we're just leveraging it's
architecture.
It was designed to call
back the controller.
We're going to be seeing this
pattern a lot in UI Kit.
We interact with our view objects so
that they reach back and
contact our control objects.
We see it here with actions, and
we'll see it later with delegates.
In general,
actions are method indications from
views back to view controllers.
Outlets on the other hand, are
indications in the opposite direction,
allowing method indication
from controller to view.
Next up, we'll transition back to
building our apps using Storyboard and
now, hopefully you can see storyboard as
a tool made to accomplish the very goals
that we just worked out in code.