Now, this is as if I had fi and I had k, etc.
But I said that this was uncalibrated right?
Right.
So, lets suppose we have a given camera, Pim equals K int times Pc.
All right, now see that k, that k intrinsics?
That's a nice, assuming we don't have zeroes sprinkled through here on
the diagonal, that's a nice invertible matrix.
So I can invert that k and that's what's shown here.
Okay, and what this says is that I can go
from the image back to the point out in the camera frame.
Now this should bother you a little bit, just a little bit because it says this,
this equation's fine okay.
We derived this a long time ago.
We said if you gave me the 3D point in the camera's frame,
I knew where it landed in the image.
But this second equation is saying that I can go backwards.
You can tell me where I am in the three,
in the image, and I'll be able to tell you where I am in the world.
And that seems wrong because that whole projection operator.
And then you say, aha!
This is not a regular three d point, this is a homogenous point.
And remember, where the projected geometry stuff we did a couple times ago?
That's anywhere along the ray.
And that's correct, right?
If you tell me where I am in the image if you just tell me the basic camera
intrinsic geometry I now know the ray in space that, that point came from.
And that's all projective geometry the homogeneous coordinate is telling me,
that if you give me the point in the image and
the intrinsics, I can tell you the ray in space.
Which is the same as a homogeneous three two the,
the homogeneous coordinate in the image.
Okay?
That's why we can go from an image, to what feels like a world point, but
is really just the ray.
So, now I can take that equation and I can say, well,
suppose I've got two cameras, typically called the left one and the right one.
Or the up one and the down one, or
the forward one and the back, or just the main and the prime.
Two cameras, okay?
Here written left and right to be convenient.
Okay?
Now we have a different internal calibration matrix per camera.
Right? They, the two cameras may be the same kind of lens,
the same everything or they may be quite different.
All I need to think about is that,
I, there exists an intrinsics calibration matrix for each one.
And by the way, this is uncalibrated, right?
Right. So I don't know what it is, I'm just assuming there is one,
and that it looks like that one that I showed you before.
I don't know what the values of those parameters are.
Okay?
All right.
Now comes the magic, all right?
Just repeated both equations here.
This says the location of that point in the right frame in terms of the ray.
This says in terms of the left in terms of the ray.
Okay?
But we know something about the relationship between the,
a point in the right and a point in the left if this were calibrated.
Right? What would I, what did I know there?
Well that was last time.
I know there's this thing called the essential matrix that would relate the ray
to the point from the right frame to the ray to the point in the left frame.
And the relation between them is called the essential matrix.
Now, I don't know what the essential matrix is.
Why?
Because I'm uncalibrated.
But I know there would exist one.
Okay?
So if I assume for
a moment there exists one, then I can rewrite this equation like that, okay?
So all I did was substitute for the point ray in,
in the right frame which was from here and I pulled that down into here, okay?
And do the same thing on the left.