Our last activity includes a mock
list of contacts in a recycler view.
And we'll be adding a touch
selector to these list items, so
that when you click them, they turn a
different color and react to your touch.
By responding to a user's touch,
selectors provide important
interactive feedback.
So even though adding touch selectors
is just a small visual detail,
it enhances the overall user experience.
Now that was the final state of the app,
but the starter code you've been
doesn't include selectors, so
when you click it, nothing happens.
So let's go in and
build a touch selector.
To create a touch selector, we'll be
creating a new drawable resource,
which is basically something
that can be drawn on screen,
in this case a colored background for
the selected list item.
To create a new drawable,
I'll right click on our res folder and
select create new Android resource file.
Then it'll prompt for the resource type,
which is a Drawable in this case.
And you want to make sure that the root
element for this drawable is a selector.
And I'll give this a name,
list_item_selector,
no qualifiers necessary.
So then click OK, great.
Then we should get this empty selector
file, which I'll add some to-dos to.
Ok, so here's our starting
selector code and to-do's.
First we created a new drawable
resource named list_item_selector and
choosing selector as the root element.
The next thing we'll need
to do is add items for
the different touch
states of our list items.
This will be kind of similar
to creating a style.
First, let's open an item tag.
Each item will include two properties.
The first is a drawable property.
This property will be the color
background for a selected item.
And I'll have this be
our primary light color.
The second will be a state property,
of which there are three main ones for
clicked items.
The first is state_pressed.
When state_pressed equals true,
that means an item has been pressed on.
The next two states I'll
add are state_activated and
state_selected, also both
true when an item is touched.
And by including all
three of these states,
you cover all scenarios when
a user has clicked on a list item.
And these will all have the same
drawable background color.
Then we also have to include one more
item for the default unselected state.
This will be an item with Android's
default background_light color.
There's no need to specify a state for
this one, since it will be a default.
And these four items
complete our selector.
Now we just need to apply
this to the list items.
So let's go to
the selector_list_item layout code.
Each list item is a linear layout.
And we just need to set the touch
selector we just created
to the background
property of this layout.
We refer to our list item
selector by saying @drawable/
the name of our selector and that's it.
Let's save this and
run it to see if it worked.
Now if we go to our Touch Selectors
activity, we can click on each of these
and it should be highlighted in
our color, primary light color.
And we can see that our
touch selector works.
It highlights each of these
items as I click on them.
Next it will be your
turn to implement this.
And then you'll be
done building this app.