For the discussion about aliasing, though, I'm just going to talk about
this in 1D, because it's a lot easier to draw the pictures and to make it clear.
So, hang on, what we're going to do is, we're going to now talk about
aliasing in the Fourier space, and we're going to talk about sampling a signal.
And we'll first talk about sampling a low frequency signal, and
then a high frequency signal.
Here we have a function, so here we have some nice function f.
And it's a nice smooth function, let's say, all right.
And it has some Fourier spectrum like this, F of u.
And you'll notice that it's kind of limited, right, it doesn't go,
it doesn't have very high frequency components, like,
no high frequency components, very, very low.
And here's our comb function pulse train, okay.
And, as we said before,
the Fourier transform of that pulse train is another pulse train.
And if the separation of that pulse train in, in space is M,
then in frequency it's 1 over M.
Now comes the point that's not so obvious.
Suppose I want to take samples of a continuous function, right, I want to
take a sample here, and a sample here, and a sample here, and a sample here, and
a sample here, et cetera, and I wanted to do it with a spacing of M.
How would I do that?
I actually have what I need here, I just multiply this times this, and
I get this.
All right?
That is, here is just the set of samples, multiplied by f.
Okay?
So sampling is just multiplying your continuous signal by this discrete comb.
This is is why we had to introduce the notion of multiplying functions, and
the notion of a comb.
Sampling is the multiplication of your signal by a comb.
Now, when I multiply in space, what do I do in frequency?
I convolve.
Remember, convolution in space is multiply in frequency, and
multiply in space is convolution in frequency.
So what I'm going to do is, I'm going to convolve the Fourier transform of f
with the Fourier transform of the comb, I'm just showing the power here, and
I get that.
Okay, so this is the convolution, and you'll see, if I just take this function
and I slide it along, I can re, I'll reconstruct it here, reconstruct it here,
reconstruct it there, and that's what this is showing you, okay.
So that's the Fourier transform of
the multiplication of the comb times the function.
Just copying that bottom row.
If this function is limited, in fact, I can show it down here like this,
all right, then if I could pull out that part of the signal,
the part of the signal that's frequency is just within some range.
Then I would be able to get back what I wanted, right.
I would be able to get back the original spectrum,
which would give me back the original function.
So this is no problem if this outer edge is small enough, that is,
that the, the maximum frequency of my signal is low enough for
the comb filter that I used.
Exactly what is that small enough?
Well, here it's written like this, okay?
If my comb filter is spacing M, so
then the comb of my Fourier of that, of the Fourier of the comb is 1 over M,
half this distance here is 1 over 2M, okay.
If the maximum frequency of that function, let's say is W,
for bandwidth, is W, if that's less than 1 over 2M,
then I can reconstruct that original signal by looking at just this part,
that is, nothing has contaminated that inner part.
So if there's no overlap, if W is less than 1 over 2M,
the original signal can be recovered from its samples by low-pass filtering,
which we'll talk about in a minute.
So those of you that know something about Nyquist sampling, so you know that if
I want to recover, say, something up to 20 kilohertz, right, 20 kilohertz, about
the, the extent of human hearing, I would need to sample at least 40 kilohertz.
By the way, CDs, like we used to,
were talking about, sample at 44 kilohertz, why?
So that we can recover everything up to 22 kilohertz,
which is the extent of human hearing.