UINavigationController is a class
that handles a stack of multiple View
Controllers. we can see one here in the
storyboard for a completed version of
Pitch Perfect. Like any other stack in
computer science or real life, you can
insert and remove items from the stack.
In a UINavigationController, you start
with a single View Controller called the
rootViewController. In this example,
the rootViewController is the View
Controller that has a recording button
and our stop recording button and our
Tap to Record label. And you can add as
many View Controllers on top of it as
you like.
Once we finish Pitch Perfect, we're going
to have a total of two controllers that
will be put on top of our Navigation Controller
One for recording and one for playback.
So our use of the Navigation Controller
will be to navigate between those two
screens.
Ok let's go back to our incomplete
version of Pitch Perfect. Now before we
can run we need to walk.
Currently our app has the View Controller
named View Controller as the start of the app.
With the Main.storyboard file open,
let's select it. And then let's
slide out the utilities panel and then
make sure you have the attributes
inspector shown. Okay, now first notice
this little grey arrow which indicates
that this is the initial View Controller.
If you have multiple view controllers,
you can drag this arrow around to change
which View Controller the storyboard and
therefore your app will start with.
Which View Controller is set as the initial
View Controller can also be modified
here in the attributes inspector, just by
checking or unchecking this checkbox.
So for now let's make sure that
Is Initial View Controller is checked.
ok with the View Controller selected,
I want you to go to the menu item for
Editor > Embed in, and then Navigation
Controller. Selecting it will
automatically create a
UINavigationController to start the app
and we'll place our View Controller as
the root. So if I scroll over, we can see
that the Navigation Controller is now
the initial view.
And then this arrow and icon represent
that our View Controller is the root
view for the Navigation Controller.
Now you're ready to add more View
Controllers to Pitch Perfect.