Now why would you want to add
perturbations to a model?
Isn't that what noise is for?
Let's consider a real life scenario.
Let's say I'm a robot
ambling away on the moon.
My goal is to reach this flag.
I can use my camera to detect and
track the flag.
This is what my view of
the world looks like.
Now, where the flag shows up
in my view and how it moves,
depends on a bunch of different things.
For instance, my movement across the
surface, both back and forth and turns.
Now the surface is really bumpy.
This can cause my view
to shake quite a bit.
I can also move my camera independently,
pan, and tilt.
The most annoying is probably
the wind blowing the flag all over.
It really messes up the appearance.
So which of these are known
perturbations that we can model for?