Welcome back.
Now let's actually start looking at
some very interesting advanced concepts.
Recall when we started talking
about computational photography.
One of the things we talked about
is we have an illuminated scene.
We want to take this illuminated
scene through a set of optics and
processing devices to be able to
capture and generate an image and
that image was basically rendered in
concepts of using things like pixels.
But during that whole process
I talked about the fact that
we want to be able to capture and
model the rays of light.
Which is the primitive
that we want to capture,
one of the things now we want to do is
look at the concept of light fields.
The concept of light fields basically
says at, at any point in a scene
you can put a camera and capture
all information about that scene.
And from the three dimensional
light that actually points and
captured at the scene is what
we're trying to capture.
So, in the concept of light feed,
what we're going to do, basically,
is look at that whole concept.
And see how we can actually capture
light at any point and generate
newer forms of cameras that actually
let us have all of this information.
That after we have captured the images,
we can generate novel views from, and
perhaps get to the pixels
a little later.