One of the best strategies is to try abstraction.
Instead of dealing with every single possible state of the game,
we can take similar states and deal with them as if they were the same.
For example, in poker one abstraction that works pretty well is to eliminate the suits.
If no player is trying to get a flush, then we can treat all four Aces as if they were identical
rather than treating the four of them as being different
and similarly with all the other face values.
Another thing we can do is lump similar cards together.
Rather than saying that 2, 3, 4, and 5 are all different values,
if I know that I'm holding a pair of 10s then I can think of the other players' cards
as being equal to 10, lower than 10, or higher than 10.
Otherwise, lump the same.
Similarly, I can lump bets together.
Rather than thinking of every dollar amount of a bet from $1 to the upper limit,
I can lump the bets into small, medium, and large.
Then finally another way to do abstraction is rather than considering every possible deal
of all the cards, I can just consider a small subset of the deals
to do Monte Carlo sampling over the possible deals,
rather than considering them all.
This approach extensive games can handle quite a lot
in terms of dealing with uncertainty, dealing with partial observability,
dealing with multiple agents, stochastic, sequential, dynamic.
But there's a few things they can't handle very well.
They aren't very good at unknown actions.
We need to know what all the actions are for either player before we can define the game.
Game theory doesn't deal very well with continuous actions,
because we have this matrix-like form.
It doesn't deal very well with irrational opponents.
We can know that we're going to do the best we possibly can against a rational opponent,
but it doesn't tell us how to exploit our opponent's weakness
if he turns out to be irrational.
Then finally, it doesn't deal with unknown utilities.
If we don't know what it is we're trying to optimize,
game theory isn't going to tell us how to do it.