If there's any kind of visual change
onscreen, from scrolling to animations,
the device is going to put up a new
picture, or frame, onto the screen for
the user to see.
Most devices today refresh
their screen 60 times a second,
which we measure in hertz.
And so to match that we need
to have 60 frames to put up.
Most of the time we'll refer to
this as 60 frames a second or fps.
People are especially good at noticing
when we miss one of these frames.
And they don't like it.
Think of how easy it was
to spot in Jank Invaders.
If the browser is taking too long to
make a frame, it will get missed out.
The frame rate will drop and
users will see stuttering.
If it's really bad, then the whole
screen can lock up, which is the worst.