All right.
You're done.
I'll show you how I did it.
So here's what I ended up doing.
I used a relative layout as the root,
which isn't really
necessary in this case.
You could have used a frame
layout just as easily.
So there's that.
And you can see we have a linear layout
here which contains our toolbar view,
and it also contains a space.
And it's colored primary.
So we could have actually done all
of this inside of the toolbar, but
we didn't really need to.
So we've created a bunch
of stacking views.
That's fine.
And then for our fragment main base,
we then just include it here and
align it to the top as well.
So right now both
are aligned to the top.
This layout also has app bar elevation.
The only reason this layout here
has app bar elevation is because
I actually did it for
you guys in the last one.
But you can't actually
set the elevation here.
You can only set layout parameters.
And elevation is not a layout parameter.
So that's one minor thing with
includes you should always watch out,
you should always watch out for,
is that the parameters that
are associated with the layout you're
including are actually there, except for
layout parameters which
you can modify on include.
If we look at fragment main base,
you can see that it actually
has app bar elevation.
Otherwise, this would not work.
It has to at least have the same
elevation as the thing that it's going
to be layering on top of.
Ideally it has a higher elevation,
but in this case it's the same.
And that's it.
That's all we did for that one.
Pretty straightforward.
I hope you're getting
really good at layouts now.
I know that it's one of my
favorite parts of doing Android.
So if you don't like this part of
doing Android, maybe you shouldn't be
doing front-end work, because there's
all that fun back-end work with content
providers and stuff like that,
which is also just as fun to play with.