For this quiz you'll be making this
slider, well, slide back and forth.
And just for reference, I'm calling
this gray box that's moving a toggle,
while the whole thing
is called a slider.
Let me show you what
the code looks like.
Like with the last event listeners quiz,
you can actually use either
JavaScript or jQuery.
The differences are minimal,
though you'll see me walk through my
solution with vanilla JavaScript.
Take a look through at.js to
see how the slider works.
It's pretty straightforward.
The crux of it being two methods,
ToggleTracker.addMovement and slide.
You'll want to call slide whenever
you want to animate a new position
of the toggle.
I also recommend using
requestAnimationFrame with it.
And that'll give you nice performance.
You can see that slide uses
transform translateX to move
the toggle some x position away
from its original origin, and
slide determines that distance by
using toggleTracker.getTtranslateX.
Back to toggletracker.addMovement.
It expects an x position
to get passed to it.
This exposition represents the current
exposition of either the finger,
as in a touch of ent, or
a mouse on the screen.
You want to call addMovement
whenever a new touch starts pr
a touch move event occurs.
And likewise, you'll want to call it for
a mouse down or mouse move.
It's going to be your job
to use the event listener
to find this exposition that
gets passed to atMovement.
In the end, all you'll need to do is set
the correct event handlers on the toggle
in the window so that both touch
dragging and mouse striking work.
Here's where your code should go inside
the attachEventListeners function.
You'll know you've done it right when,
well, the toggle is sliding back and
forth.
Make sure you test on mobile.
And if you're having a hard time,
make sure you read the comments in the
code because I left you a lot of hints.
Okay, well check the instructor notes
for more information and good luck.