We've seen this before during
Harris Corner Detection.
The answer is when lambda one and
lambda two are both fairly large and
of a comparable magnitude, it means
that there are multiple gradients in
the same region that can be used to
locate the gradient direction correctly.
>> Right, you remember this picture
here, where we take a look and we say,
well, if both of our eigenvalues
are small, then this is a flat region.
There's not much.
If only one of the eigenvalues is big,
then that's not good,
and here,
lambda 1 lambda 2 is in the order.
If we make them lambda 1
always being the biggest one,
then, then of course lambda
2 is bigger than lambda 1.
But the idea was that we were only
in a corner if both lambda 1 and
lambda 2 were kind of large, all right?
And remember, we said that we could,
we didn't have any decent corners here
in the blank area that was in the sky?
Well, guess what?
You can't really tell the motion either,
right?
Likewise, we said it wasn't a good
corner if you were along an edge
because the corner could slide along
that edge, and we wouldn't where it is.
Well, movement happened along
the direction of the edge, and
we wouldn't know how it moved.
So, where do we, where can we
estimate motion really well?
Well, we can mo, estimate it really
well in this textured region.
Basically the same constraint that we
had on the Harris corners namely to have
to have the gradients varying over
the window and that's indicated by
having two reasonably large eigenvalues
of that second moment matrix.
That's the same thing that
applies to motion estimation.