All right. So now we have our nice probabilistic model. They've been trained by data, and we'd like to see what we can do with them.
Here's an example of the type of things we'd like to be able to do, is resolve ambiguity.
So here we have the sentence, "I saw the man with the telescope," and two problem parses of the sentence.
In this part, it's the "seeing" that's done with the telescope. "I used the telescope to see the man."
In this parse, it's the man who has a telescope. So there's one noun phrase, "The man with the telescope," and that's what I saw.
Now, if we use the probabilistic model we have so far, all the probabilities are attached to these inner tree nodes,
and they only depend on the categories. So the difference between these two trees would be, one, here,
do we have a noun phrase that consists of a noun phrase followed by a preposition?
Or here, do we have a verb phrase which consists of a verb followed by a noun phrase followed by a prepositional phrase?
And yes, you could expect that there'll be different probabilities for those two cases.
But it doesn't seem like the difference between those probabilities is really getting at what's going on in this sentence.
What's really going on here is what we want to compare, and what we want to look at the probabilities for is,
does "telescope" and "with" go better with "man" or go better with "saw"?
So in other words, we'd like to condition our probabilities on the preposition with the noun "telescope"
and whether that associates better with "man," in which case we'd attach it here using this nP, or with "saw",
in which case we'd attach it over here using the vnP Pp construction.
And that doesn't seem to have to do anything at all with how common these constructions are,
whether vPs have pPs attached with them or whether nPs have pPs attached with them.
PP here of course means "prepositional phrase." But rather it has to do with the specifics of whether "men" are usually with "telescopes"
or whether "seeing" is usually with telescopes.
And so that's where we'd like to place our probabilities. And a grammar that does that,
that puts the probabilities down with the "telescope" and the "man", rather than up with the nP, that's called a lexicalized grammar.
So now we want to go--we started with context-free grammars, we add probabilities, and we got a probabilistic,
context-free grammar. Now we want a lexicalized probabilistic, context-free grammar.