Just briefly recall again the purpose of why we want to do
this kind of matching.
Again, I have been given two images.
And here are actually the images that you've seen throughout these lectures.
And here you can actually see some of the points labeled.
But you can't see them because they're not in detail.
So let's actually focus on them.
In this image I found one, two, three, four, and five different
features and I want to be able to find these same features in another image.
Again, remember, these are two different images and
you can notice that again, the sign is different across these two images.
The same features, again, same pixel types of information and
neighborhoods that are common between the left image and
the right image are now labeled here in red.
Of course I've ma, manually labeled them here, but
they're actually also exactly the features that are seen across the two images.
Now, exact is a definition here that we need to discuss a little bit.
That would be the best possible matches of these features across from one
to the other.
Because, in some sense,
they may actually look different now because of the view has changed.
But they should be as close as possible, similar to each other.
That will allow us to do matching.
The matching pipeline, now, basically, is finding that this feature is
the same as this one, and the next feature is also matched.
Another one.
And another one.
Again, now this basically starts telling me that these features are both
detected in these two images.
And are matched.
Noticing this feature one, for example, is exactly feature one here.
Feature two, feature two.
Feature three, feature three.
Feature four, feature four.
Feature five, feature five.
Of course,
to do real matching you would have to have a lot of these similar features.
And if you notice that in this image there are a lot more
features like this also marked and indexed across the thing.
Even though, of course, some of them may not exactly the same.
Because of our idea of reasons, but you can see these four, one, two, three,
four, one, two, three, four are also visible here.