Quiz!
Woohoo!
Let's see if you can work through what
the principle of balance means yourself.
Let's start with a multicore
Von Neumann system.
Suppose you start with one
version of the system,
whose parameters are perfectly tuned for
sorting very large arrays.
Then your boss comes along.
Like many bosses he's
a bit of a primate.
But hey aren't we all?
Your boss has the brilliant idea of
selling a new version of the system with
twice the cores.
Because he lives in America and
more is always better there.
My question to you is this, can you
adjusts to the other parameters of
the system in order to maintain balance?
Now to do this,
you're going to need an important fact.
For comparison-based sorting, the best
case ratio of comparisons, which
are the compute operations, and memory
transfers will be able L times log z/L.
Here are your answer choices.
You can half the bandwidth,
beta 0 and double the peak.
Or you can square both the fast
memory size and the transaction size.
Or you could double the fast memory size
or you could try doubling the bandwidth.
Now I want you to think about
these options and decide for
yourself which ones do you think have
the best chance of maintaining balance
assuming the number of cores doubles.