Back to business.
The first thing we're going to do,
is draw some very simple shapes to
the screen, like points,
triangles, and rectangles.
Ultimately, these drawing instructions
need to make it to the GPU, and
we know that the way that the CPU
talks to the GPU is via OpenGL.
Thankfully, we don't have to
interact with OpenGL directly.
Instead, we're going to use a LibGDX
abstraction called ShapeRenderer.
We ask ShapeRenderer to draw shapes for
us.
Then, it figures out all the complicated
OpenGL stuff that needs to happen under
the hood to finally talk to
the GPU to get our shapes drawn.
ShapeRenderer works in batches.
It's slow to ask OpenGL to
draw shapes one at a time.
But it's much faster to bundle up all
our drawing instruction into a batch,
then send that to OpenGL all at once.
Further, ShapeRenderer has
three shape type modes and
a batch can only contain
shapes of one of those types.
Those modes are,
well, I'll let you check out
the documentation to figure that out.
So, what are the ShapeRenderer
shape types?
If you just Google for
a LibGDX shape type,
you should get to the right
page in the documentations.
Or, you already bookmarked
the documentation right?
Should be easy to get back there.
Write your answers in these boxes.