Let's see how we can fix the problem
with the previous implementation.
If the problem is that all of
the CPUs are repeatedly spinning
on the atomic operation, let's try
to separate the test part which is
checking the value of
the lock from the atomic.
The intuition is that, for the testing,
we can potentially use our caches and
test the cached copy of the lock.
And only if that cached
copy of the lock is
indicating that the lock has changed
its value, that it's cleaned,
only then do we try to actually
execute the atomic operation.
So, here is what the resulting spin
lock, lock operation will look like.
The first part checks
if the lock is busy.
This checking is performed
in the cache value, so
this is the not involving any atomic
operation, we're just checking whether
a particular memory address is set to
one or zero, so it's busy or free.
On a system with caches,
this will clearly hit the cache.
As long as the lock is busy,
we will stay in this while loop,
it will not evaluate the second
part of this predicate.
So if the lock is busy,
this is one, this is true,
the entire predicate is true,
two will go back in the while loop.
What that also means is that as long as
the lock is busy, as long as this part
is true, the test and set, so the atomic
operation, will not be a valued at all.
We will not attempt to execute it.
Now, only when the lock becomes free, so
when this part of the predicate lock
equals busy, when this is not true.
Only then do we try to evaluate
the second part of this predicate,
at that point the test to set operation,
the atomic instruction will be executed
or will be attempted at least, and
then we will see what happens
whether we acquire the lock or not.
So what this also means is we will
try to make a memory reference
since the test and
set performs a memory reference
only when the lock becomes free.
This spin lock is referred to as
the test and test_and_set spinlock.
It is also reference as a spin and
read spinlock,
since we're spinning on the red
value that's in cache, or
spin on the cached values, so because
this is the behavior of the lock.
The Anderson paper uses the spin and
reach term to refer to this lock.
From a latency and
delay time point, this lock is okay.
It's slightly worse than
the test_and_set lock,
because we have to perform this extra
check, whether the lock is busy or
not that hits the cache, but
in principle, it's good.
But, if we start thinking whether or not
we really solved the contention problem
by allowing to spin on the cache, we
realize that this is not quite the case.
First if we don't have a cached
coherent architecture then
every single memory reference will go
to memory, just like with test_and_set.
So there's no difference what so ever.
If we have cache coherence with
right update then it's not too bad.
The one problem is that
all of the processors with
right update will see that
the lock becomes free.
So, regarding the delay.
And so every single one of them will
at the same time try to execute
the test_and_set operation, so
that can potentially be an issue.
Now the worst situation of using this
particular spinlock implementation
is when we have a right
invalidate based architecture.
In this case, every single attempt
to acquire the lock not only that
it will generate contention for
the memory module,
but it will also create
invalidation traffic.
Now when we talked about the atomics,
we said that a one outcome of
executing an atomic instruction,
is that we will trigger the cache
coherence, so the right update or
right invalidate traffic are regardless
of what the situation is.
If we have a right update situation,
that coherence traffic will
update the value of the other caches
with the new value of the lock.
If the lock was busy before
the write update event and
if the lock remains busy
after the right update event.
Great.
No change whatsoever.
That particular CPU can continue
spinning from the cached copy.
However, with the right invalidate, we
will simply invalidate the cached copy.
So it is possible that the lock was
busy before the cache coherence event,
before somebody executed
an atomic instruction.
And if the atomic construction
was not successful,
we're basically continuing to have
a situation in which the lock is busy.
However, as far as the caches
in the system are concerned,
that atomic instruction just invalidated
their cache copy of the lock.
The outcome of that is they
will have to go out to memory,
in order to fetch this copy of lock,
that they want to be spinning on.
So they will not be able to
just spin on the cache copy,
they will have to go ahead and
fetch this lock value from memory,
every single time somebody attempts
to perform an atomic instruction.
So this type of behavior will simply
just compound the contention effects and
will make performance worse.
The reason basically for the poor
performance of this lock is that,
at the same time, everybody will see
that the lock has changed it state so
that it has been freed.
And, everyone will also at the same
time, try to acquire this lock.