Let's get back to Monte Carlo localization.
Let's look at single particle that sits over here.
There's an x, y, and a θ.
Let's assume we happen to know that the robot is moving at velocity v
and at angle velocity ω, which is the differential of its wheels.
And after it moves so far, it will end up exactly over there with a heading pointing in this direction.
Now that you worked the math, you know exactly how to implement this.
In Monte Carlo localization, we don't predict the exact outcome. We add noise.
We add noise to velocity v and to the heading direction ω.
As we do so, we might find ourselves with lots of particles,
all of which have a slightly different xy coordinate and a slightly different heading outcome.
These particles together comprise our estimation after the motion command over here.
So, a single particle over here, if drawn multiple times,
gives a set of particles like the ones over here.
They're kind of hard to see at this point,
but you can imagine by varying v and ω with a little bit of noise that we
add or subtract from these values,
we will get slightly different predictions where the robot might be
and as a result get a particle cloud like this one over here.
That's really important.
We just implemented the prediction step of a particle filter in a real robotics example.
This is exactly what's happening when we drive our Google self-driving car and our Stanford car.