Our first randomized algorithm will be
one that verifies polynomial identities.
Suppose that you're working at a company
that is building a numerical package for
some parallel or distributed system.
A colleague claims that he has come
up with some clever algorithm for
expanding polynomial expressions
into their coefficient form.
His algorithm takes in some polynomial
expression and outputs a supposedly
equivalent expression in coefficient
form, but you're a little skeptical that
his algorithm works for the large
instances that he claims it works on.
You decide you want to run a test.
That is to say, you want to verify that
the polynomial represented by the input
expression A is equivalent to the one
represented by the output expression B.
Being slightly more general,
we state the problem like this.
Given representations of polynomials
A and B having degree d,
we want to decide whether they
represent the same polynomial.
Note that we're being totally agnostic
about how A and B are represented.
We're just assured that A and
B are indeed polynomials of degree d and
we have a way of evaluating them.
Well, here's a fantastically
simple algorithm for
deciding whether these two
polynomials are equal.
Just pick a random integer
in the range 1 to 100 x d.
The value of the polynomials
at this point and
say that the polynomials are equal,
if they're equal at this point.
Why does this work?
Well, the so-called fundamental theorem
of algebra says that any nonzero
polynomial can have only d roots.
So if A and B are different,
the bad case is that it has d roots and
what's worse is that all of them are in
this range 1 to 100d in the integers.
But even so,
the chance that the algorithm
picks one is still only 1 in 100.
So if the polynomials are the same,
we will always say so.
But if they're different,
then we will say they're the same
only with chances 1 in 100.
This is pretty effective and
if it is found that A is not equal to
B in some case, your algorithm is so
simple, but there can't be much dispute
over which piece of code is incorrect.