We just learned how to implement the
NSCoding protocol in our model objects.
Now we're going to learn Core Data.
Let's start out with a brief
comparison of these two techniques by
Mattt Thompson,
the author of the NSHipster blog.
The link to this particular post
is in the instructor notes.
I love the joke that this blog makes
about the two persistence technologies.
It's a joke made with two tables.
It's not easy to get a laugh out of
tables comparing NSCoding within
Core Data.
The first table compares Core Data and
the NSKeyedArchiver.
Things come out looking pretty good for
Core Data.
Core Data allows us to make
formal model of our data objects.
We'll look at that in lesson four.
It allows us to pull out select
pieces of upper system model.
Notice that in lesson two, we had to
pull out our entire data structure.
NSKeyedArchiver pulls out everything or
nothing.
Core Data will let us pull out portions
of our data based on query predicates.
That's nice.
Core Data is fast.
We'll see that Core Data lets us choose
the format on the hard drive, very cool.
And there are other things
like data migrations and undo.
All looking good for Core Data.
As Mattt Thompson says, it seems
like the comparison is one sided.
But then there's table two.
Although both strategies persist state,
one is almost universally regarded as,
let's just say one is more frustrating
and that goes on to discuss NSCoding,
but we've already covered that.
Let's move on instead and see what all
this fuss about Core Data is about