As this figure suggests,
the device space is extremely vaporous.
Device spaces come in
all sorts of shapes and
sizes, with a lot of variability
in their hardware architecture,
in the type of functionality
that they provide,
in the interfaces that applications
use to interact with them.
So in order to simply our discussion
in this lesson, we'll point out the key
features of a device that enable the
integration of devices into a system.
Any device can be abstracted to
have the following set of features.
Any device will have a set of
control registers that can be
accessed by the CPU and
that permit the CPU device interactions.
These are typically divided
into command registers that
the CPU uses to control what
exactly the device will be doing.
Data registers that
are in some way used for
the CPU to control the data
transfers in and out of the device.
And then also some status registers
that are used by the CPU to find out
exactly what's happening on the device.
Internally, the device will incorporate
all other device-specific logic.
This will include a microcontroller,
and that's like the device CPU.
This is what controls all of
the operations that actually take
place on the device.
It may be influenced by the CPU, but
the microcontroller will make sure
what things happen versus not.
Then there's some amount of on device
memory, any other types of processing
clauses, special chips, special
hardware that's needed on the device.
Like for instance,
you convert analog to digital signals
to actually interact with the network
medium, with the physical medium.
Whether it's optics or, or
copper, whatever else, so
all of those chips will
be part of the device.