So this leads us into the question of why should we be studying cameras and
computational photography?
One, these days, cameras are extremely pervasive.
Almost everyone has a camera.
All of you who are taking this class,
most probably have one, if not more than one camera.
They're in form of a smartphone or perhaps an advanced camera like a instant,
you know, instant camera or a handheld small camera, or even perhaps an SLR.
Of course, in our environment, cameras are everywhere.
They're getting to be smaller, ubiquitous.
And of course, we all know the stories about how many cameras are there
in perhaps things like security and other types of domains.
One thing that is true within all of this, and that is that as cameras get
smaller, there has always been a real significant improvement in optics.
And the applied field of optics has really kind of gotten more advanced, and
what newer kind of optics we can produce.
So of course, there has been improvements in devices and optics.
Of course, these sensors are getting cheaper and cheaper, too.
In fact, better, cheaper sensors like CCD and
CMOS are available, and essentially electronics is evolving as a field, too.
When we cover sensors, we'll talk about those advances, too.