This is a fun little site.
This is TodoMVC and it has the same
Todo application written using many
different frameworks and techniques, but
all of them have the same functionality.
Let's look at the backbone version.
There are a lot of moving parts in
front end framework-powered apps.
I want you to play around
with this site for a bit.
Add some items, take a couple off,
just mess around and
explore what can be done.
For this quiz, I want you to
pay attention to how smoothly
everything works and
how there aren't any page refreshes.
Then hypothesize on the steps
that a framework must take
to achieve this kind of functionality.
There are no wrong answers, so
write down as many ideas
as you can come up with.