So now we know how to
stabilize the camera paths.
Let's talk about how we can
re-synthesize some of them.
So here again, we're trying to
do stabilization by cropping.
Here is my window.
It's rotating, translating, and,
of course, scaling within this.
This is my output.
Of course, as we talked about,
this crop is constrained to
remain within the frame bounds.
So basically,
what we are doing is we're rendering
the image cell that actually is red box.
So, it's much simpler and
we don't have to worry about
doing any kind of interpolation.
We don't have to worry about any
kinds of filling in the gaps and
stuff like that.
Basically, what we're trying to do is,
we're applying a virtual crop and
that results in a stable video.
And you can see on top the result.