Okay, so now it's time for a quiz.
Here are four different groups of
database tables that might be used to
store information about
students in a school, and
their grades in several courses.
I'd like you to check the check box for
each one of these that is normalized.
In the first group up here, we have one
table, this table has a student's name,
the teacher's name, and the grade.
In the second group,
we also have one table,
we have a student ID, student's name,
a course ID and the grade.
In the third group down here,
we have two tables, this one has
the student's ID and the student's name.
This one has the student's ID,
the course ID, and the grade.
And in the fourth group, we also have
two tables, we have student's ID,
student's name, student's birth date.
And then in the second table we have
the student's ID, the course ID,
and the grade.
So again,
I'd like you to check the check box for
which ever groups of tables
you think are normalized.