We really want to have data that is
well randomized if we want to be
training on it sequentially.
It's important to, not present to a lot
of the those training methods, data
that has, you know, is all A's and then
all B's and then all C’s that really
breaks down the assumption that your
data is taking random steps over time. So
let's just randomize it once and that's
going to be enough for our purposes. In
some cases if you're running many many
parks over your data, you might want to
be randomized periodically your data to
improve the shuffling. It's not just a
theoretical concern, in practice bad
randomization really really can lead you
astray.
All right, and we’re panty raid so once
you randomize things.
Let's combine convince ourselves that
we've actually randomized things and we
haven't destroyed the data.
Finally we're going to save that data to
disk in the training data sets, training
labels, validation data set, validation
labels, test data sets and test labels.
The way python likes to store things is
using a little data structures like this
where you have a dictionary and you just
save the dictionary in to a file.