BURLAP uses the object oriented paradigm
to represent Markov decision processes.
Here is a brief overview of how
MDPs can be represented and
created using the library.
An MDP as a whole is represented
in BURLAP by a Domain Object.
Domains can be created directly.
But it is often useful to use one of
several classes in the BURLAP library,
specifically to generate
certain types of MDPs.
These classes are implementations
of the DomainGenerator interface.
In the JAVA documentation for
BURLAP, located at the URL here, and
also included in the instructor notes,
you can explore the classes available
through the BURLAP library.
In the left hand pane of the
documentation you'll see a list of all
the classes available in BURLAP.
Scroll down until you
find DomainGenerator.
Notice that DomainGenerator
is italicized.
This means that the class
is an interface.
If you click the link on the left
side for DomainGenerator,
you will see information about
the interface in the main pane.
Notice that at the top of the page,
there is a list of classes that
implement the DomainGenerator Interface.
If you're not familiar with Java Docs,
you can click each of these classes to
read a brief description of the type
of domain each class generates.
Now considering the type of MDP we are
interested in building, which of these
classes would be most appropriate for
us to use to generate a Domain Object.
Use the documentation for
each of these implementing classes, and
to the state diagram to
help inform your answer.
If you need a link to
the BURLAP documentation,
a URL is provided in
the instructor notes.
You'll find the state diagram there too.