You've probably noticed that SQL
queries can get pretty complicated once
the clauses and
sub-queries start to stack up.
As programmers, when we're writing
code and a function starts to
get too complex, we look for ways to
re-factor it into smaller functions.
Well we can do that in SQL too.
Every select query returns a table.
So, we can have the database
remember a select query for us, and
make it available to later queries.
When we do this, it's called a view.
Here's the syntax for
the create view command.
Views are really useful with
aggregations like counts or sums.
For instance, if we have a table of
students enrolled in courses, and
we want to know how many
students are in each course,
we can find that out
with an aggregation.
But then if we're going to use that
query a lot, we can store it in a view.
Using a view instead
of making a subquery,
is kind of like using a function
call instead of copying code.
Another use of views is to
display only particular columns,
from a table that has a lot of columns.
If you have a table with 20 columns,
and you have a lot of queries that only
refer to four of them, making a view
can make your code a lot more clear.
Here's something to think about.
Do you think that a database system like
PostgreSQL, should let us update and
delete rows in a view?