So congratulations.
You've just learned a lot about machine learning.
We focused on supervised machine learning
which deals with situations
where you have input vectors
and given output labels
and your goal is to predict the output label
from an input vector.
And we looked into parametric models
like Naive Bayes
non-parametric models.
We talked about classification
where the output is discrete
versus regression where the output is continuous
and we looked at samples of techniques
for each of these situations.
Now obviously
we just scratched the surface on machine learning.
There's books written about it
and courses taught about it.
Machine learning is a super fascinating topic.
It's the one within the artificial intelligence
I love the most.
It's really great about the real world
as we gain more data
like the world wide web
or medical data sets
or financial data sets.
Machine learning is poised
to become more and more important.
I hope that the things you learned in this class so far
really excite you
and entice you to apply machine learning
to problems that you face
in your professional life.