Awesome work.
The solution videos in this class
will be pretty short since the actual
solutions are all in the course code for
you to read on your own.
I do want to show you one thing though,
and
that's the importance of making sure you
don't put stuff in the render callback
that you don't want
called 60 times a second.
Let's say we accidentally put
initStars inside the render callback.
Any guesses on what's going to happen?
Let's give it a try.
Whoa, warp speed initiated or something.
So what's happening here is the position
of the star is being recalculated
every single frame.
Remember, be careful about what
you put in the render callback.