One of the functions of Gradle is to
define what version of various tools and
libraries your project needs,
before it can be built.
Gradle can usually go download
those libraries for you.
But it's not able to do that with
Android Build Tools and SDK platforms.
The version of the Build Tools and
the SDK platform that LibGDX uses,
ag slightly behind the latest and
greatest versions.
So, you might not have the slightly
older version that LibGDX wants.
So the last thing to do before
we import our first project
is to install the correct build
tools in the SDK platform.
To open up the SDK manager,
you can start on this
Android Studio Splash Screen.
If you can't see this, then just click
close any open Android Studio projects
you might have and you should get here.
Then we want to click on configure and
then go to SDK Manager.
Now, on the latest versions of Android
Studio, it'll open up this preferences
pane, but I really prefer to use
the older Standalone SDK Manager.
So, you can click down
here to open that up.
The SDK Manager will probably
want to install a whole bunch of
system images that you
probably don't want.
So, first of all, you want to click
deselect all to get rid of those.
Now what we do want is under tools
we want the Android SDK build tools
for vision 20.
And then scrolling down a bit,
under Android 4.4W2 or APL level 20,
we just want the SDK platform.
Click and install these two packages.
Accept the license, and
wait a bit for it to download and
you should be ready to
import your first project.
So, your turn to go ahead and
install those SDK components.
Follow the instructions below and
take another pass through
the instruction video if you need.
If you run into anything unexpected,
I want to hear about it so
I can make these instructions better.
All right, give it a try.