Now there's one more type of search for
plans that we can do with the classical
planning language that
we couldn't do before.
And this is,
searching through the space of
plans rather than searching
through the space of states.
In forward search, we were searching
through concrete world states.
In backward search,
we were searching through
abstract states in which some of
the variables were unspecified.
But in plans-based search,
we search through this base of plans.
And here's how it works.
We start off with an empty plan.
We have the start state and
the goal state and
that's all we know about the plan.
So obviously this plan is flawed,
it doesn't lead us from
the start to the goal.
And then we say,
let's do an operation to edit or
modify that plan by
adding something in new.
And here we're tackling the problem
of how to get dressed and
put on all the clothes
in the right order.
So we say,
out of all the operators we have,
we could add one of those
operators into the plan.
So here we say, well what if we added
the put on right shoe operator?
Then we end up with this plan.
That still doesn't solve the problem.
So we need to keep refining that plan.
Then we come here and say,
well maybe we could add in
the put on left shoe operator.
And here I've shown the plan as a
parallel branching structure rather than
just as a sequence.
And that's a useful thing to do,
because it captures the fact these
can be done in either order.
And we will keep refining like that,
adding on new branches or
new operators into the plan, until we
got a plan that was guaranteed to work.
Now this approach was popular in the
1980s, but it's faded from popularity.
Right now, the most popular approaches
have to do with forward search.
Now we saw some of the advantages
of backward search.
The advantage of forward
search seems to be
that we can come up with
very good heuristics.
So we can do heuristics search and
we saw how important it was to have
good heuristics to do heuristic search.
And because the forward search
deals with concrete plan states,
it seems to be easier to come
up with good heuristics.