You need to register
the TaskContentProvider
in the Android manifest, similar to
how you have to declare any activity.
Registering the provider in the manifest
allows it to be seen by the system so
that your app will be able
to refer to it later on.
EndPass calls to it through
a content resolver in your UI code.
You may recall that a ContentResolver
recognizes different ContentProviders
based on their unique content authority.
The authority is defined
in the manifest, and
it's typically just the package name
of the app that a provider belongs to.
Once a ContentResolver
knows this authority,
it can then make direct
calls to that provider.
So let's register
the TaskContentProvider in the Android
manifest XML file.
This way our To-Do List app
will know how to find it.
To register a provider,
first create a provider tag
within the main application tag.
In this tag,
define the name of the provider, which
is the full package name and class.
Then also define
the authority attribute, and
this is just going to be
the package name of the app.
The last attribute is
the exported attribute,
which can either be set to true or
false.
This attribute determines whether or
not your ContentProvider can be
accessed by other applications.
We're only building this ContentProvider
for use in this To-Do List app,
and there's no need to allow
other apps to access it, so for
now, exported will be set to false.
And that's it, now the To-Do List app
will be able to find this provider
by its unique authority.
In the next quiz, you'll be
expected to complete the checklist
of code tasks that correspond to to-do's
like this in your starter code so
that you can set up
the ContentProvider yourself.
You'll also find a link to
the GitHub repository that contains
the correct code for this step.