Let's now look at couple of
concrete examples of schedulers
that are part of an actual
operating system.
First, we will look at the so
called O(1) scheduler in Linux.
The O(1) scheduler receives it's name
because it is able to perform task
management operations, such as
selecting a task from the run queue, or
adding a task to it, in constant time.
Regardless of the total number
of active tasks in the system.
It's a preemptive and priority-based
scheduler, which has total of 140
priority levels, with zero being
the highest and then 139 the lowest.
These priority levels are organized
into two different classes, the tasks,
the priority levels from zero to 99
fall into a class of real time tasks,
and then all others fall into a so
called time sharing class.
All user processes have one of
the time sharing priority levels.
Their default priority is 120 but it can
be adjusted with a so called nice value.
There's a system call that
can be used to do this.
And the nice values can be
between negative 20 and
19, so as to span the entire
set of time sharing priorities.
The O(1) scheduler borrows from the
multilevel feedback queue scheduler, in
that it associates different timeslice
values with different priority levels.
And it also uses some kind of feedback
from how the tasks behaved in the past,
to determine how to adjust their
priority levels in the future.
It differs, however, in how it assigns
the timeslice values to priorities and
how it uses the feedback.
It assigns timeslice values based
on the priority level of the task,
similar to what we saw in the multilevel
feedback queues in the scheduling.
However, it assigns smallest
timeslice values to the low priority,
CPU bound tasks and
it assigns high timeslice values to the
more interactive high priority tasks.
The feedback it uses for the time
sharing tasks is based on the time that
the task spends sleeping, the time that
it was waiting for something or idling.
Longer sleep times indicate that
the task is interactive, it's spent
more time waiting, for instance,
on user input or in some type of events.
Therefore, when longer sleeps
are detected, we need to increase
the priority of the task and
we do that by actually subtracting five,
in particular from the priority
level of the task.
In this way, we're essentially boosting
the priority, so next time around,
this interactive task will
execute bit higher priority.
Smaller sleep times are indicative
of the fact that the task is compute
intensive.
Therefore, we want to lower its priority
and we do that by incrementing it by
adding the number five to it up
to a maximum, and essentially,
the task next time around will
execute in a lower priority class.
The runqueue in the O(1) scheduler is
organized as two arrays of task queues.
Each array element points to
the first runnable task at
the corresponding priority level.
These two arrays are called Active and
Expired.
The active list is the primary
one that the scheduler uses to
pick the next task to run.
It takes constant time to
add a task since you simply
need to index into this array based
on the priority level of the task and
then follow the pointer to the end of
the task list to enqueue the task there.
It takes constant time to select a task
because the scheduler relies on certain
instructions that return the position of
the first set bit in a sequence of bits.
So, if the sequence of bits
corresponds to the priority levels and
a bit value of one indicates that there
are tasks at that priority level.
Then, it will take a constant amount
of time to run those instructions to
detect what is the first priority
level that has certain tasks on it.
And then, once that position is known,
it also takes a constant time
to index in to this array and
select the first task from the runqueue
that's associated with that level.
If tasks yield the CPU
to wait on an event or
are preempted due to higher
priority task becoming runnable.
The time they spent on the CPU is
subtracted from the total amount of
time, and
if it is less than the timeslice,
they're still placed on the
corresponding queue in the active list.
Only after a task consumes its entire
timeslice will it be removed from
the active list and placed on the
appropriate queue in the expired array.
The expired array that contains the
tasks that are not currently active in
the sense that the scheduler will not
select tasks from the expired array
as long as there are still tasks on
any of the queues in the active array.
When there are no more tasks left
in the active array, at that point,
the pointers of these two
list will be swapped and
the expired array will become
the new active one and vice versa.
The active array will start
holding all of the tasks that
are removed from the active array and
are becoming inactive.
This also explains the rationale
why in the O(1) scheduler,
the low priority tasks
are given low timeslices, and
the high priority tasks
are given high timeslices.
As long as the high priority tasks
have any time left in their timeslice,
they will keep getting scheduled,
they will remain in the one of
the queues in the active array.
Once they get placed on the expired
array, they will not be scheduled.
And therefore, we want the low priority
tasks to have a low timeslice value so
that, yes they will get a chance to run,
however they won't disrupt the higher
priority tasks,
they won't delay them by too much.
Also note that the fact that we have
these two arrays also serves like
an aging mechanism so these high
priority tasks will ultimately consume
their timeslice be placed on
the expired array and ultimately,
the low priority tasks will get a chance
to run for their small time amount.
The O(1) scheduler was introduced in
the Linux kernel 2.5 by Ingo Molnar.
In spite of its really nice property of
being able to operate in constant time,
the O(1) scheduler really affected
the performance of interactive tasks
significantly.
And as the work loads changed as typical
applications in the Linux environment
were becoming more time sensitive,
think Skype, movie streaming, gaming.
The jitter that was introduced by
the O(1) scheduler was becoming
unacceptable.
For that reason,
the O(1) scheduler was replaced with
the completely fair scheduler,
and the CFS scheduler became
the default scheduler starting
in the Linus 2.6.23 kernel.
Ironically, both of these scheduler's
are developed by the same person.
You should note that both the O(1) and
the CFS scheduler are part of
the standard Linux distribution.
This one is the default, however,
if you wish, you can switch and
choose the Linux O(1) scheduler
to execute your tasks.