We've been digging through
Backbone's event system,
and now I want you to create your own.
You need to create an event tracker
function that accepts a name for
the object.
Then extend event trackers prototype
an add on, notify, and trigger methods.
On takes an event and
a callback, notify takes another
event track or object, and an event.
Trigger takes an event.
And the data that will be
passed to the callback.
This might seem like a one off quiz.
But you can use this to build
up your own library of custom
functionality that you've written.
If you're ready to tackle it,
click the next button.
If you want to hinder to
stick around for a second.
Okay ready for those hints.
Each event tracker object manages
a list of events and callbacks.
Very similar to how
Backbone's on method works.
But the object also has a notify
property to track the list of
other objects to notify.
Would you like hint number two?
Okay, the trigger method needs to
loop through the events list and
call each of the callbacks.
And loop through the notify list
triggering that object's trigger method.