Here's something to ponder.
Can you use algorithmic parallelism to
go faster without increasing power?
For the sake of argument, let's consider
an algorithm in the work span model.
Now suppose Brent's theorem holds,
provided you run it at some base clock
frequency on a PRAM type
machine with p cores.
Now you suppose you slowed down
the clock by a factor of sigma.
Let me give you an example.
Suppose the initial base frequency
was 1 GHz and sigma is 2.
And the new frequency is F over sigma or
500 MHz.
Ok, so that's what sigma means.
Now, a frequency change also means
the power per core goes down.
From the dynamic power equation,
it should go down by
a factor of sigma cubed.
Put another way,
you can actually use sigma cubed
more processing cores without
increasing the overall system power.
That's assuming constant power is 0.
So, my analytical question for you is
what value of sigma should you use?
I want you to type your answer
symbolically in this box,
in terms of W, D, P, and
numerical constants.