So what I want you to do now,
in a simple piece of code
given two gray scale images where
we have two images a left image and
a right image,
we'll provide that to you.
Can you actually now just
generate a simple anaglyph image.
Given again a left image, a right image
can you generate an image that once
when seen through this
A anaglyph glass set here,
which basically has again cyan and
red, would let you see that image.
Again important points to remember,
this is a red cyan glass set,
so you have to generate
an image that works with this.
So here is a simple code
I want you to now ex,
experiment with to create
an anaglyph stereo image.
Again, something that could be viewed
by a small set of glasses like this.
We've done the precursor stuff,
we basically loaded np and
computer vision open cv2 kit.
Basically if you have this function
which takes a left image and
a right image and now you want to be
able to create a red-cyan anaglyph
basically using two images.
To help you do this, we, of course,
have set up this two different images.
There's a left flowers and a right
flowers both of them are grayscale.
We can actually just do this
to show them and of course,
when you run this function it should be
able to now create an anaglyph image.
So here basically is just a simple
code that you have to write
taking the left image and the right
image to generate an anaglyph image,
which would then, of course, when you
test run, will give you the result.
Please write that code and
then test it and submit it.