Before getting started with building
an app that uses Google Sign In,
you'll need to have a few things.
First of all, you'll need a compatible
Android device that runs Android 2.3 or
newer, and includes the Play Store.
Or, if you prefer, an Android emulator
with an AVD that runs the Google API's
platform based on Android 4.2.2 or
newer.
If you're using Android Studio
you'll have this already.
You'll also need the latest
version of the Android SDK,
including the SDK Tools component.
You can get this from the Android
SDK Manager in Android Studio.
And then finally,
you'll need the Core Services SDK.
Check back to the intro for
this course to see how to get it,
and how to configure it if you need to.
Make sure you have all of
these before you continue.