Directives are awesome, and
they really take the difficulty out
of creating powerful templates.
I've created this controller for
a toy store and you need to
create a template for the store
that will display its information and
allow customers to interact with it.
Make sure you review the store's
information in this controller.
Then create the storefront template.
Use expressions and
directive to display the store's name,
the number of brick colors
that the store offers.
Create a list of the items
in this.bricks and
give it the id Color list.
For each item in this.bricks,
display an item for
each brick size that displays the size,
quantity, and price.
If the quantity is below ten, make
sure to give it the low stock class.
If it's below five,
display a more is coming soon message.
Give each item a buy button that will
decrease the quantity by one, and
a return button that will
increase the quantity by one.
Make sure to give each element
the required ID or class name.
I'll give you a preview
of what i came up with.
Here's the name, the number of colors
offered and a section for red, blue and
green bricks.
Each brick size has an entry with its
data and each one has the buy and
return buttons that also triggers
the messages and the low stock class.
The link to the starter project
is in the instructor notes.
When you finish building the template,
the feedback extension
will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.