Another type of analysis tool that you
could run in your code is called static
analysis.
Static analysis is a process
that is performed on a project
without running it.
So it's actually analyzing
the source code and
sometimes also some build artifacts.
While it doesn't find bugs of
the same way that unit testing does,
it helps find out some other
dimension of the quality of the code.
For example, it can find issues
with spacing, code duplications and
other complexity issues with your code.
Static analysis could take a significant
amount of time for larger projects, so
it's often run in
parallel with unit tests.
And it usually isn't something that's
going to block the delivery pipeline.
One popular free open source tool for
doing static analysis,
that also supports a lot of languages,
is called sonarQube and
we'll be looking into this next.
So let's learn a little
bit more about sonarQube.