The correct answer is to set
up two auto layout constraints
because the record button
has an intrinsic size.
I've used the trailing edge of
the button to the trailing margin for
the x coordinate and I've used
the bottom of the record button
to the bottom layout guide for
the y coordinate.
You can use different constraints as
long as you have one for the x axis and
one for the y axis.
The recording button has an intrinsic
size because there is an image
associated with it and
that image has a height and width.
The button could also have
an intrinsic size If it only had text,
since the text title would be using
a particular font and font size.
So it would have a height and width.