This is a radiance map now
of the image we captured.
What basically comes out now is we're
no longer in the range of 0 to 255.
This output basically shows
that this image now has a range
from 0.6215 to 12, 871 intensity.
All of the dark blue colors that
you see are close to this one.
All of the bright red, and of course,
when you're seeing the bright red
here and you actually notice that
there's a little bit of yellow because
as you notice in the image, this was
kind of getting very bright too, but
you see a lot of detail and
there's kind of really bright spots.
They're out there.
Of course, now we need to study how
we're going to take this radiance map
and create an image.
Before we go there,
we also need to think a little bit about
what kinds of file formats we can
use to save images like this.
Now that radiance image I showed you,
right, needs to be stored somewhere.
So far, we've been only as
interested in trying to say, okay,
I'm going to have 8 bits per red,
8 bits per green and 8 bits for blue.
Well, now we need a newer form
of an image, 32 bits per pixel,
because now we want to actually create
8 bits of additional information.
This is 24 bits, 8 bits per color,
so we're going to add an exponent.
Math works out the following way.
Basically, what it means is now,
if I have an RGB value of 145, 215, 87,
I'm going to actually
add another exponent
number here and what this exponent
basically does is take the RGB values,
multiplies with the 2, raise 2,
the difference of 149 minus 128.
One-twenty-eight was, again, remember
the 20 to 256 or 255, that white part.
Of course, and
this gives us values much bigger than 0
to 255 just by adding this
8 bit of information.
Of course, the other way is also there.
Rather than take this value, I can
subtract the 103, this information,
from 128 and this is this value here and
now I have much smaller numbers.
So now this allows us go from very small
numbers all the way up to larger numbers
and, of course, this format can be used
to save an image like this into a file.
This is a proposed representation
of a file format from Ward.
There are many other similar formats.
I do encourage you to look at
radiance map formats on the web.