In many cases, authorization
happens after authentication.
But it's important to know that these
two concepts of security can happen
disjointly as well.
I will provide a few examples of
some ways authorization can happen
without authentication.
If you find a key to a club's back door,
you can get in without showing your ID
because the lock doesn't care who
you are as long as you have a key.
Coupons and discount codes are a great
way for shoppers to save money.
The possessor of one of these
coupons is authorized a discount,
many times without having to
identify themselves in any way.
Dropbox and Google Drive support sharing
a file via long randomized URLs.
Anyone who possesses a link
can access the file without
authenticating an identity.
But people who do not possess
the link cannot access the file.
But the link can be shared over and
over again without the consent
of the original creator.
Logging in as root to a UNIX
system doesn't authenticate
you as a particular user,
just that you know the root password.
That's part of why it's considered more
secure to disallow direct root login and
use sudo or su instead.
So someone has to authenticate, and
their login as a particular
user can be logged.
Some web systems grant an authorization
cookie once a user has been
authenticated.
A cookie's just a code that
a browser can use as a pass to
access private data.
A browser with a cookie has
authorization to specific user
information without having
to log in with each request.
If you steal a cookie then you have
access to the user's files without
knowing their
authentication credentials.
This is called session hijacking.
If you're curious about session
hijacking works and how to protect your
sites from such an attack, some links
are provided in the instructor notes.