So after you set up
implementing this interface,
our LoaderCallback interface,
let's start by initializing the loader.
Now to do so properly, I'll first
make an integer loader constant for
my loader, and let's call it PET_LOADER.
Now I decided to arbitrarily choose
the unique ID to be zero but
you can set it up as any
other unique integer.
Now next, since further down I
know I'll be using the adapter in
all the call back methods,
let's create an instance of that class.
So let's create
an mCursorAdapter object, and
lets have it be of
type PetCursorAdapter.
So as a reminder, this will be
our adapter for our ListView.
So next, let's jump down here and
implement out these call back methods.
So first let's focus on, onCreateLoader.
So let me take a moment to type
out the rest of this method, and
then we'll talk through it.
So here, this loader will execute
the content provider's query method
on the background thread.
And notice that I've used parameters
that are very similar to the ones that I
used for creating on the main thread.
I simply just moved these over.
And one of those parameter
includes this projection.
And since we're changing our
app to be more performant and
responsive by using a loader,
I want ahead and
used a projection that was much smaller,
only having the ID, the name, and breed.
So remember the ID column
is always needed for
the cursor that you're going to
pass to any cursor adapter.
Also when you're typing this out,
if you see that Android Studio can't
resolve this cursor loader class,
that might be because the cursor
loader class hasn't been imported yet.
So one of the easy shortcut for this on
this computer, is going to be options,
return, and
then I'll select this class import.
All right, so
next stop is OnloadFinished.
So, here's the code to update the new
cursor containing the updated pet data.
So we see the cursor with
the pet data here, and
all I need to do is just
pass into my CursorAdapter.
And I do so
using the swap cursor method.
And the last call back method we need to
implement out is the on loader reset.
So here's the completed code for
this method.
So remember that this call back
is called when the data needs to
be deleted.
And that's why I can just pass
in null as the cursor here.
Now, the finishing touches on this
will require us to remove our
displayDatabaseInfo method,
so this up here.
As well as any references
to that method.
So on start we had called
displayDatabaseInfo here, so
let's delete that.
And then we also referenced it down
here in our action_insert_dummy_data
switch case.
So we can delete that.
Now all that's left to do
is to initialize the loader
as well as reestablish our adopter and
attach it to our ListView.
Since that had been called in our
displayDatabaseInfo method, and
we need to bring that back in.
So remember,
I asked you to do that in onCreate.
So data in onCreate,
let's kick off the loader using our
getLoaderManager .initLoader method.
Now all that's left to do is to
set up the adapter again, and
then attach it to the ListView.
All right, so I've gone ahead and
added these two lines here.
So this initialize our mCursorAdapter
which we'd created up above, and
then down here we attach that
CursorAdapter to our ListView.
So that takes care of
this coding exercise.