So to actually figure this out
we're going to need to check these
two conditions.
So we might actually find it useful to
check each one of them individually.
So here's the sum of the alphas, and
here's the sum of the alphas squared.
>> Okay.
>> So how are we going to start
filling some of these in?
Are there any of these cases
that we actually know what
the sums are going to be?
>> Yeah, two of them I think.
>> Okay.
>> At least.
Well, let's go ahead and get
the easiest one out of the way first.
So I think that's number, well actually
I think two of them are equally easy.
Let's do number five.
>> Great.
>> So we know that that's going to be
infinite, the sequence will be
infinite because it's a constant.
>> Yep.
>> And we also know the square of which
is just another constant,
and that's non-zero, so
it's also going to be infinite.
>> So what does that tell us
about this learning rate?
>> It says if your learning rate
doesn't get smaller over time,
then you're never going to convert.
>> That's right.
So this one, this learning rate, doesn't
work as far as the theorem's concerned?
>> Right.
>> You said there was another easy one.
>> So number two I think is easy because
you told me last time that that one
works.
>> [LAUGH] Yeah I guess that's
a reasonable way to do it.
Do you recognize this, the sum of these?
Do you know what this is called if you
sum up alpha to this sort of form?
>> Isn't it a geometric series or
is it harmonic?
Which one is it?
>> Harmonic.
>> [SOUND] Yeah, that's right.
That's our harmonic sequence and
the sum of this up to T acts a lot
like log of T, so if T goes to infinity,
we do get infinity there.
>> Okay, and we also know that
the square of it is less than infinity,
because you told me so last time.
>> Yeah, though that's again,
not the greatest reason.
It turns out that any time that
the power that we're raising,
the T to in the denominator is bigger
than one, it's going to converge, and so
that gives us both of these boxes,
right, because it's the same thing.
>> Mm-hm.
>> This problem in particular,
this one it does, it converges,
the value that it converges
to is really interesting.
I don't know if you know this, but
if you sum up the infinite sequence
of 1 over T squared,
you get pi squared over 6.
>> Oh, right, yes, that's obvious.
>> No, it's not obvious.
>> Well, explain it to me then.
>> I can't, it's bizarre.
It's like, where's the pi?
Where's the pi?
I want some pi.
>> I ate it.
>> All right.
So this problem was known
as the Basel problem, and
for hundreds of years people didn't
really know how to solve it,
and Euler worked on it and solved it,
but he didn't solve it validly,
he eventually came back and
solved it right.
But it is,
it's kind of a remarkable thing.
Pi's come up when you're doing areas
of circles and things like that,
there's no circle here, so it's kind of
interesting that you get a pi squared.
>> Or r squared, right?
Pi r squared
>> [LAUGH] Pi r squared
>> Let's hear it.
>> Sure, but
the pi's not squared, it's weird.
>> I agree it's weird.
I mean, I think I vaguely remember
this from calc two or something.
>> Cool, alright, well anyways, so
that's just sort of a fun thing that
I find to be fun, but the point is that,
so let's look at the first row here.
If we square T squared, we get T to the
fourth, which is bigger than 1 over T,
so that one's also going to converge.
So what does that give us
in terms of answers here?
>> No and yes.
>> Exactly, right, it's because
we need it to be infinity and
then less than infinity.
One of these boxes we've
actually figured out,
because this 1 over T to the 1/2 or the
square root of T, if you square that,
that's 1 over T, so this squared
box has to be the same as this one.
So that's infinity, and
actually that tells us the answer for
this one even before we
figure out the rest.
>> Yeah, I guess so, but you gave
the answer away a long time ago.
>> How so?
>> Because you said that if
the exponent was greater than 1,
then it would converge and if it was
less than 1, then it would not converge.
So I can just look at the numbers or
the exponent for number three and
number four, and
I already know the answer.
>> So let’s just fill them in then.
Go ahead, what do you got?
>> Okay, well, let’s see.
If the exponent is greater than 1,
then it will converge.
Less than infinity, that's true for
neither 2/3 or 1/2.
>> So these are infinities?
>> Right, and you just have to square
them and ask the same question.
>> Good.
So we squared this one,
and that gets us 1 over T,
which also has an infinity.
>> Right.
>> And you square this one and
you get 1 over T to the 4/3,
which is bigger than one, so
that one should converge.
>> Right.
>> So
interestingly this one works,
this one works, and this one doesn't.
>> Right.