With the content cleared out,
we can use this space to
start creating our own chart.
Let's take another look at
what we're trying to recreate.
We'd like to recreate
China's red circle.
In 2015, China's life
expectancy was 77 years, and
its income per person was
13,300 GDP per capita,
and its population was
a staggering 1.38 billion.
When creating any
visualization based on data,
you need to figure out how to translate
these data values into pixel values.
In this case,
we need to translate the income per
person value, which is an x-value,
and the life expectancy, which is
a y-value, to pixels on the screen.
These will become our x and
y coordinates for
the center of our circle.
Fortunately, D3 was created for
just this purpose, so it has
many convenient functions that make it
easy to map data values to pixel values.
The most common functions that
we can use come from d3.scale.
It's a module that has many other
methods available to it in D3.
In the upcoming videos, I'll go over
scales and show you how we can create
linear scales, log scales,
and even square root scales.
Those scales are going to be
what allows us to convert
data values to the pixel
values you see here.