To receive simple downstream messages,
use a service that extends GCM
listener service to handle messages
captured by the GCM receiver.
GCM receiver extends
wakeful broadcast receiver.
Guaranteeing that the CPU is awake so
that your listener service
can complete its task.
Recall that this is why the way clock
permission was not optional for us.
We need it in order
to use this receiver.
By overwriting the method
on message received,
you can perform actions based
on the received message.
In our case, we want to
trigger a system notification.
So let's look at on message received
where we'll need to process our message.
There are many different types
of messages so just look for
the one you want in your app and
ignore any others.
In this case,
we want a message from our SenderId,
that means that we will know
how to properly parse it.
Parsing the message is going to
be determined by you not by GCM..
The way that your server constructs
its requested Google service
is how it will be passed along.
In this case,
I used to JSON object to my fake server
in order to send data with both
a weather value and a location value.
You can build up complex messages or
use only simple ones, but
just make sure that if you
change something in your server,
you update your logic in your app.
Otherwise you might start to
notice a bunch of null values and
your app could go all wonky.
Finally, we'll pass our alert message
along to a helper function that
builds out a notification.
You recall how to build notifications.
The things you want to note here are the
content intent which directs back to
main activity and the priority.
Because this is an alert and
potentially important for
users, I'm going to increase
the priority to one.
Priorities can range from
negative two to two and
I want this one to be noticeable but
not spammy.
Choose priorities with care so that your
users have a good experience and not so
that you are always on top.
Also, note how we build up
the notification image.
We set both the small icon and the large
icon so that we can use a storm image to
make the alert more on point, but
also the sunshine sun image so
that users can understand
where the app came from.
It is considered a best practice to use
your app icon as the small icon and
something relevant as the large icon.
Also, note that large icons
must be passed as bitmaps and
not as a resource reference.
So be sure you're constructing a bitmap.
Then, just fire the notification off and
our GCM implementation is done.
Congrats, you.