Okay, here's a problem to think about
that might seem a little bit fanciful,
but it's a good way to get intuition
about bandwidth and latency.
This is a problem about computing
the bandwidth delay product
of a network link.
Which is just what you get
when you multiply bandwidth,
measured in bits per second,
times latency, measured in seconds.
If you multiply the bits per second,
times seconds, you get a result in bits.
And that has a real physical meaning,
it's the amount of data in bits that can
be in transit,
across the link at any moment.
The amount that can have
been sent by one end, but
not yet received by the other.
If you think of the network link as
being like a water-pipe, the bandwidth
is the flow rate of water through the
pipe, for instance in liters per second.
And the delay or latency is
the amount of time it takes to get
through the pipe,
from one end to the other, in seconds.
And in that case, their product
is the volume of the pipe in liters
the amount of water that's inside of it.
Now let's imagine that we have a station
on the moon that we'd like to send a lot
of data to.
We are beaming data to the moon using
a laser transmitter that can send one
gigabit per second.
Now the distance from the earth to
the moon is around 384,000 kilometers.
And the speed of light,
the speed of that laser connection,
is 300,000 kilometers per second.
So any given bit that we send to
the moon travels at that speed.
Now, if we're sending at
full speed all the time,
because the rabbits in the moon
really like Udacity courses,
how much data is in transit between
the earth and the moon at any moment?
That is, what's the bandwidth delay
product of our earth moon network link?