Before we jump into
making a setting screen,
I want to talk a little bit about
data persistence in Android.
Persisting data is the act of
saving some data to the phone.
There are five different ways to persist
data that you should be aware of.
First, is persisting data
using saved instant state,
which is what we've
talked about earlier.
This allows you to save key value pairs,
to store the state of one of your views.
It is usually used to save the state
during things like app rotation, or
if the system destroys the activity
because of memory constraints.
This is a temporary place to store
the state of an application.
And it should only be used if the user
is still actively using the app.
If the user pressed the back
button to quit the app or
restarts the entire phone,
the data saved here is gone.
If you need data to be available across
app restarts and turning the phone off
and on again you need to save
the data to an actual file system.
Android has three ways to do this, the
first is the SharedPreferences clause.
What SharedPreferences does,
is you specify a file, and
it saves simple key value
pairs to that file.
The keys for those key value
pairs are always strings.
And the values are primitives like
strings, string sets, booleans and
various numerical types.
After those key value pairs are saved to
a file all sorts of things can happen to
the steady of the phone, but, as long as
it still works, and your app hasn't been
uninstalled, you can still get
your information from that file.
SharedPreferences is usually used for
things like,
if you need to save single text or
numerical value about the user.
For example,
if the app is a game it might save the
player's name in a shared preference.
Or if you're building a browser
application, you might save the lost web
page that the user was looking at and
reopen it when the app relaunches.
Sometimes, though,
you'll have more complicated data
than just simple key value pairs.
For example, perhaps you have an
application that allows users to create
and save book recommendations
from friends.
There are a few things about this data
that makes it different from just using
key-value pairs.
First, your going to be storing
multiple book recommendations.
Second, the number of book
recommendations will change as the users
add new ones.
And finally, the book recommendations
each have a lot of associated data,
such as who recommended the book.
The name of the book, the genre, etc.
All of these differences make
a handful of key value pairs
totally inadequate for handling
the size and organization of such data.
In this case,
you should consider using a database.
Android provides full support for
relational databases in
the form of SQL lite databases.
And it provides various
framework components,
such as content providers that help
manage and share data in databases.
We'll be talking a lot more about
databases in the future lessons so
stayed tuned for them.
That up to this point we've
been talking about text data.
But at some point you might want to
create an app where users generate,
download or otherwise need to store
multimedia or large amounts of text.
For example, a podcast app might
need to store audio files for
the podcasts to play offline.
A camera app will need to
store users' pictures.
And an app for your local library you
might need to store downloaded e-books.
In these cases,
Android offers the ability to save files
using internal storage, which is just
saving it to the phone's hard drive.
And also external storage,
which is saving it to
something like a memory card.
And finally, you might find yourself in
a situation where you actually need to
save data in a place accessed
by multiple devices.
This might be something as simple
as a leaderboard of scores for
your new game app, or if you're
building a social networking app that
allows users to log in from any phone.
In these cases, you'll end up not
storing data on your phone but
in the cloud.
This usually means setting
up a database on a server or
using a service like Google's Firebase.
In this course however,
We'll be focusing on covering these
methods of data persistence in depth.
In fact we've already covered
save instant state but
if you're interested in learning
more about saving files or
setting up a server or
even using firebase.
I'll link some documentation
that will get you started but
first some quick quizzes