Here I'm showing
an interesting video.
This is actually a video from
the Georgia Tech football game.
Me and my group did a little bit
a work on analyzing football plays.
And here you notice that basically
we can register an image.
And actually, again,
on top you see a play field, and
of course you can track the players,
these are x's and o's.
And we can track the players and
also keep the field registered to know
exactly where the yard markers are.
This is all done by using computer
vision methods of tracking information
in these videos.
Tracking the players,
tracking the ground and
of course using the yard marker lines
to align the field as much as possible.
That allows us to then, of course,
extract more information about where
the players are and how they're moving.
Yes, in my group we do a lot of work on
video and this is one of the examples.