So here is a a very
interesting line drawing.
It's, it's a line with two parts and
notice it has a corner.
And here's the next one.
Voila, it moved.
Back, forth, back, forth.
I could do this all day, okay?
And you can see it moving, okay?
Great, let me put an aperture over that.
So here is a great big green aperture,
all right?
And now, I'm going to move
that line thing the same way.
And now it goes like this, whoa.
Now it's moving up or
at least it feels like it's moving up.
Is it moving up?
No.
In fact,
here I've made it transparent, okay?
So now, this is the same motion, right?
If you, fact, if you look at the corner,
you can tell this thing is moving
over and down a little bit.
But if you were to look just inside the
circle, it looks like it's moving up.
Not down and over,
that's the aperture problem, okay?
You can only tell the motion locally in
the direction perpendicular to the edge.
There are some other effects of getting,
sort of, strong gradient flow.
So this is a, single pattern and
then I'm going to use Power Point to
just put this in motion using animation.
So there's no video going on here, this
thing is just moving back and forth.
And hopefully, as you see this move,
you, every time it bumps,
you're going to see the inside
move relative to the surround.
It's not actually moving,
that's in your head and
that's because of various noise and
various ways of computing the gradient.
Like more details and it's not,
it's just not the aperture problem.
But it's showing the sensitivity in
your mind, in your head of the gradient.
The aperture problem also is sometimes
used to explain the barber pole
illusion, right?
So it's spinning around but
you see stripes going up.
And in fact,
in the you shouldn't believe
everything you see on the web universe.
Some people will say that
the aperture problem explains
the barber pole illusion but
actually that's not really true.
It has to do with it, it doesn't explain
it, because if you think about it,
the gradients here are not
quite vertical, right?
They are off a little bit and so
you can get a flow that's like that.
And you have to do some integration
to decide that the whole
thing is moving up.
And actually, Ellen Hildreth,
a very long time ago and
her PhD thesis looked at how
you use the normal flow.
And you can integrate it in
order to make the, the, the,
you might see the pole move up.
But it is the case that there are places
out there that will tell you that
this is because of the, the vectors.