Looks like we managed to get a nice
looking boarding pass screen using
the constraint layout.
If you're still not convinced that
the constraint layout was a good choice,
let's use one of the cool
features of Android Studio,
called the hierarchy viewer.
>From Android Studio,
select Tools, Android, and
then Android Device Monitor.
This should open
an Android Device Monitor window.
>From this window, select Window and
Open Perspective.
Finally, select Hierarchy View and
click OK.
Then you should be able to click
on our boarding pass activity
if it's running on an emulator.
The hierarchy viewer builds
a tree of all the views and
view groups you have in any layout.
If we try it for our current boarding
pass layout that uses a constraint
layout, you can see that
the tree is entirely flat.
And here is an overview of
what our vies look like.
This is because we never needed to
nest any view groups in one another.
And this means,
it becomes super fast to load.
If you click on specific layouts or
views, you can find out more
detailed information about them.
Now, if we compare this to the exact
same design but using a relative layout
instead, you would have seen
a much deeper tree, which usually
means a much slower rendering time and
hence, bad performance.
Another thing to keep in mind
is the total number of views.
Too many views in a layout, nested or
not, may still affect
the display performance.
That's why it's always a good
idea to break down your design
to multiple screens, if you seem to be
using too many views in one screen.
A general rule of thumb is to have a
maximum of 80 views in a single layout,
and never more then ten
nested view groups.
Even though you might that,
that's a lot, you would be surprised how
many views you would end up using
in some mildly complicated screens.