Here are the icons for
the three more popular games.
This icon with the spray can.
This puzzle icon.
And this burger icon.
So, any of these answers are correct.
But it can be hard to tell.
The point of this exercise was to show
that even if you didn't recognize
all the game icons, you still made a
decision about which games were popular
just based on the appearance.
Some of these examples have too many
tiny details, like this house, or
are boring to look at.
And this is going to be our first
impression of the game when we
search for it.
And people do this all the time.
They quickly judge how good a game
is based on how the icon looks.