Welcome to the first class on machine learning.
So far we talked a lot about Bayes Networks.
And the way we talked about them
is all about reasoning within Bayes Networks
that are known.
Machine learning addresses the problem
of how to find those networks
or other models
based on data.
Learning models from data
is a major, major area of artificial intelligence
and it's perhaps the one
that had the most commercial success.
In many commercial applications
the models themselves are fitted
based on data.
For example, Google
uses data to understand
how to respond to each search query.
Amazon uses data
to understand how to place products on their website.
And these machine learning techniques
are the enabling techniques that make that possible.
So this class
which is about supervised learning
will go through some very basic methods
for learning models from data
in particular, specific types of Bayes Networks.
We will complement this
with a class on unsupervised learning
that will be taught next
after this class.
Let me start off with a quiz.
The quiz is: What companies are famous
for machine learning using data?
Google for mining the web.
Netflix for mining what people
would like to rent on DVDs.
Which is DVD recommendations.
Amazon.com for product placement.
Check any or all
and if none of those apply
check down here.