Our program is divided into several parts.
As you move through each part,
you'll learn a specific skill set in the
classroom and then complete a project
designed to help you put that skill set to work.
In your first week, if you're
entering the program as a true beginner,
we'll start by writing lots of simple
programming statements and Swift - Apple’s
programming language for building
iOS apps. We’ll finish up part 1 with
a set of coding challenges.
If you're coming to us with some experience in
programming, we’ll start off with a crash
course in Swift syntex and quickly move
on to building your first app. Silly sounds.
We encourage you to make this path
into your own personal journey.
Skip ahead to courses that are especially
interesting to you, return to review
material that was especially challenging.