So let me demonstrate both the need for
video stabilization, how we're going to
go about it, by showing you this example
video, which I got from the Internet.
You can see this video is actually
from a GoPro-style camera,
of a person wearing it on their head.
And going for, you know,
a marathon in this instance.
Very hard to see this and
in fact if you look at it carefully you
might start feeling sick a little bit.
Almost feels like
an earthquake kind of motion.
Almost impossible to see any details.
And this is the quality of video
you get from the internet.
Lot of you know, noise in this video.
And again, this is the kind of
stuff we get and, of course,
we would like to improve
the quality of this video.
Here is what we want out
of a video like that.
We would like to take that video and
generate a video like this,
still a little shaky, but much smoother
and actually much more viewable.
So what I'm going to actually talk about
in this lecture is actually a system
that we have actually built ourselves.
And actually is running on YouTube.
And I'm going to actually step through
variety of steps that we went through to
build this whole system.
That will take the video like the one we
saw and generate a video like this one.
Just to help us see this,
let's put them next to each other.
Original video, right next to
it is the stabilized video.
You can tell much more shaky,
much less shaky.
And again, it's important to
know that these kinds of videos
are getting very popular.
And YouTube has a whole lot of these
types of videos, partially because it's
just much more of the domain of where
we are with videography these days.