You may be asking yourself, how are processes created?
What came first?
In operating systems, a process can create child processes.
In this diagram here, you see that all processes will come from a single root,
and they will have some relationship to one another where the creating
process is the parent and the created process is the child of that parent.
Some of these will be privileged processes.
They will be root processes.
In fact, this is how most operating systems work.
Once the initial boot process is done and the operating system is loaded on
the machine, it will create some number of initial processes.
When a user logs into a system, a user shell process is created.
And then when the user types in commands, like list or
emacs, then new processes get spawned from that shell parent process.
So the final relationship looks like this tree.
Most operating systems support two basic mechanisms for
process creation, fork and exec.
A process can create a child via either one of these mechanisms.
With the fork mechanism,
the operating system will create a new Process Control Block for the child.
And then it will copy the exact same values from
the parent Process Control into the child Process Control Block.
At that point, both the parent and the child will continue their
execution at the instruction that's immediately after the fork.
And this is because both the parent and the child have the exact same values in
their Process Control Block, and this includes the value of the program counter.
So, after the operating system completes the fork,
both of these processes will start their execution at the exact same point.
Exec behaves differently.
It will take a Process Control Block structure created via fork, but
it will not leave its values to match the parent's values like with fork.
Instead, the operating system place the child's image.
It will load a new program.
And the child's PCB will now point to values or
describe values that describe this new program.
In particular, the program counter for
the child will now point to the first instruction of the new program.
Now, the behavior of actually creating a new program is like,
you call a fork, where the fork creates the initial process.
And then you call an exec, which replaces the child's image,
the image that was created in the fork, with the image of this new program.