You know, I gotta say,
Trace View is an awesome tool.
>> [LAUGH]
>> I was using it to profile my app last
night and I got so much awesome
data about my function performance.
Who knew that the vector class
is slower than the array list?
>> You know,
that's the trick with Trace View, man.
I mean it's got a ton of data in there,
right?
And-
>> Yeah.
>> Makes it really hard to
use because of it, but once you
actually start getting rolling and
actually start understanding
what it's doing.
It's kind of like free awesome in a box,
or better yet,
like a one stop performance shop.
You know, I like that, like [SOUND] we
should like, make that into a meme or
something like that.
Hey, you think if I put that on
a t-shirt anybody will buy it?
>> Yeah, maybe, I mean, yeah, perhaps.
>> Oh.
>> But.
[LAUGH] I'm going to do this.
>> Oh no, no, no, no, no!
Aw.
>> Yes!
Come on, man.
That's how it's done, man.
>> Best three out of five.
>> Heh.
If you think it's going to matter.
>> Eh.
Come on.