Now you have a Tag Manager
account with its first container.
Mine's called DailySpecialContainer.
The next step is to put
something into the container and
then use it in your app.
So the steps are like this.
In Tag Manager, create a variable.
And then, publish the container.
Then in your app code, you write
the code to get and use the variable.
Then you update the variable,
publish the container again.
In your app code, well,
you already wrote the code, so
you don't need to do anything.
Your app will automatically
get the latest value.
Now lets look at how to create
the daily special variable
in the Tag Manager dashboard.
So make sure you're in the container
tab and click Variables.
You'll see that tag manager defines
a bunch of pre-defined variables, and
you can make use of these
variables in your app.
For example,
you can use a device name, so
that different devices use a different
background image in your app.
For now though we're going to
define our own custom variable.
To create custom variable, click New
in the User-Defined Variables section.
Whoa, there are a lot of variable types.
You can read about what they each
are in the online help for Tag Manager.
For now, we want a Value Collection.
Choose Type, Value Collection,
that's what we want.
But first,
you need to name the variable, and
this is going to be the DailySpecial,
and now we need to configure it.
So configuring the variable basically
means specifying the value.
And for a value collection,
it's a key value pair.
It's actually a list of key value pairs.
You could put as many key
value pairs as you want.
But for now, let's just do one for
the DailySpecial.
So since it's a key value pair,
let's have the key be daily-special and
enter a daily special of your choice.
And you need to begin and end
the value with open and closed braces.
We're going to save the advanced
settings for later.
We need to Continue, and
we need to choose when to enable it.
Well, we want to always enable it.
So create variable,
I now see in the User-Defined Variables
section, I've got one variable.
However, it's not enough to just
define or update the variable.
If you want your app to get the latest
values, you need to publish the changes.
So we press the Publish button,
it double checks if we really want to
publish and so I'll say Publish Now.
Oh, I got an error.
So this is one of the nice things,
is that the publish process does catch
errors in your key value pairs,
in your value collection list variables.
So let's go fix that.
I fixed the key value pairs in my
variable, press Continue, and I save it.
Now that I saved it,
I'll publish again, Publish Now, and
yay, success my changes are now live.
Of course I'm not actually doing
anything with this variable, but
we'll get to that in seconds.
Go ahead and create the variable for
the daily special.
So make sure that you set your variable
name, type is set to Value Collection,
that you've configured the variable,
and entered the key value pair for
the Value Collection.
Enable, Always and create the variable.
Then when your variable's created,
make sure you publish your container.
And next, we're going to look at how
to download the default container.