As Magnus said, you'll now be adding the
functionality to create conferences to
your application.
We use a conference entity
class to represent conferences.
Each conference entity will be
created with an ancestor, or parent,
which is the profile entity
of the user who created it.
Let's take a look at the code for
the conference entity class definition.
As you can see, the class itself
does not have a parent property.
Why do we want conference entities
to have their creator's profile
as a parent?
Because this makes it very easy to
quickly find all the conferences that
a particular user has created.
Using NDB,
the way you create an entity with a
parent is that you use parent equals and
then the parent entity key when
creating the key for the new entity.
First you have to get the profile key,
same as you did when working with the
profile creation and updating methods.
Then you'll create the conference
key the same way, but
also specifying the parent.
Now, when you created
the profile entity,
you specified that the user_id should
be used as the ID for the entity key.
For conference entities we
still need a unique ID.
We don't have anything that we can
use for this, unlike the profile.
However, the ndb.model superclass gives
us the ability to create unique ID's for
any entity class.
The method for
doing that is called allocate_ids, and
it returns a list of unique ids.
So if we just want one we'll have
to access item zero of that list.
We can then define a key based on
that unique id and the parent key.
Okay, so
you now have the conference key, but
when a user creates a conference they're
going to specify a bunch of information
that we want to save in the data store.
And some of that user input will
need to be processed a bit first.
So let's take a look at
the conference class.
Every conference has a name, which
is a required field, a description,
the user ID of the organizer,
some set of topics,
which is a repeated field because
a conference could be on several topics.
It's going to be located in the city,
it's going to have a start date and
an end date.
For searching purposes,
it's also going to have a month.
Are there any conferences in June?
There's going to be
a number of max attendees.
How many people could possibly
fit in this conference?
And the number of
current seats available,
which will change as people register for
the conference.
Let's also take a look down
at the conference form class.
This class defines the input parameters
to the create conference function,
just like profile form defined
the input parameters for
the function save profile.
But the fields between
conference forum and
conference are not exactly
one to one the same.
So the code that handles
conference requests will have
to translate between them.
And since we're using the conference key
as part of the URL for our conference,
this code will also have to translate
the key into a web safe text form,
that doesn't have any
funny characters in it.
Now it's your turn to add the
functionality to create conferences to
your application.
Since there's a lot to do,
we've provided you templates for
the new functionality.
To get ready, copy the code from
ToDo_1_conference.py into the API
class in your conference.py file, and
from ToDo_1_models.py
into your models.py file.
You'll need to copy the conference form
and conference classes to models.py,
and the copy conference_2 form and
create conference objects functions and
the create conference endpoint
definition into conference.py.
Once you've copied the contents of
the to do files into your project
take a look at the Conference and
ConferenceForm classes.
Specifically, does ConferenceForm have
properties that map to the following
Conference properties?
Name, topics, parent and month.
Check off the ones that it does.