And now let's consider one final case in which every single one of
the user-level threads has that particular signal disabled.
So all of the user-level thread masks are zero.
The kernel-level masks are still one,
the kernel still thinks that the process can handle this particular signal.
When the signal occurs here, the kernel sees that the signal mask is one, and
so it will interrupt whoever is executing in
the context of this kernel-level thread.
The library handling routine kicks in.
It sees that this particular thread has the mask zero.
And it sees that it doesn't have any other user-level threads that can
handle that particular signal.
Now what will happen is the threading library,
at that point, will perform a system call, and it will
request that the signal mask off the underlying kernel-level thread be changed.
So this signal mask will become zero.
Now, from the execution of one thread, we can go ahead and affect
the state of the kernel-level masks that are associated with other threads.
They may be executing on other CPUs.
So here, we can only change the mask that's associated with
this kernel-level thread, and then what the threading library will do,
it will basically reissue the signal for the entire process again.
The OS will now find another thread in that process.
So in this case, this other kernel-level thread.
It had originally the mask.
The OS will, in that case, find another kernel-level thread.
In this case, this other kernel-level thread that has the mask enable.
So this one has its zero.
And we'll try to do the same thing.
We'll try to deliver the signal in the context of this kernel-level thread.
It will interrupt this user-level thread via the library handler.
As a result, this particular kernel-level mask will be changed as well via
system call, and the process will continue until all of the kernel-level signal
masks don't show that the signal is disabled for this process.
Now another possibility is that one of the user-level threads finishes whatever
they were doing and are ready to enable the signal mask for that signal again.
Because the threading library knows that it has already disabled all of
the kernel-level signal masks.
It will, at that point, have to perform a system call to go into the kernel and
update one of the signal masks, so it appropriately reflects that
now the process is capable of handling the signal.
The solution for how signal handling is managed and
what kind of interactions happen between then kernel and
the user-level library is in the same spirit of optimizing the common case.
Signals, actual signals,
occur much less frequently then the need to be safe and update the signal mask.
So whenever we would have a certain critical portion of the code,
we would first disable and then again enable the signal.
And in most of those cases, a signal doesn't really occur.
So then we tried to make the common case cheap, so the updates of the signal
mask, we just apply them to the user-level signal mask, and the actual
system call that's necessary to reflect that change in the kernel is avoided.
As a result of that,
we have to make the actual signal handling a little bit more complex.
But hey, that's the less frequent of the two, and
we want to optimize the common case.