Alright, let's bring up the chi squared table. It says at the top, probability
of a larger value of chi squared. We want the probability of getting a larger
value than the critical value to be 0.05. With two degrees of freedom, our
critical value is 5.99. Therefore any chi squared statistic greater than 5.99
will have a probability less than 0.05. If we think of it on the chi squared
distribution, this means the probability of getting a larger value than 5.99 is
0.05. Therefore, we would decide to reject the null, since chi squared, 7.78 is
greater than that critical value. But let's also use QuickCalcs. 7.78 with two
degrees of freedom, we get that the two tilt P value is 0.02, which is, indeed,
less than 0.05. Great job. We can conclude that the verb, smashed led to more
yes responses for the question, did you see broken glass. These results are
consistent with the view that the questions asked subsequent to an event can
cause a reconstruction in one's memory of that event.