The next question is let's look at the game of chess
for which the branching factor is somewhere around 30. It varies from move to move.
The length of a game is somewhere around 40.
Certainly some games are much longer, but that's an average length of a game.
Now let's imagine that you have a computer system,
and you want to search through this whole tree for chess,
and let's assume that you can evaluate a billion nodes a second on one computer.
Let's also say that for the moment somebody lent you every computer in the world.
If you have all the computers and they can each do a billion evaluations a second,
how long would it take you to search through this whole tree?
Would it be on the order of seconds, minutes, days, years,
or lifetimes of the universe. Tell me which of these.