We're not quite to getting icon packs
into Sunshine but we are far enough
along to replace our current icons
with ones loaded with Glide.
Copy in the new getArt URL for weather
condition utility method, the new URL
string, and our dimension for the
default notification, large icon size.
Then, update the DetailFragment and
the ForecastAdapter used for
the forecast fragment.
Don't forget about the adjust view
balance attribute for the XML files.
But before we use gray scale icons for
the future dates, let's update it so
that all days use the colorized icons.
Don't forget about our notification,
we want pretty icons for everything.