[Thrun] So let's talk about robot path planning or robot motion planning,
which is a rich field in itself, and I can't give you a complete survey
of all the algorithms involved.
But one of the key differences to the planning algorithms we talked about before
is that now the world is continuous.
For example, we learned about A* in which we discretize the world.
We might have a goal location, we might have obstacles,
and then A*, a valid action sequence, might look like this.
And even though this is a valid solution to the planning problem,
a car can't really follow these discrete choices.
There is a number of very sharp turns over here that are just irreconcilable
with the motion of a car.
So the fundamental problem here is A* is discrete,
whereas the robotic world is continuous.
So the question arises, is there a version of A* that can deal with the continuous nature
and give us provably executable paths?
This is a big, big question in robot motion planning.
Let me just discuss it for this one example
and show you what we've done to solve this problem in the DARPA Urban Challenge.
The key to solving this with A* has to do with the state transition function.
Suppose we have a cell like this and we apply a sequence of very small step simulations
using our continuous math from before.
Then a state over here might find itself right here in the corner of the next discrete state.
Instead of assigning this just to the grid cell,
in the algorithm called hybrid A*, it memorizes the exact x prime, y prime,
and theta prime and associates it with this grid cell over here
the first time the grid cell is expanded.
Then when expanding from this cell it uses a specific starting point over here
to figure out what the next cell might be.
It might happen that the same cell is reached again in A*, maybe from over here,
leading to a different continuous amortization of x, y, and theta,
but because in A* we tend to expand cells along the shortest path
before we look at the longer paths, we now just cut this off
and never consider the state over here again.
This leads to a lack of completeness,
which means there might be solutions to the navigation problem
that this algorithm doesn't capture,
but it does give us correctness.
So as long as our motion equations are correct, the resulting paths can be executed.
Now here is a caveat.
This is an approximation and is only correct to the point
that these motions equations are correct that are not correct.
But nevertheless, our paths that come out are nice, smooth, and curved paths,
and every time we expand a grid cell
we memorize explicitly the continuous values of x prime, y prime,
and theta with this grid cell.