Now let's learn about if statements.
Let's start by playing our scene.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We still have one little problem.
Our coconut falls through the ground.
Let's fix that.
We're going to add an if statement to
check if the coconut is on the ground.
If it is,
then we stop moving the coconut.
Let's go back to our script and
modify it.
Okay, like before,
we'll talk about this in just a second.
But for now,
just save your script and press Play.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
All right, our coconut stops
on the ground, nice work!
Let's look at that code one more time.
The if statement says,
if the object's position in
the y-axis is greater than 0.6 meters,
then move it down.
Okay, great,
we've solved our coconut problem.
Now, just for fun,
let's do a slightly different animation.
Okay, go ahead and
save this and then press Play.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Look out over the rocks.
And there's your coconut,
defying gravity.
And it looks pretty cool, too.
Now the update is not just straight
down, but it follows the sine function.
You could do anything here.
So take a moment and play with it.
[BLANK_AUDIO]