So far you've practiced creating
an array and initializing the array.
And now you'll practice writing code
to access elements of the array.
And knowing this,
you can use the value of an array
index to set the text on text view.
So for
now you'll access elements of an array
by printing the value
to the Android logs.
So remember you can access the logcat
manager from this button here.
So given the code that we have now,
nothing shows up on the screen just yet.
And remember that we introduced
logging back in the Android for
Beginners course.
So there we learned that Android
keeps a system log of what is
happening on the device.
It's a running log of
messages from the system.
You can think of it as a diary that
includes the time something happened and
the description of what happened.
These system messages are helpful for
debugging and we could check
the logs to go back in time
to figure out what's happening in
the device before the problem occurred.
You witness this firsthand when we
were building the just Java app
back in the Android for
Beginners course.
When an app crashed,
we could see the error messages in
the logs to help us debug the problems.
Remember in Android Studio that the
messages appear in the logcat Window.
Now in addition to using
the log to view errors,
we as developers can also
write messages to the log.
And we call this process of
writing to a log, logging.
This can help us temporarily
debug our app or
just double-check the state of
our app while it's running.
So it's similar to using the debug
tool where we can add breakpoints
to check the state of different
variables in our app and
this allows us to write the value
of certain variables to the logs.
But personally, I like using logging
statements because they're quicker.
So instead of manually stepping
through each line of code in the app,
you just let the app run as normal and
log messages get printed along the way.
So this is a helpful article
on how to write log messages.
You just need a single line of code for
one log message.
Notice that there are five different
categories of log messages
based on how severe or
urgent the message is.
So it ranges from verbose messages,
which are just nice to know messages,
all the way to error messages, which
mean severe issues such as when your app
is running into unexpected behavior.
So for now, we're just going to
practice writing verbose log messages
to help us check the state of
certain variables in our app.
Notice for all these log messages,
they required two strings as inputs.
So clicking on this first Log.v method,
we see that the first input
parameter is a tag name.
So anyone can print to the logs,
the Android systems, or other apps.
So we use this tag to identify
where the message is coming from.
Often for the tag,
we just use the name of the activity or
class the logging statement is found in.
For example, we can have a log
statement in the numbers activity and
we can make the tag just be
the numbers activity string.
The second parameter is message, and
this is just the message
we'd see appear in the logs.
And the second parameter is message,
and this is just the message we'd
see appear in the logs, and it can
be whatever you'd like to be logged.
So going back to that main article,
we see an example down here.
It's a Log.I method call, which we
know from here is an information log.
We see that the tag name here is main
activity and the message is here.
So in our message parameter, we use the
plus operator to concatenate strings.
So string concatenation is a fancy
way to say, string addition.
Similar to how we add numbers together,
we can merge strings
with the plus operator.
In this case, we're merging this string
with this position variable to create
a much longer string.
So in the logcat,
you'll see MyActivity as the tag name.
And then the message
MyClass.View- get item number 1.
And this is assuming that the value
of the position variable is 1.
Here's an example in
our NumbersActivity.
So I added these two log messages at
the bottom of our onCreate method.
Now I'm going to run
the app on my device.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now with the app running, I'm going to
navigate to the numbers activity and
notice that these two messages
in the log output appear.
So we get the statements
the word at index 0 is one and
the word at index 1 is two.
Now notice two things here.
First, we need to add a buffer
space after the colon, so
that all this text isn't
all scrunched up together.
And secondly, we didn't put this
words[0] in quotations because we
want the value at this index, not
the literal string with the brackets.
So to summarize, printing out the log
message is a really useful way
to make sure that the variable has
the expected value you expect it to.
So these log messages will be temporary
and we'll remove them later on.
Now let's put logging to
practice in your Miwok app.
Take the time to log
messages in your code so
that you can see the value of
each element in the words array.
And so this is the expected output
in the logs and go ahead and
check this box when you're done.