Here's what I got.
n/L log base z/L of n/L.
Let's see how I got there.
Let's consider some run that's produced
at some level of the merge tree.
Let's say that's at level i.
At the previous level, i-1, each run
contains K to the i-1 times s items.
That's assuming that at the very top of
the merge tree, each run had s items.
So how big is the output run?
It should be K to the i times s.
Now recall the number of memory
transfers needed to produce
just this one run.
It's proportional to the size
of the run divided by L.
So how many runs are there at level i?
It's basically just the length of the
input, divided by the length of any run.
So that's n/k to the i times s.
Thus, the total number of transfers at
level i is just the product of these two
quantities.
In other words, theta of n/L.
Notice that this quantity is
independent of the level.
And, lucky you,
I gave you the number of levels.
So, multiplying that by the number
of transfers per level gives
you the result.