How is this done?
Well, simply put,
what we want to do is, we have a target image and a source image.
What we want to do is create a small graphical representation.
And now we want to figure out from this one is,
that, which pixels come from which image.
So in essence, what we can do is take this small three by three grid
representation and create a node structure out of it.
You will add constraints to it, and this linked structure is there, but
we want to make sure that there is a node on this one and another one.
So this node is related to target image,
this node is related to the source image, and you can represent that here also.
So now we laid this out here, these are all the nodes, and between each and
every node is a cost function.
A cost function basically says how similar it is to go from here to there, and
this could be dependent on, of course, how similar these pixels are.
If these two pixels are really similar versus this one,
I want to keep these two and cut this one.
And again, if these two pixels are similar over this one,
I want to create a cut here.
So looking at it,
I find the most similar ones between those two within this neighborhood.
And I choose which one to cut, this or that, this or that, or this or that.
So this allows me to now come up with a way to kind of take a target image, and,
of course, this target image is constrained to this node here, and this source
image is constrained to this, so they have to come up with one or the other.
The rest of them, I have to choose, and I have to look at,
again, similarity between these two to chose where to cut between them.
And in essence, find a path of cut through this that gives me the results.
So here, for example, a cut is through this, where I
cut through these two different connections and I find that basically these
pixels are coming from the source and these pixels are coming from the target.
Such minimum cost cut is, can be computed by a variety of algorithms, and
the more popular one is the max-flow/min-cut algorithm that's used widely.
Again, I recommend you to look at these two papers that I've cited here.
This allows me to now basically come up with a solution that says,
I'm taking pixels from target here and source here.
And that allows me to generate an image like the one I showed you.
Another approach is to use this kind of stuff dynamic programming, and
that's also something that's available for you to look at.
It's one of the cited papers in the list.