So the answer we're looking for here is
actually the computeFibonacci method.
So let's review what I
did to figure it out.
All right, so running Traceview on
the following activity, and basically
profiling the function that happens when
I press this compute Fibonacci function.
This is what the Traceview
output looks like.
All right, so here's an output
that I got from running Traceview.
You should see something similar.
Notice this large pink area.
This is a bad thing, this basically
indicates that something is
taking up a lot of CPU
time on our main thread.
So if you sort by exclusive CPU time,
or by hovering over this pink area.
You'll notice that the computeFibonacci
method, which is coming from our caching
activity, is the one that's actually
occupying the most CPU resources.
So this is something we want to fix