I'm not sure after like, I can't think definitively for
any of the, the types where it may be more difficult for that change to happen.
>> Think about adding an operation into into the architecture
to do the deletion.
Is there one architecture which would be easy to
find a place to do that deletion?
>> With the, the abstract data type solution, because we have
these well defined interfaces and what they can do, if all we need to do is
add a delete operation to a particular, I guess, interface within that system,
the ADT model seems to support, will be able to support that type of change.
>> And it had a line data instructor right there, a line ADT.
>> Mm-hm. >> Just an operation to delete a line.
Okay? >> Right.
>> It goes into a single place and because of the abstract interface,
nobody else depends upon that operation taking place.