In a lot of databases, we're talking
about unique entities out in the world,
like individual people or locations, or
email accounts, cities, or gorillas.
If something is unique,
there can't be two of them.
So for instance, names aren't unique,
not even full names.
There are a lot of people in
the world named Jennifer Smith.
But a particular person named Jennifer
Smith is still a unique individual.
You wouldn't want to give one
person another person's grades, or
their parking tickets,
just because they share the same name.
Whenever we want to unambiguously relate
a row of one table to a row of another,
to see they are about the same person or
thing out in the world.
We have to have a unique value
to talk about that thing.
In the cutest animals database, we used
a numerical ID for each animal picture,
which we used to relate
the votes table to it.
That's a pretty common choice.
Just make up a unique number for
your database.
It's so common that most database
systems can do it for you.
User IDs, comment IDs on forums and
so on, are all examples of this.
In database terminology, a column and
a table that uniquely identifies rows on
that table, can be called a primary key.
Sometimes the world gives us
a natural primary key for a table.
For instance, if you have a table of
countries and their capital cities,
you can be confident that there
aren't two countries named France.
So in that case, you can safely use
the name of the country as a key.
You don't have to call
it country number 29.
But you have to make sure
that a key really is unique.
For instance, in the US,
there are several states with
a city named Springfield.
There's Springfield,
Massachusetts, Springfield,
Illinois, and a whole bunch of others.
So it's obvious that the name
Springfield isn't unique by itself.
Now, you might be tempted to think
that city plus state is unique, but
it turns out that
that's not true either.
In the state of Wisconsin, there are
five different towns named Springfield,
and there are three in New Jersey,
and two in Texas.
Doh!
And that's why most countries
use postal codes, or
what we call zip codes in the US.
Just like saying that somebody
is player number three or
user 1,723, instead of using their name.
Using a made up number like 54028,
or 54659,
instead of Springfield,
Wisconsin, guarantees uniqueness.