We just created a variable or
parameter in Remote Config,
called friendly_msg_length
in the Firebase console.
Now we'll configure our app,
to fetch that parameter.
RemoteConfig requires its own
pod to bring in dependencies.
In the pod file, make sure you
have the Firebase/RemotConfig pod.
If the pod isn't there,
you can add it now, and run pod install.
We have all the pods we need,
so let's go back to Xcode.
Here I am in the FC view controller,
at the signedInStatus function.
When a user logs in,
I want the app to set the message length
equal to the value we've set
in the remote configuration.
I'm going to add a call,
to configureRemoteConfig,
here in signedInStatus.
This function will be responsible for
instantiating the Remote Config.
I'm also going to add a call,
to fetchConfig.
This function will assign the most
recent message length value
from our remote configuration.
Now let's dive into,
configureRemoteConfig.
We'll create a reference to
the singleton Remote Config object.
The Remote Config object stores default
parameter values that are found in
the app.
Fetches new parameter
values from the server, and
determines when those fetch values,
are implemented in the app.
I'm also going to create an instance
of the FIRRemmoteConfigSettings object,
with developerModeEnabled.
We can then assign those
settings to our Remote Config.
This will give us the ability to create
a set of conditions that only apply
in developer mode, so
we can automatically pull in
any changes we make to
the Remote Config while testing.
Specifically, it will let us change
the length of time, that the app waits
to fetch a new configuration, so
that we can see results right away.
Now, let's implement
the fetch config function,
to show you what change in
the wait time looks like.
First, I'm going to set the default,
expiration duration to 3600 seconds, or
60 minutes.
The expiration duration
is the amount of time,
that goes by before the app
fetches a new config, in seconds.
Then I'll add a condition that if
the developer mode is enabled,
the expiration duration is zero seconds.
As in the configuration
immediately expires, so
it's always looking to fetch a new one.
This condition's what's going to help
us try out configurations quickly,
while developing the app.
Then we'll call
fetch(withDurationExpiration)
using the Remote Config object.
If the configuration is
successfully fetched,
then it prints that it was successful.
We call activateFetched, which replaces
the current cached configuration value,
with the one that was just fetched.
We set friendly_msg_length to
the value from the Remote Config.
Then we check to ensure that the
friendly_msg_length came from the remote
configuration, instead of
the default variable in the app.
And if that's the case, we finally set
the message length here in the app.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Otherwise, if the config
can not be fetched,
then we'll just print the error for
now ,but we'd want to handle it.
And if the configuration
can't be fetched,
then the else statement will just
print out the error for now.
Okay, we set up the remote
configuration and
we set friendly_msg_length to 140 in the
Remote Config tab of Firebase console.
Let's see what our messages,
look like now.
I've tried typing the longest
message I can, and
it will not exceed 140 characters.
So it looks like our
Remote Config is working.