So as I introduce to you this whole amazing concept of
computational photography, I feel it's important for
me to also give you a little bit for broader overview of this discipline.
So in this lecture I'll introduce to you what computational photography is and
how it relates to the broader discipline of photography itself.
as, as you know all of us have cameras nowadays.
And there is just a pervasiveness of cameras out there.
And that changes how we think about photography, and
computational photography has a lot to do with it.
So, in this lecture while looking at the frameworks we have looked at
previously, we are also going to look at the discipline at a little bit
of a distance.
And, I'm going to try to showcase why it's important for
us to study disciplines like computational photography.