If you look up shape from shading,
you'll see a lot of pictures that look like this.
And these are typically synthetic, results.
So, given some depth map, you can make some sort of a shaded image and
then you can show that you can recover, the shape that's really there.
Unfortunately, one of the reasons, they show synthetic results so much is.
That the results on real images are somewhat, shall we say, less than wonderful.
In fact, there was a paper by mubarak shah and some students I
think the late 90s, early 2000s, where I think the phrase was something like,
well, it works poorly in the lab and not quite as well as that in real life.
You know basically,.
And, and why is that?
Well the problem is that these assumptions are, overly restrictive.
I mean a constant albedo everywhere?
That means you get no,
variation in the color of the underlying texture of what's there.
You know, knowing about the light source, the,
the orientation directions, its a very brittle type of computation.
So, what can we do instead?
Well what we can do instead is we can take more images, all right.
And this is what's referred to as photometric stereo.
So the idea is, that we take a picture from the same camera location so
we can still have Z as a function of XY.
Same object, but with different lighting.
So here we have the picture taken from the same location,
with different lighting directions and what we want to get out, is this.
Right?
The Z is a function of X, Y and
unlike traditional shape from shading with enough lights and
sort of careful calibration, etcetera, we can also recover the albedo.
The reflectance function, at every point.
So now we don't have to make this a really restrictive assumption,
that the color or the reflectance of the object is the same everywhere,
we're allowed to let it vary.