A packet filtering firewall
is relatively simple.
It basically applies a list
of rules to match the IP or
TCP header of a packet, and
based on the rules match,
the firewall will then decide to
forward or discard the packet.
Here are examples of IP or
TCP header information that a firewall
can use to filter a packet.
Source IP address, where the packet's
from, destination IP address,
where a packet's going to.
Source and destination transport level
address, this means the transport level
port number, which defines
applications such as SNMP or HTTP.
Basically, this tells what
application the packet belongs to.
For example, is it for
email or web traffic?
IP protocol field.
This defines the transport protocol,
such as TCP, UDP, or ICMP.
Interface, for firewall with three or
more ports, which interface of
the firewall the packet came from, or
which interface of the firewall
the packet is going to.
This is useful when there are multiple
ports in the interface network
that are quite different
security policies.
A packet filtering firewall is
typically set up as a list of
rules based on matches to
fields in the IP or TCP header.
If there's a match to one of the rules,
that rule is invoked to determine
whether to forward or discard a packet.
If there's no match to any rule,
then a default action must be taken.
There are two default policies.
The default discard policy means that if
there's no rule that matches the packet,
then the packet will be discarded.
This is a more secure or
conservative policy
because it provides more control about
what traffic is allowed to the network.
On the other hand, it can be a hindrance
to users who see that some traffic
are not allowed, and they have to tell
the system admin to enable the traffic.
The alternative is the default
forward policy, which means that
if there's no rule that matches
the packet, the packet is allowed.
Compared with the default
discard policy,
this policy is more user friendly,
but it's less secure.
The security admin
must react to each new
security threat add
rules to the firewall.