Here's my solution to the shuffle program. I begin by
opening the file with read and write permissions, and then
to figure out how long the file is, I call
lseek, putting the cursor at the end. This then will
return how much the cursor was moved, which I store
in this variable len. Then I put the cursor back
to the beginning. Knowing how long the array needs to
be, I can now end that with these flags here.
And then check to make sure that, that succeeded. If it failed, we'll just
exit. So now that I have the contents of the file in memory, I can
call memshuffle on it, that'll rearrange it as desired. And then I can unmap
it, close it, it'll get written to the disk, and I can exit with success.