All right.
Are you ready for a challenge?
This quiz is going to be a bit
more difficult than the last few.
For this one, I want you to
validate this new password entry
using the constraints validation API.
Notice how there are two inputs for
passwords?
This is pretty common and
it prevents users from making typos
when their letters are typed
out as little black dots.
You'll be using JavaScript and
set custom validity to check that a,
both passwords are the same.
And b, that the passwords meet all
of the requirements listed here.
The validation messages that
you pass to set custom validity
are really important.
They need to help the user out.
Don't just tell them
that something's wrong.
If the password is too short, tell
them how many characters it should be.
If it's missing a number, tell them
that it's missing a number, and so on.
Give this quiz a good, honest try,
because it's a great opportunity for
you to think through the nuances
of more complex validation.
The idea of checking for
these requirements may seem really
straightforward, but the implementation
details might surprise you.
As part of this quiz, you'll need
to think about string parsing,
which can be, well, a little annoying.
To help you out a bit,
I'm giving you some regex's in
the code that you might find useful.
All right.
Well, good luck.
I know you can do this and, like always,
check the instructor notes for
more information.