To review the different firewall types,
let's do a quiz.
Here, please mark each statement as
either T for true or F for False.
The first statement.
A packet filtering firewall
is typically configured
to filter packets going
in both directions.
The second statement.
A prime disadvantage of
an application-level gateway
is the additional processing
overhead on each connection.
The third statement.
A packet filtering firewall can decide
if the current packet is allowed
based on another packet
that it has just examined.
The fourth statement.
A stateful inspection firewall
needs to keep track of information
of an active connection in order
to decide the current packet.
Please mark each statement as
either T for true of F for false.