So one thing. >> Mm-hm.
>> That I was thinking about as I was making this list is,
so these are all the terms that we.
>> Mm-hm. >> Think are associated with certain buckets, but
we're kind of making educated guesses right now.
>> Mm-hm.
>> In practical terms how easy is it
to iterate on this a couple times where we might, you know, we try this,
we realize that oh there's, there's ten more words we want to add to this.
>> Mm-hm. >> Bucket that sort of thing.
Yeah, I think like,
one way to do simply do that is like, on this, this data, whatever you have.
This is kind of more model-building data in, machine learning terms, right?
You can continue enhancing the model by adding more and
more words as you, you come to learn about it, right?
So, a simple way to do that is either, ,.
You can, from a programming point of view, if you wanted to read those words and
the correlation word, you can have some kind of file format that you can suck it
up as a resource before launching the topology, right?
So, when you, so if you think more or less improve quite a bit, than you.
Build a login you want.
>> I see.
>> So that way it can, it can keep going.
But if you wanted to [CROSS-TALK].
>> FLAC files >> That is a simple way to do it.
I mean, on the other hand, if you want to do, do a sophisticated model,
then you have to identify twigs that you think there is some mod,
you hold along what other things that is.
The thing is applicable, but it's part in the moral.
Then you are to do a feedback.
>> Right. >> Loop kind of thing, right?
>> Mm-hm. >> So on the feedback loop, you can do it in two ways, right?
One is you can have feedbacks itself because you can
then [INAUDIBLE] into a stream also.
It's not that when this word, words are pulled out as a stream.
It's kind of a slow stream.
The data is not incoming in realtime but once in a while it comes, right?
So then whoever is computing the feedback loop, they should know,
oh these are the words I have, but this word is still, I think it's
occurred enough number of times, along with some panic-mongering words.
Because some of the words.
What do you call it, more of a correlation.
>> Yeah. >> For example, in parent modding if multiple words are given if
you incorporate a new word, if there is a enough support for
that word, because it is a current parent mongering word.
>> Right. >> Sort of like, there's a likely.
Trends that also occurs with it, right?
>> Mm-hm.
>> That also is a right?
>> Right, right. >> So that's a Then you have a discovery phase, right?
That's also computed as a stream separately, and
once you have enough confidence on that word.
Yeah, now we include that word also as a right?
So that is more sophisticated, more Automatically learns itself, as well as