Hm.
We've got all these methods and
we know when they'll happen.
I think you're probably ready to
make a ListView in the UI code so
that you can add these items.
[NOISE] Wait a moment.
JP wants to join the hangout.
Hey JP, how's it going?
>> Good.
Good.
I just wanted to check in on the app.
>> I'm having a pretty good time.
Our new developer is getting
up to speed very fast and
Firebase isn't giving us any trouble.
We're currently trying to figure out
the best way to display lists of data.
>> Well I haven't looked into it yet,
but have you heard of the FirebaseUI.
>> Yeah, I actually remember
reading something about that.
It's a Firebase library, right?
Okay, I should probably look into
that to make sure we don't start
writing code that somebody
else has already made.
>> Glad to be of service,
send over a demo when you got it.
>> Will do.
All right,
I think I've got a link
here to the Firebase UI.
This is all coming back to me, actually.
Let me show you my screen.
So here's the Firebase UI
package on GitHub.
It contains a Firebase array class,
a Firebase list adapter class, and
a Firebase recycler view adapter.
Before I go much further,
I should mention that this section
requires an understanding of ListViews,
adapters, and how they work together.
If you need a refresher of ListViews,
I've provided some links
in the instructor notes.
Please pause now and
watch these to get up to speed, or
the rest of this section
might be very confusing.
Before we dive into any code,
let's talk about how these classes
work together with your app.
Now the goal of Firebase
list adaptor and
Firebase array,
the two classes we'll be using,
is to use the Firebase SDK to keep your
list of online Firebase objects, such
as your shopping list objects, synced
with data displayed in a ListView.
The general idea is that
you have a ListView, and
this ListView is hooked up
to a Firebase list adaptor.
Firebase list adapter is backed
by a Firebase array, but
at least synced to
your Firebase database.
Changes in the Firebase
database it updates the array.
The array notifies the adapter
that the data set has changed.
The Firebase array data
converts it into a POJO, and
then uses the POJOs to make
the items for the ListView.
All you need to do is update the item
in the Firebase database, and
that will start this
whole chain process.
These classes work together.
Ways that you can add listeners for
reading from a Firebase database.
Listeners, what method is
used to attach a listener
to sync a local Firebase array,
with a list in your Firebase database?
You could just look at the source code,
but you should be able to figure this
out from what you know
now about read listeners.