The method that shakes the bugs is
called disperse bugs animation.
It gets called when
the shake motion ends.
This makes sense because
the UIEventSubtype member value that
we're checking for is motion shake.
You could have written the answer for
that second question in any
of the following forms.
Now, I'll go back to the app and
simulate a shake event.
To simulate a shake event, go to
the Hardware option in the main menu
at the top, and
then select the Shake Gesture here.
You can also use the hot key for
shaking, which is Ctrl + Cmd + Z.
Once the phone shakes,
all the spiders scatter readily from
the center of the web, and disappear.