In fact, we can take a look at that
a little more carefully, all right?
So here are the expressions that we
have before for the new mean and
the new covariance.
Suppose there's no
uncertainty prediction.
What that means is that
sigma t minus equals 0.
I don't know how that would've happened,
but let's suppose.
You just know where this thing is.
So then what happens is if,
if this is 0, okay,
gee let's take a look over here.
Then this thing is 0 here.
This thing is 0 here.
This thing cancels out.
What it means is that your
best update is the one that
just uses the prediction because you
knew exactly where it was going to go.
And furthermore, your new co-variance
is 0, that is, you have no uncertainty.
Another way of saying this is,
your measurement is ignored, okay?
So if I'm sure of my prediction,
I should ignore my measurement.
Likewise, what if there's
no measurement uncertainty,
suppose your measurement is perfect,
what should you do?
Well, if you plug sigma m equal to
0 in here, you'll see that mu t
plus your new best guess is just
the measurement divided by n,
that is, it's just the measurement's
guess as to what x is.
You're totally ignoring the prediction.
And this is what Kalman does for
you, right?
It gives you this tradeoff between
how much you pay attention to
the prediction, versus how much you
pay attention to the measurement
as a function of the uncertainty
of the prediction and
the uncertainty of the measurement.
And that's what makes it so powerful.