Now the reason that this paper described this exercise of
creating threads to handle interrupts was really motivated by performance.
The operations that are necessary to perform the appropriate checks and
if necessary, create a thread to handle an interrupt,
add about 40 instructions to each interrupt handling operation.
However, as a result of that, it is not necessary to
repeatedly change the interrupt mask whenever a mutex is locked, and
then, switch it back again whenever the mutex is unlocked.
This saves about 12 instructions for every mutex operation.
Now because there are way fewer interrupts in the system than mutex lock and
unlock operations, then clearly this ends up being a winning situation.
We end up saving much more than the actual cost that we end up
paying on each interrupt.
This observation is also one of the most important lessons in system design,
and that is, optimize for the common case.
The common case here where the mutex lock/unlock operations.
And so, we wanted to make those as efficient as possible.
We saved 12 instructions there.
Yes, we end up paying somewhere else.
We can not sacrifice the safety and the correctness of the system.
So we have to make sure we use some other technique to compensate for
the fact that we added this optimization.
But as long as the net effect is a positive one, this is a very good practice.