So there should have been four
unnecessary backgrounds in
the remaining files.
Let's go ahead and review.
In our base activities XML, remember,
we wanted to keep this white background.
Now, in the XML file for
our chat fragment, we've declared an
unnecessary white background right here.
We don't need this because we can use
the white one from our main activity.
That's it for this file.
Now, in the XML for
our individual chat items,
we have three unnecessary backgrounds.
We have one right here that we don't
need, one right here that we don't need,
and lastly, down here, we don't this
white background in our text view.
So we can go ahead and remove these.
All right.
Cool.
Let's see what kind of progress we
made as far as overdraw is concerned.
Now this is what your
screen should look like
with these backgrounds removed properly.
Much cleaner, right?
Okay, good work.
Now, we're just about done,
but there's actually one last
optimization you can make.
Notice there's overdraw
here by the avatars,
because we are drawing a rectangle and
then the avatar image on top of it.
Let's try and be a bit smarter here,
let's only set a background
when an avatar can't be found.
Now, we can do this with
some conditional code.
All right,.
So let's jump into our chat adapter
code, which is responsible for
filling in our individual chat
items as they get loaded.
Let's go to our get view method.
Now, down here at the bottom we actually
have some logic that's displaying both
the avatar and setting a background
color at the same time.
Let's see if we can get
a bit more intelligent here.
Let's write some code that
only sets the background color
when an avatar isn't present.
And when it is, we'll set the background
color to be transparent and
just load the avatar.
We can do it like this.
All right, so here's our updated code.
Notice that when an avatar isn't
present, what we're going to do is load
a transparent color into where
the avatar would normally be, and
then set a true background color for
the avatar.
Now, in the else case, which
represents when the avatar is present,
we'll go ahead and
load the avatar properly,
and then we're going to set
the background color to transparent.
This way we're minimizing overdraw.
All right, so let's go ahead and
see how this improvement helps us out.
Nice.
As you can see here now by our avatars,
much less overdraw
with our updated code.
All right, so that was our last
optimization, which means we're done.
Let's go ahead and recap.
When we started,
our overdraw was much more prominent.
The first thing we did was set
the background drawable to null.
The second thing we did was remove
unnecessary background declarations from
our XML markup.
Now, the third and last thing we
did was display a background color
only if there is no avatar present.
Now, with these changes,
we ended up with this.
Much, much cleaner in terms
of overdraw performance.
So, awesome job.
And remember, perf matters.