The data point I saw was this one,
although depending on your code,
you might have seen a different one.
If you couldn't figure out what was
wrong with the data point, that's okay.
Sometimes a little more
investigation will be necessary.
But I happened to notice
that the join_date and
the_cancel date are the same and
the days_to_cancel is equal to 0.
That could definitely explain why there
is no record in the engagement table for
this student.
The student probably
needs to be enrolled for
a full day before their
engagement is recorded.
In order to find this record,
I looped over the enrollment table and
found the account key for
each enrollment.
Then I checked whether that account
key was in the set of unique
students in the engagement
table that I had found earlier.
If the student was missing
from the engagement table,
I printed the record and
then used break to exit the loop.