Let's dive into the parts of
Firebase Storage security rules
by learning about the keyword match.
Match allows you to specify a path and
then a rule that you
want to apply to that path.
Every path starts with a forward
slash followed by a path segment.
And there are three
types of path segments.
The first is a single segment.
It's a literal reference
to a single path name.
For example, this path specifies
a file called profilePhoto.png
in the images directory.
The next type is
a single_segment_wildcard.
With this type,
we can specify a variable that can refer
to any path at a specific path level.
Here the variable is literally
called single_segment_wildcard, but
it could be anything and
it's surrounded by curly braces.
If we wanted to match all the files
stored directly within the images path,
we could use something like this.
But it's important to note
that the storage rules do not
cascade the same way
that database rules do.
For example,
this would match this path but
not this path,
which is why we have the last option.
This is the multi_segment_wildcard
option and
it matches any number of path segments
at or below the specified path.
The syntax is the same as
the single_segment_wildcard and
it ends with the =**.
For example, this
multi_segment_wildcard would match both
images/lyla.jpg and
images/profilePics/lyla.jpg.
It would even match a path like this.
The only constraint is that it
starts with the image's directory.
Now that you know about matching, let's
talk about how to write the actual rule,
which determines whether the match
location can be read from, or
written to.
Each match contains a rule,
or set of rules.
A rule starts with the keyword
allow followed by a request method.
The request method could be read,
write, or read/write.
A rule can be followed by a condition
where the rule will only be applied
if the condition is true.
For example,
this condition specifies to only allow
reads if the request is authorized.
Or in other words,
if request.auth doesn't equal null.