So the date command is for telling time.
It has a whole lot of options but
if you just say date,
you'll get the current date and time.
The expr command is a simple calculator.
The name stands for expression,
as in evaluate an arithmetic expression.
And so this command will add 2 and
2 and get 4.
Echo is just the shells name for
the print statement.
It just repeats back whatever
you give it, like an echo.
Uname prints out the operating system's
name for itself, here that's Linux.
You can get a lot more information
with uname-a, by the way.
Hostname prints out the computer's
own name for itself.
And here that's the name of
the vagrant VM you're running in.
Now host is pretty
different from host name.
It looks up a name in the DNS or
domain name service to find out its IP
address and also other information.
Here you can see it gives
an IP address for udacity.com.
And it also tells you that
Udacity's mail is handled by Gmail.
Technically it's only giving one of many
IP addresses that handle traffic for
Udacity, but it's more or
less Udacity's IP address.
Now bash--version
tells you what version number of
the bash shell you have installed.
It also gives you
the copyright information.
A lot of programs have some
sort of version command,
often with an option like --version or
dash capital V.
Like here's python.
Python -V tells us Python 2.7.6 and
the history command tells you all
the commands you've run previously.