Let's be good citizens and
adapt our audio playback behavior
to do the right thing if
the audio focus state does change.
So in this exercise, I'd like you to
modify the Miwok app to manage all your
focus state changes so that audio
interruptions are handled properly.
So these are the four steps
you'll need to go through.
First, request audio focus.
Second, create an instance of
AudioManager.OnAudioFocusChangeListener
and implement the callback method.
Third, adapt the playback behavior
when the audio focus state changes.
And lastly, release audio focus
when it's no longer needed.
Now, make sure you take care
of all four of these steps for
all four of our category activities.
So, you can start with
the NumbersActivity and
check that the code is working
there before copying this logic
over into our other three categories.
So after you finished up two, and you
want to double check to make sure that
you're headed in the right direction,
you can compare against the link below
our quiz for the code on how we define
our OnAudioFocusChangeListener.
But don't peek at it before you try
writing any of the code yourself.
Remember that you can refer
back to earlier quizzes, or
even check online tutorials on how
to implement all this in your code.
It is going to require quite a bit of
code changes to many different parts,
but I'm confident that you're ready for
this.
Good luck.