Welcome to the Udacity and Twitter course real time analytics with Apache Storm.
I'm Lewis, and I build courses here at Udacity.
>> And I'm Karthik, I'm Engineering Manager and Tech Lead for Storm at Twitter.
Storm is a real time infrastructure for
easily expressing your real time analytic techniques.
It is heavily used by Twitter for all real time analytics.
>> Storm is fairly simple, can be used with any programming language, and
as our hackathon participants discovered, it's really fun.
In this course you'll be exploring Storm topologies, implementing data spouts
and processing data bolts by connecting to the real live Twitter garden hose.
And in your final project you'll be calculating worldwide top trending
hashtags and displaying tweets that contain these hashtags,
using the interactive data visualization library, D3.
Thanks for joining this class.
Let's get started with Apache Storm.