If we look at the next three
sections of the scene tab,
they all have something in common, GI.
Now you may be asking what is GI?
GI stands for Global Illuminati,
wait, I mean Global Illumination.
Global Illumination is Unity's
system to model complex lighting
such as indirect light that
bounces off of nearby objects.
It works really well with
Unity's standard default shader
to really bring scenes to life.
These three sections let us fully
control the parameters Unity
uses when it makes its calculation for
precomputed lighting.
The first section is
precomputed real time GI.
If you add real time lights
to your scene, you could
use this section to precompute some of
the lighting effects for static objects.
Basically, precomputed real
time GI calculates how light
could bounce off static objects, and
can then use that information in real
time when you start your application.
With the real time resolution
property we can control
how much data we store
from precomputation.
And with CPU usage, we can also control
how much computation we want to let
the GI system have when we're
actually running our application.
Let's actually go ahead and
disable our directional light so
that we don't have any real
time lights in this scene.
Now that we don't have any real time
lights, we can now go ahead and
leave precomputed real time GI disabled.
Even though we're not using
precomputed real time GI, it's
still good to know that this feature
exists for whenever you need to use it.
Next up, let's talk about baked GI so
we can get the most
performance out of baking.