First let's add
the generate_auth_token and
verify_ auth_token methods in
our model [INAUDIBLE] file.
Remember that verify_auth_token is
a static method since it gets called
before we create a user object.
We also need to add a secret key
that we will use to sign our tokens.
[INAUDIBLE] I'll add the token route,
which the user can access to get
a token in exchange for
their username and password.
Let's then refactor our
verified password method.
Such that it checks for a token and
then looks for a username and password.
Running the tester,
I can now use the token to view and
create new products in
the Regal Tree Foods database.
As always, the solution code is
available in the instructor notes.