Okay, so at this point we've
got our drawing or layout.
We've identified the views, and we've
started our thoughts of positioning by
picking a relative layout
as our view group.
This is a great time to start coding.
Okay, so what I have opened here is
the code that we were working on before,
which is activity_main.xml
located in the layout folder.
Now it's first creating the views.
We already have about
half of the work done.
We have a relative layout and
we have one text view that
says Happy Birthday Ben.
To get all of the views you need
your going to make an image view.
You're also going to make
one additional text view.
Adding the additional text
view should be pretty easy.
The image view requires a little
bit more work because you actually
need that Android part of your picture.
In the instructor notes,
we've included a link to that picture so
that you can download it.
Okay, so I've downloaded the picture and
I've saved it to my desktop.
It's saved as androidparty.jpg.
Now you might recall before when
we added images our XML, we
said that we'd saved them in a folder on
the computer called the drawable folder.
Also remember how our app has a bunch of
files and folders associated with it,
which we can see in the directory
structure on the left.
These include layouts, pictures,
sometimes music, and so on.
A lot of these types of files are
going to be housed in the res directory,
which is short for resources.
The res directory contains
sub-directories for all the image,
text, layout, and
other resources the app might need.
And as we said, for images,
there's this folder called drawable.
For this app, all images should be
placed inside of the drawable folder.
Once you've put the image
into the drawable folder,
you can use the source
attribute of an image view,
and give it the value @drawable and
then the name of the image.
Note, when you're writing the image
name you do not need to add
the file extension.
Okay, so now I'm going to show you
how to actually put a picture into
the drawable folder.
Okay.
This image is in the Instructor Notes.
Go ahead and
download it to your Desktop.
Next, I want you to open Android Studio.
In Android Studio, you can go over here
and Right-click the Drawable folder.
From there, you should see something
that says reveal in finder or
reveal in explorer.
Here I can see the Drawable folder.
So right now I'm going to
move the androidparty.jpg
into the drawable folder and I'm just
going to do that by dragging it over.
Okay so make sure you're starting
with the correct XML code.
And if you don't have the correct code,
you can go ahead and copy and
paste it from the instructor notes.
All right, first things first,
download androidparty.jpg.
Then take androidparty.jpg and
move it to the drawable folder.
Once that's done, go ahead and
add the TextView that says,
from and then your name.
And after that, add the ImageView with
the source attribute as android party.
There's actually a lot
of default padding
in the code that you're working with.
So you can go ahead and delete that.
What do I mean by default padding?
Well, it's this paddingBottom,
paddingLeft, paddingRight, and
paddingTop.
You can go ahead, And just delete it.
Finally, click the green arrow
to run the app on your phone.
When you've finished all of these steps,
your app should look like this.
Note, it's a little bit hard
to see on this screen, but
the text views are actually overlapping.
That's completely normal and something
that we're going to deal with next.