So we know we need to create layouts and
assets optimized for
different screen pixel densities and
sizes.
So now is a great time to introduce
you to the Android resource framework.
All externalized Android resources,
everything from strings to layouts to
drawables and animations, are all stored
within your project's res folder.
You've already been putting your strings
in the strings.xml file stored in
the values folder.
And you've been putting your
layouts into the layout folder.
And you know to reference your resources
using at notation within both your
XML or within the code.
And then at runtime, Android will insert
the appropriate resource for you.
So far so good, and here's where
things get a little more interesting.
Android allows you to create alternative
versions of every resource by placing
them into folders with
different qualifiers.
We separate each of
those using a hyphen.
And we can add those qualifiers
based on anything, from language
and/or dialect to whether the device
is docked, the type of touch screen,
the pixel density of the display,
the orientation of the screen.
And most importantly, for
a responsive design in particular,
the smallest available screen width
which you can support with that layout.
At runtime, Android will check
the current device configuration,
its language, its screen size,
pixel density, everything, and
then load the right layouts,
strings, and drawables accordingly.
And you can even chain
these qualifiers together.
For example, to create a different
layout for German language users,
to account for
all of those really long German words.
Or more typically, for a combination of
screen size and device configuration.
Now, keep in mind that many of
these values can change at runtime,
the most common change
being that of orientation.
And it's for this reason that
Android activities are destroyed and
recreated whenever the device
configuration changes.
And that's because the layout and
all of the resources within it
could be completely different,
based on something as simple as
a screen orientation change.
Now, it's good practice as
well to localize your apps and
provide translated strings for
all of your users using this mechanism.
And that's a task made a lot easier
thanks to Google Play Publisher site
that can offer you this service.
It's also a really good idea to provide
different drawables at the appropriate
pixel density, so you can get
a nice crisp image on every device.
And when it comes to providing
alternative layouts, Android has gone
through a few alternative models,
starting in the early days with
this screen buckets idea of small,
normal, large, and extra large.
But since Android 3.2, the new smallest
width qualifier has given us much more
fine-grained control over our layouts.