You are doing awesome let us look
at one more thing you can change.
Notice how this says android:color and
it says darker grey.
I want to change it to
something like black.
Or maybe something like white.
And we see the device
updates on the right here.
How about if we change
it to my favorite color?
Blue.
Hm, so it does not exactly work
because blue is not a supported color.
There's a limited set of colors provided
by Android, but you can still access
a whole range of other colors by
specifying the exact hex color code.
You can find those, again,
in the material design spec for color.
So each of these colors is given
a name from the material team,
like 50, 100, 200.
So let's choose this blue here,
and double click to copy it, and
then go over to the code,
and then instead of blue,
I'm going to replace this with # and
then the hex color code.
Cool.
So now the background of
the text view is this blue color.
It looks pretty nice.
So now you might be wondering if
you can also change the text color.
And yes you can.
So add it right here.
Android textColor =, and I can
specify in quotations the hex value.
So go back to the color guidelines and
pick a random color.
I like green, so this color will do.
Copy that and then paste that
here in between the quotes.
#, and the hexcode.
Cool.
Now the device shows the green
text color on the blue background.
Now it's your turn.
Change the color of the background and
the text of the TextView
to two different colors from
the Material Design spec.
This is linked below, as well as XML
visualizer that has your starter code.
Have fun.