So, the correct answer over here is 0.78,
and over here it's 0.756.
To get there, let's complete this one first.
The probability of D2 = sunny.
Well, we know there's a 0.9 chance it's sunny on D1,
and then if it is sunny, we know it stays sunny with a 0.8 chance.
So, we multiply these 2 things together, and we get 0.72.
We know there's a 0.1 chance of it being rainy on day 1, which is the complement,
but if it's rainy, we know it switches to sunny with 0.6 chance,
so you multiply these 2 things, and you get 0.06.
Adding those two up equals 0.78.
Now, for the next day, we know our prior for sunny is 0.78.
If it is sunny, it stays sunny with 0.8 probability.
Multiplying these 2 things gives us 0.624.
We know it's rainy with 0.2 chance, which is the complement of 0.78,
but a 0.6 chance if it was (inaudible) sunny.
But if you multiply those, 0.132.
Adding those 2 things up gives us 0.756.
So, to some extents, it's tedious to compute these values,
but they can be perfectly computed, as shown here.