Imagine spending hours
crafting the perfect layout.
What happened to that layout
when you rotate the device into
portrait orientation?
I'll clear constraints, so
constraint layout won't help us.
The icon is completely lost here.
With the TV layout, all of the items
are kind of smashed into one corner.
As you can see, something that looks
great on one device in landscape can
look terrible or doesn't work well on
other devices or in portrait mode.
The good news is that the Android
framework provides excellent tools to
help you with layouts.
Using layout inference,
we can make our layout more responsive.
We can also easily create separate
layouts for portrait and landscape, or
for larger screen devices.