Let's get started with
FirebaseUI Authentication on Android.
I'm here on the Firebase Authentication
page and if you just scroll down,
you'll see that there's a link
to the FirebaseUI library.
Go ahead and
click on the ANDROID version.
This takes us to GitHub page for
the FirebaseUI Android repository which
is supported by the Firebase team.
You can find a direct link to
this URL in the notes below.
There's a README file in this
first page of the repository
that gives us general info
about FirebaseUI which actually
contains a lot more capabilities
than simply adding a login flow.
And, this is all very interesting and
I will let you read it on your own
if you're interested to see
what else FirebaseUI offers.
What I'd like to highlight is
this sentence here which says,
FirebaseUI is published as
a collection of libraries
separated by the Firebase API
they target.
That means that you'll need to
include the correct version
of the FirebaseUI library for the
version of the Firebase SDK in your app.
If you scroll down,
there's this handy table.
At the time of this recording,
we're using Firebase version 9.6.0.
And the latest version
of FirebaseUI is 0.6.0.
So we'll be using that in our app.
If you're using a more recent
version of the Firebase SDK,
doublecheck the README to choose
the correct version of FirebaseUI.
Now, this README is great.
But, it doesn't tell us a whole
lot about authentication itself.
To do that, you'll need to scroll up and
navigate to the specific auth directory.
Now, this README is specifically for
FirebaseUI Authentication.
You'll be following these instructions
to implement authentication in
friendly chat.
Let's begin implementing it now.