So now, actually,
let me showcase a much simpler example.
How light could be used and
variations in light can be used with
a camera to extract shape information.
This is something we've looked at
already before when we talked about
extracting shape.
And we basically said okay, now,
we can take light and change
the variations in light to actually
model and extract 3D dimensional shapes.
Let's look at this very simple
trimensional iPhone app.
>> It's a 3D scanner for the iPhone.
What it does is it shines light on your
face from different lighting directions.
It takes those images and interprets
them to create, create a 3D model
that you can then actually physically
realize with a 3D printer.
So this is really the first time you
can go from just an iPhone to you,
do the scanning to then actually get
a physical 3D object at the end.
So the way that works is,
you go to a dark room,
you hold the iPhone of
course to your face.
And when you hit capture,
it shines light on your face
from four different directions.
It then combines these images
into a 3D model which you can
then email to yourself.
If you go to a machine
hooked up to a 3D printer,
you then can just physically print
that email file, right away.
And so within about a half hour
you can go from scanning yourself
to having a physical copy.
So what's innovative here is that we're
using the iPhone screen itself as
a light source that we use to shine
light on your face from
four different directions.
So that's really the key technology
here that makes 3D scanning possible.
And with, along with the front facing
camera that's observing your face,
while the light is being shined by the
screen itself, we have just a compact 3D
scanner that you can carry around
in your pocket for the first time.
>> So this was actually Grant Schindler
who actually finished his
degrees at Georgia Tech and
actually came up with this idea.
And he started a company from Georgia
Tech on this topic and a variety of
other things he's also developing and
some other computation photography apps.
You can look up, look him up and
find more apps from him too.