So my goal with this lecture is for
it to give you another concrete example of what computational photography is.
We've looked at an example in the past,
where we've basically controlled lighting and cameras to generate a novel image.
Here, we will actually make it in the same category,
look at another way of generating something called a panorama.
Something, again, you've seen enough examples of or
may have actually generated yourself.
Here we'll open the black box and look inside how those panoramas are built.
But more importantly, this will be just an overview,
an index of what we're going to be looking at in the future lectures.
This will actually allow you to start thinking about what we're going to
do next in the next few weeks.
because it's going to connect back to what we're going to cover today in this
example, and
how it relates to different frameworks of computational photography.
Again, pay a, attention to each and every aspect of it and
remember that this will connect back to what we will learn in the future.