All right,
now that we have a functioning game,
let's walk through how it works.
I've added a bunch of break points so
we can step through the method
calls one at a time.
Here's our main function.
I'll go ahead and press run,
and you can see that first,
we initialize an instance
of our PS game controller.
Then if I go down here to the top of
the console and press play there,
you can see that the game controller
we just initialized calls throwDown.
And now we're inside the throwDown
method where I placed to the second
breakpoint.
Here we initialize the player's turn.
We initialize the computer's turn.
And then down here, we initialize
an RPSGame with those two turns and
assign that game to
the controllers game property.
I press play again, and
now we're building the results message.
messageForGame gets called.
Winner gets called,
which in turn calls defeats.
Description gets called.
Loser gets called,
which in turn calls defeats again.
And then description gets called again.
Next, we form our resultString.
Defeats gets called one more time.
And then we end on our NSLog statement.
And if I press play one
more time in the console,
we can see rock defeats scissors.
You win.
And if I want to change my move,
I just go here and I type Scissors and
then run it again.