Hi, and welcome to
Predictive Analytics for Business.
I'm Sam, and I'll be one of your hosts.
Which means that I'll be popping up
here and there throughout the program to
provide some additional explanations,
introduce you to experts in the field,
and to provide more context
to what you're learning.
&gt;&gt; And I'm Mark.
Before Udacity, Sam and I were
business analysts for several years.
The over arching goal of the program
is to advance your career
by helping you develop strong
business analysis skills.
Predictive analytics is
a rapidly growing field and
these skills will make you
an asset to almost any company.
&gt;&gt; You'll be surprise that the
prevalence of predictive analytics in
business.
Entertainment companies predicts which
ads you're most likely to respond to,
insurance companies predict how
likely you are to get sick, or
be in an accident.
Electronics companies will forecast
demand to set production levels
months in advance, and tech companies
use all sorts of business experiments to
predict the impact of product changes.
This program will prepare you to
do all of these things, and more.
&gt;&gt; In order to accomplish this goal,
there are set of skills
that you need to acquire.
The program begins by focusing
on the more foundational skills.
Then shifts to help you gain
experience in the most commonly used
predictive techniques.
Let's take a look at the map to see
a complete list of skills you'll gain
throughout this program.
[BLANK_AUDIO]