What are the problems of kNN?
Well, I would argue that there're two.
One is very large data sets,
and one is very large feature spaces.
Now the first one results in lengthy searches
when you try to find K's nearest neighbors.
Now, fortunately there are
methods to search efficiently.
Often you represent your data
not by a linear list, in which case the search
would be linear in the number of data points,
but by a tree, where the search becomes logarithmic.
The method of choice is called kDD trees
where there are many other ways
to represent data points as trees.
Now very large feature spaces
cause more of a problem.
It turns out computing nearest neighbors,
as the feature space for the input vector increases,
becomes increasingly difficult,
and the tree methods become increasingly brittle.
And the reason is shown in the following graph:
If your graph input dimension to
the average edge length of your neighborhood
you'll find that for randomly chosen points
very quickly all points are really far away.
The edge length of one is obtained
if your query point
is unit one away from the nearest neighbor.
If you have one hundred dimensions,
that is almost certain.
Why is that?
Well, in one hundred dimensions,
they are to be one where just by chance
your're far away.
The number of points you need
to get something close
grows exponentially with the number of dimensions.
So, for any fixed data set size
you will find yourself in a situation
where all your neighbors are far away.
Nearest neighbor works really well
for small input spaces like three or four dimensions.
It works very poorly
if your input space is twenty, twenty-five,
or maybe one hundred dimensions.
So don't trust nearest neighbor to do a good job
if your input and measure spaces are high.