The correct answers are saving
your progress automatically and
automatically saving
your log in information.
The difficult part of this game is
that the player has to save and
log in each time they lose a level.
And so you want to be able to save
this information automatically and
skip these steps.
Both these answers make
your game easier to access.
Whether you save your progress and
data automatically in the cloud or
automatically save
your logon information,
you're skipping the difficult and
annoying part of this game.
Which is that each time you lose
a level you have to save and log in.
These other two answers,
making the levels easier and
making fewer save points, are more
about making the game levels easier.
And affect the difficulty but not
really the ability to access the game.