The answers are, yes, the monkey has the bananas. No, the box is not at C,
it's been pushed to B. Yes, the monkey is at B. Yes, the bananas are at B.
No, the height of the monkey is not
high, because he climbed down. Which meant that the
effect was, that is at height, low. But
yes, the height of the bananas is high according
to these definitions. Now you would think, once the
monkey grasps the bananas and climbed down that the height
of the bananas should be low. But if we look
at the up rate of climb down, it doesn't say
that. It refers to the monkey. But it, it doesn't
refer to anything that the monkey is holding. because that
kind of thing is difficult to express in the language
of classical planning. So you could say, that's a weakness
in the definition of climb down.