There's one more thing we should go
over before programming Sunshine,
how it's actually getting
data from the Internet.
We're using the API service
from OpenWeatherMap.
In order to simplify things for you all
prevent additional load on their free
service, we've created our own server
that serves up fabulous fake data.
You can either use a URL that
delivers static data, or
one that delivers random data.
All of this data is
delivered in JSON format.
JSON stands for
Java Script Object Notation.
It's the primary method for data
exchange on the web because its format
is syntactically identical to the code
for creating JavaScript objects.
This means that JavaScript programs can
use standard JavaScript functions to
read JSON data since it's essentially
native JavaScript to begin with.
We use it in many other places
because like XML, it's human readable.
But it also is more compact,
easier to write, and
allows for the declaration of arrays.
Here are some contacts in JSON.
JSON is written as key value pairs,
such as first name colon John, or
last name colon Doe.
One makes an array by adding
a bracket to the declaration and
defining the objects inside.
Our weather data is
handled much the same way.
It contains some data to describe the
selected location, followed by an array,
called list here, that contains
a temp object to describe relevant
temperatures, as well as a weather
object to describe the conditions.
We also get pressure,
humidity, wind speed and
wind direction,
as well as things like cloud cover.
We won't use all of this in Sunshine,
but
it's interesting to see how
they've chosen to encode things.