Kaggle's incredibly useful for
a beginner student because so
what best way to learn something and
really know something is to try
applying it and using it for a project.
And what Kaggle does is it
provides interesting and
well architected projects for
you to focus on,
to both demonstrate the knowledge
that you've already learned,
as well as figure out how to do better
on their problem and learn from others.
We've actually released a new
collaboration tooling that's
targeted to helping students do
better on competitions as well
called Kaggle Scripts, which is a nice
computational environment where you can
go to most current Kaggle competitions.
Click on a link that says scripts
then click new script and
what that does is it merely drops
you into an R or Python or Giulia
computational environment stats both
tight links to the competition data set.
As well as has all that painful to
install in the Linux packages that you
need to use are part
of a normal workflow.
So you don't have any of the software
set up barriers in place and
you can start coding immediately.
And then the second thing that's
unique about this environment
is that every time someone says run,
it's their results are automatically
published to the rest of
the Kaggle community.
So for anyone else who's uses this
environment to work in competitions and,
or do exploratory analytics you can
click on a global scripts listing for
the competition and explore all the
different results the other participants
have used on the problem.
As well as different insights that
they've had about the data and
that really has helped new students
get started off with machine learning,
as well as learn from others during
over the course of a competition.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
If you want to make your first
submission in a competition,
one of the approaches to take is
look at any of the competitions that
are live on the main site that
have scripts enabled on them.
Click through to that and then click
through to the leaderboard, they'll
be a small icon by the teams that
made some missions using scripts and
you can click through to that icon to
see their code and their submission for
all that they've used.
And then actually click submit
to submit that file and
see what it scored directly from there,
so
there's a shortcut that's now in place
for enabling new users to really quickly
get started making
a submission to a competition.
They've got to take that solution and
build off of it.
You can hit fork on the script which
drops you into the same competition
environment that they used to
create that submission and
then run it to rewrite it and
then tweak parameters or
extend their product
very easily as well.
There's a second approach that you
can take as well, which is to go to
a couple of the competitions that
we have marked as getting started.
Two of the best ones for that, one is on
predicting which passengers survived and
died on the Titanic and the second is
on automatically classifying candor and
digits based on the pixels
from the panel and
digits sent to whether it's a zero,
one, two, three, or nine.
And these two problems are effectively
like the machine learning 101 equivalent
of learning how to sort
a list in computer science.
If you're participating in
a competition and you get stuck and
don't know where to go next or you don't
know how to get started in the problem,
the best place to get past that
block is asking a question and
saying what issue you're running
into the competition forums.
When you ask a question on the forums,
it not only helps you but
it helps the hundred other users that
have the same question or hit the same
block that you have, but haven't
asked the question in the forums.
So I really encourage new users
to our platform or anyone who's
hit block in a competition to drop
into the forums and ask a question.
And in almost all cases,
get a helpful response.