First we're going to modify
the calculatePrice method signature
to have the correct return data type.
We're also going to assume that
there's 0 input parameters.
This is where the calculatePrice
method is defined.
The purpose of this method is to
calculate the total price of the order
and then return that.
The price should be an integer so
we should change the return
data type from void to int.
That takes care of the first task.
The quiz also said to make sure that
there's no input parameters, and
that's what we have here.
Now the second task is to
modify the inside of the method
to make sure that we're computing
the correct price for the order.
And assuming $5.00 for a cup of coffee.
Inside this method we're taking
the quantity of cups ordered.
And we're multiplying it
by $5 per cup of coffee.
This equals the total order price.
So this line of code is cracked.
But there's two issues that I see,
the variable price is never used and
there's an error that says
missing return statement.
It's expecting us to return an integer,
but we're not returning anything.
Right now our code is the same
as if we just said this.
We need a line that says return and
then actually put a value here and
the value on return is a price.
So, I'm just going to put price,
which is a variable we defined up here.
Cool, so now all the errors go away.
We should also modify the Java DOC.
So that we specify that we're
turning the total price.
That way when someone's calling this
method, they know what to expect.
Okay, so now we finished all
the parts for defining this method.
Now, let's move on to where
the method is getting called.
Within the submitOrder method, we
should call the calculatePrice method.
Currently calculate price,
is floating in the middle of nowhere.
I'm going to copy it, and
I'm going to paste it up here.
Because before we would calculate
the price of the order in line,
in the submit order method, but
now we have a method for it.
So I'm going to paste this here.
Now get rid of the extra semicolon.
You'll notice that price is a local
variable in this method, and
also in this method.
It's okay if they have the same name,
because these are different
variable scopes.
So the price variable here is totally
unrelated with the variable here.
They're updated and
created independently from each other.
And once this method finishes executing,
this price variable is gone.
Okay back to our submitOrder method.
So we calculated a price and
stored it in a variable, and then we
can use it to create the price message.
So, actually,
all of this code can stay the same.
We're concatenating the integer,
price, to the string total
with the currency symbol.
Then we concatenate "Thank you!" and
then just display it on the screen.
So I'm going to erase these extra,
blank lines, and save it, and
then we can run it on our device.
Okay, so I changed the quantity, and
hit ORDER, then it correctly
shows $25 as the price.
Awesome, it worked.
But how can I be sure that
calculatePrice is actually
working because there's no user visible
change compared to our app from before.
Here are a couple of techniques that
you can do to verify that your code is
actually running.
I could have it return a really
crazy number, like 700.
Save my code and then run it.
Now what I expect to see is
if I change the quantity and
hit the ORDER button,
it should saw that the price is $700.
That way I'll know that this calculate
price method is actually getting called.
And it does, cool.
Now I can revert this change.
Another way to check that this
method is getting executed
is to add a break point here.
So I'm going to click on
this little bug icon and
then our apple enter debug mode.
If I change the quantity and
I hit order, then I expect that
the app will pause at this point.
And it does.
So now we're in
the calculate price method.
There is a global variable, quantity.
And if I step over to the next line then
I see that there's now a local variable,
price And it's set to be $15 because
quantity is 3, 3 times 5 is 15, cool.
So, it's going through
the calculated price method, and
if I hit Resume,
then it updates properly on this screen.