Rendering performance is the most
common performance issue that
you run into while building your app.
On one hand, your designers want to
produce the most usable transcendent
experience for your users, but on the
other hand, all those fancy graphics and
transitions may not work
well on every single device.
Let's take a look at what rendering
performance is all about.
Now firstly, know that the system
will attempt to redraw your activity,
every 16 milliseconds or so, which means
that your application needs to run
all of the logic to update the screen
in that 16 millisecond window, so
that you can hit 60 frames per second.
This frames per second number, generally
comes from the phone's hardware,
which defines how fast the screen can
update itself in a single second.
Now, most devices will
refresh at about 60 hertz,
meaning you've got 60 milliseconds to do
all of your drawing logic each frame.
If you miss that window,
say take 24 milliseconds to
finish your calculations,
you get what we call a dropped frame.
The system tried to draw a new picture
to the screen, but one wasn't ready yet.
So it didn't refresh anything.
The user ends up seeing the same graphic
for 32 milliseconds rather than 16.
Hm.
Any animations going on
during a dropped frame will
manifest themselves to your users
with a jump in their smoothness.
Now because even if
there's one dropped frame,
the animation won't
look smooth to anybody.
And multiple dropped frames are at
the core of what users start calling
a laggy or janky experience.
It gets even worse when lag happens
while your users are interacting with
the system, for example,
when they're dragging a list view or
trying to type in some data.
This is what users mercilessly
start complaining about.
Now that we have a better understanding
of how much time it takes per
frame to draw, let's take a look at
some of the problems that cause lag, and
how you can address them
in your applications.