I'm now going to start refactoring
this function based on
the expectations we've identified.
I've placed all the expectations
in the top right corner here and
notice how I've placed a green check
mark next to the one we are passing and
red Xs next to the ones
we currently are not.
I can now safely refactor this function
because I have these tests here to
tell me if I inadvertently
break something.
This process is called
the Red Green Refactor cycle.
I'll add a check to make sure the
parameters being passed to the function
are both of the type, number.
If they aren't, I'll throw a new error.
This changes the results of our test.
This function now passes the first and
second test, and
I just need to pass the third test.
Now I'll be the first to admit,
this solution s pretty naive.
It only applies to a very
small set of use cases.
But that's okay.
Writing a perfect add function is
not the point of this exercise.
I just want to be confident I
can safely refactor my function,
without breaking anything, and
that's exactly what we've done here.
If I check my test again,
I'll see that they're all green.
So assuming my tests are comprehensive,
I can be confident that this function
behaves the same way as it did before,
but without the errors
we initially discovered.