The next step is going to be extracting those images from the data sets.
It will create a new local directory to directories notMNIST_large, and which
is the training data.
It's a, you know, very noisy, not very clean.
There is a smaller data sets, which is notMNIST_small, which is going to be the
test data. And that data has been verified by hand, and so it’s a little
cleaner than the training data. Each of those directories have 10 sub
directories, one for each letter. And, you know, you should take a look and convince
yourself that you have the right kind of data that you can actually see it.
It's good to be able to visualize it in your notebook. You can use IPython.display
to display an image and convince yourself that you've got things
downloaded properly.