So after that detour about URIs,
let's get back to the task at hand.
Opening a map, we'll be creating
the intent that opens this map,
so here's where that
code will get called.
Let's start with the address
of Google's headquarters.
We'll need to convert
this address to a GOURI.
A properly composed
Android GO URI consist of
the geo scheme, a latitude and
longitude, and optional
query parameters to indicate the street
address or business, and the zoom level.
It's important to note that if
there is a query parameters for
our street address or business,
the lat long path must be 0,0.
Here is a geo URI that shows the city of
Antwerp in Belgium with a zoom factor of
10.
There are a couple of
ways to build the URI.
One way is to use URI.parse in
an inline string concatenation.
But it's less error prone to use
URI.builder to create our URI.
It's a bit more code,
but as the URI gets more complex, the
builder pattern makes it more readable.
Next we can create an intent
with that address URI, but
we shouldn't try to call
start activity just yet.
It's important to check to see if
the device can handle the request.
It's possible there is no map app
installed to handle this intent.
resolveActivity ensures some app on the
device is able to handle this intent.
So when we run the app,
we can see our map comes up.