Here's what I came up with.
Hex BEEF in the first entry,
FOOD in the second,
C0DE in the third and
AB8D in the fourth.
Note that by full associativity,
any permutation of these addresses
would've also been a valid response.
As for the number of evictions,
I got just one.
Okay.
Let's see if I can convince you
of what I got.
First, consider the first
four unique addresses loaded.
Notice that the first four unique
addresses actually corresponds to
the first five instructions.
I picked the first four unique ones
because the cache is empty, so
it can hold up to four values, namely,
the first four unique addresses.
This second occurrence of x
F 0 0 D will be a cache hit.
The next load to x A B 8 D
will cause a state change.
The cache is full so
something has got to go.
So which address will be evicted?
Well, remember that an ideal
cache can see the future.
So for each of these addresses in cache,
the ideal cache will look at
the future sequences of accesses and
kick out the address that is
touched furthest in the future.
So in this case,
that's the address xD00D.
No love lost here.
That dude is a total loser
of an address anyway.
With a newly freed slot,
you can load the value at address xAB8D.
After that completes,
the next three accesses
are all addresses that are in cache, so
they're all cache hits and you're done.
Notice that in this process, there
was a total of just one eviction, so
that's what the ideal cache would do.