Next we have to worry about updating the OCL.
Recall that in our previous diagram,
OCL was associated with components and associations.
The component OCL was used for specifying event handlers, and the OCL that, and
that OCL will remain unchanged in the architectural diagram.
In particular here are the two constraints that we had for
dealing with event handling.
The first one has to do with moving the handle, and there we saw that
the handle has a new position like we expect, and similarly for
the resizing the window, where the height of the window is the, is the new size.
There was, there was also OCL annotating the associations.
[COUGH] As we move from analysis to design,
we will replace these associations with dependencies and as part of
this process, we must assign each association's OCL to appropriate layer.
Here are the three constraints that specify the associations in
the analysis model.
There was one for scaling the handle, there was one for
displaying the document, and there was one for making the lines visible.
This is just a repeat of what we, what we saw before, and you'll notice that
the, in all three cases we have a single variable on the left hand side.
This doesn't necessarily always have to be the case.
You could well imagine a constraint, in which we said a plus b equals c plus d.
That doesn't have a single variable on the left-hand side and we'd have to
subtract b from both sides, or a from both sides or whatever to get that, okay.
It could also be the case that there are inequalities.
That is the constraint might say that a must be greater than b, okay.
That one is going to be
we'll have to think a little bit about how we can implement that.
In fact, if a is greater than b that's even easier than saying that
a has to be equal to be because any value of a that's greater than b will,
will satisfy the result.