So that's the end of this section
about messaging on Android Auto.
As you can see, the fundamentals of
your application remain the same, but
you added some simple extensions
to your notification objects
to get Android Auto features.
This concept of extending notifications
is very common on Android and
is similar to how the extensions
work for Android Wear as well.
Android Auto provided all
the speech recognition for you.
So, you just need to do
something with the text string.
And it takes care of speaking
to the user as well.
We also covered some of the important
things to know about extending existing
messaging apps.
So if you really have an app you
should be ready to extend it for Auto.
In the next lesson, we're going to talk
about how to add Android Auto Support
to your existing music app.
So let's go try that.
I'll see you then.
[NOISE]