Okay, let's see if we
understand the issue here.
We already have two histograms,
one that gives us the probability that
an observes Hue value is from
a skin pixel, and other capturing
the probability distribution
of it not being a skin pixel.
Now along comes a pixel whose
hue value lies somewhere here.
Say this corresponds to bin value six.
Using this, we can find out the bin
heights or corresponding probabilities.
Lets say that the probability that this
value came from a skin pixel is 0.5.
And that it came from
a non skin pixel at 0.1.
Okay, now that you have these two values
can you decide whether x came
from a skin pixel or not?
In general is this condition sufficient?
That is I'd say that x is a skin pixel
if P(x) given skin is greater
than P(x) given not skin.
How about this deceptively similar but
different condition.
That is P skin given x is
greater than P not skin given x.
While we're at it,
let's throw in a couple more choices.
P(x) given skin times P of skin
is greater than P(x) given
not skin times P of not skin.
Is that sufficient?
How 'bout this last one?
P skin given x times P(x) is greater
than P not skin given x times P(x).
Select the condition or conditions
that you think you can use to decide
whether a skin pixel is
being seen given a value x