First on is cost of purchasing identity
theft protection for your customers.
So Anthem actually offered that to me.
Some banks offered when they had
a breach to their customers and so on.
So this is a cost that is definitely
because of this breach that we have had.
Loss of business due to
reduced customer confidence.
Well, that is an impact of this breach,
as well.
It is a loss and
it impacts you adversely.
So, that should figure into
the impact of this event.
Compensation for
new cyber security personnel
the company hires to better manage
cyber security in the future.
Well, this is, if you include this or
not, actually happened as a result.
Maybe you wouldn't have done it if you
didn't if you didn't have this breach,
but this is really sort of
investment in the future.
So, in the future, we don't have such
a breach, or don't get attacked.
Act the way we did this case.
So this is really part of the response.
It's how you get to a more secure state.
This impact is probably not
something that should be included,
the loss that occurs because of this
particular incident, or this breach.
This is something that probably
should have been there and
if it was there then this
situation wouldn't have happened.