All right, let's take a look
at this first one here.
The relationship between a list and
the time stamp that it was last edited.
Thinking about list and timestamps,
each list only has one timestamp for
when it was last edited.
For example, this generic list might
have been edited at 12:05, and
this other generic list,
maybe was edited at 3:50.
It would be impossible for
a list to have two different
last edited timestamps.
It's just one.
And then similarly,
each of these timestamps is
directly associated with one list.
The single timestamp object
is generated for each list.
So it's impossible for
a single timestamp object to be
associated with two different lists.
This is a classic one
to one relationship.
As far as users and
friends go, a single user could
have a couple different friends.
For example could have J.P.
and Walter on her friends list.
So this is not a one
to one relationship.
It's not a one to many either
because Walter in turn
could be friends with more than just.
Perhaps Walter's friends
with [INAUDIBLE] and Polter.
Since each friend could be friends
with multiple other users.
This relationship is many to many.
So what about items of
the users that own these items.
Each item has exactly one owner.
Which is to fight with
the item is added to a list.
For example, Walter could add cheesy
flacks to a shopping list, and
then this item would be
associated with him.
He could add a tomato to
another shopping list.
And similarly the tomato
would be associated with him.
Same goes for if J.P.
added a insta reader to a shopping list.
Now even though each of these items
is only associated with one owner.
A single user can have multiple
items associated with them.
So items and users are an example
of one to many relationships.