The ordering constraint basically says that if I've got pixels in
my left image that go a, b c,
they're going to appear in the same order a, b, c in my right image.
And that's typically what happens when I look at a single solid surface.
So when is this violated?
Well, duh.
When I'm not looking at a single solid surface.
That's SSS, that's pretty cool.
So what's not a single solid surface?
Well, couple things.
First of all, we could be not solid.
Now, what does it mean to be not solid?
Well, suppose you have a surface that's transparent that
has some markings on it.
Okay?
So here we have this, supposed this as a transparent surface, all right?
And we can see these points, all right?
Well if they're transparent, they would go A, B, C in that order, but
over here, it would go C, A, B, all right?
And that's just because we can see through the surface.
Well that's really weird and that almost never happens.
What happens much more often is what's sometimes called the pen,
floating penel, I forget.
Whatever it's called.
Basically, if I've got a narrow occluding surface, and
you can actually do the simple experiment.
If you wanted to do a stereo put your two fingers, one in, right in front of
the other, and in your left eye, this finger is to the left of this, but
in your right eye, the other finger is to the left of this, so it swaps.
So if you have a stereo algorithm that's trying to figure out
how to do the match that's a problem.
I will tell you that current stere, stereo algorithms do a lot of work to
handle the occlusion problem, because that happens all the time, because if I've
got one edge of a, of an object in front of another object, there are going to
be pixels that are visible in one eye or one camera and not the other.
Current stereo algorithms are not so
great on violations of the ordering constraint.
Various scale problems,
et cetera so, that's just sort of where the state of the art is.