As we've seen, randomization can be
a very useful tool in the design and
analysis of algorithms.
And it turns out that this is true
in practical programming too,
as many real world computer
programs rely on pseudorandomness
to achieve their desired behavior.
Nevertheless, it's an open question
whether randomization actually helps in
the sense that the complexity classes
that we discussed earlier on in
the course.
It simply isn't known whether
there's a language that can
be decided in polynomial time with
a two sided Monte Carlo algorithm that
can't be decided with the normal
turning machine in polynomial time.
This is known as the P
equals BPP question,
and it's one of the major
open problems in complexity.