The next thing we need to do is get an
emulator ready to run the code within.
Go to Tools > Android and
start the AVD manager.
Now select Create a Virtual Device and
you can select a phone
model to use here.
I'm going to pick a Galaxy Nexus
since it's an older device
with a smaller display and
smaller memory footprint that will work
on my small laptop display easily.
Click next and
then select Lollipop API 21.
Although, any newer APIs
will also work as well.
Make sure you pick one with
Google APIs since that is required for
Android auto support.
If you pick the X86 simulator, and
have the HAXM driver installed,
the emulator will also run a lot faster.
Click next.
In the scale section, you may need to
play with the settings to make sure
the emulator fits on your screen.
Otherwise, leave
the defaults as they are and
click finish to to create the AVD.
Now, you have a list of
emulators available.
So select the one we just created and
click the play button to start it up.
Once the emulator is ready,
you can unlock it.
Now we need to install
the Audio Simulator.
This app uses the same API's as
the Real Android Audio Head Unit so
we can see how our app will work
without having to sit outside in a car.
You can also do this on a hand
held device if you'd like.
It's actually downloaded
as part of the SDK manager
just like we did it earlier for
messaging.
So let's go to Tools >
Android SDK Manager.
If we scroll down to the bottom in
the Extras category, you should see that
it's installed here from when we used it
previously for Android Auto Messaging.
So let's close the SDK Manager.
Once you've got that package installed,
now we need to find the media simulator
APK in the Android SDK directory.
In this case my SDK's in
~/Library/Android/sdk and now,
we need to change some into
the extras/google/simulators directory.
And in here you can see
the media-browser-simulator.apk file.
So let's install that to out
emulator with adb install.
And that's now ready
to go in our emulator.
Now, we need to build and install
our code to the running emulator.
So click on the green icon here,
which does it all for us.
Now, we select the emulator and hit OK.
Now, it's installing to the emulator.
Once it's done, your app will
start running on the emulator.
Note that it's just running the default
activity included with the sample.
But you can't see a music
playback interface yet.
This is because we don't provide a UI,
just service.
Let's go to the home screen on the
emulator and find the media simulator.
Let's go to the list of apps and you can
see here there's a media simulator, so
click the icon to launch it.
You'll notice that the app
needs to run in landscape mode.
So rotate the emulator.
Typically, you can press Ctrl + F11 or
Ctrl + Fn + F11 to make
this happen like so.
Now, you can select your
media app from the list.
There may be others installed
on the phone as well.
Here's their app, click on it,
and as you can see here,
the songs we had coded into
the sample are available here and
we can select one to
start playing it back.
Voila, music!
We now have built a super simple Android
media application, congratulations!