The answer is log n time.
Let's start by thinking
about the loads first.
They have no input dependences and
there are n of them, so
it should take ceiling of n divided
by p time in order to execute them.
Now in this case I told you
to assume that P equals N.
So N over P is just a constant,
in fact it's exactly one.
Okay, that was easy,
what about the additions?
Let's look at the first
level of additions.
Now notice there are N over two of these
vertices and we have N processors.
So we have plenty of
processors to execute all
N over two additions in one shot.
So that means this first level
of additions will also take
one unit of time or just constant time.
And that's basically
the same at every level.
So we're basically executing
the DAG level by level.
Each level takes constant time, so
the only thing we need to know
is how many levels are there.
Now this thing is
a complete binary tree, so
there should be log n
levels given n leaves.
And that completes our analysis.