I've been showing you this in one dimension.
It extends pretty simply in two dimensions and
here are the two dimensional forms, okay?
So this f of u, this is just when I've got a,
a continuous two dimensional function.
Here we have f of x, y.
Well, when we do it in discreet land, f of x, y is now going to be at discreet
points and we have f of kx, ky, those are the two different frequencies.
The fr, the discrete frequency in x, the discrete frequency in y.
And by the way, this works middle if you put the origin of k in the middle,
you want to put the zero in the middle.
So for minus k k n over 2 to plus n over 2.
Let's take a look at applying this two dimensional discrete Fourier
transform to images.
So remember, we showed you, we talked about that we are going to have
these bases that have horizontal vertical components that can be combined.
What does that look like when we apply these things to images?
So let's take a look at some very simple examples.
All right.
So here I have a sinusoid and it's at some particular frequency and
it's only made up of vertical stripes.
What is the spectrum, the power spectrum of its Fourier transform look like?
Well, it looks just like this and its a little hard for you to see, but
there are two bright dots there.
The origin is here in the middle and there is a dot to the left and
a dot to the right.
Okay.
Those are my spikes for the, the frequency of this particular sinusoid.
So this picture, you see has only horizontal stripes and it varies more quickly.
So these dots are now spaced vertically for sinusoid that goes in this
direction and they're further out, because the frequency component is higher.
If I have a sinusoid in an oriented direction, same deal again.
It's a little hard to see.
We've got these dots that are spread in that direction.
Let's go back to our linearity.
So let's suppose I take the picture on the left and
the picture in the middle and I sum them together.
And we're actually going to do a sum, so it's linear.
Right?
So this picture's going to look like that, so,
you know, it's some combination of sinusoids.
But remember, a Fourier transfer, Fourier series is just made up of sums and
multiplies, it's a linear operation.
Okay?
So, the Fourier transform of the sum is just the sum of the Fourier transforms.
So that's why this picture is just these combined.