Let's first consider which of these optimizations reduces the
number of writes to disk. The use of the buffer
cache does because short lived files, which are common
in when compiling code, for instance, need never be written
to disk. Journaling actually increases the number of writes
to disk. So this is false. And direct memory access
only gets involved when there is a write, so it
doesn't change anything. Next we ask, which of these improve
overall performance. And the answer is that they all do.
The basic caching principle was the main motivation for the buffer
cache since main memory is so much faster than disk and
other mass storage. The advantage of journaling, we already went over.
If the data must be written to disk quickly, better
to do it sequentially. And lastly, we saw how DMA sped
up performance through the cycle stealing phenomenon, giving more time for
the CPU to do other work. Lastly, we have the improvement
for recovery. And the only optimization that had any
effect here was the journal. Which reduced the recovery
problem to just applying the changes from the journal
to the rest of the disk, something done routinely anyway.