So, here's what we're going to do, right?
We said that L is equal to the reflectance times E, which is the,
the total illumination, all right?
So we're going to assume that the illuminance, E, is low frequency, very slowly.
So, you know, here would be an example, it's brighter here, it's darker there,
and it slowly changes.
So, that's the illumination.
Conversely, we're going to assume that the reflectance is constant over
patches that are separated by these sharp edges.
This is just what we said before, right?
So, here we have these sharp edges.
And that's our reflectance model.
And when we light the Mondrian world,
we make a picture that looks like this, all right?
And it's just that L, which is the thing we actually see is R times E.
So R is that constant part plus high frequency and
the E has the smooth elements.
So, if we want to recover the reflection, we want to recover the albedo,
the R function, all right?
How might we do that?
Well, let's look at the intensity profiles of these two pictures.
So the picture on the left is just R, this is that reflectance function.
And here is L, right?
The reflectance function times the slowly varying energy.
Now, if we took a slice through these, right?
And we compared what the plot would like,
it would look something like the following.
So on the left, you see we have these sharp changes, right?
Which are these changes here,
right there, there, there, those are the constant regions.
And on the right, we have the same thing, but
it's been modulated multiplied by this decreasing illumination, right?
So you see that, you know, in some sense this structure is reflected in here but
it's got this other slowly varying part of it.
So the question is, frankly, given this, how do I recover that?