In your starter code you should
see the TaskContentProvider class
in the data folder, and if you open
this up you can see that this class
extends from the abstract
ContentProvider class in Android.
And inside our six methods,
you can see onCreate, insert, query and
a few others that we'll
go over in a bit.
Just know that all of these are required
to build a complete content provider.
In this starter code, these are all
empty or throw an exception and
it will be up to us to write
code inside these six methods so
that the provider actually works.
And now that we have this basic
structure, let's complete the first
method, onCreate, which is called
when the provider is initialized.
In general, onCreate is where you
should initialize anything you'll
need to setup and
access your underlying data source.
In this case, the provider is working
with an underlying SQLite database.
So here's a good place to give
it a way to open that database
with the tasks db helper object.
So first to clear to this helper as
a member variable named mTaskDbHelper.
Then in OnCreate,
I'll assign this to a new task
DbHelper passing in the context.
First I'll retrieve the context
which I have to import.
Then, create the DbHelper.
And finally, instead of returning false,
I'll return true,
because this method is done.
And this is one of the first steps
in creating your own provider.
But before we can start using it,
we'll have to register it
in the Android manifest.