In this lesson we will talk about
distributed file systems and
about some of the design decisions
that are available in this space.
We will describe what are the specific
decisions made for NFS,
which is a popular example of
a distributed file system.
And we will also look
at a research paper,
Caching in
the Sprite Network File System.
This paper is useful because
it has a lot of information
why certain decisions were made
in the Sprite file system.
One thing you should have in mind is
that all of the discussion in this
lesson will focus on
distributed file systems.
The methods that we will
talk about generalize to
other types of distributed services.