Let's talk a bit more
about those references.
So far you've created a cube in
the scene, and then drag and
dropped it into a script reference.
And that's fine.
But what if you want to create and
re-use elaborate objects
across multiple projects?
Well, for that you should probably
use something called a prefab.
Let's talk about prefabs.
In Unity, prefabs allows you
to store a GameObject and
all of it components and its settings
in a file on your hard disk.
They're a great way to store and
reuse your GameObjects across scenes.
You can think of prefabs as examples for
a GameObject.
It's like a plan that Unity follows
to create certain GameObjects.
Okay, let's make one real quick.
Take your MyCube object and
scale it vertically a little bit.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay, now drag and drop your MyCube
object into the project pane.
There you go, you just created a prefab.
Now, you'll notice it
has a little blue icon.
That's what prefabs
look inside of Unity.
It also shows you the model up here.
This prefab is now an example for
objects of this type that
you can create easily.
Okay, go ahead and save your scene,
and then create a new one.
Find your prefab in the project pane.
And then drag and
drop it into the new scene.
Cool, there's your object, in a brand
new scene, with all of its settings.
Great, okay, let's go back to
the previous scene and user prefab.
And we don't need to save this one.
Locate the game object that has the
mini-object maker script attached to it.
And this time,
drag the prefab into that slot.
Okay, go ahead and press Play.
And, it worked.
It worked because,
a game object reference accepts both
objects from the hierarchy and
the project pane.
There they all are.
So why is that important?
Because most assets you get from
the Unity assets store will be prefabs.
Okay, let's try another prefab now.
Look in the text notes below for
a download link for some Unity assets.
Once you've got them,
go ahead and install them.
Okay, once everything's installed, go
and search for a prefab called seagull.
Once you've found it, drag and
drop it into the object to create slide.
Then press play.
Wow, you just created 1,000 seagulls.
That's a ton of birds.
Alfred Hitchcock would be proud.