Okay so the thing we need to do
first is generate these routes.
Without them we can't do
any of these other steps.
We need a route for toys,
and another for bricks.
Now we need the nested routes red and
blue.
Remember that to nest
a route within another route,
it's the container route name,
a slash, and the nested routes name.
[BLANK-AUDIO] Now
that we have the routes,
I can have the navigation links.
Remember that the application template
is the outermost containing template.
So I put the links in there.
Here's the link for the instructions.
So, I'll add it right after this.
Now it's just filling out
the individual route template files.
The bricks template also needs links
to the nested route so I'll add those.
Remember that the nested routes
are in their own directory.
I'll update them with
their required text.
We've touched three layers
of templates in this quiz.
The application template
that contains all others.
The toys and bricks templates,
which are both nested inside of the
application template, and then the red
and blue brick templates, which are
nested inside of the bricks template.
Nested routing can be
a complicated project.
With ember though, it's incredibly easy
to create and work with nested routes.