The model of expectation maximization
is that each data point
is generated from what's called a mixture.
The sum of all possible classes
or clusters, of which there are K
we draw a class at random
with a prior probability of p of the class C = i
and then we draw data point X
from the distribution correspondent with its class over here.
The way to think about this if there is K different cluster centers shown over here
each one of those has a generic Gaussian attached.
In the generative version of expectation maximization
you first draw a cluster center
and then we draw from the Gaussian attached to this cluster center.
The unknowns here are the prior probabilities for each cluster center
should we call P-i and the Mu-i and in the general case Sigma-i
for each of the individual Gaussian.
Where i = 1 all the way to K.
Expectation maximization iterates 2 steps just like K-means.
One is called the E-step or expectation step
for which we assume that we know the Gaussian parameters and the P-i.
With those known values calculating the sum over here
is a fairly trivial exercise.
This is our known formula for a Gaussian
we just plug that in and this is a fixed probability.
The sum of all possible classes.
So you get for e-ij
the probability that the j-th data point
corresponds to cluster center number i
P-i times the normalizer
times the Gaussian expression.
Where we have a quadratic of Xj minus Mu-i
times Sigma-i to the -1 times the same thing again over here.
These are the probabilities
that the j-th data point
corresponds to the i-th cluster center
under the assumption that we do know
the parameters P-i, Mu-i, and Sigma-i.
In the M-step we now figure out where these parameters should have been.
For the prior probability of each cluster center
we just take the sum over all the e-ijs, over all data points
divided by the total number of data points.
The mean is obtained by the weighted mean of the x-js
normalized by the sum over e-ijs
and finally the sigma is obtained as a sum
over the weighted expression like this
and this is the same expression as before
and now again we are normalizing over the sum over all e-ijs.
And these are exactly the same calculations
as before when we fit a Gaussian but just weighted by
the soft correspondence of a data point to each Gaussian.
And this weighting is relatively straightforward to apply in Gaussian fitting.
Let's do a very quick quiz for EM.
Suppose we're given 3 data points and 2 cluster centers.
And the question is, does this point over here
called X1 correspond to C1 or C2 or both of them?
Please check exactly one of these 3 different check boxes here.