Now we consider what our approximation
algorithm might have returned.
Recall that the optimum value for
a Hamiltonian cycle is 6.
The approximation algorithm begins
by building a minimum spanning
tree for the graph.
Perhaps it chooses a star, like so.
Then, preferring lowest index vertices,
a depth first traversal
would produce this cycle.
First, we go from 1 to 2.
Then the next step would
take us back to 1.
So we skip that and go to 3.
The next step would take us back to 1.
So we skip that and go to 4.
And so on and so
forth until the cycle is completed.
Notice that every edge followed in this
cycle is a red one, except the first and
the last.
Hence, the cost is two time six
minus two for a total of ten.
The ration then is ten over six,
but there wasn't
anything special about the fact that
we were using six vertices here.
We can form an analogous graph for
any n, but
in the lighter edges
be the union of a star
in a cycle around the non-center
vertices, all other edges can be heavy.
My question to you then is how bad does
the approximation algorithm get for
100 vertices?
Give your answer in this box.
Remember that the lighter edges
are the ones that go from the center
out to the perimeter plus the cycle
of edges around the perimeter.