Recall that a Turing machine recognizes
a language if it accepts every string in
the language and does not accept
any string not in the language,
it could either reject or loop.
This Turing machine here recognized the
language of binary strings containing
one, but it looped on those
that don't contain a one.
In order to decide the language,
the Turing machine must not only accept
every string in the language, but it has
to reject every one not in the language.
This machine achieves that goal for
the same language
by explicitly rejecting the input when
we reached the end of the string.
Ultimately, however, we're not
interested in whether a particular
Turing machine recognizes or decides
a language, rather we're interested in
whether there is a Turing machine that
can recognize or decide the language.
Therefore, we say that a language is
recognizable if there is a Turing
machine that recognizes it.
And we say that a language is decidable,
if there is a Turing
machine that decides it.
Now looking at this someone
might object shouldn’t we say,
recognizable by a Turing machine and
decidable by a Turing machine.
Well, of course, we could and
the statements would still be true, but
we don't.
And the reason we don't is that we
strongly believe that if anything can do
it, a Turing machine can.
That's the Church turn thesis.
So in some absolute sense, we believe
that a language is only recognizable by
anything if a Turing
machine can recognize it.
And a language is only
decidable by anything,
if a Turing machine can decide it and
we use terms that reflect this belief.
Now, other terms are sometimes used
instead of recognizable and decidable.
Some say that Turing
machines compute languages.
So to go along with that,
they say that languages are computable
if there's a Turing machine
that computes them.
Another equivalent term for
decidable is recursive.
Mathematicians often prefer this
word and those that use that term
will refer to recognizable languages
as recursively innumerable.
Some also call these languages
Turning acceptable or
semi or partially decidable.
We should also make clear the
relationship between these two terms.
If a language is decidable,
then it's also recognizable.
The same Turing machine works for both.
It feels like it should also be true
that if a language is recognizable and
it's compliment is also recognizable,
then the language is decidable.
This is true,
but there's a potential pitfall here
that we need to make sure to avoid.