All right so I've got scripting checked
off, and I'm going to hit record and
see what happens when
I click this button.
Okay, here's my timeline.
But you know, sometimes you can have
a pretty good idea of where the cause of
junk might be found in the pipeline, but
other times it could be
kind of tricky to find.
And here, I think I need a little bit
more space, so I will go ahead and
pop this into its own window.
Now, I see a bunch of frames here,
and these all happened
after the button clicked.
So, I want to know what happens
right when the button clicks,
which is going to be
right in the beginning.
It looks like the last scripting thing
to happen before all the layouts
happened right here.
So, I'll go ahead and zoom in.
I clicked on this last scripting event,
and it looks like that
was just a mouse move, and that's
not what I'm looking for right now.
So, I'll jump back a little further.
All right now this scripting event
looks a little bit more exciting
because it came from a click which
is the last thing that I did.
I zoomed in a little bit further to see
that this event caused a function to
run, I'll click on it in see that
it's location is in this quiet file
at line 172.
Click on that to see what it's
referring to in fact this function
On switch layout click is definitely
the culprit that i'm looking for here.
Toggling wide on the body is causing
all of those janki long layouts.
So, the correct answer is the function.
On switch layout click.