All right, it's your turn now.
You're going to add Parallax Scrolling
at half the primary scroll
speed to the landscape phone view.
It's going to look something like that.
In layout-land/fragment_main.xml you're
going to rename appbar to parallax_bar,
just like I did in this little lecture.
And then in ForecastFragment you're
going to add an onScrollListener to our
Recyclerview.
And then in the onScrollListener,
you're going to change the translation
y of the parallax bar in
response to changes in scrolling.
Now, we're scrolling at half speed, so
you'll want to change the translation
by half of the scroll deltas.
And of course, you'll want to make
sure that you limit the deltas to
approximately the negative
height of your view.
Finally clear all your onScroll
Listeners in onDestroy, very easy to do.