If we can get something on
the screen without waiting for
the network to succeed or
fail, that's offline first.
Delivering full content
without the network
is a full a star offline
first experience.
Delivering just the header without
the network isn't as good, but
still that header was
delivered offline first.
And getting that on screen, while you're
busy with the network will give your
app a better perceived performance
versus a blank screen.
The other two options require
the network to succeed or
fail before showing anything.
So they're online first,
not offline first.
In a moment Jake will introduce you
to a demo app that works online only.
By the end of the course,
we'll have it working lightning fast and
offline first.