Using that, we basically said, even taking these types of images, like this,
we can actually now compute the Fourier transforms that
actually encode the frequencies, and we can use that in doing blending.
So of course, what we did was, we computed the Fourier transforms for
the left image and the right image.
Then we decomposed these Fourier images into octaves, which were,
of course, the different bands here.
So for the left one and the right one, we computed all the different octaves.
Of course, then to blend them, we have to feather them.
And what we did was, we basically took the octaves, separate ones, for
different frequencies, for the left and the right, and feathered them together.
And then of course, after all of that was done, we computed the inverse Fourier
transform and also did some feathering in the spatial domain.
And then took all of that information together
to generate a feathered octave images in the frequency domain.
And that was the process we went through.
So, basically, we computed the Fourier transforms of the images, and
feathered the corresponding octaves.
And used that, and built back up to generate a blended image.
Now, let's look at another whole method of trying to do this,
which will, intuitively, be a little simpler.
And, actually, at the same time,
allow you to build your own tools to do this kind of blending.