A matrix multiply is
the following operation.
Given two input matrices, A and
B, and given a third matrix C,
perform the update,
A times B + C, and overwrite C.
Schematically, I like to draw
matrix multiplies this way.
Matrix A has m rows and k columns.
Matrix B has k rows and n columns, and
the matrix C has m rows, same as A,
and n columns, same as B.
The matrix update formula may
be interpreted as follows.
Consider some output element Cij.
This scalar update formula at
the bottom tells you how to update it.
Essentially, you compute a dot product
between a row of a and a column of b.
The dot product comes from multiplying
corresponding elements of the two
vectors and
then accumulating them into the output.
Let's look at an example.
Suppose row i of A and
column j of B have these values.
And let's further suppose that
Cij has this initial value.
The dot product is the sum of
the element-wise products.
So in this case, we take
the element-wise products 3 times 1,
4 times 2, -2 times 5.
Add them all together, accumulate
them with the initial value of C,
which was 6, and we'd get 7.
Here's what a matrix multiply
looks like as pseudocode.
It's just three nested loops.
This form makes it easy to see that
the algorithm takes time O of m times n
times k.
And of course,
when all the dimensions are equal,
that's big O of, say, n cubed.
So, where's the parallelism?
Both the picture and
the code suggests that all the output
elements are independent of one another.
So, if you were to parallelize
this code for a PRAM type system,
the first easy thing you would do
is to replace the outermost for
loops with parallel for loops.
In fact, that gives you another
useful fact about matrix multiply.
Suppose you want to compute
a group of elements of C.
Then you can do a group update by
doing a sub matrix multiply or
block matrix multiply.
For example, this block would
depend on this block of rows, and
this block of columns.
Put another way, everywhere you see
a matrix element in this picture,
you could instead imagine not a single
element, but an entire submatrix.
The computation is essentially
the same with respect to blocks.
Okay, back to parallelism.
What about this innermost loop?
I hope you recognize that
it's basically a reduction.
Notice that the element-wise products
within the loop are independent.
Once you've computed them all,
you just add them all up.
So we can replace the inner-most
l loop with the following.
So there's a temporary array, a new loop
to compute the independent products, and
then a reduction.
Now if all the dimensions
are equal to little n,
then the total work is n cubed,
and the span is just log n.
So, I hope you find a matrix
multiply to be easy to state and
rich with available parallelism.