So, this whole concept of how we can actually take a signal, and
represent it in a different way,
was something proposed by a famous mathematician known as Fourier, and
of course, this whole concept is also referred to as a Fourier transform.
So, in the previous slide,
when we did the work on trying to reconstruct a signal,
[INAUDIBLE] have to remember that those impulse functions were repeating
themselves after a fixed period, so that's why that was a periodic function.
And we looked at them and basically concluded that a weighted sum of sines and
cosines of different frequencies, because we changed the frequencies,
allowed us to reconstruct that periodic function.
So in essence, what that says is that any periodic function can be
rewritten as a weighted sum of sines and cosines of different frequencies.
So in essence, what a Fourier transform does,
is it transforms a mathematical function of time, into a new function,
whose argument is frequencies, not time, and this frequency usually has units
of cycles per second repetition, and it's sometimes referred to as hertz,
and sometimes also kind of looked at as radians per second.
So it's no longer time steps, but is measured in,
how the frequency or how many times it's repeating itself.
And the new function basically is a frequency spectrum,
of the function f, we'll show what this means in a few seconds too.
Now, one thing to note is this operation, that goes from a function to
a Fourier transform has to be a reversible operation, and for
every frequency omega that goes from 0 to infinity, the Fourier
transform holds the amplitude A, and the phase, of the sine function,
again, we will look at this carefully, but in essence, we need to be able to
both look at the amplitude and the phase variations of the sine function,
cause that's something we want to be able to use to represent that signal.
So this is the equation that we want to be able to model, frequency, phase, and
this is the Fourier transform, A is the amplitude.