Our goal is to use a search strategy
similar to the route-finding problem,
but to design an AI that
can play Tic Tac Toe.
What, in your opinion,
should be the nodes and
edges in the graph that we search?
Option A,
should each cell be a separate node,
with an edge connecting two
of them if they are adjacent?
Option B, how about using the current
position of the computer player as
a node, expressed as a row/column
tuple where row, column are ?
Two such nodes can be
connected if their row and
column values differ by at most one.
For example, (0, 1) should be
connected to (1, 0) but not (2, 2).
Option C, maybe we need to keep track of
the opponent's current position as well.
So each node will be a pair of
tuples such as .
For edges we can use the same rule-
connect if the computer player's
positions differ by at most one.
Option D, we could also think
of the whole board as a node, so
we'll have one node for every possible
arrangement of Xs and Os on the board.
In this case, connect two nodes if there
is a valid move that changes the board
from one to the other.
Mark the appropriate answer.
[BLANK_AUDIO]