Welcome to Computer Vision.
The last couple lessons we introduced the notion of filtering.
We started from a notion of how to do like,
noise removal as a way of applying a, a linear operator type.
Mostly time being linear.
And it was being able to do a local averaging.
We also talked about the difference between correlation and convolution.
Which is sort of just keeping a little bit of bookkeeping in
terms of keeping track of appropriate orientation of the filters.
Now we are going to shift a little bit.
And talk about the notion of filters as some way of
getting at an intermediate representation of an image.
What I mean by that is, you could imagine you take some image,
and you convert the pixels into some, maybe an array again.
Still an image as a function.
But the idea is that that function now, is no longer just about the intensity.
But it's about some property of the pixels locally in the image.
And then we'll get to something that might be a very useful property in terms of
representing our image.
Before we do this, I need to put in one little caveat.
Remember before, we talked about things being linear,
so if I was correlating an image, filter with an image.
If I just multiplied that correlation filter by some constant.
Okay?
Then the whole value would get bigger.
So if I were comparing the output of an image correlated with
filter one versus an image correlated with filter two.
And I want to be talking about sort of,
how much filter one responds to the image versus filter two.
It's important that in some sense,
the scale, the multiplicative scale of those filters be the same.
Otherwise the correlation will just be scaled by their difference.
So by the way,
from what I'm about to tell you, it's okay to gloss over the details.
For those of you who are doing the problem sets, you're going to learn a lot
more about this method that's referred to as normalized correlation.
Here I'll just introduce it.
Here's what we're going to do, we're going to assume when we do our correlation.
First, we're gon, we're going to normalize our filters.
By making them that,
say, the standard deviation of all the pixels is equal to one, let's say.
That would be one way of doing it, because as I scale that filter up and
down, its standard deviation grows and shrinks.
So I'm going to make standard deviation be no more, be exactly one.
That's a problem if you've got a constant.
Don't worry about that problem.
We're going to try to make it so that its standard deviation is one.
Then the other thing that we're going to do is,
suppose I've got two images that are actually the same.
Except one has just been multiplied by some constant.
Well then if I correlate, even my normalized kernel, the one that's been
multiplied by the constant, the total value is going to get multiplied also.
So when we do it's called normalized correlation.
We do two things.
We normalize the filter, like we said.
And then when we stick the filter down over a little patch of pixels,
we scale that patch so its standard deviation is also one.
And then we compute the correlation.
And as we move the filter around, we change that image scale because the,
the pixels are different.
And that's what's referred to as normalized correlation.
So for the rest of what I'm going to show you,
I'm going to be doing normalized correlation.