A lot of Android Wear apps involve
scrolling side to side, and up and down.
Grid View Pager handles
all this swiping for you.
We also have Dots Page Indicator, which
shows the little dots that appear at
the bottom,
showing where the user is located.
These two classes do everything
with a consistent look and
feel, associated with
all Android Wear apps.
To demonstrate this,
we're going to load the Grid View Pager
sample app on Android studio.
So, we go to File > Import sample,
and look for Grid View Pager.
And load that up with the defaults.
Now, let's build it, and
install it to our device.
You can see here that we can
scroll around the cards, and
Grid View Pager takes care
of all of this for us.
For your quiz,
try out the sample yourself and
go through the MainActivity.java file to
see what code was used to generate this.