So, to continue on, one of the things I'd like to kind of point is that
there's been an evolution in the whole field of photography.
We've gone from cameras that look like this to that.
Our darkroom which used to be looking like this and
is now replaced by software on our computer.
Which basically now means is that basically a whole lot of
people can actually be involved with this pipeline.
Photography is not just for the few, but everybody's exercising it.
That's why computational photography that encompasses all of this could be
just applied to photography in general but
also could be applied to advanced photography to generate novel types of
images is becoming a very interesting discipline.