So just to kind of think about it.
Lets look deeper into what film camera's all about.
And again I want to emphasis that I don't think anything's wrong with them and
I'm happy to use them all the time too.
But there are some concerns people have expressed about film cameras.
One, you need chemicals and darkrooms.
Well very nice creative work can be done with them.
But, there are still limitations to those types of things.
Of course you could only take 12, 24, 36 pictures per roll.
These days of course, all of you with your smartphone cameras most probably
taking hundreds if not thousands of pictures, whenever you feel like.
again, perhaps somebody may argue,
this is a great way of actually making the right photographs happen.
Having constraints, like being able to take 12 pictures, would actually be
great because we'll only take 12 pictures at a time, and not hundreds.
But the other thing, and this is perhaps the biggest reason for getting into
digital photography and computational photography, is in the traditional film.
By the time you take a picture and then you develop it and it takes a long time.
These days with displays you get pretty much instant gratification.
You can see the results right there.
Another part of it has been the sensitivity of film.
We'll cover the sensitivity of film versus digital sensors in a future lecture.
But some may argue, and
actually I would agree, that film is a pretty sensitive medium.
It actually can cover a lot more dynamic range, than most sensors can, but
sensors are getting better, and
now actually there is a race on comparisons between the two.
But again, purists may love to use this and I still, support that argument.