Let's consider the first statement.
There are two equations in the system
that define the same plane.
This seems promising, since it means
that we'll get redundant information.
But it is not actually a criterion for
infinitely many solutions.
Remember, that removing
redundant information doesn't
change the system solution.
So we have to look at
the rest of the system,
not just the repeated planes to
know what the solution set will be.
For example,
a system of any two non-parallel planes
will intersect in a line
as we saw earlier.
This means the property is not necessary
to have infinitely many solutions.
Also, it's not sufficient.
Just take any three planes with
a unique intersection, and
then just add a copy of one of
the planes to the bottom of the system.
Then we have a duplicate plane, but
we still have a unique intersection.
Now, let's look at the second statement.
We encounter an equation of the form
0 = 0 during Gaussian elimination.
This falls in the same trap
as the first statement.
The equation 0 = 0 is redundant
information that tells us nothing about
the solutions set.
It is not necessary to run into
an equation of the form 0 =
0 to have infinitely many solutions,
just take any two non-parallel planes.
Nor is it sufficient to
find a 0 = 0 equation and
declare that a system has
infinitely many solutions.
In the example we've seen
several times now, the final row
become 0 = 0 in Gaussian elimination,
but the system has a unique solution.
As for the third statement,
there are fewer than three
equations in the system.
It is again neither necessary nor
sufficient to form a counter
example to necessity.
Just take three copies
of the same plane,
the system will have three equations but
infinitely many solutions, any point
in the plane will be a solution.
A counterexample for
sufficiency is any two distinct planes
that are parallel but not equal.
There are just two equations but there
is no possibility of an intersection.
An interesting point though,
is if we add the condition
that the system is consistent.
If we know there's a solution,
then having fewer than three planes
is sufficient to show that there
are infinitely many solutions.
Why?
Well, remember that we need at least
three planes to have a unique solution.
Since we're assuming
there is some solution,
the only possibility left is that
there are infinitely many solutions.
Finally, let's consider the statement,
after reaching triangular form,
there's at least one variable
that isn't the lead variable
in any equation in the system,
and there are no 0 = k's.
This criterion is a bit more
technical and unwieldy, but
it's the one we're looking for.
It's both necessary and
sufficient to characterize a system
as having infinitely many solutions.
We talked about a similar statement for
characterizing systems
with unique solutions.
Like we said then,
a system with no contradictory equations
will have a unique solution if and
only if every variable can be found as
a leading variable in triangular form.
If not, then the variables that aren't
leading variables will become parameters
for the infinite family of solutions.