So here it's just a table and I've highlighted a couple of entries.
Lets first take a look at, s equal 2 here.
So lets suppose we were doing fitting a line or if we're
doing a transformation that's a similarity transform where you take two pairs.
Notice that if my percentage of outliers is 50%.
So half my matches are bad.
I only have to choose 17 examples, for
me to have a 99% chance, that at least one of them was the correct one.
So doing something 17 times in a computer like that, that's pretty fast.
If I'm computing homography, s is now equal to 4.
Even with 50%, I only have to try 72 samples.
So even though I'm totally randomly pulling these things, and
I have no idea which points are right and which points are wrong,
and half the matches are wrong, with just 72 of them.
I have a better than 99% likelihood that one of my sets is the correct one.
And in fact, even if I'm doing a fundamental matrix, all right, looking for
eight matches, I only have to check less than 1200 of them in order for it to be
likely that one of those matches, at least one, will be the cor, a correct set
of matches so the fundamental matrix that I would get would be the correct one.
One thing to notice about this table is that N does not go up
very much as the percentage of outliers goes up, but
it does go up pretty steeply as s gets bigger.
So as the number of parameters that you need gets larger,
all the sudden the number of sample sets you have to check before you,
pretty sure you'll have one that's right, goes up as well.
Now some of you are not table people, some of you are graph people.
So what I have here is a graph where I just did s equals 4.
So like a homography.
And on the axis on the bottom you should see the percentage of outliers.
And you can see that the number of samples required.
Which goes all the way up here to well at 0.8 it's above 2000.
But it stays low for a very long time.
And that's the really cool thing about RANSAC,
is that it stays low even with a relatively high percentage of outliers.