We will also learn how to extend a bunch of these concepts that we're
learning about in this class to video.
Now, to be very honest,
video is the real area that I work on as a researcher and
it's an academic discipline that I've been working on for oh, two decades now.
In this class, I will introduce some of the basic ideas, some of
them actually related to the work, we ourselves have done, of capturing video,
video of course as you know is becoming even a more popular medium now, ,.
Sports video analysis becomes very common, and,
as we start getting into fancier,
newer types of cameras like the quadcopter cameras that are capturing video.
In this context we will learn about video textures and also learn about video
stabilization, two of the techniques that my group has also worked on, and
actually more importantly, we'll introduce you to the whole area of video with
a simple and fun experiment and assignment to let you do video textures.