[Norvig] How does first order logic work? What does it do?
Like propositional logic, we start with a model.
In propositional logic a model was a value for each propositional symbol.
So we might say that the symbol P was true
and the symbol Q was false,
and that would be a model that corresponds to what's going on in a possible world.
In first order logic the models are more complex.
We start off with a set of objects.
Here I've shown 4 objects, these 4 tiles,
but we could have more objects than that.
We could say, for example, that the numbers 1, 2, and 3
were also objects in our model.
So we have a set of objects.
We can also have a set of constants that refer to those objects.
So I could use the constant names A, B, C, D, 1, 2, 3,
but I don't have to have a one-to-one correspondence
between constants and objects.
I could have 2 different constant names that refer to the same object.
I could also have, say, the name C that refers to this object,
or I could have some of the objects that don't have any names at all.
But I've got a set of constants, and I also have a set of functions.
A function is defined as a mapping from objects to objects.
And so, for example, I might have the Number Of function
that maps from a tile to the number on that tile,
and that function then would be defined by the mapping from A to 1
and B to 3 and C to 3 and D to 2,
and I could have other functions as well.
In addition to functions, I can have relations.
For example, I could have the Above relation,
and I could say in this model of the world the Above relation is a set of tuples.
Say A is above B and C is above D.
So that was a binary relation holding between 2 objects.
Say 1 block is above another block.
We can have other types of relations.
For example, here is a unary relation--vowel--
and if we want to say the relation Vowel is true only of the object that we call A,
then that's a set of tuples of length 1 that contains just A.
We can even have relations over no objects.
Say we wanted to have the relation Rainy, which doesn't refer to any objects at all
but just refers to the current situation.
Then since it's not rainy today, we would represent that as the empty set.
There's no tuples corresponding to that relation.
Or, if it was rainy, we could say that it's represented by a singleton set,
and since the arity of Rainy is 0, there would be 0 elements in each one of those tuples.
So that's what a model in first order logic looks like.