Now, lets actually build on this idea.
And ask ourselves a series of questions.
I'm going to make this into a quiz for
you to kind of think about also.
Lets concentrate only on a point light
source, an idealized point light source.
So, lets say imagine I put a idealized
point light source in this set up here.
I have a lens based system and you know,
this is my camera and
I have three different set ups.
I'm going to show you one of them first.
Okay.
Of course focus point.
This is the image plane.
This is where the location of this is.
This is an ideal camera and
the image is formed here.
Of course this pin single
point light source.
Would then of course, create a one
intensity pixel on my image sensor.
Right?
Focused and everything else.
The question for you now is if I move
this point source with the same camera.
And now I generate this thing, of course
on the image plane this is happening.
And, for the other one,
this is happening.
So, just to see if you've been paying
attention a little bit, simple stuff.
Just put in there is
what's happening in these types
of three different scenarios.
Put the number, one, two,
and three in the right box.
Which one of them is the near object,
and the output would be blurred.
Far object, the output would be blurred,
or in cases of, you know,
in focus image and
a perfect image would be generated.