Function definitions
take the general form.
We start with func,
followed by the function name,
then a pair of parenthesis,
then inside the parentheses,
you'll find the parameters
taking the form.
_parameterName: parameterType, then
an arrow pointing to the returnType,
followed by the executable
statements between curly braces.
So if we look at our
sumOfStrings method,
we see that it takes in a parameter
called aBunchOfStrings.
And that parameter is of type array,
holding items of type string.
This function returns
an object of type Int.
I know, I know, you're probably asking,
what about that mysterious underscore?
Don't worry,
we'll get to the underscore in a minute.
Let's look at another example.
The name in this function is reverse.
It takes in a string as a parameter, and
it returns an object of type string.
Keep in mind that not every
function returns an object.
For example, If we had a similar
method called reverseAndPrint,
which printed out its result,
instead of returning it, the function
signature would look like this.
No returnType, and since there's
no return type, no arrow either.
Let's see that comparison one more time.
Here's reverse again, and you can see
that when we switch to reverseAndPrint,
the returnType goes away.