For our first animation,
let's animate the clock.
To start, we'll need to open up
the Animation Apartment scene.
Next, we need to open up
the Animation window.
Go to window, Animation.
That'll create
the Animation Timeline window.
Let's go ahead and
drag that next to the console.
Now, to start using
the animation window,
we need to select
an object in the hierarchy.
In this scene,
we'll be animating the clock.
More specifically for
our clock, let's select our clock
handle seconds game object, and now in
our Animation window we should now
have an option to create an animation.
Let's go ahead and create one and
call it seconds rotation.
It'll be saved as a .anim file.
As soon as we do that,
our window now turns into a timeline
which is also known as the dope sheet.
On the left, we can add properties
that we want to animate.
These can be components on
the current game object or
components of children game objects.
Since we want to animate the hands of
the clock, let's animate it's rotation.
From properties,
let's select transform rotation.
Once we do that, you'll notice that
rotation is added as a property and
there are couple of diamonds at
zero seconds and one second.
Those diamonds represent key frames.
Key frames are points in our animation
where we can update our properties.
In this case, the rotation of our clock.
For any new property,
Unity creates two points by default that
are initialized to the current values.
We can add a new key frame to
the animation by double-clicking
on the timeline.
We can also drag key frames
around to whatever time we want.
For example something like 0.5 seconds.
To update a key frame we need
to drag the timeline selector
to a key frame we want to edit.
To edit this key frame, let's go
ahead and set this rotation to 180.
And then for the last key frame, let's
go ahead and set its rotation to 360.
Notice how the backgrounds for
the rotation values are all
highlighted in red.
That means the Animation window
is recording our changes and
setting them as key frame values.
This lets us know we
are editing the right property.
Now let's find the play button
in the animation window.
This play button slowly
runs our animation,
as opposed to the main play button,
which runs the entire scene.
So now, if we hit the play
button in the animation window,
we'll see our hands start to rotate.