When we run this version
of the Color Maker app,
you'll notice that the red
switch seems to be working fine.
The green switch doesn't
seem to be working and
the blue switch is producing
teal instead of blue.
If you are thinking that this is because
the properties are set incorrectly,
then you're on the right track.
When you're connecting a lot of outlets,
it's pretty easy to accidentally
point one to the wrong view.
Let's take a look at how things
look in the View Controller
by opening up this parallel text editor.
From the View Controller side,
everything looks as expected.
All of our controls here are connected,
and our color view's connected.
So we'll need to have a look at
the popup menus in Storyboard
to get to the root of the problem.
If we take a look at the popup menu for
the green switch,
we can see why that wasn't working.
Its outlet's not set.
And then if we take
a look at the menu for
the blue switch, we can see that it
points to both blue and green controls.
That explains the teal.
So let's fix that.
We'll go into the green switch and
add its outlet.
And let's double check the blue switch,
and
we can see that it's only
pointing to the blue control now.
And let's run it again for good measure.
Red switch still works, green switch
works and blue is producing blue.