Now when two kernel level threads belong to the same address space
there's actually information in the process control blog that is relevant for
the entire process.
However there is information here that is specific to just one
kernel level thread.
For instance this includes information about signals or system call arguments.
So when we're contact switching among these two kernel level threads,
there is a portion of this process control block information that we
want to preserve, like all of the virtual address mappings.
But then there is portion of it,
that's really specific to the particular kernel level thread and
it depends on what is the user level thread that's currently executing.
So it's something that the threading library directly impacts.
So we will split up the information that was contained originally in the process
control block, and we will separate it into the hard process state that's
relevant for all of the user level threads that execute within that process.
And then, the more light weight process state that is only relevant for
a subset of the user level threads that are currently associated with
a particular kernel-level thread.
So we started off with one large contiguous process control block structure, and
then we divided the information that was contained in it
across a number of different data structures.