The three main steps in the post-process
video stabilization that I'm going to
talk about are one, I want to
estimate the camera motion, second,
I want to stabilize the camera path,
and finally,
I want to be able to
re-synthesize a new path.
Now, couple of other
options we have to note.
Most of the casual videos we
will look at would be from
relatively wide-angle cameras like this.
And the other thing is,
one more given is most of the time,
if there's a videographer involved,
they will do the best they can to
keep one subject in the center.
Those two assumptions help us doing
the kind of stabilization we're going to
look at next.