Open up the first exercise
in the third lesson,
the one that's called exercise
recycler view layout.
Unlike in the previous lessons, for this
app you're going to fill out a different
part of the recycler
view with each exercise.
And we've given you the entire rest of
the code, which means once you complete
your changes you can build and
run the project and see it working.
In this exercise we'll be mainly
modifying these files but
we've also provided you with
this file called ColorUtils.
It contains a method that colors
the view holders for the recycler view.
Feel free to explore
the ColorUtils file and
its documentation but
we won't be do any changes here.
Currently our activity main layout
includes the frame layout and
that includes a text view in it.
The text view simply displays
the text hello world.
In this exercise,
we'll be replacing this entire
text view with a recycler view.
But to do that,
we first need to add the recycler view
dependency in the build.gradle file.
Inside the build.gradle file we can add
a new dependency by typing in compile.
And then because the recycler view is
part of the Android Support Library,
the dependency line starts
with com.android.support.
And then colon,
followed by the word recyclerview.
And then followed by v7,
which is the library type that allows
us to target Gingerbread devices.
And then followed by colon and
the version of the library.
Because we just made this change
in the build.gradle file,
we need to sync the project
with the new gradle settings.
Now, let's change the text view here and
replace it with the recycler view.
The recycler view needs to cover the
entire space in the parent frame layout.
So we need to set it to,
you guessed it, match_parent.
Now that we've created
our recycler view,
we need to assign it
an ID called rv_numbers.
This is the ID that everywhere else
in the code is expecting it to have.
Once we add the ID to our recycler
view everything should be set up and
ready to go.
Note that we could also replace the
entire frame out with this recycler view
because the frame layout isn't
really serving any purpose anymore.
We encourage you to go and
try out what we just did yourself.
Start by adding a recycler
view dependency and
then change the activity main
to contain the recycler view.
You can see what needs to be done,
by checking this TODO tab down here.
It would list all the TODO items
that we've assigned for you.
The rest of the work is already done.
So, you'll be able to see the recycler
view in action right away and
know that you've done
your work correctly.