Sharing data is great for developers.
And using a content provider, it's a piece of cake to have an app grab data from
the user's contacts, documents, or calendar with only a few lines of code.
For example, let's say you're making a new business card reader application.
The goal is to have the user take a picture of their phone of the business card,
and the app will automatically add their contact information to your phone.
Then, they can lose the business card.
[SOUND] But they'll still have all that hard wired networking information.
Pretty great, huh?
In order to make this app seamless for
users, you need to store this new contact info into the same
data source the user's already using to store their phone's contact data.
Then if all the contact data is stored in the same place, your business card
contact info should appear in your default contacts application.
So how do you have two different applications easily read and
write to the same data source?
This is where content providers come in.
In short, a content provider is a class that sits between an application and
its data source.
And its job is to provide easily managed access to the underlying data source.