In the basic square RPC example,
we said that all of the data types for
the input and output arguments
must be described in the .x file.
All of these types and data structures
must be XDR supported data types.
Some of the default XDR data types
are those that are commonly available in
programming languages like C for
things like character and byte and
integer and float.
But XDR supports many other data types.
For instance, if you specify
that something is a const,
it will be translated after compilation
into a constant, which is C,
will be a #define value.
Data types like hyper or quadruple
are used to refer to a 64-bit integer or
a 120-bit float, respectively.
And XDR also supports
a so-called opaque type,
which really corresponds to data type
that's uninterpreted binary data.
So, similar to the C byte type.
So for instance,
if you want to transfer an image,
that image will be represented
as an array of opaque elements.
Let's talk more specifically
about arrays because in XDR,
you can specify two types of arrays.
The first is a fixed-length array
that's described as follows.
And here, the exact number of
elements in the array is specified.
The RPC runtime will allocate
the corresponding amount of
memory whenever arguments of this
data type are sent or received.
And it will also know exactly how many
bytes from the incoming packet stream it
should read out in order to populate
a variable that's of this data type,
this type of array.
There are also variable-length arrays,
where the length is specified
in angular brackets.
And this doesn't denote
the actual length,
rather the maximum expected length.
When compiled, this will translate into
a data structure that has two fields.
An integer, len, that corresponds
to the actual size of this array.
And a pointer,
val, that is the address of where the
data in this array is actually stored.
When the data is sent, the sender has
to specify len, the size of the array,
and then set val to point to the memory
location where the data is stored.
On the receiving end,
the server will know that it's expecting
data structure that's a variable-length.
So it will know to read the first 4
bytes to determine what is the length,
what is the size of the array.
And then to allocate
the appropriate amount of memory,
and then to read the remaining portions
of the incoming byte stream and
to populate that memory
with those values.
The only exception to
this are the strings.
A variable-length string
is defined as follows, and
this line is really just
the C pointer to character.
In memory,
the string will be stored just like
a normal null-terminated string, so
it will be an array of characters
with the null character at the end.
Operations like string copy and
string length need that
particular representation
in order to be able to determine
where is the end of the string.
However, when that variable-length
string is encoded for transmission,
it will be encoded as
a pair of length and data.
So from that perspective,
that will be similar,
actually identical to what we see for
other variable-length data structures.