So as I said, this is a homogeneous set of equations.
Now, when you have a homogeneous set, like Am equals 0,
and let's suppose you have a lot of equations, well,
clearly what you'd like to do is you want to place some constraint on m.
because I don't want to let it be 0.
But then given that constraint, I want to find something that sort of
computes the smallest square value of A times m.
And that's what's written here.
So I'm going to try to minimize the magnitude of Am.
Now, m is only valid up to a scale.
And we know that for a couple of reasons.
Right?
One is you can just take a look at these equations here.
Since, the everything's equal to 0, I could just scale m.
Or I can go all the way back to my perspective equations.
because clearly if I scale all those ms by a value,
when I go from the homogenous to the nonhomogeneous, when I divide uw by w,
that scale factor will go away.
So m is only defined up to a scale, that matrix, all the little m's.
So since it's defined only up to a scale,
let's just assume it's going to be a unit vector.
Okay, so it, it's magnitude is going to be length 1, and the question is,
what's the best unit vector m to minimize the magnitude of Am?
I'm going to tell you the solution here, and
then I'm going to show you that it's the solution.
And some of you will have seen this before, and some of you won't.
The solution to minimizing Am, the magnitude when Am as a unit vector,
is, as you all know I'm sure, because you've studied this all the time,
you want to take the eigenvector of A transpose A as the smallest eigenvalue.
Of course, you say.
I know that all the time.
I'll show it to you in a minute.
And by the way, this only works when you have six or
more points, and that should make sense right?
How many degrees of freedom are there in m?
There's 11, because it, there's 12, but only up to a scale.
Well, I get two equations per point, so I'm going to need at least six points.
But of course this thing works a lot better the more points you have.