We're almost done with our login, but
before we go to the next view,
we need to grab the user's ID.
If we look back to the methods of
the documentation like the one for
adding and removing a favorite we
can see this ID in curly braces.
And like we said a little bit before,
this ID corresponds to the user ID and
getting it ahead of time and
storing it will save us having to
make requests later when we want to
add favorites, or do something
else that requires the user ID.
Back in Xcode lets go to
the get session ID method and
lets go to the bottom where
the completion handler is finishing.
Here we go.
And we've stored the session ID and
now it's just called get user ID.
And if we look at the get user ID
method, it's empty and it's ready for
you to implement.
So for this exercise, find the correct
movie database method to use to get
the user ID, implement the seven steps,
then store the user ID and
call the completeLogin method.
If you do all this correctly,
then the completeLogin method
will go to the next view.
And when you're done, check this box.