Once you know that a turing machine can
simulate a ram then you know it can
simulate a standard CPU.
Once you can simulate a CPU you can
simulate any interpreter or compiler and
thus any programming language.
So anything you can run on your desktop
can be simulated by a turing machine.
The turing machine can
tackle any problem
that the computer on
your desk can solve.
What about multicore, cloud computing,
problematic, quantum and DNA computing?
We won't do it here, but
you can prove turing machines can
simulate all those models as well.
The church turing thesis has
truly stood the test of time.
Models of computation come and
go but none have been, or
ever will be, any match for
the turing machine.
Why should we care about
the church turing thesis?
Because there are problems that
turing machines can't solve.
We argued this with counter
arguments in the first lecture and
we'll give specific examples
in future lectures.
If these problems can't be
solved by turing machines,
they can't be solved by any
other computing device.
To help us describe specific
problems that one can not compute,
in the next lecture we discuss
two of turines critical insights.
That a computer program can be viewed
as data as part of the input to
another program and that one can
have a universal turing machine.
That one that can simulate
the code of any other machine.
One machine to rule them all.