All right.
Welcome back to Computer Vision.
If you remember last time,
we started talking about
discriminative classifiers.
So we first did generative,
then we did discriminative.
And the idea of discriminative
classification or
recognition is that instead of
worrying about modeling our classes,
we're going to learn a boundary.
We're going to learn a surface, and some
feature space that divides our classes.
And we've talked about two simple
method, well actually, one simple
method, nearest neighbor, a much
more interesting method of boosting.
Last time, we were talking about
the Viola-Jones face detector which
used boosting.
But today we're going to talk
about support vector machines.
Support vector machines became
a very significant method of doing
classification, and especially
is applied to computer vision.
It really and today, and
still today is is, is fundamental