You can't optimize your app's frame rate
if you don't understand how the browser
actually renders a frame.
So you need to learn how a page is
actually put together when it's
first loaded.
I'll go over the process
briefly right now, but
if you want a more in-depth
look at how the page is built
I highly recommend checking
out the link to Cam's and
Ilia's website performance optimization
course in the instructor notes.
Cam already mentioned it, but
it's a super good course.
Although, don't go just yet, right?
Just stay here and, you know,
I'd miss you if you went.
Check it out later.
Okay, so let's take a look at
what goes into making a frame.
Initially the browser makes
a get request to a server.
The server responds
by sending some HTML.
At this point,
the browser does some pretty clever
stuff with lookahead parsing.
But what we care about is that it parses
the document and gives us these notes.
In Chrome DevTools,
you'll see it as Parse HTML.
Okay, so this is what
the DOM looks like as a tree.
But let's just make it a bit easier for
ourselves, and call it the DOM.
As well as the DOM, we also have CSS.
And this comes from the user agent,
it comes from your style sheets or
any inline styles you have, and
perhaps third party styles.
The next part of the process
is to combine the DOM and CSS.
In the tools you're going to
see this as Recalculate Styles.
And when combined, we get a new
tree called the Render Tree.
The Render Tree looks
pretty similar to the DOM,
except that some things are missing.
For example, we don't have the head
anymore, we don't have any scripts.
In fact, if we had some CSS that set
the section paragraph to display none,
then it would be removed
from the render tree.
Equally if we had some CSS that added
a pseudo element like after or before,
this would get added to the render tree
even though it doesn't live in the DOM.
It's important to note that only
elements that will actually be
displayed on the page will
make it into the render tree.
So this is essentially a simplified view
of where the critical rendering path
optimization gets you.