Hi there,
welcome to week two of the program.
This week we have a guest instructor,
Andrew Trask.
Andrew is a PhD student at
the University of Oxford,
where he studies deep learning for
natural language processing.
He's also the author of grokking Deep
Learning, which teaches deep learning to
anyone with Python skills and
basic math knowledge.
Andrew will be leading you through
building a network to predict sentiment,
positive or negative in movie reviews.
Then we'll cover methods such as,
Bag of Words, and
Word2vec for transforming text into
vectors we can use inputs to a network.
And finally, we'll give you
a brief introduction to TFLearn,
a high-level Python library for
quickly building neural networks.
Then, will show you how to use TFLearn
for more advanced sentiment analysis.
All right, let's get started.