So what's the difference between them?
Well you take a look and you say,
you know, to get from 75 to 225 that's
a difference of 150 and yep,
there it is, it's 150 okay?
But then you take a look between 45 and
315 and you say what's
the difference you say, oh my gosh,
to go from 45 to 315 requires a,
a, a hundred and oh, that's a lot.
So what's the difference?
What's, what's 315 minus 45?
[SOUND] 270.
It says there's 270 between them,
that's a really big difference.
Well, of course, the answer is no.
The difference between
them is actually 90.
And the reason is that,
if we go from let's say 0 all the way
around to 360 again,
45 is over here 315 is over here, right?
So the answer is it's not 270 between
them, it's only 90 between them.
So it's just a way of remembering
that things have to wrap around.