The discrete Fourier transform is what we have to do when we want to start
doing things in computers because after all we don't have continuous signals,
we only have discrete values.
So the discrete Fourier transform is written as this.
Now we say F of k,
where k in this case would be the discrete frequency, all right?
And, what we're going to do is we're going to sum over all the pixels, so
we're having x going from, or signal N-1d in this case,
from 0 through N minus 1 if I have a total of N of them.
So there's this 1 over N out here.
And now we have this e to the minus i.
And you see how it's k over N?
Because basically,
instead of now thinking of frequency as how quickly it wiggles in terms of time,
it's sort of, how quickly you wiggle over the entire length of the image.
So, k is written as, it's the number of cycles per period of the signal,
or per period of the image, all right?
Cycles per image.
This only makes sense essentially from 0, up to N over 2.
Why only N over 2?
Well, think about how quickly a sinusoid could
possibly wiggle in a image that has N pixels, right?
Well, it would go white, all the way to black, all the way to white,
all the way to black, all the way.
So it, that would be a period of ha, of, of 2.
So the frequency, the number of cycles, would be N over 2.
So basically, k can only go from minus N over 2 to plus N over 2,
because that's the highest frequency you can have in a discrete image.