So let's move on to the second step. We have some candidate classes, okay, and
we're now going to look at the features of those classes. And
in object-oriented analysis, there are two candidate, two kinds of features.
One kind are attributes and these are going to correspond to adjectives, and
the other kind is operations, which correspond to the action verbs in the text.
So for the next step, I'd like you to go back to your textual list and
this time, underline the adjectives, along with the corresponding noun,
indicate the corresponding noun that the adjective modifies. And then by
underlining these phrases and, and then combine them as you did with the nouns,
we'll have candidates as candidate attributes for
the various classes. Take a crack at that now.
[BLANK_AUDIO]