Then, we will step back further diving deeper into the technology and
learn about computational cameras.
These are newer forms of cameras that are showing up, which have
additional features and additional abilities, again, you beyond the norm of what
traditional photography is, these are commercially available cameras from Lytro,
which are light field cameras, more and more standard cell phone cameras
eventually will have an array of cameras attached to it, which is shown here,
and also newer research efforts like this one, where basically a camera and
a projector system can be merged together, to be able to then show,
you know, a different way of looking at information in a scene, so again, we
will look at light filled cameras, we will look at multi-view cameras, projector
camera systems, and, you know, this will be another fun thing we will do.