So to help us understand how imaging can be done with cameras,
let's try to build one from the basic first principles.
Help us do this, I'm starting off with a simple tree, shown here.
basically, it's kind of attempting to show a 3-D scene.
And what we're interested in is capturing this 3-D scene in a way that it
actually captures the geometry and all of the light variations of this.
Of course, nothing of the scene would be visible without a light source, right?
If you walk into a dark room, you can't see anything.
There has to be a light source, there could be an external one with sun or
simple light bulbs and stuff like that in internal situations.
Light source from this hits the tree, and basically then it reflects the light
back and it's the reflections from the scene that hit our eye,
that's why we see the scene, and again we want that reflections to hit
the camera, and store that image, and that's what we're interested in.
So in essence, any light source illuminates the scene like this, and
it's these reflections from this, kind of what we see, and
again that's one of the reasons we see color, we see specularities, and
stuff like that, depending on the type of surface it might be.
For example, if it's kind of reflecting black,
well it means that in essence it's absorbed everything.
If it's reflecting white, it means it's reflecting everything.
And you know, color come in, because again, the color properties of
the surface that actually has those color materials reflect differently, and
that's why we see those colors.
So this in essence, basically suggests that scenes have to be illuminated.
Now let's try to capture this information.
So to do this I'm actually going to pop up a, a screen of some sort, and
I'm now interested in basically saying this is my screen.
I want to capture this 3D structure onto the screen.
We can actually refer to this screen as a sensor.
Now we will talk about different types of sensors but let's assume this is
a sensor that actually captures this light and saves it for us.
But, before we get to the saving part,
let's see how light is actually created or gathered on this surface.
Of course, as I said in the last slide, if the sun was illuminating this tree,
each and every point of this tree would be reflecting back the light.
And that light would be hitting our eyes, and that's how we see it and
all that kind of stuff.
Well, so in essence, each and
every point is reflecting light and it's hitting the sensor.
And of course, no image is forming on this one because it's coming across in
all possible ways.
And of course, at present we're not thinking of this as a sensor.
Let's just claim it to be a screen and all of the light is there.
And of course it's for this reason, you walk around in an environment,
you actually don't see reflections of everything exactly on this environment.
What we want to now figure out is how to get these beams of
those rays of light focused.
So, to achieve this, let's put an obstruction in front of our screen.
And here I basically show an obstruction to be basically, a big, you know,
let's say a object of some sort, except that I do have an opening.
So, because of this obstruction, what will happen to all these sources of light?
Only the ones that actually go through this obstruction, this hole,
would make it to my screen.
The rest of them would just reflect off and
diffuse themselves in this part of the environment, and nothing will get
through, only the ones that get through would be through this opening.
So let's look at exactly what that means.
If a ray of light goes from the bottom of the tree, it goes through here,
it goes through the hole and hits the screen.
Let's see what happens on the other end.
Another ray of light goes from the top, goes through here and hits the screen.
Simple geometric kind of a way of looking at rays of light.
Remember, rays of light are the ones we are trying to
capture to create an image.
So one thing interesting is bottom is there, top is there.
So just by looking at this triangles,
we can say that this tree should be upside down when it forms on the sensor.
And again it makes perfect sense, this point is actually coming in and
registering here.
This point is coming and registering here and of course all of the points
on this tree would be going through this small hole and creating an image there.
So that in essence is basis of a camera per se.