So, list view performance is something
that a lot of developers run into from,
at some point,
you'll have a slow scrolling list.
And, again, there's a ton of reasons
why it would be slow scrolling.
And, I think being able to list off all
the possible reasons is important but
it's not, of course, the ones we
described are a subset but there's
plenty of other reasons why you could
have slow performance on your list.
So, I think Sam did a good job of
getting in a lot of the major ones
that people forget about.
So, you'll see a lot of developers they
don't recycle reviews and, of course,
they're working with very small data
sets so it's not a problem for them.
But he nailed that very well he
identified that could be an issue.
Some of those things about complex
layouts maybe you don't run into as
often, but I think you did a good job
of starting to run in that direction.