So what a basis set?
So here we've lifted this from Wikipedia.
Edited a little bit.
So a basis set, B, well you have to talk about a vector space.
So something is a basis set of a vector space, V,
is a linearly independent subset of V that spans V.
So let's expand those words out just a little bit.
So let's suppose that we have B that's just these vectors v1 through vn,
and it's just some finite subset over this field.
So field comes from mathematics, but
let's just talk about the realer complex number.
Okay, then a basis set B if it satisfies the following conditions.
So linear independence.
Okay, basically means that if I have some different constants, a1 through an, so
these are constants.
If I take a constant times each of the vectors, I've got a different constant,
and if the sum of those is 0.
Then it has to be the case that all of those constants were 0.
This is no different if you think of this in two dimensions.
If I have two vectors that are not in the same direction,
then if I combine them, right, I get this answer like that.
Well the only way that distance can be 0 is if both of the coefficients are 0.
So that's linear independence.
And then there's what's referred to as the spanning property.
Okay? That, remember it spans this vector field.
And what that means is that for any vector in that vector space,
I can create it by just some linear sum of the basis set.
Then again, you know, basically the idea is, so we normally think of
a basis set as being perpendicular, but it doesn't have to be.
Right? So if I've got this and I've got that as my two basis elements and
I want to create a vector that's like that.
Then, basically, what I have to do is I have to take some multiple of
the horizontal plus some multiple of the vertical we'll get me to that picture.
By the way, most of you are used to basis sets being orthogonal.
Okay? So you know, x, y.
All we said they had to be independent, okay?
Now, it's helpful if basis sets are orthogonal, we'll talk more about it
in a minute, because what it means by orthogonal is in order for
me to figure out how much of the x there is in a vector.
I don't have to worry at all about the y because the y amount and the,
it doesn't affect the x amount because they are orthogonal.
Another way of saying that is if I take a vector and
I take a docked product with the x direction I get one value and
a docked product in the y direction I get another value.
Well, if I take each of those dot products times their basis vector and
sum them up I get back the, the new vector.
And that's just because x and
y are orthogonal, and that's helpful if your, if your basis sets are orthogonal.
But technically they don't have to be, they just have to be independent.
That'll let you reach any vector.