The correct answer says,
well who has what roles gets defined
by the company itself, okay.
So whoever is responsible for
secure access to its resources,
trusted sys admin or whoever it is.
So what role you can take on
is mandated by the company and
what you can access depends on the role.
So, it doesn't depend on so,
remember, discretion access control,
the owner decides who can access
their file or data that they created.
Here that's going to be decided
by roles have access and
who can take on what role is
going to be decided by the company.
And because of that,
the fact that the company decides how
accesses are going to be allowed,
that's what makes this a mandatory
access control policy.