In the upcoming project,
you'll use machine learning techniques
to detect vehicles in images.
So in the next few lessons, Sebastian
and our colleague Katie Malone,
will introduce some of the different
classifiers that you'll need to be
familiar with for the project.
They'll also explain the critical
role that classification plays in
the self-driving car software Pipeline.
>> That's right.
In the upcoming lessons, you'll
learn about using classifiers like
support vector machines and
decision trees.
And later in this module,
you'll use these for
the job of identifying vehicles
in images from a video stream.
>> These lessons come
from UDACITY's free
introduction to machine learning course.
If you've already seen them,
or you're already an expert
in machine learning classifiers,
feel free to skip ahead.