Welcome back.
In the first lesson, you learned how the
browser renders pixels from HTML, CSS,
and JavaScript.
Understanding this process is key
to optimizing an app's performance.
>> Right.
And in this lesson, you'll take a step
back to think at a high level about your
app's life cycle as a whole.
The goal is to help you make intelligent
choices about when your app can and
should do the heavy work to create
a buttery smooth experience
for your users.
Now, before we start,
I have a question for you.
Should your goal be to make your app run
at 60 frames per second all of the time?
>> Ooh, ooh, I know this one!
>> Yeah.
>> Okay can I answer it for them?
>> Yes.
>> Okay cool.
The answer is no, actually, not quite.
It's important that you pick
your battles a bit, and
focus on the things that
matter to your end users.
When you think about it, there
are actually four major areas of any web
app's life cycle, and performance fits
into them in very different ways.