So here I have, the same system I had before.
Two camera centers.
Some point out there.
And these are my two image planes, okay?
Now, going your way back machine.
Well not so far back.
Just a few lectures back.
How do you map, from one plane, to another plane?
Well I told you before that if you have four points, on one plane and
four points on another plane.
And you knew their mapping, you would then have the total mapping between
the two planes, and that was called what?
That was called a homography, all right.
It took four points to get a homography, from one side.
From one plane to the next, all right.
So we're going to pretend for a moment, that we know the homography.
And just call it H that goes from the plane P to the plane that has P prime in
it, okay so we're going to pretend that we know that.
All right, and the other thing we're going to do, is we're going to say for
some point P here, l prime is going to be the fp polar line.
In the prime frame, that goes through this epipole e prime.
Okay?
So that's the two things I've set up, I'm going to pretend that I know my
homography, and I'm going to also say that that's the epipolar line, all right?
Now we do a little math.
Okay so, l is that epipolar line.
So,.
How do I find this line,
well remember, this is a line that goes between two points.
If you remember, in projective geometry, if I have two points, and
I want to find the line that goes through them, what do I do?
I just take the cross product.
That was one of the cool things about the projected, geometry.
You gave me two, points.
Take the cross product, you get the line, gimme two lines, take the cross
product, you get the point that inter, that's the intersection between them.
So, here I just wrote that l prime is just going to be
the cross product e prime and P prime.
But wait, we said, that there's a homography H.
Okay, that maps between P prime and P.
So I'm just going to substitute H times P for P prime.
Okay, no problem.
Then I'm going to use
something else you learned actually just last time all right.
We said that, a cross product can be written as this little matrix operator.
Right, right.okay great, so that says.
Let's erase that.
That l prime is just equal to this cross product operator on
e prime times H the hymography times p right, right.
But now, I said l prime is the epipolar line in the prime frame for the point P.
That's what this is.
Right? This is epipolar line for this point P.
All right?
Well.
We just learned that l prime is just Fp.
Right? F is the fundamental matrix times P.
We learned this, like, five slides ago.
That was the one that we repeat, repeated, like, 17 times.
Well.
Okay, l prime is equal to this nonsense over here on the left, and
it's equal to F P on the right.
That means that this nonsense on the left,
e prime cross product matrix times H, is equal to the F matrix.
Well, remembering a little bit from your linear algebra,
that means that the rank.
Of this thing, is going to be the rank of this thing.
And this, is rank two.
Told you this would come up before.
Remember I've said to you, and this was an exercise we left for the reader,
that this little cross product matrix operator where we took the A and
we distributed it amongst the three by three, multiplied it by B for A cross B.
I said one of the things that we're going to need later.
See I wasn't lying, is that the rank of that cross-product operator is two.
So that means, that the rank of F, which is just this matrix times H,
is also two.
F is not full rank.
But before when I was solving for
the elements of F, I didn't enforce that in any way.
It's a three by three.
And whether if you use the svd or whatever you do, it's not going to make it
become a, a two rank matrix even though it's a three by three.
So we have to fix our F to be a rank two matrix.
So, how do we do that?
Fortunately that's really pretty easy