But that ends the lesson on using Hough transforms to find circles.
That, along with the lines, is sort of the, sort of very old approach to
parameterized method methods of finding parameterized objects.
Even though it's old, it's,
it's a good way of learning about extracting structure from an image.
Remember, we go from pixels to things.
And that's actually why it's the first sort of serious problem set.
For those of you who are taking the online class, or
those of you who just want to try it.
And by the way, it's also one of the first problem sets I
give my on campus class.
Because they are not used to this idea of going from, sort of an image to a,
a data structure.
Next time, we're going to talk about,
something more general uses of Hough transforms.
Where your parameter is not based upon, analytical model,
like lines and circles.
But instead is based upon the shape of the objects that somebody gave you.
And we'll talk about how to do that and
also why that has developed a little bit of a resurgence in recent years.