Great, now that you know what
the tasks data looks like,
let's talk about how to access
that data through a provider.
To build a custom content provider,
the first step is to create a new
provider class that extends
from the abstract content provider
class that's part of the Android SDK.
And there's a link to this documentation
below, if you want to learn more.
For the to-do list app,
this is included in your starter code
as a class named Task Content Provider.
Extending from Android's
content provider class,
ensures that the Task Content Provider
will be recognized as a valid provider.
And that it will override all the
necessary methods for manipulating data.
Adding to this class,
you'll implement it's onCreate function,
which is called to initialize
the Task Content Provider.
The second step is to register this new
provider in the Android Manifest file.
Content providers need to be
registered similar to activities.
So that your app knows that
the provider exists and
knows how to refer to it by name and
authority.
You'll also need to define URIs that
identify the Task Content Provider and
the different data types
that it can return.
These are needed so that later on
a content resolver can find the provider
and the specific data you want to
access just based on a given URI.
Once you define these,
you'll then update the task
Contract Class to include URIs and
string constants that will help you
refer to the most commonly used URIs.
The last step in working with
URIs is to build a URIMatcher.
This is a class that helps
a content provider recognize and
respond correctly to
different types of URIs.
For example, it's often useful to use
this matcher to distinguish between URIs
that point to a large dataset,
like multiple rows of task data.
And URIs that point to a subset of that
data, like data for an individual task.
And we'll learn more
about this later on.
And finally,
in the Task Content Provider class,
you'll me implementing the required
CRUD methods to access and change data.
Methods like query and insert.
Now let's tackle the first step and
start coding.