One more little piece of technical detail which is easy and then we'll just show
you some examples and then we're going to go have a beer because it's Friday.
Remember, n is a function of the probability you want of success.
S, the size of the minimal set.
And e, e is the percentage of outliers.
But I don't know e, right?
If I knew which ones were wrong, right?
If the oracle of Delphi told me which ones were wrong I would of just thrown
those away to begin with, and just computed the thing that was right.
So if I don't know which ones are wrong I also probably therefore don't know
what percentage of them are wrong.
I could try to guess.
So here's what you can do.
You could say here it's just in words and then we'll do the algorithm.
You can guess say, okay, I don't know,
I'm going to assume that it's 50% are wrong.
Maybe even 80 but whatever it is I'm going to assume that some percent is wrong.
And I'm going to start computing some models.
If I start finding lots of models where
the inliers are much higher percentage than I guessed,
then I'm going to adapt my belief about the outliers to some smaller value.
So that's written here, as a, as an algorithm.
basically, I start off saying,
I'm going to assume that everything is an outlier and therefore,
I'm going to assume that I have to take an infinite number of samples.
So I'm going to be here all day or night, and weeks, and years, whatever.
But, not so bad.
The algorithm says, I start how many have I done so far?
Zero, I say as long as N is bigger than my current set of samp,
samples that I've tried I'm going to pick a sample and
I'm going to count the number of inliers.
And I'm going to guess that the percentage of outliers is
1 minus the percentage of the inliers that I've seen so far.
After all, this is just my first one, et cetera.
If that value is less than the value that I started with, and since I started
out believing that they're all outliers, I'm going to get some values smaller.
So if the new e is less than the one I had before, I set that value, and
I re-compute N.
So, first time around, N was at infinity, and then N gets lower.
And I keep doing this and what can happen is,
since I only change e if it's smaller, that means N can only get smaller.
So, eventually my samples, the number of samples that I've tried,
will get bigger than the N that I need.
And, when I do that, then I stop.
And that's a way of adapting when you don't know a priori,
the number of outliers that are there.
Something that I, I didn't mention before.
It's true if you have a real noise model in terms of how
the noise distribute from measurements, you can analytically set some threshold.
Dirty little secret, we almost never have a noise model.
Sometimes we do, but not too often.
Because we have a noise model from somebody else's censor center.
So you know what we do?
We end up adjusting it to see what works.
Now, not always, and certainly never in our papers.
But for real, sometimes you just have to make the thing work.