Many apps need to establish the user's
identity in order to customize an app to
the user's desires, to save their data,
allow them to identify themselves in
social circles, and
countless other scenarios.
There are many ways that you can allow
your users to identify themselves.
Such as implementing a sign
in functionality of your own,
where you manage your users and
their credentials.
Or, as is becoming
increasingly more common.
You can allow them to sign in using
their credentials from commonly used
platforms, such as Facebook,
Twitter, or Google.
To support this, we've built
the Google identity platform,
and the services it provides.
Including Google sign in for
Android, IOS and
the web, the Google identity toolkit and
the Chrome identity API which allows
users to sign into your Chrome apps.
As this is an Android course, we're
going to focus on the Google sign in
technology and you'll learn how to
integrate this into your mobile apps.