Now I want you to translate
the level synchronous breadth-first
search algorithm into
the language of matrices.
Consider some unvisited vertex, i.
As the BFS is running, there's some
frontier of vertices at level l.
You should ask yourself, self, is
there any edge from the frontier to I?
Because if so,
then I should update i's distance.
By the way, if you're actually
asking yourself this question,
you should be worried.
Only crazy people talk to themselves
about BFS late at night while sitting in
bed or otherwise staring at a screen.
Now remember, if there's any
edge from vertex j to vertex i,
then there'll be an entry of 1
in the adjacency matrix, a ji.
That is, think of it this way.
Consider a column i of A.
Also consider the frontier at level l.
Here I'm showing the frontier as
a boolean vector with 1 entries wherever
there's a vertex from the frontier.
Otherwise, assume an entry is zero or
blank.
The question was, is there any
frontier vertex that points to i?
That's the same as asking whether column
i has a 1 in its corresponding entries.
If that's the case,
then you might want to record this fact.
For instance, here's another boolean
vector, call it u for update.
You might mark position i
of this vector as true,
if any of these frontier entries
of column i are also true.
Now this check you've just done can
be written algebraically as follows.
You want to update i if any vertex j
is in the frontier and points to i.
This V is a logical or operator,
and this caret is a logical and.
I hope you recognize this scalar formula
as a boolean matrix vector product.
Now, being the crazy person who
talks to yourself that you are,
you might be saying, self, hold on now.
There might be n vertices to update and
up to n entries per vertex.
So does this thing cost
O(n squared) per level?
If you implement this correctly,
that won't be the case.
In particular, for a sparse graph,
meaning many of the entries are zero,
you can maintain both
the adjacency matrix and
the frontier vertices with
sparse data structures.
This makes this product a sparse
matrix times a sparse vector multiply.
If you feel so inclined, you should
head to the downloadable section and
read up on exactly how to do this.
If you implement this
operation as described there,
you can get a work optimal matrix
based implementation of BFS.
Now there's just one last detail,
which is, how to go from the update
vector to the updated distances.
From the update vector you can figure
out which entries are unvisited.
You would then update their distances
and put them into the frontier for
the next iteration.
Again, exploiting sparsity, this update
can be done in work proportional
only to the selected vertices.
Those notes in the downloadable
section explain how.