We're so close to being done.
Now we just need to use the URL
in the title to populate our UI.
For the image we need to create
some image data using the URL and
then use that data to create the UI
image like we saw in lesson zero.
So I'll create the url for the image and
then I'll create the image data
from the url, and then from the image
data, we can create our image.
For the title we can just
set the text directly.
But we have to remember that we
need to make these UIUpdatesOnMain.
So we can pull out our trust black box
called performUIUpdatesOnMain, and
we'll add our UI updates inside
the closure that we pass it.
And we'll also need to
remember to re-enable our UI,
if want to grab another image.
Let's build and run it.
Nice!
We did it.
This was quite a task to
get everything working.
And because the code you've written is
the crux of the rest of this class I
want to make sure that you've been
able to implement it yourself too.
So take some time and ensure that you're
selecting and displaying a random image
from the sleeping in the library
gallery and then check this box.