You may be asking yourself when should
I be using a service versus using
a loader?
The answer isn't always obvious,
but here are some guidelines.
If the background task is loading
information that will only be
used in the activity,
it's a good candidate for a loader.
Examples of this would be decoding
an image that was going to be
used in an image view.
Or crying a database that is going
to be used to populate a recycler
view adapter.
Some network transactions
even fall into this use case.
If your app is inherently real time,
you might want to just fetch data as you
need it in the UI rather than
cache the data in a database.
So when should a service be used?
When the task that you are doing is
decoupled from the user interface.
An example would be updating
a database in the background.
While the user interface needs to know
that this is happening, the operation
should continue, even if the application
doesn't have an active window.
In short, if you're loading or
processing data that will be
used in the UI, use a loader.
If you need to process upload or
download data in a way where the end
result will not directly affect the UI
such as caching data in database,
do it in a service.