now that we've learned a bit about the
importance of categorical variables
how about we go back to all tricks to
view how to actually analyze them what
we can use is the frequency tool with
our cleanup data to take a look at our
target field churn since it is a
categorical variable first thing we
should do
just grab that cleaned up data set to
use an input data tool to go grab it to
drop down menu and go to turn data
cleaned the next thing i want to do is
go to my back to my data investigation
category and grab this frequency table
tool inside of this we can ask to get a
frequency result from all of our
different categorical of string
variables
what I'm going to choose is just that
one turn field and then going to bring
in a browse after our interactive output
then hit run to run this analysis one of
the first things i want to know about my
different categorical variables is how
many unique groups it has within it
in this case since this term field is a
binary field it's a true or false
clearly we have two different unique
options true and false then the next
thing I look for is that frequency and
percentage of my different categories
within this variable
the next thing I look for is the
frequency in the percentage of our
different categories within this
individual variable and it definitely
looks that we have way more false values
that are true values it seems that we
actually have about eighty six percent
false values and about fourteen percent
true values and if we go to the
frequency were able to see that we have
4,200 false values and 700 true values
what i get from this result is that
since there are so many more false
values and true values
it may actually be difficult to predict
just a few number of records if this is
something that does seem actually
logical in the large scheme of things
more customers are going to stay with
their cell phone carrier then actually
turn over and go to another carrier but
what I wanted to show you is how you
actually analyze your different
categorical variables within all tracks
and hopefully you're able to see how
easy it is to perform this analysis by
simply just bringing in a free
can see table tool