The goal of testing at this stage is
to get users to actually use your app.
And if you can, sit near them as
you do it so you can watch for
any opportunities where they might
not know where to go next, or
if they get lost, or,
most importantly, if the app crashes.
Because if the app does crash, you'll
want the user to walk through exactly
what they did so
that you can fix it later.
If your testers are iOS developers, you
can just zip up your Xcode project and
share it with them for testing.
If they're not, your best
option is actually probably for
them to interact with your app using
the simulator, so that you can sit and
look over their shoulder.
However, you also have the option,
if you have an Apple Developer account,
to share the app with someone's
iOS device, an iPhone or an iPad.
Instructions for doing so are included
in the downloadable section below.
So now, you're ready.
Go forth.
Share your app with at
least three people, one of them being
with your classmates on the forum.