And the answer is that any plan that would work
in the deterministic world might work in the stochastic world
if everything works out okay
and all of these plans meet that criteria.
But no finite plan is guaranteed to always work
because a successful plan has to include at least 1 move action.
And if we try a move action a finite number of times,
each of those times, the wheels might slip, and it won't move,
and so we can never be guaranteed to achieve the goal
with a finite sequence of actions.
Now, what about an infinite sequence of actions?
Well, we can't represent that in the language we have so far
where a plan is a linear sequence.
But we can introduce a new notion of plans
in which we do have infinite sequences.