We've seen what search can do for problem solving.
It can find the lowest-cost path to a goal,
and it can do that in a way in which we never generate more paths than we have to.
We can find the optimal number of paths to generate,
and we can do that with a heuristic function that we generate on our own
by relaxing the existing problem definition.
But let's be clear on what search can't do.
All the solutions that we have found consist of a fixed sequence of actions.
In other words, the agent Hirin Arad, thinks, comes up with a plan that it wants to execute
and then essentially closes his eyes and starts driving,
never considering along the way if something has gone wrong.
That works fine for this type of problem,
but it only works when we satisfy the following conditions.
[Problem solving works when:]
Problem-solving technology works when the following set of conditions is true:
First, the domain must be fully observable.
In other words, we must be able to see what initial state we start out with.
Second, the domain must be known.
That is, we have to know the set of available actions to us.
Third, the domain must be discrete.
There must be a finite number of actions to chose from.
Fourth, the domain must be deterministic.
We have to know the result of taking an action.
Finally, the domain must be static.
There must be nothing else in the world that can change the world except our own actions.
If all these conditions are true, then we can search for a plan
which solves the problem and is guaranteed to work.
In later units, we will see what to do if any of these conditions fail to hold.