Let's dive into common field types
that we'll find in data, and
get to know them a little bit better.
Generally, they can be
put into five categories.
Strings, numeric data, date/time,
boolean, and special objects.
Strings are any kind of characters,
alpha numeric, including symbols.
Some examples can be an address field,
a state code, an open-ended survey
response, or a product description.
Numeric data are numbers which can be
whole numbers, such as integers, or
numbers with decimal places.
Some examples are sales and
dollars, population in a trade area
around a store, or an age of a person.
Date/time type data can
contain a specific date, or
a combination of both date and time.
This data can really be handy for
calculating the number of minutes
before a caller reporting a problem and
its resolution.
The boolean type is sometimes
also called a logical type and
is a conditional flag representing
either true or false.
And then there are special objects,
which can be objects such as images,
maps, report objects, and
sound files, to name a few examples.