Welcome to Graduate Introduction to Operating Systems.
My name is Ada Gavrilovska, and I will be your instructor for this course.
I've been a research faculty at Georgia Tech since 2004 when I
finished my PhD here.
And in these years, I've been involved in and led a number of research projects
in the area of systems that specialize on topics related to operating systems,
virtualization, or other aspects of system software.
In these years, I've also taught a number of times at Georgia Tech.
This particular class, I've taught it over a dozen times, and over the years,
we've evolved it to update it to reflect any changes in technology or
any changes in the student interest or the student population in general.
I've also been teaching the advanced operating systems class and
the special topics class in high performance communication.
For additional information about me, you can look at my website, and
the link is provided off of the instructor notes.