You have time for a quick story?
Okay, sure.
Anybody here ever use Photoshop?
Raise your hand.
In the older Photoshop or
even currently, they have something called the unsharp mask.
Okay?
And when you apply the unsharp mask, what does it do?
It makes it sharper.
Now you might ask,
why would you call an unsharp mask something that makes it sharper?
Don't ask.
Okay.
In the old days, like when you did things in a darkroom,
you were playing with light and you, chemicals, etc.
But you still actually able to add and subtract light.
So those of you have ever seen film knows that film were made out of
negatives, right?
And so that where it was dark, it would let out hardly any light and
where it was light it would let a lot and
then the, it would reflect on, it would be projected onto paper.
And then whenever a lot of light hit the paper, it would become black and
that's why you had to make it be a negative.
Some very clever photographer figured out the following.
Let's suppose I take a negative and then I put a piece of
wax paper over it and I put another piece of film underneath that.
Okay?
And I turn on the light for just a split [SOUND] second.
I will get a blurry negative of the original negative.
Okay?
Right? Because it, it becomes a negative, it's a piece of film, so
I, I put the, the good negative, the sharp negative piece of wax paper and
then another negative and there are other ways of making it.
But the idea is that I would get a blurry negative of the negative, okay?
So if the negative were all white, this negative would now become all black.
All right?
It was the negative value.
Then what you could do is you'd develop that film, et cetera.
You could put that blurry negative of the negative in
with the original film and expose it at one shot.
And the math that was being done was exactly this math.
We had our original and because it's a negative of it,
we're subtracting off a slightly blurry version of the picture and
that would give you a sharper picture.
So that's how you did image processing with chemicals and
film to make a sharper picture.
And what do you think that extra negative that you made, okay?
That was blurrier was called, it was less sharp.
It was the unsharp mask and it would be added to the original picture.
And the unsharp mask would yield for you sharper picture.
So now you learned something totally irrelevant,
because you probably haven't even seen a piece of film.
But it is why in software today, unsharp masks make pictures sharper.
And now you actually know why, why the math works.
Right? You're essentially subtracting off a slightly blurry version of
the image.