Now that we have some example
of different objectives for
segmenting retail stores, let's think
about other data that could be of value,
depending on your segmentation purpose.
For data related to competition,
I mention the number of nearby
competitors and distance, as examples.
But additional data such
as their store type and
hours, may provide added insight.
The actual sales information tied
to each store that would come from
the transaction systems
within the company,
could be a logical set of data to use.
But you might also want to have
access to the history and results for
many promotional programs that
have been used in the past.
In order to understand the shoppers that
actually walk in to each store, some
companies can provide rather detailed
data about their regular shopper,
through a loyalty or rewards card
program that they may have in place.
But if that's not available,
we may want to
have access to the general census
data for the area around the store.
This would provide some data about the
market size, for example population and
number of households in the area,
but also give us some more detailed
demographics related to income,
ethnicity, age, and other variables.
Because buying behavior is generally
correlated to demographic categories,
having this is usually
valuable in a retail setting.
Also helpful could be any
information that we could get
around what life stage and social groups
are geographically close to the store.
These could include already segment
categories like married with children,
or fresh out of school singles,
as examples.
The point here is to think through
the business purpose for creating
the segments, and then find the data
that relates most to that objective.