Let's now apply the resampling where the on-lane-marker particles are being resampled for probability 0.2963,
and the ones in the middle with probability 0.037.
Let's draw with replacement 6 new particles.
A typical outcome will be we draw this one over here twice,
this one down here twice, and this one over here once.
Perhaps we draw once over here.
Clearly we draw the particles that sit on the lane markings much more frequently
than the ones that sit off the lane markings for a total of 6 new particles.
We now apply our resampling method whereby we draw twice from this particle over here.
That might give us something over there and over here, given that we add a small amount of noise.
The guy over here will be resampled to something over there.
Same with this guy over here, and this guy might find itself over here.
The set over here of 6 particles in total, will now be the new posterior.
As you can see, this posterior is more consistent with the lane marking observation
than the one of not being on a lane marking by virtue of the fact that
we saw a bright measurement before.
Now we just repeat. We look at the next measurement. We weight particles accordingly.
We resample. We do forward prediction.
That's the basic particle filter algorithm.4
Look at measurment, compute weights, sample, and predict
where the prediction has a certain amount randomness.
If you get that loop implemented, you've implemented an amazing algorithm
that's exactly what has driven many of my robots in the ability to localize themselves.
Obviously they have more than just 1 pixel sensor that measures bright and dark.
They might take an entire road image and use the road image to complete the measurement probability,
but the basic mechanics is exactly the same as shown over here.
So let me ask you, did you actually understand this. Yes or no?