In this lesson,
we will talk about distributed
shared memory systems for DSMs.
These are an an example of
applications that perform certain
distributed state management operations.
Now, in this lesson,
a lot of what we will talk about will
be in the context of memory management.
Still the methods that we
will discuss will apply to
other types of distributed applications.
Specifically, we will present
certain design alternatives,
with respect to DSM systems.
And we will discuss the trade offs that
are associated with those decisions.
In addition, we will discuss several
important consistency models
that are commonly used in systems that
manage distributed and shared state