Now that we described
the possible DSM architecture,
I'd like to comment on its
possible implementation.
One thing to consider when implementing
a distributed shared memory system
is that the distributed shared
memory layer has to intercept
every single access
to that shared state.
This is needed in order to detect
whether the access is local or
remote and then trigger remote messages
requesting access, if that's necessary.
Or to detect that somebody is
performing an update operation to
a locally controlled portion of
the distributed shared memory and
then to trigger any necessary
coherence messages.
These overheads should be avoided
whenever we're trying to just
access local, non-shared pages,
or non-shared state.
So what we would like to achieve is an
implementation where it is possible to
dynamically engage whether
the distributed shared memory layer
will be triggered, and will be
intercepting any accesses to memory
in order to determine
what to do about them.
Or disengage the distributed
shared memory layer
if we are performing access to pages
which are really not shared and
are just local pages accessed
on a particular node.
To achieve this, a DSM implementation
can leverage the hardware support that's
available at the memory
management unit level.
As we explained earlier, if the hardware
MMU doesn't find the valid mapping for
a particular virtual
address in the page table,
it will trap into the operating system.
And similarly, the hardware will also
cause a trap if it's detected that
there is an attempt to modify
a page that has been protected for
a write operation, so
a write protected page.
We can leverage this mechanism
to implement the DSM system.
Whenever we need to perform an access
to a remote memory, there will not be
a valid mapping from the local virtual
address to the remote physical address.
The hardware will generate
a trap in that case.
And at that point, the operating system
will detect what is the reason for
that trap will pass that page
information to the DSM layer, and
the DSM layer will send the message.
Similarly, whenever content is
cached in a particular node,
the DSM layer will ensure that
that content is write protected.
And that will cause a trap if anybody
tries to modify that content that will
turn control over to
the operating system.
The operating system can pass relevant
information to the DSM module.
And then that one will trigger all of
the necessary coherence operations.
When implementing a DSM system,
it is also useful perhaps to leverage
additional information that's also
maintained by the existing memory
management that the operating system and
the underlying hardware provide.
For instance, we can track information,
like whether our page is dirty.
We can track information whether
our page has been accessed in
the first place.
And this can let us implement
different coherence mechanisms and
consistency policies.
For an object-based distributed shared
memory system that's implemented at
the level of the programming language
run time, the implementation can
consider similar types of mechanisms
that leverage the underlying
operating systems services or as
an alternative, everything can be done
completely in software with
support from the compilers,
so tracking whatever particular
object reference is remote or local.
Or whether an object is going to be
modified or not, we can make sure that
we generate code that will perform those
checks on every single object reference.