This article explains how you can
support multiple languages in an app.
Scrolling down we can look
at the project structure.
Within the res directory,
you can add another subdirectory
that contains resources for
a certain language.
This is the default values folder,
and we're choosing to put all
the English text strings here.
In the values-es folder,
we have all the Spanish text strings.
In the values-fr folder,
we have all the French translations.
If the user chooses Spanish as
the language on their device,
then the system will load these
resources from the values-es folder.
If this folder didn't exist,
then the system would just fall
back to the default resources.
If the user has French as the default
language on their device,
then the system will
load these resources.
By the way, es is the language code for
Spanish, and fr is the language code for
French.
Android uses the ISO language codes.
Here are some examples of languages and
the two-letter language codes
that correspond with them.
Let's go back to implementation details.
In order for this system to switch out
different translations for the text in
our app, we need to isolate all the text
from all the other logic in our app.
We do this by creating a strings.xml
file in the values folder.
This is an XML resource file
that contains a list of
all the string resources that
are visible to the user.
This is the first time we're
seeing XML be used for
something other than defining a layout,
this is defining a list of resources.
This is one string resource, and
the name that we used to refer to it is
called title, and the value of
this string is My Application.
This is another string resource, and
we refer to it using hello_world,
and the actual value is Hello World.
Then, in the values-es folder we
can create a strings.xml file,
but now these have the Spanish
translations of those same strings.
This string resource still goes by
the name of title, like here, but
now the value is the Spanish
translation of My Application.
The same applies for
the Hello World string resource with
the Spanish translation here now.
And this is one more example
of the French translations of
the strings.xml file.
Once our strings
are declared as resources,
we can then refer to them in the XML or
Java using the appropriate syntax.
In the Java code,
we refer to strings like this.
In the Java code, this is how
we reference string resources.
First, we call the method getResources
to get the app's resources, and
then we call getString and we pass as
input the resource ID of the string.
In this case it's r.string.hello_world.
String is the resource type and
hello_world is the name of the resource.
All of this on the right-hand side ends
up becoming the hello_world string, and
is stored in this string variable.
This whole expression
evaluates to hello_world and
gets stored in this variable.
By the way, this is similar to how we
refer to image resources in the Java
code using r.drawable.photo, or
whatever the name of the image is.
In the XML we can refer to the strings
using the add string notation and
then the name of the string resource.
Now the XML and
the Java code can stay the same
regardless of what language the user
has chosen on their device.
We don't need a different layout file
that has the Spanish translation for
the text attribute here.
Android will load the correct
translations depending on the primary
language selected on the device.
It's pretty awesome, huh?