Before we answer the question,
let me remind you,
that a server driven mechanism means
that it is the server that will push
any invalidations to the clients.
And also, that session-semantics
means that any changes made to a file
will become visible when the file is
closed, when the session is closed, and
when a subsequent client opens
that file, starts a new session.
So that means that it is possible for
overlapping seasons to see different
versions of the file, so it is
possible to have concurrent writers.
Session semantics doesn't specify
what will happen to the file when
all of these writers close that file.
Whether one of the versions
will become the valid one, or
whether they will be merged
in some ways, or whether some
error will be raised back to the client
so that they can resolve the conflicts.
So given this information, the items
that make sense to be part of a per file
data structure in this kind
of distributed file system
will include information about what
are the current readers of the system.
Also, what are all of
the current concurrent writers,
potentially multiple, not just one.
And also, it makes sense to keep track
of something like a version number so
that the clients know which
version were they given, and
the server also understands which
clients have been modifying an old
version of the file
versus the newest one.