Before we can crunch any numbers and
make a predictive model, we need to
plot our data in order to get a feel for
what our time series looks like.
A time series plot shows a graphical
presentation of the relationship
between time and
the time series target variable.
Time is on the horizontal axis and
the target variable's values
are shown on the vertical axis.
The first plot shows the complete
Bates Hotel time series.
We can see that the series shows
a general trend up and to the right.
We call that an upward trend.
Lastly, our bookings plot
shows two main patterns.
First, we see the upward trend.
Secondly, we see some regularly
occurring fluctuations up and
down within the same calendar year.
We called that a seasonal pattern.
Plotting out the time series allows
us to visualize these patterns and
behaviors.
We can then used our findings in
the time series plot to create and
fine-tune sophisticated
forecasting models.