Okay so now that we have
Google App Engine installed,
let's run a tutorial just to get
a hang of using the program.
So back in the window we were in,
we'll click on Python and
then you will see Python tutorial and
then you will scroll down a little and
you will see Hello, World.
We'll click on that and
we'll see some steps from Google,
on how to run this tutorial.
So first it says to create
a directory called Hello, World.
We can go to our desktop and
create a new folder.
And let's call it helloworld.
Okay, so now that we have a folder
created, we can move onto the next step.
So it says, that we want to create
a file called helloworld.pi and
give it the following contents.
So let's select this, copy it,
and then we can paste it here.
You'll notice that this is still
formatted as a plain text file, so
we can go to file, save as, And
we want to choose the folder
that we created on our desktop.
And it says to name the file
helloworld.pi so we'll do that now.
Okay, so now you can see the file
is reformatted as a python file.
Seen here.
And now let's move on to the next steps.
Okay, so
now we have to create a .yaml file.
So again, we'll copy this text.
Copy it.
And then paste it in our sub line.
Once again,we'll save as and
then this time we'll call it app.yaml.
Great, so now that we have this on our
computer, we're ready for the next step.