We've been trying to
emphasize algorithms that
are of a particular importance.
>> A star and alpha-beta pruning on
the minimax algorithm are some examples.
>> Now we're going to introduce another
key concept, simulated annealing.
>> Hold on, simulated annealing?
That implies that there's
real annealing too.
>> That's right, we're going to steal
some ideas from the physicists for
this section.
First let's talk about
energy minimization.
External conditions allow
molecules to be mobile and
then mobility of
the molecules slowly reduces.
The molecules then arrange themselves
into the lowest energy configuration.
Often these conditions
result in regular patterns.
>> You mean like mud cracks?
>> Yep, that's a common example
with the decreasing amount of
water in the mud reduces
the molecules and
mobility over time the mud
cracks into regular patterns.
>> And
we see similar structures in honeycombs.
Honeybees try to optimize
their storage space and
minimize the building materials for
the structure that they're building.
>> That's an example of
minimization done by design.
But the same affect can happen on the
Earth, as erupted lava slowly cools and
rocks form.
Here's an example of columnar basalts,
from the Devils Postpile in California.
As the rock cools, it shrinks and
cracks in a hexagonal lattice,
which is a minimal energy configuration.
>> Iron molecules have similar low
energy states into which they can pack.
They can form a lattice with
other molecules like carbon.
Some of these lattices are harder or
softer than others.
For certain applications like sword
making, a mixture of hardness and
ductility is needed.
>> Sword makers realize the need to
heat and cool iron repeatedly to get
iron molecules to align in desired
lattistructures to make swords hard but
not brittle.
They heated the iron above
the temperature where atoms could move
about, and formed new structures
with carbon and other atoms.
Then they cooled the iron,
to preserve the types of
lattice structures they wanted.
This kneeling process was repeated
according to closely guarded formulas
and times to get the desired properties.
The best steel makers were treasured.
>> Looking at the edge of the blade
of a finely made sword or
cooking knife, shows the process
of heating and recrystallization.
But how does the kneeling
help our problem?
>> We are going to use the idea
of heating and cooling
to help us get out of a local minima,
on the way to finding a global minimum.
For us, high temperature equates to
more randomness, and gradual cooling
will decrease the randomness
until we converge on a solution.