Now it's your turn.
Add a shared element into the transition
between the main activity and
the detail view.
First, create a string for
the transition name and
add it to the detail icon
in detail today grid.
Then, add a unique transition name to
each icon view in ForecastAdapter.
You'll want this to be
the same across runs.
So I recommend using the position within
the adapter to make the name unique.
Add the view holder to the on
item selected callback,
then add a pair to the make scene
transition animation and mainActivity,
and call support and
postpone enter transition.
And support stark postpone
enter transition appropriately.
As I mentioned before, I used
an attribute in the forecast fragment
to determine whether I should start
postponed animations, an argument for
the detail fragment.
For recycler view in
the forecast fragment,
I recommend waiting until it
has laid out its children,
which we already do in the on predraw
listener we add during onload finished.
In the detail fragment,
during onload finished is fine.