One way to classify AI problems is
using properties of the environment and
components of state that
need to be captured.
>> An environment can be fully
observable like Tic-Tac-Toe
where you can see the entire board.
Or could be partially
observable like in Battleship
where you can't see your
opponents ship positions.
>> An environment can be
deterministic where you know for
sure the results of each action.
Or stochastic where
there is uncertainty.
>> An environment can be discreet when
there's a finite number of states
that the environment can be in.
Or can be continuous where the number
of possible states is infinite
typically due to some properties that
need to be stored as real numbers.
>> An environment could be benign where
the agent is the only one taking actions
that intentionally affect its goal,
there could be other
random events going on.
Or adversarial where there are one or
more other agents that can take
actions to defeat its goal.
Such environments are commonly
found in competitive games.
>> Now for
each of the problem listed below,
can you mark the appropriate
characteristics?