I'll show you how to write
the max_employment function first, and
then I'll go over the output you should
have seen from the provided test code.
I'm going to show running all
the code in an iPython notebook.
To write the code I started off with
the maximum employment value as 0 and
the corresponding country as None.
Next, I looped through each
element of the two NumPy arrays.
Since the two arrays should have the
same length, I could use either line of
countries or line of employment here,
it wouldn't make a difference.
Next I checked whether the employment
data from that country was greater than
the maximum employment I had seen so
far.
If so,
I updated both the maximum country and
the maximum employment value.
Finally I returned the two values.
Now this piece of code doesn't look any
different from what I would have written
if I were using lists
instead of NumPy arrays.
That's a great technique
to fall back on.
If you can't find a specific NumPy
function to do what you want,
you can always write code
treating them just like lists.
However, in this case, there's also
an easier way to solve this using NumPy.
I didn't expect you to know that, but
I'm going to show you how it works.
You may have realized you can use
NumPy's max function to find the maximum
employment value.
But that wouldn't give you
the corresponding country name.
NumPy also has a function called argmax
and instead of the maximum value,
it returns the position where
the maximum value occurs.
I'll name that position i,
then I can get both the country and
the employment value by
using that position.
Now I'll go through the test code.
The first line imported
the NumPy library.
The next line creates a NumPy
array of the first 20 countries we
have employment data for.
One of the easiest ways to create
a NumPy array is the way I did it here.
First you create a python list and
then you call np.array
with that list as an argument which
converts it to a NumPy array.
The next line uses the same technique
to create an NumPy array of employment
rates in 2007.
Next you should have seen that this
line printed the country at position 0,
changing the 0 to a 3 prints
the country at position 3.
The next few lines each
print a slice of the array.
This one prints everything from position
0 up to but not including position 3.
In this line,
I've left the first number out, so
the slice starts at the beginning of
the array, which gives the same results.
Here I've left the second number out, so
the slice goes from position 17 all
the way to the end of the array.
And finally I can actually
leave both numbers off
in which case I get the entire array
from the beginning to the end.
There's not really a good reason to
do this since you could just use
the original array, but
it makes the notation consistent.
Now I'll look at the element
type of a few arrays.
Which NumPy calls the dtype.
I can see that the country
array has type S22.
S stands for string, and
22 means that the length of the longest
string in the array is 22 characters.
The employment array has type float64.
That means the employment values
are floating point values.
That is, they have a decimal point.
And they're being stored using 64 bits.
The next four arrays contain integers,
floating point values, booleans and
strings of length two.
When I loop over the countries array,
I see that each country gets
printed out one at a time.
And I can use this type of loop to
go over pairs of values from two
different arrays.
Here i is the position in each array and
then I get the country at that position
and the employment
value at that position.
Finally I just print both values out.
If you haven't seen Python's
string format function before,
it finds each occurrence
of these  and
then replaces them with the arguments
of the format function.
When I run this I see each country
printed out with its corresponding
employment value.
And finally, these functions give the
mean, standard deviation, maximum and
sum of the employment data.