Now let's suppose you want to create
a different animation with the second
hand, like having it spin in reverse.
To do that, we can click on
the name of the current animation
in the top left of the Animation window.
That will open up a drop-down menu
where we can click Create New Clip.
Let's do that and
call it ReverseSecondsRotation.
Just like before,
we'll have an empty timeline.
Let's go ahead and quickly create a
reverse animation with the curve's view.
First, add the rotation property,
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Set the first keyframe to start
at 360 degrees in the Z rotation.
Now, make sure the last keyframe
is set to zero in the Z rotation.
And just like that, we have our
seconds hand rotating in reverse.
Next up, we'll look at how
to use various animations