So if we're playing poker, that would
be partially observable, I think,
because you can see your own hand, but
you can't see your opponents' hands.
>> That's true.
>> It would be stochastic,
because you don't know what cards
are going to be dealt and when.
It would be discrete,
because there are only a theoretically
finite number of hands, although
the number of hands is very, very large.
And it would definitely be adversarial.
You're trying to win,
your opponent is trying to win, and
only one of the two of
you can generally win.
>> Hm, that's true.
Well, recognizing handwritten
text is a pretty hard problem.
Well, let's see.
Is it partially observable?
Not really, you can,
when given a sample of handwritten text,
you can see the whole thing.
Is it stochastic?
I am going to say, yes, because
the patterns that are generated by
human hands can vary a lot, and there
might be a lot of randomness in there.
What about continuous?
One way to think about it is
how many different dates or
conditions the environment could be in.
In this case, if the environment or
the inputs that need to be represented
are the image pixels, then there
are a lot of different possibilities.
Although those possibilities
are actually finite in number,
the underlying representation,
the underlying thing that's
creating them is continuous.
Not really adversarial,
it's not really a game, and
we're not competing against anyone.
>> No.
For driving on the road, for
something like a self-driving car,
that's an interesting question.
It can certainly see a lot
about its enviroment, but
it can't see it's entire environment.
It can't, for example, see whether
there's a car is coming around the next
corner or anything, even though that
already exists in the environment.
So I would say it's partially
observable, not completely observable.
Whether or not it's stochastic or
deterministic could be a pretty deep
philosophical problem about whether or
not humans themselves are deterministic.
But I'll say for
the purpose of the autonomous vehicle,
it's definitely a stochastic problem.
There are definitely things
it can't anticipate or
can't predict even with all
the information in the world.
It's definitely a continuous problem,
just because of the nature
of real-world information.
And I'm going to say
it's not adversarial,
although if you've ever seen me drive,
you might disagree about whether or
not driving is an adversarial problem.
>> [LAUGH]
>> Okay,
so the last one we
have is playing chess.
It's definitely not
partially observable.
It's just like tic-tac-toe,
where you can see the entire board.
And it's also not stochastic,
because when you make a move, you know
exactly what the result would be.
And since there are only a finite
number of states, again, a huge
number of states but still finite,
I would say it's not continuous either.
Lastly, it is adversarial, because
you're playing against an opponent.