So far, we've added a tracking code for
when users view products and
add them to the cart.
The next step is to
check checkout actions.
You'll be adding a Start Checkout
button to the Order Dinner screen.
You'll need to add
the button in a layout file.
And there's no point checking out
until you've put a dinner in the cart.
So start with the button
being invisible.
In the Order Dinner Activity, add a
method to start the checkout process and
to send the checkout hit to Analytics.
And for now, we're going to assume
that the cart contains only and
exactly the currently selected dinner.
As before we're going to
gloss over the implementation
actually doing the checkout
with a wave of our hands.
And put our attention into implementing
the code to send the hit to Analytics.
You'll also need to update
the addDinnerToCart method
to hide the Add to Cart button and
show the Start Checkout button.
So when the user goes to
the order online screen,
they add the dinner to the cart,
and then they can start checkout.