Let's see first which options
we can eliminate quickly.
NFS definitely allows for
files to be modified, so
immutable is not one of
the correct answers.
And also being a distributed system and
if this doesn't meet guarantees that
an update for a file will immediately
be visible, so it's not Unix.
Now we said that in principle,
NFS tries to make session semantics in
that the updates made to a file will
be flushed back to the server
when the file is closed.
And also when a client
performs an open operation,
the client can check with the server to
see whether the file has been updated.
And in that case, the client will
also update the cached value.
The problem is however, that NFS
can be configured to periodically
have client and
server interactions that check for
any intermediate updates to
our file during a session.
Now how frequently this is done
can be configured and in fact,
it can be completely disabled.
So, in that case, NFS will always
behave like with session semantics.
However, given that this option for
periodic updates exists.
It is not quite a session semantics.
At the same time, it's not purely
periodic file sharing semantics,
because we will still have changes in
the file propagate and file close.
Or on file open,
just as what happens with
a session-based file sharing semantics.
So for both session and periodic,
yes, perhaps there are elements of
the sharing semantics that NFS supports
that are session like or periodic like.
And whether it will behave like
with session or periodic semantics,
it will really depend on
how NFS is configured.
That leaves that by default
NFS is really neither.
It is not purely session-based
file sharing semantics
distributed file system.
And also, it doesn't purely support
just periodic file sharing semantics.