At this point our app is successfully
observing when messages are added to
the database.
And we're appending any new
messages to this messages array.
But to actually display
the messages to the user,
we need to implement some
table view functions.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
If we scroll down a bit we can see some
stubs for table view functions, or
we can jump to them here
in the navigation bar.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
For the number of rows in a section,
that's already set to the count of
messages in our messages array.
That looks good.
The next function self a row
at indexPath needs some work.
Right now, it's returning a blank cell.
To fix this, we need to configure the
cell to display the data for a message.
First we should access a message
from the messages array by choosing
the message which corresponds
to the indexPath's row.
The messages array is
an array of FIRDataSnapshots.
So we need to convert a single message
snapshot into something that gives us
access to the message's text and the
display name of the user who sent it.
We can do this by converting the data
Snapshot into a dictionary that match
string keys to string values.
If you're a call,
this is the same format that we
used when saving the messages.
Now to complete the function, let's
create variables to hold the values for
the messages text and
the user's display name.
Then I can set the cells labels
text consist of those values.
And also set the cells image
equal to the placeholder image.
All right, that should be it.
We just need to return the cell.
Let's run this and see what happens.
Sweet, there are messages.