You can open up the developer tools
by going to this hamburger menu here,
and going down to More tools and
then Developer Tools.
Personally I'm a fan of actually
hitting Cmd+Alt+J on a Mac,
although it's slightly
different on other platforms.
But it brings that up straight away,
without having to do anything else.
Now we're in DevTools,
we need to go to the Timeline Tool,
which is right up here.
Timeline is here to allow you to track
frames per second for your project.
You can record a timeline and it will
tell you what frames per second you were
getting and for each frame,
what work was involved.
That work will tie back into the
pipeline you learned in the last lesson.
Now I'm going to hit record which
is up here in the top corner.
And then I'm going to
scroll around the site.
Now I can stop the recording and
I get a load of records back.
At first glance I think the user
interface can be a little bit over
whelming, so
let's just look at it bit by bit.
The bars at the top indicate
the frames per second,
there's this 60 frames a second line,
and a 30 frames a second line.
If we're trying to hit
60 frames a second,
all these bars should
be below that line.
Now, we're pretty close
to the line here, but
overall, we're doing pretty well.
Underneath, there's a load of
information about how we spent our time
in each of the frames.
Right now it's quite zoomed out so
we need to actually dive
in a little bit deeper.
To do that we simply click drag in
the frames area at the top, and
now you see it's zoomed
in a little bit more.
You can also use the W, A, S, and
D keys on your keyboard if you prefer.
Here in the details you can see
the parts of the pipeline we
discussed earlier.
There's JavaScript,
there's Style Calculations,
Layout, Layer Management,
Paint, and Composite.
If you've never taken
a timeline recording before,
I'm going to give you a chance to pause
this video in a moment so you can go and
take your first recording.
Go to any website, it doesn't matter
which, and hit record in the timeline.
Then explore the timeline and
see what you can find out.
Ready?
Pause!
Okay, cool.
You're able to take timeline recordings,
and
you can quickly see
where your hitting jank.
But now you need to start digging
into the details of those frames, and
figure out why frames are running long.