All right, welcome back to Computer Vision.
So let's see, so we did the images as functions for a little bit, and
started talking about edges.
And then we took a little bit of a detour where we talked about Hough
transform in terms of extracting information using those images as evidence.
So now it's time to get back just a little bit to image processing.
And this lesson, and one more, or maybe two more beyond this.
We're going to be talking about what's called frequency analysis.
Now in the old days, that is, and that's actually pretty old already.
Now we're talking 40 years ago, 30, 40 years ago.
All of you who would be working on images,
you would have actually been electrical engineers, and
you would have spent a lot of your time studying this stuff that we're
going to be talking about extensively.
You define your filters and other types of image analysis operation in terms of
what's called frequency response.
That is, how things change when you have high frequency stuff, and
then low frequency stuff.
But most of you are much more oriented to computer science,
where we tend to think of images as data structures and not so much as a signal.
But some of this understanding is still critical.
This is especially true for a phenomena referred to as aliasing.
I know many of you are familiar with aliasing in a sort of image perspective
where you see the little jaggies, because you've got a line that doesn't go
perfectly straight, but it's actually a frequency phenomenon, and in fact,
the goal of this lesson and the next few, is to
get to a point where you can talk about aliasing from a frequency perspective.
And, it'll teach you why, if, for example, if you have an image and
you want to make it half the size, you shouldn't just throw out every row,
every other row, and every other column.
That's the wrong thing to do.
And, by the time we're done with this,
you'll, you'll see sort of why that's the case.