Now that we know that we can use
a bullion to represent the check state
of this check box,
let's modify the order summary so
that it reflects whether or
not we want the whipped cream topping.
If I say that I want the whipped cream
topping and then I click on the order
button, then it should add a line to
the order summary that says whether or
not I want that topping.
It says true if I check
the box to add the topping.
And if I uncheck the box and
click on order then it should say false.
Android already handles checking this
box and we already have code in our app
to handle clicking on the order button
to create an initial order summary.
The part that's left for us to implement
is adding this line of text here
that says add whipped cream and
we need to put in the right value based
on whether this box is checked or not.
Before we start diving into the code,
let's think about the pseudo code first
to help solidify the main ideas
of what we want our code to do.
When the order button is clicked,
we should do these steps.
The first step is to get the checked
state from check box, and
then store it in a variable.
So, that's this checked state.
Once the Android device
knows if this is checked or
not, then we can pass this information
into the order summary method,
the method that creates this text.
As the third step, we can change
this text to include this line here
about whether the whipped cream
topping should be added or not.
There are a couple of
steps along the way.
To make sure that you're on the right
path, you can actually log this
variable value here to make sure that
it reflects the actual checked state.
We introduced logging earlier, but
here's another example for you.
You can write log.v, and then use the
class name, which is MainActivity, and
then put in a string message that
you want to print out to the logs.
By printing out the price here,
we're verifying that after step one,
the calculatePrice method does
return the expected price.
When you run the app on your device,
you should be able to check the logs
with this tab to see this message.
I use the technique of logging messages
often when there's a problem and
I'm not sure which line
of code has the problem.
And then after I figure out the problem,
and everything works as expected,
then I just delete the log message.
So, temporarily,
if you want to add a log message to
print out the checked state, you can.
The reason why I delete log messages
after I don't need them anymore,
is because the log is a limited length.
If you fill it with a bunch
of unnecessary messages,
then it will cause the important
messages and errors to disappear sooner.
Once the checked state information
is showing up in the order summary
on the device, they you really don't
need the log messages anymore.
When you're done,
check this box to continue.