To bring data from a database in Altrex,
simply click on the Input Data Tool and
drop it onto the canvas.
Next we click over to
the Configuration Window.
And then to the drop down arrow and
choose Database Connection.
You'll need to know the proper way to
connect to your database, whether it
be an all ADB driver, an all DBC driver,
or a direct connection to Oracle.
In this example,
we're going to connect to SQL
server using an all ADB connection.
The first thing I do is
select the all ADB driver for
SQL server, and
then I enter the server name.
Next I select the security
used to log in to the server.
In my case, I'm using Windows integrated
security, so I select this, and
then I can select the database
from the drop down.
I'm going to select from the master
database and test the connection.
So the connection succeeded and
we're good to go.
Once we click on OK, I can pull
the data using several common methods.
So I'm pulling in all the data
from the transactions table,
taking a look at the query
in the query editor.
Test the query and click on OK.
At this point,
my connections been made, but
the data can't be shown until
I hit the Update Sample link.
And so now, all of the data is shown,
at least the first hundred
records in my file.
If I want to see all the data I
can bring in the browse tool,
run the workflow, and this is all
of the data from my data set.