Now one of the advantages for setting up
the fighter and all this infrastructure
so that we can take advantage of
framework classes such as the cursor
loader. And I showed this diagram earlier
in lesson 3, and briefly describe the cursor
loaders were able to query the provider
for pet data and help us automatically
refresh the list of pets in the UI when
any underlying data changes. So for
example, if a new pet gets added to the
database, or perhaps a pet gets updated
there, then this list will get refreshed
show the latest changes. So before we
start, let's first figure out what the
heck a CursorLoader is. So a CursorLoader
is a loader that queries the
content resolver with a specific URI
and returns to us a cursor.
So in other words the loader loads data
from a certain URI and returns back
a cursor. Now we first learned about
loaders back in the networking course or
building out the quake report app, so
there we had a download information from
the internet into our app and more
specifically we're trying to fetch
earthquake data from the USGS server on
a background thread using an async task
loader. So since there could be spotty or
potentially slow internet connection on
the device, this network request could
potentially take a long time. And
therefore it should not be happening on
the main thread, remember that the main
thread is responsible for handling all
user input and any drawing operations. So
things such as these click button events,
by performing these time-intensive works
on the main thread, the app could
potentially freeze up and maybe not even
respond to other user input events. And
nobody wants an unresponsive app. so
remember don't perform any long-running
operations on the main thread. Now as a
result we move the HTTP request to a
background thread using an async task
loader. and we created a custom loaderr
called earthquake loader, now within the
earthquake lower class we had to
override the load in background method.
So inside this method we performed the
HTTP network requests so they could be
performed on a background thread. And
once that was set up in the earthquake
class,
we implemented the loader callbacks to
create the loader, and then handle the
result that came back in on load finish.
Finally we initialize the loader in the
oncreate method of the activity and
earthquake data was magically loaded
into the app. And then we all lived
happily ever after.
Alright, so after that recap we should
probably get back to the pets app. And
where exactly are we? Ah ya, so we were
talking about loaders and how we can use
it to fetch pet data from the database.
So specifically we want a cursor order
because our data is in the form of a
cursor. So just like network operations
that are expensive and time-consuming, so
our database operations things like
reading and writing to a pets table. so
currently we're performing the content
resolver query method on the main thread
in the cattle activity. But we don't want
to block the UI thread, so a loner allows
us to do the operation on a background
thread. Now as we mentioned earlier the
loader is tied to a URI as its source
for data and coincidentally we've
already set up your eyes for our data
within the pet provider, such good
foresight. And furthermore when the
underlying data in the database changes,
the loader will automatically recreate
the data at the same URI, now this is
awesome because the list of pets URI
won't be up to date, and we also want to
keep manually recurring the database
over and over again wondering is new
data getting added so this behavior here
requires a couple of twists or provider
but will be walking you through how to
do that exactly a little bit later on. So
you can tell there are multiple benefits
to using the cursor loader, so let's dive
right in and see how to implement this.