It's no secret that in order for
your app to be successful,
a user has to run it.
And for it to continue to provide value,
sometimes it needs to keep running.
However, this can cause
problems when the user or
the system puts the phone to sleep.
While it might seem like a right idea
to wake up the phone to do your work,
there's a massive battery
problem waiting to happen here.
To illustrate this point,
let's talk about my good friend
Raido whom you all may remember from
the Android fundamentals course.
He's an avid social user and
a game player, and
his running applications are constantly
checking scoreboards, uploading photos,
and pulling down
the latest hashtag crazes.
But they do this even when
Raido puts his phone to sleep,
which means by lunch,
his phone is already out of battery.
Raido has to constantly recharge his
phone because it suffers from sleep
deprivation.
That is because these applications
are constantly waking up the phone,
they're eating up battery life instead
of letting the phone go to sleep.
Remember that Android will turn
off various parts of your hardware
in order to prolong battery life.
First, the screen will dim followed
by it eventually turning off.
And finally, the CPU will go to sleep.
All to save precious,
precious battery life.
But even in this inactive state,
most apps will try to do work, and
they will have to wake
up the phone to do so.
Now the easiest way for
your app to wake up your
phone to do work is with
the powermanager.wakelock API.
Which is used to keep the CPU running
and prevent the screen from dimming or
turning off.
This allows your app to do
things like wake up the phone at
some future date and do some work, and
then let the phone go back to sleep.
But see it's that last part
that's actually the tricky one.
Acquiring way clocks is really easy but
knowing when and
how to release them is more problematic.
There's lots of ways that
this can go horribly wrong.
Like a what if your application takes
60 minutes instead of the expected 10
seconds to analyze an image content
before uploading it to the web.
Or what if the server crashes and
you never get a response from your
social ping and end up waiting forever.
Well the result is the phone would
stay on, waiting for the content and
thus draining the battery in no time.
Which is exactly why you should be using
the version of wakelock.acquire that
takes a time out parameter.
This will force the wake lock to be
released in these cases of crazy so
that your app doesn't keep the phone
awake until the battery is dead.
But even this doesn't solve
the problem completely,
what should you set the timeout
value to be in these cases and
how long should you wait after a failure
before using a wake lock to try again?
The right solution to this
might be to use inexact
timers which allow you to schedule
work for some future date.
But if the system detects that it could
occur sooner or later in order to
conserve battery life then it will
wait for that time to do that work.
For example, if another process
has woken up the phone,
your app might wait to be woken
up with that group of processes
rather than happening ten seconds sooner
like it was originally scheduled.
And in reality,
there's a whole group of situations
that might be better to do
battery intensive work.
For example,
when the phone is charging, or
connected to wifi or
already woken up by another process.
If any of your work can be deferred to a
future date when these conditions might
be ideal, then you can help improve
battery life significantly.
And this is exactly what
the job scheduler API is for.
See this API is perfect for
scheduling some future work to occur
in a battery efficient manner.
For example, any non-user facing work
waiting until the unit is plugged in
waiting until you're on wifi,
or batching a bunch of tasks to
occur together at the same time.
Basically, with one simple API, you
can get all that scheduling for free.
So, let's take a look
at this API in action.