We know move on to our linking topology stage of our solution.
If you have followed along with the solution so
far, you notice that the count bolt is now connected to the report bolt.
But we would really like the connect bolt connected to
the intermediate rankings, total rankings and then report bolt, such as this.
If this is our goal for the topology,
we should start here looking at the total rankings bolt for the centex needed.
Navigating to the total rankings bolt.
And scrolling down to the constructors,
we see that a TotalRankingsBolt calls a constructor with topN and calls super.
Let's then look at the AbstractRanker class, and
once we navigate to the AbstractRankerBolt, we see that the constructor for
super takes in topN, and emits a default emit frequency in seconds, of two.
Doing a search on topN, we see that the count equals topN.
Therefore we see that we need to define a new integer topN.
Navigating again to our topN tweet topology, and
scrolling down to the topology builder section.
We set the total rankings bolt with a variable topN, I named this component
id total-ranker, and scrolling again to the total rankings bolt, we see
again that this bolt requires an intermediate rankings with global grouping.
Therefore we create the intermediate ranker and globalGrouping link.
We then set our intermediate-ranker, intermediate-ranker,
with a new IntermediateRankingsBolt.
Again, with an integer, TOP_N.
Which requires a fieldsGrouping of count-bolt.
And finally, a new Fields, word.
And we set the TOP_N count.
And I'm setting it to an integer of 1,000.
We've now updated our topology,
to connect the total rankings bolt to the intermediate rankings bolt.
And the count bolt is still connected to the report bolt.
Therefore, we need to make the connection between the report bolt and
the total rankings bolt.
And again, according to hint number three, we want to check the connection
between the count bolt and the intermediate rankings bolt that we've created.
We make the connection between the report bolt and the total ranker bolt.
We do this by updating the component id total ranker.
And remember that we'll then need to check the connection between the total
rankings bolt and the report bolt.
Focusing the count bolt to intermediate rankings bolt connection first,
we navigate to the intermediate rankings bolt, and
we see that an incoming tuple is handled by a rankable object with fields.
We then navigate to rankable object with fields.
And we see that the schema that rankable object with
fields expects is an object and a long count.
Therefore we navigate to the count bolt, and
we see that our count bolt is actually emitting integers.
The way I approach this was to change our integer count to a long,
first by changing the private map.
Changing the count map to string long.
Initializing the map from integer to a string long, and changing integer val
to long val, finally I actually missed this the first time, but during compile
time realized that we need to change our initialization to a long as well.
Next, now that we've updated tupple schema for count bolt and
intermediate rankings, let's test out the topology.
But notice that the total rankings bolt and report bolt is still not checked.
So to run the topology, well have to remove that connection.
Let's do this now so that we can run our topology.
We can do this simply by navigating to the topN tweet topology, and
simply comment out the report bolt.
We can test our topology by doing a Maven package.
And if you recall from lesson one, you can send the output of
the storm using the pipe character and grep total-ranker.
And here we see the output of total-ranker, and
we see that total-ranker is receiving words.
Our next step then, is to connect the total rankings bolt to the report bolt.
And I gave you a number of syntax hints in the reading node.
Here however,
I'll give you some of the intuition of how I came up with those syntax hints.
First, since we're making the connection of total ranker to our report bolt,
we first navigate to the total rankings bolt, and
see that the total rankings bolt extends to abstract ranker bolt.
Navigated to the abstract ranker bolt.
We searched for the execute method and we see the function emitRankings has been
called, and emitRankings is emitting values of rankings.copy and
finally we see abstract ranker bolt is emitting rankings.
Therefore to connect the total rankings bolt to the report bolt
we need to modify the report bolt to handle and post rankings.
At this point we're close.
Let's go to the Rankings for java file.
And we find a method, getRankings, that returns a list of Rankable.
Finally, navigating to the Rankable class, we have what we're looking for,
namely, getObject and getCount, which is a long.
Finally, we navigate to the ReportBolt.
And again, remember,
we're making this connection between Total Rankings Bolt and the Report Bolt.
And we scroll down to our execute method.
We can first comment out the existing logic and build up our connection.
Given a tuple from the total rankings bolt,
we know after our code exploration that we can use getValue at position zero,
which will return rankings that I'll call a rankable list, of class rankings.
Given our rankings, we call the function getRankings.
We iterate through the list of rankable and call the function getObject.
And next toString to extract our string word.
And finally getCount which is long.
We publish to redis with word separated by the bar and a long.toString(count).
We update our import statements.
And here ii'm simply importing everything in our tools including Rankings and
the list that we need that are in import statements in our other files.
Finally, we navigate back to topN tweet topology,
reconnect our report-bolt to the total-ranker.
And now that we've made this connection, let's check.
Package and Maven and run, and hopefully,
your visualization works with a new world cloud that's using the topN, and
here r I'll define topN equaling a thousand, to show.
And if so, our connection's correct, and more importantly,
we're finished with the second major section of Linking to the Topology.
Great Job.