Okay.
So the first one is
switching CPU from one process to
another when a process blocks.
When you go from one
process to another process
the address spaces are going to change.
Yes.
The address spaces are going to change
because the incoming process now is
going to use its own page table
to access its data and code.
Where can we change address spaces?
Remember as soon as you change
address space, you changing what
portions of physical memory can be
accessed by whoever is executing.
Address space change always has to be
in the operating system because that's
how we protect memory.
Okay the operating system manages
what page table currently can be used
by the process that has the CPU and
is currently executing and so on.
So that has to go in
the operating system.
Page fault handling we didn't
talk about virtual memory that
page fault handling
comes in virtual memory.
So if some virtual page is not
currently in physical memory then
the page table entry is going
to say it's not in memory.
It's not a valid frame that this
logical or virtual page maps to.
In that case,
we have what is called a page fault.
We have to bring this from disc,
or swap area, or whatever it is.
Find some free space in memory, and
then update the page table of
this process to point to this new
page in physical memory where this
information was just brought in.
So if you update page tables, again you
have to be in the operating system.
If you could update a page table
from user space than you can update
with a different frame number or
physical memory, some other place.
And then you can go there,
even if it doesn't belong to you.
So in user mode you should never
be able to update page tables, and
that's why it belongs in
the operating system.
The third question we have,
in changing who can access
a protected resource such as a file?
Changing permissions.
I can't do that at the user level.
If I can change permissions for
files that belong to a different user,
Alice can do this for Bob's file.
Well, she could go access Bob's
file even if Bob doesn't want
her to access it.
The way we should do it is,
go to the operating system,
request that can we have access to it?
If Bob has done something that
allows Alice to gain this access.
That's fine, otherwise the operating
system is not going to add
this permission for Alice to the file.
So, this is another function
protected resource accessed to it,
the operating system should do it.
Last one, setting up a new stack frame
when an application program calls
one of its functions.
We know that happens at the user level.
If we call functions back and forth,
every time we call a function, a stack
frame is set up and that doesn't require
intervention of the operating system.
So this could be done at the user level.
Okay, so keep in mind that
memory protection isolation
relies completely on how
page tables are managed.
Page tables are used to
implement address spaces.
So management of page tables, whether
we update, when a page fault occurs,
or switch them, all that has to
be done in the operating system.
That's the only way we can get
the isolation that we're talking about.