Wait a second.
Paul just mentioned something
called a web worker.
These are really super useful, so
you're going to be creating one for
this next quiz.
Web workers provide an interface for
spawning scripts to
run in the background.
Normally, websites run in a single
thread running on the operating system.
Web workers allow you to run JavaScript
in a totally different scope than
the main window and on a totally
separate operating system thread.
Whatever work is happening
in the main thread,
in the main window, won't affect or
be affected by the worker thread.
And of course the opposite is true.
Whatever work is happening in
the worker thread won't affect or
be affected by the main window, but the
two can send messages back and forth.
This means that you can isolate long
running JavaScript inside a worker
thread and allow the main
thread to run free unimpeded.
What's really cool though is that
the web worker in the main thread
can't communicate with each other.
Altogether, web workers
are an incredibly valuable strategy for
running long running code that does not
create any jank on the main thread.
If you're unfamiliar with web workers,
check out the link in
the instructor notes below.
Essentially you'll need to create a
separate JavaScript file which your main
app will spawn into a new web worker.
For this quiz I want you to download and
dejankify this small app.
You'll need a copy on
your local machine and
you can find a link
to download it below.
I want to point out the two
main features of this app.
On the left side there is the Jank Timer
which will tell you if any jank
appears on the page.
And on the right side there's
the image manipulator,
which will let you pick a file
from your local machine and
then do some type of
image manipulation on it.
In this case I've just gone ahead and
uploaded a Chrome logo.
The image manipulator's janky and
needs a little bit of work.
Watch what happens when i click invert.
The page froze for
more than four seconds as this
image was being inverted.
That is definitely a lot of jank and
that needs to be fixed.
Your job for this quiz is to offload
all of the image manipulation work
off the main thread and
into a web worker.
You know you've done it correctly
when the page doesn't freeze for
multiple seconds when you
click one of these buttons.
As a second challenge,
there's also a massive performance bug
in the way the image manipulators run.
I'm about to give you a big hint
about where it is in the app.
So if you want to really nice
challenge right now just stop and
click continue to quiz and
skip this hint.
Okay, are you still here?
Here it comes.
Inside image-app.js you can find this
loop, which includes the logic for
separating each pixel into
the different channels, and
then running some manipulation on them.
This function, manipulate,
is where you should start looking for
the performance bug.
To help you out with the web worker,
I'm including a file called worker.js
that currently handles
most of the web worker.
It's going to be your job
to go into image-app.js and
then install worker.js as a web worker.
So, once you've moved the image
manipulation work into a web worker and
you've found the performance bug,
check this box to let us
know that you're done.