The on connective function
has at a minimum three steps.
And I've coded them like this.
First, I created location request
object, then, I set its priority.
And I set the priority to use priority
high accuracy, as you can see here.
Then I set the interval, and in this
case, I've set the interval to be
a 1000 milliseconds, so the location
will get updated once a second.
Then using
the LocationServices.fuselocationApi,
I can start to request location updates.
The parameters that this take are simply
the API client that we're using,
the location request
that we've just set up.
And the class to receive callbacks,
in which case it's this class.
Since the location services class and
the location request class are both very
important here, it's a good time to
take a moment to go to the forums, and
to discuss how they differ,
and how they're related.
Be sure to read some of
the answers provided as well.
It's an excellent place to find
places where your mental model
may not quite match the way
things are actually working, or
if you're stuck with anything it's
a great way for you to get started.