In general, you won't know what size
your object of interest will be in
the image you're searching.
So makes sense to search
in multiple scales.
In this case, it's good idea
to establish a minimum and
a maximum scale at which you
expect the object to appear, and
then reasonable number of
intermediate scales to scan as well.
The think to be careful about here is
that the total number of windows you're
searching can increase rapidly which
means your algorithm will run slower.
You're looking for vehicles, so it makes
sense through restrict your search
to the only areas of the images
where vehicles might appear.
Furthermore, when it comes to scale,
you know for
example that vehicles that appear
small will be near the horizon.
So search in a small scales could be
restricted to even narrow a script
across the image.