To begin, we can open our AREMA
workflow from our differencing and
selecting AR and MA terms lessons.
Now, like we did in our ETS model,
we'll use a record ID to filter
out a hold out sample to start.
We saw previously in our
seasonal differencing lesson that
auto correlation after
seasonally first differencing
has now lowered to a point where
we can add autoregressive and
moving average terms to account for
any remaining autocorrelation.
This also means our lower case d and
upper case D values will be 1 since we
took a seasonal difference and
a first difference.
From the ACF plot, we saw negative
autocorrelation at Lag 1 and
it is confirmed in the PACF.
This suggests a lower case q value of 1.
We also have significant autocorrelation
at the first seasonal period like 12.
We can add an upper case Q
term of 1 to account for this.
Now that we have our terms,
let's bring in an AREMA tool.
We'll call the model AREMA,
set Bookings to our target variable,
and set Target field
frequency to Monthly.
On the Model Customization tab,
let's select Completely user
specified model, and set our terms.
The non-seasonal auto regressive
component, lower case p, is 0.
The degree of first differencing is 1.
The order of the moving
average component is 1.
The seasonal autoregressive
component is 0.
The degree of seasonal
differencing is 1.
And the order of the seasonal
moving average is 1.
On the Other options tab we
can set our start date and
the number of periods to forecast for.
Since it is wise to construct more than
one model and compare the results, let's
copy and paste our AREMA tool on the
canvas, and change the uppercase Q to 2.
We're using additional seasonal MA
terms because our time series is very
seasonal, and we want to ensure this
seasonal component is accounted for.
Before we hit Run, add a browser to
the R or report node of the AREMA tools.
We can click on the Play button
now to build our models.
The output from our AREMA tool will
show us important measurements such as
the information criteria,
in-sample error measures, and
the remaining ACF and PACF.
We'll discuss how to compare,
forecast, and
visualize these results in lesson four.
For now, save this workflow as we'll
come back to reference it later on in
the course.