All right, so one of the reasons that
contraction mappings are really cool is
because they have some very nice and
convenient properties.
So let me state those properties and
then maybe we can figure out why and
how it has these properties.
So the properties are B
is a contraction mapping,
we know that B is a contraction mapping,
and
that means that any two functions that
we pump through it are going to get
closer to each other than they were
before you pumped them through.
Then first of all the equation F* = BF*
sometimes called the fixed
point equation, has a solution
that there is some F* that you can plug
in to B that causes it not to change.
All right, so whatever F* was
before after we put it through
B it stays the same as
it was to fix point.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And there is just one of those,
it's unique.
So just setting up this equations
says okay, it has a solution and
we could just call it F* because
there is only one that works.
>> Okay.
>> And a second property is that
we can actually converge to F*
by doing this kind of
value iteration idea.
That we start off with
some value function.
We push it through the operator.
We get a new value function out.
We push that through the operator.
We just keep thing doing this over and
over and over again.
And at the sequence,
the value functions, is converging
in the limit 2, the solution, F*.
>> Okay, so that makes sense Michael.
Here's a question for you.
If 1 is true, and
I know that B is a contraction mapping,
then doesn't 2 follow from that?
>> Well, 1 is true.
[LAUGH] But yeah, it's actually not so
hard to see 2 being true given that.
So, here's the idea.
So let's say we have some F* and
we know that B is a contraction mapping.
Then let's look at what happens
to Ft minus 1, compared to F*.
All right, so
by the definition of a contraction
mapping, we have this property.
That there's some gamma less than 1
such that for any two value functions,
they're going to get closer together
after we apply the operator.
But the two value functions
that I choose are F of t-1,
the value function that's coming out of
this sequence, and F*, the fixed point.
>> Mm-hm.
>> All right, so just by virtue
of being a contraction mapping,
we have to have this be true.
But let's look to see what
this is actually equal to.
So what's BFt-1?
>> Ft.
>> Yep.
And what's BF*?
>> F*.
>> Yeah.
So we're getting closer and
closer and closer to F*.
This sequence, however far if was
from F* before we do the operator,
the next time we do the operator it's
at least 1- gamma of the way to F*.
So we just keep repeating this over and
over again and
they're going to be equal.
>> Right, that makes sense.
Okay, so
if B is a contraction mapping and
a unique fixed point exists,
then you have to get there eventually.
>> Right, and then showing that the
fixed point is unique is the same kind
of argument as here, like if we have
two different fixed points then, right.
So if we have two different fixed
points that would mean that we'd
have an F* that satisfies
an equation like this and
a G* that satisfies
an equation like this.
And that means if we take F* and
G* and we put them through the B
operator they're not going to get any
closer together because they're going to
stay exactly as far apart as they were.
And that violates the notion that
it was a contraction mapping.
So there can't be multiple fixed points.
>> That's beautiful.