So Jake, have you got updates working?
>> Yep, users will now be encouraged to
update to the latest version of the site
and here's how I did it.
So here we are with our refresh button,
but it doesn't do anything yet.
When the user clicks refresh,
I'm going to call post message
on the installing worker.
Passing a JavaScript object with
property action and value, skip waiting.
You don't have to use
this specific object.
This is just something I'm going to
read in the service worker later on.
So over in the service worker, I'm
going to listen to the message event.
Event.data is the object
past the post message.
So if .action is equal to skipWaiting,
I'll call self.skipWaiting to make
this service worker take over pages.
Now, I want to react to
skipWaiting being called.
So back in the page controller,
I'm going to listen for
the controllerchange events.
If the controller changes,
I reload the page and that's it.
Done.
To test it, I'm going to
unregister the service worker and
reload the page so
all of our latest JavaScript is cached.
Now, I want to test how it picks up a
change to the service worker in assets.
I'm actually pretty bored
of this green theme now, so
I'm going to switch it back to the blue.
And so, this change doesn't
disrupt currently running pages.
I'm going to bump the version
of the static cache.
So now, if I refresh the page,
we get our notification.
And if I click the refresh button in the
notification, we got our theme change.
This is just one possibility when
it comes to handling app updates.
You have access to all the moving
parts so, do what works best.
SVGOMG and an SVG compression tool.
It does something very similar
to what we did for Witter.
Except, if the update lands before
the user is interacted with the page,
it just tells us so as work to
take over and refreshes instantly.
If the user hasn't interacted.
Refreshing instantly isn't
disruptive in this case.
You could also ask the server for
a change log between the new version and
the current version.
If your update only
contains minor things,
maybe don't bother the user at all.
Let them get the update naturally.
Or if the update contains
an urgent security fix,
maybe refresh the page no
matter what the user is doing.
That would be an annoying experience but
it's better than the user using
something with a major security flaw.
Anyway, it's fair to say
we're well on the way
to a full offline first experience.
We've got the user onto the latest
version as quickly as possible.
Next up, we need to work on
updating the posts the user sees.