Here are the answers.
We can see that the strategy of bidding 10, the true value, is weakly dominant.
It's the same here, but it's better in these two cases.
Let's look at these cases a little bit more carefully and figure out what's going on.
If you bid 12--so if b was up here--and if c snuck in between the bid and the valuation,
then you'd be paying too much. You'd be paying more than the goods are worth.
You'd end up with a negative utility.
So you don't want to bid more than what it's really worth to you.
On the other hand, if you bid down here, and if c snuck in in between
what your bid is and what the valuation is,
then you've lost the auction, and you get a zero,
but you should have won--or it would have been worth your while to win--
because the price still would have been a bargain to you.
That says that the rational strategy, the dominant strategy in second-price auction,
is to bid your true value and that makes it a truth-revealing auction mechanism.