[Thrun] We discussed specific incidents of hidden Markov model inference or filtering
in our quizzes.
Let me now give you the basic math.
We all know hidden Markov model is a chain like this
of hidden states that are Markovian
and measurements that only depend on the corresponding state.
We know that this Bayes network entailed certain independencies.
For example, given X2 the past, the future, and the present measurement
are all conditionally independent given X2.
The nice thing about this structure is it makes it possible to efficiently do inference.
I'll give you the equations we used before here in a more explicit form.
Let's look at the measurement side, and suppose we wish to know the probability
of an internal state variable given a specific measurement,
and that by Bayes rule becomes P of Z1 given X1 times P of X1 over P of Z1.
When you start doing this, you'll find that the normalizer
doesn't depend on the target variable X;
therefore, we often write a proportionality sign and get an equation like this.
This product over here is the basic measurement update of hidden Markov models.
And the thing to remember when you apply it, you have to normalize.
We already practiced all of this, so you know all of this.
The other equation is the prediction equation,
so let's go from X1 to X2.
This is called prediction even though sometimes it has nothing to do with prediction.
It's the traditional term, but it comes from the fact that we might want to predict
the distribution of X2 given that we know the distribution of X1.
Here we apply total probability.
The probability of X2 is obtained by checking all states we might have come from in X1
and calculating the probability of going from X1 to X2.
We also practiced this before.
Any probability of X2 being in a certain state must have come from another state, X1,
and then transitioned into X2, so we sum over all of those
and we get the posterior probability of X2.
These 2 equations together form the math of a hidden Markov model
where the next state distribution and the measurement distribution
and the initial state distribution are all given as the parameters of a hidden Markov model.