We provided code for you to load
each variable into something called
a data frame,
which you'll learn about next lesson.
Then this code extracted a series
from each data frame corresponding to
the US only.
If you wanted to examine a country
other than the United States,
you could have changed this value.
Now, to make my plots,
I'll add the lines %pylab inline,
to make my plots appear
within the iPython notebook.
But if youre not using iPython notebook
you wouldn't have added this line.
And then I can plot the employment in
the US by calling employment_us.plot.
Here, I can see that the years,
which are the indexes of the series,
have been filled in on the x-axis.
And the employment values have
been filled in on the y-axis.
And the same code would work for
the other variables.