As before, the answer is sometimes,
although more often than before from a single camera image given we have two now.
To give an intimation of why it's not always,
let's look at two images where the object of interest is a vertical object
and another pair of two images where the object of interest is a horizontal feature,
like this one over here.
Now, in the vertical case, there would be displacement.
This would be slightly further to the left than this guy over here,
and we can use the displacement to recover depth in a way I'll tell you in a second.
But for the horizontal, it's really hard.
If this feature crosses all of the camera image, there is something called "aperture effect."
What this really means is we can't really tell which of the little dots on this line
correspond to which little dots on this line over here.
In cases where the image lacks structure--
or the worse one would be two images of fog.
In fog, there is certainly a depth.
Each water particle has a certain range,
but we can't really recover how far away fog is,
because, honestly, both images look alike.
There are certain degenerate cases where stereo doesn't work.
We are going to focus on this case over here right now
where we do get information from the stereo sensor.