Thanks for your response.
Now remember,
your goal should be authentic and
specific, something you
actually care about.
They should have short term deadlines,
so within the next few months or so.
They should be measurable.
And finally, they should realistic.
Now you want to pick something
that's challenging, yet
attainable given your staffing and
financial resources.
It's just not realistic to think that
you're going to go from 0 to 100 million
users overnight.
Okay, so here are our goals for
Embarkment.
First, increase traffic of dog
owners to our site by 5% monthly for
the next four months.
And second,
increase the number of qualified
sitters by 8% within the next 60 days.