So let's say, here we are wondering
around the file system.
Let's say we end up in var log.
That is to say, /var/log is our current
working directory as printed out by
the pwd command.
Now, what do you think will happen
to the working directory if we just
type cd with no arguments?
Do you think that nothing will happen,
it will just stay in var log?
Do you think that it will
go to your home directory?
Do you think that it will go to
the filesystem root or the /directory?
Do you think maybe the shell stops
having a working directory at all?
Or maybe it's an error?
Or possibly the shell prompt
turns into a shark and eats you?
Which one of these do you
think is going to happen?