Take some time now and go through these
steps to create and set up your project.
Again, the steps that you will need
to follow are first you got to
set up billing.
Maps on Android doesn't
occur any charges, but
you still need to set up billing
in order to create a new project.
Two, you create the project.
Once the project is created, you will
then get access to the project console.
And on the project console,
you can enable the Maps API.
And then once you've enabled
the Maps API, you set up credentials and
you use your SHA-1 and your application
name in order to generate an API key for
that application.
Go through these steps now and
check this box when you're done.