Okay, so, I think I'll start then with
our first use case that we talked about
which is setting the display.
We have in that use case,
I guess involved,
we have the either the wake button or
the sleep button.
So those are,
I guess they're not percepts but
they are button that
we can interact with.
But our percept that we
see is the clock time.
So we both have the hour and the minute.
>> You're talking about
setting the time of day?
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
So, I guess we have the display time as
the first percept, and then we also
have the percept for, and when we change
the frequency with the tuning dial.
>> So this is now the second use case?
>> Yes.
>> Well, let's stick with the first one.
Actually you're getting some feedback
from the button when you press it, so
that is a percept tactilely, but
it's not retaining any state.
Okay.
So we probably don't need
to model that as a thing.
But we'll model it as an event that
takes place, you pressing the button,
releasing the button.
>> And
then when we're pressing those buttons,
want to make sure that I
got the inscription right.
Would the light come one for wake?
Like when you press wake
down is there like a little
light that indicates that we're setting
the wake time or are you just by sheer
fact that you're pressing wake, we now
know that we're setting the wake time?
>> So good question.
>> I guess theres some
ambiguity with the term, okay.
When you set the wake time that
doesn't turn on the alarm mode.
It's setting the time which, if you set
the alarm mode, the radio would come on.
>> Right, okay.
>> So the light is not going to
come on when you set the time, but
only when you slide that switch
over either to radio or to alarm.
>> So does that, I think that
takes care of use case one then.
>> Okay.
And then for use case 2 in which
we're tuning, using the tuning dial,
we have the percept of
somewhere on the radio seeing where
we are in the frequency band.
>> Okay, so there's that vertical
white bar that moves across.
>> And then we, I guess we're actually,
you know, we're adjusting that dial, so
we're not seeing anything.
I guess you could see the dial moving,
but
that's something we're interacting with.
>> You're definitely interacting with
it, and in fact, tactilely again,
you're getting a feel for it.
And this one does retain some state,
okay?
Although, in the middle of the night
you're not going to be able to tell
what state it's in.
>> Oh, right, okay.
>> Which is different than the volume
knob, where actually there's a little
vertical piece of plastic on top
of it that indicates its position.
>> Okay, is there like a limit I guess
mechanically maybe with that switch too,
that we could probably,
or with the dial?
If you turn it far enough you
get the aliens in outer space,
but no, it's limited to normal AM and
FM radio bands.
>> Right, okay, so
we have the vertical bar and
then the dial or two percepts that we're
interacting with for this use case.
And then for our third use case,
which was pressing the snooze button,
we have the snooze button.
>> Right.
Okay, yeah, I guess for
that particular use case,
I feel like I might be tying in other
use cases that are involved with
what would set you into actually
pressing the snooze button,
which would be either be being
an alarm mode or in music mode, but
those themselves I think,
could we put a separate use cases.
Should we worry about them
as separate use cases?
>> So recall when we talked
about use case modeling that
we can have contingent use cases that
is we can, the UML modeling notation
allows use to say that one use case is
included in part of another use case.
And that allows you to factor
out the common part and
have separate other parts.
However, there is one another percept
concern with this particular use case.
When you set the,
when you hit the snooze button,
what's your purpose for
setting that button?
To turn off the alarm or
the music that's going.
>> So turn off the speaker, essentially,
and the speaker is certainly a percept.
In fact, that's the whole purpose of the
clock radio is to have that, to control,
that particular percept.
So we definitely are going to have to
model the fact that when the snooze
button is hit,
something happens with the speaker.
So to summarize the various
percepts that are involved here.
The speaker, the time display.
We just went through those along
with those indicator lights on
the time display, saying whether
the alarm is turned on and
the AM/FM percept.
There's also, as we indicated, the
rotational position of the tuning knob,
the horizontal position, that left and
right position of
the vertical frequency bar.
Rotational position of the volume dial,
the current setting of the switch
which is the AM/FM band, and
the current setting of the slide switch,
which is on/off, radio, or alarm.
Think of it as a mode switch there.
The other devices,
the various buttons, are in fact that.
They don't retain any state.
But you can still use them to cause
other effects in the clock radio.