There's another way to
write a network size,
which is often used in
network configuration.
This is a subnet mask, which is a binary
number made of 1s on the left and
0s on the right to indicate
the size of the network.
You'll often see subnet masks in
network configurations on hosts.
Now, like IPv4 addresses,
subnet masks are 32-bit values that are
usually written as decimal dotted quads.
The mask for a /24 network in
binary is 24 1s, followed by 8 0s.
Now since an octet full of
1s makes the number 255, and
an octet full of 0s makes the number 0,
that means that the subnet mask for
a /24 netblock in dotted quad
notation is 255.255.255.0.
Now you will occasionally see some
systems that spell out their subnet
masks in hexadecimal
instead of in decimal.
In that case, the same subnet mask
would appear as ff, ff, ff, 00.
Now knowing what you just saw,
what's the decimal subnet mask for
a /16 network?