Now that you've downloaded CocoaPods,
we can use the pod file
included in our example code, to fetch
the dependencies we need for Firebase.
Let's open the pod file, inside
the project folder for FriendlyChat.
This pod file was provided for you, so
you don't have to create
one from scratch.
But when you start using Firebase for
your own apps,
you're going to have to
create one yourself.
If you're curious what a process for
this would look like,
we've included instructions for making a
pod file from scratch, in the resources.
So here's our pod file, and we have
this list of dependencies called pods,
that we will be using for our app.
to incorporate these dependencies,
for the first time.
We need to run pod install.
But before we do,
it's best to close Xcode,
to ensure a smooth download and install.
So I've closed the project and
I'll run pod install, from the terminal.
While at the root directory,
for our project.
This creates an Xcworkspace,
that includes all the dependencies
mentioned in the pod file.
And we can see that file, right here.
Now a quick note.
If you've already generated
an Xcworkspace, but
then you decide to make
changes to your pod file.
You can always run Pod Update, and
this will reconfigure the Xcworkspace.
Based on the changes.
Just be sure to close your workspace,
before you do it.
Also, from now on, we'll be sticking
strictly to using the xcworkspace,
instead of the previous xc project file.
In case you weren't aware Xcode
projects or XC projects contain files,
settings, and targets, for
building products like an app.
And expanding a little
bit further on this idea,
we have Xcode workspaces,
or Xcworkspaces.
Which contain multiple Xcode projects,
that can reference one another.
So this Xcworkspace
that we just generated,
actually contains multiple projects.
One containing your code, and
another containing the code, for
the pods that we pulled in.
Now let's open the new Xcode workspace,
and try running the app.
If the app compiles and
you see this empty table view,
then you're good to go.
But if you aren't seeing this, or
you get stuck somewhere along the way.
Then I suggest, going on the forums and
asking around, to get some help.