While we're on the subject of this sort
of picture of a matrix multiply, and
I mean the picture on the left, I want
to mention a related geometric way of
thinking about how
a matrix multiply works.
This geometric view will give you a
handy fact which you'll need later when
I ask you, what's the minimum amount of
communication a matrix multiply needs?
Oh, the intrigue.
The intrigue, oh!
Starting with this initial picture,
I want you to imagine a cuboid where
the faces are the matrix operands.
Notice how the edges match the same
way the dimensions need to match.
For example, where A has k columns,
and B has k rows.
There's a matching edge.
The same holds for the columns of B and
the corresponding edge of the cube.
Columns of B, and corresponding edge.
Recall that an element i, j of C depends
on row i of A and column j of B.
In the cube,
there's also an element i, j of C.
The dependents on A and
B is a line that cuts through here.
And if line is a projection of
a row from A and a column from B.
Now each of these scalar multiplications
is like a point inside this cube.
Let's think about what that means.
Suppose I pick a set of matching
rectangular blocks from A, B and C.
So here I picked an r by s block of A,
a matching s by t block of B,
and of course there's the corresponding
matching output which is r by t.
If they're perfectly aligned,
then they define a volume of
the interior of the cube.
In other words, this volume is the set
of all multiplications you need to do
in order to update this output block
with these two surface sub-blocks.
How many multiplies is that?
Well, it's just the volume of the
interior, so that's r times s times t.
In terms of the sizes of the sub blocks
it's just the square
root of their product.
In fact, there's a general result
from the geometry of discrete
lattices like this one, for
any integer cube of point,
suppose I give you
a subset of its surfaces.
Let's call them SA, SB, and SC.
Now there may be some blob of
intersection in the interior,
we'll call that I.
The theorem is this,
the volume of I is at most
the square root of the size of A, times
the size of B, times the size of C.
This is a theorem due to Lumis and
Whitney in 1949 and
a sighted in the instructors notes.