So in this lecture, I'm going to go in
to details of a video stabilization
system that's actually
in wide use currently.
This is a system that has been built
at Google in, in cooperation with
myself and a bunch of my own students
who are now working at Google.
Here's just example again of me taking
a video of my son giving a speech.
This was using a camera, but
of course, maybe a variety of reasons.
Again, I did not have a tripod, holding
it with my hands, maybe I was nervous.
I was able to not keep
the camera stable.
This is the output from the system, and
in fact I'll show you how, I'll show
you how we get to something like this.
This is actually a research system that
we have been working on for a while.
This was a Was a PhD thesis project
that included my PhD student
Matthias Grundmann, another PhD
student Vivek Kwatra, myself,
we published two papers on it.
Matthias and
Vivek are both working at Google.
In another paper, we also had Matthias,
Vivek, and Daniel Castro are working
with me on a paper to the International
Conference on Computational Photography.
So here just to show you,
this is Matthias, Vivek and Daniel.