The general correspondence problem is given
if there are two identical-looking points in the scene that have different depths.
For example with P1 might reflect into the image over here,
and P2 will reflect into the image as indicated by these red lines.
Now we understand the correspondence of P1 in both images
that this point corresponds to this point, we are well off,
and we can estimate the depth of P1.
If we get it wrong, if we correspond this point over here in the image to this guy over here,
then what we will see is this point right over here--P1 prime.
If we correspond this guy over here with this guy over here,
we get P2 prime.
These aren't really points in the action image, but they'll be phantom points
that occur because we got the correspondence wrong.
It's really important when we look at two camera images
to understand what is the actual correspondence.
Here are actually two images from a stereo rig of a scene,
and you can see there's a slight displacement. It's actually really hard to see.
We're looking at this feature over here for now.
I'd like to correspond it to something in the right image.
We have already learned that the search will have to be along a line.
Here is the green line, which is the corresponding line.
It can't be that this point over here shows up somewhere in the sky over here,
but even along the point, it's not completely obvious how to do correspondence--
how to match this image over here to this image over there.
So my question is how can we possibly find
where this feature corresponds to a feature over here?
How can we determine correspondence?
By matching small image patches using some of the linear techniques we talked about in
the last class by just basically comparing how similar looking small image patches are
or by matching features, and particularly edge features or corner features
that we might extract from the original image.
Or maybe neither of those two. Please check any or all of those that apply.