There' s at least
one function in this app that
would benefit from transactions.
And, that is registration for
a conference.
When a person registers for a
conference, the app needs to change two
pieces of data, the number of seats
available at the conference, and
the set of conferences,
the user is registered to attend.
The number of available seats
is the seats available field in
the conference record.
And, we'll keep track of people's
registrations by adding a field to their
profile, with the conference keys.
Transactions let us guarantee that both
of these changes will happen in sync,
with each other.
If we updated the conferences for
a user, but didn't update the seats
available, then if two people
registered at the same time.
They could both be trying
to take the last seat.
Transactions prevent
that race condition.
Making sure that an api function
uses transactions is easy.
You just have to add the decorator
nbd.transactional to the function.
And, if the transaction has to work on,
several kinds of entities that belong to
different entity groups, you have to
use the parameter xg equals True.
xg stands for cross group.
The default behaviour for transactions
is to work on only one entity group.
An entity group is defined as, entities
that belong to the same ancestral path.
So, in this case, a conference
that was created by user Joe, and
the profile of user Joe,
are in the same entity group.
While a conference created by Alice,
is in a different group than
the profile of user Joe.
You'll also need to modify
the user profile class,
to have a property that
will hold conference keys.
See TODO 6 files, for
the additional functions that
implement conference registration.
So as you complete this, check these
off, and then, think about this.
What is the correct decorate
to use in this case?
Is it ndb.transactional,
ndb.transactional xg equals False,
or ndb.transactional xgequals True?