So let's go down this list.
Editing and running a program.
Well, programs are text files and
they're a perfect fit for
the terminal's text-based interface.
People have been editing and
running programs in the terminal for
a long time.
Finding files on your computer
that have particular names.
Files names are also text.
The terminal interface
makes sense here too.
Downloading a file from the web,
if you know it's URL.
You can definitely do that.
Although some files
contain graphical content,
the process of downloading a file can
be done from a text-based interface.
We'll actually see that
later on in this course.
So you can use the terminal for
some media editing tasks,
but you really do need
a graphical view for somethings.
You probably don't want to edit a major
motion picture using only the terminal.
Starting a web server on the other
hand is definitely possible.
The server has a specific kind of
program that you can run in a terminal.
Really, you can run any program that
doesn't need a graphic interface.
Starting a web server in
the cloud is possible too.
You can send commands over the internet
to control remote computers,
all from within the terminal.
And lastly, you cannot break the entire
internet using your terminal.
If you really tried,
you might break your own computer or
maybe a computer next to you, but nobody
could take down the entire Internet.