We'll start by adding a new activity
called settings activity and
then adding the appropriate
navigation to and from this activity.
Okay, so let's go ahead and
create a new empty activity, and
I'm going to call it settings activity.
This activity will extend
from AppCompatActivity.
Now, we need to add a menu and
an item for the settings.
We need a way to open
the settings activity.
So, going back to the visualizer
activity, I'm going to want to both
add a menu and an item in that menu for
the settings activity.
You've done this before so
I'm going to move a little bit fast, but
you can always check out
the link below this video for
a slower version of when we
added a menu for the first time.
To start, I'm going to add a new
resource folder called menu and in this
new resource directory, I'm going to
add a new file called visualizer menu.
The menu is going to have
one item called settings.
Note that I add the app
namespace up here.
I'm going to make my ID action settings.
I'm going to give it a priority of 100,
and I never want it to
show in the action bar.
Also, for its title I'm
going to make a new string.
So over here in the values
folder in my strings.xml,
I'm going to add a string for settings.
Okay, and here's that string.
Now that I have this finished XML
menu file, I can go back to my app.
So here I am in VisualizerActivity and
I'm going to scroll down and
I'm going to override
the OnCreate options menu and
in here, I'm going to replace this.
Okay, so
here I'm getting a menu inflater and
I'm inflating that menu
that I just created.
Great, let's run the app.
Okay, everything is going okay.
And now, I can go up here and
I have a settings item in my menu.
It doesn't do anything so
let's work that part up.
Back here, the VisualizerActivity code.
I'm going to now override
on options items selected.
Back at theVisualizerActivity code,
I'm going to now override
on option items selected.
This is the method that is called when
you select an item in one of your menus.
I'm going to get the I.D.
I'm going to check if it matches
the I.D. that I created,
and if it does, I will use an explicit
intent to open up my settings activity.
Okay, so that's all the basic stuff, but
I've got a few more navigation
related quick changes.
I want to make my settings activity
a so-called child activity
of my visualizer activity, and that
can be done in the Android manifest.
So, down here, I'm going to change this
settings activity so that it now has
a label and it has it's parent activity
defined here as visualizer activity.
I'm also going to change the
VisualizerActivity to have a launchMode
which is singleTop.
Let's make sure that when you
navigate back from SettingsActivity
it doesn't remake
the VisualizerActivity.
Finally, there are few more changes that
I'm going to make in SettingActivity
itself I'm going to override the back
button so that it looks like
an up button and so that it goes back to
the main visualizer parent activity and
does not exit the app.
To do that I will get the action bar and
then If the action bar
is not equal to null,
I'll set DisplayHomeAsUpEnabled.
I'm also going to override
the settings menu here to get the ID,
check to see if they pressed the home
button and then navigate them up.
Okay, now that we sorted out
the navigation, let's run the app again.
Okay, here I am in
the visualizer activity.
I'm going to press the menu,
go to the settings activity, and
then I can also navigate back.
Great, so I'll hand you over to
Asir to start fleshing out the rest
of settings activity.