Looking backup at the top
of helloworld_api.py,
you'll see these imports
from the protorpc library.
Now, protorpc is a tool kit for
building APIs and
it uses Google's protocol
buffers as a message format.
Protocol buffers or proto buff to its
friends is an efficient data format that
can be used through lots and
lots of programming languages,
including Python and JavaScript.
Now, unlike Python itself,
protobuf is statically typed.
Every message and
every field has a declared class.
That means that you'll see a lot
of type information in APIs and
messages that use protobuf.
And a lot of the syntax that you'll
see in endpoints APIs has to do with
protobuf.
For instance, in protobuf,
every field in the message has a number.
These messages has only one field,
so that field is number one.
But messages with several fields
will have their numbered one, two,
three and so on.
The classes that fields can have
are listed in the ProtoRPC field classes
documentation, which is linked
in the Instructor's Notes.
Also, every field has a name.
That's what we see here
in the Hello class.
The name of the field is greeting.
It's type is messages.Stringfield and
one is its number.
Protobuf also has a concept
of nested messages.
A field inside one type can be, instead
of a basic type like String or Boolean,
it can be another message type.
Since we're going to be seeing a lot of
these protobuf things, let's do a quiz.
Here are some Python variables.
And over here is the outline for
protobuf message class.
Now take a look on the messages module
documentation in the instructor notes
for a list of the field classes, then
fill in the appropriate class definition
for each field in the message.