The answer, it turns out, is in the DOM.
Like I mentioned before,
in bindCounterToCat,
it gets the current number from the DOM.
It finds the counter object, grabs
the text out, turns it into a number,
adds one, and
then updates the DOM with a new number.
So where is that data coming from again?
It's coming from the DOM element.
Now the number of clicks shouldn't be
stored in the view or octopus areas.
Remember that the model is for data.
And the number of clicks
belongs in the model.
But Andy is storing it in the view.
And that's a problem.
So, we've established that Andy is
storing his data in the DOM, and
that's one of the reasons that his
code has become kind of spaghettified.