The next construct we will
talk about is semaphores, and
these are a common synchronization
constructs that have been part of
operating system kernels for a while.
As a first approximation, a semaphore
acts like a traffic semaphore.
It either allows threads to go or
it will block them.
It will stop them from
proceeding any further.
This is in some ways similar to
what we saw in, with the mutex.
It either allows a thread
to obtain the lock and
proceed with the critical section,
or the thread is blocked and
has to wait for
the mutex to become free.
However, semaphores are more general
than just this behavior that can be
obtained with a mutex, and
we will take a look at how,
what exactly a semaphore is
a bit more formally next.
Semaphores are represented
via an integer number,
some positive integer value.
When they're initialized,
they're assigned some maximum value,
some positive integer.
Threads arriving at
the semaphore will try it out.
If the semaphore's value is non-zero,
they will decrement it and proceed.
If it is zero,
then they will have to wait.
This means that the number of threads
that will be allowed to proceed
will equal this maximum value that
was used when the semaphore was first
initialized.
So as a synchronization construct,
one of the benefits of semaphores
is that they'll allow us to express
count-related synchronization
requirements.
For instance, five producers may be able
to produce an item at the same time.
The semaphore will be initialized with
the number five, and then it will count
and make sure that exactly five
producers are allowed to proceed.
It a semaphore is initialized with one,
then its behavior will be
equivalent to a mutex.
It will be a binary semaphore.
All threads that are leaving
the critical section will
post to the semaphore or
signal the semaphore.
What that will do, it will
increment the semaphore's counter.
For a binary semaphore,
this is equivalent to unlocking a mutex.
Finally, some historic tidbits.
Semaphores were originally
designed by Dijkstra.
He was a Dutch computer scientist and
also a Turing Award winner.
And the wait and post operations that
are used with semaphores were referred
to as P and V, and P and
V come from the Dutch words proberon,
which means to test out, to try, and
verhogen, which means to increase.
So if you ever see a semaphore
used with operations P and
V, you will now know what that means.