First are the says, does this ensure
that can never read the data?
So the first one says yes, Charlie does
not have access to read this file foo.
So Charlie made a direct
request to the system, saying,
I want to read this file.
The system is going to check the access
control matrix information that we have.
It's not going to find the information
for Charlie, so it's going to deny.
So Charlie is not going to be able
to gain access to the file directly.
But things are a little
bit more interesting.
So what can happen here is that
Bob is able to read this file.
So what can Bob do here, is read this
sensitive data from file foo, and
Bob can create a new file that he owns.
And he can then tow the read data into
this new file that is owned by him.
So the data is now being moved
from file foo into a new file
that is owned by Bob.
And that's possible because Bob could
read the data into some buffering
memory.
And then Bob is writing that buffer
into this new file that he just created.
The new file that Bob has created
is owned by Bob and he, of course,
can give permission to read
that new file to Charlie.
And this new file contains the same data
that was there in Alice's file, foo.
So the answer here actually is
going to be the second one.
It does not ensure that Charlie will
never be able to read the data.
This is called information flow problem.
Can the information that you shared
with someone else flow to another user?
And discretionary access control,
unfortunately there is no way to
prevent that kind of information flow.
And so we can't make this guarantee.
The only guarantee we can make
is that Charlie will not be able
to directly read the file foo.