Let's create a local permission
system that leverages the information
stored in the log in session object, and
uses server side logic in the database
to control the user experience
based on provided credentials.
In order to implement this local
permission system, our database has to
start storing information in
a more user specific manner.
We need a table of users, so we can
identify what data belongs to whom.
Our restaurant and
menu items tables should also be aware
of their creators for each entry.
A user ID column should be added to both
the restaurant and menu items tables.
And finally, a little backing
code to hook everything together.
So let's get started.