Hopefully, those connections worked for
you.
If not, here are a few pointers.
To set the actions, we start by
ctrl+clicking on each switch.
Here you'll see a familiar list of
events, just like with the button.
And, down here,
you'll see the event value changed.
This corresponds to the UI
control event value change,
that you found in the documentation.
We want to invoke an action
method on the view controller
each time this event occurs.
So, we drag from the circle to one of
the view controller representations, and
then choose the method.
We also have the option to
open the Assistant Editor, and
drag straight to the method, like this.
And, don't forget we also need to
connect our four properties, so
let's move back to storyboard.
Then you can open the pop-up menu for
each switch,
go down here to New Referencing Outlet,
and drag to the view controller icon.
This ones the green switch, and
we'll need to do the same for
the red, blue, and the color view.
It doesn't matter which view
controller icon we drag to.
Last one is the color view,
and then we should be all set.