Your goal in this lesson is to design
AI that is smarter than yourself,
at least in playing a real game.
Now granted,
a single game is a very limited context.
But making a program that can play a
game better than you can is an exciting
introduction to AI.
It's the way I got hooked.
I'm hoping to share my enthusiasm.
Along the way,
you will learn how to use adversarial
search to find optimal moves.
In particular, we will talk
about the minimax algorithm and
alpha-beta pruning.
We'll also talk about how to create
evaluation functions for games.
These ideas are enough to create
surprisingly powerful game AIs.
And we will apply our
knowledge to Isolation,
a complex game with
surprisingly simple rules.
We will then examine multi-player and
probabilistic games.
As your assignment for this lesson, you
will need to create a game player for
Isolation.
Note how long it takes you and
how difficult you find it.
That should give you a sense
of the amount of time and
effort that this course will require.