All right.
You're done.
Let's take a look at my solution.
First, we add a function to utility.java
to get the location status.
Note that we need to
suppress warnings for
our end def because we are reading
integers your out of shared preferences.
Which could be out of the range
of our location status.
Then we add the new strings we need.
Now we can make update empty view,
update the view based upon both the
location state and the network state.
And of course, we only update the empty
view of the forecast adaptor is empty.
Next, we'll have our forecast fragment
implement our on shared preference
change listener.
We need to register that listener and on
resume, and unregistered and on pause.
And our listener will now
call update empty view.
Done.