But that doesn't help us.
>> Well why not?
>> Well, the whole point of limiting
the depth of our search and
using an evaluation function was to
avoid the exponential explosion in
the number of nodes we have to examine.
With quiescent search, we have to
search the game tree for two levels,
and maybe a whole lot more if
the results are changing between levels.
>> Well, we don't have to use
quiescent search all the time.
In fact, if we play isolation a lot,
and see that the evaluation function
is giving us consistent results,
then we might not bother at all.
However, we might find that in our
testing, that certain times in the game,
quiescent search might
give us better results.
Oftentimes, that's at the beginning of
the game or at the end of the game.
Also, we have another trick we can
use called iterative deepening, and
that might help us too.