So that ends this lesson.
Gives you a little bit of discussion of about how images are formed.
This is reality.
But in general lenses
are designed to make it look like as if you had a perfect pinhole that
happened to give you really bright pictures that were very clear.
That's really good for us because the mathematics of a pinhole camera are very
well understood and are very clean.
They're a little bit, shall we say, complicated than simple algebra.
But they're, they're very easy to model.
So, when we do the mathematics of how images relate to the geometry of
the world, we'll use the pinhole model.
But everything that I've showed you here is how we build lenses that give us
this illusion of having a very powerful pinhole imaging system.
See you next time.