The first step is to modify
the activity_main XML layout so
that the app looks something like this.
Let's go into Android Studio and
look at that file.
Here's our activity_main
XML layout file.
And we have the preview on the device
showing up on the right-hand side here.
I can click on this magnifying
glass to zoom in to the device.
There that's better now.
To build the desired layout I
want to first add a plus button
in between the quantity header and
the quantity value.
We already have a button in our layout
which is for the order button down here.
So I can just copy this code and
then I'm going to paste it
in between the quantity header and
the quantity value.
Now I see the button appearing
in the right place, but
I need to change the text so
that it says plus instead of order.
Cool!
And I'm also going to remove
the margin top because we already
have 16 dps of margin from the bottom
of this text field.
So go ahead and delete this.
The button is pretty big and in the quiz
we asked you to change the size
of it to be 48 dps tall and 48 dps wide.
So I'm going to edit
the button XML here.
Nice.
Now it's the right size.
Now I can copy this XML and
paste it below the quantity value so
that we have the minus button.
I deleted the white space because
according to the Android code style
guidelines, you shouldn't have
extra white spaces in your code.
Now I'm going to change the text of
this button so that it says minus.
It already has 48 dps width and height.
Now the plus and
minus buttons are in place.
We mentioned earlier that we also
want the initial quantity to be 2 and
the initial price to be $10.
So let's make that change now.
This is what our layout looks like so
far.
Let's go back to the quiz image
to check on our progress.
We've successfully changed the layout,
but we also need to modify
the plus button so that when it's
clicked it calls the increment method.
And when the minus button is clicked
we need to call the decrement method.
Back in Android Studio,
I'm going to modify the plus button so
that the value of the Android
onClick attribute is increment.
That way when the plus button is
clicked on it will call a method
called increment in the main activity.
Similarly for the minus button, I'm
going to modify the onClick attributes
so that the value is decrement.
I'm going to save this, and
then run this on the device.
The layout looks good, but if I hit
the plus button, then it crashes.
Do you remember how I showed
you to look at the logs for
the stack trace of the error?
The log's already opened by default,
so let's drag this arrow up so
that we can see more of the message.
If we scroll up we see
that this is our error.
This is our app justjava and
it says illegal state exception.
If I scroll to the right I can
see more of the error message.
The error message says could not find
a method increment in the activity,
MainActivity.
This looks very similar to the error
that we had in the previous video.
Basically there's no method called
increment in the main activity.
And that's actually expected because
we didn't make that change yet.
For the second step,
we're supposed to add an increment
method to the main activity, create
a quantity variable that's initialized
to 3, then also display the quantity.
To do this,
I open up the main activity Java file.
Hooking up the behavior for the plus
button is going to be very similar to
how we hooked up the behavior for
the order button.
So let's copy this method here
that handles the order button.
Immediately I get an error that
says submit order is ready to find
in the main activity.
You can't have two methods that are
exactly the same in the main activity.
But that's okay,
because I'm going to change this to
be the increment method anyways.
And now the error goes away.
I'm going to modify the comment
because now this is a new method.
I'm going to update the comment
to refer to the plus button
instead of the order button.
Within the increment method, I'm going
to create an integer quantity variable.
I'm going to initialize it to
a value of 3, as the quiz requested.
Then I can display this
quantity to the screen.
I don't need to update
price in this method so
I can delete that line of code.
That looks good so let's test this now.
Now when I click on the plus
button It actually updates to 3.
That's pretty cool.
But if I hit the minus button,
then it crashes.
Let's check the logs, I'm going to
scroll to the bottom to get the most
recent logs, and then scroll
upwards to see the last error.
For our app,
there was an IllegalStateException
because it couldn't find the method
decrement in our activity.
This is also expected because we
didn't add the decrement method yet.
Let's go ahead and do that now.
I'm going to copy this method and
then paste it below it.
I'm going to rename this to decrement.
Now this comment needs to be updated.
This method is called when
the minus button is clicked.
To figure out what we're suppose
to do within this method,
let's go back to the quiz.
We've finished two steps so far.
The last step is for the decrement
method in the main activity.
We want to create a quantity
variable and initialize it to 1.
Then we're going to display
the quantity to the screen.
In the decrement method we've created
an integer quantity variable.
I'm going to initialize
it to a value of 1 and
then display that
quantity to the screen.
Now let's run it on our device.
Okay, cross your fingers that
it doesn't crash this time.
If I hit the minus button,
then, yeah, it decreases to 1.
If I hit the plus button,
it increases to 3.
So, these buttons are working
as expected, at least for
this stage of our app.
Ideally, as I mentioned earlier,
we want this to increase to 4, 5, 6,
and we want this to decrease to 2, 1, 0.
But that will come at
a later stage in the lesson.
Great job so far.