On the map,
you'll be receiving a written spec for
how the app should work.
But since I'm kind of a visual person,
I want to give you a demonstration
of what it should look like.
At the log-in screen, you're presented
with the option of either logging in
with your Udacity email and password,
or you can authenticate with Facebook.
Since the Facebook authentication
is optional and not required,
I'm going to go ahead and log in
with my Udacity email and password.
Once I've entered my email and
my password, I'll go ahead and log in.
The first screen I'll see is this tab
view controller, with a tab for map and
a tab for a list.
In the map view,
I can drag around on the map and
I can see pins of other students
who have placed their locations.
So there's some over here on
the east coast of the United States.
Then we also have some over here on
the west coast, near San Francisco.
I've gone ahead and
zoomed in on Florida.
And if I tap this pin here, we can see
that this was the pin posted by Jessica,
and her link is for
her LinkedIn profile.
If I were to tap the link this would
take us directly to Jessica's LinkedIn
page in Safari.
I'll go ahead and
switch over to the list view, and
we can see the names of the same
people that have posted pins.
In the same way,
if I were to tap any of these entries,
they would take me to the links
that these students have provided.
And if you haven't noticed,
all the students here are actually some
of the iOS instructors that we have.
Now let's go back to the map.
Here in the top left corner,
I have the option of posting a pin.
The basic requirements of this app say
that you could post as many as pins as
you would like.
However, if you'd like to go the extra
step, when you try to post a pin,
you should check to see if a pin has
already been posted for this user.
And in my case,
there already is a pin from me.
So this menu here is asking me, would
I like to overwrite my location, or
do I want to cancel this request?
I'll go ahead and select Overwrite.
And now I'm presented
with this input view.
I'm going to overwrite my location
to go back to my hometown
of Huntsville, Alabama.
And I'll find it on the map.
And behind the scenes, the app geocodes
the location into a longitude and
a latitude where this
pin will be placed.
For my link,
I'll share my LinkedIn profile.
And then I'll tap Submit.
So now the input process is done and
my new pin is posted here in Huntsville,
Alabama.
And if I tap the pin,
then there's my name and
there's the link to my LinkedIn profile.
And if I tap the annotation,
then it takes me to my
LinkedIn profile in Safari.
These are the main user interactions for
the app.
If you're a visual learner like me,
I hope this helps.