There's a area of computer vision people know a little bit less about.
It's used a lot in special effects,
everything from capturing the shape of somebody,
so you take the scan of somebody's face, whether it's laser or otherwise.
You build models, and then you can make lots of these people, and
you can light them from different sides and
different directions because you have a full 3D model.
Likewise, motion capture, so if you saw Pirates of the Caribbean,
the one with the, the guy with all the weird things on his face, and of course,
you know, that's all CGI, but the question is,
how do they know exactly where to put his face and everything?
Well, that, there are these markers that are being worn that
are being tracked by these cameras.
And they have to figure out the three-dimensional geometry, and
that's also a form of computer vision.
Another area that's become but this is a shot from Google Earth actually,
this is from Microsoft's Virtual Earth.
Google Earth is yet another version of it.
Where basically, they can take imagery, so here's imagery, aerial imagery.
But also, they can use that to figure out the models of the buildings.
Put those three-dimensional models in there, and
then you can fly around them however you want.
So that's a structure for motion method of using lots of images,
a sequence, to recover the three-dimensional structure.
We'll talk only a little bit about that.
We'll focus mostly on a couple of images.