[Man] Now I'm going to give you some sentences or axioms in first order logic,
and I want you to tell me if they correctly or incorrectly represent the English
that I'm asking about.
So tell me yes or no, are these good representations?
And the first, I want to represent the English sentence
"Sam has 2 jobs," and the first order logic sentence is
there exists an x and y such that job of Sam x
and job of Sam y and not x = y.
And so tell me yes, that correctly represents Sam has 2 jobs,
or no, there's a problem.
And secondly, I want to represent the idea of set membership.
Now, assume I've already defined the notion of adding an element to a set.
Can I define set membership with these 2 axioms?
For all x and s, x is a member of the result of adding x to any set s,
and for all x and s, x is a member of s implies that for all y,
x is a member of the set that you get when you add y to s.
And third, I'm going to try to define the notion of adjacent squares
on, say, a checkerboard, where the squares are numbered with x and y coordinates
and we want to just talk about adjacency in the horizontal and vertical direction.
Can I define that as follows?
For all x and y, the square x, y is adjacent to the square +(x,1), y,
and the square (x, y) is adjacent to the square (x, +(y, 1)
and assume that we've defined the notion of + somewhere
and that the character set allows + to occur as the character for a function.
Tell me yes or no, is that a good representation of the notion of adjacency?