Here's the solution that
uses querySelectorAll.
First things first, the class
toggled is toggled on the body.
Then, I look for
every element on the page with
class box, using querySelectorAll.
And then with this clever
iterator i plus equals 2,
I go over every other element in this
list and toggle the class grade.
There's a second parameter here which
should resolve to either true or false.
It's looking to make sure that
the body contains the class toggled.
If it doesn't, then don't do this.
But if it does, then do it.
The class gray is pretty simple.
Gray simply changes
the background color.
So now the selectors
are pretty simple and
all the iteration is
happening with JavaScript.
I want to see how this performs.
I'll hit the Record sign,
click, and then stop recording.
It looks like the action's here,
so I'll zoom in.
Here's the click and
the Recalculate Style is happening
in just under 5 milliseconds,
which is way faster than before.
In this case,
a little bit of JavaScript and
a little bit less CSS went a long way.