Let's talk about it's going to call it weak calibration, and
what I mean by that is we're just assuming that we've got two projected cameras.
So that they're going to behave like projected cameras, but
in particular, we don't know anything about focal length or, or their offsets.
But we are going to assume, for example, that we don't have radial distortion.
We're going to assume that we don't have a non-uniform stretch of the image.
So, but what it's say weekly calibrated that's all we mean.
We correct for that.
So the main idea is that we're going to estimate the epipolar geometry
from a set of corresponding points between uncalibrated camera images.
And we'll probably use a large set, so
it's going to be somewhat redundant in order to make this thing more robust with
respect to noise.
All right, so let's get started.
So before, from our all our projection stuff, you'll remember that
we had this projection that went from a world coordinate through our
extrinsics to our intrinsics to a projective representation of the image
coordinate right and so to get the non-homogenous you had to divide through.
So it's written here like the it's a scale w times the image point is
equal to the world point times our extrinsics times our intrinsics.
So phi is just as we did before, we're going to use a three by
four version here since K will be a three by three, where the left hand side is
that rotation matrix and the right hand side is the transformed translation and,
and you'll notice this slightly weird form written here of it's r times t.
And all that's saying is that if you know the translation in
one frame you might have to translate, you might have to express in
the other frame depending exactly on how you're, you're doing this.
Don't, don't worry about that detail, okay?
So that's phi, our extrinsic parameter matrix.
And K if you remember, that's our intrinsic calibration matrix.
And the K that I'm showing you here has a focal length and an x scale and
a y scale and of course as we said before they're multiplied together.
You really only need two numbers you've got f divided by sx and
f divided by sy, so they, they always appear in multiples like that.
But we have a scale in both directions.
We have the offsets.
But what we don't have is,
we don't have any skew, that is that this value here is 0.
That makes this math a little bit easier and
as I said before in general for modern cameras skew just isn't an issue.
All right.
So I'm going to write that this way.
The point in the image,
and this is a homogeneous point, is a point in the world times our,
multiplied by the extrinsic matrix, multiplied by the intrinsic matrix.
But this, of course, is just the world point put through the extrinsics,
that is the location of the point.
It's a 3D point, but it's in the camera frame.
Remember that the extrinsic matrix maps us from
some arbitrary world frame into the 3D frame of the, of the camera.
Okay, so that, we're going to call that pc.
And so we can write down this very simple relationship that K,
the intrinsics here, maps us from the point in the camera coordinate
system to the homogeneous point in the image, okay?
So p in the image is equal to K intrinsic times p in the world.
It's the point in the world, but expressed in the camera frame.