Compared to what you've done so far,
this last bit should be a breeze.
We need to cache the avatars.
This is almost the same as caching the
photos but there's one small difference.
Some people like to change
their avatar a lot and
we don't want people to be
stuck with some old version.
So when we fetch a particular
avatar from the cache,
we'll also fetch it from the network and
update the cache.
Avatars are also responsive images, but
they vary by density rather than width.
Pretty much the same as photos but
a slightly different URL pattern.
We're going to cache the avatars
in the same cache as photos.
So the first thing I'm going to
do is edit our clean up code so
it includes the avatar URLs in
the images that we want to keep.
We don't want those getting
lost in the clean up.
Since I get a call from
across the Atlantic,
I'm guessing the rest is down to you.
Hey, Mike.
>> This is it the final
task of the course.
To start you want to catch up
with a code Jake just wrote
do this by running git reset --hard
to remove any local changes you have.
Then git checkout task-cache-avatars
to get the stub methods.
Now head over to public/JS/sw/index.js,
the service worker script.
There are two things for
you to implement.
You need to call serveAvatar for
avatar URLs.
Then you need to implement serveAvatar.
It should return them from
the cache if they're there.
If not, get it from the network and
put it in the cache.
But here's the difference.
Even if you return it from the cache,
you need to go to the network
to update it for the next fetch.
Once again we're removing the size
specific parts of the URL so
use this URL to put and
match in the cache.
The solution will be similar to
servePhoto, but not exactly the same.
Once you've written the code,
head over to the browser and
refresh the page using the force
update on reload option so
you only need to refresh
once to see changes.
Looking at dev tools, you should see
avatars arriving into the cache.
If you go offline and refresh,
the avatar should still load.
To double check everything is working,
head to the settings page and
type cache avatars into
the test field and press enter.