In practice, it is very common that
treatment units are chosen for
the analyst.
Many companies have a set of test units
that they use over and over again.
For instance, there are set of target
stores in the US that are designated as
test stores for the company.
If you have to choose the treatment
units, you should first,
identify potential outliers.
Second, decide on the number
of treatment units.
And third,
randomly select the treatment units.
To identify potential outliers for
the new product experiment,
we would want to remove stores that
have outlier values for sales and
any stores that are in
states with very few stores.
For a refresher on outliers,
checkout the course linked
in the instructor notes.
When selecting the number
of treatment units,
the general answer is as many
as possible within reason.
In general, less than ten
treatment units is very low.
Similar to randomized experiments, the
smaller the number of treatment units,
the less confidence we'll have that
the experiment results are valid.
Sometimes, when small numbers
of treatment units are used,
the experiment may need
to be repeated or run for
a longer period of time to increase
confidence in the results.