Let's walk through the changes together.
Right now I'm in the documentation for
the authentication/token/new method.
Let's look at an example response.
It shows that if the method
returns successfully,
we should have a request token,
as shown here.
Let's go back to the code.
I'm going to go ahead and copy in some
boilerplate guard statements like
the ones we've been using
in the previous apps.
So I'll have this function
called displayError.
And it'll print out the error, and
then on the main, it'll set the UI
back to true, or re-enable it.
And it'll also set the debug text
label to hey, our login's failed.
And it's because of Request Token.
And then the first guard statement we'll
make is to make sure that the error
is nil.
Then we'll make sure that our response
status code begins with a two, or
that it's successful.
And then we'll make sure that some
data was actually returned and
the data isn't equal to nil.
For parsing the data, we'll use
the tried and true NSJSONSerialization.
And turn the data into
a dictionary that we can use.
And then the last step is
to get our request token.
So for this statement,
we'll look in the parsed results, and
make sure that we have a value that's
stored at the request token key.
If this statement succeeds,
then we have the request token, and
we'll just print it.
Now, let's build and run this.
And I'll just enter in
some dummy username and
password because it shouldn't
matter at this point.
And I'll click Login.
Great, there's our request token.