So let's just summarize.
Using SVMs for say recognition, okay?
So you have to define your
representation that is you need some
base feature space, all right?
Some feature vector in
which you're representing.
So whether you're doing HoG or,
or whatever it is.
You select a kernel function.
I'm not going to tell you at
the moment yet how you do that.
Given a kernel function, you can compute
the kernel between all your inputs,
all Xi's and all the Xj's.
That matrix is what you can then
use to find your support vectors.
Remember to, to find the support
vectors, it has to be able to compute
the dot product of Xi and Xj, but in
this case, we're going to use the kernel
of Xi and Xj because it's
the dot product in some space.
And what's cool is you'll notice
here that there's a boundary
that's not a line.
It's a line or hyperplane in
some high dimensional space, but
back in the original space
the boundary is whatever it is.
And in fact if you use RBF,
a radial basis functions,
you can sort of see it move
around your points elegantly.
And that's part of what gave the power
of SVM, is that you can essentially bend
the surface where you need to
near your support vectors.
So, training.
This is how you do the training.
And then at recognition,
to classify, it's very simple.
You take a new example.
You compute the kernel values between
it, and only the support vectors.
Multiply by the weights, the alphas.
And if it's positive, it's a,
it's a positive example, negative net.
So, here, it's sort of faces and
non faces.