When we do a Fourier transform, all we're doing is computing a basis set.
And I'll show you what I mean by that.
See this ugly, ugly integral here?
Ok, what I've got is, I've got the sine of one function, and
the sine of another.
Two different frequencies, a and b.
Okay and I'm integrating this all the way from minus infinite to plus infinite.
And I claim here that it equals zero if a does not equal b.
Now why is that true?
Any guesses?
Well let's just think about this intuitively all right?
If I have some sinusoid.
And now I've gotta do one of a different frequency.
That's easy.
[LAUGH] Boy, that's beautiful, huh?
Essentially, at some point when this is positive and
this is that same positive value, I'm going to try to find,
hopefully there's some positive, I have to make one up.
Yeah, let's pretend the red thing went down here like that a little bit, right?
That when the, the red is same positive.
The yellow was the negative of it.
So the product of those two numbers and then some together is going to
cancel each other out and that sort of a hand wavy way of saying that
this entire integral is going to be zero as long as a does not equal b.
But you might ask what happens when a does equal b?
>> What happens when a does equal b?
>> Let's start with assuming they're in the same phase, exactly the same phase.
Well, then it's just sine squared.
Sine squared is positive.
Sum that over infinity, what do you get?
You get infinity.
So, if you have two sinusoids that are the same frequency,
you'll get an infinite value.
Unless they're perfectly pi over 2 out of phase,
in which case it's going to be 0.
In other words, sine times cosine keep going.
But the bottom line is the way of thinking about this is that the,
if I integrate a function, if it's made up of a sinusoid that's different than
omega, when I take the sine of omega and I do that full interval I get nothing.
But if it's equal to that sine, I would get infinity.
And that's going to be written like this.
So let's just do a simple example.
Suppose I've got a simple function: f of x as cosine of 2 Pi Omegax.
All right?
Well then, let's pick some frequency and
we'll call it u here just keep things simple, right?
If I take this integral, okay, that's going to be infinite if u
is equal to that same omega, all right, and it's going to be zero otherwise.
So that looks like this, okay?
So we just have these two member impulses.
We just have these two infinite spikes here.
And that's referred to as an impulse that corresponds to the cosine.
You see that they're positive this way, and that's because it's cosine.
If we have a sine, because sine of negative x is negative sine of x,
that would look like it would be up here and that would be down there.
That's what the sine is, okay?
That's, and that's kept us the imaginary part.
So we're just computing a basis set of saying how much of this,
sinusoid is in there, all right?
And we can do that for all frequencies.
But then you might ask, well don't we also have to do it for all phases?
>> Don't we also have to do it for all phases?
>> She studied that one.
Well, the short answer is no.
One of the cool things is if I have cosine of omega x and
sine of omega x, right?
So one is 90 degrees or power of two phase out of phase.
I can make any phase by a linear combination of those.
You can show that, it's just true, we can do a little demo.
But basically, if I have a sinusoid of any phase, if you just tell me sort of
what its integral is with respect to cosine and what its integral is
with respect to sine, I can tell you what the phase of that sinusoid is.