So this command
has the host name en.wikipedia.org
in it in two different places.
Now, the second one is telling
Netcat what address to connect to.
We want to connect to the server
with the address en.wikipedia.org.
And the first one is printed
out into that connection.
Sent by a printf to Netcat.
Through the pipe.
As part of an http header.
It says what the host name is of
the web page that we want to fetch.
But suppose we wanted to
access a different page.
Like instead of
Wikipedia Lets access google.
To do that try changing the host header
and the nc destination from Wikipedia
to google or
from en.wikipedia.org to www.google.com.
And in the output look for
the server header which tells you
what kind of web server Google uses.