Right now, the QR code app is
doing all of the image decoding
on the main thread.
It's hard work, and it sometimes
introduces a bit of jank to the app.
This is actually a perfect situation for
Web Workers.
Image decoding can be handled in
a separate thread by a worker while
the main thread is simply concerned with
delivering 60 frame per second video.
The main thread can send off image data
to the worker so it can do its analysis.
And then when it's done,
the worker will simply post
the data back to the main thread.
In this case, the processed data that
the worker thread will be sending back
to the main thread is simply a URL
if the QR code was resolved, or
undefined, if not.
Now, I am about to give you some hints
about where you should do your work
including things like where you
should be putting the worker.
But to be honest, you might actually
enjoy reverse engineering the QR code
app yourself and trying to figure
out where to spawn the Web Worker.
So if you are feeling brave and
up to the challenge,
stop this video right now and
just hit the Continue to Quiz button.
All right, there's my advice.
Here we go into some hints.
The big question to ask yourself is,
where will I be doing most
of the work for this quiz?
You will actually be able to find the
web worker inside a mostly ready state
inside app/scripts/qrworker.js.
You'll need to spawn the Web Worker
from inside the QRCodeManager,
which you can find in main.js.
You should be posting data to
the web worker from inside
the detectQRCode function, which you
can find inside the same object.
And you'll notice that qrworker.js
includes a lot of scripts.
Right now they're already in index.html.
But with the worker, they're pretty much
redundant, so go ahead and remove them.
Okay, and there's one last thing.
You might encounter a small bug when the
main thread starts receiving messages
from the worker.
I'm just going to leave it up to you to
figure out what it is and how to fix it.
All right, good luck.
Check the box here once you've
got the Web Worker working.