Now that we have talked about
a couple of the laws, U.S.
laws, let's see how
they have been applied.
Have they been used, the cases where
they were used to go after someone?
The first question actually is
asking you about The Melissa virus.
It was a while ago, I think in the early
2002, or 2003, or something like that.
The CFAA was used in this case.
The first use actually was,
of the CFAA, was for the first
large scale Internet worm, was
the Morris Worm, but this came later on.
And the goal of this question is, what
exactly did the author of this virus do
because of which he was sentenced
to a prison term and also fined?
What was the abuse that was illegal,
that was perpetrated by
the author of this virus?
So we talked about the CFAA.
We know that to destruction of data on
a protected computer is illegal and
carries criminal sanctions.
Similarly, denial of service,
becomes unavailable to you,
interruption is illegal as well