Now your development environment is
set up and you have the starting code.
I'll walk you through a very
simple Endpoints API project.
You can find the code in the Lesson_2
folder named 000_Hello_Endpoints.
Add that whole folder
to your code editor.
The app.yaml file is where
the configuration of the app is stored.
There are important configuration
parameters that go here,
like your project ID and
the version number of your app.
Project ID needed when
you deploy your app and
you can have several versions of
your app running at the same time.
Down here there's configuration for
URL handlers that determine what
should be done with a request.
You can configure static file paths,
and for Endpoints,
what to do with when an Endpoint
request is performed.
As you can see, there's a secure
always line for the handlers.
That means the connection
between the client and
the server will always be over HTTPS.
Even if the client initially
tried to use HTTP.
And at the end,
you'll see the library's configuration.
For this simple app, you just need
to include the Endpoints library.
So, back up in the handlers,
you'll see there's an entry for
slash that points to static/index.html.
But what's much more
interesting is this handler for
Endpoints that points to
helloworld_api.APPLICATION.
And there's this file called
helloworld_api.py, and
this is where the application code lives
and where the endpoints are defined.