Before I give you my thoughts on which
of these suggestions is valid and
good of the scenario, I want to
re-remind us of these data tips.
The key to deciding
where data should be,
relies on what portions of data that
you're going to need at the same time.
And that's really about using
your activities as guides.
If you don't need the same
doubt at the same time,
you should think about denormalising.
Again remember,
that we're optimizing for
making a minimal number
of data transfers.
Remember what you're optimizing for,
you don't want to have to make a million
different listeners to get all
the data that you need for one screen.
But more importantly, you want to
optimize your data structure in such
a way that you're allowing for
minimal data transfer.
Suggestion one suggestion two
could be compared to one another.
Let's take a look at
what one looks like.
For both of these were going to
extract out shopping list items.
For suggestion one,
I just have a simple list of all items.
And then embedded within the item,
is the push idea of the shopping
list that it is associated to.
Let's take a look at option two.
For option two, I similarly have
de-normalized out shopping list items.
But instead of these being a list
of items, there are sub-lists for
each shopping list push ID.
And you'll notice the item itself does
not contain a shopping list push ID,
because you have to push I.D. up here.
This is our original design for
where we put items in
shoppinglist++ from way back when.
So just looking at suggestion number
one, and number two, which again,
are very similar,
which one do we think is better?
So here's data structure
number one again.
And number one might seem
like a better option.
After all the data is
less deeply nested.
When you want to get all the shopping
list items that are part
of a certain list, you do a query,
which selects out all the items that
have the same shopping list push ID.
But the issue is that you need to
make that query in the first place.
Remember, shopping list items
is going to get long so
eventually that query could be
looking over millions of items.
With suggestion number two, if you
organize your shopping list items so
that they're already grouped by list,
you don't need any sort
of extra processing.
So actually, where we put the shopping
list items way back when.
Which is what it says, that option two
is the better of these two options and
better than what we have right
now darn those data architects,
that did not design for Firebase.
Why did I hire them?
Anyways, lets look at suggestion number
three move the list of user's shopping
on a list to it's top node.
Have them organized under the push
IDs of the list they are a part of.
All right,
let's see what this looks like in data.
Okay, so here's suggestion number three,
we have one of our list push ids and
then this is showing that Walter and
I are shopping on that list.
And it is denormalizing the data.
Again, we've taken
usersShopping out of users.
But you gotta ask, is there a purpose
that we are doing this for?
Remember, on the active list
details screen right here,
we need to be able to say
who's shopping on the list.
And also here the shopping
list fragment.
We say how many people
are shopping on the list.
So whenever we are using
the shopping list data in our app,
we're actually also using the data for
who's shopping on the list.
Separating out the shopping list
users from the shopping list object
therefore it doesn't
make a lot of sense.
Because there's never a point of
the app that you need to display or
use the list of shopping users on its
own separated from the shopping list.
Okay, so I say no to suggestion three.
Okay, so this is suggestion four.
And again we've denormalized.
We took user friends, which used to
be inside of the user objects, and
put them on the top node.
So instead of having a user friends
category in Walter's user data
we've denormalized it out here so that
the fact that Walter is friends with me
is up here, and not embedded with,
inside his user information.
So is this helpful?
Okay, so looking at our screens again
here are the two screens that have to
deal with shopping lists.
And I'm actually going to pull up the
screen that shows the friends as well.
So let's think about our screens again.
These two screens here,
will probably need to get user data.
For example, to be able to display while
as lists, you need to get the user.
And just in general, to do things
with permissioning about what you
can actually click on a list you need
to know who the current user is.
But these screens don't need to
know anything about who the user's
friends are.
The share lists screen on
the other hand has a list
that lists out the user's friends.
So it does need this
user's friend details.
But because here we're using the user
object without needing to know anything
about the user's friends.
It makes sense to separate
these two things out and
sort of denormalize the data.
So that action forces
actually looking pretty good.
Okay.
And finally,
we have suggestion five which is to move
the shopping list out of the user class.
And here's what that would look like.
We move the shopping list
out here into activeLists.
So that's looking pretty good.
And suggestion five is actually
a must when we're grabbing user data,
which we do on basically every
screen of the app, we don't want to
also be pulling down all the shopping
lists associated with them.
Now this still leaves us with some
interesting things to say about sharing.
But it does pinpoint where our
original problem came from,
with the shopping list fragment
taking so long to load.
Okay, so it looks like we should
have implemented suggestions
two, four, and five.
Well, that would have been good
to know before all this happened.