In which of these situations should
you consider using Promises?
Should you consider using Promises when
you're working with information from
an Ajax request?
Should you use them when
you're executing long-running
image manipulation in the main thread?
Should you use them when you're
creating a series of divs and
appending them to the body
in a specific order?
Or should you use them when
you're posting messages back and
forth between the main thread and
a web worker.
If you're not familiar with web workers,
it's an API that allows you to create
independent threads to execute long
running JavaScript off the main thread.
There's more than one answer,
so check all that apply.