So, that ends the lesson on edge detection and
in fact, the first subunit all together on image processing.
Hopefully you've learned a little bit about filtering with convolution and
correlation, and the idea about taking these derivatives.
We've also talked about filters being used as templates.
next, what we're going to do is we're going to take a little detour, and
do some real computer vision.
That is, computing some data structure that tells us what's in
the picture from our images, and will actually use these edges and
then we'll come back to doing more about image processing.
But first, you'll get to go find some lines, circles, coins, and
cool stuff in pictures.