Well if you don't have a trusted path,
what is the problem?
So not the case that the user, so
let's say what the problem could be that
we may have a trojan, okay, that creates
an interface that looks like what
the operating system to be
do we normally would have.
So, for example,
would ask you for user id and
then when you type that it may you
know next ask you for your password.
Trojans may sort of do exactly that.
You just don't know you're
talking to the trojan so
if it does this that steals your
password and logs you in anyway.
Then it's not the case that
you are not able to log in.
What's really happening is that
you're giving your password to
a trojan who is going to steal it so
you're giving your password
to a malicious program because if you
don't know for sure that you're talking
with a trusting computing base that
means you don't have trusted path.
So possibly, potentially you're giving
your password to some malicious code.