In sort of a related way,
there's a lot of technology these days involving object recognition.
So there was this company.
There is this company, Evolution Robotics, that had developed this thing called
Lane Hawk, which basically prevented some of you.
None of you.
From putting stuff on the bottom of a basket and
then wheeling it out and forgetting to mention to the cashier that it was there.
This is actually a huge problem.
And the system, you can see the camera here.
Right, see, that's a camera down here, looking at this.
I wonder if we're going to have to, like, erase that that's a beer.
Yeah, you see, now nobody can see.
Okay, you can't tell what that is.
Okay. And it can detect what that is, which is not only pretty cool.
But if you go on their website they'll tell you that five years later,
that product was bought by a different company.
So, there's money to be made in computer vision.
Go do a really cool startup.
Object recognition used to require a lot of computing power.
It's, the computing power has gotten smaller.
And it allows us to now operate in smaller packages.
So, there's this whole area of augmented reality and
object recognition by mobile devices.
So, here's a system of where you, you're showing it a picture of this statue.
It recognizes who this is and what the monument is.
And here's an old picture from Nokia, where you can actually go off to the web,
pull out information and display it to you.
So for a while we were talking about doing this on smart phones,
now it sits on your face.
This is Professor Thad Starner, a Georgia Tech professor as well.
He was instrumental in the developement of Google Glass.
And one of the things that Glass does is you've got a camera looking out of
what you're seeing.
And can, through the same object recognition methods,
can give you information about what you're looking at.
And this is also part of computer vision.