Okay, so we've seen TextView code for
the first time.
>> But
it's kind of hanging out in limbo.
>> Right, we do need a space
where we can house it.
>> Yeah, that space is an IDE.
>> There's that acronym again.
What does it stand for again, Catherine?
>> Integrated Development Environment
>> Right, and
we are going to be using
Android Studio in this class.
This is what it looks like.
Still a little intimidating.
>> Yeah.
I think we might need something
that will help our learner
ramp up a little bit easier.
>> Right, so we've been working
on developing something that is
Android Studio on training wheels,
in the tradition of really convoluted
acronyms in computer science,
we are calling it XMLV.
>> Which stands for XML Visualizer.
>> So you write a little bit of XML?
You get to see the output.
You write some more,
you get to see more output.
>> Yeah.
So let's go use it.
>> Okay.
>> Since this XML visualizer was
created specifically for this course,
it won't provide all the functionality
that Android Studio supports.
But eventually in the problem
set of this lesson,
we'll get you into Android Studio so
you won't need this website anymore.
A link is in the instructor notes
If you want to follow along.
For this code,
the text says Happy Birthday.
So when I look at the device it says,
Happy Birthday.
Now let's try to change the text
to Happy Birthday, Kunal.
And then when I zoom in on the device
preview you see that it now says,
Happy Birthday, Kunal.
And what happens by trying to
stand the width and the height.
I'll pick some arbitrary
values like the 300dp for
the width and 500 for the height.
And now in the preview pane, you see
that the TextView is a lot bigger.
The text though, however, is still
the same size in the top left corner.
Notice that for the width and
height values of 300 and
500 is followed by dp in each case.
This is a unit of measure
like centimeters or
millimeters, that we use to describe
the size of views on Android.
As well as the distancing between views.
The unit dp stands for
density-independent pixels.
Let me explain why we need that.
Say these beautifully drawn rectangles
represent different devices.
They're the same physical size, but
they differ in terms of resolution.
This is a medium resolution device with
a medium number of pixels on the screen,
high resolution and
extra-high resolution device.
When I say pixel, I mean a phone screen
is made up of many tiny squares,
which are pixels, and they light up
based on what you're looking at.
So if I define the size of a view, for
example, a button, to be 2 pixels tall
by 2 pixels wide, this is what it would
look like on a medium resolution device.
On a high resolution device,
it would also be 2 pixels by 2 pixels.
But it's a little bit smaller,
because there's a lot more pixels trying
to be packed into this device, and
then on an extra high resolution device
where there's tons more pixels packed
into this space,
this button is actually pretty tiny.
I can barely tap on it with my finger.
I have to use edge of my finger or
my fingernail to reach it.
Just because I have extra
high resolution device,
doesn't mean I have a smaller finger.
I still want to be able to tap
the buttons on the screen.
And that is why we have
density-independent pixels.
I can define my button to
be 2dps tall by 2dps wide.
This is what it would look like
across the different devices.
It is the same physical size, but
under the hood Android is mapping
it to a different number of pixels.
You don't have to worry about any of
that logic, all you need to remember
is that you need to define your
sizes in terms of dp values.
When designing your apps, we recommend
that all touch targets like buttons
should be at least 48dps tall and wide.
Notice that it says 48dps and
not 48 pixels,
otherwise it would be really tiny on
this extra high resolution device.
This will make your app easy to use for
everyone.
So with all of this knowledge,
I want you to try and
change the TextView code now.
You're going to be writing your very
first lines of XML, how exciting.
So first try to change
the text in the TextView.
And then try to change
the sides of the TextView.
Then I want you to try to
create an error sad face.
And then I want you to undo it,
happy face.