If you typed out the code that we gave
you, then when you run it on your phone,
when you hit the ORDER button, then
the quantity is 2 and the price is $10.
Now let's try to change
the initial value of the variable.
Instead of 2,
let's make it 5 cups of coffee.
It's just one of those days.
So when we say display(numberOfCoffees),
it's going to display 5 as the quantity.
If we say displayPrice,
then numberOfCoffees is 5, and
5 times 5 should be $25.
So, let's run it on our phone to see if
that's what happens, and yes it does.
Now, let's try to change
the variable name.
I'm going to delete this variable name,
numberOfCoffees, and
I'm going to change it to quantity.
It's a lot shorter name so
I like it better.
Immediately the variable
name is grayed out,
and we get a warning that says,
variable quantity is never used.
That's because we never actually
refer to the variable quantity.
We just create it but never use it.
But not for long.
We're going to use it.
We need to change these two lines of
code to use the variable quantity.
Right now there's an error because
it cannot resolve the symbol
numberOfCoffees, because
that's not a variable anymore.
So let's copy over quantity and replace
those references to numberOfCoffees
with the new variable name.
Cool, now there's no more errors.
Let's run the app.
When you hit the ORDER button,
the quantity is 5, and price is $25.
This is the same behavior as
the last time we ran the app.
When you change the variable name,
there's no visible
difference to the end user.
The variable name is just for
us developers to use when
we're writing our app.
Since quantity is a shorter name and
it's still accurate in terms of the
information that it holds, quantity of
coffee cups ordered, let's continue
using this variable name going forward.