Yay, it's coding time again.
This time I'd like you to
write three functions.
A function to find the cross
product of two vectors.
A function to find the area of the
parallelogram spanned by two vectors.
And a function to find the area of
a triangle spanned by two vectors.
You can assume the vectors will
all be in three dimensional space.
However, as an optional exercise, it's
possible to extend the area functions.
To vectors in two dimensional
space by treating them as
3D vectors with a Z coordinate of zero.
After you're done with your functions,
use them to fill in the answers
to the following questions.
Within an accuracy of
three decimal places.
First, find the cross product
of the vectors 8.462, 7.893,
negative 8.187, and 6.984,
negative 5.975, 4.778.
Second, find the area
of the parallelogram
spanned by the vectors
negative 8.987 Negative 9.838,
5.031 and, negative 4.268.
Negative 1.861 and they give 8.866.
Third, find the area of the triangle
spanned by the vectors,
1.5, 9.547, 3.691 And
-6.007, 0.124, 5.772.