So, let's actually do the calculation for each
season. This time you'll have to copy and
paste the data into your own spreadsheet like
we showed you before. Highlight the data by
clicking and dragging from cell A1 all the way down to cell C27 since that will
ensure that all of the data is copied. Then type Cmd C or Ctrl+C to copy it.
Then go to your spreadsheet that you created in your statistics folder,
and type Ctrl or Cmd+V. Then in any of the blank cells, type your
command. Equal sum, and for Season 1, that would be
A2 to A24. For Season 2, you would type, equal sum
( B2 all the way to the end cell, then you'd do the same
process for the total sum for Season 3. Type in your answers here.