At this point, we have seen
the code that we are examining for
a vulnerability and
we'll soon discover that.
We talked about the stack where some
of these variables that we have
in this code are going
to be allocated space.
So, to further sort of reinforce what
our goal here is to exploit that code,
or exploit that program,
we're going to do another quiz.
And before I show you how exactly
how we end up exploiting it,
I want you to sort of think about it.
So I want you to sort of look at
these three possibilities we have.
The input that I pass is greater
than 12 bytes and ends in 123.
Any password of length greater than
16 bytes begins with MyPwd123,
which is the correct password.
Or any password of length
greater than 8 bytes.
Any string,
only requirement we have here is
that it should be more than 8 bytes.
So what would happen if we
passed input to this program?
Extremely important,
the vulnerability in the exploit
is going to rely on that input.
So I'm asking you,
think about the three different
inputs that we have here
in these three choices.
And, could defeat, the answer to that is
that whatever check that we're
providing, that should fail.
Okay, defeating here just means
the password check should fail.
So remember, if we exactly pass
this the answer should be yes.
If it's anything different than this,
the answer should be no.
And rejected or
allowed should be printed at the end.
So defeating means actually producing
a result that is not what I just said.
Giving incorrect password, and getting
an allowed answer, that would be bad.
That way you defeat the check.
Or giving the right password and
getting rejected is also defeating
the check that we're talking about.
So think about these three inputs.
Think about what I just said about,
what does it mean to defeat
the check that we're doing here.
And check all that result in
the check getting manipulated or
being defeated as we say here.