The answer is that both the first and
the second statements are true.
Computation is much less
than communication, so
you should probably avoid communication.
It's an unfortunate fact of life that
many computer scientists are very
good at this.
The second statement is essentially
about the relationship between beta
and alpha.
So think about that.
According to this, in looking at
this formula, it's evident that
you can deliver something like
on the order of, I don't know,
1,000 words or bytes in the same time
that it takes just to start a message.
So, that suggests it would be better to
send a few large messages rather than
many small messages.