Okay, here are the answers that I came up
with, let's go over this together. As in our example
we have one bit for the offset, and then
the next two are the index. So this here, I'm
going to look at these two bits, see index 00, and then go over and look at the
cache. I see there that the tag is 0 1, and oh that does not match my 1 0 tag of
the part of this address here, so that's a
miss. For the next one again I begin by consulting
the index, that's 11, so I go over here, and
I find that the tags part of my address and
of the cache match. So that looks like a
hit. Which of these two's values is it? Well, for
that I'd look at the offset, and I'd see that
it's the second one. So I write the value 99.
For the third one, again, the index is here, 1 0. I go and look at that in
my table. I see I have a tag,1 0,
and oh, that matches the tag part of this address.
So it's another hit. Which of these two values
is it? Well I go look at the offset, that's
zero, so it's this first one, 5 7. And
lastly, again we'll start by looking at the index That's
one one, and up, the tags do not match, so that's a miss.