Let's add Stack Views to Pitch Perfect.
Open the Main.storyboard file and
navigate to the Play Sounds View Controller Scene.
I haven selected it in
the document outline and then let's
select the View for this View Controller.
In the attributes inspector, let's
change it’s background back to white.
There we go. Ok now to add the Stack
Views.
We're going to have a Vertical Stack
View as our base with Horizontal Stack
Views embedded inside of it.
make sure the object library is open
here in the bottom right and put in the
words “stack”. You should see Horizontal
and Vertical Stack Views. Drag a Vertical
Stack View onto the View. We can see it
now in the document outline. Hold control
and drag diagonally from the Stack View
back to the View. with shift held down,
select Leading Space to Container Margin,
Trailing Space to Container Margin,
Vertical Spacing to Top Layout Guide and
Vertical Spacing to Bottom Layout Guide.
And then add the Constraints. This will
add the constraints we need, but the
Stack View is still the wrong size.
The reason that the size of the Stack
View is incorrect is because the
constraints which were automatically
created have constant values that tried
to fix the size of the Stack View to
what we see here. What we need to do is
change the constant for each of these
constraints so that the size of the
Stack View is equal to the size of its
containing View. To do this, we need to
select each constraint in the document
outline and set its constant to 0.
And as you do this, you'll notice that
the Stack View begins to change its size.
Once you finish setting all the
constants to 0, the Stack View will be the
same size as the View for our
PlaySoundsViewController. Let's make sure
the main Vertical Stack View has the
correct alignment and distribution
properties. With the Stack View selected
from the document outline, choose Fill
for Alignment and Fill Equally for
Distribution and make sure the Spacing
is set to zero as you see here. From the
object library, drag a Horizontal Stack View
underneath the Vertical Stack View
in the document outline. Select the
Horizontal Stack View in the document
outline and make sure its Alignment is
set to Fill and Distribution is set to
Fill Equally. In the next step, we're
going to add the buttons for the slow
and fast audio playback.