We can use Tag Manager to publish the
daily special in different languages.
Not everyone speaks English after all.
I'll show you the process and
then you will do it.
Let's take a look at the built
in variables in Tag Manager.
Go to variables, and
you see them grouped by application,
utilities, and device.
We'll be using the language variable.
Make sure that it's selected,
the little check box is green.
We're going to use the language built
in variable to define a trigger that
determines which version of
the daily special to show.
[FOREIGN].
So next rename the daily special
variable to daily-special-en,
because it's going to
have the English version.
So the name of the variable is just for
your use.
The code doesn't refer
to the name of variable.
What the code refers to is the key in
the value that you've configured for
the variable.
So, here it's daily-special,
and we can't change that.
Then create a custom
trigger by clicking Custom.
Click New.
And we're going to call the trigger,
english-trigger.
So it's a custom event, and that's fine.
Here in Fire On, in this first menu,
you see a list of the built in
variables that were enabled.
So go ahead and choose Language,
and then in this middle field,
we don't want it to be contained.
Just set it to equals.
And over here, the last field enter en.
If you wanted more rules for
the trigger, you'd enter plus and
add then but
we're not going to do that right now.
And then save the trigger.
And down here,
click the X to delete Always
because we don't want to use
this trigger Always any longer.
We only want to use it when
the user's device is set to English.
And save the variable.
So over here in the trigger screen,
we see the english-trigger.
Now make a copy of it, and
rename the copy the french-trigger.
And in this case we want it to
fire when the language equals fr.
And Save Trigger.
Now we have two Triggers.
Now back in the variables screen, make
a copy of the daily-special-en variable.
Copy it, call the copy daily-special-fr.
This variable's going to hold
the French Daily special, so
we need a French translation.
So copy the value.
If you speak French, obviously just go
ahead and translate it, but otherwise
copy the value and go to Google
Translate to translate it to French.
I'm going to copy this and
go back to Tag Manager.
So, you have to leave
the daily special as it is.
Don't translate the key, just the value.
The one thing to notice here is that
my menu included the word d'epice.
And it has a d'.
These kind of apostrophes
show a plush in French but
here is the value of the variable.
This apostrophe's actually going to
be interpreted as the closing
delimiter of this string.
So we need to escape
the apostrophe with a backslash.
Oh, and there's another one, [FOREIGN].
Now see the innate,
it says Enable When english-trigger,
well we don't want that.
We want the french-trigger,
not the english-trigger.
And now, Create Variable.
So, to summarize,
I've got two variables, one for English,
one for French.
And I've got two triggers, one for
English and one for French.
We have the English and
French versions of the daily special.
And we've defined triggers for
each language.
Got to publish the changes.
Now it's your turn.
Make sure that in the built in
variables, that language is selected.
Then go to the variables screen and
rename the daily special
variable to daily-special-en.
And while you're editing
the daily-special-en variable,
create the english-trigger and
delete the Always trigger.
Create the french-trigger,
create the daily-special-fr variable and
get the french translation
of your daily special.
Don't forget to publish your changes.
Strangely enough,
that's an easy one to forget to do.
So go ahead and do these steps.
Check boxes as you go and then in
the next video, we'll try it out.