Hi everyone, it's Jared.
I'm going to be joining you
this weekend for iOS Things.
Let's take a peek into the future and
see the final version of the app
you'll be building with Firebase.
This is Friendly Chat.
Friendly Chat is a chat app that allows
you to chat with friends in real-time
and send texts and photo messages.
So as we can see, we're logged in to
the main Friendly Chat interface, and
there are a few text messages
as well as some photo messages.
I'm going to go ahead and
send a message myself right now.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And this is sent in real-time, but
it'd be even cooler to show that I can
send a message from another device or
another simulator, and have it appear
here in my simulator in real-time.
So I'm going to go off screen.
You're not going to see this step, and
send a message from another simulator.
And we should see it populate here.
Awesome, and there it is.
Now, this isn't the only screen.
Let me log out and
show you the log in screen.
On the login screen,
we'll be working with various
ways to authorize ourselves
to use the Friendly Chat app.
And we can log in with just a regular
email, or even with Google.
And that's Friendly Chat.