In the last few videos, we described
some issues with remote communication
and the RPC mechanisms that solve them.
This included the binding
mechanism that's used so
that the clients can figure
out how to find the server and
what is the server that they need
to talk to in the first place.
We discuss the use of interface
definitional languages,
to determine how to
package arguments and
results that are being exchanged
among the client and the server.
And in that sense, the IDL is used
to specify how the client and
the server talk to one another.
How they are able to unders,
understand each other.
Next, we observe the problem of
dealing with pointers as arguments
in remote procedure calls.
And we said that, the use of pointers
should either be completely disallowed,
or that the RPC system should build
in some kind of support to serialize
the data that's being pointed.
Finally, we'll also talk about
partial failures, and explained
how it is tricky to determine exactly
what went wrong in an RPC system.
And that instead, the RPC run-time
provides some special errors and
tries to, in as much as possible,
determine what exactly was the cause
of the error without making any kind of
guarantees that it will be able
to provide a precise answer.
For all of these, we mention that there
are multiple choices that can be made in
the concrete implementation
of an RPC system.
For instance, for binding,
we can choose to have a distributed or
a per machine registry.
Or we can choose to use
a language agnostic or
language specific interface
definition language.
In summary,
these issues define the design space for
an RPC system in different RPC or
RPC like solutions, we'll make
different choices in this space.
And we will also very briefly contrast
this with the RPC like support in Java
called remote method invocations or
Java RMI