Let's look at a very simple
one-dimensional example.
Now that's not very exciting but
we've got our our one-dimension stage so
x is where is this
thing along some line.
I may have state that says where it is,
I might also have state
about how fast it's moving.
So here, what I'm showing you is
a state vector that's both position and
velocity.
So, here, our state vector x is,
I'm using p for position instead of x,
'because otherwise those x's
would get too confusing.
So, we have p and v.
What's v?
Velocity.
All right?
Now, going way back to, physics that
you took in either 12th grade or
10th grade, 8th grade, or
if you're really smart, 3rd grade.
You'd learn some very simple,
updated equations, right?
That basically your belief about where
the point would be at some time,
t would be wherever it was at t minus 1.
Plus delta t times
whatever the velocity was.
All right?
That's just simple integration by
velocity.
And then you'll notice there
this little element here.
That epsilon, that's noise.
That says, oh, there's some
noise that's been added, right?
So maybe things aren't exactly perfect.
Further more, I'm assuming
that my velocity is constant,
except that some noise
gets added to that.
That is, I might speed up or slow down a
little bit, but it's totally random, so
I don't know anything about it, and
so that's also going to be noise.
Now, I can write these same set of
equations in a very simple matrix form,
okay?
And here it is,
that x at time t is dx plus noise.
And here is this matrix, right?
This is that matrix one delta t 0 1.
Which times the state vector,
there's our state vector there.
Plus noise, gives us what your
next state vector will be.
So this is a linear dynamics model.
We're using position and
velocity as your state.
Now what are we going to measure?
Well, maybe we can only
measure the position.
So even though my state that I'm trying
to estimate is position and velocity.
Maybe I only measure the position.
I've got a little radar thing
that pings out and says, oh,
okay, I think this thing
is about 2.4 meters away.
All right?
So, that would be just a matrix
of 1 0 that multiplies the state,
cause all it does is it pulls out the,
the position.
And again there's noise.
Because there's noise in my measurement.
Here's my m matrix, so
this is the same linear model
that I have for measurements.
So I have a linear dynamics model,
and I have a linear measurement model.