Check it out,
this is me completing the exercise.
On the left side I'm typing without
using keyboard shortcuts and on
the right side I'm doing the same thing,
but this time with keyboard shortcuts.
Notice how much faster I am on the right
side using keyboard shortcuts.
On the right side I'm almost done and
on the left side I've hardly started.
If I speed this up,
you can see it took me only1 minute and
38 seconds to complete the exercise
with keyboard shortcuts.
But on the left side
I'm still typing away.
If I fast forward to the end it took
me another 84 seconds to finish
the exercise without keyboard shortcuts.
That's a huge difference.
By using keyboard shortcuts you will no
doubt increase the amount of code you
can write in a given period of time.
And as you continue to practice and
adopt more keyboard shortcuts
you will only improve.