The first one says,
we are traversing the ACL and
we run into an ACE that says, this user
does have access to this resource.
You can stop right there.
So this talking about termination
of traversal that we are doing.
Saying, you stop right there and
grant access to the user
who's making the request.
Oh, this is not correct, because we
said, there is a possibility that there
is another ACE that
contains a negative access.
So we said all students has positive,
Alice had negative, so
then we have to go to
Alice's ACE as well.
So we can't stop at the first one,
positive one that we run into.
So this one, is not a correct answer.
The next one, a negative or
deny ACE is found,
you actually can stop right there
because negative takes precedence.
If there's a negative ACE, then maybe
a positive somebody else in the list,
it doesn't matter, okay?
Because this is going to
take precedence anyway.
Or, sometimes we may have
to traverse unless use or
implement a list in a smart fashion,
that actually Windows does do that.
But and it does that by putting negative
ACE's in the front of the list.
But if you don't do that optimization or
that smart thing that I just mentioned,
then you have to actually traverse the
entire list to make sure that there is
no negative or
deny access ACE anywhere in the list.