So rmdir -f junk doesn't work,
since rmdir doesn't
understand -f as an option.
curl -o junk empty, well, this curl
command won't actually do anything.
Curl is for downloading from a web
URL and empty isn't one of those.
rm -r junk is the right answer.
The r stands for recursive.
And this is the standard way to
erase an entire directory and
all of its contents.
Any files or
directories that may be inside it and
anything inside those directories,
and so on.
And mv junk trash will do
one of two different things.
If there is a directory called trash,
it'll move junk to inside of it.
And if there isn't a directory called
trash, it'll rename junk to trash.
So, again the correct answer for
removing the entire junk
directory is rm -r junk.
And the junk that was there is now gone.