We're excited about the portfolio
apps that you'll be writing.
If you're going to install these
projects on a physical device,
you'll need a paid Apple
developer account.
It can be fun to see your own apps on
a phone and it's nice for debugging.
But you won't need a paid Apple
developer account to complete
the nanodegree.
All of the projects can be built and
tested in the simulator which is free.
Let's take a look at the apps.
The first app is called Pitch Perfect.
It lets you record sounds and
play them back with modulation.
This app is a lot of fun, and
you can share it with your friends.
After that, you can dive deeper
into user interface development
with a Meme Me app.
It's an app that lets you
create custom memes and
share them with your friends
in a number of ways.
Text, email, Instagram, and others.
The third portfolio app
is called On The Map.
It lets you post a description of your
study location and a link to some of
your work and then download the
locations and links of fellow students.
The focus is on networking.
You'll authenticate with
the Udacity back end using the same
mechanisms that the Udacity app uses.
Fourth app is called Virtual Tourist.
You can tour the world
without leaving home,
and keep a photo album of your travels.
The Apple showcase your
abilities with core data.
The last app is the Capstone
of your portfolio.
We're going to ask you invent,
design, and develop your own app.
They'll take it all the way from
the drawing board to the App Store.
We strongly believe that a hands on,
app writing approach is important for
two reasons,
it's a great way to learn and
it gives you a chance to
develop a valuable portfolio.
We've chosen the first four apps
carefully to emphasize important skills.
We always look forward to seeing what
you dream up for the Capstone project.