All right, so I've downloaded
SQLite from the website and
I saved it off here.
So in my C directory,
I created a folder called sqlite and
then into it,
I pasted the sqlite3 program.
So you might have saved it
off somewhere else, but
this is the path where I've
saved off the program.
So if all downloaded correctly,
we should be able to go into the command
prompt, navigate into this folder and
then start the sqlite3 program,
so let's check that out.
So now here I am in the C directory, and
I've navigated to the SQLite3 folder.
And we can double check that,
that's where we are by typing
this command echo, echo is
a command that tells the computer to
pronounce something to the screen.
And then I'm going to type the %cd%,
and cd here stands for
current directory, and these two
delimiters here just indicate that
rather than printing out just explicitly
the letters cd to the screen,
I want it to print out whatever
the current directory is.
So I might hit enter and
here to the screen,
it printed out that yes I am correctly
in the sqlite folder like I expected.
So note that if you're on a Mac, the
command to do this will just be pwd, but
I'm on a Windows right now.
All right, so now from here,
to get into the SQLite3 program,
I'm going to type sqlite3 and
then hit Enter.
So that took us into the program
itself and this program here
will allow us to download and create and
be able to modified databases.
So note that in upcoming text commands
that I'll be typing into the command
prompt, they'll be shown also
as text below in this video.
And I highly suggest that
you type them along with me.
But if you do end up being stuck or need
some text to compare your commands to,
the ones listed below will
be about to help you out.
Also note that the commands
will only successfully work,
if you've properly downloaded
the SQLite 3 program.
So in the case that you
mistype a command or
you've installed SQLite 3 incorrectly,
you might see a message such as
bash sqlite 3 command not found or
something similar.
So if you do see some kind of error,
remember to check your spelling, also
look at the text commands below, and
if that doesn't work, maybe uninstalling
and then reinstalling everything again.
So from here to know that
I'm in SQLite 3 program,
I can see that the version number is
here and that it has provided some text
here to tell me how to get to the help
prompts, or to open up a file.
So now that we're in the program,
the question is, what do we type here?
Well, English text won't
work in this case.
And we've learned about different
computer languages such as Java and
XML which you've become
intimately familiar with.
So XML is a language that, primarily for
Android, is specialized for
generating layouts.
Whereas Java is specialized for
coding the logic of the program.
So our SQLite 3 program understands
another computer language
that's called SQL and that's short for
structured query language.
So to reiterate,
SQLite is a database library, and
it understands the SQL
computer language.
So, SQL is a computer language that is
optimized for working with databases.
And unlike Java, which has language for
making classes, variables and
control flow statements,
SQL is all about creating tables and
then adding and removing and
then manipulating entries within them.
Now, unlike Android Studio, where you
type a program and then press Run, well,
here with SQLite is much more
like having a very one-sided
conversation with your computer.
Or, actually, it's more like just
ordering a computer to do a bunch of
things for you, but you get the point.
So, for example, if I'm going to
order the computer to open new file,
a file that I want to call pets db.
I'm going to type in .open pets.db and
then, hit Enter.
So, since the pets database didn't exist
before, what I just did created it.
Now we should be able
to see in the folder.
So let's check that out.
So let's go back to our directory here.
And notice here that the pets.db
file is created for us.
So what I just demonstrated here was
that I can type any instructions into
SQL here, and as soon as I press enter,
the command happens immediately.
So when we first enter the program,
SQLite 3 let us know that
there's a helpful .help command that
we can use to help find useful hints.
So let's try that one out, .help,
and if you noticed, SQLite 3 provided us
a big list of all the different
commands that are available.
So here's a list of the commands.
And then here's a little
description about each of them.
Now one that catches my
eye here is the .quit, and
it allows us to exit the program.
So let's try that one out.
So I'm going to type .quit,
and now at this point,
I'm just looking at my normal terminal.
So I'm no longer using
the SQLite program.
And remember here, sqlite is the name
of the folder that I've saved it in,
not the name of the program itself.
And that's indicated by
the C directory here.
So it's important to note
the difference between the sqlite and
the normal terminal.
So notice here if I type .help,
the computer doesn't recognized it.
Because only the SQLite3 program
recognizes this .help command.
Now I'm going to open
SQLite3 program again.
But this time I'm going to start it off
by giving it the name of the database
that I wanted to be opened to,
directly once I'm in the program.
So typing sqlite3, is the name of
the program and then we'll put space,
and then pets.db.
So telling the program that I want to
jump directly into the pets database.
So I'm going to hit Enter.
And so there you have it, so I've gone
into the SQLite program, and remember
this prompt looks different from this
prompt, and I've opened up the pets.db.
All right, so
now you know how to open up SQLite 3,
close as SQLite3, and
how to open up a database file?
So now let's go ahead to
making a table for database.