First, the challenge values used
in an authentication protocol
can be repeatedly used
in multiple sessions.
This is false.
If the challenge values are repeated
then there's a chance that
the attacker can capture and replay
the same challenge and response and
impersonate Alice or Bob.
Second, the authentication
messages can be captured and
replayed by an adversary.
This is true.
We should always assume that the
messages that are sent over the Internet
can be captured by the adversary.
An adversary can attempt to replay them
in order to impersonate Alice or Bob.
Third, authentication can be one way,
for
example only authenticating
Alice to Bob.
This is true, as we have discussed
the first three steps of the protocol
authenticate Alice to Bob.