[Thrun] So let me ask you about dependence.
Suppose we flip 2 coins.
Our first coin is a fair coin, and we're going to denote the outcome by X1.
So the chance of X1 coming up heads is half.
But now we branch into picking a coin based on the first outcome.
So if the first outcome was heads,
you pick a coin whose probability of coming up heads is going to be 0.9.
The way I word this is by conditional probability,
probability of the second coin flip coming up heads
provided that or given that X1, the first coin flip, was heads, is 0.9.
The first coin flip might also come up tails,
in which case I pick a very different coin.
In this case I pick a coin which with 0.8 probability will once again give me tails,
conditioned on the first coin flip coming up tails.
So my question for you is,
what's the probability of the second coin flip coming up heads?