I chose to also ask a machine
learning question because
machine learning is a very big part of
data science and any data analyst job.
And it presents some unique,
some inequalities, right.
When you're trying to solve
a machine learning problem,
you really have to
think about how to make
that problem I'm presenting the way that
a computer can actually learn from it.
And that is something that
is not very easy to do.
You definitely need to understand
what machine learning is.
And also have that wit to come
up with the right features, and
that's what I'm looking for, that wit.
So in her case, she immediately
came up with one of the features.
Her first feature was whether
this person had received an email
from the same person.
That is an excellent feature, and
that's exactly what I'm looking for, for
the user to come up with
a good set of features,
which don't have to be
excellent by the way.
I just really want the person to be
able to come up with a couple features.
I want that ability to convert
a thought into a number.
And I also want a couple
of them to be really witty.
And a couple I mean one or two,
like the case of whether this person
had received an email from them before.
After coming up with some features,
then I asked her about what algorithms
she would use to fit this, what machine
elements she will use to interpret
these features and
actually come up with a classification.
I think this is a tricky
part of the question because
in this question I'm actually looking
to test her in machine learning.
I think this was the point
in the activity where she
struggled the most because the trick is,
right,
and I think she came up with
a quick algorithm first.
She said nine-based algorithm, and
this algorithm is a very,
very simple algorithm.
There's maybe not too much to talk
about when you have a nine base.
Yeah, so then I asked her to try
to come up with something deeper,
I was looking for anything.
Actually, it doesn't have
to be anything too deep.
Right from the beginning I was looking
for anything that sounded like logistic
regression which is one of
the most basic algorithms.
She said support vector machines,
which are an excellent
classification algorithm as well.
I think the part where it was
a little bit problematic for
her is that she said
support vector machines,
but maybe wasn't completely familiar
with support vector machines.
And my recommendation to anybody doing
a machine learning question is to almost
never mention an algorithm that you're
not very familiar about because you're
definitely going to start
getting tested on this.
The algorithm portion of the machine
learning question is usually a test,
more than a thought process.
And I think that's the part
that gives trouble the most.
But definitely be familiar with
whatever shape or algorithms you
suggest you will be using, or
you have used in your projects.
It definitely correlates with
the first question where I asked here
what is the project that you worked on?
If you used an algorithm
in that project,
you should definitely be very
familiar with how it works