As always we're going to
start with a hand simulation.
I'm going to look at line one first.
So, we declared a new variable called
raspberryPrice and set it to 5.
Okay, now this one's a little bit
interesting in that we have three
display areas this time,
display1, display2, and display3.
And we're just going to pretend that
there's three different text boxes.
Okay, so in text box 1 we're
going to display 1 box: $ and
then whatever the current value
of raspberryPrice is, which is 5.
Okay, in the next display area, we're
going to say 2 boxes: $ the current
value of raspberryPrice, 5, multiplied
by 2, which is going to be 10.
And in the third text box
we're going to say 3 boxes: $,
the current value of raspberryPrice
times 3, it's going to be 15.
So again, this is going to
print 1 box: $5, 2 boxes: $10.
It doesn't print any of this math,
it just prints the end value.
And then 3 boxes: $15.
And since raspberries are $5 a box,
well, that seems to work out.
So it looks like this code
is correct in this case.
There's one important thing
that I want you to note though,
which is really that there's only one
way to change the value of a variable,
and that's using
the assignment operator.
In these cases where we're
displaying some sort of math,
we're not actually changing
the value of raspberryPrice.
So throughout this program, the value
of raspberryPrice remains at 5,
even though we're printing 10 and 15.
That's because we're not using the
assignment operator anywhere but here.
All right,
let's look at the next question.