Starting at the first part of the quiz,
it needed a maximum.
So I added a max of 100,
that's easy enough.
The second one needed a minimum,
so I added a minimum of 0.
The third one needed both a minimum and
a maximum, so I added a minimum of 0 and
a maximum of 100, not too bad.
And the last one, the fourth part of
the quiz, needed a minimum, maximum and
a step so I added a minimum,
maximum and a step of 10 so
that the controls would jump up or
down by 10 each time.
And here's the input for
the bonus question.
In the bonus question, I challenged
you to add a pattern attribute with
a regular expression to validate
the letter grade going into the input.
Here's the one that I used which
looked for either an A or A+.
Or anything between a B and
D with a plus or
minus after it if it needed it,
or just an F.
Your regex may or may not have looked
different and that's totally fine.
Different school systems use
different grading systems so
use whatever works for you.
And here,
let me show you the form in action.
All right, it looks good,
each input is going up by 10,
it looks like, all the way up to 100.
Yep, won't go down all the way to 100.
All the way to 100, and won't go down.
And when I hit Calculate,
I still see an average.
And let me check this pattern attribute.
Let me see if this works.
I'm going to add a grade of M,
which is not a real grade.
So this should fail,
and let me hit Submit.
Oh, look at that.
This field needs to be filled out.
And that's because the required
attribute was on it.
So I filled that out, and
let me hit Submit again.
And now look,
I'm getting an error here that asks for
the requested format for this grade.
So clearly an M doesn't work.
Let me try an A.
Hey, look at that.
The form was submitted.
I really hope you're starting to see
just how useful these validation
attributes are.
They provide a fantastic first pass at
making sure the data that's going into
your forms is accurate.