We can also use this kind of
stuff to do tracking of features.
There are many types of
approaches to do this,
I'm going to just summarize two of them.
One is direct approaches to tracking,
where basically again, what I can do is
find a specific feature,
something that I'm interested in, or
interest point could be a corner, and
match it to a feature in the next frame.
So that would be much more point
tracking, finding a point,
or interest point, and
seeing where it is in the next frame.
Motion based approaches
are also widely used,
where basically we compute
motion at each and every pixel.
We do not find an interest point like
feature track detection had been doing,
which we applied for
variety of other projects but
here basically, it says I'm going to
look at each and every pixel, and
find that pixel again In the next frame.
This is a method called OPTICAL flow and
is also widely used in computer
vision types of methods.
Those of you who are taking the computer
version class or will take it sometime,
you'll learn a lot more about
OPTICAL flow in that class.