With the basic parts of our Sunshine app
finished, like downloading the data and
displaying it in a UI, your users
might want a little more control and
personalization over what they see.
>> Right, for example, I travel a lot.
And in some parts of the world
outside of California,
they have this weird
thing called weather.
So if I'm visiting friends in New York,
I want to be able to see if it's really
there and then,
maybe the rig got out of storage.
>> Right, and I like to see
my temperature settings and
Celsius degrees instead of
this Farenheit nonsense.
>> But, for those who us of US,
Bahamas and
Belize, Farenheit will work just fine.
So, how do we offer
the sort of customization.
Well, you've already seen things
like buttons and edit text.
But as we mentioned when talking
about rotating the app screen,
the state of those values doesn't
always automatically get saved.
>> Because of this, simply adding
views that take input isn't enough.
We need to think of how to save
that input throughout the different
life cycle changes that
the app might throw at us.
Including just shutting it
down without any warning.
>> In addition, many apps will
have this specific screens for
things like app settings and
configuration.
>> Luckily, Android provides us with
the tools to both save data, and
easily create a starting screens for
the app.
And how does Android do this?
Preferences.