Let's take the Inverse Warping example.
We basically have pixels
going this way and
now of course we have the inverse
of the transformation.
We want to basically create or
get every pixel from g x prime y prime
to its corresponding
location in this image.
Transformation is again the inverse and
now the question is,
what if a pixel comes from between
those two pixels, in this range?
Looking at it again, without the images.
Basically, see this pixel
now is falling in green, and
basically in this instance, what we
want to do is interpolate the color
value from the neighbors and
fill this in.
This will not have any holes and stuff,
but it will have minification problems.
Forward warp, that we talked about,
the forward warp will have more
problems with holes and overlaps