Finally, one last thing to show you just sort of in completeness.
So, you remember one dimensional case of the second derivative of the Gaussian.
So, what we have here is, this was our original Gaussian.
This second derivative was this inverted Mexican hat operator, and
when we applied that to f.
It's the same thing as taking the second derivative of the smoothed version.
We were looking for that spot there and those what are called zero-crossings
that, on that bottom graph, that corresponded to where the edges were, okay?
But to do this in two,
in two dimension is a little bit harder, and the reason is.
There's more than one direction to take our derivative.
So here we have our Gaussian, the formula there, and it,
you know, is this nice mountain in the middle.
But we have to take a derivative in one direction, and so,
you know, that's the one that's saying x, and there'd by one and Y.
And then on our second derivatives there'd be three choices.
I could take the partial of x again, so
that's a partial of f squared is partial of x twice.
I can do the partial of y, twice.
I can also do the partial of f with respect to y.
Which one am I supposed to use?
Well, the correct answer is,
you use what's referred to as a Laplacian of Gaussian.
The Laplacian operator, shown here, is this second derivative of x of
f with respect to x squared plus the secondary of f with respect to y squared.
And that's what actually gives you this Mexican hat operator symmetrically.
And if you apply that to the image and
you take the 0 crossings, you will get your edges.
And in fact, if you run the some demonstration code in matlab for edges.
You can take Canny edges, or you can take difference of Gaussians or
Laplacian of Gaussians, they're, they're almost identical.
And you can see, what that does is it's looking for
the 0 crossings and it's another way of getting the edges.
One of the challenges there is those tend to be closed counters all
the time whereas the Canny will only find you the,
the contours that have some magnitude support.
I would tell you most people, more people probably use canny for
just doing regular edge detection.