As we're defining a button,
we can have a number of images for
that button depending on its state.
Now possible states are the normal
look for the button,
what it looks like when it's pressed,
what it looks like when it has focus and
also what it looks like
when it's disabled.
To achieve this easily in Android,
to create these multiple states of
graphic for your button,
you create what is called a selector.
Now selector is simply an XML file
that you put in res/drawable.
You can call it whatever you like,
but for
this sample I called
my button_custom.XML.
Now in this file that you then
specify the drawable that you use for
each state.
I've started the file for you here,
how would you finish this to allow for
the disabled and
normal state of the button.
If you look closely, you can see I have
to draw both google_signin_pressed for
state_pressed, and
google_singin_focus for state_focused.
So think about how you would finish
this file for the disabled and
normal states of the button.
You'll see that in the next video.