We'll start by writing a new
method called escapedParameters.
We're going to want this method to take
a dictionary of the argument value,
aka keyvalue pairs in the URL,
so that's what this is.
And then we want to return a string
where they're correctly formatted and
don't have unsafe ASCII characters.
And also, each pair should be
separated by an ampersand.
I think this will start to make more
sense as we start building this method.
The first thing we'll do is check
if any parameters are provided.
If none are provided we can
just return the empty string.
Otherwise, let's create an array
to store each key value pair
as we format it.
Then let's loop through the dictionary
looking at the key value pairs.
For the keys, I don't think we
really need to do anything to them,
they're the argument names themselves.
And we can assume that they're
always safe ASCII characters.
And this is probably a safe
assumption for this simple app and
just knowing that the Flickr API
hasn't used key values or
argument names that are unsafe ASCII.
Then for the values,
we need to convert them into strings.
Because if we look at the method itself,
we're taking a string,
AnyObject dictionary, so it could be
that we pass in a value that's a number,
and we need to convert
that number to a string.
So we'll add this line of code to
convert the value into a string.
And then once it's a string, we need to
convert the string itself into an ASCII
compliant version of a string.
And we can do that by using this nice
stringByAddingPercentEncodingWith
all characters allowed, method.
And that's definitely a mouthful for
a method name, but
at least we know exactly what it does.
It takes one argument, a character set,
and that character set specifies
which characters are going to be
allowed in the string that it returns.
And in our case, there's a nice
character set that we can use called
NSCharacterSet.URLQueryAllowedCharacter-
Set.
And this is going to return characters
that are only considered safe ASCII.
Then once we have the key and value as
safe ASCII strings, we can add the equal
sign in the middle like this, and we can
append it to our keyValuePairs array.
And once we've converted
all the keyValuePairs,
we can join them into one string
with the joinWithSeparator method.
And the separator that we
want to use is the ampersand.
And we also can't forget to add
the question mark to the beginning,
that's what's going to set off all of
our argument value, or key value pairs.
Now once you've implemented
this method yourself,
you should be able to call it
using a dictionary like this.
So if you were to use these lines of
code and a correct version of the escape
parameters that you've implemented,
what would the output be?
So take some time and write this
method yourself, and then test
your implementation using this code,
and enter your answer in this text box.
If you correctly implemented
the escapeP arameters method,
then you should have returned
some variation of the string.
And the reason I'm saying variation is
because the argument name pairs could
show up in a different order.
Right now,
the quiz argument is the first one to
show up in this particular answer.
But because we can't be sure how
our escapeParameters method is
going to iterate through
the dictionary the argument key
pairs could show up in
any particular order.