To get the what's for dinner app, go to
udacity's GitHub repo for analytics and
tag manager.
So we've provided Android Studio
projects for the start of each lesson,
and also for the very final project,
which would be DinnerApp_FINAL.
You can download everything by
clicking the Download ZIP button, and
then the zip file downloads with all
the Android Studio projects in it.
So then,
find the downloaded zip file and
move it to the folder where you
have your Android Studio projects.
Expand the zip, and inside you'll
see the different directories for
the different projects.
So then, go to the Android Studio and
open DinnerApp_BEGIN.
And then compile it.
So one handy hint is if the Gradle files
get out of sync, you can force a resync
by going to Tools > Android >
Sync Project with Gradle Files.
And as you work through the course, you
can continue working in the same app, or
you can get the Android Studio Project
for the start of each lesson.
Okay, let's go do some work in the app.