Here, we can see
onActivityResult is implemented.
It takes a requestCode and
a resultCode as integers.
And it also takes an Intent
that we call data.
Then we want to take
a look at the requestCode.
And if it's RC_SIGN_IN, we will then
want to take a look at the resultCode.
If the resultCode is RESULT_OK.
Then we set our SignInProgress
to STATE_SIGN_IN.
That means that
the error was successful.
But we may want to continue
catching more errors.
Otherwise, if we didn't get a RESULT_OK,
then we believe that
we're actually signed in.
So we set our SignInProgress
to be signed in.
And then finally,
if we reach the stage where the Google
API client is still connecting.
Then we just want to call
GoogleApiClient.connect(), so
that we can continue the cycle.