Here are my answers to the questions.
For the first question, I got the cross
product was the vector -11.205,
-97.609, -105.685.
For the second question, the area
of the parallelogram is 142.122.
Finally, the area of
the triangle is 42.565.
Now, let's take a look
at the Python code.
The first code I wrote was
the cross function where I more or
less just copied
the formula from earlier.
The meat of this function is in
some exception catching clauses
in case self or
V isn't a vector in three dimensions.
I won't take too much time to go
through them except to say that in my
implementation.
If both vectors are in two dimensions
I add a Z coordinate of 0 to each.
And then take the cross product
of the resulting vectors.
Otherwise the function
raises an exception.
The remaining two
functions are much smaller.
To find the area the parallelogram, I
first take the cross product of the two
vectors and return its magnitude, and
to find the area of the triangle,
I just return one half
the area of the parallelogram.
After coding all the functions,
I ran this code here to find the answers
to the questions asked earlier.