Any answer you might have given for
this quiz should work, so
let's go over some of these items.
All right, I'm going to scroll down and
download a spreadsheet for magnitude 4.5
and higher earthquakes that occurred
within the past seven days.
And then I'm just going to
import this into Google Sheets.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Cool, this lets me look at
the data a little easier.
All right, so
I'll reposition these cells.
Now I can see everything clearly.
By the way,
this data is given to us in CSV format.
And CSV just stands for
comma-separated values.
This is a very simple text based format
that puts each row of data on its own
line, and
the columns are separated by commas.
Most spreadsheet programs,
including Excel and Google Sheets,
support importing CSV files,
which we just did.
Here I can browse all
the data in a spreadsheet.
I can see the columns for
time, latitude, longitude,
depth, magnitude,
even over here I have place.
So I imagine for this half it's probable
that I want to display things like
place, time, and of course magnitude.
Those would be my top picks for
the first round of this half.
Later on I might want to add things
like latitude, longitude, and depth.