[Narrator] There are other problems with
the search paradigm.
The second one is that the tree could be very deep,
and the reason is we might be able to
circle forever in the area over here
without reaching the goal state, and
that makes for a very deep tree, and until
we reach the goal state, we won't even know
it's the best possible action.
So conventional planning might have difficulties
with basically infinite loops.
The third problem is that many states
recur in the search.
In a star, we were careful
to visit each state only once,
but here because the actions might
carry you back here to the same state,
C1 is, for example, over here and over here.
You might find that many states in the tree
might be visited many, many different times.
Now if you had a state it doesn't really matter how you got there.
Yet, the tree doesn't understand this, and it
might expand states more than once.
These are the 3 problems
that are overcome by our policy method,
and this motivates in part by calculating policies
is so much better of an idea than using
conventional planning and still casting environments.
So let's get back to the policy case.