So a problem that often
confuses new Android developers
is usually around rotation, right?
So a common issue you'll see is
like if I have a progress bar or
I have suppose I'm building a game and
I have a score or something.
But when I rotate, I lose that
information I lose like maybe
the progress either set it out or
the score that I calculated at the time.
Can you explain to me in some more
detail why that is occurring?
>> Right, so this has to do with one
of the fundamental concepts of Android
development and
the Android operating system,
which is the activity lifecycle or
the fragment lifecycle as well.
So when you create a fragment,
it's attached your activity.
When you rotate a device
your activity is destroyed,
your fragment will be destroyed.
And so if you don't have any sort of
check to see if your application has
been running, that activity will reset
as if it's the first time it opened.
Everything will, any sort of data or
something that you change throughout
the lifecycle of the application
will then start anew.
>> So what you're saying is that,
this is all information that was
either set by the user,
before the activity started?
So these are things where they mutated
state while the activity was running and
then we need to save those off.
>> Right.
>> Beforehand.
>> Right, and even if we do save them
somewhere and we turn the device again,
if we don't reference that,
nothing's going to happen.
The way around this is to in your
own create usually for your activity
you would have if saved instance state
is not able to know the saved instance
state is something that Android
uses to to account for this.
So, you check if it's not equal to null
because if it is not equal to null that
means your activity or your application
was running before it got to this point.
So before this activity was
created it was running and
there we can reference some
data that we wanted to save and
we can have it translate over to
the rotation with a new activity.
>> Yes of the save state
is effectively saying,
you're saying if it's null that means
this is the first time it's ever run.
>> Right.
>> And
if it's not null will then
something has occurred.
And someone cared enough to
write this out to a bundle.
So it could be progress or things, so
in this application maybe it's a game.
I have more than just
a simple primitive, right?
Maybe I have a really
slightly complex object.
I have a lot of,
not necessarily a lot, but
I mean certainly more data than an
integer or string or something simple.
What are some ways that I could
write that out to the bundle?
>> So one, there's a couple ways
to pass information through.
When you have something complex,
you might want to use
something like a par syllable.
Perhaps, or a database.
Maybe through a content provider or
something like that.
Or even if you're accessing something on
the network you would want to account
for that so if you're maybe-
>> So you're saying maybe like caching
results so that I don't have
to like redo their press.
>> Yeah, so
say if you're using a cloud database.
Cloud storage you could
reference that as well,
that could be through
a content provider.
So instead of just maybe passing strings
or something through it in ten or
saving something simple
in as shared preferences.
You would want to go with something more
robust like that database or parcelable.
>> Yeah, that makes sense because we
were saying is if we stored it in
a database, then when I rotate it,
I really don't have to worry about
saving that state in and out.
Because it's going to get loaded
from the database regardless.
And the state which should update.
I'm wondering, too,
why wouldn't I use something like
Serializable, for instead of a parsable?
>> So
I'm not too familiar with Serializable.
I know the general idea of it and
I think it's some sort of
persistent object that's related to
a database but I've never had to use it.
>> So a lot of times it's Serializable's
very much a Java concept.
And it was used very often where you're
a way of writing out a class and
so you could write out a class for
serializable.
But generally parsable like
you suggested is a better way.
Because Serializable
tends to be very slow.
It uses, it has to use reflection.
It has to use other things.
So, definitely building a parsable
would be a better idea.
>> Okay.