Now that we've seen some sorts of
information that we can store in
a database table, let's talk about
how our code talks to a database.
When our code fetches data out
of a database it does this by
sending a query, in response,
the database will
send us a result containing a new
table with the data that we asked for.
Depending on the specifics of our
environment our code might be talking to
the database over the network, or
it might just be calling a library
that keeps a database on local disk.
Those design details would
be important later but for
now we can actually ignore them.
The basics of databases work the same
no matter what the implementation is.
So let's take a look at running
some queries in SQL against
an actual database.
Don't worry about the syntax right now,
we'll see that in the next lesson.
Okay, so here's a query we saw before,
select food from diet where
species equals orangutan.
And when we run it, here is the result.
Now, something to notice about
the result is that it's a table.
It has two rows, even says two rows
down underneath the table, and
it has one column,
the food column that we asked for.
So running a query against the database
isn't like returning a single value from
a function,
it's more like returning a list,
even if there might only be one element.
In fact, even if we ask the database for
2 plus 2 like this.
The answer is still actually a table
with one column and one row.
If we ask the database for the answers
to three arithmetic problems at
once then we'll get back
a table with a single row and
three columns, each one of them
giving one of the answers.
You might have noticed that these
columns have rather unusual names,
they all are question marks
column question mark.
If we want to give them more descriptive
names we can do that, by using as sum
here we get back still a table
still with one row and
one column, but now the column has
a more descriptive name of sum
instead of question mark column,
question mark.