There are a lot of other
resources besides the manual for
finding out about shell command stuff.
Even experienced users can always
find something new that can be
done in the shell.
But if you don't know what a command
does and you're not sure if you want to
run it, applying your favorite search
engine to the problem is a good idea.
You can put any shell command
into Google or DuckDuckGo or
Yahoo or whatever and
usually find a lot of help.
In fact, let's do that now.
Here's a command that you should
definitely research, but don't run it.
Seriously, don't.
Open up your favorite search engine and
look up this command, rm -rf /.
You might need a search keyword
such as shell or command.
What does this command do?
What do the r and the f stand for?
Put your description of what
this command does based on your
research here.
And does the r stand for
read, recursive, or root?
And does the f stand for
force, file, or flag?