Comparing with the external firewall,
an internal firewall performs
more stringent filtering.
This is because the internal network
would require more protection,
than the public facing systems on a DMZ.
The internal firewall protects
the remainder of the enterprise network
from attacks launched from the DMZ.
For example, if the public facing web
server in the DMZ is compromised,
the internal firewall is to stop attacks
from that compromised web server.
In addition,
the internal firewall also controls
access to the DMZ from internal network.
For example, only the authorized
traffic from the internal network
can reach to the DMZ to change the
settings of a public facing web server.
For example, such activities must
be from a sys admin's work station.
In addition, multiple internal firewalls
can be used to protect different
parts of the internal
network from each other.
That is, even if one part of the
internal network has been compromised,
the other parts are still
being protected by their own
internal firewalls.