Now let's talk about how to include
color and font styles in this app.
In the Colors and Fonts activity starter
code, we already have a few examples
of colored views and text views
of different font families and
sizes, just so
you can see what they look like.
Then later, you'll see how
to use some simple font and
color styles to add consistency
to different layouts.
Right now, we will be changing an add
in to the colors in phones activity.
To add new colors, I want to add them
to a file in the values folder, and
our resources directory.
Its named colors.xml.
And this is in the same values
folders that contains the strings
which you've seen before.
In this colors.xml file,
you already sen some colors here.
With the name and the hex code that
defines their color, the name is color
primary, color primary dark, and
color accent are especially important.
These are names for the default app in
Android, so when your app is created,
components like the menu bar and
this special buttons like Fabs or
radio buttons who will be
colored base on these values.
And when I run these app you can see
these main colors in the top menu bar.
And also in the views displayed
in our Colors and Fonts activity.
And you can see a preview of these
colors in swatches to the left
of the text in Android studio.
For this app, I want the primary
color to be a dark purple.
So I'll change the primary and
the primary dark colors to the hex codes
provided in the comment above and
I can just copy and paste from here.
I will also change the accent color to
be orange and as I change these hex
codes, you should see to the left
that these color swatches change.
I also want to add a third
light primary color and
I will name this color primary light and
I will give this a light purple color.
I am actually getting these hex values
from the material design color pallet
for Android which has
pre-chosen vibrant pallets.
And now, if we run our app,
we'll see that the menu bar and
our list of activities has
changed from blue to purple.
And let's take a look at our Colors and
Fonts activity.
The colored views here
have changed as well.
This is because in our Color and
Fonts Layout XML.
We have views with their
background set to these colors.
If we look at our
Color Font Activity XML.
We can see that each of these views has
a background set to different color.
The first is color primary,
the second color primary dark and
the third are accent color.
So when we change these values
in our colors.XML file,
that change was
reflected in these views.
Let's create one more view at the top of
this layout to display our newly created
primary light color.
I'll give it an id of primaryLight and
the same layout width and
height as our other views.
Then I'll set its background
to our colorPrimaryLight.
And we know this is a color
resource because of this @color
part of this value.
Now let's save this and
run our app again.
Now if we click on our colors and
fonts activity, we can see our
light purple color appear.
Okay, now let's move
on to our text views.
There are a lot of text views in here,
all displaying a different size and
font family of the Roboto font.
Let's take a look at the XML.
If we scroll down in our
color_font_activity XML,
we see a lot of text views.
In the first text view we see that
the text to size property is set
to 56 sp and
the font family to sans serif light and
this is a thinner,
lighter text family than the default.
We also see some Views with
a text style property.
This can be set to bold,
italic or normal.
You can also set a text
color if you want to.
And in the app these views display
text that describes their style,
font family and size.
>From 56 sp down to 20 sp.
Back to the xml, let's scroll down to
the bottom and add one more text view.
I'll create a view with
a text size equal to 16 sp
In the font family of
san-serif-smallcaps.
And smallcaps is all capital letters.
And the text of display
will be Smallcaps 16sp,
in fact I'll actually create
the string resource for this.
So, I'll go to our strings.xml and
create a new string named
smallcaps_16 that displays this text.
Then in our activity code I
can reference that string.
And that's it.
Let's run our app again.
Now in your colors and fonts,
you can see our new color and
our new text view, small caps, 16SP.
Next, it'll be your turn to change
the color scheme and create views.
Also, feel free to look
around this code and create
more views to test out the appearance
of different colors and fonts.