When you've written code before, you've
used data structures such as variables,
lists, dictionaries, and objects.
These all let you store information
while your program is running.
You can build up a complex data
structure like a list of dictionaries of
objects, and when your program exits,
that structure will be gone from memory.
You've probably worked with files, for
instance, the files
containing your own code.
If you edit code in a text editor and
save it, then quit the editor,
your code doesn't vanish the way
a variable does, when the program exits.
The file is persistent, or
durable, whereas in memory data
is ephemeral, or temporary.
Programs can read and write files just
fine, so why bother with databases?
Well, there are several different
kinds of databases, but
what they all have in common is
that they give us both persistence,
like a file, as well as data structures
for storing and searching our data,
usually much faster and
easier than we could search a flat file.
They also make it possible for multiple
programs or users to access, and
modify data at the same time without
stepping on each other's toes, or
accidentally undoing
each other's changes.
That's generally not
possible with flat files.
If two programs write a new version
of a file at the same time,
then one will overwrite the other.
So these other sorts of
databases do all that, but
relational databases do even more.
Aside from storing your data,
relational databases also offer very
flexible tools for
querying and summarizing data.
If we're doing comparisons, and
if we're drawing connections between
related pieces of information.
They also let us set up constraints
which are rules to ensure the changes to
our data are consistent.
We'll see more about those
later in the course.
Now, let's see how relational
data bases store data.