To define linear regression,
we need to understand what we are trying to minimize.
The word is called here, are loss function
and the loss function is the amount of residual error we obtain
after fitting the linear function as good as possible.
The residual error is the sum of all training examples,
J of YJ, which is the target label,
minus our prediction, which is W1 XJ minus W0 to the square.
This is the quadratic error between our target labels
and what our best hypothesis can produce.
The minimizing of loss
is used for linear regression or any regression problem,
and you can write it as follows:
Our solution to the regression problem W*
is the arg min of the loss over all possible vectors W.