Well, one obvious answer is HTTP. This is a web based application, and most,
web communication uses the HTTP protocol. These days,
a second protocol often is part of these kinds of interactions, and
that's AJAX, in which the web browser, and the web server cooperate.
In a more timely fashion, then going in a kind of round trip HTTP page rewrite
situation. Third, is the fact that, ultimately we're updating a database.
Typical databases are relational databases and the standard language for dealing
with relational databases is SQL. So SQL can be thought of as a protocol.
In typical applications like that, the SQL is embedded inside of PHP.
You can think of PHP, as a language but any language is in itself a protocol,
that is, has certain rules for how it's programs are expressed.