So that ends the lesson on extrinsics or extrinsic.
Not really calibration, because we're going to do the calibration part.
So I should change the title of the, that was about extrinsic geometry.
Later we're going to do extrinsic calibration where we
figure out how a camera is oriented in the world.
We're going to have to revisit this whole thing when we talk
about mapping from world points to a location on an image plane, all right.
But before we can do that, we're going to have to talk about,
once I have the location of a point in a camera frame,
where does that point end up in the image?
And that's the intrinsic and we're going to do that at the next lesson.