To answer this question, let's look at
the execution scenario in this system.
T3 is the first one to
arrive in the system, and
it will be the only task for a while.
So, T3 will be the first
one to be scheduled.
At time, T3 it will be preempted,
and task T2 will start executing,
because it has higher priority than T3,
at time T5.
Task 1 will arrive, and
that one will execute for three seconds.
T1 will preempt the execution of T2,
because T1 has higher priority than T2,
according to this assumption.
And then, we have two more seconds
to finish the execution of T2,
followed by the execution of
the lowest priority task, T3.
So, that one,
we had one more second remaining.
So, the finishing times of the three
tasks according to this diagram
are going to be 8 seconds,
10 seconds and 11 seconds, respectively.