One thing to notice is that by
using document.queryselector or
document.getelementbyID, we
get a dom node back.
There's the dom node.
And here we can see the same thing
by saving the footer element
by grabbing its ID.
Now, wouldn't it be much better
if we got a D3 object back, so
that way we can use other
D3 methods on this element?
If we tried using a D3 method,
like the append method,
which adds elements to
an existing element,
then we'll get an error in the console
saying that the method is not defined.
This is because the variable elem
does not contain a D3 selection, and
it doesn't have the method
append available.
It's really just a plain dom node.
You can inspect the methods available by
typing in a dot after the variable name.
So, for element variable, these are the
different methods that are available.
In order to be able to use the full
power of the D3 chainable API,
we need to create a D3 selection.
I'll explain more about the chainable
nature of the API, but for
now let's just focus on
these D3 selections.
Looking at the documentation,
I want to find a method to select
different elements on the web page.
It looks like this method,
select or select all, will do.
Let's read more about it.
The D3 select function looks very
similar to document dot query selector
which you saw earlier,
and it works in the same exact
way by using CSS selector syntax.
Notice, however, that the method returns
an array, rather than a single dom node.
In fact, the select method only
returns the very first dom node
that matches the selector syntax.
And if no elements, or no dom nodes,
match the selector syntax,
then an empty array is returned.
So let's grab our element again
using the .main class and
see if this method's available.
Notice now that the append
method is now available,
because the variable holds a D3 object
rather than just a DOM node as before.
Also notice that we get an array which
is returned, rather than a DOM node.
This is the selection in D3.
Now, we have some of the similar
attributes as a plain DOM node.
But, there's a little bit extra
because this is a D3 object.