let me explain why measuring performance
is subtle
let's go back to our classification task
you've got a whole lot of images with
labels you could say okay I'm going to
run my classifier and those images and
see how many i got right that's mayor
measure and then you go out and use your
classifier on new images images that
you've never seen in the past and you
measure how many you get right and your
performance gets worse the classifier
doesn't do as well so what happened well
imagine i construct a classifier that
simply compares the new image to any of
the other images that I've already seen
in my training set and just returns the
label by the measure we defined earlier
it's a great classifier it would get a
hundred person accuracy on the training
sets but as soon as it sees a new image
it's lost it has no idea what to do
it's not a great classifier the problem
is that your classifier has memorized
the training set and it fails to
generalize to new examples
it's not just a theoretical problem
every classifier that you will build
will tend to try and memorize the
training sets and it will usually do
that very very well your job though is
to help it generalize to new data
instead so how do we measure the
generalization instead of measuring how
well the classifier memorize the data
the simplest way is to take a small
subset of the training set not use it in
training and measure the error on that
test data problem solved
now your classifier cannot cheat because
it never sees the test data so we can't
memorize it but there is still a problem
because training a classifier is usually
a process of trial and error you try a
classifier you measure its performance
and then you try another one and you
measure again and another and another
you tweak the model you explore the
parameters you measure and finally you
have what you think is the perfect
classifier and then after all this care
you've taken to separate your test data
from your training data and only
measuring your performance on the test
data now you deploy your system in a
real production environment and you get
more data and you score your performance
on that new data and it's doesn't do
nearly as well what can possibly have
happened
what happened is that your classifier
has seen your test data indirectly
through your own eyes every time you
made a decision about which classifier
to use which parameter to tune you
actually gave information to your
classifier about the test sets just a
tiny bit but it adds up
so over time as you're in many and many
experiments your test data bleeds into
your training data so what can you do
there are many ways to deal with this
i'll give you the simplest one take
another chunk of your training sets and
hide it under a rock never look at it
until you've made your final decision
you can use your validation sets to
measure your actual error and maybe the
validation set will bleed into their
training sets but that's okay because
you always have this test sets that you
can rely on to actually measure your
real performance