We showed you how to do
the first two steps.
If you still need help with those,
that's no problem at all,
you can just watch
the previous video again.
Now I'll show you how to update
variables within the decrement method.
We ask you to initialize
the quantity variable to 1, and
update it down to 1 cup of coffee.
I'm going to make the code change
in the MainActivity.java file in
the decrement method.
We're creating a quantity variable and
initializing it to 2.
Then I'm going to add another line of
code that updates the quantity variable
to be 1.
And lastly, I displayed this
new value to the screen.
Let's run the app to
check that it works.
If I hit the minus button,
then it decreases down to 1.
I can add a breakpoint here and
run the debugger to show that
the quantity variable is being updated.
I'm going to click on this debug
tab to open the debug pane.
I click on the minus button to
trigger the breakpoint here, and
then step through each line of code.
At this point,
the first sign has executed, so
the quantity variable has a value of 2,
and then it changes to a value of 1.
And then I can just resume the app and
the app should update to
have a quantity of 1.
And there it goes.
All right, I think we've nailed
the concept of how to update an integer
variable to a new number and
verify its value in the debugger.
This is still limited, though.
There are actually other ways to
update a variable aside from just
setting a fixed literal value.