[Norvig] The simplest way to do planning is really the exact same way
that we did it in problem solving.
We start off in an initial state.
So P1 was at SFO, say, and cargo, C1, was also at SFO,
and all the other things that were in that initial state.
And then we start branching on the possible actions,
so say one possible action would be to load the cargo, C1, onto the plane, P1, at SFO,
and then that would bring us to another state
which would have a different set of state variables set,
and we'd continue branching out like that until we hit a state which satisfied the goal predicate.
So we call that forward or progression state space search
in that we're searching through the space of exact states.
Each of these is an individual world state,
and if the actions are deterministic, then it's the same thing as we had before.
But because we have this representation,
there are other possibilities that weren't available to us before.