So, first thing you probably notice
about TCP dump data is that there's
a lot of details here.
What is all this options sack stuff?
We're not going to look
at that in this course.
I'm going to wave my magic wand and
make it go away.
I know it's kind of silly to say,
but don't panic about the fact that
this output probably looks
like a big pile of weird.
Some parts of it may jump out at you
as already saying something, and
if not right now,
maybe by the end of this video.
So, there's some things in here
you might already recognize.
If you're using your own data, you'll
see your machine's IP address here.
Here's mine.
Notice that just as we saw with pings,
sometimes it shows up to
the left of this little angle bracket,
and sometimes it shows up to the right.
That's because some of these
packets are going from our machine
to example dot net, and
some of them are coming back.
Likewise, here's the IP address for
example dot net.
If you want to check that,
you can use the host command
to look it up in the DNS.
Now, let's look at something that
differs across these packets.
At the end of each record,
there's a length field that's telling us
how much data was sent in that packet.
That's just the payload,
the actual HTTP data,
as opposed to all the TCP overhead like
addresses and port numbers and such.
So, the interesting thing here is
that out of all of these packets,
only a few of them even
have any payload data.
For most of them,
the length value is zero.
This is an important fact about TCP.
Even before the client and
server get to exchange any real data,
they've got some set up to do
to bring up the connection.
And after they're done with the real
data, they have some tear down to do.
So, looking at the first of these that
has any real data, it says link 38.
And the only other one has length 321.
Well, where did those numbers come from?
Let's look back at what
data we actually sent.
Here's our HTTP request.
And if you count these new line
characters the end of each line as only,
because the backslash
doesn't really count,
it's going to come out
to exactly 38 bytes.
Which means that this
record in the TCP dump data
exactly represents
the transmission of the HTTP
request from our client to
the example to that server.