So let's discuss the solution
to this exercise.
So for this first functionality,
in order to save a new pet,
well this requires inserting
information to the database, so
we'll call the insert method.
Next, to display an existing pet,
this requires us to read information
out of the database, so
we'll be calling the query method.
Thirdly, in order to
update an existing pet,
well as its name implies, we'll need to
update information from the database,
which means we'll call
the update method.
And fourth, to delete an existing pet,
we should call the delete method.
And lastly, to delete all the pets,
we'll also be calling our delete method.