Now, let's add some code to disconnect
the user from the Google account,
logging them out of our web application.
This is done by telling the server
to reject its access token.
Let's create another route and
method, both called gdisconnect.
I'll grab the credentials from
my login object session again.
If the credentials field is empty,
we don't have record of a user.
So there's no one to disconnect
from the application.
I'll return a 401 error for this case.
Now I will use the access token and
pass it into Google's url for
revoking tokens like so.
Then I will store Google's response
in an object called result.
If a response of 200 was received, then
I successfully disconnected the users
Google account from my application.
Using the del command in python,
I will delete the credentials, gplus_id,
username, email address and
picture from my login_session object.
Then I will create a response to
indicate that a user successfully
logged out of my application.
If I got any other response back
from Google besides the 200,
then I assume something went
wrong in the disconnect process.
And return a 400 message to the client
with a statement of what happened.
Now, when I visit the /gdisconnect URL,
my user successfully logged
out of my application.