Now and then I think of when they were together
Like when you found a route that went from X to Y.
All those paths, they went through A and B
which isolates them from that whole subtree.
It was a bridge and it’s a bridge
that now is severed.
You can try computing when a graph is all connected
You put the neighbors on a list, the open list
So when I tried to run a depth-first search.
And found that half the graph was in lurch.
I guess it means it makes the search
that more efficient.
But you didn’t have to cut the path.
Drop that singular connection
start a new component.
Now each is in a separate graph, so their
reachable descendents have been split in half.
No it doesn’t change the time, big O or the
clustering coefficient in the social network.
I guess it that I don’t need that though.
Now there’s just no pathway that can use two nodes.
Now and then I think of all the times
you queued me over.
Part of me believing it was algorithms that I'd run.
that I'd run. But I don’t wanna loop again.
Though my running time is D(N). You said
you’d use efficient codes and you wouldn’t
waste your cycles finding pathways
that can use two nodes.
But you didn’t have to cut the path. Drop that
singular connection, start a new component.
Now each is in a separate graph, so their
reachable descendents have been split in half.
Though it doesn’t change the time, big O or the
clustering coefficient in the social network.
I guess it that I don’t need that though.
Now there’s just no pathway that can use two nodes.
[No pathways]
That can use two nodes.
Now there’s just no pathway that can use two nodes.
[No pathways]
That can use two nodes.
Now there’s just no pathway that can use two nodes.
[No pathways]
That can use two nodes.