Let's just do a few of these things,
all right.
Clearly, this lets us think about
clusters of pixels that are similar in
color because we get clusters of
pixels that are similar in color.
Yeah, but why is that useful?
Well, one might believe that pixels
that are similar in color are ones that
are somehow supposed be treated
as a unit and pull them apart.
It certainly doesn't let us
understand the shape of objects.
Size, yeah, not so much because you
can think of sort of the number of
pixels but that would only work
if an object was constant color.
Identify pixels that are different,
well maybe kind of etc.
and separate them so
we'll give that a partial credit.
Count how many pixels of
each color there are, well,
what do you mean each color?
Color's not like, you know,
are these all red?
I don't know, it's been, remember,
the idea is that color's going to be
a categorical thing that's operating in
psychology, psychological space, right?
All this lets us do is think about
clusters where it says similar in color,
so we're going to have
some notion of a distance.