So of course, we are invested in looking at the Fourier
transforms of the two images, the left and right image of this parts, so
let's look at the Fourier transforms of those images.
But this image, this is the Fourier transform.
It does have a little bit of a dominant structure, but
as you notice, it's got a lot of spectral frequencies distributed around it,
because it does have, while it has reputations in x and y.
It does have a distribution of this thing because it's not the most
structured image.
Similarly, for the other one,
of course, here you notice it should have more frequencies.
These are larger objects or larger spots.
These are smaller spots.
When you have smaller spots like this,
you expect the frequency diffusion to be much thicker.
And, of course, it does have the directions but not as strong as in this one.
So, of course, this has more frequency.
This has less frequency in it.
So, continuing to look at the same to examples of the Fourier transform of
this on the left and the right spots here.
We have these two different frequencies of spectra, we can compute those.
So we would compute the fast, the Fourier transform.
Here as an FFT, which is fast Fourier transform which is, and this is so
far the same thing.
And this is the left image which give us Fl, and similarly we do this for
the right image which gives us Fr.
What we can do now is actually, again if you recall from the last lecture,
we can decompose this into different frequency spectra.
So we can take the left image and break it into it's F1, F2, F3, all the way.
And we can do the same thing for the right image, F1, F2, F3, F4,
and that gives us another whole set of you know
information that is actually now separated out into its different bands.
Now to help us generate these images what we can do is we can
feather corresponding octaves.
Now I know I haven't covered the concept of feather.
I'll talk about that in just a few seconds.
What we actually want to be able to do is feather.
That basically in essence means is we want to kind of merge the right kinds of
things from two different images.
We want to do this now in the frequency domain.
So we want to take the frequency, the fast,
the Fourier transforms of the left and the right.
And we want to do the corresponding octaves, remember the F1, F2, F3, F4.
For the left and then the same for the Fr.
But we want to do the combination of the F1 for the left and
the F1 of the right.
And, do a feathering between them, and do it for each and every one of them.
And then use that to reconstruct the signal.
So in essence, what we want to do is, we want to compute the octaves,
feather them, and then compute the inverse fast Fourier transform.
And that will allow us to feather everything in the frequency domain and
actually the output would be in the spatial domain.
So now what we can do is basically sum the feathered octave images in
the frequency domain and we actually have a very nice smooth image.
Let's look at that example.