So now, we are going to start talking about how we blend or
merge two different images together.
Remember different types of things we have looked up before,
where we can do different types of processes of enhancing the quality of images,
or being able to do additive information on images.
Now, we're going to look at how we can actually take two images, put
them on each other and be able to kind of get the pixels registered and actually
provide you a much more crisper information after that blending is done.
We will look at some concepts of both Fourier analysis we've looked at and
see how we can actually apply this to things like panorama building, and use
that concept to build further to hold technology of how we can do blending and
merging of images.