The answer to each question will
be depend heavily on the size of
the data transfers.
For a keyboard which likely will not
transfer much data for each keystroke,
a programmed I/O approach is better
since configuring the DMA may be more
complex than to perform one or
two extra store instructions.
For the network card the answer is
the popular, it depends, answer.
If we're sending out small packets,
that require that we perform
a less than five store instructions
to the device data registers,
given that the difference between
the store instruction and
the DMA controller in this hypothetical
example is one is to five.
Then it's better to perform program PIO.
If we need to perform larger data
transfers, then the DMA option will be
a better one since we just need to
configure the DMA controller and
then issue the request.