This is how the flow goes.
The user logs in with the app,
calling auth with password or
auth with o-auth token.
This triggers
the unauthenticated callback.
It could also trigger any authentication
state listener you've added.
Finally, if I call get auth,
it will give me a valid auth
data object at this point.
>> Great, so
does that solve your problem?
>> Well I guess the answer to that one
is, it's just the AuthData object,
give us all the information and
everything that we need for the app.
>> I don't see why not,
what's everything in the app?
What will change in the app
bases on what user is logged in?
>> A lot.
For example, if Walter is logged in,
and he creates a list.
It should have is name as
the owner of the list.
Similarly, if he adds an item,
it should be attributed to him, so
that way we know who requested what.
It could get more
complicated from there.
I probably want to add things
like it only shows lists
to the users that either made the list
or have the list shared with them.
I'll also want to record who
says they bought which items.
And maybe have even some
way of signaling that
users are currently in the store and
shopping.
>> Hm, that's a lot.
>> It is, but for now,
let's make this just a simple goal.
Number one, have a user log in.
And then number two,
that effect should show up in the app.
Here, let me show you
one of the screens.
>> So my first thought is,
does the AuthData object contain all
the information that we actually
need to be able to make this change?
And the other thing
I'm thinking about is,
how are we going to get the data from
the login activity to the main activity?
After all we get the authData here and
then somehow in the main activity we
have to pull up the information,
Walter's list.
So basically what's the best form for
this information and
what's the best way to move this
information around in our app, great.
And I think maybe we should
tackle the first question first.
Okay, so, what do you think?
Does the authData object contain
everything you need to display this
data here?
Let me know what you think.