Now that you know how to selectively
display data using your provider's query
method, let's add the ability
to actually delete a task.
This way, you'll actually be able to
get rid of a task when you finish it.
That's satisfying.
Looking at our list of CRUD functions,
we see that the delete function takes in
a URI and also an optional selection and
selection args as parameters.
So it does look a little bit like
the query function which we're familiar
with, and so it's going to be
pretty similar to implement.
In fact, I think you're ready
to jump into the code and
do this with just
a little bit of guidance.
In the delete function,
you should be doing four things.
First, you should gain access
to the task database and
write the URI matching code.
And then use selection parameters
to delete just one row of data.
Third, don't forget to notify
the ContentResolver of any change after
deletion.
And finally,
you need to return an integer, and
that integer is the number
of items deleted.
Got it?
Okay.
After you program the delete
method in the provider code,
I'll show you how to hook up your UI.