One of the things I've been working on for most of my professional career are self-driving cars.
The vision is that in the future cars will drive themselves,
and in doing so they can be significantly safer.
We lose about a little over 1 million people per year in the entire world in traffic accidents.
I believe most of these accidents can be avoided by making cars safer.
If they drive themselves, they can drive disabled people.
They can drive blind people, young children, aging people,
and they could drive all of us while we do better things that staring at the road ahead.
So one of my life passions has been to be develop self-driving cars.
Today, I'd like to tell you about those, and also show you some of the basic techniques
so you can in principle program your own self-driving car.
So for me the work on self-driving cars started in 2004 after the first DARPA Grand Challenge.
This was a government-sponsored robot race
in which autonomous robots were asked to drive through the Mojave desert from California to Nevada
along 141 miles of really punishing desert terrain.
Lots of teams competed from various universities, car companies,
and also lots of hobbiests that were new to the field competed,
and built this huge set of different cars.
There were over 100 different entries into the first DARPA Grand Challenge.
Despite all this work, most robots failed out of the starting gate,
like this one over here flipped over less than 100 meters into the race.
Some were very, very large.
This is a major defense contractor who built this 35,000 pound vehicle,
which on the course was rather timid,
and some of the the teams had very small robots, like the next one by UC Berkeley,
which was a motorcycle.
So here we go.
The first DARPA Grand Challenge came with $1 million of prize money,
and despite this prize money, no team made it further than 5% of the total course.
In fact, almost all cars stopped for something very stupid,
some went up in flames,
and the furthest any team made it was this car over here by Carnegie Mellon University,
which made it about just below 8 miles of the total distance.
So for many of us, this was a massive failure of robotic technology,
which motivated me to get involved in this race.
My own story is really simple.
I started a class at Stanford, and I got about 20 students to work with me
on what would become the Stanford racing team that would ultimately go and win this race.
We modified a Volkswagen Toureg to put all kinds of sensors onto the roof
and actuators into the car that could actuate the steering wheel, the gas pedal, and the brake.
The sensors came in multiple versions.
Some were related to localization, such as global positioning sensors,
and some were related to understanding where obstacles are, like laser-range finders.
We talked about computer vision in this class.
The actuators were basically a motor on the steering wheel and on the brake pedals and on the gas pedal.
Early on, we tested on Stanford's campus.
This is the roof of the medical parking garage.
Here you can see my students and I performed simple maneuvers.
Now, I've got to tell you that this is usually a busy parking garage.
It's the medical parking garage at Stanford Hospital,
but as we practiced autonomous driving, people would come and pick up their car
and ask us about, what we were doing, so we kept telling them,
well, we're building a self-driving car.
Within less than a week, people just chose not to park there anymore.
Closer to the next version of the Grand Challenge, the second one in 2005,
we had built a car that could drive competently on most desert tracks
at speeds up to about 60 km per hour through dry river beds, through steep inclines and declines,
and would be able to avoid obstacles like this little shrub on the right side over here.
It was never really elegant, but it was insanely effective.
Now, not all testing went smooth.
This is imagery that the New York Times shot of us when we invited them for a test drive.
During this day, we managed to crash into a tree and get stuck in the mud.
It was pretty embarrassing.