When you design an algorithm for
a distributed memory system,
the communication pattern of your
algorithm implies a network.
For example, you designed algorithms for
scatters and
gathers that worked well
on a linear network.
By working well, I mean concurrent
messages never overlapped, and
so would not contend for links.
Now, suppose you design an algorithm for
a linear network, but
then decide to run it on something else,
like a Mesh or Fat Tree.
How well would it work?
To answer this question, you need to map
a logical network, to the physical one.
Consider an example.
Suppose you design an algorithm
assuming this network.
It's a ring with, in general, p nodes.
Diameter of p over 2 and
a bisection width of 2.
Now suppose the underlying
machine is physically a 2D Torus.
You first need to decide how to
assign nodes of this network,
to nodes of this network.
Let's use a very natural
row by row numbering.
So the first 6 nodes
of the ring go here.
The second 6 nodes go here.
And, so on, row by row.
In fact,
let's redraw the linear network,
according to this numbering scheme.
Notice, that the edges of the 2D Torus,
are a superset of the edges of the ring.
So, what does that mean?
If there's no contention for length in
the linear network, then there will be
no contention for links in the torus
either, at least not under this mapping.
So, what if you did the reverse?
That is, what if this is the logical
network, and this is the physical one?
Intuitively, there are a lot more links
over here, than there are over here.
So even if there's no
contention in the torrus,
there might be a lot of
contention in the ring.
To see what would happen, let's start
with the same node numbering scheme.
Let's look at a couple of edges.
For example,
let's consider this edge from 0 to 6.
In the ring, where's the shortest
path between 0 and 6?
It's here.
Now, let's take a different edge.
How about 1 to 7 in the 2D Torus?
In the ring, it must go along this path.
So what if messages, from 0 to 6 and 1
to 7, are trying to go at the same time?
Then the messages might have to
serialize, because the paths overlap.
To help model this problem, let me
introduce a new property of the mapping.
This property is called congestion.
Achoo.
I'll define congestion as follows.
Given a logical to physical mapping,
the congestion of the mapping,
is the maximum number of logical edges
that map, to a given physical edge.
That's a mouthful.
For example,
suppose the logical network is a ring.
Suppose the physical
network is a 2D Torus.
Suppose the mapping is
this row by row numbering.
But suppose that a path,
in the logical network, maps two
a shortest path in the physical network.
You already argue that
there's a one to one mapping,
from each logical edge
to each physical edge.
Because of this one to
one correspondence,
the congestion of a ring,
going to a torus, is just one.
Let's consider the other direction,
with the same node to node mapping.
That is suppose the 2D Torus is logical,
and the ring is physical.
Now let's pick an edge.
How about this one?
Now this edge also appears
on the logical network.
But remember your earlier analysis?
What if you take this edge from 4 to 10?
Or this edge from 3 to 9?
These map to shortest paths that
intersect the 5 to 11 edge in
the physical network.
In fact, you can keep going.
All of these edges in this row have
to go through the 5 to 11 edge.
So, we have so far,
that at least 6 logical edges
map to this 1 physical edge.
Therefore, we have that
the congestion has to be at least 6.