All right, welcome back to Computer Vision.
So having done lines, and
remember lines are sort of the easiest version of a parametric model,
now let's move to something just a little bit more complicated, namely circles.
So, here's the equation of a circle.
You remember this from, this is Mrs. McGillicutty's algebra class.
X minus a squared plus y minus b squared equals r squared, where a and
b are the center, and r is the radius.
And for now we're going to assume the radius is known.
How did you know it?
You know, Megan sent you a postcard and
said, the radius is 11, okay, fine, so you know the radius.
Oh, and we're also not, not going to use any gradient information just yet.
We're just going to find the location of the points.
So here we have a circle, we don't actually know where the circle is, but
we've detected say, three points on that circle, the blue dots here, okay?
So what is the Hough space?
What is the accumulator erase space for the circle?
Well since there are typically three unknowns, a, b, and r, but
I told you the radius, Hough space is just a and b.
Right, the center locations and the x and y direction.
So, now let's consider the first point, say let's say, x0,
y0, this point right here, okay.
So, that point has to lie on the circle, and we know its radius.
So one way of thinking about that, is that the circle is gotta
be some radius r around that point, all right?
And so what that does is it votes for
a set of points, and that's what this green line represents, right?
This set of points that are r around this location in the ab space, okay?
So for a single point in the image space,
we get a circle of radius r in the Hough space, all right?
Let's move to the next point.
Well, same thing, right?
So it's gotta be, again, a radius r around here.
And in Hough space, we're going to vote along this circle.
And again the next point.
And so if each point votes each point in the image votes for
a circle, we collect all the votes.
And so just as before, we get the majority of our votes here and
that corresponds to this middle point, and that's what's drawn there.
So it acts just like before where we were voting for lines, except now
instead of using the sinusoids, we're voting in a circle in an ab Hough space.