Okay, let's look at multiplying
by a positive scalar.
So I started out by writing
out this equation Q,
which you recognize as
>> The usual thing.
>> The usual thing,
the Bellman equation, uh-huh.
So let's imagine we've got some reward
function R and it therefore has
a corresponding Q function or
solution to the Bellman equation.
And this is going to
tell us how to behave.
If you know the Q function for a given
reward function, then for each state
you're going to take the action that
maximizes the Q value in that state.
So this is kind of capturing
everything we need to know if
we knew the solution here.
But now what we're going to do is we're
going to generate a different reward
function, R prime.
So R prime for a given state action pair
is going to be defined as the old R,
the old reward function for that state
action pair, multiplied by a constant.
And that constant should be positive.
Why should it be not 0?
>> Well,
if it's 0 then everything's the same.
>> Yes, if it's 0 then we shouldn't
expect any of this to work.
If you multiply all the rewards by 0.
>> You lose all information.
>> Yeah, very good.
And negative, what do you suppose
would happen with a negative?
>> I'm going to say
the opposite of what you want,
except I'm not sure what
opposite means in this case.
>> That's right, it kind of flips
reward and punishment so then you end
up trying to find the reward function
that maximizes pain, which could be
an interesting exercise, but I think not
what we're trying to do in this case.
>> Yeah, it's just like grad school.
>> [LAUGH] I don't think the sign
is flipped for grad school.
I think it's just-
>> Oh,
I'm pretty sure the sign is flipped for
grad school.
>> [SOUND] All right, so
here's what I would like you to do.
I would like you to make a guess
as to if Q is the solution to this
original Bellman equation, and
R prime is our new reward function as
a function of the old reward function.
How can we write the new Q function,
corresponding to this R prime,
as a function of the solution to
the old Bellman equation with this Q?
So I want Q'(s,a) in terms of Q(s,a).
And that's going to give us some insight
as to whether or not we have a monotonic
transform, that the action that
was best before is still best now.