Awesome job.
You have an app that sends and
receives messages and photos that
uses authentication so you can limit
who can access and send messages and
it also limits the size of photos
to regulate storage space.
Now imagine this is your app.
You've just gone from a brilliant
idea to an even better execution.
You've tested it in all
sorts of conditions.
You've gotten feedbacks from friends.
And if that published your apps,
sharing it with the whole world.
So now what?
How do you know if your app
is working for your users?
Well, you could go back and
ask friends for more feedback.
But surely your app is now being used
by people you've never even met.
And their feedback is just as
valuable if not even more valuable
then what your friends could tell you.
Well, so
then you could send that survey out to
all of your users to get all of that
feedback, but that is a huge ask for
these people's time and most of
them just want to use your app and
they probably dont want to be bothered
with helping you to help them.
And even if you had
surveyed all your users,
that wouldn't be the whole picture.
It's what your users actually do in your
app that gives you the genuine feedback.
And here's where
Firebase Analytics comes in.
Firebase analytics is a free and
unlimited analytics tool that gives you
insights on all aspects of your app.
It also integrates with
the other Firebase features and
Firebase analytics automatically
collects a handful of events for us.
Without any setup.
This means that Firebase analytics
has been collecting analytics data
this whole time while we've
been working on Friendly Chat.
This all happened when we first started
using Firebase and Friendly Chat.
So aside from the automatically
collected events,
Firebase analytics gives you the
flexibility to define your own events.
You can log things such as when a button
is pressed, when a screen of the app is
visited, or maybe how long users have
spent in any one area of your app.
This can help you see where users are
not spending time in your app, so you
can make data driven choices on where
to spend your limited developer time.
Now learning the techniques to best use
the insights from Firebase analytics
that could be a course in and of itself.
So we'll get started
with the basic here.
Specifically we'll check out
the analytic dashboard in
the Firebase council.
And then we'll explore the data that's
automatically being collected by
friendly chats, so we can dive into more
ways that you can understand your users
behavior through analytics.