So we finished with our layout.
That means we're all done with
the UI of our app, right?
You might have noticed that
there's no way to actually submit
the query to GitHub.
While most applications would make
use of a button in the main layout,
we're going to take this opportunity
to teach you something new.
Android is the concept of menus.
We usually create them like any
Android resource using XML.
This example shows a menu item
that will display search.
The orderInCategory field indicates the
order that the menu item will appear in
relative to other items.
Android devices prior to Honeycomb
actually have a menu button.
But the visual design team felt it hid
too much functionality from users.
So in Honeycomb, we added a UX
control we called an action bar.
This sits at the top of the activity
window, and provides a place for
an overflow menu.
We also allow applications to
specify menu items as actions.
If there's enough horizontal space,
those actions appear on
the action bar as buttons.
To do this in our menu XML,
we add the show as action attribute.
We're doing this in the app namespace
because we're using AppCompat
to make our app compatible with
API Level 10 Gingerbread devices.
In Android API Level 21 Lollipop,
as part of our material design overhaul,
we generalized this to a standard
toolbar widget, allowing us to animate
the toolbar in, as well as use it
in different places in our layout.
This new functionality is available to
Android applications targeting most
Android versions, thanks to its
implementations in the support library.
We'll cover more on material
design later in the course.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
To create our menu, we override
onCreateOptionsMenu within our activity.
We can then handle
menu item selections by
overriding onOptionsItemSelected
within our activity.