Okay, there's a lot of code here so
this was a little bit tricky, but it shouldn't have been too bad.
So, the correct answer is this one.
So, why is this one correct?
Well, the first clue is that you're trying to change something.
You're not trying to read something, or insert something, or delete something.
You really are trying to change or
update something, so it has to be one of these two.
All right. Then the question is, what do you want to change to red?
Well, you want to change the calendars themselves.
Therefore, the correct URI is the CalendarContract.Calendars.CONTENT_URI, not
the Events URI, which is right here.
So again, you needed two parts to do this.
First, that you're changing something, so it's update.
And then it's the calendar that you're trying to change.
Therefore, the URI is the calendar URI.