I've got the Flame view open, and
it's pretty apparent that some kind of
work is being repeated over and over.
I'll just go ahead and
zoom into one of these chunks.
With this closer inspection,
it becomes pretty obvious that render is
causing InitWebGLObjects to be called.
At the top, you can see that the code
ran for about 60 milliseconds,
which is well over the 16
millisecond budget per frame.
This unfortunately means that there is
no way this app is going to run at 60
frames per second.
Looking at the frame viewer at the top,
you can see that these frames are made
up almost entirely of JavaScript,
hence all the yellow bars.
This means that this code is definitely
going to need some refactoring
if it's going to run at
60 frames per second.
So the correct answers are,
render as the function and, no,
it is not going to run
at 60 frames per second.