Let's look at a successful
request first.
We provided you with a link for
a valid query.
We visited that URL in a web browser,
and then copied the JSON
response into a JSON format, which
is what you see the results of here.
At the top of the JSON response,
within the metadata JSON object,
there is a status field.
The value of the status field is 200,
so our HTTP response code is 200,
which means that it was
a successful response.
You can double check this by going
to the documentation for JSON and
then looking for the status field.
And indeed,
here you see the definition of a status
field is the HTTP status
code of the response.
Okay.
So in the quiz,
we can write that a successful request
will yield a 200 response code.
Now, the next question is
about an invalid request.
Here, we've provided you
with an invalid URL,
where we just typed in a silly
parameter at the end of the URL.
If you visit this page in a browser,
you'll see a 400 type of error.
Bad request.
It complains that we have
a bad value in the URL.
This is helpful information so
we can figure out what's wrong and
how to fix the URL.
Not all invalid requests will
provide this type of advice.
It just depends on how
the server was configured.
Okay, so going back to the quiz,
an unsuccessful request will
yield a 400 response code.
Note that there are other possible
response codes that we can encounter,
but these are the most common ones
that we want you to be aware of.