Okay, so how many views
are there in this screenshot?
Well, we have two text views and
one image view.
So that makes three views.
But then also remember that
a view group is also a view.
So that's actually four total views.
So we write that in here.
Sorry, I know that was
kind of a trick question.
But now you will remember it next time.
Next, the mountain image is a child or
parent of the red ViewGroup.
If I draw in the faces, hopefully
you will remember that the image
view is a child of the red ViewGroup.
So I circle this one in.
Number three, the red ViewGroup is the
child or parent of the Hiking TextView.
If I draw in more faces,
then we see that the red ViewGroup
is the parent of Tommy Textview.
So we circle this in.
Number four,
which views are siblings of each other?
Well, the three of these views
are siblings of each other.
So, we have the mountain ImageView and
the two TextViews.