So to get some insight into this question, I want to show you some very
very greatly reduced images which are still going to be meaningful, that is,
you know, what is going on to me in use, so normally when I do this in class,
what I do is I say raise your hand when you can tell me, if you can tell me,
what’s in the picture.
So I would show then this.
And everybody would raise their hand, and
they would say it’s some goofy looking lion.
All right?
And I would show them a picture like this, okay, there, there’s an elephant.
There’s a really cool, old car.
There is a, something I'm never going to own, a private jet.
But what you can see about these pictures is there's actually not a lot of
pixels being used in this, in these pictures of different grayscale values.
Instead, somebody has just sort of drawn in the edges.
And yet, that conveys to you a lot of the information.
So the idea is that, in some sense, edges in an image seem to be important,
they seem to convey something about what's going on.