Looking at this definition and
the cloud computing requirements that we
discussed already, here are how these
phrases map to these requirements.
When we think about elastic resources,
that means that these are on demand
network resources, whenever we
need them they will get created.
They come out of a shared pool of
resources, so that's how we can support
this requirement, and
this provisioning happens rapidly.
When we think about API-based,
that really means that the resources,
the cloud computing resources
are ubiquitously available.
They need to be professionally managed,
so that's the definition,
the part of the definition that talks
about minimum management effort.
There really isn't anything
in this statement that
talks about the pricing aspect of
cloud computing and in principle,
there really isn't a solid
well-established definition of what
cloud computing is,
that the entire community subscribes to.