But you know, monitoring is pretty
vital for operations work, too.
From an ops standpoint,
we can talk about measuring facts about
our infrastructure resources,
like individual servers and our network.
Measuring resources like CPU
utilization, RAM usage, disk space,
network bandwidth, lets us know if
our infrastructure's overloaded.
Or better yet, it can give us warning
well before it's overloaded so
it can scale our service correctly.
On servers, we might also want to record
things like the hardware temperature and
the disk I/O error rate.
By looking at that,
you can often predict a disk failure
before it breaks your machine.
How about on the application side?
If we have ten web servers
with a load balancer in front,
we probably want to know how many
requests each server is handling.
And the monitoring system
can sum those numbers
up to get the total number of
queries the whole app is taking.
If you care about how fast or
slow your service is, well,
you have to measure its latency.
And likewise, if you want those
web servers to be serving
200s like a happy web server,
instead of 500s like a broken one,
you'd better monitor whether all those
requests are succeeding or failing.
And once you have all this information
recorded, you can do things like
calculate how much total CPU is needed
to handle the average transaction.
Or how service latency responds
to increased RAM pressure.
Or any number of other things.
In a really awesome world,
you could even plug that back into
your continuous delivery automation.
And before letting a release
go out to production,
load test that release and make sure
that it's not a lot more resource
intensive than the last version.