Let's set up the link from our
main activity to the newly created
child activity.
To move between two activities we
call the method start activity
which takes an intent as a parameter.
You might be wondering why we should
bother with an intent if we know exactly
where we want to go.
Remember that intents
are like envelops and
can package bits of information
we want the new activity to have.
If you look at the documentation
on developer.android.com, for
the activity class, you'll find many
ways you can start an activity.
We're most concerned with the signature
that takes an intent, but
there are also variants allowing the
called activity to return results back
to the caller, perhaps a reference to
a contact or a photo in a gallery.
The app currently shows a toast
message when the button is clicked and
we want it to instead start an activity.
So now we need to create our intent.
Like with the signatures
of start activity,
we have several choices of
constructors for intents.
Since we know the destination activity,
we can use this one
that takes a context and
a class object as parameters.
In an Android application, activities
can be started and stopped at any time,
so the context gives us a way of doing
certain things that might effect
an app as a whole or might outlive
the lifetime of a single activity.
Every activity extend from context,
so we can use MainActivity.this
to retrieve a static reference to
the context as our first parameter.
And to get a static reference
to our destination class,
we use ChildActivity.class.
Now, this isn't very readable, so
let's put them into discreet variables
to better show what's going on.
Now, we use those variables context and
destination activity to
initialize our intent.
And when we run the app, and
put in some text, child activity gets
started, and we see the default text.
And that's because we
haven't told the intent
what the data is we want to pass from
main activity to child activity.