So the really cool thing about doing this is that now we
can take perspective projection and
make it a linear matrix operation while we're working in homogenous coordinates.
And we don't have to worry about the nonhomogeneous part until the very end.
So that looks like this.
So here I have a three by four matrix, and you notice it's 1, 1, 1 over f.
And I multiply that by my homogenous 3D coordinate, xyz1, and
I get out this three dimensional homogeneous coordinate, right.
So it's 2D homogeneous coordinate 3, with component x, y, and z over f.
Okay?
And I can just keep this around as a homogeneous coordinate until I
actually need to use it in an image.
And when I use it as an image, I do the division of the top element by
the homogeneous element, and I would get f times x over z and f times y over z.
Which by the way is sometimes called u, v.
And those are the coordinates in the image of some point x,
y, z out in the world projected through a projection with a focal length of f.
And so our projection operator was this linear matrix multiplication, and
as we know, we all love linear matrix multiplications,
because we know how to do them a lot.
And invert them and all other kinds of stuff.
And it's really the basis behind projective geometry, and the projection
mathematics that we'll be using for a bunch of the course actually.
By the way, f, from now on, is for focal length.
Before we're talking about that distance D, so
here our focal length is the distance from the center of projection to the image
plane, and it is not the f of the aperture that we were talking about last time.
I probably shouldn't have even reminded you,
because it's probably months ago since you watched that lecture.
But f here is always going to be focal length,
which is the distance from the center projection to the image plane.
So how does scaling the projection matrix change the transformation?
Well, here what I've done is I've scaled my projection matrix by f.
I could have scaled it by something else, but I'll, I'll scale it by f.
So now, instead of having along that diagonal of 1, 1, and
1 over f, instead, I just multiply by f and I have f, f, and 1.
Multiply that by my three dimensional homogenous coordinated vector which has
four dimensions to it.
Now I get out fx, fy, and z.
And then when I do that division, what do I get, the same thing I got before.
Okay? So it was invariant.