Now find the point marked number
11 in your starter notebook and
split the daily engagement
data into two lists.
The first list should contain
the engagement data for
students who eventually
passed the first project, and
you should name this
list passing engagement.
The second should contain records for
students who don't eventually
pass the first project, and you should
name this list non-passing engagement.
Throughout most of the time that this
data was being collected, the first nano
degree project was analyzing New York
subway data, so that's the project
that you're going to assume is
the first project for this purpose.
Now this project was actually
updated at some point and
the key identifying it changed,
so I've given you both keys here.
You should consider a student to have
passed the first project if they ever
pass a project with
either of these two keys.
As a reminder, here's what the project
submission data looks like.
You can use the lesson_key field to see
which project was submitted, and you
can use the assigned_rating field to see
whether the student passed the project.
The table descriptions file available
in the downloadable section lists
the possible values for
the assigned rating field.
Once you're finished, find how many
engagement records correspond to
students who passed the first
project and how many correspond
to students who didn't, and enter your
number in the boxes on the next screen.