Motion events are triggered when a play
moves the joystick or shoulder buttons.
And in the same way, we overrode methods
in our view to capture KeyEvents,
we can override another
to capture MotionEvents.
And that method is going
to be onGenericMotionEvent.
Of course, you can capture this
in activities in a similar way.
And check out the note for more info.
There's more to MotionEvents
than KeyEevents, and
to understand them,
let's use an example.
Pretend that the player sweeps the
joystick up into the left into counter
clockwise motion, as you can imagine,
joysticks are pretty sensitive.
Each dial on this diagram represents
an individual sample that Android
took of the joystick's position as
the user moved it up into the left.
Each sample contains a set of axis
values, for example, the x and
y positions of the joystick.
Event creation in Java is expensive,
so a MotionEvent isn't created for
each individual sample.
Instead, the system batches
up samples into Windows.
Each window becomes a MotionEvent, so
a MotionEvent can contain many
individual movement samples.
Keep in mind that each MotionEvent
contains all the samples since
the previous one, so you never miss any.
Each MotionEvent contains a list
of historical samples and
the current sample.
You can figure out how many historical
samples it contains by calling
getHistorySize.
You can then process the individual
samples in sequence.
If your frame rate can sustain it, you
can redraw the screen after each one.
Alternatively, you could update the
player's position for each sample, but
only redraw the screen when you can.
Also keep in mind that MotionEvent
still come in extremely fast and
this won't be a source
of any lag in your game.
And by the way, the number of samples
in each MotionEvent is variable and
is determined by the system at run time.
You can get the access value for
the current sample by
calling get access value.
And you can get access values for
historical samples by calling
getHistoricalAxisValue with the index
of the sample you're interested in.
We always get the value for
a single axis at a time.
And the integer access parameter
corresponds to the axis code
that we saw earlier on.
Here's how this looks in code.
We're back inside Game View, inside our
onGenericMotionEvent that we overrode.
In addition to game controllers,
many devices can trigger MotionEvents,
including touch screens.
In this line and the next,
we figure out the event source, meaning
what type of device it came from.
To be honest,
this code is a bit of a mess, and
I wouldn't recommend doing it this way.
If you're targeting API level 18 or
higher, there's a helper
method to do this for you.
And if you're targeting
an earlier version of Android,
then I'd recommend writing a well test
method and encapsulating this logic.
There's another property of MotionEvents
you should be aware of, and
that's that you can get an action code.
For joysticks the action code is
always going to be ACTION_MOVE.
You should be aware that other
types of input devices can generate
other types of action codes.
For example,
if you're working with a touch screen,
when the user first taps the display,
the action code might be action down.
You can check out the notes for
more detail.
Let's check out the onGenericMotionEvent
handler of the ship class
to see how the MotionEvent
is actually processed.
Here's where we determine how many
historical samples the event has and
we'll use this method to
handle an historical sample.
And the current sample, in the same way.
We begin to work with the MotionEvent
itself inside processJoystickInput.
The first thing we'll need to
do is figure out the values for
the x and y axes.
Inside the getCenteredAxis method,
the first thing we need to do is check
whether the joystick's centered.
Joysticks have a flat area.
A flat area is a range
of values near 0,0 with
the joystick should be
considered centered.
We can find the flat area for
an access by querying a range object
we retrieve from an input device.
And remember, you can always get
the input device that generated an event
by calling event.getdevice.
Finally, we get the actual access value,
depending on whether we're working with
a current sample or a historical sample.
To recap,
lets see how its all put together.
Here's the diagram from
our previous lesson.
I've slided it over to
the left a little bit and
added all the methods we talked
about for motion events.
If you're thinking,holy crap
there's a lot here all at once!,
don't worry its not so bad.
Again with the MotionEvent always call
getHistorySize first to determine how
many historical samples you have.
Then, call getAxisValue, or
getHistoricalAxisValue to figure out
the axis position for
a sample that you care about.
With joysticks, the action code is
always going to be action moved,
although this can be different for
different types of input devices.
To figure out whether the joystick
should be considered centered,
you have to get its flat area.
And to do that you can figure out
the input device that generated
the MotionEvent by calling getDeviceId.
Once you have the InputDevice,
you can call getMotionRange to
determine the motion range for an Axis
and then call getFlat on that object.
Also keep in mind that different Axis
can have different MotionRanges.
Check out the link in the instructor
notes for more detail on that.