The final topic in this unit is called hierarchical planning.
The idea here is we want to close the abstraction gap. What do I mean by that?
Well, let's think about what you have to do to plan your own lifetime.
You live about maybe a couple of billion seconds,
and during that time you have a choice of actions to make,
and you have maybe around 1,000 muscles,
which you can operate maybe around 10 per second.
You end up at a lifetime as somewhere around 10^13 actions
give or take an order of magnitude or two.
But there's a big gap between 10^13 and the 10^4 or so actions
that current planning algorithms or programs can deal with.
Part of the problem with such a big gap is that it's just difficult to deal at the level of an individual muscle movement.
We'd rather deal with more abstract plans.
We're going to introduce the notion of a hierarchical task network,
and rather than having a plan be a sequence of individual steps,
we can talk about higher order steps where maybe there's a smaller number,
and the individual steps can correspond to multiple steps.
This idea is called refinement planning.