The correct answer is when we handle
a tap and when we animate the bugs.
Let's see how we can use
Stack Traces to prove it.
I already have a breakpoint set and
the create bug method of
the bug factory class.
And we'll run the application.
I'll select the breakpoint debugging
scene, and then Alt+tab on screen.
And as we can see from the stack traces,
the createBug method is being called by
addBugToView, which in turn was
called by handleSingleTap, and
the breakpointBugViewController.
So we know that create bug
is called when we tap.
But what about when we animate?
If we continue the app's execution,
we're dropped right back into the same
breakpoint, and we can see that
the stack frames have changed.
This time it looks like we're
calling adbug to view again,
which in turns calling create bug.
If we keep clicking Continue,
the stack frames just keep increasing.
And the culprit seems to be
the move bugs to animation method.
If we click on it, then we can see that
after bugs finish animating here in
the UIView.animateWithDuration,
we have the other add bug to view call.
This probably explains why so many
spiders are being drawn to the screen.
For now we're going to
leave this call here,
even though it's not the behavior that
we want, because in the next lesson,
I'm going to show you another way
to troubleshoot this same problem.