So, let's see what happens if
we execute this block of code
on this cursor variable
containing all this data and
see what the integer value of
the result variable is returned.
So, here's the cursor variable that we
started with, and our initial line of
code has us move to the first row of
the cursor, which is this row here.
Following we have the moveToNext method,
which advances the cursor
one row from its current position,
and then we have that call again, and
our cursor advances one more row
to this third row down here.
Following we have these
two Java statements.
They get us the column index of first
the name column, which we see here is 0,
so the name column index
variable is set to 0, and
we also have the weightColumnIndex
variable that is set to 1.
Finally, the last line of code here
passes in the weightColumnIndex,
which we previously saw is 1, and
in this cursor passing in 1
gives us the value of 30.
So, the value of result here,
this variable, will be 30.
Back to the exercise, this blank here,
our result would be the 30,
which is the weight of
the value in our third row.