This Nanodegree is
a series of projects and
courses that we'll have design and
with data sense experts to teach
you the skills that you need to
become a data analyst yourself.
Along the way, you will build a series
of projects that you can showcase to
your friends, colleagues, recruiters,
and potentially hiring managers.
>> As you build this
technical expertise,
you'll also participate in
career development activities.
That will guide you in how to
showcase your skills and potential.
Unicri is also a very
community centered experience.
You're part of a cohort,
a couple of students that are working
at about the same pace, and
you'll interact with your fellow
students frequently as you learn.