[Male narrator] Here are the answers.
For P and P implies Q, we know that P is true
in these bottom 2 cases, and P implies Q, we saw the truth table for P implies Q
is true in the first, second, and fourth case.
So the only case that's true for both P and P implies Q is the fourth case.
Now, this formula, not the quantity, not P or not Q, can work that out to be the same
as P and Q, and we know that P and Q is true only when both are true,
so that would be true only in the fourth case and none of the other cases.
And now, we're asking for an equivalent or biconditional between these 2 cases.
Is this one the same as this one?
And we see that it is the same because they match up in all 4 cases.
They're false for each of the first 3 and true in the fourth one,
so that means that this is going to be true no matter what.
They're always equivalent, either both false or both true,
and so we should check all 4 boxes.