When you have used programming
languages before such as Python or
JavaScript, you've been exposed to
concepts such as function and statement.
Commands that you run at the shell
prompt are a little bit like
function calls.
>> You could even do some of
the same things in the shell and
in code, like the command to
delete a file in the shell is rm,
which stands for remove And
it works like this.
>> And you could do the same thing in
Python with the remove function in
the OS module, os.remove.
>> So, this analogy helps some people
think about commands in the shell.
If it doesn't work for
you, that' okay, too.
But take a moment to think about how
shell commands are similar to functions
in Python or JavaScript, and
think about how they're different.