Did you know that you can find out how
many layers you've got in a website?
Of course for this, it's once again
time to head over into Chrome def tools.
I'm looking at the parallax demo and
I've already will changed all
the blobs with the paint profiler on.
So I'd check this box.
I'll go ahead and
start a recording and scroll the page.
I've opened devtools in a separate
window to get a little bit more space.
Notice how each frame has
a gray bar at the top.
You now have the ability to see
all the layers on the screen.
And why, for each layer,
it was composited into its own layer.
At the top, you've got a few
looking around and rotating tools.
For instance, with this one checked,
I can now rotate the page to get
a 3D view of all the layers.
Pretty cool?
Anyways, when I click on one of the
layers, I can see exactly why it became
a layer which, in this case,
is because it has will change.
Now it's your turn to
try counting layers.
Head to this link which you can
find in the instructor notes below.
Re size the window or zoom in far enough
so that you have the ability to scroll.
Click on the click me button and then
record a timeline trace of scrolling.
And of course make sure
the paint profiler is enabled.
I've got two questions for you.
The first one is how
many layers are there?
But don't worry about counting document,
type your answer into this box.
And the second question is
why was totes promoted?
Was it because it has will change?
Was it because tote's promoted overlaps
with some other composited content?
Is it because it has a 3D
transform applied to it?
It is it because totes promoted
is a hardware accelerated canvas?
Or is it because totes
promoted animates a transform?
Check one of these answers.