Let's do the essential matrix computation for the example of parallel cameras.
Okay?
So, first, what is, so, so, by the way, you recognize this picture?
Right, this is the picture of our parallel image planes when we were
doing the stereo the derivation of the relationship between disparity and depth.
So I have two parallel image planes, nothing is rotated, oh,
nothing's rotated, so what's the rotation matrix?
Well, it's just the identity.
Great.
All right, what's T, well, what was T?
T was the translation between the two camera centers.
Well, in the geometry that we've defined here, the camera center has just been
translated an amount B in the x direction, or negative B in the other x
direction, doesn't matter, but we'll just say it's minus B, zero, zero, okay?
So, T is just minus B, all right?
Well, that means I can now compute my essential matrix, because my
essential matrix defined before was this weird cross product thing of T times R,
R is the identity, so we just plug T into the cross product,
little formula I gave you, and it looks like that.
So that's our essential matrix.