At this point, you probably set
downloading your database and
we'll see if your pet
was inserted correctly.
So next, we're going to learn how
to read from SQLite database.
So recall that you can execute pure
SQL statements using this method,
execute SQL.
Additionally, there's a this raw query
which is a similar API used to
read the database using pure SQL.
However, this isn't
the recommended way to do it.
So much like there's this
an SQLiteDatabase.insert method,
there's an SQLiteDatabase query method,
and
this helps you avoid syntax errors
by helping you structure your query.
So let's take a look at how this works
by looking at this tutorial here.
Now, the first thing we see in this
tutorial win to do Is to define an array
of strings called a projection.
And projections is just a fancy name for
the columns that were
interested in getting back.
So remember from our cheat sheet how
we use select name breed from pets,
so let's stick on like this, well
defining a projection lets you specify
exactly the columns you want back.
So if you don't define a projection,
then by default you get
all the columns back.
So similar to if you were
executing select * from pets.
Now, an example in this tutorial,
a projection is defined with
these three columns, ID,
the name title and the name updated.
So as you can see the type
is in a rare strings and
each string included as
a column from the contract.
So next stop only to invoke
the query method on the data base.
The query method takes
a bunch of parameters.
The first one starting
with the table name.
Now, the rest of these
parameters are optional and
represent different parts
of a select statement.
And when I say they're optional,
it means that you can pass in null for
all of them, so what we taking
a look at this three parameters.
And you can look over for the rest if
you would like later in your free time.
So this parameter here, this first one
is the projection we just made up here,
if you were to pass in null instead
then all the roads would being selected.
So this is similar as if you were
using the select asterisks from pets
instead of explicitly stating
select name breed from pets.
So in this example we pass it
in this particular projection.
As a side note, there is a performance
implication to the projection size.
So passing in null all the time
could lead to long queries,
if the dataset were really large.
Now, these next two parameters,
selection and
selectionArgs deal with
an optional WHERE clause.
So from our cheat sheet,
we had one statement used for
selecting a single pet by id.
And remember, we did so
using this WHERE clause.
So unfortunately this tutorial example
doesn't have any example of this so
in that case I'll be showing
you an example here.
So let's say I want to narrow my query
search to this, so using my selection
and selections parameters this
is what that will look like.
So the selection parameter is the actual
statement that comes after the where
keyword.
And it is of type string, so
here you use a question mark as a place
holder which I'm doing here which is
then filled in by the values in
the selection arcs parameter.
Now, the selection arc is an array of
string that replaces the question mark
up here In the selection, and
I've indicated that I want it to be 1.
So why use a question mark and
selectionArgs,
instead of explicitly just writing =1?
Well, in this case,
it doesn't make a difference.
You could use null as
your selectionArgs, and
just set this equal to 1.
But in some cases,
when a selection might come from a form,
say the use of a placeholder
is a security measure to prevent a type
of attack called an SQL injection.
So if you're interested in learning
more about how SQL injections work,
I've added some explanation
links down below.
So after all this is said and
done, when the parameters
of the query method are set up, this
code will return object called a cursor.
So I'll be talking more
about cursors shortly.
But for now just imagine that a cursor
looks like a table that appears when you
type the statements into the SQLite
3 program on your computer.
So essentially, it's an object
that captures a subsection
of all the data in your database.
So here's what I'd like you to do for
this exercise.
Given this example table, so if you were
to execute this query code from the app
what information in an objects
called the Cursor would be returned?
So here's all that information
compacted into this one slide.
So to reiterate, given the database
table, the image I've linked also below.
If we execute the query code
from the gist linked below,
describe the resulting cursor.
How many rows will it have?
As well as,
how many columns will be present?
Check all that apply.