Here we are back at
the Firebase console.
I'm going to over to the Auth tab and
see what it shows us.
This page is telling me that
we can authenticate and
manage users from a variety of
providers without any server side code.
So it look like we're
in the right place.
I'm going to go ahead and click on
SET UP SIGN-IN METHOD Sign-In Method..
Here are the different authentication
options that Firebase provides.
By default,
all of these options are disabled.
That's no good.
Let's enable some of these.
For FriendlyChat, we're going to enable
a simple email password login and
a Google login.
So I'm going to click on email
password > enable > save it, and
the same with Google.
And now they're enabled in Firebase.
That's everything we need
to do on the console.
Let's move on to implementing
the upside code.