The ability to generalize code for a
variety of possible inputs is a powerful
tool when creating easy to understand,
non-repetitive code.
Take this example, here's
a function that reverses a string.
You can pass in the string Julia as
an argument and it will reverse it and
return ailuJ or ailuJ, who knows.
There are quite a few steps
involved in this process.
The function has one parameter,
a variable reverseMe,
that will be used to store the argument,
in this case the string Julia.
The function has a variable called
reverse that will eventually contain
the final string with all
the characters in reverse order.
It then loops over the reverseMe
string from back to front and
adds each character in that
order to the reversed variable.
Finally, it returns the result, so
we can print it using console.log.
Like I said, there's a lot going
on here, but think about it.
If all of these steps were not wrapped
inside this reverseString function,
you would have to repeat
this code over and
over and over, every time you wanted to
reverse the characters in the string.
Using a function simplifies the process
by wrapping all this code together and
generalizing the process for
all strings.
It allows you to use and
then even reuse the function
by just calling it by its name and
passing in a different string each time.
Let's take a closer look
at how functions work and
the different ways you can define and
call functions in JavaScript.