Okay, let's take a look at the code.
So, in order_dinner.xml,
which is the layout file for
the order dinner screen,
I've added the button for the payment.
So, text=Payment, given it it's unique
ID and the onClick is getPaymentInfo.
And it starts out being invisible.
Up here, in order dinner activity,
I've defined getPaymentInfo
which glosses right over getting
the payment and just shows us a toast.
But then I call a method to
send hit to Analytics and
here's the code to show and
hide the buttons appropriately.
And then here's sendPaymentInfoHit.
This is all very familiar.
We create the product etc.
Now down here in the productAction,
the action is ACTION_CHECKOUT_OPTION and
I've set the CheckoutStep to 2.
Get the tracker.
And when I create the EventBuilder,
categorize shopping steps as before,
change the action to Get payment,
add the product,
set the productAction and build the hit.