Let's think about these dice values for
a second.
Even though they were displayed
in the dice to controller.
They were actually generated
by the RollViewController.
It is usually necessary for
a presenting controller to configure or
pass data to a new view controller.
We are about to learn two more ways
to use storyboard to present view
controllers using segues.
Each of the three ways finds
a slightly different strategy for
passing information from one
View Controller to the next.
Of the four view controllers that we've
presented so far, which ones required
the presenting controller to provide
information to the new view controller?