Okay. So, Team Awesome, thanks so
much for participating in our hackathon last week.
We really loved your [LAUGH] project and
we'll be providing it to our students in the course.
So, I just wanted to know your process and
how you arrived at your final typology.
And how did you break up the work between your group?
You had a group of six or seven.
>> Basically, the idea is we were just thinking about what we
can do that's nice or useful.
And then, after we came up with a few ideas,
we thought of something that would fit well together.
>> I guess we started kind of brainstorming on what
kind of cool things we could visualize.
We first went to the D3 repository and saw various things.
And, we saw a map and thought, well, you know,
Twitter, we can perhaps correlate location based information.
And, we wanted to have something really pretty to look at at the end.
so, I guess that's kind of how we started and kind of,
looked at what the tweets kind of, contained and see any emoticons, hashtags.
In short sentences, so thinking what one can do with that information.
>> We kind of took the original spell and
we did some, we added some functionality to it.
One thing that we did is we did a sentiment analyzer.
We put a sentiment analyzer in the spell to give a sentiment for
the tweet, original tweet.
We also put in a few filters in the spells.
So, one thing we did is we are only, since the map is only for
the United States,
so we added a filter only located in the United States region.
And, we also have another filter.
Since we're very interested in, you know, putting this on a map, we only get,
we're only getting tweets that has a latitude and longitude information.
>> So, you checked whether or
not it existed and then made sure that it was in the region.
And then, ran sentiment on the entire Tweet coming out of the spout.
>> Yeah.
>> Did you think of putting the sentiment analyzer in to its own bolt?
Or, was it just more efficient or,
was that something that or Chris, recommended?
>> So, we originally did try that.
And then, I think that to initialize the sentiment analyzer it requires I
think a couple hundreds of megabytes of memory.
And, since we're using a virtual cluster and we have, you know,
maybe 10 instance of the bolts we don't have enough memory to actually do that.
So, we put in the spout instead.
I know it's kind of like a bottleneck now because sentiment analyzer,
it takes time to give, score each, tweet.
But, you know, given, given the constraint that's, that's where we end up.
The parse tweet, bolt, we're doing the filtering on the skip words, so we took
out all the pronouns, and, you know, articles that we are not interested in.
So, we filter them out, and then send them to the next next spout.
And, the next one next bolt is called info bolt and
this is the bolt that does the emoticon analysis.
So, this one takes in the tweet from the previous bolt and
then it then it maps each emoticon it sees to cinnamon score so
a happy face would be like, a large number.
And then, a sad face would be a pretty small number.
But, that's kind of the scale that we went with.
Now, the next bolt is called top-words.
So, starting from this bolt,
we are looking at information that are only grouped by the county ID, county_id.
So, all the, just the tweets that go to a single bolt,
they have a sort of pretty consistent set of counties and, that way,
we can aggregate the stats for them.
And, in the top-words bolt, you did aggregation on the stats for, you know,
the most frequent tweets,
say we're also doing some manipulation with the sentiment score,
where we combine the emoticon sentiments and the tweet sentiments.
And, the report-bolt, that's the last bolt that we have.
For this bolt, I did more processing on the final sentiment, you know,
the moving average for
the sentiment score, and also send the sentiment score to the D3 map.