Now we have a set of predictions that might arise from a single particle,
and the other important step in particle filtering is the measurement step.
We need to understand at what rate will these particles survive,
and that's usually done in proportion to the measurement probabilities.
Let's talk about measurements.
For the sake of this exercise, let's assume we only have 2 measurements.
We would either see something bright or something dark.
It does a certain response to whether it's on land marking.
Just for simplicity, let's assume we have certain locations that have land markings,
like this one over here and these over there.
If a robot center is aligned with a lane marking, it should see a bright spot
because lane markings tend to be bright.
But if it's off the lane marking on the regular road, it should see a dark spot.
Let's turn this into a probability that's called the measurement probability.
The probability of seeing something bright is going to be large when it's on a lane marker, say 0.8.
From that we can deduce that the probability of seeing something dark on a lane marker is 0.2.
The probability of seeing something dark when off a lane marker is even higher at 0.9,
and from that it follows that the probability of seeing something bright
on the regular road with regular pavement is going to be 1 minus 0.9 equals 0.1.
Here's my quiz for you. This is an entirely nontrivial quiz.
If you get this right, you understand particle filters.
Suppose we measure bright.
The actual sensor told us it saw something bright underneath the robot.
I'd like to know what is the importance weight of the particle over here,
which we're going to call x1, and the particle over here, which I'll call x2.
Tell me what's the weight w of x1 after I apply the measurement probability
and the normalization that's common in particle filters.
Please do the same for the particle x2 where x1 happens to be on the lane marker,
and x2 happens to be off a lane marker.
So please put in these two numbers of over here.
It'll take a while to calculate those, so please take the time.
I assure you if you get those right, you really understand particle filters.