The answer is 18/31, which is approximately 0.5806.
4/31 is 0.1290,
and 9/31, which is half of the thing over here, 0.2903.
And again, we look at the same as before.
We look at the total nonnormalized measurement probabilities for our particles.
In a white square, the probability of seeing white is 1 - 0.1, that is 0.9.
Since we have 2 particles, the nonnormalized cumulative particle weight is 1.8.
Doing the same for the black square, the probability of seeing white is 0.2,
which is 1 - 0.8.
We have 2 particles in the black square to get a nonnormalized total probability
of 0.4, so you get a nonnormalized total importance weight of 0.4.
And finally, the probability of seeing white in the white square is 1 - 0.1 is 0.9,
and here we only have 1 particle, so the nonnormalized importance weight is 0.9.
If you add those up, we get 3.1.
So we have to divide all of those by 3.1.
So 18/31 is the 1st one. 4 by 31--the 2nd, and 9 by 31--the 3rd, as indicated on the left.