So now what we're interested in asking
the question, given an image like this,
how do we transform it
to an image like this?
Again, here I'm basically showing
a little bit of scaling
in one direction only.
Let's start off by basically finding
two points on my original image, f.
This is my original image f.
And I'm trying to get my output image g.
Here, I basically have two
points that I've kind of marked.
Of course, what we're now interested is
seeing where these two points would be
on this image.
Where would they transform to?
So, call this one P1.
And we call this image,
or point here, P2.
This P1 and P2 have now moved
to different points here.
So of course this is now
all these two points.
And just for sake of parity we
will call this P2 prime, and
then we will call this P1 prime.
In essence, now what we have to
figure out is how to transform
the point P to P prime.
So in essence, what we need now is the
simple function that takes any point,
P, of course in this case, in this case,
they would have values of x and
y to generate a new point, P prime.
In this case, we want to find one
function, T, which has a set of
parameters that actually applies this
thing entirely to the whole image.
So in this case,
I'm basically talking about one function
that directly applies to each and
every pixel.
This basically means that
this would be a global warp.
Every, the same function,
the same parameter function would
be applied to the entire image.
So in essence, what we're talking
about is ,a global function,
that given a P,
we would always get a P prime.
And just to reiterate,
what basically I'm talking about is,
I want to come up with a few
set of simple parameters.
So by now, you've noticed I like to
convert everything to matrices because
that's a great representation for
us to be playing around with.
And, of course, this is true here.
What we really want to
do is find a matrix
that encodes all of
the transformation or
the parameters, and then when applied
it to point p, and again, remember,
this would be just simple x and
y, to generate a new x and y.
Basically, this is the simple
two-dimensional transformation
we're looking at.
Given a matrix M, that has certain set
of parameters, when applied to point
x and y, any variable in this f
function, which is my first one,
I would get an output, g, which would
have all x primes, and y primes.
So, by just looking at this,
you may note that this M should be two,
a two by two matrix, and
now we, let's start to figure out what
would be in this two by two matrix.