[BLANK_AUDIO]
My gosh, you are so annoying.
>> Ow, ow, I didn't, why am I.
You.
Stop.
>> Roommates, cut it out.
All right.
Now.
What has gotten into you two?
>> Some anonymous owner has
gotten into my grocery list and
changed it all to components.
>> I swear, I didn't do anything.
Lila, we need a way for each of us
to have a separate shopping list.
>> All right, all right.
Well, I'm going to work on user
accounts in the next version, so
I can't do that right now.
But what I could do is give
you guys multiple lists.
>> Yeah, that sounds reasonable.
>> Fine.
>> Good, now why don't you two make up.
>> I guess I can forgive you.
>> Good, Grace?
There, isn't that beautiful?
All right,
now we can all get back to work.