Currently, I'm in the
BreakpointBugViewController.swiftfile
of the SoManyBugs app.
I want to know the state of our
application when a user taps the screen
to create a new spider.
And I'll do this by setting a Breakpoint
in the handle single tap method.
First I'll go down to the method
handleSingleTap, and then I can create
the breakpoint by clicking in
the gutter, left to the main code area.
If you accidentally place
the breakpoint in the wrong place,
you can remove it by clicking and
dragging it off like this.
But let's go ahead and
keep our breakpoint here for now.
When you create breakpoints this way by
clicking in the gutter next to a line of
code, we'd say that we're creating line,
or instruction breakpoints.
If you can't see the line numbers
currently, go to Xcode, and
then Preferences.
Go to Text Editing and
then make sure that you have the
checkbox selected next to line numbers.
Another way to access the breakpoints
that we're setting is by looking at
the Breakpoints Navigator in
the Navigator side panel.
This is the second to last
icon in the Navigator panel.
Optionally, you can use the key
Command Seven hotkey to
display the breakpoint navigator.
In this view,
we can see the breakpoints that we set.
So right now we have a breakpoint set in
the handle single tap method on line 85.
And it's in the
breakpointbugviewcontroller.swift file.
We can toggle these breakpoints on and
off here by clicking on
the breakpoint icon.
And in the same way in the code,
you can click on the break point
icon to toggle it on and off.
So let's keep this breakpoint active for
now, and run the app and
see what happens.