Unity encapsulates an object's position,
rotation, and
scale into a structure
called a transform.
Check out these books
sitting on a table.
I've written a little program
to show you the transform for
these books, as I manipulate them.
When the books go up in the air,
you see their Y position increase.
I should note a couple of things here,
first,
when I talk about the y position,
I'm referring to Cartesian coordinates.
Hopefully, that's
familiar from math class.
Unity uses something called a left
handed coordinate system, it looks like
this, a left handed coordinate system,
just means that the positive y-axis
is up, positive x is right,
and positive z is forward.
The second thing I should note
is we're working in meters
throughout this course.
It's very important to work in real
world coordinates when developing VR
software, we'll talk
more about that later.
Anyway when the books are rotated,
you see their angle's change.
Unity allows you to view and manipulate
rotations in a lot of different ways.
In this case,
we're looking at Euler angles.
Each one of these numbers corresponds
to the rotation around the given axis.
It looks like this,
this is a rotation around the z axis,
this a rotation around the y axis, and
this is a rotation around the x axis.
When I rotate the books
around the y axis,
you can see it continually update below.
When the books are scaled,
you see the scale value increase.
The scale is a multiplier,
if it is set to one,
then the object is set to
its original starting size.
Setting the scale to 2.0 doubles
the object's size relative to its
starting size.
So, that's the basic theory.
Now, let's see it in practice.