Remember in lesson one, we learned that
A B testing is a type of experiment
with two variants, A and B,
which are the Control and Variation.
However, in this experiment,
we have three variants.
The Control stores, and
the stores with facials offered at
$76.99, and those offered at $87.99.
Additionally, the stores
are spread across three regions.
To properly match our control and
treatment units, we'll need to separate
our data so we're really performing two
AB analyses, one for each price point.
Therefore, we need to create a data
table that shows the stores,
the region, and the group the store
was in, Control or treatment, and
if treatment,
what was the price of the facial?