This app right here doesn't know
anything about the Firebase SDK right
now.
I'm going to quickly fix that by adding
a few key dependencies to Gradle.
In the project's root Gradle file,
I'm going to add the required
Google services plugin.
Over here in the documentation for
adding Firebase to your Android project,
I could scroll down and
get that exact plugin.
So I'm going to copy it,
and I'll add it right here.
Now I'm going to go to
the apps build.gradle file.
And I'm going to scroll
down to the bottom, and
again copying from the documentation,
I'm going to get this
apply GoogleServices plugin, and
I'll add it right here at the bottom.
The Google Services plugin is what
reads the configuration information for
the google-services.json
file that you added before.
Now once you go ahead and
sync, you effectively added the
Firebase SDK dependencies to your app.
If you scroll down further
in the documentation,
you'll see this list of
available libraries.
These are further dependencies that
you'll need to add when you want to
enable certain features.
So cool,
at this point you're pretty much ready
to start using Firebase in your app.
So let's get our users chatting by
adding our first Firebase feature,
the Realtime Database.