Looking closely at this screen shot,
we have two text views and one button.
The reason why I say we have two text
views is because they are styled
a little bit differently.
For example, the text color is
different for each of these.
So let's fill that in for
this first step.
The second step is position the views.
The question asks which view
group will be the root view.
From this screenshot it looks
like the views are shown
in a vertical column, like this.
So, from what we learned in lesson one,
a vertical linear layout
would be a smart choice.
So, I wrote down that we need a linear
layout as a parent view group
with three children views and we'll
set the orientation to be vertical.
If you said relative layout here,
that's okay.
That would work as well but
it would just be a lot more code
to have to define view IDs for
each of these and then position
them relative to each other.
So for
our use case a vertical linear layout
would be a little more concise and
easier to use.
Lastly, for
step 3 we want to style the views.
For the most part these views
look pretty standard but
we can make some slight adjustments.
For example, we notice that the quantity
header here is in all caps.
The quantity number down
here is in black font color
as opposed to the grey default color.
We also notice that there's a little
bit of space in between these views.
Which can be accomplished
with padding or margin.