Since a digital image is sampled at
discrete locations in space, it can
be written down as a two-dimensional
array or matrix of values.
Here is an example.
Note that this matrix
has fractional values,
both positive as well as negative.
But what if we could only represent
a small set of integer values,
say between 0 and 5?
How would you quantize this matrix so
that the result consists of
only the integers 0 through 5?
Enter the converted values
in the corresponding boxes.
Assume that we always round down.
For example, 1.8 becomes 1.
Also, be careful about the limits.
Anything less than the lower limit 0,
should be converted to 0, and
anything greater than the upper limit 5,
should be converted to 5.