First, the files or
the file blocks can be cached in the
client memories in their buffer cache.
The first place where files or
file blocks can be cached
will be the client's memory.
As the files or
the file blocks are brought in
from the server to the clients,
they can be present in the client's
memory as part of their buffer cache.
This is what regular file systems do
when they're bringing in files they're
reading from their local discs.
Second, the clients may
store cache components
on their local storage devices,
hard discs, SSDs.
It may be faster to retrieve portions
of the file from the local storage than
to go via the network to
the remote file system.
Finally, the file blocks can also
be cached on the server-side
in the buffer cache in memory
on the file server machine.
However, how useful this will be will be
the hit rate on that buffer cache will
depend a lot on how many clients are
accessing the server at the same time,
and how are their requests interleave.
If there is high request interleaving,
the buffer cache may prove
not to be very useful.
Because there may not be much
locality among the accesses which
are originating, in this case,
from many, many clients.