In the verged case, drawn here, you can take a look at
the epipolar lines by considering a couple of different points.
So remember, each point defines a pair of epipolar lines, and
here they're drawn.
And so here's an example of epipolar lines of two verged cameras.
And what that means is, that, for example, this point here since it's on,
this happens to be on this line, must be somewhere on that line, and
in fact, there it is, okay, and this point here.
Now, only a few lines are drawn here, of course, if I was looking for
this point here, there's some epipolar line, because there's some point here
that defines an epipolar plane, and there would be a corresponding epipolar line
on the other side, we've only drawn in a few of them.
So, here's a question for you.
We said that all the epipolar lines converge at the epipole,
well where's the epipole?
Well, let's take a look at just this image on the right.
The problem is, is that this image ended here.
If this image were huge, this line and
then this line, here's where they would intersect, okay?
So the problem is, is that the, the image, if you will, is sort of cropped,
the image sensor is too small to actually find the epipole.
The epipole is a mathematical construct that's the intersection
of the baseline with the infinite plane that contains the image plane.
So that's why the, the epipole lines look like they would converge, but
they they do it off the screen.