Now we're going to try
something slightly different.
Instead of one text field,
we'll have two of them.
Let's see what happens when
we try to stretch them.
When we think about what should happen,
they both have the same content hugging.
I'll create the views and stack them.
Ready?
Let's stack them.
Now let's add the last
remaining constraint.
And in order for the StackView to
stretch, we're going to change the size.
Ready?
Here we go.
Well, well, well.
Not sure about you but
I didn't see that one coming.
Apparently when the StackView has to
stret several views that have the same
hugging content value, instead of
stretching them all a little bit.
It concentrates all its stretching
power on the first one from the left.
This is a bit odd and it doesn't
provide the layout I was looking for.
We'll find out how to
fix this pretty soon.
But before we do so,
let's run a small experiment.