Shelly, is there any idea of reducing
the amount of randomness over
time in genetic algorithms,
like say in simulating kneeling?
>> Well,
not limitations that we've shown so far.
But the fitness function
naturally reduces the randomness,
as each generation gets
closer to the solution.
However, we could argue that
the method could do better.
In fact, there are a lot
publications that talk about tuning,
crossover mutations, number of parents
and all the other parameters to
optimize genetic algorithms to
converge as quickly as possible.
>> In some sense,
genetic algorithms are a fancy
version of stochastic beam search.
It happens to make a nice
analogy with biology.
>> Yep.
Some people call genetic algorithms
the second best solution to any problem.
But analogies are nice things when
learning or using different methods.
We used a lot throughout this section.
Hill climbing, annealing and
genetic algorithms are all analogies
to some physical or biological process.