So here's the solution.
To start off I'm creating
a Promise by using new Promise.
I'm going to pass a function into the
Promise with the parameter (resolve).
There is no reject in this case because
I'm never going to need to reject so
I just don't include it.
Inside the Promise I'm logging (this) so
I can check out its scope later.
And I've got the setTimeout.
You'll see that in the callback
function to the setTimeout,
I'm calling resolve to
resolve the Promise.
In this case the Promise will resolve
after some number of milliseconds that's
getting passed into wait.
Also notice that I am
returning the Promise.
And you'll see why in a second.
Then I've uncommented these two lines
which say that after 2000 milliseconds
the (finish) function should get called.
All right, let's see how this looks.
I will go ahead and refresh the page.
You see that two seconds
later it is complete.
It looks like this logged out
the window, or the global Object.
Incidentally, this, the scope of this,
could change depending on the context.
For instance,
if you use arrow functions with ES 2015,
you will see a different this,
so keep that in mind.
So the correct answer
is the global object.