Sometimes you wish to find corners,
as in this checkerboard over here.
Corners have an advantage over edges.
Edges aren't localizable.
They could be anywhere on an edge.
But a corner like this or a corner like this
can be localized, which is useful in computer vision.
What you see here is a Harris corner detector
applied to a checkerboard pattern.
And you can see all the points that define the checkerboard
clearly found by a relatively simple algorithm
which I'm just about to explain to you.
The Harris corner detector is really a simple algorithm.
Suppose you wished to find a corner just like this.
Then in the small region over here where the corner resides,
you will find a lot of horizontal gradients
and a lot of vertical gradients.
Now, what's our trick of finding gradients?
Well, we know about horizontal gradients.
We know about vertical gradients.
If those summed up over a small window--
as shown right over here--are large, we have a corner.
If only one of them is large and the other one is small, we likely have an edge.
We already learned this before.
It should be no surprise so far.
Now, the Harris corner detector generalizes to images,
we might have a corner like this
that is rotated from the original corner.
An image like this on a horizontal gradient
isn't quite as pronounced as it is on the vertical gradient.
But if you were to rotate our coordinate system
back into the correct orientation,
we could reduce it back to the case over here.
The trick that's being applied is to de-rotate
this image over here using eigenvalue decomposition.
We use a matrix that slightly generalizes these 2 things over here
where again we add our small windows.
We plug in the statistic over here up here.
The statistic over here down there.
And here we have a mixture with the sum over the product
of Ix and Iy in the off-diagonal terms.
If we apply eigenvalue decomposition to this matrix over here,
we get 2 eigenvalues.
And if both eigenvalues are large,
we again say we have a corner.
So, applying this eigenvalue decomposition
to every positive pixel in the original image
and then taking the local maxima of that result
where both eigenvalues are large gives us exactly
the Harris corner detector in a very robust way
to find corners in an image.
This is exactly what's being done over here,
and you can see it's very robust even to small rotations of the image,
and of course, to a scale of the image.
It's a beautiful way to find stable,
localizable features in contrast-rich images.