[Man] The answers are the first sentence is valid.
It's always true.
Why is that?
Because every model has to have at least 1 object
and we can have both x and y refer to that same object,
and so that object must be equal to itself.
Second, let's see.
The left-hand side of this implication has to be true.
X is always equal to x,
and the right-hand side says for every y, does there exist a z
such that y equals z?
And we can say yes, there is.
We can always choose y itself for the value of z,
and then y = y, so true implies true.
That's always true.
Valid.
Third sentence: for all x, P of x or not P of x,
and that's always true because everything has to be either in the relation for P
or out of the relation for P, so that's valid.
And the fourth: there exists an x, P of x, and that's true for the models
in which there is some x that is a member of P,
but it doesn' t necessarily have to be any at all.
P might be an empty relation, so this is satisfiable.
True in some models, but not true in all models.