All right, so look, what I'm showing you
here was sort of a state of the art of
motion estimation 20 some odd
years ago for derivatives, and for
our first class where
you're starting to do this.
That's fine, we're not assuming you
have any background in computer vision.
But if you were actually to take
a look at work that's going on now,
you will find motion estimation
that takes this as the basis and
then it adds a lot of other stuff to it.
So they worry about, sort of,
how the, the, the gradient behaves,
the constancy of the gradient.
They have energy-minimization terms.
Remember we did energy minimization for
stereo?
And that came up to
be a better solution.
It not only had the local matches but
it also had more global structure to it.
It also does keypoint matching,
which is saying I've got something
that has moved a long distance.
So remember, the, the short distance,
the, the expansion works really well.
We have to do things hierarchically
to get the long distance.
Or, you could just use point to point,
right?
I know this point went over here,
let me fill in the stuff behind it, or,
or around it.
And, when you do that, you get sort
of a much better result all together.
And this is an image taken from
a paper that came out in 2009