Let's start by taking a look at
the requestActivityUpdatesButtonHandler.
You can see the code here.
First, I just want to check if
the Google API Client is connected, and
if it isn't,
just send a notification to the user
to say that we're not connected.
Then, using
ActivityRecognition.ActivityRecognition-
Api.requestActivityUpdates,
I'm going to start the activity
updates process going.
I pass it the Google API client.
I pass it my detection interval in
milliseconds which I've just stored
as a constant.
And then I pass it this function,
getActivityDetectionPendingIntent(),
which will return a PendingIntent for
me.
I haven't written this function yet
which is why it shows up in red.
We'll see that in a few minutes.
Now once I've done all this,
I just set its ResultCallback to this.
And then I'm just enabling and
disabling the relevant buttons.
So similarly, now let's take a look at
the removeActivityUpdatesButton, and
it's very similar.
We're going to say, if the Google API
client isn't yet connected,
we'll just throw
an error to the message.
And now, using
ActivityRecognition.ActivityRecognition-
Api, I'm going to removeActivityUpdates,
passing it the API Client and
the same PendingIntent function
handler that we had earlier.
I'm then setting
the ResultCallback to this.
And then just enabling and
disabling the buttons as appropriate.
And now as you can see, because I
set the ResultCallbacks to this,
I have to enable
the callbacks on this class.
And I do this on the class level itself.
If I come here where I'm implementing,
I want to implement the callbacks.
And what we get in this
case is a ResultCallback.
So I'm just going to paste it in here.
Okay, we get a ResultCallback of Status.
So then I just set up the callback here,
and
it's going to be
a ResultCallback of type Status.
Now as you can see,
this is triggering an error for
us because it's expecting us to
implement this abstract method onResult.
So let's go ahead and
implement this now.
So I'm just going to paste it in here.
Again, all this code will
be in the speaker notes.
And onResult just takes a Status, and
what I should do in this case
is just to log something.
I haven't specified my tag yet.
That should just be a string for this.
So let's go ahead and
implement the onResult now.
I'm going to paste it in here.
And it's just going to take a Status,
and if the Status is success, I just
want to say that we've successfully
added activity detection in my logs.
Otherwise, I'm just going to say there
was an error adding or removing activity
detection and qualify that with
a status message for the status.
So now, you can see my class.
There's no more red underlines,
and I'm good to go to compile.
But there's one more thing
that I need to implement.
And that was,
if we remember, we had created this
getActivityDetectionPendingIntent()
function which returns
a PendingIntent to us.
So let's go ahead and
just implement that quickly.
So I'm just going to go ahead and
paste the code for that in.
In this function, I'm just going
to return a PendingIntent, and
how I'm going to do that is I'm
going to create a new Intent.
And this is a new Intent based on the
DetectedActivitiesIntentService class
that we created earlier on.
And then I'm going to return
a PendingIntent by calling the abstract
class PendingIntent.getService,
passing this intent to it, and
just saying I want to
flag update current.
And the idea behind FLAG_UPDATE_CURRENT
means I'm just going to return the same
instance of the class
if I have one already.
I know this is pretty complex stuff, but
just check out how PendingIntents work
and how Intents work by checking
the Android fundamentals courses and
by reading the documentation.
And that's it.
I now have everything I need
to be able to build and
run the application
that we saw earlier on.
Congratulations, you've just built
your first activity recognition app.