So the Home screen is where you go to
see a list of your Analytics accounts.
For now, you've only got
one Analytics account, but
if you had more they'd show up here.
And the Reportings dashboard is where
you'd go to see where in the world
people are using your app.
You go to the Admin dashboard
to see the Account Id.
You go to the Reporting
dashboard to see real-time data.
Course, no users right now.
And you go to the Customization
dashboard to create custom reports.
We won't be covering customized
reports in this course, but
it's helpful to have a high-level idea
of what each of the tabs are for.
And if you want to give permission
to other people to use your account,
you'd do that in the Admin dashboard
in the User Management section,
can add new users.
So how did you do on that quiz?