We are now going to move to a class
of AI problems where it's not
as easy to find a solution.
In search, we generally have a few
correct routes and we have a few
algorithms that help us find that
route in a fairly straightforward way.
However, in some problems
the state space is so large,
that we need other techniques to search
the space and find optimal solutions.
In this lesson we'll look
at simulated annealing,
one such technique to navigate
a potentially large space.
In particular,
we'll use simulated annealing
to solve the end queens problem,
a puzzle where we try and
setup end queens on a board in such
a way that they can't attack each other.
Let's get started.