The first system turns
out to have no solutions.
The second system has
infinitely many solutions.
And the third system has a unique
solution of x equals negative 1.177.
Y equals 0.707.
And Z equals negative 0.083.
Here's the code I wrote
to compute the solution.
I return the output of a function called
do_gaussian_elimination_and_extract_sol-
ution.
If an exception is raised, I return
either a message saying there is no
solution, or infinitely many solutions,
depending on which was raised.
In the do_gaussian_elimination, etc.,
function, I first compute the reduced
row echelon form of the system, and then
I check for contradictory equations.
That is,
equations of the form zero equals K.
And for too few pivot variables.
Both of those will raise exceptions
if those conditions are found.
If those conditions aren't found,
then I return a vector
whose coordinates are the constant terms
of the first inequations in the system.
Since the reduced-row-echelon form
of the system with a unique solution
will just consist of equations of
the form x equals some number,
y equals some number, and
z equals some number.
In the function
raise_exception_if_contradictory_equat-
ion, I'm just checking each
plane to see if it has
all zeroes in its normal vector.
If so, I check its constant term for
a non-zero entry.
If I find a non-zero entry in
the constant factor, then I know I found
a contradictory equation and
I raise the appropriate exception.
In the raise_exception_if_too_few_pivots
function,
I use list comprehension to count the
number of indices that are non-negative.
Since indices of first non-zero terms
in each row returns negative one
if there is no non-zero term in a row.
So the number of non-negative indices
is the number of pivot variables.
And I compare that number with
the total number of variables to see
if it's smaller.
If so, then I know I must have
an infinite number of solutions
as we talked about
earlier in the lesson.
So I raise the exception.