So we can see, at any given time,
the handle in the tray,
and where its position is.
>> Okay.
>> And
we can also see the size
of the view port as well.
>> So let's go back.
What's the user's purpose
in using this application?
>> Is via the text.
>> So that's got to be a percept, right?
>> Okay.
>> That has to be something
that's there.
And there's one other one.
It's a little bit more subtle.
That was part of the statement
of what the application does.
And has to do with the scrollbar handle.
>> Oh, okay.
So
I think I might know what
you're talking about here.
The size of the handle will have to
relate to how much of the document
we're currently seeing.
>> So if we were ultimately
going to implement this thing,
we have to make sure that that
particular percept was updated when we
change to a file of a different size or
we change the view port Window's size.
So we have these four percepts that
are going to correspond to attributes.
And we can assign them to the particular
components that we're modeling.