When it comes to defense
against attacks,
the most important principle
is to employ defense-in-depth.
In other words, we should deploy
multiple layers of defense mechanisms.
The first line is a prevention mechanism
that stops attacks from getting
in our networks and systems.
Inevitably though, some attacks can
defeat the prevention mechanisms.
That is, there are holes or
weaknesses in the prevention mechanisms
that allow some attacks to get through.
For example, an attack can be a
JavaScript that can only be triggered by
a specified time in a future, and so
it'll be hard for the prevention system
to stop this attack now because it does
not know or see the attack behavior yet.
The second line of
defense is detection and
response mechanisms that watch
activities on our systems and
networks to detect attacks and
repair the damages.
Again, there will be attacks that can
go undetected, at least for a while.
For example,
attacks that blend in with normal
activities such as the ATP malware that
is a malicious browser plugin would be
hard to detect initially, not until its
effects such as data loss due to stolen
credentials manifest sometime later.
The third line of defense is
attack resilient technologies.
The enable the core elements or
the most valuable systems on the network
to survive attacks and
continue to function.
For example, a server is actually
a collection of diversified systems.
Varies with different implementations so
that at least one of them will not be
susceptible to the attack because
an attack typically exploits
specific vulnerabilities that only exist
in some, but not all, implementations.
To summarize, we need to deploy
defensive in-depth mechanisms,
or multiple layers of security
mechanisms to protect our networks.