There are benefits of multithreading both to applications when we
have multithreaded applications, but also to the operating system, itself.
By multithreading the operating system's kernel,
we allow the operating system to support multiple execution contexts.
And this is particularly useful when there are,
in fact, multiple CPUs, so that the operating system context can execute
concurrently on different CPUs in a multiprocessor or multicore platform.
The operating system's threads may run on behalf of certain applications.
Or, they may also run some operating system level services,
like certain daemons or device drivers.