What are the challenges that you find with Storm?
>> The challenges that we're finding in Storm is the operation aspect of it.
>> Mm-hm.
>> I mean, like keeping.
Like, we're running hundreds of jobs, right?
And keeping them alive.
And there are some business-critical processes and
jobs that keep running all the time.
The downtime of the jobs cost us business dollars.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So we have to keep them from running all these.
So one of the first challenges we faced was when initially
Storm was deployed so it was using two people as I was mentioning.
So, now as we were scaling because our data was growing.
So we were hitting the zookeeper very hard.
And that became an issue and zookeeper was not able to keep up.
And zookeeper is not a, a, a what we calls a scalable system.
It's a scale up system.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Because the reason why is like when you write something and
the zookeeper is replicated to all the nodes before it [INAUDIBLE].
So, so you can't do that with zookeeper.
So, so then we figured out what is the issue in storm that really causes that.
So we, we figured out there are two issues that caused it.
One is, whenever you have a, these workers, and
a large number of workers happen.
When the, there's a, the only way knows that a particular worker is alive right
now is by worker sending a heartbeat to the zookeeper and
zookeeper storing that.
So when the large number of, big cluster of few 100 missions on
probably around ten workers, 20 workers, that's lot of workers.
And all these workers are writing their heartbeats into the zookeeper.
And that made the zookeeper price go very high and
brought, and [INAUDIBLE] zookeeper also.
Which is not a good thing, so what we do here
is like we look into it here in order to facilitate such scalability.
The mood lit functionality of [INAUDIBLE] to separate things.
So, for instance, a process is [INAUDIBLE] going to zookeeper.
>> Nice. >> And the column is [INAUDIBLE] and the zookeep,
the members which are done on the lasers [INAUDIBLE] looking at the zookeeper.
So that's all [INAUDIBLE] problem.
Then there were additional topic for zookeeper as well too.
We chose called the Kafka offsets.
So when I'll be reading some data from the Kafka, distributed queue, so
that Kafka offsets also [INAUDIBLE] zookeeper.
Okay, but, for like every two minutes every one minute, and last time when I
read it, I wasn't exhausted, because remember when another process fail and
machine failure occurs, the small fails which means I
would at least target the affected machine so it can be restarted.
When I restart it doesn't know where to start from,
because it was processed til up to end.
I don't know where to start from now, right?
I can go back to one.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Which just means it's, there'd be a lot of errors in the right?
So it's, every two seconds, it saves where it is.
So, mm, so then it when it comes back out, then it picks up where it left off.
By looking at the offset, in the zookeeper, oh, I was there before here.
Then he starts from there.
So that traffic also was causing the zookeeper.
And now, what we have done is, we have moved that out and
we arrive at [INAUDIBLE] too.
So those two are the one of the biggest issues will stop.
And so, generally keeping up with the scalability of
the stock itself, it's [INAUDIBLE]