In addition shared memory
accesses can by synchronized
operating system provided mechanisms for
inter process interactions.
This is particularly important
because the process shared option for
the mutex condition
variables with p threads,
isn't necessarily supported
on every single platform.
Instead, we rely on other forms
of IPC for synchronization,
such as message queues or semaphores.
With message queues for instance,
we can implement mutual exclusion
via send/receive operations.
Here is an example of protocol
how this can be achieved.
Two processes are communicating
via shared memory and
they're using message
cues to synchronize.
The first process writes to the data
that's in shared memory and
then it sends a ready
message on the message queue.
The second process receives
that ready message,
knows that it's okay to read
the data from the shared memory.
And then it sends another type of
response, an OK message back to P1.
Another option is to use Semaphores.
Semaphores are an operating system
supported synchronisation contract and
a binary semaphore can have two values,
zero one.
And it can be achieved,
the similar type of behavior like
what is achieved with a mutex.
Depending on the value of semaphore,
a process is either allowed to
proceed or it will be stopped at the
semaphore and it will have to wait for
something to change.
For instance,
a binary semaphore with value zero and
one, we use it in a following way.
If its value's zero,
the process will be blocked.
And if its value is one, the semantics
of the semaphore construct is such that
a process will automatically
decrement that values.
It will turn it to zero,
and it will proceed.
So this decrement operation is
equivalent to obtained a lock.
In the instructor's notes, I'm providing
a code example that uses shared memory
and message queues and
semaphores for synchronization.
And the example uses the System V, or
the System five API as a reference.
The system five APIs for these two
IPC mechanisms is really somewhat
similar to those that we saw for shared
memory in terms of how you create and
close, et cetera,
message queues or semaphores.
For both of these constructs
are also posex equivalent to APIs.,