Now it's time to add
Android auto support.
So let's open up
the mainactivity.java file and
let's go to the start of the send
notification method here.
The first step is to create an intent
and pending intent to be triggered
when a message is heard and
when a message has been replied to.
We already created broadcast
receivers earlier, and
now we're going to use them.
So let's created a message heard intent,
and note that we use addFlags to
indicate that we should be able to
trigger packages that are stopped.
Our messaging app might not be running
at the time when a message is heard
by a driver.
We use set action to specify
a unique action name so
that the broadcast receiver
we want is triggered.
Make sure the package name here matches
your package name in the Android
manifest.xml.
Also, you putExtra to
specify the conversationId
which is some kind of identifier that
your app might need in the broadcast
receiver to identify which conversation
notification is referring to.
We've used 42 here, but you would
normally have some kind of index
into a data structure that
your messaging app has.
Now we create the PendingIntent
which is a wrapper that lets
the notification trigger this intent
on behalf of our application.
We pass the same 42 value as used for
conversation ID earlier.
We parse in the intent and
we allow this notification to be
an update on a previous one if needed.
We need to now create the intent and
pending intent to be triggered when
the driver replies to a message.
The code for this is almost
identical to the previous code so
we're going to cut and
paste that in now.
The code for this is almost identical,
except we used
a different action string.
You can see here we're using
MY_ACTION_MESSAGE_REPLY instead.
You'll see this is the same
ConversationId from earlier
since this is the same conversation.
Now we need to implement
the remote input object,
which will handle the speech
recognition for you and
deliver it to your broadcast
receiver as a string.
The voice reply key here will be
the key used to extract out the reply
later on in our broadcast receiver.
An interesting thing to note is that
Android wear implements a similar remote
input extension as well, and
the set label call is used there.
You'll notice here that Android Studio
has highlighted remote input as
not being valid.
You can press Alt+Enter and
it will import the package for you.
Make sure you pick the one
from the support library.
Let's now go and
show you how to receive the results
in the two broadcast receivers.
Open up my message heard receiver,
the onReceive method is called when
a message has been heard by the driver.
You can retrieve
the ConversationId key value
by using the following code
to get it out of the intent.
We should remove the code that
generates this exception here, and
let's put some logging here instead.
Once again,
we do Alt+Enter to add this dependency.
Now, let's look at
the MyMessageReply receiver.
This unreceived method is called
when a message has been replied to
by the driver.
You can retrieve the same ConversationId
here as well just like before and
now we can retrieve
the text of the reply.
Once again, we hit Alt+Enter a few
times to resolve the dependencies and
now we can retrieve
the text of the reply.
Note that we use voice reply key that we
supplied earlier to the remote input and
we can retrieve it
using getCharSequence.
You can do whatever you need with this
stream of characters for your app.
In this case here we're logging it so
we can see it in the ADB logcat output.
And just like before,
we need to remove the code that
generates the exception here as well.
Let's go back to
the MainActivity.java file.
The next step here is to create
an unread conversation builder.
We will use this to organize
a group of messages that are From
a particular sender.
So, use the code.
You'll notice here we have conversation
name which is the person who these
messages are from.
I've had coded my name in here but
you typically get this information
from the messages in your application.
Also, you can see we've references
the two pending intents from earlier.
So that auto knows which intents to
run when your conversation is read or
replied to.
Now we need to actually add
the messages from the conversation.
So we've hard coded an example here
that you would typically loop through
an array and
add each message separately.
The add message method here is used to
add the message string through this
conversation.
Set latest time stamp is used
to indicate when the message
actually arrived.
I've used the current time stamp here
since we're just simulating things.
So this is all the new code that we
need to add, now we need to edit
the existing notification to use
the objects we just created.
The way we extend a notification
if using car extender.
Once again, use alt enter to
add the package for this.
At this time, we call the build
method of the unread conversation
builder from before and
store it into the car extender.
The car extender is then stored
into the notification builder
using this extend method.
Finally, we need to issue
the notification and
the code is already here for that.
But there is one gotcha here
that you need to watch out for.
When creating notifications
with extensions, such as for
auto aware, you need to use
notification manager compact.
If you use the standard
system notification manager,
the car extender will be lost,
so why is this?
Well, if you're building against
an auto framework, such as API10,
the system notification manager does
not know about these extensions and so
will not pass them on.
So to be safe, you should use the
compact versions of both notification
and NotificationManager to ensure
that everything works properly and
you don't have any problems.
First, we work the NotificationManager
code here like so.
So we grab the NotificationManagerCompat
like this,
use old answers to resolve dependencies,
and we're done.
So now, let's test this by compiling and
installing it to our phone.
Click the green triangle,
select the emulator Hit okay,
switch over to the emulator.
If you followed the previous steps,
it should run on your phone,
although you won't be able to
see any difference just yet,
since we're not actually using this
inside an android enabled vehicle.
Go ahead and try to replicate
all the steps that I just did.
You can refer to the Android auto
messaging training guide for
a detailed rundown of how to
do what we just discussed.
The URL is at the top, right here, it's
developer.android.com/training/auto/messaging.
Once you've completed the task,
check the box to continue.