Another big economic place for computer vision is sports.
If you watch any sort of professional sports on TV,
you see them leveraging computer vision sometimes in powerful ways,
sometimes in simple ways but are really useful.
So here, this is Sportvision first down line for American football.
I say American football because sometimes when I go to Europe and
I say football they think a ball is round.
We know that footballs are not round.
And what's interesting about this line here is this is the line that he has to
cross to make a first down.
Of course that's not on the field, it's drawn in there.
The only interesting computer vision that's going on here is you'll notice that
that line does not go through him.
So the system had to separate out the player from the background, okay?
And even though, by the way, kind of greenish color in there,
it's able to separate the grass from the player.
In fact, if you ever watch one of these games when it's rainy and
it's an outdoor field and
it gets all muddy, the first down line stops working so well.
Because the grass is now mud and it doesn't look like grass anymore and
it can't tell the players and the whole thing doesn't work so well.
And you can see a computer vision failure right there.