First, ESP can provide
both confidentiality and
integrity protection.
This is true.
Second, if authentication
option of ESP is chosen,
message integrity code is
computed before encryption.
This is false,
because the message integrity code
is computed after encryption.
Third, to protect the confidentiality
and integrity of the whole original
IP packet, we can ESP with
authentication option in tunnel mode.
This is true, because in tunnel mode the
encryption will cover the whole original
packet, and the authentication will
also covers the original packet.
Fourth, in The integrity
hash covers the IP header.
This is true.