Hello world, it's Siraj and
welcome to intro to deep learning.
In this first episode,
we'll predict an animal's body weight,
given only the weight of its brain.
This course will be four months long,
and
it will all be released on my channel.
I'll have a Live session
every Wednesday at 10 AM PST,
that explains every
week's topic in depth.
And I'm collaborating with Udacity
to offer a Nanodegree to those that
successfully complete this course.
This course is for anyone who wants to
learn how to harness the incredible
power of neural networks and
become a deep learning engineer.
You don't have to be an experienced
developer or a mathematician,
the only prerequisite for this course is
knowing quantum mechanics, just kidding,
only basic python syntax.
We'll learn what we
need to along the way,
by building an AI that
can do everything from
predicting the price of Tesla stock,
to painting surrealist masterpieces.
Traditionally, programming has been
about defining every single step for
a program to reach an outcome.
The machine learning flips that
approach, with machine learning
we define the outcome and the program
learns the steps to get there.
So, if I wanted to build an app that can
recognize California license plates.
Instead of writing out code to
recognize the hundreds of different
features of a license plate,
like the shape of certain letters and
the colors, we just say, here's some
examples of a California license plate,
learn the steps you need so
that you can recognize it.
Or, if I wanted to make a bot that could
beat Super Mario, instead of writing
code for every possible scenario, like
jump if you see a Koopa and it's running
toward you, we'd say the goal is to
get to the end point without dying.
Learn the steps to get there.
And sometimes we don't even have an idea
of what steps could possibly be.
Like if we're a bank and
we suspect there's some kind of
fraudulent activity happening.
But, we're not sure exactly
how to detect that, or
even know what to look for.
We can say,
here's a log of all user activity.
Find the users that are unlike the rest,
and
it'll learn the steps to detect
the anomalies by itself.
Machine learning is already
everywhere on the Internet.
Every major service uses it in some way.
In fact, YouTube's using it right now to
decide which other videos you might like
as you watch this.
And it's uses will only grow over time.
It'll be embedded in all of our
Internet-connected devices.
Everything from fridges,
to cars, to personal assistants,
will be learning and
adapting to our needs.
And you know that rule that says you
need 10,000 hours to master any skill?
Well, we'll just be able to offload
that training time to our machines and
it'll give us super powers instantly.
Anyone will be able to
compose a symphony.
Alexa, I feel melancholy,
make me a piano piece for this.
[MUSIC]
And add a beat to it.
Anyone will be able to direct a movie.
Ok Google, recreate Star Wars but
put me in it.
&gt;&gt; I darker-ize most of my code now.
&gt;&gt; Breaking my heart.
&gt;&gt; Damn right.
&gt;&gt; With machine learning,
if you can dream it, It can exist.
And the field is currently
advancing very fast as researchers
build on each other's work.
[SOUND] My neural net sucks.
Go deeper.
Wow, I just achieved state of the art.
[MUSIC]
There are a lot of machine
running models out there, and
one of them is called a neural network.
When we use a neural network
that's not just one or two,
but many layers deep to make a
prediction, we call that deep learning.
It's a subset of machine
learning that has outperformed
almost every other type of model.
Almost every time on
a huge range of tasks.
We'll dive into Deep Learning
more in next episode,
but this video we'll just focus
on Machine Learning in general.
We usually class learning
into three different styles.
The first style is called
Supervised learning,
it's where we give a model a labeled
data set like car pictures,
so it gets feedback on what's
correct and what's not.
You just have to learn the mapping
between the labels and the data, and
then it can solve some given task, like
classifying the type of car in an image.
It's all relatively straight-forward,
and
we've gotten incredible results from it.
The second learning style is
called unsupervised learning.
This is when we give a model
a data set without labels.
It gets no feedback on what's correct or
not.
It has to learn by itself what
the structure of the data is
to solve some given task.
This is harder to do,
but more convenient,
since not everyone has a perfectly
labeled data set sitting around.
Most data is unlabeled.
It's messy and complex.
And the third type is
reinforcement learning.
This is where a model isn't given
feedback right off the bat,
it only gets it if it achieves its goal.
So, if we're trying to create
a reinforcement learning bot that can
learn to beat humans at chess,
it would only receive
feedback if it won the game.
Whereas in the supervised approach,
we get feedback every move, and
in the unsupervised approach,
we'd never get feedback, even if it won.
Unlike the other two learning styles,
reinforcement learning is linked
to the idea of interacting with
an environment through trial and error.
So I've got a data set of
measurements of different animals,
and we want to predict an animal's
body weight given its brain weight.
Since our data is labeled,
this will be a supervised approach, and
the type of machine learning task
we'll perform is called regression.
We'll write out a ten line
python script to do this, and
I'll explain things as we go.
We'll start off by importing
our three dependencies.
The first one is pandas,
which will let us read our data set.
The second one is scikit learn,
which is the machine learning library
we're using for this example.
And the third is matplotlib, which will
let us visualize our model and data.
Now that we've imported
our dependencies,
we can read our data site using pandas.
We'll use the read fwf function
to read our animal data set.
A table of fixed-width formatted
lines into a pandas datafram object,
which is a 2D data structure of rows and
columns.
Our data set contains the average
brain and body weight for
a number of animal species.
Once our data is in our dataframe
variables, we can easily parse and
read both measurements into
two separate variables.
We'll store our brain measurements
in the x values variable and
the body measurements in
the y values variable.
So if we were to plot this data
right now on a standard 2-D graph,
it would look like this.
And our goal is that given
a new animal's body weight,
we'll be able to predict
what it's brain size is.
So how are we going to do that?
[MUSIC]
Linear regression.
learns linear model object to
initialize our linear regression and
store it in the body
regression variable.
Then we can fit our model
on our xy value pairs.
Now we have the line of best fit.
We can plot our x y value pairs
on a map plot line scatterplot,
then plot our regression line by
saying for every x value we have,
predict the associated y value and draw
a line that intersects all those points.
We can then display it using
the show function, lets go ahead and
compile this code in terminal.
Our scatterplot will appear with
all our data points mapped out.
The x axis represents brain weights,
and the y axis represents body weights.
Our regression line seems to fit most of
the data pretty well and there seems to
be a very strong correlation here
between brain weight and body weight.
And as we move along the line,
given any brain weight, we can also
predict the associated body weight.
So to break it down, while traditional
programming is about defining the steps
to reach an outcome, machine learning
is about defining the outcome, and
our program will learn
the steps to get there.
There are three different
learning styles.
Supervised, unsupervised,
and reinforcement learning.
And linear regression models the
relationship between an independent and
dependent variable,
to create the line of best fit,
which we can then use
to make predictions.
The winner of last week's coding
challenge is Mick Van Hulst.
He modified the game world to be more
complex and his cue learning bot was
much more efficient at reaching
the goal than my demo bot.
Wizard of the week.
And the Runner up is Vishal Batchu,
he generated maps using cellular.
The challenge for
this video is to use and
learn to create a regression line for a
different data set that I'll provide and
print out the error between your
prediction and the actual value.
Details are in the read me, post your
git help link in the comments, and
I'll announce the winner in one week.
Please hit that subscribe button and
for now,
I've gotta feel the learn,
so thanks for watching.