So here you can see my onCreates and
in my onCreate,
I've done most of these tasks.
So first of all my three buttons are my
mSignInButton, mSignOutButton, and
mRevokeButton.
And these I just find them
using findViewById and
passing in the ordered id of the button.
These are objects that I've declared.
Two of them are button and
one of them is one of sign in buttons.
I'm also saying the TextView status,
I'm just, again, sign_in_status
is my TextView, and allocating this
to the local object called mStatus.
So then, for the three buttons, I set
an OnClickListener, and I just set it to
this, so then this class becomes
the callback for OnClickListener.
And then finally, I'm saying, for
my GoogleApiClient, I've defined
a local Google API client here.
If I scroll up,
you can see here where I've defined it.
It's a private GoogleApiClient and
GoogleApiClient.
I've done the same with the buttons and
the textView.
And so now here, I'm just assigning my
GoogleApiClient to the output of this
function, buildApiClient.
I've created that function here, and
this just builds the API client.
It uses the Plus.API
as we had discussed.
And it just does the usual API Client
stuff, adding the ConnectionCallbacks,
adding the OnConnectionFailedListener,
adding the API,
but also adding Scope as we've defined.
So we're going to use the PROFILE Scope
and we do it in this way.
Now we'll build that and then return it.
So now in my onCreate,
I'm going to get a Google API client And
it's going to be built
by this helper function.
And it's going to be one to use
the Plus.API and PROFILE scope.
Pretty straight forward, right?