Divs are great for
general all purpose blocks but they can
lead to a condition called div soup.
Div soup happens when developers only
use divs to build their web page and
as a result the page is
just a mess of nested divs,
inside of divs, inside of divs.
And it's hard to tell what markup
corresponds to which
elements on the page.
Which is the problem I had in the game
at the beginning of this lesson.
Technically there's nothing
wrong with only using divs but
cognitively there is.
HTML is a markup language,
meaning that it describes a document.
If you can't easily figure out what is
describing then it's failing at its job.
Look at this page.
It's all divs, however,
you can build the same page using
elements that are much more
descriptive than divs.
These elements are called
semantic elements and
you've actually been using some already.
Here's the same page
with semantic elements.
Do you notice any differences?
You shouldn't.
It's the same result but
much nicer HTML.
Besides being easier to read, semantic
elements offer some additional benefits.
Using semantic tags makes your page
friendly for search engine crawlers like
the Googlebot, which determine where
your page shows up in searches and
makes it possible to show cool
previews of your content.
In effect this helps with SEO or
search engine optimization.
Semantic elements are also good for
accessibility.
Many people with vision impairment use
screen readers and semantic elements
makes it easy for screen readers
to make sense of your page.
That way it's easier for
everyone to enjoy your content.