The meta, paper concludes by having a case study using
the Linux operating system.
Case study was concerned with higher-order connectors.
In particular, a operating system like Linux provides several major
elements in support of all the applications they're going to run on the system.
One key component is the file system.
Another is shared memory.
And the third is process, support, support for processes.
As far as the files are concerned, the underlying hardware doesn't have files.
Right? The.
It has bytes.
There may be a mechanism by, for, for blocking those bytes into groups.
But the operating system self provides some kind of facade,
that makes it look like there are files there.
And in so doing, it ne, needs to deal with contention.
If there are multiple, accesses to the file, are you allowing them
to take place concurrently or is there some kind of synchronization.
required.
And it's the operating system's job to provide these arbitration, adaptation,
and coordination connectors to get a composite file facade connector.
Shared memory, is a data-access type connector but there are issues there,
synchronization as well.
And finally, in terms of process scheduling,
okay, processes are all about controlled access to resources so
an arbitrator type connector is required there.