With our JSON data converted into
a foundation object, how do we use it?
Let's go back to the postman
tool to see where to start.
In our JSON response,
if you look at the very beginning we can
see that it starts with the curly brace.
And if we scroll down to the bottom,
the very bottom on line 251,
we can see that it ends
in a curly brace as well.
This is indicative of a JSON Object,
which in SWF is comparable
to a dictionary.
This means that when we call
the JSONObjectWithData method,
that we should be getting
some kind of dictionary back.
It's actually an NSDictionary and
we can interact with it
just like a SWF dictionary.
So the next thing we need to do if
we know that we have a dictionary
is that we need to identify the key
value pairs that we're interested in.
Ultimately we know that we want to
get one of the url_m values and
then also the title value.
We need the URL in order to
display the image to the user and
we'll need the title for
the title label in the U.I.,
but, to get at these values,
we have to take a top down approach.
Because at the highest level,
we have this photos key value
pair that contains everything.
And we can see that the photos value
starts with the curly brace and
ends with a curly brace, so
this is just another JSON object and
it can be represented
in SWF as a dictionary.
So back in our code let's create
a photos dictionary and we'll
want to populate this dictionary with
the values stored at the photos key.
So this constant is the same
thing as photos like this.
But I'll leave it as a constant for now.
And then we want to try to convert
it to a string AnyObject dictionary.
And we'll use this if let syntax in case
somehow our response doesn't have this
key value pair, then it won't crash.
Also, know that the reason that
we're using the String and
any object dictionary is because
we know that the JSON keys
themselves are strings, but then the
values, they could be any other object.
They could be a JSON object,
which is another dictionary.
It could be a number.
It could be a string.
We don't know.
And we'll just print
the photosDictionary.
Awesome, our output looks similar and
we're starting to get closer
to the values that we want.
Now, back in Postman, the next key value
pair that we want to target is for
the key, photo.
This value starts with a bracket and
it ends with a bracket.
And that's indicative of a JSON array,
which is comparable to a SWF array.
But then the question becomes,
what type of array?
Well, if we look closely it looks like
each element here in the array is itself
another JSON object, and
each item is separated by a comma.
So we have a JSON object here, and
actually I'll just collapse it,
and we have a comma,
then we have another JSON object.
Another JSON object, and so forth.
This means in SWF,
we can use an array of dictionaries.
So back in our code,
let's get the array of dictionaries, and
we're going to call
this the photo array.
That's stored at the photo key, and this
is critical, of the photos dictionary.
Remember it's contained
within the photos dictionary.
And then we'll create
an array of dictionaries.
Notice the outer brackets
denote the array itself.
And within the brackets
we have the array's type,
which are string any
object dictionaries.
And to make sure this works,
let's try printing the first
photo dictionary in the array.
Nice it works.
We're almost there.
But before we continue forward I want to
make sure you can follow my steps.
That is, get the photos
dictionary at the photos key.
Then in the photos dictionary,
get the array of photo
dictionaries at the "photo" key.
I know, this sounds confusing, but this
is the way the results are returned.
And finally,
print the first photo dictionary.
When you're done,
check this box and continue.