Next, let's go one step further and
slightly change the style for
our inbox text.
The inbox is the most important and
frequently used mail folder.
And so I'm going to create a style for
the inbox text named inboxStyle,
that will be similar to the folderStyle,
but bold so that it stands out.
To create this new style, I could copy
and paste this folder textStyle and
add another item to bold the text, or
I could utilize style inheritance.
At the top of our styles.xml, you may
have noticed this parent attribute in
our AppTheme called
Theme.AppCompat.Light.DarkActionBar,
and this is a pre-defined theme
that our AppTheme inherits from.
Styles and themes use inheritance
similar how classes use inheritance.
If a style has a parent, it will inherit
all the parents that the parent style
includes, whether that's color or
padding or more.
And then it can define only
the properties that you want to
add to that style or
override in the parent class.
And Android comes with a couple of main
themes already, referred to as light and
dark themes.
Our AppTheme inherits
from the light theme,
named
Theme.AppCompact.Light.DarkActionBar.
This light theme basically means our
app has a default light background.
But if we get rid of this light,
and leave this as Theme.AppCompact,
this will default to
Android's dark theme, and
that gives a very dark
background to an app.
This theme is often used for settings
activities or media players, and
could also be good if you just want
a different look for your app.
To change the theme of your app or
even an individual activity,
you just need to set its theme attribute
in your Android manifest file.
Like here, where our main app
theme equals style/AppTheme.
But back to our styles code and
inheritance.
If you're defining completely
new styles like folderStyle,
then you don't need
a parent attribute at all.
But for our inbox style,
we'll just want to add
one more bold style property
to this folder text style.
So we can set the folderStyle
as a parent to this one.
We'll just add the one additional bold
text style property that we want.
Now let's go back to our
style activity layout and
apply this style to our inbox TextView.
Instead of folderStyle,
we'll say inboxStyle.
And let's save this and
run our app again.
Now, when we look at our styles and
themes activity,
we can see that the text looks the same,
but with this additional bold property.
And now we have styles
that add consistency, and
help to highlight important
components in our app.