Doing a merge sort with 2-way
Merging is pretty good in terms of
the number of slow
fast memory transfers.
By way of reminder,
that number asymptotically is n
over L log based 2 of n over z.
I've rewritten this in a funny way for
reasons that you'll see momentarily.
Now this number of transfers still
falls short of what it turns out is
the lower bound.
And here's that lower bound now.
It's n over L,
log base z over L of n over L.
Here is it is rewritten in
terms of log base twos.
So this scheme relative to this
scheme is off by a little bit.
That little bit is approximately
log base 2 of z over L.
And, in fact,
it's not even a little bit.
For typical adjacent levels of the
memory hierarchy on a real machine like
disc and main memory or main memory and
the last load of cache.
It might be roughly of factor of ten or
as high as a factor of 100.
Hence, my question for you.
Why doesn't merge short,
based on a 2-way merging scheme,
obtain the lower bound?
This question is
deliberately open-ended, so
there isn't necessarily a very
precise single correct answer here.
I'm mostly asking to force you to
think about how two-way merging works.
Force you?
I know what you're thinking.
What?
Is this Russia?
Are you forcing me to Gulag?
And if you are Russian,
I am truly sorry if I have offended you.
It's just that my wife is Polish, and
there's this natural distrust there.
If you don't believe me, just go ask any
mid 20th century European historian.