So the first step in what you had to do
was to modify your build.gradle file.
And as you can see here,
I've done this by adding
the Google Play services libraries.
I'm just using 6.5.+, but
as we spoke about in earlier sessions,
you should always make sure that
you're using the most recent version.
And use the full number,
don't use a plus.
But I'm just putting plus in here for
ease of use.
Next, you have to edit your
AndroidManifest file, and
you can see that here.
So, if I double click on that, and
open it, I can see my AndroidManifest
file and the details in it.
Now, there are a number of
things that needed to be added.
The first thing that you had to
add was the ability to use OpenGL.
And, as you can see, I'm using OpenGL
here with the users feature tag.
android:glEsVersion=0x002000 and
required=true.
So this gets added onto the manifest
tag above the application tag.
The second thing that you wanted to
add within the application tag was
metadata saying that you're using
the play_services libraries.
Here you can see Android name equals
Com Google Android GMS version.
Android value equals ad integer
of Google Play Services version.
So these are the same tags that
you've been adding to be able
to use the services libraries
throughout this course.
The next tag here is the metadata for
your API key.
And the API key is what you
created in the Google Developers
console earlier on.
Here you can see I've added the API key,
and just the values that I was
able to get form my API console I
put into the Android value tag for
com.google.android.maps.v2_.API_KEY.
So you've added the OpenGL,
you've added the Google Play services
libraries and you've added your API key.
The final thing that you need
to add to your Android manifest
are the users' permission tags,
and here you can see them.
So users' permission for
android.permission.internet,
android.permission.accesssnetworkstate,
and
androidpermission.writeexternalstorage.
So, once you've added all of these,
your android manifest is good to go.
Your build gradle is done and
you're now ready to add
the map to your application.