With our test for GET method in place,
it's time to write our
first convenience function.
I'm here in the login view controller,
and I ultimately want to make a single
call to run the entire authentication
flow and access the app.
To do this we've created a method called
authenticateWithViewController, and
it's part of the TMDB client.
To use this, we'll use the TMDB
client shared instance and
we'll call the
authenticateWithViewController method.
This method takes a host ViewController,
which should be this log in
ViewController and a completion
handler to let us know if the off flow
succeeded, or
there's an error string if it failed.
So I'll go ahead and specify self,
and then if I'll hit enter on this
parameter, it will auto complete,
and we have our trailing closure.
We can get rid of void for now.
So at this point,
we actually know enough to
finish this completion handler.
If the off flow is successful,
then we need to log in.
But if it's not successful,
then we can display an error to users.
Now for either of these cases we want to
make sure that these lines of code,
which affect the UI, are run using
the form UI updates on main function.
Now let's dive into the
authenticateWithViewController method
and see what's going on.
Yikes, okay,
this method is definitely not pretty.
We have this pyramid of code kind of
jutting out to the right and then it's
coming back down to the left here and
just hard to understand what's going on.
Sometimes you hear this type of code
referred to as a pyramid of doom.
And the reason that this is happening
is because we have a bunch of
completion handlers
nested within each other.
Now the reason we have to do
this is because, for instance,
when we call getRequestToken,
we have to wait for it to complete
before we call loginWithToken.
And this continues all the way
down until our final step,
which is getUserID.
And this looks exactly like
what we saw in this flowchart.
So let's kind of break
this down piece by piece.
So I'll just bring this back up, so that
we can have a restricted view here, and
let's look at the getRequestToken.
If it succeeds, then we're going to
print the requestToken, we'll store it,
and then, we'll call loginWithToken.
Otherwise, we're going to call
this completionHandlerForAuth and
we're going to pass it success,
which in this case is false, and
an error string that's
generated by getRequestToken.
Now if we succeed,
we're going to log in with the token,
and let's see what this looks like.
And let me go ahead and
collapse the getSessionId.
And similarly, if this request succeeds,
then we are going to call getSessionID
with our request token, otherwise we are
going to call completionHandlerforAuth.
We are going to pass it at failure and
then the error string in this case
is coming from our loginWithToken.
Then if that suceeds
we'll go with sessionID.
Let me bring this back up,
store the session ID, get the user ID.
This is our successful case.
Otherwise not a success.
Only pass the error string.
And let's get user ID.
And there we go.
And this is hopefully our
final success case here,
where we're storing the user ID.
And then, success or fail, we're
going to call completion handler for
auth with whatever value
success gets from getUserID,
and whatever value error string it's
populated with, hopefully null.
Now, all this nesting of completion
handlers is extremely hard to look at,
it's hard to manage, and it's hard to
reason about, and if you follow people
in the iOS community, they're saying the
exact same thing about code that looks
like this, which is why there are nice
alternatives to this nesting structure.
But they're outside
the scope of this course.
If you're interested,
I'll post some links in the instructor
notes where you can find out more.
Let's go back to the getRequestToken.
We'll follow it by command clicking,
there we go.
This is the first convenience method
that you're going to be implementing in
this exercise.
The comments include these three
steps that you'll want to complete
to call the taskForGET method
that we implemented earlier.
And for this third step,
we see it says send the desired
values to completion handler.
The completion handler it's referring
to is this completion handler.
We have success, requestToken,
which can be an optional string.
So it's nil or a string, and
then the error string as well.
And this is what's going to
be populating, here we go,
these values here, so take some time to
finish implementing get request token.
Remember you'll need to
specify the parameters and
method in order to
call taskForGET method.
Then take the data resulting
from task forget method call and
extract the desired value and return
it back in the completion handler.
If you do this correctly, then
the request token should be printed out.
When you're done, check this box.