We had this problem, of when we put in through a correlation,
we got back out sort of this flip thing, all right.
And, if you remember,
here's the equation of correlation, we have this kernel H and we sum over it,
going from minus k to plus k, multiplying it times our image, and
what that did was it caused us to end up with that flipped result, all right.
The right way of thinking about this, is that, when an impulse comes in and
it hits the filter, what comes back out is sort of this, this reverse signal.
So, the, the right way of thinking about the operator is there's
something called convolution, and when we do convolution, that's what we
actually mean when we say we're going to apply this filter or this kernel, and
what convolution does, is it, flips both the left-right and
the up-down direction, you could have either flipped the kernel or
flipped the axis to the pixels, it doesn't matter, you would get the, the same
value, and, so that flipping gives you what's referred to as convolution.
So by the way, if I was using a Gaussian or
a box filter, how will the outputs be different for correlation and convolution,
that is what happens if I flip my Gaussian, answer, nothing, okay?
For a circularly symmetric or for a symmetric filter, whether I do convolution
or correlation doesn't matter, it is going to matter to us in the next lecture,
the one after that when we take derivatives in one direction or
the other, and that's when you have to be careful, but
if you have a symmetric filter, it doesn't matter.
So this can be illustrated nicely in the following way, so
here we have the, equation for
the convolution operator, and we're going to illustrate it like this, all right.
So here we have our filter and there's this little asterisk up here and
the asterisk is to show you sort of what the top right hand corner is.
When we do correlation, we just pick that up and then we sort of slide it
around, when we do convolution, what we do is we rotate, the thing, and,
because it essentially flips it left, right and up, down, right, you
see that the little asterisk is now down here in the bottom left hand corner.
Okay? And then, thank you, Kristin.
We zoom that all over the image and that gives you your output.
So, that's our convolution operator.
Again, the difference between correlation and convolution only matters if
you have an asymmetric filter but now you know the difference.
Like I say, convolution is actually sort of the physics, so
what's going on when you put an impulse through this response.