The answer is only the first
sequence is bitonic.
Remember that the definition asks
us to check all circular shifts.
So, let's imagine the values of
the first sequence arranged in a ring.
Next, let's check whether
consecutive values go up or go down.
Going clockwise, 2 to 3,
3 to 6, and 0 to 2 all increase.
By contrast, 6 to 1 and
1 to 0 both decrease.
With respect to the ring,
all the pluses are consecutive and
all the minuses are consecutive.
So the sequence is bitonic
up to a circular shift.
Makes sense?
Let's try the same thing
with the second sequence.
First, we draw a ring.
Then we take differences going,
say, clockwise.
Phooey, the pluses and minuses are no
longer consecutive along the ring.
Therefore, there is no circular shift
that will satisfy the first condition.