deep learning is a hands-on empirical
field more experiments that we engineers
and researchers try the more ideas we
generate and some of them actually turn
out to work other ideas that seem
promising initially don't work the
practice is definitely ahead of the
theory in many cases and so it's
important not to get too attached to
theories about different network
architectures are exactly what layer
follows another in a network instead to
be a successful deep learning
practitioner you need a bias towards
action experiment to answer your
questions rather than just thinking deep
thoughts also don't be too discouraged
if something doesn't work immediately
the first time you try it
keep experimenting until you find a
network and hyper parameters that work
for your problem i like to think of deep
learning is one of the few places in
computer science where we actually do
science most of computer science is
really more about engineering but in
deep learning we really do spend a lot
of time running experiments and building
theories of what works and why just like
real scientists yeah i would say that
does make us real scientists you're
learning about several important network
architectures that you can use as a
basis for your own projects but more
important than the intricacies of these
networks is to get your hands dirty and
try to solve real problems
this will develop your confidence and
give you practical skills with that in
mind let's look at that other network
from $MONTH 2014 which has its own
strength