Let's look at it in a little bit more detail.
So, what we're interested in, of course, is to compute the Gaussian at level k.
We take the h, which was one we looked at previously, convolve it with the Gau,
the original Gaussian from the previous level.
So in essence, that's why it's a pyramid.
So you take the previous level to compute the next one.
You take the previous to compute the next one.
And this, in essence, is known as the reduce function.
And again, basically takes the previous image to generate the new one.
So for example, this is my image at level one.
I can use this to generate an image at level 2.
Here, while the samples of these images that go from g1 to
g2 is half, I'm still scaling it up,
all of them to be the same scale to kind of show what's happening as we go down.
Of course, g3 would basically be based on g2.
So here, of course, recursion is going on.
These are recursive functions.
g4 is based, now, on g3.
Again, I'm scaling them up, all to be of the same size,
to showcase the fact that information is being blurred out.
So, here, of course, you see a lot of pixelation, and even more.
So we've gone from images that were 256 by 256 to 128 by 128
to 64 by 64, 32 by 32, and 16 by 16.
Now we can actually start noticing an interesting fact.
This is extremely blurry, much more crisp.
This is encoding all of the high frequencies.
This is encoding all of the low frequencies.
Here you can see the blurry shape of Einstein.
Here you can see all the details, including even, for example, the hair.