So Jake, what's your favorite animal?
Well, let me show you.
I'm going to create a read write
transaction with access to
the keyval store.
Then I'm going to get the store and
call.put on it.
Now I know it's a cliche these days,
but cats are actually my favorite.
So I'm going to pass in cats as the
value and favorite animal as the key.
I'm going to wait on completion
of this transaction.
Then log out a little
confirmation message.
Over in the browser, let's refresh.
And there's the Console Log and
over in resources, there it is as well.
Okay, so if you're still alive at this
point, you're doing really well but
take my hand as we dive deeper into this
API, it's time for another crash course.
So far we've created a key
value objects store but
what if I wanted to create a different
store with objects all of the same kind?
People, for instance.
To do that, I'll need to create another
object store, as I mentioned earlier,
to maintain database integrity.
You can only create objects stores and
indexes within the upgrade function.
But this upgrade function
isn't getting called,
because it's already been called for
version one of the database.
So, I'm going to start by
bumping the version up to 2.
Then I'm going to create a new
object store called People.
And this isn't going
to have separate keys.
I'm going to make the name property of
the objects inside the stall be the key.
Okay, sure in the real world you
can have more than one person with
the same name.
But we're going to assume names
are unique for the sake of this demo.
Now we've actually created a bug here.
And we can see it if we
try loading the page.
We get all of these nasty errors.
Because the browser hasn't seen version
2 yet, it will call this function, and
unfortunately it will fail.
This is because the browser
hits this line.
It tries to create the key file store,
and
errors because it's already created it.
Thankfully the upgradeDb object
has this old version property
telling us the version
the browser already knows about.
We can use a switch statement to make
the browser skip the bits it already
knows about.
So we switch on the old version number,
if it's 0, we set up the key file store.
If it's 1, we set up the people store.
Usually with switch statements you
have a break after each case, but
we specifically don't
want to do that here.
So with this code,
if the browser hasn't set up this
database at all, it'll start here.
Create the key file objects store but
it will continue and
create the person object store.
If the browser already has version 1,
it'll start here and
only set up the new person object store.
If we refresh the browser now,
the errors are gone.
And the store has appeared
in the resources panel.
Let's put some stuff in it.
Now we have this object store set up,
I'm going to create a transaction for
the person store and
I want it to be read write.
Then I get the object store and
I'm going to add a person to it
including the name, age,
and favorite animal.
I'm really having to fight spelling
favorite the British way here so
I hope you appreciate that.
Anyway, in this model a person
is just a JavaScript object.
Notice that I'm calling put but
I'm not providing a key this time.
This is because we've told the store
to treat the name property as the key.
I'm going to wait on
the transaction completing and
logout a little success message.
One person isn't enough of course.
So here are a few more
that I prepared earlier.
If I refresh the browser we can see in
the console the operation completed.
But also in the resources panel,
you can see all the people.
If I want to read
the people in the store,
I create a transaction for people.
I get hold of the object store and
I call get all which returns a promise
for all the objects in the store.
And then I'll log those out.
If we run that code in a browser we
can see all the people are logged in
alphabetical order of their
name since that's the key.
But what if I wanted to group them
together by their favorite animal.
This is where indexes come in.
Like other modifications
to the database,
indexes can only be created
as part of a version upgrade.
So we bump the version number and
start adding to our switch clause.
Now we're going to add
an index to the person store.
And at this point, we need to get
ahold of the person object store.
In other places we've called
transaction.objectStore to do this.
And there's no exception here.
Database upgrades have their own
transaction object found @ upgradeDB
transaction.
So now we have to store.
I'm going to create
an index called animal.
Which sorts by the favorite
animal property.
To use this index,
I'm going to modify this code.
Where I'm listing all the people.
I'm going to get the index from
the object store by name, animal.
An index has a very similar
API to the object store.
So instead of calling
get all in the store,
I'm going to call it on the index.
If I refresh the browser,
the people are logged out.
But this time, all the cat people are
logged first, and then the dog people.
In def tools we can
see the index as well.
I can even execute queries on the index.
For instance,
I'm going to pass cats into get
all just to return the cat people.
If I refresh the browser, there they
are, just the two people who love cats.
And I think there's a task coming
your way as the micphone is ringing.
Hey, mike.
Got some IDB for the student to do.
>> I certainly do.
>> Brilliant, take it away.