Firewall is a widely deployed
prevention technology.
To motivate the need for
firewalls, let's look at a typical
enterprise network at a high level.
An enterprise network is
part of the Internet.
It typically has an internal or
trusted part, where only the company's
employees can access to.
For example, if this is a bank, the
trusted part of the enterprise network
has the internal email servers and
systems that process
financial transactions.
And only the authorized staff
can access such systems.
The enterprise network can also
have a public face, in part.
For example, the bank has a web server
for its customers to log in, or for
the public to just learn about the bank.
This public facing service or
in the so-called demilitarized zone or
DMZ, that while it is part
of the enterprise network,
it is separated from
the trusted network.
For example,
while customers can interact with
the web service in the DMZ to log in and
submit transaction requests, they
cannot directly access the servers in
the trusted network that are authorizing
and processing the transactions.
When a company has multiple physical
sites, for example a bank can have
different branches in several cities,
then each site can have its own local
and trusted network, but the sites
need to communicate with each other.
For example, employees in one city or
one branch, these are the trusted users,
need to access the corporate network
at the headquarters in another city.
And such access or
traffic is from across the Internet,
which is not trusted.
How do we get traffic to its destination
correctly across the Internet?
We need routers.
Each local or enterprise network has
at least one router at its perimeter.
And there are core routers
on the Internet that bond.
Together, these routers transport
packets from one local area network,
to the Internet backbone,
and on to the destination,
local area network and
to the specific host on the network.
The routers can send traffic to the
correct destination on the Internet, but
as we have discussed, whether
the network should allow such traffic,
depends on security considerations.
For example, traffic from another
trusted network such as a branch office
should be allowed to the trusted
network of the headquarter.
Another example,
traffic from untrusted network
should only be allowed to
the web service in the DMZ and
access from the DMZ to the trusted
network is again restricted.
In short, we need a device that can
enforce these different security
restrictions on traffic.
A firewall is such a device.
More precisely,
a firewall is a device that provide
secure connectivity between networks.
For example, between internal trusted
network to extended untrusted network.
It is used to implement and
enforce a security policy for
communication between the networks.