[Thrun] So we learned a lot about invariances.
Let's now take actual images and do something with these images.
This is an image I took a while back in Amsterdam,
and it's interesting because there's a lot of interesting features
like these line features over here and possible corner features over there.
In computer vision we don't use color images very much.
We mostly use black and white images like this greyscale image over here,
which misses information from the original image,
but it turns out that greyscale is more robust to lighting variations than color is.
That's a fairly common representation for images for computer vision.
So a greyscale image is a matrix typically of several hundred rows
and several hundred columns
that has small values imprinted that correspond to the greyscale of a pixel.
These values scale between 0 and 255, where 255 is white and 0 is black.
You can see how this matrix is full of values that together compose the image.
Here is a very small image of size 4 by 5,
and based on the numbers I put in, it feels like there's a transition going on.
At the top the image is relatively bright.
These have values close to 255.
And at the bottom it is relatively large.
This is way too small an image to recognize anything.
Picture a matrix much, much larger than this,
yet an image that's still just a 2-dimensional matrix of singular brightness values.
At least a greyscale image is a matrix like this.
A color image would have 3 different values per pixel
which correspond to red, blue, or green or some other encoding of the color itself.
But for now we're going to be content with greyscale images.