Thanks for helping us out with our first
steps of marketing plan for Embarkment.
Some of the things we considered for the
geographic segmentation, for example,
were neighborhood and
proximity to dog parks.
So, we can tailor our solutions for
each neighborhood and
map other solutions available for
the dog owners there.
>> When thinking of
behavioral segmentation,
we came up with dividing families that
are going on a family vacation from
individuals going on business trips.
This way the service they are looking
for might be different and so
do our messaging, and
the places we decide to advertise on.
But there is no right or wrong here.
You could go with demographic
segmentation, and
divide it based on demographic
characteristics of the dogs themselves.
Like big dog versus small dogs,
for example.
Or even psychographic segmentation of
the owners with different solutions that
may be priced differently.
Like come and
get a deluxe service versus come and
be just another dog in our backyard.