Let's look at some popular operating systems,
starting with the Linux architecture.
This is what the Linux environment looks like.
Starting at the bottom, we have the hardware, and the Linux kernel abstracts and
manages that hardware by supporting a number of abstractions and
the associated mechanisms.
Then come a number of standard libraries, such as those that implement
the system call interfaces, followed by a number of utility programs that
make it easier for users and developers to interact with the operating system.
And, finally, at the very top, you have the user developed applications.
The kernel, itself, consists of several logical components,
like all of the the I/O management, memory management, process management.
And, these have well defined functionality, as well as interfaces.
Each of these separate components can be independently modified or replaced.
And, this makes the modular approach in Linux possible.
The Mac OSX operating system, from Apple, uses a different organization.
At the core is the Mac micro kernel and
this implements key primitives like memory management, thread scheduling and
interprocess communication mechanisms including for, what we call RPC.
The BSD component provides Unix interoperability via a BSD
command line interface, POSIX API support as well as network I/O.
All application environments sit above this layer.
The bottom two modules are environments for development of drivers, and also for
kernel modules that can be dynamically loaded into the kernel.