Let me just quickly now preview Harris Detector Algorithm.
And I'll also talk about the feature the other type of featured detection
methods, we'll cover them in detail in the next set of lectures.
So what basically what you do for
Harris Detector is we want to compute the Gaussian derivatives at each pixel.
Remember again, we have learned how to do Gaussian derivatives.
Then we want to compute the second moment matrix M using the ix and
iys in a Gaussian window around each pixel.
Then we want to compute the corner response function R.
Again, we know how to compute R once we know M.
We want to threshold R a little bit because you want to kind of have a,
you know, a lead as to how many corners we want to protect and
then we want to find a local maxima of response function.
I have a doc doing any kind of mon, maximum suppression.
Now what basically that means is now I can take an image like this, and
I would find a lot of features which are basically Harris detector features.
Again, we will cover this in detail in a future lecture.