At this point, you should have
modified the submitOrder method and
also added the displayMessage
method within the main activity.
Then you can hit run to
see it on your device.
First, I'm going to change the Quantity,
and
then I'm going to hit the Order button.
Now the app says free for price.
That answers the first question.
When the ORDER button is clicked,
then the price text field now says Free.
For the second question we talked
about creating a string variable
in the submitOrder method.
Even though we haven't seen code for
a string variable before,
I ask you to guess what you think
the variable name and value would be.
The answer is that the variable name
is priceMessage, and the value is Free.
To arrive at these answers,
let's look more closely at how
we create string variables.