Let's learn how to animate a coconut
falling from a tree onto the ground.
First off, open up Unity and
load our starter scene for this lesson.
Check out the notes below for
the specific scene to load.
Okay, great.
So if we want to take this
coconut right here, and
make it fall,
then we have a lot of options.
The easiest way to make a coconut
fall would probably be to
use the Unity physics system,
so let's try that first.
Just attach a sphere collider and
a rigid body to this coconut.
Just like that.
Okay, press play.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And you're done and it looks great.
Very realistic.
But what if you want to defy gravity, or
what if you want the coconut to
follow a different path entirely.
Well then you'll probably
need to write some code.
So instead of using a physics system
let's write a script that does exactly
what the rigid body does to the coconut,
that is, it lets it fall to the ground.
First things first, let's clean up and
remove the rigid body and
sphere collider from the coconut.
Okay, great.
Then let's create a script
called fall from tree.
New C# script, FallFromTree.
Double-click on the script,
and load it up in MonoDevelop.
Remember, we want to move
the coconut down, every frame,
until it hits the ground, then stop.
Since we want to move
the coconut every frame,
we're going to put some code
inside of the Update method.
Go ahead and
add this code to the Update method.
Okay, now I'll explain all of
this in just a second but first,
save your script and go back to Unity.
Now drag and drop the fall from
tree script onto the coconut.
And then press play.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Hm, well you see the coconut fall, but
it falls right down through the ground
and continues falling forever and ever.
It's a good start, but
that's not exactly what we want.
We need to stop the coconut
when it hits the ground.
Okay, let's take another
look at our code.
We start by typing transform.
This is a shortcut to access
the transform component
of whatever game object
the script is attached to.
Remember studying the transform
component earlier in this nanodegree?
Well, this is the same thing.
We're just changing it using
code instead of the editor.
So that code is really just changing
the position of the transform component,
right here.
Okay, after that,
the Translate command tells Unity that
we want to move an object In 3D space.
We then tell Unity that we want to
move the object 0 units in the x axis,
-2.5 units in the y axis,
and 0 units in the z axis.
There are a couple
things to notice here.
First, we put an f next to -2.5.
That f just tells Unity we're typing
a number with a decimal point.
It's a way of specifying exactly
what kind of number we're using.
The f stands for floating point.
But you can just think of it
as a decimal value, for now.
You'll also notice that we
multiply -2.5 by time.deltatime.
That's pretty strange, isn't it?
Well, we'll cover
time.deltatime in depth soon.
For now, just know that this
smooths out our animation.
Lastly, we put Space.World
to say that we want to
move the coconut in World Space,
rather than Local Space.
This means that,
even if we rotate the coconut,
it always falls towards the ground.
Okay, let's wrap up this section,
now that we've covered the very
basics of procedural animation.