So, what did you get?
I got 5.5 years.
Here's my reasoning.
Let t denote time, measured in years.
Now R we said doubled every 1.9 years.
Mathematically, that means R is
proportional to 2 to the t/1.9.
Beta is similar.
It's 2 to the t/2.9.
The balance point is just
the ratio of these quantities.
Simplifying it, you should get
roughly 2 to the t divided by 5.5.
The doubling time is there for
5.5 years.
Now you might be suspicious.
This is just a quiz, right?
Or is this a real life trend?
Well, let's check it on Wikipedia,
purveyor of all things good and
definitely 100% true
with no questions asked.
Here's some stats on two
mobile GPU processors.
The top one was launched in June 2008,
and the bottom one in March 2015.
That's a period of
time of almost 7 years.
Let's call it 6.75 just to be
a little bit more precise.
Now, the balance point is supposed
to double every 5.5 years.
So, after 6.75 years you would
expect the balance point to
increase by a factor of roughly 2.34.
Now, what I've been calling beta is
given by these bandwidth parameters.
R is given by the peak
processing power parameters.
Those are these two.
So, are these data consistent
with the predicted rate of change
in the balance point?