Setting up a local development
environment for Ruby is hard.
It's one of the biggest barriers for
people just starting out to code.
They often think if I
can't even set this up,
how can I possibly become a developer.
The reality is setting up an environment
has very little to do with your
ability to code.
It's just a painful process that
everyone has to go through at least once
and setting it up on Windows
makes it even harder.
One thing is Ruby development is very
heavily focused on the command line.
And the Windows command line is
very different than the ones in
Unix based systems like Mac or Linux.
Here's what using the Windows
command prompt looks like.
And here's the Unix command line.
Even if the prompts and
output looks similar to you,
the commands are different.
And this could confuse
you in the long run.
Issues with software compatibility,
speed, and available support for
Windows users are also
factors to consider.
This does not mean that it's impossible
to work in Windows as a Ruby Developer,
but we want you to have a development
environment that allows you to focus on
learning Ruby.
Not undebugging Windows.
You don't need to go out and
buy a new computer for this program.
In this lesson,
you'll set up a virtual machine or v.m..
That will allow you to run an operating
system different than the one currently
installed on your computer.
This means you will be able to
follow along with the lessons.
As if you were on a UNIX computer,
like Linux or Mac.
Here are two ways you might use a VM.
Some VMs are like having another
desktop computer inside your computer.
You can interact with the VM through
its graphical user interface
by opening windows and clicking buttons.
The same way you would interact
with your regular computer.
Some VMs, like the one you'll
set up in this lesson,
only allow you to interact with
the computer through the command line.
These are called shell VMs.
In this lesson you will set up a Linux
shell VM that you'll be able to use for
the rest of this Nano degree program.
Using the Windows command prompt,
you will be able to start up your
VM with a simple command and
run all your Ruby files through the VM
as if you had a Linux computer.