The goal number one is to reduce
latency, and this implies that we want
to try to execute the atomic
operation as soon as possible.
As a result, the locking operation will
immediately incur an atomic operation
and that can potentially create some
additional contention on the network.
Therefore one conflicts with three
is one of the correct answers.
Similarly with two, if we want to reduce
the waiting time to delay, then we have
to make sure we're continuously spinning
on the lock as long as it is not
available, so that we can detect as soon
as possible that the lock is freed and
we can try to acquire it.
Again, this will create contention and
so two is conflicting with three.
As for any conflicts between
reducing latency and
reducing waiting time or delay, it is
hard to answer this in a general case.
It will really depend on from
one algorithm to another.
So we're not going to mark this
answer as a conflicting one.