So all the tweets come in from a lot of places.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And then they form some master, big pipe.
And then Storm processes that.
What do you use to aggregate all the tweets from [CROSSTALK] is it
storm in reverse?
[LAUGH].
>> Actually it's not there's a sophisticated pipeline and
scaling system that runs those things.
>> Okay. >> So like, we have what you call Ascribe running on
pretty much all the, the servers, and so whenever you create and
do engagement with the computer application and everything.
>> Yeah.
>> Those are all captured as log units.
>> I see.
>> Those log units are captured on the [INAUDIBLE].
So, I the logs and collected like on the door.
And we can more of the that's the main part.
And once you collect them,
then it goes to something called a Skype application system.
Where it's coming from several hundreds of thousands of
nodes [INAUDIBLE] aggregated nodes.
And those nodes in turn pump the data into HTFS for complete persistence.
>> Okay. >> And also push towards Kafka.
And that is to be a queueing system, that I said.
And up all these out of it.
>> Out of the Kafka.
Okay, thank you.
No, that's very interesting.
>> Yes. [CROSSTALK] So that, that pipeline/ is a pipeline unless