Now that we have a blank canvas, we
can insert SVG elements, like circles,
to start drawing.
In order to be able to add any SVG
element, such as circles or rectangles,
we need to first insert a top-level,
generic SVG element.
Let's select the main content area
by using our select method, and
then with this selection,
we can append an SVG element and
store the SVG element into
a variable called SVG.
Notice that this blank SVG canvas
gets inserted into the DOM, and
this is what we'll use to insert points,
lines, and bars, or
any other graphical shapes that we want.
Now, hovering over this element, we can
see that Chrome indicates that we have
an SVG canvas that's 300 pixels wide and
150 pixels tall.
It looks like nothing is
displayed on the page, but
by default, SVG elements don't
have any visual representation.
Well, let's make our SVG element,
which will be our plotting region,
a little bit larger.
To do that, I'll change the width and
the height attributes.
I'll set the width to 600 pixels, and
I'll set the height to 300 pixels,
and there we go.
We have a place to
start making our chart.