We now talk about spectral clustering.
The fundamental idea of spectral clustering
is to cluster by affinity.
And to understand the importance of spectral clustering,
let me ask you a simple intuitive quiz.
Suppose you are given data like this,
and you wish to learn that there's 2 clusters--
a cluster over here and a cluster over here.
So my question is, from what you understand,
do you think that "EM" or "K" means
we would do a great job finding those clusters
or do you think they will likely fail to find those clusters?
So what were the questions--Do "EM" or "K"
mean succeed in finding the 2 clusters?
There is a likely yes and a likely no.