Here's my answer.
How did I get this?
I hope this argument will make sense,
even though it's not completely precise.
First, ask yourself what
steps do I need to perform?
There are really just three.
First, each node needs to scan
its local list of elements and
decide which elements go where.
All nodes can do this in parallel.
And the local work is linear in
the number of elements per node.
Next, the nodes need
to exchange elements.
That's an all-to-all operation.
In this case, every node has about n
over P elements so in the all-to-all,
you'll expect them to send about n over
P squared elements to every other node.
To get a concrete cost for
the all-to-all,
let's assume a fully connected network.
Oh, that assumption is good fodder for
this box.
In this case,
the all-to-all will have this cost.
Now the last step is
just the local sort.
Assuming we do a sequential
bucket sort within each node,
this step could have linear cost.
Voila.