Guesses.
Further explore this idea of ethics and
laws that we covered before.
Let's look at this question.
And this perhaps has happened to you,
and happened to others.
Let's say due to an error or
mistake, somebody sends you
sensitive data in an email.
They just put the wrong attachment.
They were trying to send you one thing
and end up sending something else.
Well this is sensitive information
that is arrived at your desk, or
your desktop, should you read it.
First of all, if you were to read it,
you obviously didn't go into
the computer, and didn't do unauthorized
access that's been sent to you.
So, the two options we have here, should
you decide to read, or not read it.
And if you decide not to read it,
what's the reason why you think
you should make that choice?
So pick the right option,
and we'll talk about it.