For the techniques we're
going to learn in this course,
we need a sample app with a little
more state than Pitch Perfect.
So we return to the movie DB API that
Jared used in the networking course.
We made an app that's
called My Favorite Actors.
It lets you keep track of
a list of actors that you like.
We're going to persist the state
of the app in two ways.
In this lesson, you'll see NSCoding.
In the next lessons,
we'll use Core Data.
You'll find the app in the repository
if you check out step 2.1.
We didn't choose this app
completely at random.
The app is meant to have a really
similar state to the Virtual Tourist
app, the portfolio app for this course.
If you can learn how to make this app
persistent, you'll be really set up for
the Virtual Tourist app.
The list of actors corresponds to
the pins in the Virtual Tourist app.
If we select an actor, we can see
the actor's movie poster images.
These correspond to the Flickr
images in the Virtual Tourist app.
We can add actors, which is similar
to dropping pins in the map and
then we can go and
download their movie posters as well.
In the code available in step 2.1,
the app has no persistent state.
Every time we turn it off,
we have to start over.
Now I'm going to turn it back on and
everything's gone.
It's terrible really.
We need to fix this.
So let's pause for a second and
imagine this app while it's running.
How does it organize the data
that it's displaying?
Does it keep an internal table, like
a spreadsheet with rows and columns?
Does it use arrays to
hold struct instances?
Or does it use key value
pairs like user defaults?
Check the answer that seems best to you.