A lot of times you'll be working with
projects that require different library
versions or different versions of Python, even.
In my experience, and many other
people's, it's really difficult to get
all these versions to play nicely
together on one computer. To solve this
problem we use virtual environments
manage with libraries such as Virtualenv.
Virtual environments let you separate
libraries required by different projects
so you can avoid conflicts. If you're
working with data though, Anaconda is
the way to go.
Anaconda is a distribution of libraries
and software specifically built for data
science. It comes with Conda, a package
and environment manager that will make
your life a thousand times better. Now
I'll show you a bit about using Conda. I
didn't really create a new environment
for each project I start. This way I can
keep the necessary package versions
separate. For example, I wanted to start a
new project using Python 3, which you
should be using for all new projects, I
can create an environment for it.
Type in "conda create" give it a name.
"tea_facts" - it's a bot that tweets facts
about tea - and the Python version 3. And
enter.
This will create the environment for me,
now I can enter the environment like so
"source activate tea_facts"
This is the command on Mac and Linux. On
Windows it's just "activate." Now i'm in the
environment. You can see the name in the
prompt and you can see here the packages
that are installed. These are just the
default packages. Now I can start
installing what I want for this project.
Let's install Numpy and Pandas for
working with the tea data and matplotlib
for making visualizations.
Then install your notebooks, which I
like to use to develop code.
And again, looking at the installed
packages, I have all these ready to use
for my project. And, these are separated
from other environments so I won't run
into any conflicting version issues.
Okay, now it's your turn to learn how to
use Conda for your own projects.
This lesson will take around 30 minutes,
up to an hour. Have fun!