What's iterative deepening?
>> Let's go back to our problem
of making our computer respond to
an opponent in two seconds or less.
Before, we calculated the maximum
depth we thought we could search in
time safely.
With iterative deepening,
we are going to do something simpler.
We are going to search to level one and
get an answer for
what we think is the best move.
We'll keep that answer in
case we run out of time but
we'll start the process again and
go to level two this time.
If we finish searching level
two before time runs out
we'll keep it's best move and restart
the search going from level three.
We'll continue doing this process
until we run out of time and
then return our best answer.
>> So you're saying we
should do the same thing
we did to determine quiescence?
>> Basically, and
quiescence is a good side effect.
>> But that just still
doesnt answer my question.
Isn't this process inefficient?
>> Surprisingly, iterative deepening
doesn't waste that much time.
Because of the exponential
nature of the problem,
the amount of time is dominated
by the last level searched.