So today what we're going to do is we're going to finish up Hough with two
significant changes.
The first one is we're going to use non-analytic models.
So it's not going to be lines, not going to be circles,
where we had, where our parameters were analytic parameters.
Instead, the parameters are going to express, say, the orientation or
the scale of some fixed but arbitrary template.
The second thing, and this we'll only talk about briefly.
Is a visual code word based approach where we
used what are called visual code words for
the features instead of edges, and this is much more modern computer vision.
Edges really came from a, an older view of, of how objects would be described.
And now the focus tends to be a lot more on individual features.
And, later in the course, we'll talk about interest points, and features about
those points because I don't want to teach you just old computer vision.
So, that was the, so the, the first one was then, and this is the now