Okay, let's look at each of these.
So here we have our type, and here we
have our name, but we don't put a space,
we put a dash here.
And honestly,
that's really no different than just
writing something like, stringname.
Java won't be able to see
these as separate words, and
will cause an error because it thinks
you're trying to declare a variable
without giving it a type.
Oops, and apparently we also forgot
a semicolon, that's no good.
So this has a lot of problems.
Okay, let's look at the next one.
String is a correct data type,
so that's all good.
But over here, the variable name.
We're breaking our variable naming rule.
Variable names really can't contain
miscellaneous punctuation like these
quotes, here.
Whoever's just declared this variable,
might be confusing the variable
name which is just a typed word,
with the value which is a string and
must be surrounded by quotes.
So, variable names can't have
weird punctuation in them.
Strings require you to
surround them by quotes.
Okay, on this last one,
the data type looks correct.
And now we have name on profile.
Well, this is actually breaking
one of the variable naming rules,
which is in your variable
name you can't have spaces.
Java's basically going to see
the word name and expect to have
some sort of initialization off of it,
or semi-colon, or something.
It won't expect for the name to
continue after there's a space.
So how do we solve this?
Well, usually if we want a name like
this we'd just write it in camel case.
So you could write something out
like name on profile with the O and
P being capitalized and
no spaces in between.
And this is a great variable name,
especially if you want to be able
to include all of these words.