The subset sum problem emits a fully
polynomial time approximation scheme, or
FPTAS for short.
Recall that the decision version for
subset sum was whether,
given a set of numbers, there was any
subset summed up to a particular value.
The optimization version
of this is to maximize
the sum of sub subsetted numbers
without exceeding some threshold t.
This problem emits a very
important class of approximations.
For any epsilon greater than 0 there
is an order n squared log t by
epsilon time.
Factor 1 over epsilon approximation
algorithm for the subset sum problem.
The smaller the epsilon,
the better the approximation, but
the slower their running time.
It may be intuitive, that one should be
able to trade-off spending more time for
a better approximation guarantee, but
it isn't always the case that we get to
do so arbitrarily as in this theorem.
Because this isn't
a particular algorithm, but
rather a kind of recipe for producing
an algorithm with the right properties,
we call this
a Polynomial Time Approximation Scheme.
Or PTAS, for short.
For every epsilon you choose,
there's an algorithm that
can approximate that well.
This approximation scheme is extra
special, because the running time
is polynomial n 1 over epsilon, as well
as polynomial in a size of the input.
Therefore we say that this is a fully
polynomial time approximation scheme.
The alternative would be for the epsilon
to appear in one of the exponents
perhaps and then it would just be
a polynomial time approximation scheme.
The scheme itself and it's analysis
are a little bit messy, but
they're still well worth
looking up on your own.