Let's now illustrate the policies that
are used in Sprite by walking through
what happens in different
types of file axises.
In the process, we will also look at
what are the different pieces of stale
that the Sprite distributed file
system would have to maintain and
the server, and at the client's
side in order to be able to
maintain the required
file sharing semantics.
Let's say, initially we have n clients
that are a, accessing the files for
reading and one writer client.
All open operations will
go through the server and
the server will allow all accesses.
All of the clients, readers and
writers will be allowed to cache blocks
of this file and the writer client
will have to keep track of when was
each block of the file modified in order
to be able to enforce the write back
policy in Sprite every 30 seconds,
the blogs that have not been
modified in the past 30 seconds.
So we'll have to keep
track of some timestamps.
The Sprite writer can
keep closing the file and
then deciding to reopen it
to modify it some more.
When it decides to do this, the contents
of the file are cached locally in
the writer's cache, but
the open still has to go to the server.
At this point, the writer will need to
check quickly with the server whether
its cached value is the same
as what the server sees.
And because of that, they'll need to
keep some sort of version number.
To support these operations,
the client would need to keep track
of some information for each file.
This includes some status whether or
not the file is in the cache or not,
then what are all the cached
blocks from that file.
For all of the dirty blocks,
when were they modified last?
So that we can run the write back
mechanism and then also version number.
The server will also keep track of
some information for each file,
like what are the current readers?
What is the current writer of the file?
And also what is the current
version of this file?
Now let's say,
at some point after the writer W1
has closed the file,
another writer W2 shows up.
And this is what you refer
to as a sequential writer.
They're not trying to write
the file at the same time.
When a situation like this happens,
this is what we refer to
as sequential sharing.
What needs to happen in that
case is the server needs to
contact the last writer
that it is aware of.
In this case, that's going to be W1 and
to gather all of the dirty blocks and
it's very convenient that W1
keeps track of the dirty blocks.
If W1 has closed the file,
the server will update.
The new version will
update the new writer.
The W2 is the current writer
of the file and at that point,
W2 can proceed and
it can actually cache the file.
And now while W2 is still
modifying the file,
it still has the file open and
is accessing it and it's writing to it.
We have that unfortunate situation that
rare situation where W3 appears and
it wants to concurrently at
the same time write to the file.
So this is what Sprite refers
to as concurrent sharing.
There are two writers, W3 and W2 trying
to write to the file at the same time.
When the write request comes, the server
will just like before, contact the last
writer to gather the dirty blocks and
that's going to W2 in this case.
Now, once the server contacts W2,
it will also realize that W2
hasn't actually closed the file.
What will happen in that case is that
W2 will write back all of the dirty
blocks and then the server will mark
this file as it is not cachable,
it will disable the caching
of this file for everybody.
Both W3 and W2 will continue
to have access to the file,
except they will not be able to
use their client's side caches and
all of the file accesses will
have to go to the server.
For this reason,
it makes sense on the server side to
maintain some information for each file
whether or not the file is cachable.
When one of the two writers,
W2 or W3, closed the file,
the server will now see
that close operation,
because every single operation in
this case will go to the server.
The file is not cached, otherwise.
When the server sees that one of the
clients closes the file, at that point,
it will change this cacheable flag to
point to yes, the file is cacheable.
And so the remaining clients
can start caching the file and
can enjoy the performance
optimization of caching.
So, one unique feature of Sprite
is that it dynamically enables and
disables caching depending on whether or
not there is a sequential write
sharing versus concurrent write sharing
among the clients in the system.