In your layout file, you had actually
set up the button handler functions for
the two buttons.
Go and check it out now.
Now, you had specified that these be
called request activity updates button
handler, and
remove activity updates button handler.
Go ahead and create these functions now.
They both take a view as a parameter.
In the request function,
you should do the following.
First, you should call
ActivityRecognition.ActivityRegonitionA-
PI.RequestActivityUpdates and
set its results call back to this.
It takes three parameters.
The first is the API Client, the second
is an interval in milliseconds.
And then the third is a pending intent.
You don't have that pending intent yet,
so for now,
just enter this function,
getActivityDetectionPendingIntent().
You're going to create this
function in the next step,
and this function will return
the pending intent for you.
Similarly, in
the removeActivityUpdatesHandler, call
activity recognition.activityrecognition
API.removeActivityUpdates.
And this just takes two parameters,
the API client and a pending intent.
And as you don't have
the pending intent yet,
just use the same function call
as in the request function.
When you're done implementing these,
check this box.