Okay, let's consider these questions.
So, how will you associate buttons and
methods?
Well, we're going to make
some methods first, and
then we'll associate them by using
the on click attribute of the buttons.
Okay, so the next question is
what new variables will you need?
Well, you're actually only going
to need to make one more variable.
And this is to represent Team B's score.
Team B's score needs to be a variable,
and it needs to be a global variable,
for similar reasons that Team A's
score needed to be a global variable.
And these reasons are basically,
that you want to save the score between
button clicks, and
you want to be able to update the score.
Now, you can't use the same variable for
both.
If you did that,
then the score would be the same.
Meaning that whenever
Team A scored a point,
Team B would also be scoring a point.
It's not much of a game that way.
So it's important to have a separate
variable that isn't affected by
changing the score for Team A,
which brings us to the next question.
How will these scores
actually be changed?
Well, it's going to
be similar to Team A.
The scores will change
when you click buttons.
So, you click a button.
This triggers a method that you've
associated with the button.
You'll add some amount to
the score variable for Team B, and
then you'll display it.
It's very similar to the Team A side.
Okay, let's see this in practice.
OK, so here's my Java code.
And I've scrolled up so
that I could see the three methods
that allow me to update the scores for
Team A.
So I want a pretty similar one for
Team B.
I'll start with just
making the free throw one.
Okay.
So I'm going to go ahead and
just start typing, public void.
And we'll call this, add,
and it's free throw.
So I'm adding one point.
OneForTeamB.
Add one for team B.
And I'll put view v in there,
curly braces.
Okay.
Now, hm, what should I do in here?
Now I want to basically be doing
the same thing, taking a variable,
updating it, displaying it.
But I don't have a variable yet
for team B.
I guess I'll go up and
make it right now.
So I'm going to scroll all
the way up to the top.
Now right before
the variable score team A.
I'm going to make int scoreTeamB,
and I'll also set it to 0.
I'll go ahead and add a similar
comment to the one for TeamA.
Now I"m going to scroll down.
All right, and
now I have a variable to work with.
So I'm going to say that the score for
team B, well I've clicked the add 1 for
Team B so it's going to be
equal to its current value
plus 1, because I'm adding
1 to the score for Team B.
Okay, and then I'm going to display it.
Now I need to make sure to pick
the display for Team B method and
not the display for Team A.
And I will print out Score Team B,
and not the score for team A.
Well that looks pretty good.
The only thing now,
is to make sure that clicking the button
will actually trigger this code.
So I'm going to go over to my XML.
And go down the free throw, for Team B.
So, it looks like I'm in Team B.
This is the score for Team B.
Okay, here are the buttons.
It's three points, two points.
Free throw, okay, good.
So, I actually already have
an OnClick attribute here,
because I copied and pasted.
But I don't want to be adding one for
Team A, I want to be adding one for
Team B.
Maybe I'll change these as well.
Okay, well, I'm not done, but it
should work for the Free Throw button.
So let's try this code.
Okay, so let's just make sure
that Team A still works.
It's looking good.
All right, now let's see if
the Team B free-throw button works.
Yeah, awesome.
It looks like it works.
Okay, let's try pressing plus two.
Hm.
Well, that wasn't so great.
Let's see why.
So, if I scroll up,
I can see an error here,
that says it couldn't
find the addTwoForTeamB.
Oh, right.
So, I changed these methods to say
addTwoForTeamB and addThreeForTeamB.
But if I go back to my
main activity Java,
I don't actually have
the corresponding code here.
I just have add one for team B.
Let's solve that by copying add one for
team B and pasting it.
Because one, two, three here,
so I'm going to addOneForTeamB,
addTwoForTeamB, addThreeForTeamB,
and we'll actually have to change what
it does to add to And to add three.
Okay.
Then, and
I kind of like these comments here.
So, I'm going to copy this comment,
and paste it here.
And it says Increase the score for
Team A by three.
But this method is actually increasing
the score for Team B by one.
I'm going to copy it again, paste it,
increases the score for TeamB by two.
This increases the score for
TeamB by three.
Okay, so
I think that might be everything I need.
I'm going to try running it again.
All right, moment of truth.
Team A still working fine.
All right, Team B scores two points.
Yes.
Scores three points, awesome.
Scores two points again.
Scores a free throw, free throw.
Three points.
Cool, looks like it's working.