Let's add the FirebaseJobDispatcher
to our hydration reminder app.
The end goal is to run a job
which triggers a notification
every 15 minutes when
the device is charging.
To do this,
you'll need to follow a few steps.
First, you're going to be adding
the Gradle dependency for
FirebaseJobDispatcher.
Then, you're going to create a new task
for our ReminderTasks, which creates
a charging reminder, and updates
the charging count on the screen.
After that, you're going to create a new
Service that extends from JobService.
This service will run the charging
reminder task that you just made.
As part of creating that JobService,
you're going to need to
add that to the manifest.
Then finally, you'll use
FirebaseJobDispatcher to schedule
the JobService you just made
according to the constraints.
Now, these constraints are listed and
introduced in the code.
But to just cover them again, the first
is that you gotta execute the job
every 15 minutes with
a 15 minute window.
You should only be executing
the job if the device is charging.
And you want to be continuously
executing this job every 15 minutes,
even if the device reboots.
Okay, that's a lot, so let's dive in.
So first, I'm going to go ahead and
open the Build.gradle file for the app.
And then down here, I'm going to add
the depency for Firebase Job Dispatcher.
Once that's done,
I'll go ahead and sync the code.
The next step is to create
a new task in reminder tasks.
I'll start by making a new
constant up here for my new tasks.
And it's going to be called
action charging reminder.
Next, I'm going to check for
that action here in execute task.
So if it's an ACTION_CHARGING_REMINDER
and execute action,
I'm going to check now if it was called
with the ACTION_CHARGING_REMINDER.
So if
ACTION_CHARGING_REMINDER.equals(action),
I'm going to call issueChargingReminder,
which is a method that I need to write.
So I'm going to create
that method down here.
And the point of this
issueChargingReminder method
is that it's going to
make a notification.
And then it's also going to increment
the charging reminder count.
Now, in PreferenceUtilities,
there is a method called
incrementChargingReminderCount.
And I just need to pass into context,
which I have up here in the parameter.
And then we just created
in NotificationUtils,
the remindUserBecauseCharging method,
which also needs a context.
And by calling these two methods, I will
update the ChargingReminderCount, and
I will send out that notification.
So now, I should have a working task.
Next, I'm going to create a new job
service that actually runs the task.
Here I am in
WaterReminderFirebasedjobService.
Wow, that's a mouthful.
So here I am in
WaterReminderFirebasedjobService.
Wow, that's a mouthful.
Anyways, this class is going to
extend from JobService.
And it's very important that it
extends from this JobService class,
because that's the type that
Firebase JobDispatcher expects.
Now, I should note that, like a service,
JobService runs on the main thread.
And it's upset at me right now because
there are two methods that you need
to override, and
those are onStartJob and onStopJob.
onStartJob is going to execute that task
that sends out the notification which we
just made.
Now again, by default, this is going to
be doing it on the main thread.
And in this case, making a notification
is a pretty fast action.
But in many of the use
cases of JobService,
you're going to need to schedule
a repeating job that's going to do
something large, like downloading
bulk data from the Internet.
Because of this, in this example,
I'm going to show you how to move
the operation off of the main thread.
So the first thing I'm actually going to
do, is make a variable up here,
which is an AsyncTask.
And it's going to be
called mBackgroundTask.
And then down here in my onStartJob
method, I'm going to set that background
task to a new AsyncTask,
which is anonymously subclassed.
Now, this is the code that's going to
happen off of the main thread.
So in here, I'm going to get
a reference to the context.
And this is going to be a reference
to the context of the outer
WaterReminderFirebaseJobService.
And then I'm going to take that
reminder task that I just made.
And I'm going to call executeTask
with this context and
with the CHARGING_REMINDER action.
JobServices need to tell the system
when the job is actually done
by calling job finished.
The job is done when
the AsyncTask is done.
And the AsyncTask signals that it's
done by calling onPostExecute.
Because of that, I'm going to
override the onPostExecute method.
And here in onPostExecute,
I'm going to call jobFinished.
And I'm going to pass in
the jobParameters and false.
The jobParameters are a bundle
of key value arguments that
are passed in when the job starts.
And this job here represents whether or
not the job needs to be rescheduled.
The job was successful so
there's no need to reschedule it,
which is why we are passing false here.
Okay, so now, I have a background
task that's going to do this.
And after I define that background task,
I actually need to execute it.
And then finally,
I'll just return true, which signals
that our job is still doing some work.
Because remember, it's doing it
on this other thread here now.
Okay, so now,
we have a completed onStartJob method,
which will execute our task.
And we have to just scroll down and
define this onStopJob method.
So what is onStopJob, and
when does it get called.
Well, it gets called if the requirements
of your job are no longer met.
So, for example,
let's say that you, maybe,
specified a job that wants
to upload large video files.
And because you want to be
kind to your users data plan,
you say that you're only
going to do this over Wi-Fi.
In this case, onStopJob would
be called if, for example,
you started this job when
the user was on Wi-Fi.
And then in the middle of
downloading this huge file,
the Wi-Fi connection gets shut off.
So in our case,
what we're going to do here,
is we're going to see if
our AsyncTask is null.
And if it is not null, we're going to go
ahead and cancel that backgroundTask.
And then here, we're going to
return not false but true.
And what this means, is that as
soon as the conditions are re-met,
the job should be re-tried again.
Okay, and with that,
you have created your first JobService.
But there's one more step,
we have to add it to the manifest.
So right here after our other service,
I'll make a new service.
And I'm going to set
exported to [INAUDIBLE].
And I'm going to set exported to false.
And I'm going to add
a intent filter tag in here,
with an action tag which is equal to
com.firebase.jobdispatcher.ACTION_EXEC-
UTE.
You'll learn a lot more about
intent filters shortly.
So don't worry if this XML here
looks a little bit strange.
Whew, okay.
You're about half done with
adding your scheduled job.
Time for a quick water break.
[SOUND]