The common answer here is 5,
although I realize many, many different answers are possible,
and there is clearly no single answer that is really correct.
But 5 is my favorite.
It's the 3 kinematic state variables, and in addition we care about velocities,
so there is formal velocity of the vehicle itself
and the faster the vehicle moves, the further it is going to advance in a max timestep.
There is also something called a yaw rate.
Yaw is one way to name the heading of the car,
the orientation of the car, or the bearing as some people call it.
The rate is the change over time.
This car will not just move forward. It will also turn.
That turn has a velocity, and the velocity is often called "yaw rate."
We're going to talk about this in a few minutes.