From the previous example where the threads were inserting elements in the list,
how does this list actually get updated?
An implementation make look as follows.
Each list element has two fields, a value field and
then a pointer that points to the next element in the list.
We call this one p_next.
The first element, we call it the list head.
It can be accessed by reading the value of the shared variable list.
So in this code sample this is where this is happening,
read list, as well as it's list pointer element.
Then, each thread that needs to insert a new element in the list,
will first create an element and set it's value.
And we'll then have to read the value of the head of the list, so
this element list.
And then it will have to set its pointer field to point to whatever is
still in the list.
And it will have to set the head of the list to point to
the newly created element.
What that means is for instance when we are creating this element value X,
we will first create this data structure.
And then we will first read the pointer of the list,
originally this pointed to value Y.
Set the new elements pointer to point to value Y.
And then set the head pointer to actual point to the newly created element.
And in this way, new elements are basically inserted at the head of the list.
The end of pointing to the rest of the list and
the head of the list points to the newly created element.
Clearly there is a problem if two threads that are running on
two different CPUs at the same time try to
update the pointer field of the first element in the list.
We don't know what will be the outcome of this operation if two
threads are executing it at the same time and
trying to set different values in the p_next field.
There is also a problem if two threads are running on the CPU at
the same time because their operations are randomly interleaved.
For instance, they may both read the initial value of the list.
So this is where they're both reading the value of the list.
And it's pointer to the next element of the list.
In this case null.
They were both set the pointers p_next in their elements to be null.
And then they will take turns setting the actual list pointer to point to them.
Only one element will ultimately be successfully linked to the list.
And the other one will simply be lost.