Hey again.
Now that you're well familiar
with kinds and properties,
let's talk about what goes into
a data store kind for user profiles.
Let's do in the same way we did recipes.
What do we need to store for
users of our conference app?
Unlike a recipe,
where we have one type of user,
our cook who is storing recipes.
This time we have two different
kinds of users, those who create and
manage conferences and
those who are looking for conferences,
registering for them and going to them.
But we need to save information for both
of those types of users in one kind and
we're going to name that kind Profile.
So the first thing we need is a unique
identifier for the entities key.
Now we need to decide what data
we need in a user profile.
First, we'll have displayName.
That's the name that users want to have
printed on their conference badges,
that might be different from
the name on their account after all.
Maybe Jennifer Smith wants to be
called Jen, or Jenny or maybe Unicorn.
Next, we need the user's email address.
We're going to call this mainEmail for
now.
At some point, you might want to extend
this with home and work emails and
need to decide, which is primary or
support another email address for
their mobile device to
send them text messages.
But for now, we'll just have mainEmail.
And the next very important
thing is your teeShirtSize.
People certainly do appreciate having
the right sized t-shirt when they go to
a conference.
Now, it's time for
you to think about these.
What sorts of properties
are each of these fields?
Use your imagination and if you need to
look up the various property types you
can use, check out the docks
linked to the Instructor's Notes.
For each field,
fill in an appropriate property type.
Be careful when filling in the answers,
because like other Python identifiers,
these are case sensitive.