Well we still have the same two components.
We haven't added anything there, but for each of the components we've
added another port for dealing with these error messages.
In particular for the client, it's now got a port which is called here err-trap,
and symmetrically the server has another port, this one for sending the alert.
We're going to add a new connector for dealing with this communication channel.
It's called error, okay, and it's got two roles.
One being the source of the error and
the other being the sync or receiver of that error.
We still have the same two attachments we had for, for dealing with the main
flow of communication, but now we've added two more for dealing with error flow.
In particular, a clients error trap is connected to the connector sync and
the receiver's alert port is connected to the connector's source role.