In shared memory IPC, processes read and
write into a shared memory region.
The operating system is involved in
establishing the shared memory channel
between the processes.
What this means is that the operating
system will map certain physical pages
of memory into the virtual
address spaces of both processes,
the virtual addresses in P1 and
the virtual addresses in P2 will
map to the same physical addresses.
At the same time,
the virtual address regions that
correspond to that shared memory buffer.
in the two processes, they don't need
to have the same virtual addresses.
Also the physical memory that's
backing the shared memory buffer
does not have to be a contiguous
portion of physical memory.
All of this leverages the memory
management support that's available in
operating systems in
our modern hardware.
The big benefit of this approach is that
once the physical memory is mapped into
both address spaces,
the operating system is out of the way.
The system calls are used
only in the setup phase.
Now, data copies
are potentially reduced, but
not necessarily completely avoided.
Note that for data to be visible to both
processes, it actually must explicitly
be allocated from the virtual addresses
that belong to the shared memory region.
So if that's not the case,
then data within the same address
space has to be copied in and
out of the shared memory region.
In some cases however, the number
of required copies can be reduced.
For instance, if P2 needs to
compute the sum of two arguments,
that were passed to it from P1 via
the shared memory region, then P2
can only read these arguments, it
doesn't actually need to copy them into
other portions of its address space,
compute the sum, and then pass it back.
However, there are some drawbacks.
Since the shared memory area can be
concurrently accessed by both processes,
this means that the processes
must explicitly synchronize
their shared memory operations.
Just as what you would have with threads
operating within a single address space.
Also, it is the developer's
responsibility to determine
any communication protocol
related issues such as,
how are messages going to be formatted?
How will they be delimited?
What are their headers
going to look like?
And also, how this shared memory
buffer will be allocated?
When which process, we'll be able to use
a portion of this buffer for its needs.
So this adds some complexity, obviously.
Unix based systems, including Linux,
support two popular shared memory APIs.
One of these was originally
developed as part of System V and
the other one is the official
POSIX shared memory API.
In addition, shared memory based
communication can be established between
processes using a file based interface.
So the memory wrapped files
in both address spaces.
This API's essentially analogous
to the POSIX shared memory API.
Also the Android operating system
uses a form of shared memory IPC
that's called Ashmem.
There are a number of differences in the
details of how Ashmem behaves compared
to the system files POSIX APIs, but
I'm just providing it
here as a reference only.
For the remainder of this lesson,
we will focus on briefly describing
the Unix space shared memory APIs