Here is one of my favorite examples of unsupervised learning--
one that is yet unsolved.
At Google, I had the opportunity to participate--
in the building of Street View,
which is a huge photographic database--
of many, many streets in the world.
As you dive into Street View--
you can get ground imagery--
of almost any location in the world--
like this house here, that I chose at random.
In these images, there is vast regularities.
You can go somewhere else--
and you'll find that the type of objects--
visible in Street View--
is not entirely random.
For example, there is many images of homes--
many images of cars--
trees, pavement, lane markers--
stop sign, just to name a few.
So one of the fascinating, unsolved, unsupervised learning tasks is:
Can you take hundreds of billions of images--
as comprised in the Street View data set--
and discover from it that there are concepts such as--
trees, lane markers, stop signs, cars, and pedestrians?
It seems to be tedious to hand label each image--
for the occurrence of such objects.
And attempts to do so--
has resulted in very small image data sets.
Humans can learn from data--
even without explicit target labels.
We often just observe.
In observing, we apply unsupervised learning techniques.
So one of the great, great open questions of artificial intelligence is:
Can you observe many intersections and many streets and many roads--
and learn from it what concepts are contained in the imagery?
Of course, I can't teach you anything as complex in this class.
I don't even know the answer myself.
So let me start with something simple.
Clustering. Clustering is the most basic form of unsupervised learning.
And I will tell you about two algorithms that are very related.
One is called k-means,
one is called expectation maximization.
K-means is a nice, intuitive algorithm to derive clusterings.
Expectation maximization is a probabilistic--
generalization of k-means.
They were derived from first principles.