The Udacity and Twitter Course Real-Time Analytics with Apache Storm
is considered a T-shaped course because we touch on a number of
different topics and go in depth in Storm.
We use the virtualization technology Vagrant Cloud and Virtual Box.
And using git and Vagrant commands we launch a virtual machine,
the open-source Linux distribution Ubuntu.
We then use the Java build tool Maven to explore real-time analytics with
Apache Storm.
We also use the programming languages Python and Java.
Along with packages Beautiful Soup and
lettuce, and I'm not making that up, to connect to the Python microserver Flask.
And the in-memory key-value store Redis to
finally drive real-time visualizations using D3 written in JavaScript.
In Storm, we'll explore concepts like a spout, a bolt, and
a connection called a topology.
We explore these components written in both Java and Python.
And finally connect to the Twitter sample stream using the open API Twitter4J.
We then explore more complex topologies using streaming joins.
And finally, you'll work on your own final project ideas as you
watch our students work through a hackathon here at Udacity.
Also, since we can't cover everything, some of the topics we don't cover
include the programming language Clojure which most of Storm is written in,
an actual cluster administration to submit your Storm topology to.
. And finally, ack which allows at least once processing.
Finally, after you're done with this course or
even as you're working through this course, you'll be happy to know that
Udacity has courses that cover Ubuntu, git, Python, Java, D3, and JavaScript.
Let's get started in Real-Time Analytics with Apache Storm.