Here, you can see my on click function.
I'm only going to process button clicks
while the Google API client isn't in
the midst of connecting.
So this is just going to
be a big switch statement.
Because the on click
will take in a view v.
And v's ID will be the ID of
the button that was pressed.
So, in this case, when the v.getId
gives me R.id.sign in button,
the sign in button has been pressed.
We just said we want to set
the status to signing in,
and then call this result
sign-in error function.
We'll write that function shortly,
and then just break out
of the switch statement.
And then when we're signing out, we can
clear the default accounts, just so
that the Google services don't
return an unconnected callback,
without any interaction.
And the result, so once you've
signed out, it's good to clear
any of the default information out, so
that you don't have any security issues.
So just going to call
Plus.AccountApi.clearDefaultAccount and
pass it the API client.
We then disconnect the API client and
reconnect it.
And then break out of
the switch statement.
Finally, for
revoking access on the plus account API,
we call the default account for
the same reason.
And then also in the Plus.AccountApi,
we call revokeAccessAndDisconnect and
pass it the GoogleApiClient.
Once we've done that, we'll start the
process of building a new client ,and
getting it ready to connect.
So again, we just say mGoogleApiClient,
and we call the same helper
function that we had earlier.
And then we reconnect that.
So that's all we have to
do in our three run-ins.
So signing in is setting the text and
resolving the errors.
Signing out is clearing the default
account, disconnecting and reconnecting.
And revoking access to
clearing the default account.
Revoking access and disconnecting.
And building a new API client and
connecting that.