Let's go back into Unity.
Okay, go to File &gt; New Scene.
Great.
Now look in the course notes below for
a link to the Udacity modern
apartment Unity package file.
And download it.
After you've downloaded it, locate
the Unity package file on your computer.
And double click it to open it.
Go ahead and
import all the files into your package.
Cool, now we have lots of
new stuff to play with.
In the Project pane go to
Udacity Modern Apartment &gt;
Scenes &gt; Udacity Modern Apartment.
Double click the scene to load it.
It may take a moment, but soon you'll
see a nicely lit modern apartment scene.
Cool..
Now let's find a model called
Udacity Icon.
In the Project pane go to
Udacity Modern Apartment
&gt; Art &gt; Models &gt; Udacity Icon.
And then you should see
a model called Udacity Icon.
Go ahead and
drag that into the hierarchy.
Now take a look at the apartment.
See the Udacity logo hiding
underneath the table?
Let's move it somewhere
nicer inside the apartment.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
That looks much better.
That's all there is to it.
Now you've seen just how easy it is
to bring objects into your 3D scene
using Unity.