With this background on SMPs,
cash coherence, and atomics,
we're now finally ready
to discuss the design and
performance trends of
spinlock implementations.
The only one thing that's left to decide
are what are the performance metrics
that are useful when reasoning about
different implementations of spinlocks.
To determine this, we should ask
ourselves, what are our objectives?
First we want the spinlock
to have low latency.
By latency, we are referring to how
long does it take for a thread to.
Acquire a lock when it's free, ideally
we want the thread to be able to acquire
a free lock immediately with
a single instruction, and
we already established that spinlocks
require atomic instructions.
So the ideal case will be that,
we just want to be able to execute a
single atomic instructions and be done.
Next we want the spinlock to have low
delay, or to have low waiting time.
What that means is that whenever it
is spinning and a lock becomes free,
is we want to reduce that time that it
takes from the thread to stop spinning
and to acquire that lock
that has just been freed.
Again ideally,
we would like for the thread to the able
to do that, as soon as possible,
as soon as this lock is freed, for
a thread to be able to acquire it.
So to execute an atomic.
And finally, we need a design that
will non generate contention.
On the shared bus or
the shared network interconnect.
By contention,
we mean both the contention that's
due to the actual atomic memory
references as well as contention that's
generated due to the coherence traffic.
Contention is bad because it will delay
any other CPU in the system that's
trying to access the memory, but
more importantly it will also delay
the owner of the spinlock and.
That is the thread, that is the process
that's trying to quickly complete
a critical section and
then release the spinlock.
So if we have a contention situation,
we may potentially even be delaying
the unlock operation for this spinlock.
That will clearly impact
performance even more.
So these are the three objectives
that we want to achieve in
a good spinlock design.
And the different alternatives that we
will discuss in this lesson will be
evaluated based on these criteria.