The main workhorse of an intent
service is its onHandleIntent method.
Most of the work you will do in
the service is writing the code in this
method.
Now there's a lot to do, so we're going
to break it down into a number of steps.
The first of these steps is
to get the geofencing data
from the intent that was
passed into the service.
This can be achieved using
the geofencing API, so
check the documentation for that.
The data that you want will be in
an object called geofencing event.
Once you've done that,
it's good practice to ensure that
the data is good and without any errors.
Think about the code for this and
write that into your onHandleIntent, and
then check this box when you're done.