First, an IP address.
Can this be an anomaly?
If the IP address is not the one
that normally accessed by users or
is not well known, it can be anomaly.
So this is anomaly.
Second, a port address.
Similar to the IP address, if the port
address is not normally accessed,
then this is an anomaly.
How about packet length?
Again, if the length is unusually long,
for example, then this is an anomaly.
How about flag setting on a packet?
Again, if these flags are not normally
seen under the same traffic conditions,
then this is an anomaly.
That is, all of these can be anomalies
if they are not normally seen in
normal operations of the network.