For this exercise,
I made a new Line class that I'll
be using in my Python examples.
Here are the basic functions for
the class that I've written.
You can find the stub with
the initial Python code in
the downloadable section on this page.
The Line class will make use of the
Vector class from the previous lesson.
Like in the previous lesson, I'll ask
you to write some functions, this time
for the Line class, to implement some
of the concepts we've discussed.
The initializer takes two
pieces of information.
A normal vector to the line and the
constant term for the lines equation.
The normal vector gives
me the coefficients for
the standard form of the line.
Note that I don't take a directional
vector as an argument.
This is because in two dimensions,
we can quickly find a directional vector
for the line from the normal
vector if we need to.
More importantly, as we'll see later on,
the normal vector representation
is more easily generalizable
to higher dimensions.
Similarly, we can compute a base point
quickly by choosing a variable with
a non-zero coefficient and
setting the other variable to zero.
I've implemented this in a separate
compute base point function.
The str function outputs the standard
form of the lines equation
using the variables x1 and
x2 instead of just x and y.
It's a bit messier, but it's set up so
that later, we can generalize it
to equations in higher dimensions.
Finally, there is a helper method
called first_nonzero_index.
We will use it to find the first
non-zero coefficient of an equation.
At the bottom, I have implemented
in extension to the decimal class
that allows us to test whether a number
is within some tolerance of zero.
We will use this to avoid incorrect
answers due to round off error.
There are three functions I would like
you to implement for this exercise.
First, I'd like you to create
a function that determines whether
two lines are parallel or not.
Here, I'd recommend using
functionality from the Vector class to
make your function easy to write.
Next, I'd like you to write a function
that tests whether two lines are equal,
where we define equal to mean
consists of the same set of points.
So for example, if l1 is the line
with normal vector 1, 1 and
base point 0, 1, and l2 is the line with
normal vector negative 3, negative 3 and
the base point minus 3, 4,
even though these lines
have different normal vectors and base
points, they still define the same line.
Since their corresponding
equations x + y = 1, and
negative 3x- 3y = negative 3
are satisfied by the same points.
Feel free to use your parallel
checking function in this function.
And you may want to refer back to the
previous video to see how to determine
if two parallel lines are equal.
Finally, write a function that
determines the intersection of two
lines.
Ideally, if the lines are not equal but
parallel, the function should return
some indication that the lines
have no intersection.
And, if the lines are equal, the
function should return some indication
that the intersection is
the entirety of both lines.
Otherwise, just return the single point
of intersection of the two lines.
Again, it will help to
leverage the functionality
of these two functions in writing
the intersection function.
Once you're done writing your functions,
here are the questions I'd like
you to answer to check your work.
For each pair of lines, fill in the
coordinates of the intersection point to
three decimal places of accuracy, or
else check the appropriate box
under no intersection or same line.
The first system I'd
like you to solve is
4.046x + 2.836y = 1.21, and
10.115x + 7.09y = 3.025.
The second system I'd
like you to solve is
7.204x + 3.182y = 8.68, and
8.172x + 4.114y = 9.883.
The third system I'd
like you to solve is
1.182x + 5.562y = 6.744,
and 1.773x + 8.343y = 9.525.