The documentation for Android, it's on
a site called developer.android.com.
It contains a lot of helpful
information, such as code samples,
tutorials and articles.
You can think of it as an instruction
manual for how to build apps.
I use this site daily, and often times
I get to it using a Google search.
I'll show you what I mean.
Let's look at the documentation for
text view.
So I search for textview android.
The top link that comes up is
a developer.android.com site, so
I click on that.
This is what we call the reference
documentation for TextView.
I know there's a lot of information on
this page and it can be overwhelming.
But usually when you're looking
at reference documentation,
you're trying to solve
a specific problem.
So you can actually filter out
all the unnecessary information
that you don't need.
When I come to this page I check
that it is indeed for TextView.
I may read the class overview,
and then I can scroll down.
This is the interesting part.
It lists out the XML attributes.
These are all the possible
XML attributes for TextView.
It also includes a nice description on
the right-hand side for what it does.
Now you don't need to memorize
all of these attributes.
In fact, I haven't used some of them.
I usually work with a small subset
of them on a regular basis.
But I know that if I ever need
something special, I can always come to
the TextView documentation to
find that specific attribute.
Here's one that we recognize.
Android:textSize.
So we click on it, and it links to
the description of this attribute.
It says that this controls
the size of the text.
And the recommended dimension type for
text is sp for
scaled pixels, for example, 15sp.
Cool, so we learned this earlier.
And if you ever forget you can always
come back to the TextView documentation
and look up what the attribute is.
Now say for example I don't
know what the exact name is.
In your web browser you can use
the find feature to search the page.
The other way to open up this Find
window is to use Cmd+F on Mac, or
Ctrl+F on Windows.
Then I can type in what I'm looking for.
Say, for example, I'm looking for
a way to capitalize all
the letters in a TextView.
This might be useful for example,
if I'm trying to show tabs like this, or
if I'm creating a snack bar
at the bottom of the screen,
like this UNDO text here is in all caps.
Buttons are also in all caps.
Going back to the TextView
documentation, I can search for caps.
I can browse through all the search
results, but these look pretty good.
It says that there's an XML attribute
called android:textAllCaps, and
this description says to
present the text in all caps.
If I click on it and
read the description,
it sounds like what I'm looking for,
and it says the possible values for
this attribute are either true or false.
So I can try this out in code now.
So going back to the XML Visualizer,
say I have this TextView on screen and
I want to change it to be all caps.
According to the documentation,
I can add an attribute here that says
android:textAllCaps, and
then I can set it to be true or false.
If I set it to true then look,
it's all in caps, cool.
The nice thing about this attribute
is that I don't have to go and
change the text.
Like, oh the possibilities,
and capitalize everything.
Instead I can leave the text as is,
and all I need to
do is just toggle this attribute
to change it from true to false.
Now, it's your turn to practice.
Being able to look at documentation and
then update your code accordingly to try
it out,
is a really useful skill to have.
That means you don't have to memorize
everything you could possibly ever want
to do in Android.
It's only a Google search away and
you can find it when you need it.
So first,
I want you to Google search for
textview android to find the reference
documentation for TextView.
Then I want you to use the Find feature
in your web browser to search the page
for the XML attribute that makes
the TextView text bold or italic.
We haven't covered this XML attribute
before, so this is an opportunity for
you to learn it on you own.
Once you find something that might work,
go ahead and try to use it.
If that doesn't work
then no problem at all.
Just keep going back to
the documentation until you find the one
that works.