Now I want to talk about approximate inference
by means of sampling.
What do I mean by that?
Say we want to deal with a joint probability distribution,
say the distribution of heads and tails over these 2 coins.
We can build a table and then start counting by sampling.
Here we have our first sample.
We flip the coins and the one-cent piece came up heads,
and the five-cent piece came up tails,
so we would mark down one count.
Then we'd toss them again.
This time the five cents is heads, and the one cent is tails,
so we put down a count there, and we'd repeat that process
and keep repeating it until we got enough counts that we could estimate
the joint probability distribution by looking at the counts.
Now, if we do a small number of samples, the counts might not be very accurate.
There may be some random variation that causes them not to converge
to their true values, but as we add more counts,
the counts--as we add more samples,
the counts we get will come closer to the true distribution.
Thus, sampling has an advantage over inference in that we know a procedure
for coming up with at least an approximate value for the joint probability distribution,
as opposed to exact inference, where the computation may be very complex.
There's another advantage to sampling, which is if we don't know
what the conditional probability tables are, as we did in our other models,
if we don't know these numeric values, but we can simulate the process,
we can still proceed with sampling, whereas we couldn't with exact inference.