Now so far we've dealt only with games that take a single turn--
that is there are two players, they both simultaneously reveal their move,
and the game is over.
But game theory can also deal with more complex games
that have multiple rounds of turn taking.
Here I'm describing a simple game of poker,
the simplest type of poker you've probably ever seen.
The deck only has four cards.
One card is dealt to each player.
There are two rounds.
In the first, player one has a choice to either raise--to bet a dollar--or to check.
Then in the second round, the second player has the chance to call--
to say I want to see what's up--or to fold.
Now this format begins to look very much like the game tree
that we talked about in the previous unit.
It starts out and there's a chance node.
This corresponds to dealing the cards with the 1/6 that the first player gets an Ace
and the second player gets an Ace.
One-third that the first player gets and Ace and the second Player gets a Kind, and so on.
There there are maximizing nodes and minimizing nodes.
What this format, which is known as the sequential game format,
is especially good at is keeping track of the belief states of the possibilities
of what each agent knows and doesn't know.
The tree as a whole describes everything that's going on,
but each agent doesn't know at which point in the tree they are.
So if you're agent number one, you know that you have an Ace,
so you know you're in one of these two states denoted by the dotted lines.
You're either in the state where you have an Ace and the other player has an Ace,
or in the state where you have an Ace and the other player has a King,
But you don't know which one you're at.
Similarly, over here there is confusion for the second player as to what state they're in.
Now, we can solve this game using this game tree approach,
and it's not quite the same as the max and the min approach,
because where you are in the states, what you know about the partial information,
affects your strategy in a way that we haven't dealt with before.
One possibility for how you can evaluate again like this
is just to convert it to the other form.
The form we've seen before is called the normal form or matrix form.
This is the sequential game in extensive form.
If we convert the extensive form, we get something like this.
Here for each player, we've denoted by a two-letter strategy
what you should do when you have an Ace and what you should do when you have a King.
So we end up with an exponentially large search space,
but here the game was so simple, that it ends up being rather small,
and the game is rather trivial, and you can solve it.
It turns out that there are two equilibrium corresponding to the strategy for player two,
which is he should check when he has an Ace, and he should fold when he has a King,
and strategy for player one is it doesn't matter if he raises or checks when has an Ace,
but he should check when he has a King.
That would give the game a value of zero.
Now this works fine for the simple version of poker.
For real poker, this table would have about 10^18 states,
and it would be impossible to deal with.
So we need some strategies for getting back down to a reasonable number of states.