Our store is currently displaying all
the information on the home page, but
marketing needs a way to send
customers to a specific URL for
red bricks, one for blue bricks,
and one for green bricks.
The cart should also have
its own dedicated page.
To complete this quiz,
you need to add the UI router module
to the app, then configure the app so
that loading each of these URLs
displays the correct template.
We currently only have a home link, so
you'll also need to add a link to each
of the brick colors and the cart.
As a last step, create a nested route
for each brick color that will display
the cart if the user clicks
on the view cart link.
A link to this project is
in the instructor notes.
When you've completed these steps, the
feedback extension will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.