So linear regression works well
if the data is approximately linear,
but there are many examples when linear regression performs poorly.
Here's one where we have a
curve that is really nonlinear.
This is an interesting one where we seem to have a linear relationship
that is flatter than the linear regression indicates,
but there is one outlier.
Because if you are minimizing quadratic error,
outliers penalize you over-proportionately.
So outliers are particularly bad for linear regression.
And here is a case,
where the data clearly suggests
a very different phenomena for linear.
We have only two ?? variables even being used,
and this one has a strong frequency
and a strong vertical spread.
Clearly a linear regression model
is a very poor one to explain
this data over here.
Another problem with linear regression
is that as you go to infinity in the X space,
your Ys also become infinite.
In some problems that isn't a plausible model.
For example, if you wish to predict the weather
anytime into the future,
it's implausible to assume the further the prediction goes out,
the hotter or the cooler it becomes.
For such situations there is a
model called logistic regression,
which uses a slightly more complicated
model than linear regression,
which goes as follows:.
Let F of XP, or linear function,
and the output of logistic regression
is obtained by the following function:
One over one plus exponential of minus F of X.
So here's a quick quiz for you.
What is the range in which Z might fall
given this function over here,
and ??? the linear function of F or X over here.
Is it zero, one?
Is it minus one, one?
Is it minus one, zero?
Minus two, two?
Or none of the above?