All right, last question.
Remember we said features are not 2D,
no problem, just hydro planes.
If the labels are not
linearly separable,
we do this really cool thing
with the kernel trick and
that puts us in a higher dimensional
space, and we separate them up there.
Well, what if we have just, we,
we don't have just two categories,
what if we have more than two?
Well, you have a couple of choices, none
of which are particularly satisfying.
Basically, SVMs allow you to
create binary classifiers.
This versus that.
The simplest thing you can do,
well, not the simplest,
one thing you can do is you can train,
it's called one versus all.
You can train the As versus not As.
Right?
And the Bs versus not Bs, and
the Cs, you, you get the point, right?
And then at testing time,
you apply all of these machines, and
you assign it to the SVM that
is it's actually interesting,
we haven't talked about this, maybe
two of the machines say that you're
on the positive side of the line,
but remember that
W dot X plus B, or the kernel,
plus b, that actually
gives you something like a distance
away from the decision boundary.
So, you could actually pick the one
that had that highest value.
The one that seems to be farthest
away from its decision function.
So that's one versus all.
The other thing that you can do is you
can do what's called one versus one.
You learn an SVM for
each pair of classes.
So A versus B, A versus C, A versus D,
B versus C, B versus D, C versus D,
if you had A, B, C, D.
And then what you do is you apply all
of those to some point that comes in,
and, essentially each SVM is trying to
vote for which class it belongs to.
Now, if I apply a D to the A versus B,
I'm going to get some random value,
right?
But if I apply the, a D to the A versus
D, and the B versus D, and
the C versus D, I hope that three
of those would vote for it being D.
So you basically count the votes.
It's not very satisfying either way,
most people I know actually do the one
versus all, so they do n of them.