I want you to write
the numLetters function.
It needs to take a letter and
return a newly created function,
then call that function with a number.
This number will be how many times
the letter should be returned.
For example if I call numLetters with
the letter a, I'll get a function back.
Now if I call LotsOfAaas with the number
4.3, four as will be returned.
For a tip in writing your constructor
function, it might be helpful to
know that you can break up a string
into several lines with a backslash.
For example, these two variables
hold the exact same string.
Alternatively, you can concatenate
your strings together.
All three of these form the same string,
without any line breaks.