My intuition is that this
problem is related to
the PrintSettingsViewController.
So before we run the app, let's go to
the PrintSettingsViewController here.
And add a print statement to
the bugTypeSelected method.
This is the method that get's called
when any of the bug type buttons
are pressed.
And I'll rebuild and run.
Print debugging > Settings and
select a bug type.
And we're still crashing, but from the
debug output, we can see that we're at
least calling the method because our
first print statement is reached and
then something goes wrong.
In the crash report, it's saying
that we have a fatal error and
then it unexpectedly found nil,
while unwrapping an optional value.
If we look at the line
causing the error, line 31,
we see that there
are three unwrapped values.
One here, here and here.
So let's try printing out each of
these before the lines reached.
And rebuild and run,
going to stop first.
Build, there we go.
Select the Print Debugging
again > Settings > Select, and
there's our problem.
The current title of the button is
Button, and when we try to convert this
to an integer in the second print
statement on the two int call, It fails.
The behavior that we want is for
each button title to be an integer which
corresponds to a particular bug type,
so let's go to the storyboard here.
And we're looking at
the PrintSettingsViewController.
Let me zoom out a little bit so
that we can see what we are doing.
There we go.
So hide this and here are our buttons.
So these first four are the ones
that we're worried about.
Let's change these.
We'll go zero for the first because
it's a zero index bug type.
One, two, and three.
And we'll rebuild and run, and
let's select a new bug type.
And it looks like it worked.
But let's do a quick sanity
check to really make sure.
A sanity check when debugging is a basic
test that'll quickly evaluate whether or
not the program's working as expected.
So since we set the bug
type to the blue bug here,
we should be able to create blue bugs.
There we go, our first blue spider.
Try a different type.
Green.
Red.
Here's red.
And we're good to go.