There is more that goes into dealing with deadlocks.
Detecting them, avoiding them, and recovering from them.
But for the sake of this class, remember that maintaining order of
the deadlocks will give you a deadlock-proof solution.
So in summary, a cycle in the wait graph is necessary and
sufficient for a deadlock to occur.
And this graph itself is one where the edges are from
the thread that's waiting on a resource to the thread that owns a resource.
So what can we do about this?
First we can try to prevent deadlocks.
Every single time a thread is about to issue a request for
a lock, we first have to see if that operation will cause a cycle in this graph.
If that is the case, then we must somehow delay that operation.
And in fact, we may even need to change our code so
that the thread first releases some resource and
only afterwards it attempts to perform that lock request.
Clearly this can be very expensive.
The alternative of completely preventing deadlocks is to detect deadlocks, and
if you detect that they have occurred, to have mechanisms to recover from them.
We do these kinds of things based on, basically, analysis of the graph to
determine whether at any given point of time, any cycles have occurred.
This maybe isn't as bad as monitoring and analyzing every single lock
request to see whether it will cause future deadlocks.
But it's still expensive in that it requires us to have ability to
roll back the execution so that we can recover.
And the only way that that can be possible is if we have maintained enough
state during the execution so that we can figure out how to recover.
And in some cases,
these rollback mechanisms are essentially impossible to perform.
If we have inputs and outputs that came from external sources,
we don't have ways to roll back their execution.
And finally we have the option to apply the Ostrich Algorithm.
And as sophisticated as that sounds, the Ostrich Algorithm is that, will
basically just hide like an ostrich with his head in the sand, and do nothing.
This is even more optimistic than this rollback based mechanism,
in which we were letting the system execute, allowing it to cause a deadlock,
and then recovering from him.
Here we're essentially just hoping the system will never deadlock, and
if we're wrong, then we'll just reboot.
The truth is that although we know that lock order will help remove
any cycles in the graph, when we have complex codes, when we have codes from
different sources, it's really hard to guarantee that all of the mutexes will be
acquired in exactly the same order across multiple source files.
And so deadlocks are a reality.
These types of techniques are possible, exist, and
they can help us deal with deadlocks, however they're rather expensive in
terms of the overheads they impose on the execution time of the system.
So typically they're applied only in really performance-critical systems.