As we discussed in
the beginning of the lesson,
we wanted to introduce you to
the method of building models.
The kernel density estimate example
covered one of the most important
concepts behind models.
That is to understand
the probability distributions
corresponding to processes and
phenomena.
We did not go through parametric or
machine learning models in this lesson,
hoping you have learned how
to build a regression or
mathematical model if you need to
by asking the right questions and
selecting your features well
to answer these questions.
The next part of this
process is to validate and
verify the results that
we get from our models.
We got a little taste of that in
this and the previous lessons.
In the next lesson,
we will build classification models.
Through that example, you will learn
about testing and validating your
models, and ways to select between
models based on performance.