Now this quiz is actually a pseudo quiz.
By that I mean it's not designed
to test what you've learned.
Rather it asks you to make
an educated guess and
in coming up with that guess hopefully
you learn something in the process.
Start by recalling
the dynamic power equation.
Notice that it has 4 nobs for
controlling power.
The first is the capacitance of
the circuit element, like a gate.
The second is the supply
voltage of the circuit.
The third is the clock rate or
the clock frequency.
Lastly, there's the activity factor.
The activity factor was
the frequency of state changes
relative to elapsed cycles.
Now put on your algorithm and
software hat.
Do you have any guesses or intuition
about which of these knobs might
be within the control of algorithms and
software?
I want you to think about it,
and if you don't know, it's okay.
In fact, it's a little bit
of a research question, and
there isn't necessarily a right or
wrong answer.
The main point of this pseudo-quiz
is to make sure that you stop and
think about the question before
I tell you what I think.