Suppose you execute the first
nine loads of this program.
Assume that you start
with an empty cache.
In the ideal cache model there
would be one cache eviction, and
here's what the state of
the cache would look like.
This is what happens with
an optimal replacement policy
which sees all future accesses
when deciding what to evict.
And you might be asking yourself,
self, how does that compare to
a more realistic replacement policy?
One candidate that you might know about
is the least recently used replacement
policy or LRU.
As its name suggests,
LRU evicts the address that was
accessed most distantly in the past.
So here's my question.
Under LRU replacement how many
evictions would you expect to see?
Again, start from an empty cache.
Now I'll put some empty boxes here so
you can use this for scratch space.
However, the grade-o-bot
won't be checking these,
it'll just be checking
the number of evictions.