Next up, you're going to need
to create a new project and
configure it to use
the Services libraries.
Now you've seen how to do
this in the intro, and
several times in this course,
but here are the steps again.
First you should create a new single
activity app in Android Studio.
When you create that app,
make sure that you use the same name
as you specified in the console.
Remember when we had
the com.audacity for
a sign in name,
you want to do the same thing.
Then you're going to want to configure
Build.gradle to use the Services
libraries, and
configure Android.manifest to
uses the Services libraries too.
And then finally, you need to
configure Android.manifest for
the following permissions,
android.permission.INTERNET,
android.permission.GET_ACCOUNTS and
android.permission.USE_CREDENTIALS.
Do all of this before continuing.