Now that we've set up our array,
let's jump back into our script to
pick a random song for it to play.
Since we want this to happen as soon as
we hit play, let's put this in the start
method, so that it's the first thing
that happens when our experience starts.
To pick a random object, we first need
to pick a random number between zero and
the total number of objects in our list.
The reason we use zero is because,
with lists and
arrays, we used zero-based numbering.
So the first element is referenced with
a zero, the second referenced by one,
and so on.
Picking a truly random number is
actually a pretty hard thing to do.
But luckily for
us, there is a method we can use called
random.range that does just that.
We'll be using the int version of range,
and as we see here,
it accepts two parameters, min and max.
Note here, that max is exclusive.
So that means,
it's not included in our range.
So, for example,
if we use Random.Range 0 10,
where 0 is our min value and
10 is our max value,
we'll only get numbers between 0 and
9 as possibilities.
The reason that this is done is
specifically for arrays, and
the fact that they are zero-based.
For us, that means if our
array has four objects, and
we want a random object, we want to get
a random value that's either 0, 1, 2 or
3, to have a unique
reference to each object.
As a result, to get a random number to
reference in our array, we need to pick
a number between zero and
the length of our array, which is four.
So, back in our script,
let's type index = random.range,
zero to soundfiles.length.
Arrays are extremely nice, in that
they always maintain their length
in a variable that happens
to be called length.
The next thing we need to do,
now that we have a random index,
is actually get the random
object out of our array.
To do that,
we need to access our array, using
a handy little tool called brackets.
We can simply access the array
with soundfiles.bracket index.
Next, we just have to assign our
sound clip to our audio component.
Since we already have our
reference to our audio source,
we can type soundsource.clip
equals soundfiles at index.
And the last thing we
need to do is actually
play our clip with soundsource.play.
And since our script is already
hooked up, we can hit play, and
each time we'll get a random song.