The next topic I want to address is called "Segmentation."
This is the problem of given a sequence of language,
figure out how to break it up into words.
Now, in Chinese we don't have spaces between the words,
and so in order to understand if the first word of this message corresponds
to a single character or two characters or what,
we have to be able to do the process of segmentation and figure out where they are.
In English, we don't have that. Words have spaces between them.
So we don't have the segmentation problem,
but we certainly have it in speech recognition in languages like English,
because this speech sounds are sometimes run together without pauses in between them,
and there are places where we do have a language without segmentation.
For example, in the language of URLs
you could have a URL like "choosespain.com",
which is the travel site that tries to encourage you to choose Spain as your travel destination,
but if you segment it wrong, you'd come up with "chooses pain,"
which would not be the intended expression for that particular URL.
So segmentation is an important problem. Let's talk about how to do it.