Looks like we're getting pretty close.
The only thing that's missing here is
the plane image on top of the line.
I've created this plane image from
a template that I found online.
You can download it from
the instructor notes below.
Vector images like this SVG file are the
best to you in your Android application.
Because they can resize easily
to work with any phone size and
resolution without affecting
the quality of your image.
To add this vector image to your
application download that SVG file and
then head back to the Android project,
right click on the Res folder,
and then select New vector asset.
Then select the local file and browse
for the file that you just downloaded.
And let's give it a name art_plane.
Now for the size check the override so
that uses it correct dimensions and
also enable auto mirroring for
right to left layouts.
This is because we want the plan to
indicate the direction of travel
give the origin and
destination of the airports.
So in right to left layouts where
the origins are on the right and
the destination is on the left we
want that plane to indicate that.
Perfect, now let's click next and
then finish.
And it will appear under the Drawable
folder as art_plane.xml.
If you open this xml file,
you can see that everything that
describes the image is in plain text.
You can update the fill color,
the size of the image, or
even the image data itself.
But for now, let's just change this fill
color to be the primary color light and
we'll leave everything else as it is.
Now if we head back
to our main activity,
we can just drag another image view, and
place it on top of the line here, and
then select our art_plane, and make
sure that we create a left constraint,
to the left rectangle, the right
constraint to the right rectangle, and
then a bottom constraint to the line.
You also want a little bit of margin
there, and it's all set to go.
To make sure that our image view is
using the correct information from
the drawable art plane,
make sure that you set the image view's
background to that drawable art plane.
Awesome job,
our design looks complete now but
remember that we've only used
the android text for actual labels.
And we've used the tools text for
fake data which means if we run this you
can see that only the label text and
images would appear but
not the hard coded values.
To fix this, we will be binding
the values to real data later.
Awesome job.