The immediate question
is why does this work.
What is the benefit of having a single
thread that's just going to be switching
among the processing of different
requests compared to simply assigning
different requests to
different execution contexts,
to different threads or
even to different processings.
Recall our introductory lecture
about threads, in which we said that
on a single CPU threads can be useful
because they help hide latency.
The main takeaway from
that discussion was that,
if a thread is going to wait more than
twice the amount of time it takes to
perform a contact switch,
then it makes sense to go ahead and
context switch it to another thread
that will do some useful work.
And in that way we hide
this waiting latency.
If there really isn't any idle time.
So if the processing of a request
doesn't resolve in some type of blocking
idle operation on which it has to wait,
then there are no idle periods.
It doesn't make sense to context switch.
The context switching time will be just
cycles that are spent on copying and
restoring a thread or
a process information, and those cycles
could have been much better spent
actually performing request processing.
So in the event driven model, a request
will be processed in the context
of a single thread,
as long as it doesn't have to wait.
Whenever a wait needs to happen,
then the execution thread will
switch to servicing another request.
If we have multiple CPUs,
the event driven model still makes
sense, especially when we need to handle
more concurrent requests
than the number of CPUs.
For instance, each CPU could host
a single event-driven process, and
then handle multiple concurrent
requests within that one context.
And this could be done with
less overhead than if each of
the CPUs had to context-switch
among multiple processes or
multiple threads where each of those
is handling a separate request.
There is one gotcha, though, here.
It is important to have
mechanisms that will steer,
that will direct the right set of
events to the appropriate CPU,
at the appropriate instance
of the event-driven process.
And there are mechanisms to do this, and
there's current support, a networking
hardware to do these sorts of things,
but I'm not going to go into
this in any further detail.
So just know that overall in the model,
this is how the event-driven model would
be applied a multi-CPU environment.