I want to introduce you to my two
most favorite performance techniques,
batching and caching.
As we already talked about,
some functions or
operations have a specific amount of
overhead involved with them that is
different than the performance
costs of the operation itself.
For example, loading data into a new
place in memory before executing on it,
or sorting a set of values before
doing a search through it.
When executed multiple times,
where multiples are really big number,
this overhead can become a serious
performance burden for your application.
Batching is the process of
fixing this performance problem
by trying to eliminate the per execution
overhead of these operations, kind of
like sharing a car instead of everyone
driving themselves, thus saving gas.
This is most often seen in your code
where you have to prepare your data
before actually operating on it.
Now, for example, let's say the most
efficient way to find a value
existing in a set is to sort it, and
then execute a binary search on it.
Now, wait to, to be clear, this isn't
actually the most efficient way,
but just stay with me,
I'm trying to make a point here.
Anyhow, the simplest way to do this
would be to write a function that,
given a set and a value,
would sort the set and then search
it to see if the value exists in it.
Now, this may be fine for
some performance level but
let's say you've got like 10,000
values you want to test, and
the size of the set is in the millions.
Suddenly you're incurring
a ton of overhead per test
in the form of the sort.
The answer here is pretty clear.
You'd want to create a sorted
version of the set once, and
then allow all 10,000 values to be
tested for inclusion after that point.
This is batching in action.
We factored out the operation that
is repeated and do it over once.
Now, similar to this is actually
a concept known as caching and
is by far the most important performance
technique you can understand,
mainly because it drives everything
in modern computer technology.
Take your computer, for example.
The whole point of your RAM hardware is
to provide a place to store information
that's faster to access for
the CPU than the hard drive is.
Or take networking, and
look at the modern internet itself,
huge warehouses of servers called data
centers exist all over the world.
Their only purpose is to store or
cache frequently accessed content so
that your computer doesn't have to hit
a server 12,000 miles away every time
your friend in Egypt posts a picture.
Well, unless of course you're in Egypt,
but, you know, you get the point.
Now in your code, the most common place
that you can find optimizations for
caching has to do with data that
is calculated multiple times, but
the result is always the same.
For example, if you're in the middle
of a loop that you're calculating
the derivative of a four by four matrix,
and
that result is always the same, then
you're actually wasting performance,
recomputing it for
each iteration of that loop.
Instead, compute and save the results of
that derivation outside of the loop, and
then let your inner portions of
the loop reference that cached result.
The reason that I love batching and
caching so much is that pretty much
every performance improvement
that you can think of,
including the ones that we're
talking about in this course,
is effectively a variance of
these two basic techniques.
And if you're serious about
becoming a performance ninja,
then you better become a pro
at what it means to leverage
the awesome power of these techniques.
So, let's get started.