At this point, you should have
a project at your Firebase console.
And in the friendly chat folder on your
machine, if you go to the app folder,
you should have moved your
google-services.json file here.
Now it's time to actually open
your project in Android Studio and
see it run.
Here I've got mine
running in an emulator.
Now Firebase needs a recent version of
Google Play services installed to be
able to run.
So, like I am here,
make sure that you're up and
running with the Google Play services.
We've provided full instructions
in the notes which,
I'm providing instructions in the notes
to get you started if you're having any
trouble getting an emulator set up.
If everything goes well
though you should be,
like me, looking at an app on your
computer that looks like this.
This is a great starting point for
friendly chat.
Let's go ahead and familiarize ourselves
with the code that's already here.