The first question is true. There exists at least one environment in which every agent is rational.
Take an environment where the actions have no effect on the performance whatsoever.
So any agent that acts in any possible way will be the same performance, and it'll be rational, it'll be the optimal one.
Second one is also true. For every agent, there exists at least one environment in which the agent is rational.
So an agent generates action sequences, and just make an environment that pre-guesses those actions, and this agent will be optimal in this environment.
You can also use the example from the first question here, an environment where the actions have no effect.
And yes, for the specific environment I just gave you, the agent will actually be rational.
The third one is also true. It turns out a table lookup reflex agent would have to have a huge table to cover every possible
observation in the sliding tile 15 puzzle. That's much better with a planning agent, so it tends to require much less memory
than pre-caching every possible situation.
And the final one is false. It turns out that you can actually pre-cache the optimal action in every possible situation.
So a table lookup reflex agent might be optimal, it might be rational, but as a result, a planning agent will not always do better;
It might actually do just as good.