Now In the studio,
I modified the activity mainly layout to
replace the numbers category text view
with the code snippet that was provided
in the previous instructor's notes.
So I added a different background
as well as a black textColor.
Now I'm going to install the app on
my device and see how that looks.
So here's the new version running.
Hm, so there's no longer a colored
background on the numbers text view.
Well, that's expected because I
did change the background color.
So it looks like the background
is now the same color
as that of the whole activity.
So to answer a quiz question,
of what do we observe when we
tap on the numbers activity?
Let's see what that looks like.
So I'll click on the numbers activity.
And when I release,
I see that cool gray circle animation
starting when I put my finger down.
And as soon as I release,
the button click gets triggered and
the numbers activity opens.
So we go back and do it one more time
because it happened really quickly.
See if you can catch it.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now note that if you have an older
Android device, you may just see a grey
or blue rectangle up here when
you press down on the view, but
going back to the main activity,
I won't get any of that animation when
I press on any of the other activities.
So let me show you.
So the family members activity,
no ripple, colors activity typing on it
no ripple and
phrases activity also no ripple.
But with the numbers activity one more
time, we saw the circular ripple.
So when you modify the background
of the numbers text view to be
the selectable item background,
then you'll see a visual change on the
screen when you press down on a view.
And on Lollipop devices and
newer, they'll show up as
a circular ripple animation.
So next, we'll talk about why
having a touch feedback on your app
is an important feature.