Now you have the development
environment ready, and
can get the application source.
That's the next part of
the instructions in the Read Me.
We've provided a sample application
that also serves as a presentation on
the topic of Devops.
So, since this is meant to be
a development environment,
it would make sense to have a fork
of the application you can push to.
So, if you have a GitHub account,
you can fork the repo in GitHub and
then clone it down onto
the vagrant home directory.
If you'd rather just get it running,
you can clone the master repo, but
you won't be able to push to it.
Which really isn't much
a development environment.
Then cd into the app directory and do
the last couple of steps in the readme.
run sudo npm install,
then run the tests using grunt -v.
Then after the test pass,
just open up your regular browser and
go to localhost:8080.
And when you do, what's the first
word you see on the app's home page?
Fill it in here.