So let's take another look
at this n by n matrix.
What we're going to do is to divide it
into what we're going to call tiles.
They're square chunks of the matrix.
What we'll do is calculate
each tile in parallel,
which would then calculate all total
forces on the elements within that tile.
Then we'll add the resulting
forces across horizontal
tiles to get the total force for
each destination object.
We're going to say a tile
is p by p elements.
So we'll make n square over
p squared tiles overall.
We're not going to talk
about how big a tile is yet.
We'll cover that later.
But for now just think when
we run this particular tile,
we're going to run it
within a kudu thread block.
And we can potentially share data
between threads in the block.
Recall that the x axis
here is the source and
the y axis is the destination.
We'd really like to only fetch each
object once per tile and reuse it among
all the threads in the tile, instead
of fetching each item p times per tile.
Thus, instead of doing two p squared
memory fetches per tile, p times p,
and two fetches for each item,
we will instead do how many fetches?