One of the reasons that using a pattern
like recycler view is useful,
is that it makes it easy
to handle clicks on items.
Recycler view doesn't include
any type of click listeners, but
it's pretty straight
forward to implement.
>> In the last exercise,
recycler view click handling, we need to
make a few changes in the green adapter.
The first step is to create an interface
that will define your listener.
The signature can be
anything you want it to be.
Let's call it list item click listener.
We only care about the adapter
item index that was clicked
which is an integer.
So let's give it a method
called on list item click
that takes in an integer as a parameter.
Next we'll add a member
variable to the green adapter,
to store a reference to
a list item click listener.
And to initialize that we need to
modify our green adapter constructor.
The constructor needs to take an extra
parameter list item click listener.
This allows us to use the green
adaptor as a component,
with an external click handler,
such as from our activity.
So inside our constructor,
we'll initialize the unclick listener
to the past ten listener parameter.
Now that the adaptor has
access to a listener,
we need to pass it to the view holder so
that the view can invoke it.
So we change the number of view holder,
to implement View.OnClickListener.
Doing so, means that we need to
override the on click method,
set the body of the function to get the
adaptor position, which is the item that
was clicked, and then invoke the onClick
listener of the other class.
By passing in the clicked
position value.
Lastly in the green adaptor, you need
to call the set onClick listener,
on itemView in the constructor to this.
Now flipping over to our main activity,
we'll start by adding an nToast member
variable, to allow us to cancel toasts
if the user rapidly clicks on items.
We'll see how we'll
use that in a second.
But first we have to have our
main activity to implement
our greenAdapter.listItem
click listener,
and by doing that we also have
to implement the function.
And we'll change our green
adaptor constructors to pass in
the parameter this for both cases.
In the previously created
onListItemClick function,
we create a toast message using
the clickedItemIndex and show it.
If we run the app right now it works,
but if you click a bunch of items,
you would notice that the toast
messages aren't delayed.
That's because they're being queued up.
To avoid that, we can check if
the previous test is not null, and if so
we just cancel it, and
then show the new one.
Now you can see that
clicking on the items
refresh the toast message immediately