Here's the answer.
At level zero,
we have 1 node on the tree and iterative
deepening has only visited 1 node.
At level one,
we now have 4 nodes in the tree.
Iterative deepening level is at 5,
the 4 nodes in the tree now and
1 node from the previous level.
At level two we now have 13 nodes in the
tree and iterative deepening level is
at 18, 13 from this tree plus
5 from the previous time.
At level three we have
40 nodes in the tree,
plus 18 makes 58 nodes visited
by iterative deepening.
Finally, level four we have
121 nodes in the tree.
Iterative deepening
will be visiting 179,
which is actually less than 1.5 times
the number of nodes in the tree.
Remember that before,
when the branch factor of 2 we had
2 to the d + 1- 1 nodes in tree.
Now, with a brand new factor of 3,
we have 3 to the d + 1- 1
over 2 nodes in the tree.
Let's go ahead and generalize this.
For a branching factor of K,
the formula is K to the d plus 1 minus
1 over K minus one for
the number of nodes in the tree.