Before going further,
let's discuss scopes.
When defining your API client to sign
in, you'll be defining a scope for
how the sign in works.
A number of the scopes that
are available are these.
First, is Profile.
This is the basic login scope.
It gives your app access
to the authenticated user's
basic profile information.
This includes things such as the ID,
the display name, the image URL or
the profile URL for the user.
Secondly, there's PlusLogin.
And this gives access to the social
features from Google Plus.
It includes the same
as the Profile scope.
But it gives access to a number of other
information, such as the age range,
the list of circles that the user
has given permission to access and
things such as the ability to read and
write activities on
the person's Google Plus wall.
The next is the Email scope.
An Email scope gives the access
to the user's email address for
their Google account that they
use to sign in as well as
the Google Apps domain that the user
belongs to, if this is appropriate.
Next is the Email scope.
This gives access to the user's email
address for their Google account and
the Google App Store name that
the user belongs to if appropriate.
Next is the PlusProfilesEmailsRead.
This is very similar to the Email scope,
and
it gives the same as the Email scope,
except it also gives your app access to
any public verified addresses that
are in the user's Plus profile.
For this example we're going
to be using the Profile scope.