Welcome to the coffee break challenge.
During this challenge I'm going to
ask you a series of ten questions.
If you get the question correct be
sure to check the question feedback.
It'll give you a clue that you need for
your final prize.
Now there are no answer videos for
these questions.
So you can't really cheat, but
hints are provided in the instructor
notes if you need help.
All right.
Let's get our mental
loading bar on the screen.
As you complete questions,
the loading bar will get filled.
When it's full,
you've completed all the questions.
Okay.
First question.
If I want to show a picture on my phone,
what XML element should I use?
You can put your answer here.