Here's my solution. I begin by opening the file, with
read and write permissions, and then I read from the file.
Remember, it goes key value, key value. So, this first
read, will represent a key. I check to make sure that
I read in as much as I intended, and assuming
that that goes okay, I enter this loop here. I first
check the key to see if it's the value that
I'm looking for. If it's not, then I simply move the
cursor past the associated value and then read
in the next key. If it does match,
however, then I want to overwrite the value with
the new one, close the file descriptor, and exit
with success. If I ever reach the end of the file or if a read fails for
any reason, I can simply print that the
key is not found and then exit with failure.