So we've discussed cases where we
don't need to update the cursor.
So situations such as when the user
rotates the app, closes or
reopens the app or just scrolls up and
down the ListView.
And this is because nothing changes
in the data in the database.
However, we did discuss that
we need to update the cursor
whenever the data does change.
So, meaning when the data is either
inserted, updated, or deleted.
So for example, if we were to
add a new pet from the Uri.
So, let's say, Baxter,
down here, well, a new row will
need to be added to the table.
So, when you think about it, maybe
a really good idea if it was one place,
we could trigger the cursor to update
whenever the data was either inserted,
updated, or deleted.
Now if you're thinking, wait a moment,
all the commands to insert, delete, and
update data all come through
our content provider.
And you're absolutely right,
so that's why our content provider
is the place that we need
to set up to tell our cursor loader
that we need to reload its data.
Whenever any of these situations happen.
So, in Android there's a mechanism to
tell the Cursorloader that the data it's
associated with needs to be reloaded
because each loader is associated
with the URI particular to its data.
Remember the URI is used to
say what data we want to load.
For example,
this URI here that end in /pets,
well this loads all
the pets from the table.
And meanwhile,
this URI that ends in /pets/3 will
only load the pet with the id 3.
So this particular URI might be used for
an activity.
Something such as our editor activity,
which will only show the details for
one pet, so this pet here with the id 3.
So if we have a cursor, which was
generated using this particular URI.
So /pets/3, well that means we only want
to reload the data in the cursor and
then trigger any UI changes If this
particular part of the database changes.
For example if we were to
add a pet down here and
then remove these two pets, well those
changes didn't affect the pet in row 3.
So that means we don't need to reload.
Now to allow for
this type of behavior, cursors have
an attribute called a notification URI.
So the notification URI refers to some
specific point of data as all URI's do.
Now, once a cursor is set
up to be notified when
a URI changes we signal
that the data has changed
at that URI by calling the notify
change method on the URI.
Now keeping that in mind,
let's take a look at how
Android manages reloading data.
So here I am in the PetProvider code and
I've gone ahead and
made some changes to the code
to help us with data reloading.
So first,
let's take a look at the query method.
So here in the query
method down at the bottom,
I've called cursor.setNotificationUri,
passing in these two parameters.
So what this method does here is set
the notification URI on the cursor.
And this so that we know what content
URI the cursor was created for and
if any data at this URI does change then
we know we need to update the cursor.
So inside this method,
we're going to pass in the first
parameter is the content resolver.
So this is so that the listener which in
our case is a catalog activity that's
attached to this resolver will
automatically be notified.
Next we'll surpass in a URI which is
the content URI we want to watch.
So doing this sets
the notification URI for
any cursor returned by the query method.
So if the data at this URI changes, then
we know we need to update the cursor.
Now for each of the methods that
changed data in the database,
meaning our insert method, our update
method and our delete methods.
You'll need to modify the code so
that they properly notify all
listeners If the URI has changed.
So let's take a look at insert for
example.
So since in our situation the actual
inserting of pet information
happens in this method,
InsertPet, let's look here first.
So, in InsertPet in order to
notify listeners that the URI has
changed, I'm going to call this line
getContext.getContentResolver.notifyCha-
nge.
So what this method does is notify all
listeners that the data has changed for
the pet content URI.
So the notify change method
takes in two parameters.
The first one here is the URI and
secondly this one here is an optional
content observer parameter.
Now content observer is meant as
a class that receives callbacks or
changes to the content.
Well Android is nice to us in that if we
pass in null here by default the cursor
adapter object will get notified.
And so that means the loader callbacks
will still be automatically triggered.
So remember in our situation the content
UI that I'm interested in is this one.
So having this call with this URI will
update cursors such as the catalog
activity cursor which is listening for
notifications for this particular URI.
So let me demo this implementation
where the cursor now is helping us
automatically load the data.
So let's run it on the emulator.
All right, so here's the latest version
of the code running on my emulator.
And I highly suggest uninstalling the
app and then reinstalling with a brand
new version in case it's still
running the old version.
So from here let's go back
down to insert dummy data.
And remember previously when we click
this, we had to exit out and then come
back into the app so the cursor
loader would rerun the newest data.
But let's see it again.
So insert data and from here the cursor
loader is automatically pulling in
the latest information without us
having to kill and rerun the app.
So we've covered a lot of information.
So let's take a look at summarizing all
the interactions between the cursor
loaders, content resolvers,
and providers.
So to start off, our CatalogActivity
implements a LoaderCallback interface.
Now inside this activity
is the onCreate() method,
where we initialize the query
with the InitLoader method.
Now once this background framework is
all set up, it's going to call our
implementation of onCreateLoader() which
initializes our CursorLoader object.
Now using the content resolver
the CursorLoader finds the appropriate
content providers query() method.
And inside this query() method Is
the URI matcher which will help us find
the right data so
that we get back the correct cursor.
Next, using the set
notification URI method
we tell the cursor what URI to watch.
So it knows when its source
of data has changed.
So this cursor is returned back
to our cursor loader object.
Now an example of this section from
our pet app is in the query method,
we set up the notification URI to be
content://com.example.android.pets/pets.
Then if we were to insert a new pet
into the table the URI would be notified
which in turns tells the cursor
something's changed.
So once this updated,
it'll get pass back to the provider,
back to the resolver and
then back to the cursor loader where
the new information will be reloaded.
So once it's reloaded, on load finishes
column with the new cursor and
the UI can be updated.
Now if any information needs to be
refreshed, onLoaderReset is called so
that the stale cursor is removed.
So the fresh new data can be swapped in.
So currently this entire set up right
now is only working for insert method.
So what I want you to do is to implement
this functionality for update and
delete methods as well.
So here are the instruction for
this exercise so
you can automatically load and we reload
data with the latest information.
So in PetProvider class for
the query method call setNotificationUri
on the cursor before
returning the cursor result.
Next for insert, update, and delete,
call the ContentResolver
notifyChange method on that URI.
Remember this, you can test inserting
pets from the CatalogActivity and
the EditorActivity and see if they
automatically update the list of pets.