To get started I want to show
you something really cool.
This is a list of the top iOS apps for
December 2014.
And they're ranked by
monthly active users.
So if we take a look here,
you can see USA Canada, Mexico.
It's broken down this way.
There are a lot of popular social apps.
Facebook.
There's Twitter over here.
Instagram.
FaceTime.
What I'm going to do is,
I'm going to take a subset of the USA
list from apps one through ten and
I want you to indicate which
of these apps that you use.
And, I'll tell you in a minute
why we're doing this.
So here you can see that same list, and
I want you to put a check mark next
to each of the apps that you use.
If you haven't used any of these apps,
you can check,
I have used none of these apps.