A responsive UI is simply a UI
that reacts to the amount of
available space in the screen.
We will talk a lot more about how to
update our designs to match different
screen sizes in the next lesson.
But for now let's at least look at
what happens when you simply turn
the phone into landscape mode.
Well, it seems like when we turn
the phone into landscape, everything
stretches out smoothly following
the restraints that we created earlier.
However, this seems like
a huge waste of space.
Actually, we should be able to
fit everything in the same screen
if we made better use of
those blank spaces here.
But that means a totally different
layout for landscape mode.
This is why Android offers
something called alternate layouts.
Basically, you can create an entire new
XML layout file only for landscape mode.
To do that, simply create a new folder
called layout-land for landscape,
and then copy the activity_main, and
then place a copy inside layout-land.
This will appear as another new XML file
in Android Studio with the label land,
as in landscape.
Now you can try to
modify this XML to fit
everything in the same screen
when it's in landscape mode.
For example, this looks like a much
better layout for landscape.
Notice that all we did was
just change things around and
maybe change the font for
some text views a little bit.
But this blue table down here,
for example, is identical between
the two landscape and portrait modes.
Same goes for
the flight information up here.
So instead of recreating them in both
layouts, it's wise to move each of them
into a separate small layout themselves,
and then use Android's include tag
to combine them in the default and
landscape layout.
That way if you need to update
the blue table, say for
example, you only need to
do that in one location.
So, let's start by updating
the default layout first, and
then we will work on reusing those small
layouts to create the landscape version.
So first, let's create a new constraint
layout for the boarding table.
So let's call it boarding_table.xml,
and we'll change the type to
ConstraintLayout, and then we will move
anything that has to do with the blue
table from the default layout
into that boarding_table layout.
So the activity_main.xml,
let's just copy everything that has
to do with the blue table,
including the text field inside it, and
then copy that over to
the boarding_table.xml.
Now make sure that there are no
views that are still constrained to
some of the views that don't
exist in this boarding table.
Like, for example, the HeaderImage
should not be constrained to
the DepartureTime any more.
Now if we open that
boarding_table XML in design view,
you can see that it contains
everything in the table all by itself.
Okay, let's do the same for
the flight information.
Let's call it flight_info, and then set
the type to ConstraintLayout again.
And then move everything that has to
do with the flight information like
the rectangles, the divider,
and the origin_codes and so on.
Now to update the default
activity_main layout,
simply replace all those tags
that we've copied over already
with an include tag that just points
to the new layout that we just created.
To point to another layout, you just
set the layout="@layout/flight_info".
And then the same goes for
the header and body tables.
And then also make sure that if there's
any other views that are depending on
those tags that we've just removed, that
the constraints are updated accordingly.
Perfect.
Now it should be really easy to go
to the landscape version of our
main activity layout,
and then just move things around using
those two layouts that we created
to create the landscape design that
fits everything in the same screen.
So go ahead and try it yourself.