The term flow in web security refers to
the way information is exchanged between
a client, server and
OAuth provider to ensure secure
communication across the internet.
The specifications for
OAuth 2 provide a lot of flexibility for
developers to implement a security flow
that works best for the project at hand.
OAuth allows for a flow that
can happen on the client side.
This means that all of the code to
authenticate the user is initiated via
JavaScript from the user's browser.
This implementation is very useful for
single-page browser-based
web applications.
OAuth also supports mobile
authorization, such that
mobile device apps can authenticate and
gain access similarly to a browser.
Another possible and
very popular flow is on the server side.
Server side flow allows the server
to obtain an access token
to allow the server to make API
requests on behalf of the user.
The user has the option
to set a timeout or
revoke access to these
tokens at any time.
Each of these implementations
has various pros and cons.
Client side authentication is quick and
easy, but
a lot of trust is placed on
the browser or mobile device.
And the server cannot make API
calls to the OAuth provider
on behalf of the user.
Server side implementation gives more
power to a server side application, but
the server is now responsible for
securely implementing session
checking for its users and
secure storage of these access tokens.
Choosing the right OAuth flow for
an application really depends on
the specific needs of
a particular application.
If you are interested in learning
more about each of these flows,
I have provided some documentation
in the instructor notes.
Google+ uses a hybridized flow for
logins that requires authentication
to happen on the client, but
allows the server to make API
calls on behalf of the client.
This lesson will focus on the design and
implementation of this hybridized flow.