Here is what I would say.
Let me explain myself.
One way to think about the question
is to ask an analytical question.
Mainly, when does the alpha
term dominate the beta term?
When that happens,
then we might not care that
the beta term depends on log p.
Algebraically, this term dominating this
term is the same as saying that it's
much, much greater.
You'll notice the log p's cancel.
That leaves us with something like this,
which basically says n is much less
than the ratio of alpha to beta.
So let's compare that to our options.
The first option is
algebraically equivalent.
The fourth option,
even though it's qualitative,
kind of captures what this says.
So this says that we want n to
be small compared to something.
So to me, this is kind of
an acceptable intuitive answer.
What about the other options?
Option two has the relationship
algebraically wrong.
Option three is just kind of irrelevant,
there's no dependence on p here.
The last option is also
a bit of a red herring.
I don't know what that's
supposed to mean.
In fact,
even if you assume n is constant,
it doesn't satisfy this relationship.
You also remember,
it's far from reality.
Remember, I said at
some point you expect,
in real networks, for
alpha to be much greater than beta.