To finish our little tutorial on projective geometry,
talk about something that's really more of a vocabulary issue.
There's this notion of Ideal points and ideal lines.
So, Ideal points come this way.
We said that points are the intersection of a ray from the origin,
hitting the image plane.
Okay, fine no problem.
And all the rays will hit that plane, unless what.
Unless the ray is parallel to the image plane.
The ray is parallel to the image plane, where does it intersect the image plane?
We answered this before we said you had to go, they intersect out in infinity,
remember you had to go ask somebody high in the Himalayas about why that's true?
That's the second time,
that joke was so good the first time I thought I'd use it a second time.
Anyway, but the idea is that this notion of an ideal point is
essentially a point in infinity.
And the way you get a point in infinity is that you have z, the, the,
the last term is x, y, 0, scale being 0, gives you a point at infinity.
And if you want to think about that, what happens when you divide by zero, x and
y blow up, and, and they go to infinity.
So that's an ideal point, and the problem with an ideal point is that the ray
that's supposed to define it is parallel to the image plane.
Well, what about a line, where the normal
that defines the plane is parallel to the image plane, and that's shown here.
It's a little difficult to see but here's our normal, right here.
And you'll notice it has a z value of 0, okay?
So it's parallel to the image plane.
Well, that's actually okay, what it means is that the plane that it
defines is also going to be perpendicular to the image plane,
which means it's going to go right through the origin.
So, the ideal line corresponds to the image that go through the origin, or
the principle point.
And that's typically in the middle of our images, but
remember, you, your images might be offset.
So an ideal point is off in infinity, an ideal line goes through the origin.