The first output with sequential thread number 0, 1, 2,
3, is possible since I, whose values past this an argument to
the thread creation function, has values that reach from 0 to 3.
The next output, the print out,
is a little bit arbitrary thread number 0, 2, 1, 3.
But this is still possible because as we said earlier.
We don't have control over how these newly created threads will be
actually scheduled.
So, it's possible that just the order in which their execution was scheduled, so
the order in which every one of them performed the printf
operation was slightly different that the order in which they were created.
Now the last output that's actually also possible.
Now, you may be asking yourself how since the print out thread number one,
which appeared in the previous two options, doesn't even appear in this case.
Is that an indication that that thread wasn't even created?
If we look at this loop in main, we see that we must have really
executed the printout operation for every one of the four created threads.
So we really would expect that one of them would have printed out
thread number one, when we pass the argument i equals 1.
Let's explain what happened to that line in the next morsel.