Let's see what's required
from the system software that
provides support for RPCs.
First, the model of inter-process
interactions that the RPC model is
intended for needs to manage
client/server interactions.
A server supports some
potentially complex service.
Maybe it's running a complex
computation but really fast, or
maybe it's a file service that
services a remote file content.
The clients do not need to
have the same capabilities or
they don't have to be able to
perform accesses to the same data.
They just need to be able to
issue requests to the server for
whatever they need.
The second requirement has to do with
the fact that when RPC was first
developed, the state-of-the-art
programming languages for
procedural languages including Basic and
Pascal, and Fortran and C.
So this is what programmers
were familiar with.
One goal of the RPC systems was
to simplify the development
of distributed applications underneath
a procedure called interface.
This is why the term remote
procedure calls came to be.
As a result, RPCs are intended to
have similar synchronous semantics.
Just like regular procedure calls.
What that means is that when a process
makes our remote procedure calls,
the calling process or at least
the calling thread, will block, and
wait until the procedure completes,
and then returns the result.
This is the exact same thing that
happens when we call a procedure in
a single address base.
The execution of the thread
will reach the point when
the procedure call is made.
At that point,
we jump somewhere in the address base
where the procedure is implemented.
The actual original thread of
execution will not advance beyond
that procedure called point until we
get the results from the procedure.
And then when we move
on to the next step,
we act,
actually already have the results.
So this is what we mean by
the synchronous call semantics.
And this is what we require
from the RPC systems as well.
RPCs have other useful features that are
similar to regular procedure calls, and
one is type checking.
If you pass to a procedure
an argument of the wrong type,
you'll receive some kind of error.
This is one useful reason why RPC
systems would incorporate type
checking mechanisms.
In addition, type checking mechanisms
are useful because they allow us,
in certain ways, to optimize
the implementation of the RPC run-time.
When packets are being
sent among two machines,
it's just a bunch of bytes that
reach from one endpoint to another.
And some notion about the types of
the data that's packaged into those
bytes can be useful when the RPC
run-time is trying to interpret what
do these bytes mean.
Are they integers or they're file.
Do I need to put them together so
as to create some kind of image or
some kind of array.
This is what the type
information can be used for.
Since the client and the server
may run on different machines,
there may be differences in how
they represent certain data types.
For instance, machines may differ
in the way they use big endian or
little endian format
to represent integers.
This determines whether the most
significant byte of that integer is in
the first or
the last position in the sequence of
bytes that corresponds to the integers.
Or machines may differ in their
representation of floating point
numbers, may use different
representations for negative numbers.
The RPC system should hide all of these
differences from the programmer, and
should make sure that data is
correctly transported, and
it must perform any of
the necessary conversions,
any of the necessary translations
among the two machines.
One way to deal with this
conversion is for the RPC run-time
in both endpoints to agree upon a single
data representation for the data types.
For instance,
it can agree of that everything will
be represented in the network format.
Then there is no need for the two
endpoints to negotiate exactly how data
should be encoded,
exactly how data should be represented.
Finally, RPCs intended to be
more than just a transport-level
protocol like TCP and
UDP that worries about
sending packets from one endpoint to
another in an ordered reliable way.
RPC should support underneath
different kinds of protocols, so
we should be able to carry out the same
types of client-server interactions,
regardless of whether the two
machines use UDP or TCP, or
some other protocol to communicate.
But RPC should also incorporate some
higher level mechanisms like access
control, or authentication,
or fault tolerance.
For instance, if a server is not
responding, a client can retry and
reissue their same request to either the
same server or it can make an attempt
to contact the replica of that original
server that it was trying to contact.