The first logic we would consider
is called propositional logic.
Let's jump right into an example,
recasting the alarm problem
in propositional logic.
We have propositional symbols B,
E, A, M, and
J corresponding to the events of the
burglary occurring, of the earthquake
occurring, of the alarm going off,
of Mary calling, and of John calling.
And, just as in the probabilistic
models, these can be either true or
false.
But unlike in probability,
our degree of belief in
propositional logic is not a number.
Rather, our belief is that each of these
is either true or false or unknown.
Now we can make logical sentences
using these symbols and
also using the logical
constants true and
false by combining them together
using logical operators.
For example, we can say that the alarm
is true whenever the earthquake or
burglary is true with this sentence.
E, or B a parenthesis, implies A.
So that says, whenever the earthquake or
the burglary is true,
then the alarm will be true.
We use this v symbol to mean or,
and a right arrow to mean implies.
We could also say that it will
be true that both John and
Mary call when the alarm is true.
We write that as A implies
parenthesis J and M.
And we use this symbol to indicate an M.
So this upward-facing wedge looks kind
of like an A with the crossbar missing.
And so you can remember A is for
and, right,
where this downward-facing v
symbol is the opposite of and.
So that's the symbol for or.
Now, there's two more
connectors we haven't seen yet.
There's a double arrow for equivalence,
also known as a biconditional,
and a not sign for negation.
So we could say, if we wanted to, that
John calls if and only if Mary calls,
we would write that as John
is equivalent to Mary.
When one is true, the other is true.
When one is false, the other is false,
or we could say that when John calls,
Mary doesn't and vice versa.
We could write that as
John is equivalent,
with double arrow, to not Mary.
And this is the not sign.
Now how do we know what
the sentences mean?
A propositional logic
sentence is either true or
false with respect to
a model of the world.
And a model is just a set
of true false values for
all the propositional symbols.
So, a model might be the set B is true,
E is false, and so on.
We can define the truth of a sentence in
terms of the truth of the symbols with
respect to the models
using truth tables.