So I asked you to try your best at
reading this article on linear layout,
knowing that you probably
would run into concepts and
terms that you may not understand but
that's totally okay.
Hopefully, each time you
read the documentation,
you'll understand
a little more each time.
We're going to spend the next few
videos learning about layout weight in
more detail.
But here's one thing that could
be useful to our problem at hand.
This section is called Equally weighted
children, and it talks about how we can
create a linear layout where each child
is given an equal amount of space,
whether it's a vertical layout or
a horizontal linear layout.
For a vertical linear layout,
we would set the layout height attribute
of each child view to be zero dp.
Then we would need to set the layout
weight attribute of each view to be one.
I'll show you what this looks
like in the next video.