All right.
So instead of doing a super duper formal
proof, here's how I like to think
about this particular result.
So here's a picture that
I'm hoping is helpful.
It's kind of a weird graph
of the x axis is the arms.
In this case, this is a five arm bandit.
And the y axis is the value of that arm.
And these rectangles represent
our uncertainty integrals
of that arm's value.
Does that make sense?
>> Okay.
They're not the arms themselves,
that's just the uncertainty.
>> Yeah, if they were actually arms
then I'd have to draw like [NOISE].
>> [LAUGH]
>> Ooh, that's terrible.
That was supposed to be a hand,
so I apologize.
>> That's a seven-fingered hand.
That's okay.
>> Yeah, I think that was the problem.
You know what it is, it's to make up for
the fact that, like,
Mickey Mouse only has four.
>> That's perfectly reasonable.
>> So if we do this.
If we make sure that each arm,
we are 1 minus delta over k sure
that its estimate is within
epsilon over 2 of what r.
Our sample to valuation is.
So how big are these bars, exactly?
>> Oh, okay, I see.
So those are uncertainty bars or
error bars.
So that means your estimate is right
smack in the middle of each of them.
>> Right, so we have our estimates for
each of the individual arms and that
estimate is, we're pretty sure, epsilon
over 2 close to the actual value.
Right, so that would mean that you
could be epsilon over 2, too high or
epsilon over two, too low,
which means the total
height of those bars is 2 times
epsilon over 2 or epsilon.
>> And those estimates hold
true with some probability.
>> Sure.
>> So each one is correct with
probability, 1-delta, over k.
So the first thing we need to
do is basically make sure that
all these estimates are correct
because if one of them is wrong,
then it casts doubt over
the entire calculation.
So what's the probability that
all of these estimates are actually
correct simultaneously.
>> Well, if I pretend they're all
independent of one another then
isn't it just one minus
delta over k to the k?
>> Delta over k is the probability
that a given arm is wrong.
One minus delta over k is
the probability that that arm is right.
So if that probability is one, for
example, then raise it to the k power,
sure
they're all going to be right because
they all have certainty of being right.
But if it's a little bit less,
you know 0.95 or something like that.
Then it's 0.95 and this one has to be
right, it's another probability 0.95 and
this one has to be right.
So we ended up with the raised
to the K power of that
individual arm probability.
>> Right.
>> It turns out for
various reason that this kind of
quantity is hard to work with, and
also sometimes, I think not in this
case, but sometimes it's also a little
risky because it assumes statistical
independence of all the estimates.
And sometimes it's safer to just say
maybe they're not
independent of each other.
Maybe they actually all fail together or
all fail separately.
So we use a standard trick
to get around this idea.
And this is the idea that we can
estimate the probability that
at least one is wrong.
If we know the probability that
one is wrong, it can't be since
there's k of them, it can't b any
worse than k times delta over k.
And this kind of follows from if you
think of it as like a Venn diagram.
Here's the probability that one
thing is bad, here's the probability
that the other thing is bad, here's
a probability that a third thing is bad.
What's the largest that this can be.
The maximum badness probability is
actually going to be the sum of
these if their
intersections are all zero.
And so this is really like taking
the union of all those sets.
So this is referred to
as the union bound.
Which I don't know, to me sounds
like kind of a fancy name for
not such a fancy idea.
We're just going to add
the probabilities because
we don't know how to account for
the overlaps.
>> Oh, but that just follows
from probability, right?
The probability of a or
b is just the probability of
a plus the probability of b minus
the probability of a and b.
And sort of the worst case in this
situation is that a and b is zero.
>> Right.
So this is just how these probabilistic
quantities are defined and what we're
saying is if we want to maximize
the probability of this or,
that at least one of them is wrong,
then if we set this intersection
to zero that maximizes it.
So it really is just,
the sum is an upper bound.