Now, let's talk about the fact this
is not that trivial all the time.
We are dealing with feature detection
which does have some times problems and
sometimes of course you know why there
are problems with feature imaging.
Let's look at two images.
I'm going to zoom in again just
to kind of show you more details.
So this is my right image,
and my left image.
Now, what I can start doing is
of course, finding features.
So I found one here and, of course,
this also here and I can match it.
I can keep doing this for
a variety of features.
Another one here.
And of course, if we look at it, decent
feature detection will do fine for
some of these types of things.
Another feature match between
these two points also works.
Now, basically what I'm
doing is I'm just, kind of,
running a feature matching algorithm,
finding features, and
seeing if they match between two images.
Notice each one of them,
right now, looks pretty good.
And the transformation
looks to be correct.
All of them seem to be moving
approximately by the same amount.
Remember?
These are cameras moving.
And these are images moving because
we have kept the point the same.
So we expect these row, these arrows
that kind of show the distance between
these features to be the same, right?
And of course the same thing is true for
this one.
But if we keep doing this, we will find,
and of course there will be instances,
there will be features
like this matches to this.
Now this looks like
a bad match to anyone.
Especially if you consider the fact that
all of the other ones were you know,
the distance between them was this much.
Another bad match here.
So we want to be able to
discount these matches.
And here you, you can see it,
this is a bad match, so
we want to be able to kind of look for
good matches, we refer to them as
inliers, and ignore the bad matches,
referred to as outliers.
So, this can be done by a process called
RANSAC, or random sample consensus,
which basically means randomly
we're going to sample things.
But at the same time we're going to
see which one of them are actually
creating a consensus.
Which one of them are more popular.
Just looking at this you can see that
the yellow ones are more popular,
there are more of them.
They will actually be the inliers, and
they will actually kind of out vote
I'll popularize the red ones,
which are outliers.
So, we want to build consensus, but
we want to do this randomly,
not to have a bias.
So, in essence, what it means is,
start with one match and
then find all of the other
ones that match it.
These are the inliers.
Then find the average translation
vector, of these inliers,
which in this case would
be this line here.
Notice this line is shorter.
Much more similar to
all of the yellow ones.
Not anywhere close to the red one.
And basically now this gives
me an algorithm to be able to
kind of compute which matches inliers.
Lets look at that algorithm for
RANSAC next.