So, here I've added some print
statements, and we can see what's going
on inside this function when it
gives us these weird results.
Hm, location -1.
That looks kind of odd.
So when the find method doesn't
find sub inside some string,
like do isn't inside ding,
it returns -1, but then reusing that
value as if it were an actual
location in the string, down here.
Looking at these
variables shows us that.
Now, really what we should do is
if find doesn't find anything,
we could return some string unchanged.
Now that we've found the bug, we should
remove the print statements we added.
That's one thing you have to be careful
with when you use print statements
for debugging.
If you don't take them all out,
your code will print debugging
information when you don't want it to.