Let's start with coding
the insert method so
that we can add data
to out task database.
Our end goal for implementing this
function is to hook it up to our
add task activity UI, so
then when a user types
in a new task with a selected
priority and clicks the add button,
this will insert that newly created
data into our task database.
One thing that the provider will do
differently than straight up SQL code is
to have different actions for
different URIs.
In this way,
it can do some simple data validation
by making sure it only
responds to valid URIs.
When you insert data,
you'll be inserting a new row of data
into the entire tasks directory,
which holds all of our existing data.
So you'll want your content
provider to respond only to the URI
that identifies that directory.
And to handle this case, you'll use
your URI matcher and a switch statement.
So that we can write new data to it,
we'll use
mTaskDbHelper.getWritableDatabase().
And we'll be using this
throughout this function.
So I'm declaring it as
a final variable named db.
This match will be either 100 for
all tasks or 101 for
a task with ID, or an unrecognized URI.
And we want to check these
cases with a switch case and
respond to only the tasks case.
If the tasks case is met, we can insert
a new row of data into this directory.
We can't insert data into just one
row like in the task with id case.
And if we receive any other
type of URI or an invalid one,
the default behavior will be to throw
an UnsupportedOperationException and
print out an Unknown uri message.
Now let's actually fill in the code for
this directory case.
First, we know this
method returns a URI.
So let's create a variable to
store that, named returnUri.
We'll declare this right
above our switch case so
that we can assign it a value
later on in the directory case.
Then, in the tasks case, we'll insert
new data into the tasks directory
by calling insert on our database.
We just say db.insert and pass in our
table name and our content values.
And this may look familiar from
the wait list app you've coded before.
This insert should return an integer ID.
If the insert wasn't successful,
this ID will be -1.
But if the insert is successful, we want
the provider's insert method to take
that unique row ID and create and return
a URI for that newly inserted data.
So first, let's write an if that checks
that this insert was successful.
So if ID greater than 0 will work.
That means the insert worked and
we can construct the new URI.
Otherwise, we'll throw
a SQLiteException,
because the insert failed.
So if the ID is valid, then the URI we
construct will be our main content URI,
which has the authority and tasks path,
with the id appended to it.
And we can do that using
ContentUris.withAppendedId,
and passing in our main CONTENT_URI and
this new row id.
contentUris is an Android class
that contains helper methods for
constructing URIs.
And this method creates a URI starting
with this first argument as a base, and
then with this id added on
to the end of the path.
And we're storing this as the value for
our returnUri variable.
Then at the end of our switch statement,
we can return that URI.
And don't forget to delete the not yet
implemented exception.
And we're almost done.
One last thing, right before
this return statement, you'll
also notify the resolver that a change
has occurred at this particular URI.
You'll do this using
the notify change function.
This is so that the resolver knows
that something has changed, and
can update the database and
any associated UI accordingly.
Phew!
That was a lot of little steps.
But now we have a complete
insert function.
And the next step will be to
actually call this from the UI code.