Let me describe one simple scheme and
illustrate it on a sample graph.
Pick any vertex as a starting point.
Then, run a level synchronous
BFS from this vertex.
The BFS will assign
levels to every vertex.
Notice that every level
serves as a separator.
Because of this fact, you can stop
the BFS after you visited, say,
half the vertices.
For this example,
that midpoint is about here.
From the stopping point,
you can assign all visited vertices to
one partition and
all unvisited vertices to the other.
Now, that's not your only option for
a stopping criteria.
Can you come up with any others?
Anyway, BFS based schemes tend to work
pretty well on planar graphs, and
they're fairly cheap.
But there's at least one odd bit about
using a BFS to do a partitioning.
Weren't we motivated to solve
the graph partitioning problem
in order to efficiently
compute a distributed BFS?
Yet, we're using BFS to do that.
Is it just me or
does that seem perversely recursive?
Dun dun dun!
Oh no, recursion.