Up to this point, we've only made
simple style changes to our web pages
by changing the font color.
But there are many other properties
that you can change using CSS.
In fact, there are hundreds, and
the list of properties
is constantly growing.
Not only that, but
remembering the correct values to pass
to each property can be a nightmare.
Thankfully there are resources like
Mozilla's CSS reference or CSS tricks,
CSS almanac that give us the entire
listing of standard CSS properties, and
their acceptable values.
There's always Google too.
In the next exercise I want you to get
comfortable with using CSS references.
I've listed a couple of
questions to get you started.
What CSS properties are used
to italicize, underline,
uppercase, and bold text?
If you get stuck check below for
links to some different CSS references.