Let's take a look inside the app. So so far I can think of two potential objects:
people which are actors and movies. What would be the relationship from actor to
movie. An actor can star in many movies, but a movie can only have that actor in it
once. There are no clones of that actor. So the relationship is one to many, that is
one actor to many movies. Let's look at some potential attributes for movie.
Keep in mind you may have a different answer for this, but we picked title, release
date, a path to the movie poster and the ID of that movie in the movie database
website that we were using, to be attributes of the movie entity. For actor, we had
name, image path to the actor’s picture and movie database website ID. For attributes
for actor, you may have also ahead date of birth,
movie starred in, awards won or something else.
For actor, we had name, image path to actor’s picture and movie database website ID.