To understand the idea of heuristics,
let's talk about another domain.
Here we have the sliding puzzle domain.
Remember, we can slide around
these little tiles and
we try to reach a goal state.
16 puzzle's kind of big, so
lets show you the state space for
the smaller 8 puzzle, and
here's just a small portion of it.
Now, let's figure out what the action
schema looks like for this puzzle.
So we only need to describe one action,
which is to slide
the tile t from location
a to location b.
And the precondition,
the tile has to be on location a,
and has to be a tile,
and b has to be blank,
and a and b have to be adjacent.
That should be an and sign not a a,
so that's the action schema.
Oops, I forget we need an effect,
which should be that
the tile is now on b and
the blank is now on a.
And the tile is no longer on a and
the blank is no longer on b.
Now, we talked before about how a human
analyst could examine a problem and
come up with heuristics.
And encode those heuristics as
a function that would help search do
a better job.
But with this kind of
a formal representation,
we can automatically come up with
good representations of heuristics.
So for example,
if we came up with a relaxed problem
by automatically going in and
throwing out some of the prerequisites.
You throw out a prerequisite,
you make the problem strictly easier,
then you get a new heuristic.
So for example, if we crossed out
the requirement that b has to be blank,
then we end up with the Manhattan or
city block heuristic.
And if we also throw out
the requirement that a and
b have to be adjacent, then we get
the number of misplaced tiles heuristic.
So that means we could slide
a tile from any a to any b,
no matter how far apart they were,
that's the number of misplaced tiles.
And other heuristics are possible.
For example, one popular thing
is to ignore negative effects.
To say, let's not say that this
takes away the blank being a b.
So if we ignore that negative effect, we
make the whole problem strictly easier.
We'd have a relaxed problem and that
might end up being a good heuristic.
So because we have our actions
encoded in this logical form,
we can automatically edit that form.
A program can do that and
the program can come up with heuristics
rather than requiring the human
to come up with heuristics.