I'm not going to walk through
this solution step by step, and
I hope that most of this code that you
see here has become pretty routine.
Let's just go down to the bottom.
Keep going.
Here, we store the user ID
in our app delegate, and
then we call the complete login method,
to go to the next view.
So let's test this and see what happens.
I'll enter my credentials and
click log in.
And there we go.
We've completed the authentication
flow plus we've gotten the user ID.
And we're here in our main tab view.
And for fun I'll go to the favorites
tab just to see if the movies that I've
already selected as favorites
on the website show up here.
And there they are.
Next we're going to tackle our
first post request to favorite and
unfavorite movies.