The correct answers to this question
are that, the fact that virtualization
wasn't dominant technology
all these years is that
first mainframes weren't ubiquitous,
and then other hardware was cheap.
Majority of the companies did not
necessarily run mainframe computers.
They ran servers that were based
on x86 architecture mostly.
This was affordable, and it was always
much simpler to just add new pieces
of hardware than to try to figure out
how to make multiple applications and
multiple operating systems coexist
on that same hardware platform.
This trend of just buying more machines
if you need to run a different kind of
operating system to support
different applications continued for
a few decades actually.