Let's visit each comparator and
look at the outputs.
Remember that plus comparators
take their inputs and
produce outputs in increasing order.
So for this example, 8 and
7 would become 7 and 8.
Minus comparators do just the opposite.
In this case the inputs
are already in descending order so
the outputs will be the same.
Now this comparator takes 7 and
6 as its inputs.
So it will flip them.
Same thing happens here.
Finally, you can check that this
column of inputs matches this
column of outputs.
Now, here's a thought question for you.
Suppose I change this minus
comparator to a plus comparator,
lets update these values.
Now, lets propagate the new values.
Notice what just happened.
The sequence is actually
already sorted at this stage.
Now that would seem to suggest that
these two comparators are actually
unnecessary.
But is that really true?
That is if I eliminated
these plus comparators,
would the leftover circuit
sort any input of four values?
I'll let you ponder that one.