In this question, we apply naive Bayes with Laplacian smoothing--
the same as we have learned in class.
We have now 2 classes of movies. One is called "old" and one is called "new."
There are titles in here. There's three old movies--Top Gun, Shy People, Top Hat.
Two new movies--Top Gear, Gun Shy.
Use Laplacian smoothing with k=1 to compute the probability of a movie being old--
this is a prior probability, which is just based on class counts--
the probability of the word "top" as a title word in the class of old movies,
and the probability that a new movie that we look at--
by new I mean a movie we've never seen before--
that is called "top," the probability this movie that corresponds
to the old movie class with the new movie class.
I recommend you use a single dictionary for smoothing,
so look at all the words and see how large the dictionary is.
Top occurs here in two different ways.
One is a word over here, but one also is a movie title over here.
Don't pay too much attention to it, just don't get confused by it.
Again, use Laplacian smoothing with k=1.