Then finally, let's take a look at one
of the results from the performance
measurements that are shown
in the Anderson's paper.
This is Figure 3 from that paper
if you're following along.
This figure shows measurements
that were gathered from
executing a program with
multiple processes.
And each process executed
a critical section,
the critical section was executed
in a loop 1 million times.
The number of processes
in the system was varied
such that there is only
one process per processor.
In the platform that was used,
was a Sequence Symmetry
that had 20 processors.
So that's why the maximum number
of processes was also kept to 20.
Also this platform was cache
coherent with write and validate.
The metric that was computed based
on the experiments was the overhead
that was measured compared to
in a case of ideal performance.
An ideal performance corresponded in
these measurements to
a theoretical limit.
How long it takes to execute that
fixed number of critical sections.
So basically there is no contention,
no effects due to the fact that
each of these critical sections
needs to be locked and unlocked.
Then how long would it take to run
these number of critical sections.
The measured difference between that
theoretical limit and whatever it
actually took to perform this
experiment was considered the overhead.
And this is what these graphs represent.
These experiments were performed for
every one of the different spinlock
implementations we discussed.
From the spin on read,
the test_and_test_and_set,
all the way to the queuing
implementation.
These results don't include
that the basic test and
set when we're spinning on
the atomic construction.
Basically that implementation would
result in something that would just
completely be off the charts.
It would be the highest overhead
the worst performance measurement.
And then, notice how we have for
the different variations of the delay
both the static and the dynamic delay.
So let's see what
happens under high load.
This is where we have lots of processors
and lots of processes running on those
processors that are contending for
the log.
We see from these measurements that
the queuing log, it's the best one.
It is the most scalable and as we add
more and more processors, more and
more load, it performs best.
The test_and_test_and_set log,
that's this line here,
that one will perform worst.
That isn't particular the case, because
here we have an architecture that's
cache coherent with right invalidate.
And we said that in that case,
on release of the test_and_test_and_set
log, we have an order of n
squared memory references.
So a very high contention
on the shared bus and
that's going to really hurt performance.
After delay based alternatives,
we see that the static implementations
are a little bit better than
their dynamic counterparts.
Since under high loads with static,
we end up nicely balancing
out the atomic constructions.
First with dynamic,
we still end up with some randomness,
with some number of collisions.
Those are avoided in the static case.
Also note that delaying after every
single memory reference is slightly
better than delaying after the log
is freed only, it's only on release.
Because when we avoid
after every reference,
we end up avoiding some
additional invalidations
that come from the fact that sequence
is a right invalidate architecture.
Under light loads, when we have few
processes then few processors as well,
we can make couple of observations.
First we see that test_and_set performs
really pretty well in this case.
And that's because this implementation
of a spinlock has low latency.
We were just performing a check,
if lock equal busy and then we were
moving on to the atomic test_and_set.
We also see that in terms
of the delay alternatives,
the dynamic delay alternatives.
The backup delay alternatives
perform better than the static ones.
And that is because with
the dynamic alternatives,
we end up with lower delay.
But we said that static alternatives
can lead to situations in which the two
processors that have the extreme,
the smallest and the largest delay.
Are the only ones that are contending on
the lock and so we have wasted cycles.
We also see that under light loads,
the queueing lock performs the worst.
This is the performance
of the queueing lock.
And the reason for that is we
explain that with the queuing clock,
we have pretty high latency.
Because we need to implement
the read and increment and
the modular processing, etc.
So this is what hurts the performance
of the queueing lock under light loads.
One final comment regarding
the performance results that
we just discussed is that
this points to the fact.
That with system design, there isn't
really a single good answer that
the design points should be driven
based on the expected workload.
Light loads, high loads,
architectural features,
number of processors,
write invalidate, write update, etc.
The paper includes additional
results that point to some of
these trade offs in more detail.spi