One of the scariest problems related to multithreading is deadlocks.
An informal definition of a deadlock is that,
it is a situation in which competing threads, at least two or
more, they're each waiting on each other to complete.
However, none of them ever do because each waits on the other one.
So thus, the execution of the process overall of all of
these threads is stuck and it cannot continue.
The threads are, we call, deadlocked.
We can use the visual example to help explain a deadlock using our
toy shop example.
So, imagine that two workers in the toy shop are finishing toy
orders that involve a train, and each worker will need a soldering iron and
a solder wire to finish their toy.
The problem is, there's only one of each of those.
So, let's say the first worker grabs the soldering iron first, and
the second worker grabs the solder wire.
And because both workers are stubborn, they're unwilling to give up either one
of the items that they've grabbed, so none of the toys will ever get made.
The workers remain continuously stuck in a deadlock.
In practice, the deadlock example can be described with the following situation.