The first statement, intrusion detection
is based on the assumption that
the behavior of the intruder
differs from that of a legitimate
user in ways that can be quantified.
This is true.
This is the primary assumption of IDS.
The second statement,
the primary purpose of an IDS is
to detect intrusions,
log suspicious events and send alerts.
This is true statement, because these
are the basic functions of an IDS.
The third statement,
signature-based approaches attempt
to define normal, or expected,
behavior, whereas anomaly approaches
attempt to define proper behavior.
This is false, because a signature
based approach is typically used to
represent known intrusion patterns.
The fourth statement,
a network IDS sensor monitors
a copy of network traffic.
The actual traffic does not
pass through the device.
This is true because a network ID
typically performs passive monitoring
by copying the network traffic.
The last statement.
Network-based intrusion detection
makes use of signature detection and
anomaly detection.
This is true.
You can indeed use both approaches.