Now let's move on to the next exercise,
where we get to bind this cool looking
UI with some data to see
those values filled up.
When we were first designing the UI, we
set those view text to string resources,
just to help us design and
build that UI.
But to display actual data that can
change from one user to the other,
we need to be able to modify those
text values programmatically.
In earlier lessons and
exercises, we managed to do so
by using the findViewById.
And then setting the text to
something or changing any attribute.
This time, however,
we're going to use something new.
Android offers a really cool library
called the Data Binding Library.
This can help us link
any UI with actual data
without having to call
the findViewById for every view item.
Let's see how to use this.
First thing, make sure you're using
the latest Android Studio, or at least
something that's later than 2.1 so that
it can actually support dataBinding.
These here are the steps that we're
going to go through to connect real data
to our UI using dataBinding.
The first step is to enable
dataBinding in our application.
To do that,
open up the build.gradle file and
inside the Android section, make sure
to set the dataBinding.enabled to true.
And then sync to update your project.
In this exercise,
we've already created a class for
you that can hold all the data
you need to bind to the UI.
It's called the BoardingPassInfo.
And it's a simple plain old Java object
which simply acts as a placeholder for
the actual data.
Ideally, this will filled with
data from say, an airline API or
some database lookup.
But for simplicity, we've provided you
with another FakeDataUtils class that
just generates random information and
fills up power plain old Java object.
The second step is to change
the root tag in our layout XML
to use a layout tag.
Android automatically
generates a binding class for
any layout that includes
this tag as its root.
And we will need those
binding classes later.
So let's go ahead and open up our
activity_main.xml and then surround
this with our layout tag and then
let's copy those definitions up here.
And make sure to close our
layout all the way at the end.
This way we've surrounded
our ScrollView tag,
making our root tag this layout tag.
Once we are done with that,
make sure to rebuild our project to
create those binding classes for us.
Perfect, next, we'll be creating
something called a binding instance.
This will help us access those
UI components from the code.
Open up the MainActivity and create
a variable for type ActivityMainBinding.
This is the class that was generated for
us based on the name of the layout.
So activity_main becomes
MainActivityBinding.
Whatever you named your layout, the
class would follow the same convention.
The following step is to point the data
binding instance to the correct content
view.
This is done using the DataBindingUtil
class by calling the setContentView and
passing in the actual main activity.
This sets the context of our binding
class to the elements in the layout
we just passed.
Next, let's try to generate some fake
data using the FakeDataUtils class
that we've provided.
And let's put them in a BoardingPassInfo
class called fakeBoardingInfo.
The final step is to actually
bind the data one by one
using that binding
instance we just created.
Simply go through the attributes in
the binding object one by one and
set the text values to
our fake data object.
We're doing this in the function
displayBoardingPassInfo
where you pass in this
fake object called info.
And then we could set
the passenger name, the airport,
and flight code information.
And then we could do some formatting for
our times, and set the values for
those as well.
And then finally, our gate and
terminal information down here.
And then the very last tab is going
back to the onCreate method, and
calling this displayBoardingPassInfo,
passing in our fake data.
Now if we run this app.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Voila, we got our design
filled with actual data.