Here I'm going to show you a median filter and image processing.
At the top here, we have a chunk of our image and
notice that in the middle is a pixel that probably is not right.
Probably is a piece of salt.
All right.
Because there are all these other lower numbers and then poof a 90.
So the question is, what should we replace that with?
If we just do the regular filter, then we would take the local average of
everything, including the 90, and stick that there.
A better idea is to do a median filtering.
So we sort all those pixels.
Whoops, I left out the 10.
There we go.
And we pull out the middle value, the 27.
And we replace that here.
So now you see the 90 is totally gone.
The 27 happens to be replicated.
We don't care.
But the idea is that we replace that pixel with this median value.
So before you're gone, we ask some questions about that.
First of all, what's kind of nice is every value we put in
the picture was present locally.
Especially if it's odd.
If it's even, then it's the average of the two,
but if it's an odd number of pixels,
the median is one of those pixels whose value is somewhere around me.
So I'm not introducing any sort of really weird values.
So that's good for when I have these weird spikes, like this salt and
pepper, but here's a question for you.
Is it a linear operation?
What do you think Megan?
>> No?
>> Good. Yeah.
Right. No, look median is not a linear thing right.
I add in a couple different things.
I summed them up and the median can move however the median going to move.
It's not going to behave nicely.
So what is this look like in a real picture?
So here we have our pepper image.
So here is the salt and pepper version of it.
Again, different peppers.
And here it is with the median applied.
If you zoom on that you'll see that that's a really well cleaned up image.
And you can see,
this was a scan line, the plot of a single row across the image.
And you can see all the salt and no pepper noise.
And when I replace that with the median, I get a much nicer signal over here.
And that's why median filtering works so much better for salt and pepper noise.
So I'm showing you this because the median is really an example of
a non-linear thing.
It's also sometimes refered to as edge preserving.
And the reason for that is shown on this simple drawing here.
Suppose I have, I've got a signal that's supposed to be like this but
there was a single spike added to that.
If I take the median, I get this nice effect.
This thing comes here, this, et cetera.
If I were to take the mean or the average or a blur.
I would tend to blur across that nice sharp edge and
that's why median filtering is referred to as edge preserving.
And so this is class of nonlinear filters that are useful but
they're a little less well behaved in terms of the mathematics.