So that ends our conversation about lightness constancy.
The, as I said, the, the truth is our computational methods are still
not really adequate in this space.
It could be it hasn't received enough attention to think of it from recovering
each element.
It's received, actually, more attention in the computational photography domain.
And I think if you take Professor Irfan Essa's class in
computational photography, which I highly recommend,
I think we spend a lot of time talking about that there are a lot of algorithms
related to computational photography that are connected to computer vision.
And this is an area where this lightness and
color constancy is an area where we need more work.
So the good news is there's plenty of research in computer vision to be done.
So hurry up and go get your degree and come join us in the field.