Inside the module, you'll find
a vector class with three functions,
init, str, and eq.
I will give a brief description
of these functions in case you're
not familiar with Python.
In that case, I also encourage you
to make use of some of the resources
in the instructor notes on this page.
The initializer creates a vector based
on an input list of coordinates, and
also sets the dimension of
space that the vector lives in.
For example, if we wanted to create the
vector 1, 2, 3, we could write my_vector
= Vector([1,2,3]).
Then, my vector would be a variable
referring to the vector that we want.
The str function gives us the ability to
print out the coordinates of the vector
using Python's built in print function.
Using our example,
if we input print my_vector,
we would receive the output Vector: (1,
2, 3).
The eq function gives us the ability
to test whether two vectors are equal.
As I mentioned earlier,
two vectors are equal if
they have the same amount of change
in each coordinate direction.
Therefore, since we are storing
vectors using their coordinates,
we just need to compare
two vectors' coordinates.
To see how this works in Python, we can
input my vector2 = Vector ([1,2,3]) and
my vector3 = Vector ([-1,2,3]).
Then if we input print my vector ==
my_vector2, we'll
receive the output True,
since all coordinates of my
vector in my_vector2 match.
On the other hand, if we input
print my_vector == my_vector3,
we'll receive the output False,
because the two vectors have
different first coordinates.
Now, let's start defining some
basic operations on vectors.