All right, let's look at the solution
to systems with no solutions.
Let's go through each of the statements.
For the first statement,
the planes defined by the equations do
not have a common intersection point.
In fact, this is more or
less the definition of what it means for
a system not to have a solution since.
A solution to a system is
a common intersection point
of the planes defined by each equation.
Second, there are more than three
planes or equations in the system.
It may be tempting to select this as
a criterion for having no solutions,
especially if you are familiar with
overdetermined systems of equations.
However, there are instances of systems
with more than four
planes having a solution.
Take a look at this system,
x + y = 1, y + z = 0,
z = negative 1, and x + 3y + 2z = 1.
The first three lines of this system
actually have a unique solution,
0, 1, negative 1.
The last plane also contains
the point 0, 1, negative 1.
In fact, this last equation is just
equation 1 plus two times equation 2.
So even if a system of planes
has more than three equations,
it's still not enough to
show that it's inconsistent.
But is it necessary for
a system to have more than three
planes in order to be inconsistent?
No, you can have inconsistent
systems of planes with three or
even just two equations.
Here's an example, x + y + z = 0,
and x + y + z = 1.
These two planes are parallel since
they have the same coefficients in front
of their variables, but
they aren't the same plane since
they have different constant terms.
Therefore, they don't intersect,
so this system is inconsistent.
Third, we encounter an equation
of the form 0 = k, for
some nonzero number k while
doing Gaussian elimination.
This condition is both necessary and
sufficient.
If we encounter a contradiction like
this while going through the elimination
procedure, then we know that the initial
system could not have had a solution.
Conversely, if we don't encounter
a contradiction like this,
then we always end up with
the solution of some form,
though it may be a parameterization
of an infinite set of solutions.