In this task we're going to make
changes to the code Jake just wrote.
So you want to get your
project into the same shape.
You can run get reset hard to
remove any local changes you have.
Then run get checkout task IDP people,
to get the project into
the same shape as Jake's.
Once again,
we're editing the IDB script so
head over to public/js/idbtest/index.js.
We just saw Jake creating an index
to sort people by favorite animal.
But your job is to create an index
where they're ordered by age.
So in the upgrade function,
you'll need to create your index.
Then at the bottom of the script,
write some code to log out
all the people in that order.
Once you're done, refresh the browser.
You should see the names
log out in order.
You can also confirm in dev tools.
To double check everything is working,
head to the settings page and
type IDB age into the test
field then press enter.