So to review, Translation and rotation.
From frame A to B.
To express this in the non-homogeneous or regular coordinates.
We take the location of some point p in the A frame, we rotate it and
then we translate it.
In, in Homogeneous coordinates, we write it as this single matrix.
Where the matrix has the rotation matrix in it in the top left and
the translation vector located here in the right-hand column.
And the key is that homogenous coordinates allow us to
write this coordinate transforms as a single matrix, but
I said that four times already, so you're saying like get on with it already.
So, now finally, we can talk about going from World to Camera frame.
Here's our equation, using sort of non-homogeneous regular coordinates.
Where the idea is, if we have some point p in the world, so
it's a point location in the world frame, we have to rotate it,
orient it with, to know which way it would be oriented in the camera frame, and
then we have the translation from the World to Camera frame, okay?
So, we have this sort of ugly equation that would get us from a point in
the world to a point in the camera so that p in the C frame,
that's now the point in the camera frame.
In homogeneous coordinates, it's just expressed like this.
The top left three by three is the coordinate,
the right-hand column is the translation.
And that whole four by four is referred to as
the extrinsic parameter matrix, okay?
This is the thing that transforms a point in
the world to a point in the camera frame.
By the way, that bottom row is not so important unless we're doing inverses,
that bottom row is what makes this equation invertible.
So when sometimes we're doing projections we're going to use the three by four
instead of the four by four, but don't worry about that till the next lecture