The recycler view is set up so
that a single adapter can
drive multiple recycler views.
To add back end support for
click handling and
empty views, we're going to give the
recycler view adapter knowledge of our
particular recycler view, which does
kind of break the standard model.
But it's alright,
because we're not going to
be driving multiple recycler
views to our single adapter.
So we're going to add
back click handling and
empty view into forecast fragment.
In forecast adapter, we're going to
create a forecast adapter on click
handler that returns a date long,
and a ForecastAdapter ViewHolder.
And then we're going to add
a ForecastAdapteronClickHandler
member variable.
We're going to update the
ForecastAdapter constructor to have it
take the ForecastAdapteronClickHandler
and empty view.
Then we'll have
ForecastAdapterviewHolder implement
a view.OnClickListener.
And when you construct a viewHolder,
set the viewHolder to be
the OnClickListener for the view.
So, does that make sense?
You basically pass in the view to
the ViewHolder when you construct it.
You have the ViewHolder
implement OnClickListener and
then, you actually set that viewHolder
to be the OnClickListener for
the view at that time of construction.
Then, you call the ForecastAdapter
OnClickListener from your
individual ViewHolder OnClickListener.
If you have any questions,
I'm sure we'll have some
great instructor notes here.
Set the visibility of the empty view
In SwapCursor based upon the item count.
So this is pretty simple,
we're going to put back in empty
view handling which is awesome.
And then in the ForecastFragment,
we're going to add back in empty
view and onClick handling.
When I say in ForecastFragment, add
back in empty view and onClick handling,
what I mean is we commented a whole
bunch of code out in ForecastFragment.
We're going to un-comment that, and then
we're going to connect it up to these
new mechanisms we've built to handle
empty view and onClick handling.