Reflecting back on my own experiences,
I never fully understood
content providers until I
had to actually build one.
When I was on the contacts team,
I used a content provider,
but I didn't understand
the inner workings of it.
It was this unknown beast that
other engineers got to deal with.
When I became the tech lead of the
Google Keep app, which the note taking
app, we had to build the app from
scratch, including the content provider.
We face some really challenging
decisions in early days
about how to model data.
We knew we wanted to have a database so
that's we could easily search notes, but
there was still a lot of
details about the database and
the content provider that
we had to figure out.
We did some investigative work.
Talking to other app teams like Gmail,
calendar, music apps and
we also looks at their
code basis as well.
And even though we got
advice from these engineers
I still felt like I had
analysis paralysis.
I couldn't make decision on which way
we should go because I wasn't sure,
you know, if we met regret later or
in my influence.
It might limit us from extending
to other features in the future.
Ultimately, though I had to realize that
every decision we make will have trade
offs and you just have to make the best
decision you can with the data you have
available and know that in the future
you could always refactor the code.
So we buckled down, made some decisions,
built the content provider and
we also wrote a lot
of unit tests to make
sure that the provider was working
in the way that we expected.
Once the provider was solid, then we
could move on to other challenges, like
syncing notes across devices, and so
that it would appear on the Web as well.
And as we added all those features,
the team naturally grew, and
I had to work on my leadership and
mentoring skills,
and there are also many more technical
decisions that I had to make.
One last stop before I close is when
we were first creating the nano degree,
I asked a lot of my coworkers, what are
the qualities of the best engineers that
you've worked with because we
want to teach those to our students.
And one answer I really love is when
someone said the best engineers
are fearless.
They're not afraid to tackle
a problem that seems impossible and
where they don't know if they're
going to succeed or fail.
Because I think that's how amazing
products and experiences get created.
You don't have to have all
the technical knowledge on android, but
the attitude that you carry
can bring you very far.