I think that is the most important
question of an interview,
any good interview so
you can examine how they dealt with a
project from beginning to start, right?
So you want to to see how they are
proficient what is the problem how can
they describe a problem,
is very important, right?
And then how they approach
to actually solving it and
what things they consider
while solving it.
Then you also want to make sure they use
some tools that are their standard for
the industry.
I think it's the most
important question and for
anybody that is going to be going into
an interview they should always be
prepared to answer that question.
I think she did an excellent job in
describing the problem in saying and
explaining the interface and
you have for the project.
I think she could have explain a little
bit more the technical side, so
separated the problem from the solution
from the learning a little bit more so
that I could understand
a little bit better.
But overall I think
the candidate did very well.