In the documentation for
the GraphDefinedDomain class, we can see
that it has only one constructor,
which takes as an argument a single int.
This int is the number of states
that the domain should have.
Since we have already defined and
initialized the variable numStates to
be 6, we could either pass
the variable num_States or
the number 6 to the constructor.
Though it would probably be
better to pass numStates, so
we don't have a magic
number in our code.
Also, looking through the list
of methods available to
a GraphDefinedDomain object,
we can find the method, generateDomain,
which takes no arguments and
outputs a Domain object.
This Domain object will have six states
since we specified this in creating
the generator object.
I'll go ahead and fill in
the second blank with this method.
Note that we could create a second
domain by calling the generateDomain
function a second time.
This second domain would be functionally
separate from the original domain
object, but they would have the same
initial structure as defined
by the specifications given to
the GraphDefinedDomain object.
Essentially a GraphDefinedDomain
acts like a blueprint for
the domain objects it generates.
However, since we won't be needing
tow different domain objects for
this project, I'll go ahead and
delete the object I just added.