So, first things first.
You'll need to create a new app and
set it up in the same ways
you set up the last app.
That means you'll need to go
through these steps again.
So first, you'll create a new
app with a single view.
Then, you'll add the services
libraries to Build.gradle.
Then, you'll edit your Android.manifest
by putting the services libraries,
the open GL stuff, the API key, and
the internet, network state, and
write external storage permissions.
Check that you've done each of these,
and if you need to review how to do
this, refer to the answer video for
creating and configuring the app earlier
in the lesson,
where we showed a simple fragment.
When you're done with all of that,
check this box to continue.