I want to talk just a little bit about two of these other constraints that we
talked about for the correspondence problem.
And I can talk a lot about them, just give you some insight.
One is uniqueness and the other is ordering.
So, uniqueness says that there's no more than one match in the right image for
every point in the left and vice versa.
Same thing.
Okay?
So why does it say no more than one?
Shouldn't it be exactly one?
Well, no.
The problem is occlusion.
And that's illustrated here.
Let's suppose I have a green bar in front of a red bar.
All right.
So.
Here's my left image and here's my right image, and
these are the pixels being seen in my left image and
these are the pixels being seen in my right image, all right.
You'll notice, I have two red ones here, then two green and
a red, and here I have a red, two green, and two red.
And the problem is that these pixels are occluded.
And what we mean by occluded is that they're only visible, sometimes they're
called half occluded, because this pixel is only visible in the left image.
And this pixel is only visible in the right image.
Right there.
Okay.
This happens at occlusion edges.
So, if I hold it like this.
So, if Megan, if I asked Megan to close her left eye,
your other left she can see, she can't see this thing with her left eye.
But if I asked her to change her other one, she can see it with the right eye.
So, the, the tip of this finger is only visible in, in one of her eyes.
So, that's, that's why you don't have necessarily a unique
solution that every pixel is matched in every in every frame.