Sorting through command line output like this, will get boring really quickly.
So I've created a visualization that we will use throughout the course.
We'll launch this with the following commands, but what I recommend is to have
one tab open, where we will compile and package our Storm program in Maven, and
run using the Storm submission process I just showed you.
I recommend you create on your local machine, and
depending on your operating system this can either be a new window,
where you launch a new batch shell, or simply a new tab on your terminal.
I've created three new tabs here.
But here we see the tab in real time, this is in my local machine and
if I type ls I can see that here is ud381, cd into ud381.
And now instead of vagrant up, we simply log into the machine using vagrant ssh.
So now you see I have one tab open with our mvn storm commands, and
one tab open that I'll be using for our visualization.
In step one of the written direction, simply cd into /vagrant/viz and
ls and you'll see the Python program, app.py, along with the static and template
folders that, if you follow the optional exercise, you put your picture into.
In step two, launch your Flask microserver by typing python app.py.
Python app.py and hit Enter.
Here we see that our flat server is running on an IP address of 0.0.0.0:5000,
which simply means that it's running on our local machine on port 5000.
In step three of the written instructions, open a new tab in your web browser,
either Chrome, Firefox, or Internet Explorer, type
in the following address, or simply cut and paste.
It's http://127.0.0.1:5000.
I'm just going to copy and paste this.
Copy, paste.
And once I hit Enter,
I'm now communication with our virtual machine through port 5000.
And you should see the visualization, Udacity and
Twitter bring you real time analytics with Storm.
Along with the Udacity and Twitter logo.
Next, if I look back to our flash server, we see that we
have a GET request that just came in for channel, WordCountTopology.
One note here is that if you're having problems making that connection,
that's okay.
And we do have a troubleshooting section at the end of this lesson,
that can review a few of the common troubleshooting solutions.
Finally for an optional personalization exercise this requires your photo or
icon to be located in the folder /vagrant/viz/static.
And remember this was the optional exercise to a previous lesson.
So in step one of the optional exercise open your text editor, and again I'm
using Atom in your text editor, and if you're using Atom click Open and click.
On the top level file, ud381, not any of the individual files, but
on the top level and click Open.
And you should see the file hierarchy appear on the left-hand side like so.
Once you have the top folder open in your text editor, navigate to.
Your vis templates section.
So we go to vis templates and open the file cloud.html.
So cloud html.
This is our basic html file for our visualization.
We see that the Udacity logo, and
Twitter logo, are defined right here in the body h1 tag.
To add our image, we simply copy and
paste the Twitter logo, and change the name to the picture that you defined.
Mine was LouisAtUdacity.jpg.
Let's personalize the page further, by coming to the Word Cloud
exclamation points, and just naming it with your name.
So I'll say Louis's Word Cloud.
Next, navigate to your visualization, and simply hit the refresh button.
And you should see your picture, and your name with your word cloud appear.
So congratulations, on personalizing your visualization.
And as we go through the course, you can take screenshots of
your visualization and post them to the forum, and we'll know it's you.
Great job.