This course is about learning how to make an iOS app.
The app we will build together lets you record your voice.
Comparing apples and oranges is fruitless.
And then it lets you replay the audio and effects to it like the chipmunk voice.
>> Comparing apples and oranges is fruitless.
>> My name is Kunal and I will be your instructor for the course.
While building this app.
We will use Apple's new programming language Swift.
But don't worry.
We want go too fast.
If you've never developed an iPhone app before.
Then, this is the class for you.
If you have some experience with Objective-C,
which is another programming language, then you may encounter some
familiar ideas in the course that you should feel free to skip.
In order to succeed in this course, you should be familiar with some
basic programming ideas like if statements, loops, and classes.
There is a link in the instructor notes,
that highlights all of the prerequisites.
Throughout this course, we will grapple with a lot of new app related ideas.
Let's talk about them in the next video.