Now our boss wants us to
know which customer segment
makes up the most of
our Denver customers.
We can do this easily by summarizing our
data on the Customer Segment field and
counting up the records in each segment.
To do this, we'll use the Summarize tool
and drop it next to the Filter tool.
Then we'll click on the Customer Segment
field &gt; Add &gt; Group Buy.
Now, the data will be
grouped by segment.
Next, to count up the records,
we'll go back to Add, select Count,
then, we'll run the work flow again.
The results shows us
four customer segment
types with the number of
customers in each segment.
While it's pretty easy to see
the segment that contains the most
customers, imagine this list
had 10,000 records in it.
The way to find the top
segment by counts of customers
would be to sort the data.
To do that, let's grab the Sort tool
next, attach it to the Summarize tool.
Then we'll select the Count
field under name, and
set the order to be descending.
When we run the workflow again,
we can see that the customer segment,
corporate, has the most customers
at has the most customers at 390.