Now we weren't very strict
in grading this question
because there's technically no right or
wrong answer for which order
you should write your code in.
And since there's a dependency
on our designer for
these images,
it can affect our schedule as well.
However here's one approach
that we recommend.
So let's modify the list
item layout in step 1.
For now we can use
a placeholder image here
until we get the final images we need.
Even with that,
we should still be able to run
the app after making this XML change.
Now deciding what the next step
should be is a little bit harder
because changing one thing could cause
a ripple effect in other places.
You could have several
different answers here.
But in the best case, if the designer
has those images ready, we can add
them into the app in step 2 then we can
start referring to the correct images.
So we can modify each word in the list
of words to refer to the correct images
for step 3.
So lastly we should make
sure that the WordAdapter
creates proper list item views
to reflect each word object.
So this means that
within the WordAdapter
we need to modify the instructions on
how to create a proper list item view.
So these instructions should
include setting the correct image
onto the image view in
the list item layout.
Now if you didn't receive the images
from the designer until later,
you could have used placeholder
images up until the very end.
And then go back and
incorporate the actual images.
So if your ordering
reflected that situation,
that's an acceptable answer as well.