So a really important example
of machine learning is SPAM detection.
We all get way too much email
and a good number of those are SPAM.
Here are 3 examples of email.
Dear Sir: First I must solicit your confidence
in this transaction, this is by virtue of its nature
being utterly confidential and top secret...
This is likely SPAM.
Here's another one.
In upper caps.
99 MILLION EMAIL ADDRESSES FOR ONLY $99
This is very likely SPAM.
And here's another one.
Oh, I know it's blatantly OT
but I'm beginning to go insane.
Had an old Dell Dimension XPS sitting in the corner
and decided to put it to use.
And so on and so on.
Now this is likely not SPAM.
How can a computer program
distinguish between SPAM and not SPAM?
Let's use this as an example
to talk about machine learning for discrimination
using Bayes Networks.
In SPAM detection
we get an email
and we wish to categorize it
either as SPAM
in which case we don't even show it to the reader
or what we call HAM
which is the technical word for
an email worth passing on to the person being emailed.
So the function over here
is the function we're trying to learn.
Most SPAM filters use human input.
When you go through email
you have a button called IS SPAM
which allows you as a user to flag SPAM
and occasionally you will say an email is SPAM.
If you look at this
you have a typical supervised machine learning situation
where the input is an email
and the output is whether you flag it as SPAM
or if we don't flag it
we just think it's HAM.
Now to make this amenable to
a machine learning algorithm
we have to talk about how to represent emails.
They're all using different words and different characters
and they might have different graphics included.
Let's pick a representation that's easy to process.
And this representation is often called
Bag of Words.
Bag of Words is a representation
of a document
that just counts the frequency
of words.
If an email were to say Hello
I will say Hello.
The Bag of Words representation
is the following.
2-1-1-1
for the dictionary
that contains the 4 words
Hello I will say.
Now look at the subtlety here.
Rather than representing each individual word
we have a count of each word
and the count is oblivious
to the order in which the words were stated.
A Bag of Words representation
relative to a fixed dictionary
represents the counts of each word
relative to the words in the dictionary.
If you were to use a different dictionary
like hello and good-bye
our counts would be
2 and 0.
However, in most cases
you make sure that all the words found
in messages
are actually included in the dictionary.
So the dictionary might be very, very large.
Let me make up an unofficial example
of a few SPAM and a few HAM messages.
Offer is secret.
Click secret link.
Secret sports link.
Obviously those are contrived
and I tried to retain the recovery
to a small number of words
to make this example workable.
In practice we need thousands
of such messages
to get good information.
Play sports today.
Went play sports.
Secret sports event.
Sport is today.
Sport costs money.
My first quiz is
What is the size of the vocabulary
that contains all words in these messages?
Please enter the value in this box over here.