Let's talk about now a specific mathematical model of body reflection.
Remember before we said it comes in,
bounces around a little bit, and then scatters out.
Okay? So, the model we're going to talk about is called Lambertian model, or a,
it's a Lambertian BRDF, but
we'll just think of it as being a Lambertian, all right?
And we're only going to talk about the body reflection part.
And Lambert's law, Lambert being the guy who did this.
The sort of folksy way of thinking about it is, that no matter how I look at it,
no matter what direction of reflectance that I have,
it looks to be the same brightness.
That is the only thing that's going to impact this, is the incidence component
of the light, not you know, the more perpendicular the surface is
to the light source, remember the radiance and air radiance thing, right?
It gets more of the light and therefore the brightness will only be
effected by the angle between the lig, the surface and the light source.
Now, most people, not most people,
some people will then show you a picture that looks like this.
And by the way, if the person who made this picture is listening,
I'm not saying that you didn't understand what happened.
I'm just going to say that most people when they see this picture
think the following, which is not true.
Okay?
What they think is that, you know,
depending on the light source coming in, you know,
the more, the more perpendicular it is, the more light you have reflecting out.
That is true, but what's drawn here is that the amount of
light coming out is the same in all directions.
That is just not true.
Okay?
By the way, I want to thank Berthold Torn,
who by the way invented the shape from shading problems and
most other computer vision problems way back in like the 70s and
80s, because I took my first computer vision course and he made a big deal.
And you see that Berthold, I was paying attention.