Now we're going to add a second
View Controller to our app. Adding another
screen and View Controller to manage
that screen is just what we need to turn
Pitch Perfect into the app that we want.
With the library panel open in the
bottom right hand corner, we need to find
a View Controller, so that we can drag it
onto the screen. Let's give ourself some
space and then drag the View Controller
onto the storyboard like this.
You may want to position it as I've done
here to the right of our View Controller
for recording. Also, let's use our old
trick of changing the background color
of this new View Controller, so that it's
something other than white and we can
distinguish it from our View Controller
for recording. So I’ll select the View
and I'll go with this light blue color.
You can set the color to whatever you like,
just something other than white.
For now what I want to do is connect that
transition to the stop recording button.
This will cause the after transition to
the second View Controller whenever the
user taps the stop button. First select
the Stop Recording Button in the
document outline, then hold control and
click and drag to the new View
Controller. You can either drag to the
View Controller here in the document
outline or you can drag to the View
Controller over in the main editing area
for storyboard. When the pop-up appears
for the Action Segue, select Show.
You'll now see this new symbol and arrow
connecting the two View Controllers.
This is called a Segue. Remember that we
previously wired up the Stop Recording
Button to stopRecording function
via an IBAction.
This means the Stop Recording Button is
now doing two things. First it's going to
call our code in our View Controller for
the stopRecording function, and now it's
also going to cause this Segue to occur,
that moves us to the next View Controller.
Now you may be thinking to yourself,
wait a minute, where's the code
for this new View Controller? We never
created any class. Well you're correct,
storyboard is just using a default
UIViewController right now. It's not a
subclass that you've written, it's just a
plain old View Controller with a plain
old UIView, where we change the
background color. Let's run the app and
see what happens.
If we click to record and then click to
stop the recording, we can see the
UINavigationController has transitioned
us to the second View Controller.
Also take a moment to notice this bar at the top.
It's called the navigation bar and
it has a Back button. This is the default
back button that will return you to the
previous View Controller. it's sort of a
breadcrumb if you will. If we click it, we
go back to our initial View Controller.
we've just scratched the surface of the
UINavigationController, because that's
all we need for now in order to continue
building the Pitch Perfect app. In UIKit
fundamentals, you're going to learn about
UINavigationControllers in much
further detail.