Wait a second,
why do we need probabilities?
I guess it makes sense for prediction,
because we don't what the value of x is
at time t since we only have
information until time t minus 1.
But what about correction?
We know what the measurement
is at time t.
Why can we not get
a definitive value for Xt?
Why is this a probability distribution?
Is it because the state end
measurement are different quantities?
Like in our pendulum example,
where we said the state could be just
the angle theta and the observation
was the location of the target.
Or could it be that observation
values are unreliable
due to underlying sensor noise or
even imperfect detection algorithms?
What if observations are missing or
beyond known limits?
Is that a good reason to model state
as a probability distribution?