Android automatically detects
when input devices are attached.
This means that when a player connects
the remote controller game controller
Android begins reporting its
input events to the active view.
And whether controllers happen
to be connected physically or
via Bluetooth doesn't matter,
that's handled by the system.
There are two types of input
events you should be aware of.
Key events are triggered
by button presses.
And this is important.
Note that the movement of
a D-Pad is a button press.
Such as up down left or right.
Likewise the deep pad
it has a center button.
And if you press it guess
what you get a key event.
Next up are motion events.
These are triggered by
joystick movements.
Both of these are subclasses
of input event so
they have some common functionality.
Every input device has a device
idea associated with it.
You can get this by calling
the get device ID method.
This is really simple, but
it will become important later.
In multiplayer games,
you can use the device ID to map which
controller belongs to which player.
To find out which button
press triggered a key event,
retrieve the key code by
calling get key code.
A key code is a constant integer that
indicates which button was pressed.
Keep in mind it's a constant
not the Unicode character that
corresponds to the key.
The most important key codes
are listed here on this diagram and
you can find a complete list by
following the link in the notes.
For example, when the user presses
the B button, the key code will be,
you guessed it, Button B.
And by the way, Axis_ Hat refers
to the D-Pad on a game controller.
Whereas Dpad_Up and Dpad_Down refer
to the Dpad on a remote control.
We'll get to the codes that begin with
keyword Axis later, these are for
joysticks.
And by the way,
here's something I didn't know
when I started developing games.
Notice that we've two joysticks,
of course.
The Axis on the first
joystick are called X and Y.
The axes on the second
joystick are called Z and RZ.
To capture key events in your game,
override these callback
methods in the active view.
For convenience, the key code is
available directly from the parameter.
It's also available from the event.
You can also capture key
events from an activity,
and you can find out how to do
that in the instructor notes.
Next, notice these
events return a boolean.
Return true if you've
handled the event or
false if you like to give the parent
method a chance to handle it.
Conceptually you can think of input
events as working a little bit like
exceptions in Java.
They propagate up the stack
until the method handles them.
Let's see how this works in code.
I've just downloaded a controller sample
and imported it into Android studio.
The Asteroids game in this project
contains code that demonstrates
best practices for
handling input events.
The rest of the code
though is super hacky.
So consider anything that's not
demonstrating how to work with input
events and
input device events to be suspect.
Our game is divided into two packages.
One which contains the view in the game
logic, and another which makes it easier
to work with input events across
different Android versions.
For now let's just focus on
game view because that contains
all the logic we need
to handle key events.
There's a lot of coding game view,
but the basic design is pretty simple.
Here it is to make it clear.
First, when an input device is
connected, we'll retrieve the deviceId.
We'll will use this to create
a new ship for that player.
And we're going to cover exactly
how to do this later in the course.
The next step is going to be to
override the on key down and
on key up methods in our view,
as we saw earlier.
When a key event is received, the first
thing we'll do is get the deviceId, so
we know which player it's for.
Next will check the key code to
figure out which button was pressed.
And finally we'll update
that ships heading.
Let's see how this looks in code,
will start in a GameView class.
Here's the on key down
method that we overrode.
And here's where we get the device
ID from the input event.
Next we have some game logic that looks
up the ship that these device ideas
associated with.
It does this by maintaining
a mapping from device ID to Ship.
To handle the actual KeyEvent, this game
just passes it directly to the ship.
Before we look at that code, notice that
this method returns true if the event
was handled, and if not, returns
whether its parent handled the event.
Now let's check out the onKeyDown
method of the Ship class.
We use a switch statement to check for
different types of key codes.
And if we scroll down, we can take
a quick look at the isFireKey method.
And this is just showing a quick way of
checking for multiple key codes at once.
Not bad right?
Because Android automatically detects
when input devices are connected and
begins reporting their input
events to the active view,
all you need to do is override
a method and plug in a controller.
None of the other coding game view
is required to capture key events.
If you want here's
an optional exercise for you.
If you're an experienced
programmer this isn't necessary.
But if it's your first time
dealing with key events
I'd recommend you knock it out.
Start a brand new Android TV project.
Create an activity containing a view.
And write code to log
which keys are pressed.
Refer to the developer training by
following the link in the instruction
notes if you get stuck.
And check out the solution
if you'd like.