There are two correct answers.
100 of those players
leave after 24 hours, and
40 of those players stay after one week.
First, let's review the 40-20-10 rule.
We measure good retention to be at
least 40% after the first 24 hours,
20% after a week, and 10% after a month.
For this first answer, if 100 out
of 200 players leave after a day,
you still have retained 50% of
your players after day one.
And this is higher than
the 40% in our 40-20-10 rule.
But for this answer, if only 70 of
our players stay after one day,
this is only 35% retention, and that's
too low for our first day measurement.
If 40 out of 200 stay after a week,
that's the same as 20 out of 100,
or 20% retention,
which matches our rule for a week.
In this last answer, we have 100
new players joining later on.
And this gives us no information about
the retention of the 200 players
we were originally interested in.