In this case the correct answer is B but
let's see why.
FirebaseListAdapter and
FirebaseArray are providing the logic
to receive events from the database.
Answer A doesn't make any sense.
The FirebaseArray is stored at
a variable called M snapshots
within the FirebaseListAdapter.
As such, it's encapsulated within
the FirebaseListAdapter and there are no
methods in FirebaseListAdapter that
allow you to write to its contents.
So you or
your app's code cannot actually change
anything in FirebaseArray directly.
Because of that, you manually removing
ShoppingLIst from FirebaseArray is just
something you can't do.
C is incorrect for a similar reason.
Again you can't manually remove
things from the FirebaseArray.
Now the FirebaseArray does have a bunch
of on child listener methods and
this is because it implements
the child event listener interface.
Which reactively changes
the underlying array when the Firebase
database changes.
Which is what this could
connection here is showing.
So, if you were to manually remove
the shopping list from the Firebase
database, that removal is automatically
pushed to the Firebase array.
Now Inter d is just a little bit funky.
While Firebase does make
a lot of stuff happen for
you automatically, If you want something
to be removed from the database,
you can't just sit around
hoping that it'll happen.
If you're using your app,
and let's say J.P.
deletes something, it could seem like
magic that both your database data and
your Firebase list adapter just so
happen to update.
But ultimately somebody,
somewhere is using the app to manually
make a change to the Firebase database.
So D really isn't a correct answer.