an understanding of the data combined
with the business issue understanding
will help you as you prepare the data
for analysis which is the third step of
the problem solving framework when
starting analysis
it's a rare occasion for the data to be
ready without some level of preparation
preparing the data generally includes
one or more of the following actions
gathering cleansing formatting blending
and sampling the data when gathering the
data you may need to collect data from
multiple sources within your
organization the data set you are
working with may have issues that you
want to resolve prior to analysis
this can be in the form of incorrect or
missing data you may need to format the
data by changing the way a date field
appears renaming a field or even
rotating the data similar to using a
pivot table
you may want to blend or combine your
data with other data sets to enrich it
with additional variables similar to
using the vlookup function in Excel and
lastly you may want to sample the data
set and work with a more manageable
number of Records referring back to our
electricity example we identified that
we may need to obtain some data from the
national weather service to get forecast
high and low temperatures as well as
historical temperature data the data we
obtain may not be in a usable format so
we may need to prepare the data for
analysis by formatting enriching and
cleansing the data will also gather data
from our internal systems such as past
electricity usage as well as any other
data we may have that may prove useful
to our analysis
Maureen Wolfson has dedicated an entire
course of preparing your data for
analysis and we'll go into detail about
the data preparation step