Welcome back introduction computer vision.
Today, we're going to be talking about intrinsic camera calibration.
Last time, we said, that we're going to do geometric calibration in general, and
that there were two parts to calibration.
The first transformation is from some arbitrary world coordinate system,
to the camera system or the camera pose, and this was the extrinsic parameters,
and it mapped from, world coordinates to camera coordinates, or
camera coordinates to world, depending upon how you think about it.
When we write it as T, W, C, it takes you from the world, to the camera.
We expressed it in terms of homogeneous coordinates,
where we had a world coordinate p here expressed in that world coordinate frame,
and it was homogeneous so there's a one down there.
And we pump it through both the rotation component and the translation component
to get the three dimensional point in camera coordinates.
And, that world to camera matrix and codes what were referred to
as the extrinsic parameters or the extrinsic parameter matrix.
We also said that,
that encodes six degrees of freedom, three translation, three rotation.
Today, we're going to talk about the second transformation which goes from
the 3D camera coordinates to the 2D image coordinates or the 2D image plane.
And these are referred to as the intrinsic parameters, and
we'll again come up with the intrinsic parameter matrix.