The answers are P and not P is valid.
That is, it's true when P is true because of this, and it's true when P is false because of this clause.
P and not P is unsatisfiable.
A symbol can't be both true and false at the same time.
P or Q or P is equivalent to Q is valid.
So we know that it's true when either P or Q is true, so that's 3 out of the 4 cases.
In the fourth case, both P and Q are false, and that means P is equivalent to Q.
And therefore, in all 4 cases, it's true.
P implies Q or Q implies P, that's also valid.
Now in ordinary English that wouldn't be valid.
If the 2 clauses or the 2 symbols P and Q were irrelevant to each other we wouldn't say that either one of those was true.
But in logic, one or the other must be true, according to the definitions of the truth tables.
And finally, this one's more complicated,
if Food then Party or if Drinks then Party implies if Food and Drinks then Party.
You can work it all out and both sides of the main implication work out to be equivalent to Not Food or Not Drinks or Party.
So that's the same as saying P implies P, saying one side is equivalent to the other side.
And if they're equivalent, then the implication relation holds.