In this exercise, I'm going to write some logical expressions
in propositional logic and ask you
if these expressions are always true or always false
or if their truth value depends on the values of the propositional variables.
The first sentence is smoke implies fire
is equivalent to smoke or not fire.
Is that true or false, or does it depend on the values of smoke and fire?
The second sentence, again, smoke implies fire
is equivalent to not smoke implies not fire.
The third sentence, smoke implies fire
is equivalent to not fire implies not smoke.
The fourth sentence, big or dumb
or big implies dumb.
The final sentence, big and dumb
is equivalent to not, not big or not dumb.
For each of these, tell me if they're always true regardless of the values of the variables,
always false or sometimes true and sometimes false.