In the break point debugging scene,
we currently have way too
many spiders being created
when a user taps the screen.
But there's another more pressing
problem that I want you to solve using
break points.
If we tap the settings
icon from the main view,
we should be able to set the spider type
that we want to spawn on the screen.
However, if I tap any
of the spider icons or
even the back arrow here,
the settings view doesn't dismiss.
We're just stuck.
I want you to solve this
problem using breakpoints.
As you work through the problem,
write the steps that you take
to debug it in this text box.
And when you're done you can
compare your steps with mine.
Now while you may not go the same
way solving the problem that I did,
it's always really useful to
see other's perspectives for
solving the same problem.