If you took website
performance optimization,
then this website may
look a little familiar.
Inside the project for the course,
there's this pizza site
that has a lot of problems.
And I think it's fair to say that one of
the problems with this website is that
it will probably burn your eyes out, if
you spend too much time looking at it.
When you scroll down to this our pizza
section on the left side of the screen,
you'll notice this slider.
When you toggle the sliders,
the pizzas change size.
Now it doesn't look so
bad when you toggle back and
forth between the different sizes, but I
want to take a look at its performance.
You'll notice two things when
you open up the council.
The first is the average time
to generate the last ten frames,
which in this case is way too low for
a site that's a simple as this one.
The second thing you'll notice is
the amount of time it took to resize
the pizzas.
This number will be logged out anytime
somebody clicks on the slider over here.
Right now, it's displaying times
at around 100 milliseconds.
A good question to ask is is 100
milliseconds reasonable for this?
In fact, this resize time falls under
the response category of rails.
And that's because this is happening
as a response to a user action,
which includes clicking on the slider.
Resizing the pizzas probably falls
under the response category of rail,
which as you remember
is 100 milliseconds.
In that case, this app is actually
meeting the budget for response.
However, just given how
simple this site is.
There is no reason the resize pizza
action should be taking 100 milliseconds
where this happening in the Animation or
idle phases,
this would totally be
blowing the frame budget.
A recorded timeline to see if I can
find out a little bit more about
what's happening with the slider.
I will hit Record.
I will slide the pizzas and
I will stop recording.
This purple is a really bad sign.
Let me expand this into its own
window to take a closer look.
It looks like the slider
is calling a function and
then the function is causing a ton
of layouts one after another.
That is a major issue.
I'll click on one to get
a little bit more information and
in the details pane,
I see that there's a warning that says,
forced synchronous layout is
a possible performance bottleneck.
That is a problem.
So for this quiz, it's going to be
your job to download the pizza site,
find the cause of the sliders for
synchronous layout and then fix it.
Check this box to let us know
that the slider is no longer
creating a forced synchronous layout.