In order to propagate wins and losses
up the game tree to the point where our
computer player can make a decision, we
need to start at the bottom of the tree.
Let's start with the left
side of the tree.
In the left most branch, o wins.
The next branch over,
o never gets to use the last square
on the game board and loses.
Since our opponent x plays to win and
minimizes o's score, it will
never choose the leftmost branch.
Instead, it will choose this branch,
which is guaranteed to give
the computer player a score of -1.
However, our computer player
can avoid this situation
by making a wiser choice one level up.
Both branches of this tree lead
to victory and scores a +1.
We can keep propagating these scores
up the tree, alternating min and
max levels, until we arrive at the top.
This process of computing values for
each node,
bottom to top,
is known as the minimax algorithm.
For each max node, pick the maximum
value among its child nodes.
If there's at least one +1 child, the
computer can always pick that to win.
Otherwise, it can never win from that
point on assuming a perfect opponent.
Of course to represent the opponent at
each min node, we pick minimum value.