To illustrate the use of binding and
registries by applications when they
use RPCs, we will draw an analogy
with how toy shops rely on
directories of outsourcing services.
For instance, in a toy shop
when considering whether or
not to use some kind of outsourcing
service, the manager will want to know
who out there can provide
that particular service.
What are the specifics service details
that those outsourcing companies offer?
And exactly, what are the shipping or
packaging options they provide.
For instance, the toy shop
manager may consider looking at
the directories service to
find out what are the shops
where outsourcing of assembly
operations can be supported.
He will look up what
are the exact services that
each of these shops provide.
And for instance he's trying
to find the service where
the assembly of train
cars can be provided.
And then the manager may be interested
in exactly what are the shipping options
that they offer.
For instance,
whether they ship with UPS.
To give an analogous example in
the context of operating systems and
the applications use of binding and
registries in RPC.
Now we can see that the same types of
steps are required to be performed by
applications when they rely on
the RPC to execute some service.
For instance, they have to look
up the registry to find out
who can provide a particular service.
They can look up a registry with
a service name that requires specify
somehow some image processing.
The registry provides some detail
regarding the various services that
are provided by each server,
the version number.
All of this relays on the use of some
interface definition language so
that the interface can be
describe in some standard way.
And then finally, also the registry
will provide information regarding
the protocols that a particular server
or services support like TCP or UDP.
The applications can take all of
this information into consideration
when determining which
particular process to bind with,
which particular server to bind with.
And similarly in the toy shop, the toy
shop manager can consider the answers to
all of these questions when determining
how to outsource a service.