All right.
Let's try to do this in code.
I want you to write a function, find_best_match, that takes two arguments,
an image patch and a strip, which is basically the same height as the patch, but
has a width equal to that of the image.
Your function should return the x coordinate where the patch is
found in the strip.
Here is some test code.
Let's load up two images from a stereo pair, left and right.
This is a left image and here is the right one.
If I switch between the two, you can see some key elements moving.
All right, let's convert these to grayscale, double type, and
scale them down to 0, 1 range.
Here are the grayscale versions, left and right.
Okay, let's define the location and size for the patch we want to match.
Let us extract this from the left image.
Here's what the patch looks like.
Using the patch specifications, let's extract a strip from the right image.
Note that here,
since we want to go across the width of the image, we select all the columns.
And here's the strip from the right image.
Once you have implemented your function,
call it by passing in patch_left and strip_right.
You should be able to use the best x coordinate found to extract a patch from
the right image.
Go ahead and give it a shot.