Propositional logic. It's a powerful language for what it does.
And there are very efficient inference mechanisms for determining
validity and satisfiability, alhough we haven't discussed them.
But propositional logic has a few limitations.
First, it can only handle true and false values.
No capability to handle uncertainty like we did in probability theory.
And second, we can only talk about events that are true or false in the world.
We can't talk about objects that have properties,
such as size, weight, color, and so on.
Nor can we talk about the relations between objects.
And third, there are no shortcuts to succinctly talk about a lot of different things happening.
Say if we had a vacuum world with a thousand locations, and we wanted to say that every location is free of dirt.
We would need a conjunction of a thousand propositions.
There's no way to have a single sentence saying that all the locations are clean all at once.
So, we will next cover first-order logic which addresses these two limitations.