Inter-process communication refers
to a set of mechanisms that
the operating system must support
in order to permit multiple processes
to interact amongst each other.
That means to synchronize,
to coordinate,
to communicate all of those
aspects of interaction.
IPC mechanisms are broadly categorized
as message-based or memory-based.
Examples of message passing based
IPC mechanisms include sockets,
that most of you
are familiar with already,
as well as other OS supported constructs
like pipes or message queues.
The most common memory based mechanism
is for the operating system to provide
processes with access
to some shared memory.
This may be in the form of
completely unstructured set of
pages of physical memory or also may
be in the form of memory mapped files.
Speaking of files, these two could
be perceived as a method for
IPC, multiple processes read and
write from the same file.
We will talk about file
systems in a separate lecture.
Also, another mechanism that provides
higher-level semantics when it comes to
the IPC among processes is what's
referred to as remote procedure calls,
or RPC.
Here, by higher-level semantics,
we mean that it's a mechanism that
supports more than simply a channel for
two processes to coordinate or
communicate amongst each other.
Instead these methods prescribe some
additional detail on the protocols that
will be used,
how will the data be formatted,
how will the data be exchanged,
et cetera.
RPC too will be discussed in
a later lesson in this class.
Finally, communication and coordination
also implies synchronization.
When processes send and
receive to each other messages,
they in a way synchronize as well.
Similarly, when processes synchronize,
for instance,
using some mutex like data structure,
they also communicate something
about the point in their execution.
So from that perspective,
synchronization primitives also fall
under the category of IPC mechanisms.
However, we will spend a separate lesson
talking specifically
about synchronization.
For that reason this lesson will
focus on the first two bullets, and
we will talk about these
remaining topics later.