So now let's review something
we had looked at before.
We had started a lecture off talking
about that images best represented
in this coordinate frame, x and y,
but an object in the real world.
And I referred to them as capital X,
Y, and Z.
With Z is in the inside the camera
lens itself, that is the depth.
Y and X basically show the width and
the height of an object.
So if I had an object like this, I
actually would actually capture an image
and, of course,
the coordinate frame X and Y here.
We represented that scene in 3D
this way, where now basically,
I've turned it around.
Z is going in this direction.
Y and X are this way.
And of course, the same object is here,
shown by this arrow.
And here, I'm just giving it, you know,
values of X0, Y0, and Z0 in capitals.
Let's build this to kind of see what
the camera model would look like and
how we can compute depth.
These are the coordinate frames
in real-world coordinates.
Of course,
in a camera an image is formed.
Here I basically show this image and
the coordinates X and X and
Y, sub i for image.
Of course, this image is being
formed at focal length f.
And if you remember when we
looked at cameras we knew
did all of the calculations.
That is, the similar triangles
to figure out that xy,
xi over f is equal X0,
Z0, because you know,
focal length is this distance, and
these are two similar triangles.
And of course,
I want to be able to use this to compute
where the x would be in the image.
And this would be my equation,
similarly for y, Y sub i.
That is the pixel information.
In this image it's basically
related to both the focal length,
how far it is, and
knowing information like where the Z is,
how far away this object
is from the scene.
Notice, this information is not
contained in this image, that is,
where is Z.
And that's the point that we want to
actually now start thinking how to
actually compute.
So in essence, this equation would
apply the same if this point was here.
So this point here could
actually be at this location.
Same equations would apply.
Also if, I can basically find
any point in this line here,
which is the ray of light that's
going through this point.
So, the point I wanted to emphasize
here is there is a fundamental
ambiguity here.
That is, any point on this line
in the same ray maps to the same
point on the image plane, right?
Any point here, of course,
the values of Zs are different.
The values of X and Y are different.
But when it comes down to where there
are, that is x sub i and y sub i.
All of those values of
any point in this ray
of light is going to project
exactly to this point.
In essence, what that suggests is
I can actually scale any of these
three values, X naught, Y naught, or
Z naught for the world coordinates.
Basically that means put the same scale,
I mean, this, the same equation.
So in essence, that suggest is there is
a scaling factor here between both of
these images that will actually
produce the same x i, y i, and
actually make sense, right?
As I move closer,
the object is get, getting smaller.
And therefore,
this would be the scaling factor.
So, moving farther in, closer,
would be the scaling factor, and
of course, by multiplying and dividing
by the same k, we can see that impact.
So this is the ambiguity.
This is the one we want to resolve
in variety of different ways, and
that resolution of that ambiguity will
give us depth or structure of a scene.