So I just snuck one past you there.
Okay. We said the magnitude of the noise is determined by sigma.
Fine that's great.
In fact, we could just look at the noise function itself, right.
So don't add in the original image.
Just look at the noise function.
But we can't do that just yet until we make a decision, and the reason is this.
What's the mean of the noise.
Megan?
>> Zero.
>> Very good.
So that means some of the values are going to be what?
Positive, some of the values are going to be negative.
How do we look at a picture that has positives and negatives in it?
Right? If we said zero was black and
one was white, or zero was black and 255 was white, so how do we do this?
Well, the mistake is saying that zero is black.
Okay?
We're going to say, look, we'll map some minimum value to black,
some maximum value to white, and we'll distribute them in between.
In particular, zero should be what color?
What color do you think zero should be, between black and white?
What comes between black and white in the universe?
Grey. All right?
So let's suppose we have values that you know,
go from minus 20 to plus 20 in our image,
well we can make minus 20 black, plus 20 white and, and zero would be grey.
And if we did that, it would look like this.
So here we're showing you images of Gaussian noise.
Just the noise, So if there's a very small sigma, so
remember sigma's up here, so a very small sigma.
All right?
You can barely see that this is anything but a constant grey.
As we let sigma get bigger and bigger and bigger, you start to see more and
more speckle.
And that's the effect of sigma so
it's just a noise function being added to an image.