Congratulations!
You've reached the end of the course.
I hope you've had as much fun taking
this course as much as Paul and
I had making it.
>> For sure!
You've learned a load of tricks to get
your apps to run at 60 frames a second.
>> Share your stories about how you
made the app performant alongside your
fixes and successes in the forums,
on Twitter,
on Google+ or
whatever other social media you like.
Make sure, when you're
reading about other people's,
you apply the same approaches
to your own projects.
>> Yeah, profile sites in your apps,
figure out where your bottlenecks
are and stomp out that jank.
Basically, as always,
performance matters.