To edit the activity, there are a number
of steps you need to follow.
First of all,
the activity itself should implement
OnStreetViewPanoramaReadyCallback.
Once you've done that in
your OnCreate method,
you have to create
a StreetViewPanoramaFragment Object and
hook it up to the one you put
in the layout of the XML file.
Once you have this object,
call this method
getStreetViewPanoramaAsync(this) on it.
Next you have to create an override and
it's the override for
onStreetViewPanoramaReady.
And this is because you've implemented
the OnStreetViewPanoramaReadyCallback.
The onStreetView PanoramaReady
override takes a single parameter.
And this is the streetViewPanorama,
and you just give that an object.
For example,
you could just call it Panorama.
Then on this object, you call
.setPosition() for the location.
If you want to set it to
the Grand Canyon as I have done,
this is the latitude and
longitude of the Grand Canyon.
You then create a
StreetViewPanoramaCamera, which is very
similar to creating a Maps camera,
as you've done in previous modules.
Once you've done that,
on the panorama you called .animateTo,
the camera that you've just corrected,
and then the time in milliseconds.
And the camera will animate
to that latitude and
longitude as you've set it for
the location.
And you'll then see the Street View for
that.
This is all that we did to build
a Grand Canyon application,
just using this latitude and longitude.
See if you can go ahead and
implement this now for yourself.