There are a bunch of different
tables in our zoo database.
I'd like to just have the database tell
you about them, but weirdly enough,
there isn't one standard
way to do that in SQL.
If you want to know what
tables are in a database, or
what columns are in a table, well, each
database system supports doing that, but
they all do it in different ways.
And in most of them, you can't do
any of these from your code itself,
only from the database console, or
special administrative software.
Yeah, that kind of sucks.
It's as if SQL was designed back
in the days when you had to
plan out your whole
application with flowcharts and
stuff, before you were allowed to touch
a computer and ask it any questions.
Oh wait, it was.
So in order to save you a bunch of time
and frustration, I've put a list of
all the tables in our zoo database,
in the instructor notes below.
You might want to copy that, and
put it somewhere you can easily read it
while you do the rest of this lesson.