So an obvious question is
why are they doing it?
What's in it for them?
And I said what's in it for
them is that they monetize the data.
All right, this is like walking
into a bank and stealing cash.
They're able to do it online.
So one way that this works
is that you steal data,
you sell it to somebody who's
actually able to use it.
So if you're going to
sell it to somebody.
What kind of price does it fetch you?
So we have a couple of examples.
The security code that you
have on your credit card.
Credit card number or other information
that is stored in magnetic strip.
Paypal/eBay account.
Some health information about you now
that we have electronic medical records.
Think about how much would credit
card information sell for?
How much would an eBay account sell for?
Then we'll come back and
see what those numbers look like.