Now we want to find out if this is significant. Do we really have a better
chance of climbing Mount Shasta with Summit Up guide company? Just like with
all tests, we have a null hypothesis. If there's nothing special about this
guide company, Summit Up, meaning they have no effect on our likelihood of a
successful summit attempt. Then we would predict our chances of success to be
the same as that for the population. That means that our null hypothesis is
basically our expected frequency. We could turn this into percents as well. If
our null hypothesis were true and the guide company provides no added value to
our likelihood of success. Then we would expect a successful outcome about 33%
of the time and an unsuccessful outcome 67% of the time. Basically the null
hypothesis states that there is no difference from our known population. Before
we continue with our example, let's explore the null hypothesis a little more
because it changes depending on the situation. Let's say we're asking if people
prefer Coke or Pepsi. What do you think our null hypothesis would be? Type in
the percent for each.