So our signature, our name for
this function is r ordered.
It'll take an input, a vector, we'll
say type integer call it x and it will
return a Boolean value, representing
whether it's in reverse order or not.
And we'll call that Bool y.
>> So it's exactly the same
as what we had before,
except the name of
the function is different.
It's only when we get
to preconditions and
post conditions that we're going to
see a difference between them.
Okay, give a crack at
the precondition for this.
Okay, so for the precondition,
I fell like that one's the same.
I think-
>> You got it.
>> Okay.
>> This should be straightforward.
A precondition is going to be true, or
you can just leave out the precondition.