In this lesson, you'll learn how to
use an ARIMA model, which stands for
Auto Regressive Integrated
Moving Average.
I know, it sounds intimidating, but
we'll take it step by step, and
by the end, you'll be a pro.
Your first step to becoming a pro will
be look at a process that transforms
a time series into
a more workable format.
Then we'll discuss each component
of the model in detail, and
finally, we'll go through the process
to build a model and make a forecast.
There are two types of ARIMA models,
non-seasonal and seasonal.
We'll first discuss
non seasonal ARIMA and
then move into seasonal ARIMA later on.
Non-seasonal ARIMA
models forecast future
points based upon the construction of
three components, an autoregressive, AR,
a differencing, I, and
a moving average, MA, component.