All right. So let's begin our trip down computer vision lane here.
So the first question you might ask is, what is computer vision?
>> What is computer vision?
>> See, I told you you were going to hear from Megan.
Well, there's a couple of ways of thinking about it.
I like this slide that I borrowed from Steve Seitz,
where he talks about every picture tells a story.
And one way of thinking about computer vision is the goal of
computer vision is to interpret images.
That is, say something about what's present in the scene or
what's actually going on.
So, what we're doing is, we're going to take images in,
and what's going to come out is something that has some meaning to it.
That is, we're going to extract,
we're going to create some sort of interpretations,
some sort of an understanding of what that image is representative of.
This is different, many of you may have some exposure to image processing,
which is the manipulation of images.
That's images in and images out.
And we'll talk a little bit about that because you use image processing for
per, for computer vision.
But fundamentally computer vision is about understanding something
that's in the image.