[Norvig] Another way to search is called backwards or regression search
in which we start at the goal.
So we take the description of the goal state.
C1 is at JFK and C2 is at SFO, so that's the goal state.
And notice that that's the complete goal state.
It's not that I left out all the other facts about the state;
it's that that's all that's known about the state is that these 2 propositions are true
and all the others can be anything you want.
And now we can start searching backwards.
We can say what actions would lead to that state.
Remember in problem solving we did have that option of searching backwards.
If there was a single goal state, we could say what other arcs are coming into that goal state.
But here, this goal state doesn't represent a single state;
it represents a whole family of states with different values for all the other variables.
And so we can't just look at that,
but what we can do is look at the definition of possible actions that will result in this goal.
So let's look at it one at a time.
Let's first look at what actions could result at C1, JFK.
We look at our action schema, and there's only 1 action schema that adds an At,
and that would be the Unload schema.
Unload of C, P, A adds C, A.
And so what we would know is if we want to achieve this,
then we would have to do an Unload where the C variable would have to be C1,
the P variable is still unknown--it could be any plane--
and the A variable has to be JFK.
Notice what we've done here.
We have this representation in terms of logical formula
that allows us to specify a goal as a set of many world states,
and we also can use that same representation to represent an arrow here
not as a single action but as a set of possible actions.
So this is representing all possible actions for any plane, P,
of unloading cargo at the destination.
And then we can regress this state over this operator
and now we have another representation of this state here.
But just as this state was uncertain--not all the variables were known--
this state too will be uncertain.
For example, we won't know anything about what plane, P, is involved,
and now we continue searching backwards until we get to a state
where enough of the variables are filled in and where we match against the initial state.
And then we have our solution.
We found it going backwards, but we can apply the solution going forwards.