Let's quickly talk about the high
level differences between mobile and
desktop VR.
First, mobile VR devices
are phone based.
They use their IMU for tracking.
Because of this, mobile VR only
has three degrees of freedom.
It can only track your head's
rotation but not its position.
Mobile VR is untethered,
this means that there's no wire
connecting to headset to a computer.
This is really nice because you
won't ever get tangled up in a cable
by using the headset.
Lastly, mobile VR less powerful
than Desktop VR in terms
of graphics performance.
It's small hardware
powered by a battery.
And so you have to optimize more
to make great looking mobile VR.
Let's contrast this with desktop VR.
On the desktop,
you get full 6DoF tracking.
Because the graphics processing is
happening on a desktop computer,
the headset is tethered.
This means a long cable runs
from the headset to your PC.
Also because a desktop computer
is running the VR software,
you have a lot of computing power.
This means that the VR simulations,
generally speaking,
can have higher visual quality.
And lastly, desktop VR also sometimes
has hand controllers, the Vive and
Oculus Touch are both examples of this.
So those are the major differences
between the current generation of mobile
and desktop VR systems.
Now let's talk about the different
types of VR development platforms.