The problem of minimizing quadratic loss for linear functions can be solved in closed form.
When I reduce, I will do this for the one-dimensional case on paper.
I will also give you the solution for the case where your input space is multidimensional,
which is often called "multivariant regression."
We seek to minimize a sum of a quadratic expression
where the target labels are subtracted with the output of our linear regression model
parameterized by w1 and w2.
The summation here is overall training examples,
and I leave the index of the summation out if not necessary.
The minimum of this is obtained where the derivative of this function equals zero.
Let's call this function "L."
For the partial derivative with respect to w0, we get this expression over here,
which we have to set to zero.
We can easily get rid of the -2 and transform this as follows:
Here M is the number of training examples.
This expression over here gives us w0 as a function of w1,
but we don't know w1. Let's do the same trick for w1
and set this to zero as well,
which gets us the expression over here.
We can now plug in the w0 over here into this expression over here
and obtain this expression over here,
which looks really involved but is relatively straightforward.
With a few steps of further calculation, which I'll spare you for now,
we get for w1 the following important formula:
This is the final quotient for w1,
where we take the number of training examples times of the sum of all xy
minus the sum of x times the sum of y divided by this expression over here.
Once we've computed w1,
we can go back to our original articulation of w0 over here
and plug w1 into w0 and obtain w0.
These are the two important formulas we can also find in the textbook.
I'd like to go back and use those formulas to calculate these two coefficients over here.
You get 4 times the sum of x and the sum of y, which is -32
minus the product of the sum of x, which is 18, and the sum of y, which is -6,
divided by the sum of x squared, which is 86, times 4, minus the sum of x squared,
which is 18 times 18, which is 324.
If you work this all out, it becomes -1, which is w1.
W0 is now obtained by completing the quarter times sum of all y,
which is -6, minus -1/4 times sum of all x.
If you plug this all in, you get 3, as over here. Our formula is actually correct.
Here is another quiz for linear regression. We have the follow data:
Here is the data plotted graphically.
I wonder what the best regression is.
Give me w0 and w1. Apply the formulas I just gave you.