Now that you've seen how to run the
sample, now's a good time for you go and
try it out for yourself.
The first thing I want
you to do is to build and
install the sample to your phone and
wearable.
Then, switch between the watch
faces I just demonstrated.
Finally, I want you to select
a sample digital watch face.
Then I want you to use
the configuration activity
to select the same colored background as
the text for the interactive watch face.
So the question is what happens when
the watch goes into ambient mode?
And note that if you're
using the simulator,
you can enter ambient mode by pressing
the power button emulator interface.