At the end of the last video,
we posed the question, can we predict the next time a person will tweet?
In order to make this question quantitative, we proposed two ways forward.
One was to use the quantity, the time of day.
The second was to use the quantity, number of seconds since the last tweet.
And we propose that using this quantity makes sense if we think about
the tweeting process as starting over each time some one makes a tweet.
Let's go ahead and add a Q note here, to signify our selection.
Now as far as our next step,
we know that our goal is to create a regression estimator of inter-tweet time.
Although as we know,
we can capture this quantity in another statistical inference problem.
For example, we could capture this as a hypothesis test or
also as a classifier, but our goal is to be bold and create an estimator.
I've tried to capture that here with the expression r of delta t.
So to make that more precise, I'm going to use the quantity,
time since the last tweet.
And let's abbreviate that as delta t.
And r of delta t is just time until next tweet.
The thing we're trying to predict.
So now that we've arrived at a statistical formulation of the problem,
the next step is to propose a model to represent this estimator.
But in order to do that,
we must understand what structure exists within the data.
To do that, let's examine a histogram of the inter-tweet times.
So to create a histogram of the inter-tweet times,
we first need to collect the values.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So in the first line here we're just using Pandas to read in the JSON data.
Let's go ahead and do that.
Then we're going to pull in the created at attribute for every row.
Now, for each tweet that we've collected, we're just going to
evaluate the difference between the times in which each tweet was created.
Okay, now we've got most of those values in the time until next list.
Now, Pandas has a very handy data type called a Series.
A Series wraps a list of values, and
provides a lot of handy functionality around that list.
For example, once you've got a list of values that has been wrapped in a series,
you can evaluate a histogram very easily.
Now that's very interesting.