An alternative to having all workers in the system perform the exact same task,
so all workers be equal, is to have different workers specialized for
different sets of tasks.
In the context of the toy shop example,
this may mean that we have workers specialized for different types of toys.
Or it could mean that we have workers specialized for repairs versus for
brand new orders, or
even we can specialize the workers to deal with different types of customers.
One added stipulation in this case is that now the boss has to
do a little bit of more work for each order.
Because in addition to just accepting the order it has to take a look at it, and
decide which set of workers it should actually be passed to.
Now the fact that the boss has to do a little bit of more work per
order is likely offset by the fact that each of the worker threads will now be
more efficient, because they're specialized for the task.
So overall we can achieve better performance.
The real benefit of this approach is that it exploits locality.
Each of the threads, by having to do a subset of the tasks,
it ends up probably accessing only a subset of the state, and
therefore that state is more likely present in the cache.
And we already talked about the benefits of having state present in cache.
It is much faster to access than if we have to go to memory.
Also, by being able to assign different workers to different types of tasks or
different types of customers, we can do better quality of service management.
So we can assign more threads to those tasks or
those customers that we need to give higher quality of service to.
This main challenge in this variant of the boss-workers model comes from
the fact that it is now much more complicated to do the load balancing.
How many threads should we assign for the different tasks?
This is not necessarily a question that has a unique answer regardless of
the amount of flow, the number of requests that are coming in the system,
the kind of hardware, so the kind of tools that these threads use.
So it ends up being a more complicated type of question.