What do you got?
>> So, I think the first one is a little
bit more obvious, or at least to me.
You can't check out a book
if it's already checked out,
it has to be availed to be check out.
>> Or it might be back, being rebound.
>> Sure.
>> Pages came loose and
they're being reglued or
something like that.
So it has to be available.
What else?
>> And then also, I could just imagine
a scenario that you walk up and you're
trying to check something out and they
say, well, you have some outstanding
fees that need to be paid before we
let you check out anything else.
>> So you run a tough library.
>> [LAUGH]
>> My library,
they say you want to pay
the $0.10 now or hold off on it?
And they make me pay it but
I can hold off on it.