Let's talk now about these
cases where there isn't a clear
distinction between servers and clients.
For instance if you look at all of the
big data applications that we hear about
today, the state of the application is
distributed and stored across all nodes.
The processors on these nodes
run certain applications such as
the analytics codes, the mining codes,
searching for patterns or searching in
order to answer your Google web search
request or some other applications.
And they access the state
that's distributed across
all the other nodes in the system.
The key about these applications
is that every node in the systems
owns some portion of the state.
By own here we mean that there is
some state that's locally stored in
a particular node or that's generated by
computation that's running on that node.
So the overall application
state is the union of
all of these pieces that
are present on every one node.
It's as if all the nodes
in the system are peers.
They all require accesses to
the state anywhere in the system and
they all provide access to
their local storage state
to any of their other
peers in the system.
For instance, think about the large
web search applications, like Google.
The state in that application,
which is the information about
every single webpage in the world,
is stored on many machines.
And at the same time,
it's also processed on all of them.
Whenever you type in a web search,
it may get processed on a different
processor in this distributed system,
but the statements required for
that web search,
regardless in which processor it hits,
may be somewhere on some
of the other nodes.
Applications like Facebook and
YouTube, also have state that includes
billions of images and videos.
In these images and
videos are a process to detect
certain objects to transform them
into different formats and sizes.
So there's some computation that's
performed on that distributed content.
The code that performs these
processing operations,
these transformations,
trans-coding of the videos or
the images, may run on different
nodes in the system, but
may potentially need to access state
that's distributed on other nodes.
These applications are examples
of applications where every node
is responsible for
managing the locally stored state and
providing access to
the locally stored state.
But also at the same times accessing
the state that's stored by
the remaining nodes in the system.
The reason I'm putting the term
peer here in quotation marks, and
not using a popular term that you may
have heard of, peer to peer systems,
is that in these kinds of distributed
applications it is still possible that
there will be some number of
designated nodes that will perform some
overall management and configuration
tasks for the entire system.
So, there's some portion
of control plan tasks or
management plan tasks that are performed
by some more centralized designated
set of nodes that's not evenly
distributed among all nodes.
In a peer-to-peer system,
even the overall control and
management of this system
would be done by all.