Now let's do a question, to help summarize the
optimizations we just talked about. Check the box if you
think the optimization given, has the merit provided in the
column. Most of these should be pretty clear. The tricky
one is whether journaling helps improve overall performance. And it
really depends on what one considers the alternative to be.
If the alternative is leaving changes in memory for longer.
Then no, it doesn't improve performance. But if the alternative
is spending lots of seek time trying to backup in memory changes to the disk,
then obviously it does help. Let's assume the latter, so that this one is true.