Alright I want to try to explain this
convergence theorem specifically in
the context of Q learning.
It's intended to be general and apply
to lots of algorithms of this form,
but mostly we want to use it to
show that Q learning converges.
So let me express Q
learning as an update rule.
In the form of this kind of weird Bt
operator notation that
was used in the theorem.
Okay.
So Bt is the operator that we're
going to use to update the Q function on
the t timestep.
And so, given that we know
that we're on the t timestep,
we know that we're in some state
St minus one, took sub action
At minus one, ended up in new state St,
having received reward Rt.
Alright, so, what I'd like to
kind of argue is that this
strange definition of operator Bt Q
is exactly the Q learning update.
So, let me try to argue that.
So this looks a lot like
the Q learning update.
Saying that we're going to take
the Q function at (S,a) and
I'm going to move it a little
towards the immediate reward
plus the discounted
value of the next state.
That much toward where away
from that old Q value was.
So, the only thing that's different
between the Q learning update and
this is that we've separated
out two different q functions,
this w thing and this q thing.
Q is using to play the role of
essentially the q function in the state
action pair that we just left, and
w is playing the role of giving
us an estimate of what the q value is
at the state that we just arrived in.
And in regular q learning
those are the same.
But we're now separating them out
because the theorem is going to
find that easier to swallow.
>> Okay.
>> All right so
you buy the fact that this is Q learning
just in a slightly different notation?
>> Well it certainly is if w and
q are the same.
Which is what you just said.
>> Yes, certainly the case now that
w and q are different but when,
oh are you are saying it is q
learning when w and q are the same?
>> Isn't that what you said?
>> Yes.
>> Okay, so yes, that's what I'm saying.
>> Great.
All right, so
now what we want to argue is that
this definition of the update
rule causes the things that we needed
to be true for the theorem to be true.
All right, so
let's start with condition 1.
Why is this true for
the learning rule defined this way?
>> Is that a question?
That's rhetorical, right?
>> It was intended to
actually be a question.
So let's look at what needs to
be true of this learning rule,
what needs to be true is
that if we have, essentially
if we did this update in the form
of knowing what Q* was and
use it as a one step look ahead here,
then what do we want to be true?
What we want to be true is that if
you give me any two value functions,
they're going to get no farther apart.
In fact, they're going to get closer
together if the learning rate,
if we're actually updating that
particular state action pair,
the learning rate is non-zero,
they should be getting closer together.
So why is that the case?
Why is it the case that if we do
this update at a state action pair,
doing our look ahead with Q star,
that everything is sort of moving
towards one particular answer.
It's moving towards a particular answer.
Do you know what it is?
>> Q star?
>> It is moving towards Q star, but
in particular it's trying to compute
the expected value of this one-step
look-ahead where the expectation is
taken over all possible values of St.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So it's essentially doing the
averaging part of the Bellman Equation.
And the reason that
works is because well,
that's sort of how things converge
if you let learning rates converge.
We've talked about that
in previous lessons.
So all this rule is saying is that if
we knew where we were going, we could
use this update rule to average out
all the stochasticity that we get from
on different trials taking a step from
a state and ending up in a different
state, because of the stochasticity
of the Transition function.
That's all this is saying,
is that we can smooth out
these stochasticity transition function
using the rule that we worry about.
>> Okay.
That makes sense.