Let's go ahead and
look at a tool called Memory Monitor.
Memory Monitor is a tool that can
show you how your application
is using memory over time.
Let's go ahead and start it.
As with other demos,
if you want to follow along,
make sure you start Android studio.
Connect the physical device,
enable debugging,
and then make sure your Sunshine
application is in the forefront.
So if we want to start Memory Monitor,
we can do so through the menu, like so.
We're going to go to tools,
Android, Memory Monitor.
Or if you have an icon here at the
right, you can go ahead and click that.
So let's do that.
Okay, so the tool opens as a tab at
the bottom right of your Android
studio window.
And if it finds your application, it's
going to immediately start recording
memory usage right from your app.
Just like you should be
seeing right about here.
At the top left of your
Memory Monitor window,
you will be able to toggle your
currently connected devices.
And on the right, you can select
the application you want to monitor.
The stacked graph that takes up most
of the window shows the total memory
available to your application.
The amount of memory that your
application is currently using
is shown in dark blue.
And the free memory,
or unallocated memory,
that's available to your application,
is shown in light blue or light gray.
The graph updates continuously to
show you changes in memory usage.
And it shows how much memory the app
has available to it over time.
Now, in a world where your app
isn't doing much of anything,
you should see a flat
graph like this one.
From a performance perspective,
this is actually an ideal scenario.
But as your application allocates and
frees memory, you'll see that the
allocated amount changes in your graph.
And if your app suddenly needs a lot
more memory, the overall memory
allocated for your app will also
increase, represented by this box here.
Because if it didn't, your app would run
out of memory and essentially crash.
Now anytime you see the allocated memory
drop by a significant amount like here,
that's a pretty good signal that the
garbage collection event has occurred.
Now in this example, the garbage
collection looks pretty healthy.
On the other hand in this graph it looks
like there might be some problems.
You see, the app allocates a lot of
memory within a short time, then
frees that memory almost immediately,
creating these narrow, skinny spikes.
And it does it over and over.
This means that your app is spending
a lot of time garbage collecting.
And the more time you spend doing GCs,
the less time you have to do other stuff
like rendering or streaming audio.
So let's see what this looks like live.
Okay, so here we are with memory
monitor running on Sunshine and
once we start tapping on a day and then
looking at the detail view and then say,
tap the back button or
say we do this a few times.
We're going to see that our
memory starts to fill up.
Just like around here.
And say we were to go ahead and
change the zip code a few times
just to get some new data.
And go back and check out some
more detailed weather information.
Cool, looks like it's going to
be clear on Wednesday.
Ooh, a little rain on Friday.
So gradually we're seeing
how memory is filling up.
And eventually,
it will actually grow until we actually
have no more free memory left.
If we keep going, at this point,
a garbage collection event will be
triggered to free up a chunk of memory.
You can see this drop happen right here.
Now remember, this does not
free up all the memory because
Android's memory management
system is generational in nature.
In our nifty tool, we can actually force
individual garbage collection events.
There's this garbage truck tool here
on the top-left of the Memory Monitor.
If you press it,
it's going to go ahead and trigger
an individual garbage collection.
Notice what's happening here
on the right of the graph.
Now, we can go ahead and
actually press it a few times.
And if you do that a few more times,
you can free all
the freeable memory like so.
And this seems to be back
to our original state.
Okay, so next, we're going to
take a look at memory leaks and
the heap viewer tool.
And finally,
we'll use all of these together to find
and fix memory leaks in some real code.