Open up the second exercise
in the second lesson,
T 2.2 exercise add
menu in Android Studio.
In this exercise, we're going to add
a menu for the GitHub query application.
First, we'll add the title for our menu
action to our strings.xml file, and
we'll call it Search.
Then we'll create a menu
resource called main.xml.
To do that, we first need to create a
directory to hold all of our menu files.
Right click the res directory,
select Android Resource Directory,
choose menu for
resource type, and hit OK.
Then right-click the new menu directory
and choose Menu resource file.
We'll name it main and
add one menu item with
an ID of @+id/action_search.
Even though it's not technically
needed for a one-item menu,
we'll then set the orderInCategory to 1,
since it's the first menu item.
Now we'll ask Android to show
a button in the action bar using
app:showAsAction="ifRoom".
Note that if there isn't room to
show the menu entry as a button,
it would still end up
in the overflow menu.
We use app:showAsAction rather
than android:showAsAction to keep
things compatible with Gingerbread and
the support library.
You can use the Android Studio
shortcut Alt or
Option/Enter to add the app
namespace to your XML.
Finally set the title to the search
string, search from strings.xml.
On to the main activity code.
First we'll override
onCreateOptionsMenu and
call getMenuInflater to inflate our menu
resource into our passed in menu object.
Then we'll override
onOptionItemsSelected.
To demonstrate that your
onOptionsItemSelected is
being called with the correct menu item,
we'll introduce another nice Android
framework element, the Toast.
A Toast is typically used to provide
simple feedback about an operation in
a small popup.
It only fills the amount of space
required for the message, and
the current activity remains visible and
interactive.
For example, navigating away from
an email before you send it triggers
a draft saved toast to let you know
that you can continue editing later.
Toasts automatically disappear
after a certain timeout.
Menu items are identified
by integer IDs, so first,
I'll grab the selected item's ID.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Once I have the ID,
I'll check if it equals the ID for
our action_search menu item.
Remember, we specify this idea
in the XML resource file.
When you have more than one menu option,
a switch statement is a little cleaner
than a bunch of chained if statements.
But I'll use a single if
statement here for simplicity.
If this item was the search menu item,
I'll show a toast.
Later I'll make this do
something much more interesting.
To create a toast, we call the static
Toast.makeText method with the current
context, our activity, the text to show,
and one of the two constant values for
how long to show the toast,
Toast.LENGTH_SHORT or Toast.LENGTH_LONG.
Make sure to call show() on the toast
after you've created it to display it.
So now it's your turn.
Add the menu to your application,
hook it up in code, and
use it to display a toast.
Have fun!