This should look familiar from the previous material.
It's 77, and the reason is in A3,
we have an 80% chance
for the action going east to reach 100.
But the remaining 20%, we either stay in place or go to the field down here,
both of which have an initial value of 0.
That gives us 0, but we have to subtract the cost of 3,
and that gives us 80 - 3 = 77.
It's also easy to verify that any of the other actions have lower values.
For example, the value of going west will be
0 in all possible outcomes given the current value function
minus 3, so the value of going west would right now
be estimated as -3, and 77 is larger than -3.
Therefore, we'll pick 77 as the action that maximizes
the updated equation over here.