Since the physical memory is much
smaller than the addressable
virtual memory,
allocated pages don't always have to be
present in physical memory, in theorem.
Instead, the backing physical page
frame can be repeatedly saved and
restored to and from some secondary
storage, like disks, for instance.
And this process is referred to
as paging or demand paging, and
traditionally with demand paging,
pages are moved between main memory and
a storage device such as disk,
where a swap partition resides.
In addition to disk, the swap partition
can be on another type of storage medium
like a flash device, or it could even
sit in the memory of another node.
Let's see how paging works.
When a page is not present in memory,
it has its present bit in the page
table entry that's set to zero.
When there is a reference to that page,
then the memory management unit will
raise an exception, and that will cause
a trap into the operating system kernel.
On an access, the memory management
unit will raise an exception, that's
called the page fault, and this will
be pushed into the operating system.
So it will trap into
the operating system kernel.
At that point,
the OS kernel can determine that
this exception is a page fault.
It can determine that it had previously
swapped out this memory page onto disk.
It can establish what is the correct
disk access that needs to be performed.
And it will issue an I operation
to retrieve this page.
Once this page is brought into memory,
the OS will determine a free frame
where this page can be placed.
And it can use the page frame number for
that page to appropriately update
the page table entry that corresponds
to the virtual address of that page.
At that point, control is pushed back
into the process that caused this
reference, and the program counter will
be restarted with the same instructions,
so that this reference
will now be made again.
Except at this point,
the page table will find a valid
entry with a reference to this
particular physical location.
Note the the original
physical address of this page
will very likely be different
from its physical address
that was established after this
demand paging process was over.
If, for whatever reason, we require a
page to be constantly present in memory,
or if we require it to maintain the same
physical address during its lifetime,
then we will have to pin the page, and
at that point we basically
disable the swapping.
This is, for instance,
useful when the CPU is interacting
with devices that support direct
memory access support, or DMA.