How about another way, okay?
I'm going to show you another approach.
Which in some sense is easier to understand, but it's actually not as good.
That's why I showed you the other one first, all right?
So here I'm using the same equation again.
Now using uv1 as being projectively similar to m times XYZ1.
But remember, if m can be changed by
a scale value without affecting anything, then I could
divide all the values by whatever that was on the bottom right-hand corner of m.
And what I would get out would be a 1 here.
So I can just put a 1 in the bottom right-hand corner of that matrix.
And the reason I do that is now my equations for Ui and Vi become this.
All right?
And what you'll notice is I now have terms when I multiply out.
This, the 1s and the denominator multiply Ui and Vi, which remember I,
those are knowns, because those are the locations of the points in the image.
So I now have terms that don't have the variables in them.
That's why this is referred to as the inhomogeneous solution.
And one of the reasons this is not as good is suppose the original m23
was supposed to be much, much smaller than the other values,
that is close to zero compared to the others.
Well you've just set a number that was supposed to be really close to zero to
one, that's dangerous with respect to numerical stability.
So in general and, and
also in terms of overall minimization, doing the singular value decomposition or
doing the eigenvector finding on a transpose a, is, is the preferred method.
And, by the way, it's one line in MATLAB, so you might as well just do it.