Well, I went with speed up.
My reasoning stems from
the definition of power.
It's energy divided by time.
Energy is like algorithmic work and
the algorithmic work would basically be
the same thing as the time to execute
the algorithm on a single processor.
So the time on one processor divided
by the time on p processors,
looks like energy, which is work,
divided by the time on p processors.
Now think about that for a second.
If you need to run at low power,
then either you need to use very little
energy, or you need to go really slow.
So if you're energy optimal,
then there's a fundamental
tension between speed and power.
High speed is less time,
which would appear to imply more power.
This probably explains why
my de-identified no-name
brand cell phone has a pretty good
battery life but runs slow as [BLEEP].
Oops, did I say [BLEEP]?
Can you drop f bombs in OMSCS?