So let me reiterate here again what to expect from this class,
why you should be taking it, and what I am expecting out of this class.
And well actually, more importantly, the topics I'm covering and
the goals of this class.
So one thing of the offset, I want to make sure it's clear to everyone.
This is not a photography class.
What that means is I'm not going to be teaching you the basics of how to
take pictures or also to take good pictures.
I, personally, am a photographer.
Hopefully, I'll share with you all of the kinds of different things I
have done in the area of photography.
But, I have an amazing job where I can actually also work in the field that
I actually am also a hobbyist in.
I take photography for, as a hobby, but I really want to kind of
spend time also on the technology related questions associated with photography.
So this class is really about the technology related content.
You will learn about the back end technology.
We open the black boxes of cameras and other types of image analysis softwares.
Again take a very computation driven effort through it.
Now, I do argue that learning about what's behind the tools that
you use may actually help you bec, become a better photographer.
But, that's a, not a direct, you know, prerequisite of this class.
If you are taking pictures already you may enjoy this class a lot more because
you'll learn more about the technology behind it.
But, more importantly if you don't know anything about photography,
this won't teach you much about photography.
But, it'll teach you about the cameras that you use, and the tools you use,
and you know, some may argue that might make you a better photographer.
This is also a hands-on class.
So you will learn by doing things yourselves.
So, that's important too.
Many people have asked questions like,
oh, I'm not really comfortable with a lot of programming.
Well, this class will get into a little bit of programming.
Or quite a bit.
And you will need to know some of the tools that require you to actually
manipulate images using simple programs.
So I do want everybody to be aware of that.
At one point,
you will learn by doing by yourself, and with the class you will share things.
As I said, we have homework assignments, and peer feedback assignments,
to just kind of keep things interesting, and also learning from each other,
while learning from the content and the material shared with you.
So, to summarize this class is going to be an interesting class where we're
going to learn about the technology aspects of photography.
Computational photography's are a discipline of its own.
We're going to cover our ideal ways to introduce to
you the concepts of computational photography.
You will learn by doing things and you will hopefully have fun and
the tag line that I love to share with this class all the time is you will
learn to have fun computing with photographs.
So that's the goal and hopefully you'll have fun doing it.
Thank you.