when we talk about computer vision were
literally talking about using algorithms
to let a computer see the world like we
see it full of depth and color and
shapes and meaning computer vision is a
really broad field and right now we're
just going to focus on a few features
later in the nanodegree program will be
getting much more in depth with the
tools and techniques used in computer
vision for self-driving cars at this
point will introduce you to two powerful
techniques that you use for your first
project where you'll be identifying the
lane lines and an image of the road
the first technique will look at is
canny edge detection so let's give it a
go