So today I showed you a variety
of fun and interesting things.
You will also have, exposure to them in
an assignment that we are going to have
on exactly the topic.
So, basically taking a bunch of
pictures and generating panoramas and
other types of artifacts
like Photosynth.
The whole purpose of this is, of course,
ho we can use photos to show space or
environments.
We can imagine this has value in
real estate and in architecture,
and all that kind of stuff,
beyond tourism.
We talked a little bit about
the whole concept of photo tourism.
That is,
somebody took a bunch of pictures.
How can we actually tour that site
without actually going there?
Of course, it's always fun to go there.
Photosynth and
also something we looked at in detail.
And I just kind of touched on
the whole concept of street views.
Again, it's building on a whole lot of
concepts that we have looked at already.
Lot of detail, again, refer back to
the original paper by Noah Snavely,
Steve Seitz, Richard Szeliski.
There's a newer paper by the Google
folks on the photo tours,
which is running on Google right now.
There are many other similar
examples that are out there.
I encourage you to look for
them and post them in Piazza.
And of course, the Szeliski book
also has more details on this.
One thing I also recommend
when you are actually on the,
photo tour site is you will actually
see examples of additional work.
For example, building Rome in a day,
where a bunch of pictures that are taken
of the city of Rome, how they can be
used to actually model the whole city.
That's the kind of stuff that both
is being done for more targeted,
you know move your own car with a bunch
of different cameras in the city, or
have more citizen-generated imagery
to generate, models of cities.
There is another paper also referred
to as Building Rome On a Cloudless Day,
which basically does, attempt to do the
same kinds of reconstruction of cities
like Rome, but with less computation.
That is, lack of a cloud,
computer cloud, that is.
Again, loads of stuff on this one.
We'll discuss this on
Piazza as much as we want.
But hopefully,
I hope you have enjoyed all
the concepts of your coverage so far.