Now that I have a login and
disconnect function,
I'm going to add the following
code to my header template.
Now a link to login appears
if the user is logged out.
And a link to disconnect appears
if the user is logged in.
Whew.
Well that was a lot of code, but
let's see how it looks now.
I'll fire up my server and
visit my restaurants page one more time.
Now when I login, I have the option to
login with Facebook or with Google.
And logging out is just
a simple click of a button.
Pages that don't belong
to me I cannot edit.
But if I'm logged in and I'm the owner
of a page, I do have the editing option.
We've successfully added two O op
providers to our menu application