When I started these last
version three updates,
there were two things
that I really wanted.
First was to know if somebody
had already bought something.
On me and my roommate's limited budgets,
it kind of sucks to
double buy Cheesy Flakes.
The second thing I wanted was some
way to know who was shopping.
If I'd had known that JP was in the
store, I would have been able to just
call him immediately instead of
randomly calling all my roommates.
Now, you've effectively
solved the first issue.
By implementing buy and
un-buy it's pretty clear whether
an item's been bought or not.
So, can we try to add this feature here?
I am imagining a button that when
clicked put's you in shopping mode.
When you're not in shopping mode
you can't buy or un-buy things.
Shopping mode would signal that you
are in the store and actively shopping,
and when your not in shopping mode
you couldn't accidentally buy
or un-buy things.
But if you were at the store,
you could click this button,
turn on shopping mode, and
be able to buy and un-buy things.
This would also signal to everybody that
you are in the store at that moment.
I'm going to provide you with an updated
layout that includes this button here.
Something should probably change
in the Firebase Database, but
to tell you the truth,
I'm not sure what.
What do you think should change in
the Firebase Database to support
the shopping mode that I talked about?
And remember,
the goal is to eventually be able to
know who's shopping in the store.
Here's some options that I came up with,
which one do you think is the best?
Option A would be to change the item
POJO to have a boolean, and
this boolean would basically
represent whether the list
that the item was a part of is
currently being shopped on.
Option B would be to actually
change the shopping list,
POJO itself, to store a list
of who's currently shopping.
Option C would be to change
the shopping list POJO to
have a boolean that represents whether
the list is being shopped on or not.
And option D would be to not change
either the shopping list class or
the item class, but to instead
change the user class to store for
that current user, what shopping
lists they are currently shopping on.
Now, I do think that shopping mode
should be on a per list basis.
After all, one shopping list
could be for outdoor supplies and
another shopping list could be for food.
So users shop on specific lists and not
universally, just to make that clear.
All right, tell me what you think.