Earlier I showed you how to
create a new textView and
then call a method to
change the text on it.
What if I want to change the text size?
I can just call textView.setTextSize and
hit Enter.
And then just pick
a random value like 56.
And then I can run it on my device.
And this is what it looks like.
Wow, that's big.
Then I can change
the text color as well.
I can do textView.settextcolor and
then pass in a color.
I showed you the possible
colors earlier.
So let me just pick one like green.
When I run this on the device,
it shows up in neon green.
If you look through
the textView documentation,
you may have found other
methods you can call.
For example,
you can call textView.setMaxLines.
This limits the number of the lines that
the text view shows to only two lines.
If the text is longer than that,
then it just gets cut off.
To test this,
we'll need a really long string here.
And, actually, in order to know
whether this is working properly,
I should comment this out first.
I'm going to run the app to make sure
that this string is actually longer than
two lines of text.
Okay, we verified that it's actually
two and a half lines of text.
Once I uncomment this line of code
to set the max line limit to 2 then
when I run the app then it should
truncate this to two lines here.
And it does, cool.
So hopefully you got some good practice
in with calling methods on an object
like textView.
It's actually uncommon to
call a setContentView and
then pass in a single view like this.
Normally the content view of your
activity will be a lot more complex.
And so that's why we would normally
leave it as setContentView and
then passing in the resource
ID of an XML layout.