Let's Google search for how to do this.
I'm going to type in how to
scroll in an android app.
Let's check out the first result.
The question is, how to make
my layout able to scroll down?
That's pretty similar to what we want.
I skip down to the answer part and
this has a green check mark and
lots of up votes.
So this could be a good answer.
It says, just wrap all of
that inside a ScrollView.
And then it has an example, ScrollView,
and then it specifies name space and
then it says.
Fill_parent for width and height, and
then it has an ending tag here, and
in this comment it says, put the rest
of your current view inside of it.
For background knowledge, fill_parent
is actually the same as match_parent.
It's just an older version of it,
but they mean the same thing.
On this next line it says that
ScrollView can contain just one item.
It looks like this was
someone's original layout, and
then to put inside of
scroll view then they just
made scroll view be the parent view and
the linear layout be the child's view.
Okay that was a helpful response so
let's go back and
see if there's any other solutions.
This person is describing
the same thing.
They have XML lay out and
I think they want to make it scroll.
Usually, I don't read
the full question in detail.
I just get to the answer part.
This person says,
have you tried to include all of
your XML into a parent ScrollView?
And then they give an example
of ScrollView, and
then the child is a RelativeLayout.
And then they have a closing tag for
ScrollView.
That's all they have in this thread.
But it looks like the two search results
here gave the same advice of using
a ScrollView.
So let's change our search query
to search for ScrollView android.
Awesome.
So it is a view in Android.
And there's a description here.
There's a lot of text here, so
I'm going to skip reading it, but
if you want to skim it, you can.
Then I'm going to hit Back.
I prefer looking for a code example.
So, the code examples that
we had earlier were good,
and this one is good as well.
So let's go back to Android Studio.
All of those XML examples
started with ScrollView.
Immediately there's an error that says
I don't have the required width and
height of the view.
So, I just added those in and
specified them to be match_parent.
If I add a closing bracket, then I
immediately get the closing tag here.
So, I'm going to copy that and
then paste it at the bottom
of this file down here.
That means the existing linear layout
is now a child of this ScrollView.
I'm going to select all of this and
then try to indent it by four spaces, so
it's easier to read as
a child of this ScrollView.
In Android Studio, if I click on the
Edit menu, I can go to Indent Selection,
and that will indent it
over by four spaces.
There.
Now that looks better.
Oh, but I still have an error here.
It says,
namespace 'android' is not bound.
I can click for more information.
It says, this inspection checks for
unbound namespace prefixes in XML.
If you remember way back in lesson one,
I said that Android colon comes
from this name space right here.
So I think we need to copy this and
then put it up here.
You should also move
the tools name space up here.
The tools name space is to provide
additional attributes that you can add
to your XML to help you debug and
build your app.
Okay, I'm going to run
this on my device now.
Okay, there's no visible difference
to the app because there's not enough
content in the order form to
make it need to be scrollable.
To really test this,
I need to add more views to this layout.
I'm going to do same trick as before.
I'm going to copy all these views and
then paste it into the layout so
that we have a really long order form.
Okay, now the order form is
really long and it scrolls.
That's exciting.
If I rotate the device,
then it also scrolls.
Now I can undo those changes and
go back to our original order form.
I'm still going to leave
the ScrollView in, though,
because our app will work
better across all devices.
For users with devices that
are shorter than this,
they'll still be able to scroll and
see all the fields.