Now the string.find function
was really helpful.
By just putting the word
we're searching for
in between parentheses, we were returned
with the index where that word occurred.
But our ultimate goal is to
replace the instances of noun or
verb in a string with our own words.
Wouldn't it be nice if we could do
this in one step rather than having to
slice strings and
add replacement variables?
Well, why don't we find out?
So I'm just going to do a quick Google
search for Python string replace, and
see if anything comes up
that piques our interest.
So python string replace.
Hm, let me check out this first link.
Hm.
So it seems like there's this
replace method built in to Python.
Now, you'll learn a lot more about what
methods are in stage three, but for
now just think of a method as
a fancy word for a function.
I'll refer to this replace method
as a function from now on.
Now let's read up on this documentation.
It says the method replace()
returns a copy of the string
in which the occurrences of old
have been replaced with new,
optionally restricting the number
of replacements to max.
Now this sounds pretty intimidating
with words like copy of a string and
optionally restricting the number of
replacements, but let's not panic.
If we scroll down,
it seems like they have an example here.
So it says if they have this string
which is set to this string example
wow this is really string, and
they call str.replace with is in the
first position, and was in the second.
Looks like they get thwas was string
example wow thwas was really string.
So it seems like every instance of is in
the string is being replaced with was.
Although we have no idea
how this function works,
we can see how by swapping out noun or
verb for is and our replacement word for
was, we'll be able to replace noun and
verbs with our own words.
And will uses replace function in
the quiz following to do just that.
Now, if that felt a bit rushed, don't
worry I'll explain how this function
works in more detail in just a second.
I just wanted to give you an example of
something programmers do all the time
which is searching for tools and reading
up on their documentation online.
By looking or even asking for
what you need help with you'll find
out there's a lot of good information
out there, which is often times free.
You'll also become more and more self
reliant, which is a very important skill
to develop as you continue
your programming career.
Now, let's get back to
the replace function.
Now, if you remember this string.find
function from the last quiz,
you see that replace is
pretty similar to that.
The basic structure of the replace
function looks like this.
So we have this string test_string,
which is followed by .replace which
is followed by a parenthesis.
And this is where we
pass in two strings.
The first string is old which
is the string we want to replace
in test_string.
And the second is this string new,
which will replace old in test string.
So, let's go through one more example
to really understand how replace works.
So here I have this sentence variable,
set to I am a NOUN and I'm calling
sentence.replace with NOUN in the first
position and bird in the second,
because I want to replace NOUN
with bird In the string sentence.
And the output of this
code will look like this.
I am a bird.