Hey, remember this fact?
From a partitioned graph you create
a special vector x with plus minus
one entries depending on the partition.
And then we said,
well, if you want to count the number of
cut edges then you look at this product.
Let's write this product out explicitly.
So x transpose l times x
it turns out is this sum.
It's a sum over all pairs of vertices
above l i j, times x i, times x j.
Now let's go one step further and
actually break this sum
apart into five components.
Yikes.
Looks complicated.
But don't worry it's not that bad.
You can with some effort
interpret these sums for
instance, what is this first sum?
Well, it's a sum over the subset
of INJ where I is equal to j.
In fact, that simplifies the sum and.
For example, lij for i equal to
j is just the diaganol of l and
i equals j of xi and
xj is just essentially xi or xj squared.
In other words, the sum and
is just lii times xi squared.
But you know exactly what that is.
The lii are the degrees of the vertices.
And xi squared is just always one,
independent of whether xi is plus one or
minus one.
So if I were to ask you to give me the
values of say, lii and xi Xi squared,
you would say lii is di, the degree
of vertex i, and xi is plus 1.
By the way, what is this?
Well, if I'm summing the degrees of all
the vertices, then what am I doing?
I'm basically counting
the number of edges twice.
My question is,
can you do the remaining sums?
For instance, can you interpret this sum
and then figure out what lij, xi, and
xj are?
So, think about that and
write your answers in the boxes.