There is also the POSIX API for
shared memory.
On Linux systems, it has been
supported since the 2.4 kernel.
Although it's supposed
to be the standard,
the POSIX API is not as widely supported
as, for instance, the System V API.
Here is the API.
The most notable difference is that
the POSIX shared memory standard
doesn't use segments.
Instead, it uses files.
Now, these are not the real files that
exist in some file system that used
otherwise by the operating system.
Instead, these are files that only exist
in the so called tmpfs file system,
which is really intended to look and
feel like a file system.
So, you can always reuse the same
type of mechanisms that is used for
file systems.
But, in essence, is just a bunch of
state that's present in physical and
volatile memory.
The I/O simply uses
the same representation and
the same data structures that used for
representing a file to
represent bunch of pages in memory that
correspond to a shared memory region.
For this reason,
there is no longer a need for
the awkward key generation process.
Instead, shared memory segments can
be referenced by the file descriptor
that corresponds to the file.
And, then the rest of the operations
are analogous to what you'd expect
to exist for files.
A segment is opened, or closed.
So, they're explicit, shared memory,
open and close operations.
But, in fact, it can really
only call the regular open and
close operations,
since you will anyways pass a file.
And, the operating system will manage to
figure out which file system this file
sits in.
To attach or detach shared memory,
the POSIX shared memory API
relies on the mmap and
unmap calls that are used to map,
or unmap files into
the address space of a process.
To destroy a shared memory segment,
there is an explicit unlink operation.
There is also a shared memory close, and
this will remove the file descriptor
from the address space of the process.
But, in order to tell the operating
system to delete all of the shared
memory-related data structures, and
to free up that memory segment,
you must call the explicit
unlink operation.
I have provided a link to the reference
of the POSIX Shared Memory API
in the instructor notes.