I call the four major areas of
a web up's life cycle Rail.
Rail stands for response,
animations, idle, and load.
>> Wait.
That's not chronological order.
Shouldn't it be Liar, load,
idle, animation, response?
>> Okay.
Yeah, maybe.
It turns out liar is a less
popular acronym than rail, okay?
It's just a good way to remember it,
and yeah,
even though, you do loads at the start,
most apps do multiple loads with XHRs
and web sockets and HTML imports.
So, you know, like chill out, right?
>> All right.
>> Anyway, orders of letters,
not withstanding, it's
really a useful way to conceptualize and
group your apps workload.
To keep you happy though,
let's do them in chronological order.
>> I appreciate that.
>> Okay.