Here's what your layout code
should look like when you're done.
If you set the android.text
the same way as I did,
by referencing a string
using @string/add_geofences,
you'll also need a strings.xml
file with content like this.
Here you can see I have a string
that I call add_geofences, and
I put the text add_geofences
into that string.
So now, when I draw my activity,
my button will be using that string.
This is always handy for localizing or
if you want to change it later to
geofences capitalized or
something along those lines.
Other than that,
it's a very straightforward button, and
I've added the onClick handler here.
I'm just saying, android:onClick
equals add.GeofencesButtonHandler.
Of course, that can be done at
runtime in the onCreate event, but
I've done it in here now just
to make things a little simpler.