So this is a planning question.
And I apologize, it's a little bit hard to read.
There's a lot of text here.
And I ask you to consult the pdf document to read the text.
Given the resources on the left, over here,
can we reach those five goals;
A, B, C, D, E, on the right side?
And in looking at those, there's words like 'consume',
which means, the action eliminates the resource.
Whereas 'use' means,
you have to have it, but you retain it after using it.
Now initially, you know there's a couple of books;
one by Nau, about planning,
one by Zweben, about scheduling,
and one by Melville, about Whales.
And there's also videos.
Video 8 is about Planning.
And Video 15 is about Scheduling.
These might be our in-class videos.
That's your initial state.
And your goal is that you, as a student,
know about planning,
and you know about scheduling.
So the question is, with certain resources
that are available in the beginning,
and they differ from question to question,
can you attain the state of knowing about planning and scheduling?
Now, there's two ways to know about a topic.
One is to study it using a book.
And one is to view it using a video.
In both cases, the outcome is to know about the topic over here.
Now either one has a different precondition.
In the 'book' case, you have to have the book,
and the book has to be about the topic you care about.
In which case, the action 'study'
lets you understand the book and you know about the topic.
So for example, if you have a book about planning,
and study it, then you know about planning.
In the 'view' case, you have to have a video that's about the topic,
and you have to have a certain bandwidth,
which happens to be 2.5.
If you don't have the bandwidth 2.5, you won't be able to view the video,
and you won't be able to know about the topic.
That's the way the problem is set up.
Now, books can be bought or borrowed.
In the buying case, you consume 50 dollars
In the borrowing case,
you have to have a privilege, at the library, that's at least '1'.
It might be larger but it can't be lower than '1'.
And in either case after doing this, you have the book,
and you can now plug this into the 'study' action,
and you can read about it,
and study it, and know the topic.
So here are the questions.
If your resource is that you have 50 dollars,
and you have library privileges of '1',
can you then attain the state of
knowing about planning and scheduling?
Secondly, suppose your resources is no dollars,
but you have library privileges of '2',
can you attain the same state?
Third, what about the same with library privileges of '1'?
Can you get here?
Fourth, what about if you have 40 dollars,
and bandwidth of '3'? Can you get here?
And fifth, what about if you have bandwidth of '2', and 95 dollars?
Can you get here?
Check all, or any, or none
of those five questions that apply.