Well, this is a tough one.
The answer is either b or c.
Look, as long as you keep track of what's going on, it doesn't matter.
You can do whatever you want, which case it would be c.
Remember before I showed you those correlation operators that I'm
doing correlations, because I want to know which way is the right way?
So the right versus to the left.
So I think when you're doing filtering for
gradients, doing correlation probably works better for you.
And by the way, so in the old days,
we used to have to either call correlation or convolution explicitly in Matlab.
Now we tend to use i m filter, as we've talked about before.
I m filter by default does correlation.
So if you want convolution, make sure you tell it.
All right?
So you just have to keep track of that.