Alex net was developed at the university
of toronto by Alex Khrushchev ski suits
giver and their professor Geoffrey
Hinton although the fundamental
architecture of Alex not resemble the
net from 1998 Alex that was a
breakthrough in several respects first
and foremost Alex not use the massive
parallelism afforded by gpus to
accelerate training using the best gpus
available in 2012.the Alex net team was
able to train the network in about a
week
additionally Alex net pioneered the use
of rectified linear units as an
activation function and dropout is a
technique for avoiding overfitting in
2011 the year before Alex that was
developed the winner of the image net
competition successfully classified
seventy-four percent of images or in the
terminology the competition it's error
was twenty-six percent the next year
Alex net lowered its error to fifteen
percent this was a huge leap forward