In summary, here's some of
the key architectural features
of distributed shared memory systems.
Specifically we're talking about page
based distributed shared memory systems.
Every node contributes part of its
main memory pages to the DSM layer.
Local caches are maintained
to improve performance
by minimizing the latency of
the access to story node modes.
All nodes are responsible for some
portion of the distributed memory and
of its management.
Specifically, the home node for a page
manages the accesses to that page and
also tracks who
currently owns that page.
Who has ownership rights.
And finally, some explicit replication
could be considered in order
to assist with load balancing.
In order to further
improve performance and
to address certain reliability concerns.