Okay so here's the answer code, and
here's an image of what our
data snapshot looks like.
You were listening to the list
name location in the database.
It has no children nodes, so the child
method is not one that you'd use.
That's because you already
navigated to this location here.
So now the question is whether
we want the key or the value.
This is the key and this is the value.
The key stays the same.
The value stores the list
name set by the user.
You can think of these data
structures as representing objects.
Each key is like a member
variable of an object and
each value is the value
of that variable.
The name of the member
variable doesn't change, but
the value can update quite a bit
depending on what is being stored.
In fact,
the comparison between JSON data and
an object is not at all farfetched,
and we're going to see this shortly.