We said earlier that threads can exist at both the kernel and the user level.
Let's take a look more at what we mean by this distinction.
Kernel level threads imply that the operating system itself is multithreaded.
Kernel level threads are visible to the kernel, and
are managed by kernel level components like the kernel level scheduler.
So, it is the operating system scheduler that will decide how these kernel level
threads will be mapped onto the underlined physical CPUs, and
which one of them will execute at any given point of time.
Some of these kernel level threads may be there to directly support some of
the processes.
So, they may execute some of the user-level threads and
other kernel level threads may be there just to run certain OS level
services like daemons, for instance.
At the user level, the processes themselves, are multi-threaded, and
these are the user level threads.
For a user level thread to actually execute,
first, it must be associated with a kernel level thread.
And then,
the OS level scheduler must schedule that kernel level thread onto a CPU.
So let's investigate a little more, what is the relationship that exists between
user level threads and kernel level threads.
In fact, there's several possible relationships between the user
level threads and the kernel level threads.
And we will now look at three such models.