Okay.
So we actually haven't quite found out how the content resolver knows
magically what content provider to use.
To understand that, and
also what this parameter is doing, we're going to need to know what a URI is.
URI stands for uniform resource identifier.
If you're thinking that URI sounds a lot like URL, you'd be correct.
URLs are actually a subset of URIs.
URLs refer to a location, usually on a network.
Whereas a URI has a bit of a broader definition where it's meant to identify or
give the location of some data.
Okay, so I want to see what this URI actually looks like.
I'm going to go over to the code, and I'm going to put in a quick log statement
to see what the actual text is stored in this constant.
Okay, so I'm here in the code.
I'm going to go ahead and write my log statement.
Okay. There it is.
I'm going to go ahead and run this and then open logcat.
Okay, so you might have to peer a little bit closely at your screen, but
here's my log statement.
And it says, content://user_dictionary/words.
So I'm going to go ahead and take that sentence over to the other screen.
And we will tear it apart and take a look at it.
Okay, so this constant URI is equal to this.
Content:// is the standard way that content URI's start.
So we always start with this.
The word user_dictionary tells us what the content authority is.
The content authority is super important.
This little string right here says what content provider the content resolver is
supposed to be using.
And this last part here says that we want to get a list of words.
So all together we're saying this is
a content URI that's accessing the user_dictionary content provider.
And we know that because we're using the user dictionary's content authority.
And finally, we're specifically interested in looking at the words in
the user dictionary.
Okay.
So to review, the first line right here gives us the ContentResolver.
We then use the ContentResolver to go to the right content provider.
How do we know what the right content provider is?
We use this URI here, which specifies a content authority,
and the content authority matches the correct content provider.
How do we know what data we want to use in the content provider?
Well, we use this last part of the content URI,
which signifies that we're trying to get a list of words.
And when we want to know what we're going to do do that data,
we have the method call right here, which defines what we're doing.
In this case, we're querying.
Now, we have all these null parameters as well.
Which I'll mention what they are in the next node.
Right now though, I have a quiz for you.
All right, so with what you know, which of these six statements would you
most likely use if you wanted to change the color of all calendars to be red?
You can assume that this values object right here is the information that you
would need to define the values for one row of data.
Also, if you want to know more about the URIs here that I use you could go
ahead and check out the instructor notes for links to documentation.