When you try to write a program or
a script, you're actually testing
that program in a very basic way.
You'll see if the program runs and
you'll usually see if it passes a bare
minimum in terms of functionality.
These types of tests actually have
a name and they're called smoke tests.
So, I smoke.
One hypothesis is that it comes
from testing electronic devices.
You turn on your device and
if you start seeing smoke, you'd know
that there's probably something wrong.
Another possible origin of
the name comes from testing pipes.
Before running water or maybe some more
dangerous liquid through the pipes,
engineers would test with smoke
to see if there were any leaks.
So, that gives you a little
background of the name, but
what do smoke tests do
in terms of software?
A smoke test is a series of test cases
that make sure that the most critical
functions of a program work,
but they don't go into details.
This is why they're sometimes
described as wide and shallow tests.
Since these tests don't
go into the details,
they could be run much faster
than a full test suite.
The speed of the smoke
test is pretty important.
If a smoke test breaks anything in the
application, you could stop working and
fix it immediately.
And at that point, there's no
need to run more advanced tests.
Some of these other and longer running
tests involve more expensive resources
such as dedicated human testers.
And in general, it's good not to bother
them with obviously broken builds.
So, in short, smoke tests are meant to
catch problems fast, and save time and
money by providing
feedback on quality fast.
They're very important when
using Continuous Delivery.
You don't want a bad build to
go through the pipeline and
run all those long extensive and
expensive tests, if the build is bad.
And this is why smoke
tests are sometimes called
build verification tests.
Let's look at an example of what
a series of smoke tests might look like.
Let's say that you have an application,
and
the point of that application
is to listen to a port.
Some example tests might be,
if you're connected to the port,
do you get the expected response?
Does it process a simple request
in a reasonable amount of time?
Does your program return
the data in the expected format?
Keep in mind that it's important to not
only test the functional requirements
like does this button work, but
also non-functional ones like does this
process in a reasonable amount of time.
In the same way that there's no
point in testing further if basic
functionality is broken,
there's no point going forward
if the new build of the application is
ten times slower than the previous one.
In the context of DevOps and Continuous
Delivery, you'd run smoke tests at
the time of continuous integration
right after the build.
And then, you'd run them again
after deploying the build to every
environment, test staging,
and possibly also production.
[BLANK_AUDIO]