Here's how refinement planning works.
In addition to regular actions, we have abstract actions
like going from my home to the San Francisco airport.
Then we have possible ways to take to refine these abstract options into concrete actions.
Here one refinement is I can drive from home to long-term parking
and then take the shuttle to the airport.
Another refinement is I can just take a taxi.
Here's another example of an abstract action,
which is if I'm at one point on a grid, ab, and I want to get to point xy,
and if I know the grid is all connected,
and I have this abstract action of just navigating from ab to xy.
One refinement says if I'm already there I do nothing.
Another refinement says I can start the journey by going left.
Another refinement says I can start the journey by going right and so on.
The idea is I can figure out a complex plan that involves
navigating around picking up and object, doing something else,
and do that planning just at the level of abstract actions like navigate
rather than having to figure out a path from ab to xy.
How do we know when we have a solution?
A hierarchical task network achieves the goal if for every part, every abstract action,
at least one of the refinements achieves the goal.
We only need to at least one of them, because we're the planner.
We get to make the choice.
It's like an and/or search where we can make the best possible choices,
and if any of the choices work, then the goal can be achieved.