So now what we're going to do is we're going to step through bare with me
this whole second order Taylor expansion about u,v of 0,0.
By the way you should appreciate that I am not writing this.
So you actually can read it and it will be PDF presented of some sort so
you can get it from there or you can go to Rick book it's, it's all there.
But believe me you don't want me to write this you just want me to
be humourous and light hearted.
All right, so here we have our Taylor expansion written just as before.
So we're going to knock these derivatives down one at a time.
We're going to start with our first derivative, right?
We have to do the first derivatives then the second derivatives.
So the first derivative we're going to look at [LAUGH], the first,
first derivative we're going to look at.
Is respect to the u direction.
Now u is the offset in the x direction.
Okay, just remember that u is the offset in the x direction.
And we're going to take the derivative of this function E
of u,v with respect to u.
Okay, let's see, well we've got this square term here, so
that gives us this, we, we raise it to, to single power instead, and
then we have to take the derivative of the inside term with respect to u,
and, let's see, there's no u's in there, that's go away.
So there's a u in here, so I have to take the derivative of I of x plus u,
y plus v, with respect to u.
Okay?
Not me, you.
Anyway.
Well, remember, u is in the same direction as x, so
the derivative of the image in the u direction is the same as the derivative of
the image in the x direction.
So I need the image gradient I sub x.
Got it? Good.
I'm not going to do v.
V's exactly the same thing except instead of xs, you get ys.
Now what we do is we're going to do the second derivative.
So we're just going to take the derivative of this with respect to u.
Well, there's two parts here.
Right? We've got this part, and we've got that part.
Right? So the derivative of a product is u times dv plus v times du.
Remember?
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Except Us and Vs is a terrible choice because we've got different U's and V's.
But basically the derivative of
the first time the second plus derivative of the second time.
The first what is that going to look like?
That's going to look like this.
Okay?
So we take the derivative of a part that's the image and
multiply it so that just gives us this twice.
And then the second one is we take the derivative of the derivative and
multiply that by the original.
That gives us the second derivative.
-okay?
The math's pretty easy, you can work it out.
This is the e respect to u, u term, all right?
So we've done the first derivative, the second derivative, u and v are the same.
The only thing left to do from that matrix, we had e, u, u, e, v, v,
we need the the cross derivative and
that just looks like this where we take the derivative of,-
The previous one of u except to v now.
And we get something that looks like this.
And you'll notice that this has the gradient in y, the gradient x.
Remember x is the same direction as u, y is the same direction as v.
And it also has this cross derivative.
We haven't talked a whole lot about the cross derivative,
and in fact, we're not going to talk even more today about cross derivative.
because later we're going to make it go poof!
Go away. So we won't even think about it.
So now we have our first derivative, u,v is the same.
Our second derivative u,u.
v, v is the same.
And our cross derivative.
Right?
Right.