So now we have some more another trick under our belt that allows us to
do this feature matching whether we're doing the or really,
in this case, throwing some features away.
Match selection, whether we're doing exhaustively hashing or some other method.
But remember that distinction we talked about earlier where we said,
well, we've got two competing criteria, goals for feature descriptors.
We want them to be invariant, that is we don't want them to
change very much from one image to the next at the same scene point so
that I'll be able to do the match.
Which means you want them to sort of, the description to sort of stay the same.
But what you don't want is if I've got two similar points in the scene.
You want them to have two different descriptors because I
don't want to match to the wrong one.
That was this notion of being distinct.
So we have this invariance versus distinctive.
And that's the fundamental trade off.
And because of that trade off you have this problem that when you
pick the best match, because you've done this tradeoff,
you are still going to get a bunch of what we'd call wrong matches or outliers.
That is, we have some point matches that actually fit what we want and
some of them are just wrong.
So the question is, what should we do?
All right.
So, this sort of lent, launched into the last part of this, and
then hopefully, naturally, because I'm such a spectacular teacher into the,
the next lesson, all right.
So, remember, why are we doing this?
Well, we're trying to compute a fit,
a model that aligns one picture with the other, right.
We're going to compute a model that is the relationship between entities.
So what we're really doing is model fitting.
Okay.
Now, remember this picture of model fitting of lines and circles.
Remember when we did that whole Hough transform thing?
Where we were saying, Well, we've got a bunch of points and we'd like to
find which line is the right line, or which circle is the right circle?
Right. And the idea was that some of our edge points come really
from the circles, and some of them don't.
So really, that's what we're doing here.
Is we're doing model fitting.