This was a tricky one.
I really hope you just went ahead and
ran these lines,
to find out what they do.
the thing to realize,
is that this foo is going to be
the value of the variable foo.
This foo is just the string foo.
In here, again this foo is
the value of the variable foo.
So that's bar, and
this foo is just the string foo.
So it's "$foo + foo =$" So
bar + foo = barfoo, there we go.
Over here the list method allows
us to generate a new list,
by applying a closure to
each item in the list.
That would be Collect, awesome work.
That's all the Groovy we'll
discuss directly in this course,
though you'll get to write plenty more.
If you're ready for
a bit of a break from me and
Mark, we've got some suggestions for
where to go to learn more.
Learning new languages is one One of my
favorite things about working in Tech,
and Groovy is a particularly handy
language to have in your back pocket.
Check out the links in
the instructor notes to learn more.
Next up, we'll use our new Groovy
knowledge to start configuring
Gradle builds.