So here's an image of an old and I think now expired comedian who's,
therefore, cannot sue me.
That's Phyllis Diller, by the way, in case you remember.
And by the way, we're going to start with black and white because black and
white just makes everything easier because it's just a single channel.
We, we'll do color on and off, but pretty much everything we do for black and
white do, you do for color, hold for black and white, and, and it's just easier.
So when I show this to you, you actually think of it as a picture or
something to look at.
But what actually is, is a function.
In fact, we can just call it a function of I of x y,
all right, where the I has something to do with the image intensity.
So, if I think of this as a function, then I can just plop this as a surface and
MATLAB makes this incredibly easy.
And if I did, it would look something like this.
Okay?
Now this is the exact same function, but
instead of showing you as a picture where, you know, sort of straight on, and
by the way, the way MATLAB does it it's really cool, the,
the higher the thing is it also makes it brighter, so you can see.
So if you take a look at like the,
the, the checkers pattern on that awful shirt she was wearing, right, so
the bright spots are here, and the dark spots are down there.
Okay, that function is the same function as the image that I
was showing you before.
Computer vision and especially image processing, we'll be
talking mostly about the image processing side of computer vision today and
the next few are about taking these functions and computing something from them.
Often, we're just going to computer another image-like function, so images in,
images out.
And sometimes, we'll be getting some sorts of information.
So here's a very simple example.
Suppose I took that previous function, and I just smoothed it.
All right, so now you see, I have the same surface I had before, but
it's now, you know, it blends smoother, and the peaks and
the valleys of that shirt are, are much smoother.
They're not as steep as they were before.
Okay.
So that’s the function.
Now, of course, I can show that to you as an image again.
What’s that going to look like?
Well, you’ve probably figured this out because you’re all so smart.
It’s just going to be a blurry version of that image, okay.
And I’m showing it here side by side with the blurred function, oh, sorry,
the smooth function, right?
Because there is this direct analogy between what we call blurring in
the image and smoothing of that function.
It's exactly the same thing.