Often times,
you won't want to have a blanket role
that allows all authorized users to
read or write anything in storage.
Firebase storage rules include
context to handle these situations.
Context are part of the rules condition,
allowing you to specify when to enforce
rules, based on specific properties.
For instance, here,
if request at off not equal null
is the whole condition then request at
off is the context of the condition.
Firebase provides two
main types of contexts.
Request and resource.
A resource context
contains information for
resources that are already
on file based storage.
So you can enforce a security rule
that's based on a file's name,
a file's size, or a content type.
Like whether it's an image,
an audio, or a video file.
The request context is different
as it deals with request data.
And that's incoming data.
This includes context about the user
that's requesting to read or
write to far a bay storage.
You can get info like whether
the user is authenticated or
not with request.off.
For authenticated users, you can
enforce rules based on their UID.
The request context can also include
information about files that are being
uploaded, or updated we're updated
is a special case of uploading
we're the old version of the content
already exist in storage.
You can get the same properties
from request of resource
like the resource context.
The difference is the request
context is for in coming files,
where the resource context are for
existing files in storage.
An example condition for
this context could be to limit the file
size that can be uploaded to storage.
The request context has
a third piece of information
which is the time of the request.
It's a time stamp meaning it includes
both date info, like the day, month, and
year as well as time info, like hours,
minutes, seconds, and time zone.
An example condition here could allow
for time limited access such as only
allowing users to read files that have
been uploaded within the last 24 hours.
All that being said,
you can compose all of these contexts
to build sophisticated security
rules for your files and storage.
If you want to learn more about using
match, rules and context, take a look at
the documentation where you can see
all about Firebase storage security.