Now let's talk about how
Receiver Applications work.
First, recall that receivers are written
in HTML five and JavaScript.
They're loaded onto
a cast device via URL,
via an application ID
provided by the sender.
Senders can control the receiver by
sending them messages, for example,
to play or pause media.
You can send custom messages as well.
There are three types of
receiver applications.
Two of which require you to register
an application ID on the cast
developer console.
And one of which does not.
Which one you choose depends on the type
of application you're building, and
how much customization you'd like to do.
The Default Media Receiver plays
a wide variety of simple media types.
No styling or
customization is possible though,
and there's no way to modify
the receiver's behavior.
Next up is the styled media receiver.
This is also a prebuilt receiver
that's hosted by Google.
Likewise, it's designed for
streaming audio and video content, and
works with all the same types supported
by the default media receiver.
This time though, you can customize
it's appearance by supplying a CSS
file during registration
on the developer console.
You can use this to add your own colors
and branding, and the styled media
receiver is fully compliant with
the user experience guidelines.
This is your best bet,
if your app doesn't need to utilize
advanced capabilities like DRM.
This style media receiver
also has a splash and
loading screen that you can customize.
Now, as I said, you can customize the
style of the media receiver by providing
a CSS file, when you register
on the cast developer console.
There's five elements you can customize,
such as the background, the logo,
and a splash screen.
You can also add a watermark
when your media's playing,
and you can checkout the link in the
instructor notes for more details, and
for requirements on the different
types of images you can use.
Now Custom Receivers are the way to go,
if you want to have full control over
all aspects of the behavior
of your application.
There are main use cases
if you want to play d or
m content with dynamic licenses,
or if you need authentication.
Custom receivers also make sense
if you're building a data centric
app, like a game.
To help you build these, we've open
sourced a reference custom receiver
that's equivalent to
the default media receiver.
You can find a link to that in the
instruction notes, and many Google cast
featured apps use this as the starting
point for their integration.
Now custom receivers is a HTML five app
that you host on your own servers, and
they must be implemented using
the JavaScript receiver API.
You can use this API to hook into
the various events that are fired
within the cast receiver message system.
You can also use the cast media player
library to build media applications that
use a variety of techniques,
like adaptive streaming,
HLS, MPEG DASH,
smooth streaming, and more.
I've switched over to Android Studio,
and
I've brought up the sample receiver
from the hello cast text example.
We'll explore this example in
a little bit more detail soon, and
it's a great teaching tool.
The reason is, is that it has a one file
sender app and a very simple receiver.
I just want to note right here,
that you should not use this as
a reference point for your integration.
Instead, you can use the cast video
sample, which we'll also get into later.
The receiver app is located
within the receiver folder.
And if you don't see this by default,
change this display here to be
project instead of Android.
Your receiver app should access
the Google Cast receiver API
using this reference.
Don't self host this file because
it's updated periodically.
You can then get an instance
of the castReceiverManager and
use it to implement call backs
to handle various events.
There are a number of these,
like onSenderConnected or
onSenderDisconnected.
And you can find details for
all of them in the notes.
You can also debug your receiver
using the Chrome developer tools,
by connecting your browser to your
receivers IP address on port 9222.
Before you can connect, your Cast device
must be running your receiver app.
And your Cast device
must be registered for
debugging on the cast developer console.
The debugger's quite powerful, and
it supports full dom manipulation as
well as JavaScript console support.
Let's recap with a quick quiz
about receiver types, and
an optional learning exercise.
The best way to verify that you've got
your cast device set up properly with
the developer console, is to set up
your own custom receiver app, for
the hello cast example
that you can find here.
What I did on my own when I first
started using cast, was just basically
copying it and changing the background
color, but making sure that I could get
it up and running on my cast device
with its own application ID.