>> Now the final example and I want to
show you this pretty interesting example
that was produced by a bunch of people
at Microsoft with collaboration with
a lot of universities.
>> RoomAlive is a proof of concept
prototype that transforms any room
into an immersive, augmented,
magical gaming experience.
RoomAlive uses projectors and
depth cameras to cover an entire room,
including the people and the furniture
inside with pixels that can be used for
both input and output.
With RoomAlive, users can touch,
shoot and dodge augmented content.
That seamlessly coexist with their
existing physical environment.
Our system consists of multiple
projector camera units or ProCams for
short.
Each unit contains a depth camera,
a commodity wide field of view projector
and it's own computational unit.
These ProCam units can
be used individually or
combined through a scalable distributed
framework to cover an entire room.
The ProCam units
are auto-calibrating and
can self localize within the room as
long as their views have some overlap.
The auto-calibration requires no
expertise or calibration fiducials,
so the pro cams can easily
be installed by end users.
One just positions the pro cams in
the room and the system does the rest.
The system automatically creates
a unified model of the room by combining
the depth maps from each ProCam unit.
In addition to the 3D model, our system
automatically extracts the surfaces in
the room, identifying vertical and
horizontal surfaces and the floor plane.
We expose this information
together with the 3D model and
the ProCam controls in the plugin
to a unity game engine.
This enables game designers to offer
rich immersive gaming experiences.
To show how RoomAlive can
transform your living room,
we have created four
interactive experiences.
RoomAlive supports procedurally
texturing the living room,
transforming the room
into a new environment.
Here the living room can be
transformed into a holodeck,
an indoor factory or can show a river
running through the floor with
dynamically generated raindrops.
Virtual critters can also be
procedurally generated to appear around
the living room.
>> So here you see actually an example,
where a whole lot of other ideas have
been brought together into
one Interesting setup.
It's a projector camera system, except
they use def cameras, like connect
combined to a projector, which allows
them to extract much more detail,
3D information,
a depth map of the scene.
And then of course, the light is shown
based on the knowledge of the 3D scene.
So, and of course,
the calibration process is very
similar to what we had seen before.
An interesting example of creating
augmented reality experiences like this
in much more of a spacious do, domain
with various types of augmentations in
the display space with a variety of
things like, you know, colors and
also objects showing up.
Again, please look at the website for
more details on this one.