In this lesson, you'll get to build
an app that helps restaurants organize
their wait lists for
guests as they show up.
With the app, the waiter can
add new guests to the wait list
as they walk in by typing in their name
and the number of guests in the party.
Once added, the name and the party
size will appear in the list below
in the order that they have been added.
And when it's time to seat that group,
they can be simply swiped off the list.
We will be storing this guest
list into an SQLite database
by adding new guests as they show up and
removing guests from the database
by swiping them off the list.
So that if the app was
killed at any time,
we certainly don't want to lose
that precious list of guests.
As we've done with earlier toy apps, we
will building this step by step as well.
Each exercise completes
an important part and
you will be gradually building
up the app to its final stage.
The first step is to create a special
class known as the contract that will
define the structure of our database and
how the rest of the application sees it.
Then we'll create the actual database,
specifying the table schema and
the data types of each of
the columns in the database.
Once we get the database up and running,
we will get to write queries to retrieve
all the records stored in the database.
And then the following step is to modify
the adapter in the RecyclerView to
display the list of guests that
was retrieved from the database.
And then finally, we will get to write
some slightly more complicated queries
to add and
remove guests in the database.
Ready?
Well, let's get started.