So here are the solutions
to these five questions.
So first the two activities are named
CatalogActivity and the EditorActivity.
Secondly, the type of button that we're
using to connect the two activities
is a floating action button.
So notice that the toggle button,
if we looked it up in the documentation
is sort of like an on and
off switch, whereas the spinner
is similar to a drop down menu.
Third, which of these menu options
exists in either activity?
Well, there's a delete
all pets menu option,
as well as an insert
dummy data menu option.
Now for the fourth question
asking what view allows us to show
a dropdown menu for the spinner?
In this case we used a spinner.
You might have looked up what the picker
was in the Android documentation and
if you did, you would have seen that
it's a dialogue that's commonly used to
set dates and times.
Whereas the checkbox is
just a simple checkbox,
used to help the user select an option.
And for the last question of what
activity method did we need to override
in order to handle
the menu option clicks?
Well, that would have been
the onOptionsItemSelected().
So the onCreateOptionsMenu method
creates the options menu in the app bar
while this one specifically
the onOptionsItemSelected method
will help us set up what should
happen when the user selects one of
the options from the menu.
So we don't need to use
the onClick here because we have
this method here specifically
handling menu clicks.
Now let's take a more detailed
look into the starter code and
see where we found all these answers.
So once you've downloaded a starter
code run the app on your device, this is
the first screen that should open up and
this is our catalog activity.
So eventually we'll be building it out
so the catalog activity displays a list
of all the pets that are in
our shelter database.
Now down in this bottom right corner
here is our floating action button.
So clicking on it takes us to our
second activity, our editor activity.
So this screen allows the user to input
information about a specific pet for
just the name, the breed,
the gender, and the weight.
I also want to point out that the gender
here uses a spinner, which allows
the user to select from a limited list
of three choices about the pet's gender.
Now up here in the tool bar
there's a couple things going on.
First, there's a save button.
Notice currently clicking on
it doesn't do any action.
Eventually we'll be building it up so
that clicking that button
allows the user to save
information off into the database.
To the right of it is
this overflow menu.
Now clicking on that
pulls up a delete option.
This right now also doesn't
do any specific action.
But eventually we'll
be building it out so
that the user can delete a pet that was
incorrectly entered into the table.
Now back here is that up arrow,
it allows us to navigate
back to the parent activity.
And the parent activity here
is our catalog activity.
So notice here in the catalog activity
it also has an overflow menu.
Now clicking on that
displays two options.
Either inserting dummy data,
or deleting all the pets.
Neither of these doing action just yet
as well, and
don't worry we'll make sure
that we build those out.
All right so now that we know
what the app looks like,
let's take a look at the code.
So let's start with our
Android manifest file.
So this file contains all
the important information
about our app that the Android
system needs to know.
Things such as the package name,
the app name and activity names.
Now if we have an app that
has multiple activities,
the AndroidManifest also indicates
which activity is the parent activity.
In our case, it's the CatalogActivity.
Next, expanding out the Java folder.
We see this is where all
the logic of the app happens.
Let's skip over that for now and
head over to the res folder.
And remember,
here is where we store everything that
is related to the appearance of the app.
So things such as XML files,
images, and other media files.
Now on the layout folder here,
we have our activity_layout.xml file and
our activity_editor.xml file.
So these two files define the layout for
the two screens of our app.
And back under the res folder,
we have our mipmap folder.
And remember these are specific for
building out our app icons and
that is a big icon.
All right, so back to our resources
folder we have our values folder.
And inside here we can define files that
define the colors, the text strings and
the style, as well as any string
arrays that we're using in this app.
So specifically in this app we're using
an array to store the gender options.
Remember here we saw that gender
is stored in a spinner and
has three different options.
All right,
let's head back to Java folder.
So first off is the CatalogActivity and
this was the mainstream of the app
where the pet information
will eventually be displayed.
Now when this activity
is created in onCreate,
a floating action button is
set up using a click listener.
And this we'll use an intent to
open up our editor activity.
Now following that, is this method
here onCreate options menu.
And this creates the options
menu in the app bar.
The following method here, the on
options item selecting method, allows us
to set up what happens when the user
actually selects one of those options.
So currently the two options that
exist are insert dummy data and
then deleting all the entries.
But right now they're not
setup to do anything just yet.
So lastly let's check
out the editor activity.
So this activity is where the user
can either create a new pet or
edit information about an existing one.
So up top, we have several
private edit text variables
as well as a variable
down here called mGender.
So this variable sorts an integer value
that corresponds the gender of the pet.
So note that we can
only have three values.
0 that corresponds with unknown.
1 that corresponds with male.
And 2 that corresponds with female.
Now further down in this activity,
we have the onCreate method.
And here's where we connect all those
edit text variables to their views.
So all these added text
variables to their views.
And we also setup our
drop down spinner here.
Now in order to populate this
spinner with the list of options,
we needed to create an ArrayAdapter.
And that uses the string array that
we saw earlier that existed in
the res file.
So remember this one here, and so
that corresponds with this name here,
this array gender options.
So for this spinner we also
specify its layout and
the drop down style of the spinner.
So when the user selects an item from
that drop down spinner, this one here,
we check that selection,
do they select male, female, or unknown?
And depending on which
one they selected,
we set the variable mgender
to the appropriate value.
Now because we've created
an instants of the abstract adapter
variable class here,
and we did that inline.
We're required to define this
method onNothingSelected,
and I called that out
in the comment here.
So if nothing is selected, then by
default mgender is set to unknown.
All right so
the last thing you'll want to call out
in the editor activity here is
the onOptionsItemSelected method.
So remember this method here allows
us to set up what action happens when
a user selects something from the menu.
So the last thing I want to call out
here is the onOptionsItemSelected method
in the EditorActivity.
So here we can set up what happens
when the user clicks on a menu option
in the app bar overflow menu.
So remember we had our three options.
So one the saving check mark.
Currently it's not set up
to do anything just yet.
Next we have our delete menu option
also not plugged in to any action.
And then lastly, this android.R.id.home
case which allows the user to
navigate back up to the parent activity
which is our catalog activity.