Okay, after playing with
five by five isolation for
a bit, the average branching
factor seems to be about eight.
So we now we get an estimate
of eight to the 25th nodes.
>> That's about ten to the 22nd nodes.
>> Great.
That means that we only have to wait for
around 1.2 million years
to get our answer.
>> Yeah.
You're not going to be alive by then.
>> Them dang kids.
No good.
>> Thanks.
>> No problem.
>> Okay that means we need to be more
clever about how we make a computer
player for isolation.
The exponential growth of the game tree
means we can't brute force the problem
and search to the end game easily.
In general more interesting games
will not be searchable to the end.
Either the branching factor
is too large or the depth or
both, when the number of nodes which
we can estimate by branching factor to
the depth power starts becoming
comparable to the number of
seconds remaining in the life of
the universe, we know we are in trouble.