Greetings, salutations, and
welcome to the next lesson.
Let's talk about a very important topic
in software development, testing.
>> Automated testing can
bring many benefits.
It provides a safety net by
allowing developers to experiment,
add new features, and
improving existing ones,
without being afraid that that
will break existing functionality.
Automated testing helps catch more
bugs by streamlining repetitive tests.
Therefore, giving testers time to
spend improving the testing suite
as opposed to manually
performing the same actions.
Proper testing is even more
important when using continuous
integration and delivery.
>> Now depending on what your background
is and what you do day to day,
you might not be familiar with all the
different types of tests that can and
should be performed.
You might feel as if you're starting
from zero knowledge about testing.
But no matter what your background is,
if you have written and
run some piece of code,
it means you've tested it.
>> Also, what if I've literally
never written any tests?
>> Well,
in a way everyone tests a program
every single time they try to run it.
The test is, does this thing even run?
But of course that is not enough.
You also want to know,
does it run correctly?
Does it work under different
conditions and with different inputs?
Does it work fast enough,
and is it secure?
If it fails does it fail gracefully?
>> Right, and
you want to know all these answers very
soon after you've pushed your code to
the repository, not after it's been
deployed to a production system.
>> Right, so let's agree that
tests are pretty important, but
who should be writing these tests?
Developers, testers, operations,
security, product owners?
>> Maybe all of them.
Let's get into more details.