Let's recall some basic facts
about this type architecture.
Assuming perfect overlap
of computation and
data movement, you can estimate
the maximum normalized performance.
It's this expression,
which I've denoted by Rmax.
Rmax is defined in terms of W star,
which is the work of the best
sequential algorithm.
It also depends on the work
of your algorithm, W.
It depends on the works
overall intensity, I.
And finally, it depends on
the machine's balance point B.
In performance analysis, one way to
visualize the relationships among these
parameters is through something
called a roof line plot.
Start with a pair of x,y axes.
It's usually drawn as a long log plot,
but
let's ignore that fact for the moment.
On the x axis, you plot intensity.
On the y-axis,
you would plot normalized performance.
For this problem,
let's assume that W star and
W remain fixed, but I might vary.
This would happen if you had,
say, a bunch of algorithms or
a bunch of implementations that
all did the same amount of work,
but varied the communication.
The curve you would get if you plotted R
max as a function of I would look like
the following.
Because of it's shape it's
sometimes called a roofline plot.
So what do you see?
Well the plot has a linearly increasing
slope followed by an inflection point,
followed by a plateau.
The interesting features
are the value of the plateau and
the location of the inflection point.
Let's call these Y0 and X0 respectively.
Here's my question.
What are the values of X0 and Y0?
Express your answer in terms of i,
b, w, and w_star.
And when you type out w_star,
use the notation w_star.