The final category of connectors to
look at it are called Distributor Connectors.
They're role is also primarily facilitation.
They identify the interaction pads and they rout things among them.
In a sense, they are assisting other connectors.
A primary example here is DNS, Domain Name Services.
Whereby various components on the internet can talk to
each other using names rather than strictly by addresses.
Some of the variations that are possible with
distributor connectors include naming.
That is are they structured based.
Can they be hierarchical or flat?
Or are they attribute based?
What's the delivery policy?
Is it best effort, exactly once and so on?
And is the mechanism unicast?
That is point to point or multicast or broadcast, and then routing, okay?
Is there a bounded list?
Or is it more ad hoc?
And is the path static, cached, or dynamic?