Surprisingly it's, who knows?
Keep in mind, that dispatch_async
adds your closures to each queue and
then returns immediately.
Therefore, the print("end")
statement will likely run before
any of the closures get a chance to run.
Later on, the closures will run.
However, the precise order
in which each of them will
run will depend on how busy the queues
that you reuse are at that moment.
With dispatch_async inference we can
run things in the background, but we
apparently lose the ability to predict
in which order the code will run.
There is a way around this and
we will see it in the sample app.
Until then see if you
can find it by yourself.
We need the following.
Each print statement must
run in its own queue.
They should always run in the following
order, end, and then 1, 2, and 3.
Think of a way of achieving this.
I'll give you a tip.
It's much,
much easier than you might expect.
Think of the movie Inception,
dreams within dreams within dreams.
Think about it.