One question that you can ask is also, are threads useful on a single CPU?
Or even more generally, are threads useful when the number of
threads is greater than the number of CPUs?
To answer this question,
let's consider a situation where a single thread, T1, makes a disk request.
As soon as the request comes in, the disk needs some amount of time to
move the disk spindle to get to the appropriate data and respond to the request.
Let's call this time t_idle.
During this time, thread 1 has nothing to do but wait.
So the CPU is idle and does nothing.
If this idle time is sufficiently longer than the time it takes to make
a context switch, then it starts making sense to perhaps context switch from
thread one to some other thread, T2, and have that thread do something useful.
Or specifically rather,
we need the execution context that's waiting on some event to be waiting for
an amount of time that's longer than, really, two context switches.
So that it would make sense to switch to another thread.
Have that thread perform some operation.
And then switch back.
So basically as long the time to context switch, t context switch,
is such that t idle is greater than twice the time to context switch,
it makes sense to context switch to another thread and hide the idling time.
Now this is true for both processes and threads.
However, recall from the last lesson, we said that one of the most costly steps
during the context switch is the time that's required to create the new virtual
to physical address mappings for the new process that, that will be scheduled.
Given that threads share an address space.
When we're context switching among threads,
it is not necessary to recreate new virtual to physical address mappings.
So in the threads case, this costly step is avoided.
For this reason, the time to contact switch among threads is less to
contact switch among processes.
The shorter the contact switching time is there will be more of these
t_idle situations when a thread is idling where it will make sense to
contact switch to another thread and hide the wasted, the idling time.
Therefore, multithreading is especially useful because it allow us to
hide more of the latency that's associated with IO operations and
this is useful even in a single CPU.