So how do we find similar frames?
Again, what we are trying to
compare each and every frame,
frame i versus frame j, basically we
can do now is create a simple matrix.
And here is my output.
This is an interesting way
of looking at things, right?
In this case, assume that if it's
a black value, it's the most similar.
That is, they're pretty much the same.
If I did a Manhattan distance
between two pixels, two frames that
are the same, so if I just did say
that's our difference between f1 and
f1 itself, what would I get?
Well, I'd get distance zero.
In this case, zero would mean
a black pixel in this image.
So basically, this kind of starts
showing an interesting structure.
This is for
the candle example we've looked at.
And now we start looking at it,
you kind of notice that yes, the most
similar one is the image itself.
That's why the diagonal is black.
But once in a while, you see it
sometimes off diagonal and off course.
You also see other
frames that are similar
that are actually somewhere far off.
So, for example, here might be a frame.
This might be f50, but here it's f100.
That is also somewhat similar so
now I can actually look for
these types of things.
So, we can compute the Euclidean
distance between all of them for
all the N frames.
And now, basically,
this is what our major axes looks like.
These were the most similar.
So of course, one way of transitioning
in the traditional way in video is just
going this way, right?
We go from the beginning to the end,
and we play all the frames.
In this matrix here,
black are similar frames, because again,
the distance is almost zero, while and
white are dissimilar frames.
Similar frames are the ones that
would be the best to jump to.
So now I can of course go here, and
rather than go all the way there,
I can jump to another one.
Black are the most similar frames,
so I can move to this one.
And then of course I
can jump back this way.
And that's the looping we come up with.
So I've already just shown
you one simple loop.
You can imagine we can do
loads of loops like this.
I can go up here and
jump back and go there.
Go up here, jump here, and
come around and keep on looping.
And that was the yellow dot you
saw at the bottom of the candles
that I was showing you.