The answer for this should, maybe was
obvious, and that is, a pattern like
this, which basically has more circular
information going out from the middle.
Asymmetries and stuff like that
would be quite discriminative, and
in fact, when they did
the experiments in that paper,
they found this to be
the most discriminative.
This actually came out pretty good too,
and this is decent because again,
it has more information, but
this one actually came out more.
But, of course, a conventional
aperture came out as the worst.
This could have been
a little bit of a toss up,
this one was actually a really
good aperture design.
Of course in that work, they came
up with various types of metrics
to help you figure out
the best possible design too