So how can we answer?
Of course, one is cheaper but
the risk reduction is also lot smaller,
it's 150 only.
And it's the cheaper because it's 100K,
but
the risk is only reduced by 150 here.
Other one is two and
a half times as more expensive, but
it's reducing the risks lot more, 500K.
So, we said one way we can think
about it is risk leverage.
So the risk leverage was reduction
in risk, so the first case,
it's 150, divided by the cost,
and that's 100.
So the risk leverage is 1.5 for the
first solution, or the cheaper solution.
So this is 1.5.
For the more expensive
solution it's 500, the amount,
this is how much the risk is reduced by,
divided by 250 which is the cost.
So risk leverage is higher for
the more expensive solution, and
based on that reasoning you
would recommend this one.