So reviewing it,
sort of the pros and cons,
what's the biggest pro
of account filter.
It's all listed here as one but
look, it's just very simple.
You know those equations.
You just implement them.
You write them.
It's compact.
It's efficient.
It works pretty well.
You have to surf,
sometimes tune some things like
you never want to let your
process noise get too small.
It's much better to overestimate
process noise than under.
Why?
Because if you, for
example, suppose you didn't think
there was any process noise at all?
You thought this point is just there,
okay?
So you're taking measurements, well,
if there's no process noise, remember,
every time you take a measurement, your
uncertainty goes down, eventually you go
to an uncertainty of zero and you'll
stop listening to your measurements.
So it's always good to have
a little bit of process noise.
So there's some tuning to make it work,
but in general, it's pretty clean.
The biggest problems with it
are that it's first of all,
fundamentally a unimodal distribution,
right.
I've basically got a Gaussian,
which means I basically
have a single hypotheses.
Allright?
And
it's some uncertainty
within that hypothesis.
There are some other issues here.
Remember we have this linear model.
There are ways of fixing that.
There's something called
the Extended Kalman Filter.
Which basically just takes,
for those of you who care.
You linearize about your current point.
That's like taking a Jacobean
around a nonlinear system.
you currently estimate it linearly,
update,
then recompute your
equations in the nonlinear.
Prediction, so the linearity part
is not that big of a problem, but
this problem of [INAUDIBLE]
having a single hypothesis okay,
that's a Gaussian, that doesn't work so
well sometimes, so the question is
what you should do if the world is not
Gaussian or if it's not even unimodal
and the answer is, you should come back
next time, because we'll tell you then.