The answer is that you have a 1/3 chance of winning if you stick with door #1
and a 2/3 chance if you switch to door #2.
How do we explain that, and why isn't it 50/50?
Well, it's true that there's 2 possibilities,
but we've learned from probability that just because there are 2 options
doesn't mean that both options are equally likely.
It's easier to explain why the first door has a 1/3 probability
because when you started, the car could be in any one of 3 places.
You chose one of them. That probability was 1/3.
And that probability hasn't been changed by the revealing of one of the other doors.
Why is door #2 two-thirds?
Well, one way to explain it is that the probability has to sum to 1,
and if 1/3 is here, the 2/3 has to be here.
But why doesn't the same argument that you use for 1 hold for 2?
Why can't we say the probability of 2 holding the car
was 1/3 before this door was revealed?
Why has that changed 2 and has not changed 1?
And the reason is because we've learned something about door #2.
We've learned that it wasn't the door that was flipped over by the host,
and so that additional information has updated the probability,
whereas we haven't learned anything additional about door #1
because it was never an option that the host might switch door #1.
And in fact, in this case, if we reveal the door,
we find that's where the car actually is.
So you see, learning probability may end up winning you something.