I'll start answering this question by
looking at Apple's documentation for
the UIWebViewDelegate.
If we scroll down, of these four methods
listed, webViewDidFinishLoad definitely
stands out as the method
that we're looking for.
With this method we should have
access to the URLs that are being
loaded by a webview, including the URL
that's loaded after a user taps Allow.
Now checking for
this is surprisingly simple.
Back in the TMDBAuthViewController,
I'll start by implementing
webViewDidFinishLoad.
In this function, I can check for
the webview's current URL by
digging into this absoluteString.
I'll just print this value out first
to see what the URL is after the user's
clicked Allow.
So, we've clicked Allow, and
the last URL that's printed here,
this is the value we'll want to
capture in order to dismiss the view.
So let's stop this and
finish the implementation.
So we'll check the absoluteString, and
if it's equal to the AuthorizationURL
plus the requestToken and
allow, then we can assume that
the user's clicked the Allow button.
If that's the case, then we'll
dismiss the ViewController and
call the completitionHandler
that we stored earlier.
Let's see if this works.
And there we go,
the controller dismisses.