Fun examples of constraint, satisfaction
problems are cryptorithmetic puzzles.
Each letter represents a digit and all
the letters represent different digits.
None of the numbers start
with a leading zero.
Try to solve the problem and keep track
of the methods you use to attempt it.
It takes awhile to figure out these
values and it can be frustrating,
however by then end of this lesson,
we'll be using the strategy of back
tracking, with forward checking, using
the minimum remaining values heuristic,
and the least constraining
value heuristic.
This will solve the problem in
a principled and efficient manner.
These techniques are powerful tools
that can help optimize searching for
solutions for constraint
satisfaction problems in general.
Please fill in the boxes for
which number each letter represents.