Anamorphic images are ones that require the viewer to
look from a particular viewpoint to show the desired visual.
Other perspectives usually yield a stretched or distorted result.
Artists use their knowledge about perspective projection to
create some amazing illusions, like this Lego army designed by Leon Keer.
Viewed from any other angle, it looks strange.
This art activity popularized by Myrna Hoffman uses a curved mirror to
undistort a flat drawing.
Can you find other cunning examples of people hacking perspective projection?
Share with your peers in the discussion forum.
I encourage you to create your own, it's a lot of fun.
Check out this excellent instructable from Mr.
Grease Tattoo for some inspiration.