When you drag and
drop a file into a folder,
you're taking advantage of a computer's
GUI, or graphical user interface.
You're not actually taking a file and
putting it into a folder, but
it's a useful way of visually
representing a moved file.
The reality is,
computers don't have eyes, for now, and
that visual interface is just for
humans.
To speak directly to a computer,
you can use a command line interface,
which may look familiar if
you've ever seen The Matrix.
Programmers use the command line
because there are certain tasks that
simply can't be done with a GUI.
In fact,
anything you can do with your mouse
can be done from the command line, too.
Proficiency working with your computer
in this way will speed up your workflow
and prepare you for life as a developer.