Imagine that I've finished the Friendly
Chat app and I've already published it.
At first, my user base is growing, but
now when I take a look at analytics,
I'm starting to notice a drop in
active users and user engagement.
Also, when I take
a look at the database,
I notice that users are sending
some very, very long messages.
My hypothesis is that when users
are chatting with friends,
there's a good chance they don't
want to read an entire dissertation.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Back in the FCViewController,
the variable that handles message length
is set to a limit of 1,000 characters.
And I wonder if these long messages
are what's causing a drop in user
engagement.
This would be a great case for
using Remote Config to run an a/b
test to help find what is
the best message length.
But for simplicity's sake, in
the example we're about to show, we'll
change the Friendly Chat message length
for all users and not groups of users.
Back in the Firebase console,
we can create a variable using
Remote Config that'll allow
us to set the message length.
First, navigate to
the Remote Config tab, and
then we'll click
Add Your First Parameter.
I'm going to make a nod towards a text
messaging and certain bird themed
service and try setting the friendly
message length value to 140 characters.
That seems like a tried and
true amount of characters for
friends to use while chatting.
Make sure the publisher changes.
Great, now that Firebase console is
set up for Remote Configuration,
let's dive back into the code