So maybe it updating was
the wrong thing here.
We got rid of the spam, but
now we have way too much cheese.
Let's find out how to get rid
of the cheesy posts entirely.
Remember how bobby tables
deleted all of our posts once?
It was with the delete statement,
but delete can be used for
good as well as for evil.
We just need to be a little
selective with it.
Just like select and update, the delete
statement can take a where restriction.
And just as with update, you can task
that where restriction by using it in
the select,
before you go deleting anything.
And now you can probably clean all of
the cheese out of your database with
a single command.
When you're done, reload the forum and
see that all the cheese posts have gone.