All right, so here is the simple Harris detector algorithm, courtesy 1988,
still used today a lot.
We're going to talk about different versions of it, going forward when we
talk about scale and stuff, but for now, we're just going to talk about this.
And here's the basic algorithm.
You first compute Gaussian derivatives at each pixel.
Okay? So remember you need this ix and iy.
And we've talked all about how to do derivatives,
where you take the derivative of the Gaussian operator, apply that, and
you get back, your nice image derivatives.
Then, you compute that second order moment matrix M,
that M matrix that we were talking about.
And, the recommendation is you use a Gaussian window so that you
weight the points near the middle more than the points that are further away.
And then you compute, that R function on that M matrix,
remember you have a different M matrix for every point in the image.
Right?
Because you take a little window around a point, compute the moment,
compute R, move on.
So you do have one for every point in the image.
So you get all these Rs, you're looking for high values, you threshold that.
And then, and we talked a little bit about this when we were doing the edge
detection, you do what's called local non-maximum suppression.
Right. So I might have a heart, I might be a strong R value, but
if there's a stronger R value next to me, throw me away and keep him.
Sorry about that.
But the idea is that you're looking for
local areas that have the highest possible R value.
And like I said, this was presented originally in this paper in 88.