Let's step through this just a little bit.
So when we talk about building a panorama, what do we have to do?
Well, we're going to have to sort of align our pictures in order to be able to
paste them together.
That's what we just, just saw.
So to do that, here's the basic process.
The first thing we do is we're going to detect some features, okay?
And here features just means some interesting points.
In fact, we're going to define something called an interest point
operator that'll find some points that we define to be interesting.
Don't you wish you had an interesting person operator.
You could just scan it around a room, and
it would just tell you who's interesting?
It wouldn't go off a lot in my house.
Anyway, no, sorry, sorry hon.
So, here we've detected a bunch of points in in both images, and
these are going to be our feature points.
The next thing we have to do,
and, you know, just looking at this, it looks a little bit like a mess.
We need to find the corresponding pairs.
That tells us how we need to transform one image to the next, and
then we can use those pair to align the images.
And, if we do them in this particular example.
You get something that looks like this.
By the way the seam has been left in here just to
make it clear how that image is being moved.
If you were actually splicing these images together you would do
something you know sexy in order to make sure that those seams became invisible.
Now to do this detection and matching and
alignment, there are a couple of things that we have to worry about.
The first problem is well,
I can't possibly match points if I don't find them in both images.
And remember I'm going to detect interest points here, and
interesting points there, and look for a match.
So it better be the case that a point that's been found here to
be interesting is also found over there.
In this particular case there would be no chance to match.
Because I found some set of four points on the left, and
a different set of four points on the right.
So what we need is what is referred to as a repeatable detector.
If I run on this image, most of the points that I find over here
as being interesting, I will also find over here, over there and vice versa.
So that's the first problem, reliable finding them at all.
The second problem is let's assume that these points on
the left are somewhere in the right.
So I found here it's four points on the left, and
then there's four points on the right.
Which point is which?
Okay, I have to do the match.
The way we do that is what's referred to as using a descriptor.
A descriptor is just what it sounds like,
it's a description of this of a point, or of a feature to be precise.
What I want are distinctive descriptors, that is, you know,
if I write down the description of each of these.
So you can think of the description as being the name, right?
So I want this one to be Bob, Ted, Alice and George.
That's mixing some metaphors from the sixties, by the way.
because if they all said George, George, George, and this one says George, then
I've got a French movie, and I don't know whether, what's going anywhere, okay.
But if this one says Edward, it better be that one of these things says Edward.
Maybe if it just says Ed I'll be okay, but
my descriptor can't change that much of the same point in, in the two images.
So that's what we talk about it being distinctive.
You know, Bob, Carol, Ted and Alice.
That's who it was from the movie, right?
They have different names, but they also have to be reliable.
So Ed might become Edward, but Ed doesn't become Francesca.
All right?
So Feature points are used for all sorts of operations in computer vision.
Image alignment we talked a lot about, 3D reconstruction, Motion, Motion
tracking, I'm trying to figure out how either the object's moving or the camera.
Object recognition in fact, in a couple lectures from now we're going to
take some features on, from a bunch of different objects.
Take the features in our image, and
figure out up, it's this object that's in that image.
All right.
Database indexing, Robot, features are used for all sorts of things.
And that's one of the reasons why we have to talk about them in the class.