Now in fact, every time we have a polynomial function that has rational zeros,
we can be sure that whatever those zeros are, they'll be in this form. They'll
be the ratio of a factor of a constant term at the end of the expression,
divided by a factor of the leading coefficient. The coefficient of the highest
degree term. This looks like a super useful fact, and it's so useful that it
has a special name. It's called the rational zero theorem. Now, we're going to
have to add one little addendum to this rule in a second. But, first, let's
just look at it as it is. This is an incredibly powerful tool. It's going to
help us narrow down the zeros that we think a polynomial function could have,
from an infinite number of possible numbers. All the rational numbers, to only
numbers that fit this form. It's going to make our lives a ton easier.