As we saw in the last video
in order to bake our scene,
we needed to open up
the lighting window.
This window allows us to control a lot
of settings that will make our scene
optimized and really come to life.
To start with, it's divided into three
tabs, object, scene, and light maps.
Let's start with object.
In a similar fashion to the inspector,
this tab allows us to look at specific
properties of a selected game object.
For convenience, at the top of this tab,
we can filter out our scene by lights,
renderers and terrains.
Let's filter by lights.
If we now look at the inspector,
we'll see that all of the lights
have been filtered out.
Let's click on our directional light.
As you can see that brings
up our lighting component.
So, nothing really new,
just another way to look at our light.
Let's now filter by renderers.
In the inspector we can now see a list
of all of our geometry in our scene.
If we click on Any, the mesh
render component gets listed, but
this time there's a lot more
specific lighting properties listed.
As you can see, we can make sure
that our model is set to static
as well as tune parameters that
will effect how our model bakes.
For more information
on these properties,
check the additional reading.
The last filter is terrains, but
we actually don't have any
terrains in our scene.
If you want to learn more about them,
again, check the additional reading.
Moving on to the next tab,
we have the scene tab.
This tab lets us control the settings
of the light in our scene.
It's broken into six tabs.
Environment lighting,
pre-computed real-time GI,
baked GI, general GI,
fog and other settings.
We'll take a closer look at this
tab over the next few videos.
Last, we have the Lightmaps tab.
Once we bake a scene
like we did last video,
we can come to this tab to check out
how our lightmaps actually look.
Here, you can see the files and
textures that were actually created.
It's pretty hard to glean information
from the image, but this tab is useful
for seeing how much data is being
stored and if you need to tune
your parameters to optimize the number
of textures or how big textures are.
And that covers all three tabs.
Now let's start diving
deeper into the scene tab.