When you need to perform asynchronous
work, the work may not be isolated.
You often need to perform
multiple asynchronous actions.
And so you are in the chaining
stage of the course
where you will be chaining
promises together.
There are two main strategies for
performing multiple
asynchronous actions.
They are actions in series,
and actions in parallel.
Action in series occur
one after another,
like these three cats all waiting
their turn for the rocket.
While actions in parallel
all occur simultaneously,
like each of these cats getting
its own rocket to ride.
You could say that synchronous
code is always in series.
But asynchronous code can either be in
series or it can also be in parallel.
Neither option, series or parallel,
is inherently better than the other,
each has its own purposes.
In the quiz where you fetched
the list of planet jsons and
then performed a request for
an individual planet json You have to
perform the two requests in series
because one depended on the other.
But if you need to request a lot of
planet jsons, as you will soon be doing
in a quiz, then you will need to
programmatically send out the request.
You'll also want to make
the request in parallel
because that will reduce the amount of
time it takes to load all of the data.
So with that in mind,
here's a quiz for you.
There's a problem with this code.
It appears to be looping over the URLs
from the planet search query, but
something unexpected will happen.
What is it?
Is it that the requests
are being sent in series but
they will return in parallel,
causing some kind of collision?
Is it that the requests are blocking so
that this code will never finish?
Is it that the thumbnails will
be created in a random order?
Or is there just simply nothing
wrong with this at all and
I just gave you a trick question?
I want you to pick one
of these four answers.