Next up, we have Bake GI, which is
what we're primarily interested in for
our apartment.
Like with real time GI,
we can set our Baked resolution
to control how much data we store for
each calculation.
Since we're on mobile,
this value is actually pretty important.
We want to set this value high enough so
that the resolution of
our lighting is good.
But not too high that we run
into performance issues.
So let's set it to 20.
The next property is padding, which is
the separation between all of the Baked
calculations we do for every object.
Currently, it's set to 2.
If you go to the Lightmaps tab and
look very closely,
you might be able to see some small
spacing in between each image.
Now let's play around with this and set
the padding to 20 and then hit Build.
Now once it's built, let's go ahead and
look at our light map.
As you can see, there's a lot more
spacing between images in our light map.
But of course we're taking up
a lot more space in the map.
In general, we want to keep the spacing
small so as to take up less space,
which again is really important
on mobile for efficiency.
Let's go ahead and
set it back down to 2.
Another property we can play around
with is indirect resolution.
As you can probably guess from the name,
it's another map to capture
indirect lighting calculations.
Just like with our Baked light we don't
want to get extravagant with this
property, so
we'll keep it at a value of 1.
We also have ambient occlusion,
which is a property that lets us control
how ambient light bounces off and
gets included by meshes.
This property becomes most apparent
near the intersection of meshes
like the walls for our apartment.
Let's play with this by setting the max
distance on ambient occlusion to 10 and
then hitting Build.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
As you can see,
it creates a high contrast on our walls.
So let's set it back down to 1 and
then hit Build.
The last property I want to
talk about is atlas size.
This property lets us control the actual
size of the white map texture.
If you look at all the choices,
you'll see that they're all powers of 2.
This is because this allows Unity
to make performance optimizations.
If this value is too small,
it will result
in creating many small light map
textures, which is not optimal.
Too big, and
we'll be wasting space within our map.
Just to see what happens when
the light map is too small,
let's set the atlas size to 128 and
hit Build.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
This results in getting many small
textures, which is something we want to
avoid, as this results in a lot of
wasted time indexing several files.
It just so happens that 1024 is
the smallest size that captures
all of our lighting
data into one texture.
So let's go ahead and
set it back to that.
And that covers all of the core
components of Baked GI.
There are couple of properties
I skipped over, and
you can learn more about them
from Unity's documentation.
The last important section
to discuss is general GI.