There are several problems
with this rule set.
For example,
let's look at rule number four.
This rule allows inbound traffic to
any destination port above 1023,
whereas, the original intent is
to allow an inbound traffic,
that is part of the email connection.
In other words, it is more
permissive than its original intent.
For security purposes, we want to
make these rules more specific.
Therefore we can add another
condition to the rules.
This condition is on
the source port of the packet.
For example for rule number four,
our intent is to allow inbound traffic
that is part of an email connection.
Therefore the source port should be 25.
We can make these rules
even more precise.
For example,
because the intent of rule number four,
is to allow inbound traffic, there's
part of a established email connection.
We will want to check the ackbit of the
packet, and make sure that it is set.
This is because in TCP,
once a connection is set up,
the TCP flag in the TCP header is set.
So we can check this bit,
to make sure that the inbound packet
is part of an establish connection.