So, in summary, what I showcased today was basically the example, of how,
novel illumination, novel cameras, and generalized optics and stuff like that,
are foundational in the whole principle of computational photography.
We basically looked at one's example, dual photography, that actually
showcases how this be done to generate newer images, you are able to see a card,
which was not visible directly from where the camera was, but by just doing
control illumination and control capture, we can actually still indirectly
measure things that were not visible before to generate a novel image.
So in the next class,
I'm going to introduce the concept of computational photography with
another example, specifically we will look at panoramas.
The dual photography concept is really interesting and kind of makes you
want to think more about the extent of what computation photography can do,
more in the future and kind of things it's empowering.
Panorama, on the other hand, is much more real, it's something that's
available to you already, so for example, if you have a mobile smart phone,
it already has software to do panoramas, but basically the goal for
us now would be, is to study,how, images are stitched together to generate
larger image and pretty much open the black box of what panorama software does.
We'll relate back to the principles of computational photography, and use that
to kind of understand more about what we can do with computational photography.
Again, I encourage you to look at the dual photography paper mentioned here,
and, of course, thanks to again people that I've been leveraging off
their work to kind of explain these concepts.