So what we're interested in is a stable,
virtual camera, which basically means is
we're interested in finding a viewpoint
in the whole image itself, or
the video itself, that is actually much
more stable than the original one.
So here, basically, now we're
going to start seeing this red line.
This red line is going to start showing
you a virtual camera within the original
one, and our goal is to
identify from the data itself,
what's the best possible red
box here within the big one.
Do remember I did say things like oh,
most of the viewpoints that we're
going to get from these
cameras from wide angle, so
this does reduce the scope of
the viewpoint by a little bit.
We'll talk about variety
of aspects in a bit too.
So here you basically see now What we're
doing is basically tracking the subject
and the camera and
refining where this red box could be.
Of course in this instance you notice
the red box is going out of the range
and the domain, the aspect,
of the image Itself.
The challenges with this of
course is if that happens,
we really will actually start
creating problems for ourselves.
We really can't deviate too much from
the original camera, because if we do
like for example, when I see the red
box move to this side or that side.
We'll have to start filling in holes,
otherwise we'll get black
borders in the image.
We can't actually go to
content that we don't have.
We have to be always finding
the content that we have.
So we want to be able to get
this red box in a region so
I don't have to
synthesize other regions.
What that basically means is if I
actually just look at the red box
as it is.
And I started tracking it,
this is the kind of output I would get.
So as the red box moves, basically,
you start seeing black borders.
Yes, the subject is now more stable.
But, in keeping that stabilization,
you notice that I'm actually now
going out of the scope of the image.
And I have to then figure out
how to fill up that image.