[Thrun] So we just learned a number of things.
One is about complementary probability.
If an event has a certain probability, p,
the complementary event has the probability 1-p.
We also learned about independence.
If 2 random variables, X and Y, are independent,
which you're going to write like this,
that means the probability of the joint that any 2 variables can assume
is the product of the marginals.
So rather than asking the question, "What is the probability
"for any combination that these 2 coins or maybe 5 coins could have taken?"
we can now look at the probability of each coin individually,
look at its probability and just multiply them up.