I had a ton of fun implementing the real time visualization in D3,
and I hope you explore and
extend this functionality in your final project if you're interested.
Also, remember that Udacity's course visualization using D3
could be super useful to take if you want to expand on this brief introduction.
Let's explore the basic D3 implementation by navigating to the the app.pi file.
Scrolling down note that the decorator function, @app.route(*/basic*).
And function shom_basic calls the render_template method,
on the basic.html file.
Navigating to the Templates folder,
you see a few files that you should be familiar with if
you completed the optional personalization exercise in Lesson 1.
We navigate to the basic.html file, and
inspecting further we see that our D3 files are loaded via this source file, and
our second source file is under static/app.js.
We scroll down further to the body and
script tags, where I've defined a variable colors, and
variable svgContainer which stands for scalable vector graphics container.
This uses D3 methods to select the body, and
appends an svg element with the given attributes.
This is the svg container that is updated in our app.js script,
to visualize our tweets.
Remember, if this HTML and JavaScript section is interesting to you,
you can always explore this in much more detail in an HTML and CSS class.
JavaScript course or our data visualization, with D3 course, here, Udacity.
We then navigate to the static folder, and
open the file app.js, sourced in our basic.html file.
Well, since here, a familiar stream path that was defined in app.pie.
And if we navigate quickly to app.pie,
we see the stream path, and function response and event.stream.
And finally, the event.stream is connecting to retis and
the pubsub.subscribe function to the WordCountTopology,
connected to our publish function in our storm.report bolt.
Navigating back to app.js.
Notice that I'm using an event source constructor.
You can read about event source further by clicking on the Mozilla link
provided in the instructor notes.
And you can search for the on message, attribute.
This takes an event which is again a message received from our
redis subscribe method, and splits the method by a pipe character.
Let's again link this back to the syntax,
that we used in our report bolt Storm topology.
Navigating to any report bolt,
we see that the we have a word separated by the pipe character and the count.
Navigating back to app.js, we see that at position 0 we define our word,
and at position 1 we set our count.
Next using the JavaScript associative array which I've named hash,
I simply set the word =count.
Notice that I have another skip word check but
be removed after completing lesson three top and words filter, and by now you
should see that filter at this late stage in our data flow is very inefficient.
Remember to always filter as early as possible in your topology.
Scrolling down further, we finally come to the real D3 syntax,
that I've entered into an updateViz function for timing purposes.
We define a new variable text, that takes in the svg container and
the D3 selectAll, with text attribute.
Notice there are none to begin with, but the will be created by D3.
We then bind our data, using the D3 entries function on hash.
This entry function is great in that it takes a word count association, and
transforms it into a keyword value count association.
And this is the form that we are using throughout the rest of our D3, functions.
Additional information, along with a great tutorial, can be
found in Michael Bostock's selection page, included in the instructor notes.
Next, we enter this data by calling the text.enter function, and
append text with the given attributes.
Again following Michael Bostock's example,
I followed the selection.text with value.
Syntax by calling the text with an added word by using the d.key
notation, and remember that key maps to word coming from Storm.
Now that our text is the word coming from Storm, I added a few fun transitions,
delays, and explicitly tried to demonstrate how the x and y positions,
can be set using the d.value, which is again our account coming from storm.
Along with the position order that the word count comes,
in our associated array.
Next, again for fun,
I updated the font size, to be linked to again the value which is the count.
And finally the fill color, using our colors variable,
again linked to count and now position.
A fun demonstration of this,
can be seen by going to the forward /basic location.
And I'm running the solution from lesson two, stage four.
Notice that in the random sentence word count, as each word count is updated.
We see them moving in the y direction, changing colors with transitions, and
growing in size.
We can play along with this more by going into our app.js, and commenting out
the previous line and uncommenting out, a different fill function.
We save our app.js file, but
we don't need to recompile our storm topology, and refreshing the page we
see that the color palette has changed, to be a smooth transition to a dark red.
We can play along with this further by removing the dependencies in the order
that the words show up in our associative array by deleting, our I variables.
And we see now that x and y position is controlled only by the count, and
the two words in the lead are and and seven which are overlapping.
Notice that it's really simple to simply save and
refresh in chrome, and we don't need to rebuild our Storm topology.
This makes iterating on visualization super fast and easy, so.
Play along with this if you like, and maybe use some of these ideas in
your final project visualization if this interests you.