All right, let's try to load and display an image.
To load an image, we want to use the imread command.
The image will be stored in this variable img.
To display it, we want to use the imshow command.
Hit Test Run and scroll down to view the output.
A bottlenose dolphin surfing the waves.
All right, what more can we find out about this image?
What if we wanted to find out the size of the image?
You guessed it, we'll use the size function.
That returns the size of the image.
To display it, we'll use the disp function.
We can also find out the class or data type for the image.
Go ahead and
type out these commands, run the program, and note down the results.