With the Alpha-Beta Model,
an algorithm has three costs.
The message cost defines the first two.
It's essentially the latency, alpha,
and the inverse bandwidth, beta.
Now our algorithm will, of course,
do other kinds of basic operations
like comparisons and arithmetic.
Let's denote the cost per
compute operation by tau.
Now in practice,
it turns out the following is true.
Tau is typically much less than beta,
which is in turn much less than alpha.
To give you an idea,
you should be thinking of something
like 10 to the minus 12 seconds,
versus 10 to the minus 9 seconds,
versus 10 to the minus 6 seconds.
So something like three orders
of magnitude in between.
Let's suppose you buy this.
Here's my question.
Which of the following claims is true?
And I want you to check all that apply.
Is it true that computation is
less than communication, so
you should avoid communication?
Or is it true that it's faster
to send a few large messages,
rather than many small messages?
Or is neither of these statements true?