I'm Michael, a course developer here at
Google and a former Nanodegree student.
All of the course code for
this course can be found on GitHub.
The code has been divided
into exercises for you and
each exercise has been
separated into the steps.
We highly recommend that you try to
complete the programming exercises
independently, the best way to
learn is definitely by doing.
Of course, if at any point you do find
yourself stuck, each exercise folder is
paired up with a solution folder so you
can review the code changes made during
each programming quiz and
compare them to your own.
Something that used to get me through
early challenges when learning to
code was this quote,
The master has failed more times
than the beginner has even tried.
So remember, failure is just
a way to verify that you're
really working hard and
getting out of your comfort zone.
I recommend to start each programming
exercise by moving to the next project
folder rather than continuing
on with the previous folder.
You'll have plenty of time to build your
own apps after you've finished learning
here.
And staying in sync with the course
will save you time and frustration.
The code for each exercise step
contains helpful TODO comments that
Android Studio displays
in the TODO tool window.
So open the TODO tool window,
click on the TODO tab at
the bottom of Android Studio.
If you don't see that tab, you can
press Shift twice and type in TODO and
then click Enter.
Clicking on the TODO in the TODO tool
window will take you directly to that
code in Android Studio.
This will be incredibly helpful to
you as a student to quickly navigate
between required tests in the code.
These buttons on the left side of
the TODO tool window allow you to
easily navigate to the previous or
next TODO item.
Filtered TODO items get previews of
the source around each TODO, and more.
Each TODO is ordered with a number.
There's no strong need to follow
our ordering, but if you do,
the code can be compiled
without errors at each step.
If at any point there's a discrepancy
between the videos and the code,
the GitHub code repository should
be considered the source of truth.
Also make sure to always check
the text surrounding the videos if you
are confused.
We will often mention updates or
small discrepancies here.
If you think we've missed something,
you can report an issue.