So in lesson two,
you learned about the importance
of officially managing memory.
So this is critical in
mobile because phones and
tablets have much more
limited memories resources
compared to that of a traditional
large desktop computer.
You begin to see that resource
efficiency plays a significant factor in
influencing the way the Android
framework is designed.
And we saw this for
example in views recycling,
where we needed to design a way
to efficiently display data.
Now that's only half the story.
In order for the Android device to run
smoothly, respond quickly to user input,
as well as not drain the user's battery,
developers like you and
me need to be memory-conscious as well.
Now one of the most important
things you as a developer can do,
is to free up resources when
they're no longer needed, so
that other apps on the device
can use them as well.
Now Media Player is an excellent context
for this type of developer behavior.
So let's take a closer look at what
we have to do in order to play audio.
So first, we'll need to obtain
an instance of the MediaPlayer class.
And remember that whenever
you instantiate an object,
you're using some of the memory
allocated on your app.
And then you need to
pass in an audio file
which must consume memory in order for
it to play.
Now all these things take up memory and
it's also known as taking up resources.
So the optimal question or
task becomes two fold.
One, how do you determine when you no
longer need media player resources?
And two,
how do you free up those resources.
Now in order to determine
when you no longer need them,
we need to think back to the states
the audio media player can be in.
So we know that when we first
create the media player.
We used the create method and
it moves it into the prepared state.
Afterwards it moves into the started.
And then pause state, or
can move into the stopped, or
play back completed state as well.
Now there's a final crucial step here,
the end state.
So once the media player object is in
the end state, it can't be used anymore.
So we can move it into
any other state again.
So when the MediaPlayer is destroyed
the memory that was used by the player
can be reclaimed by the system for
other tasks.
So back to our original question,
how do you determine when you
no longer need memory resources?
Well our audio files are pretty short.
Only about a second or two long so
that means that playback will
finish relatively quickly.
So after it's finished playing.
We don't need these resources anymore.
So we shouldn't hang on to the media
player resources while wishing and
hoping that the user will
click on the same list item.
We should just release the resources
immediately by calling the release.
So this moves the player into the end
state so that the systems over claim it.
So for the documentation
specifically in this paragraph here,
it highlights that once the MediaPlayer
object is no longer being used.
I call the release method so
that the resources
are immediately released from
the internal player engine.
It would cause future media player
object instances, so ones for
future object files that we want to
play, to not perform as efficiently or
even drain the batteries that we need.
So if you would like
more details on this,
I highly suggest reading through
the release method documentation.
Now back up to the state diagram.
In the case of the user clicks again,
they will need to create
a new mediaplayer object for the same or
even a different audio file and
go through this entire
lifecycle once again.
Now in this exercise
complete the following tasks
to clean up resources
properly in our app.
So for this first step of using
the provided code snippet
to release the resources after
the sound file has finished playing.
We've provided you with
the code snippet for
a helper method that calls
the release method itself.
Now here's what that
code snippet looks like.
So it's called a helper method because
it performs a task that is meant to help
another part of your code.
So you can copy and
paste this helper method,
that we've named here releaseMediaPlayer
into the numbers activity,
as well as the other
category activity files.
So this method checks whether or not
the media player has been initialized.
So if the nMediaPlayer
variable is not null or
not empty, then we have
a invalid MediaPlayer object.
And we should call
release on that object.
So you'll see this checking
as common practice in Java.
So if you have a variable
with an object at a type, so
here in this case MediaPlayer, and the
default variable is null, meaning empty,
that means nothing was set
equal to that variable.
And before you call
a method on that variable,
you need to make sure that the variable
is referencing a valid object.
Otherwise you'll get a java error.
So once we've called release,
we can clear out the variable by setting
it equal to null and we use a no value
to indicate that the media player isn't
currently configured to play audio.
So back to this exercise instructions.
You can copy and paste that method
that we showed you in the code snippet
into all four of the category activity
files, and then call the method
once the MediaPlayer has
finished playing a sound file.
So you need to use what you
learned in the last exercise
about getting a callback when
a media file is done playing
in order to know when to call
the releaseMediaPlayer method.
And lastly, I would like you to
also call the helper method again,
in order to release the media player
resources right before we start to
initialize another media player object,
in order to play a different audio file.
And we do that.
So we clear out any resources Android
was using to play the old file
before moving on to
a brand new audio file.