So you might have noticed that
computers that are on the same network,
like an individual home, or business, or
school, usually have IP addresses
that are similar to each other.
To be more specific about it,
all of the addresses on a specific
network block share a particular prefix.
They all start the same and only differ
after some particular bit position.
And computers that are on the same
network block can communicate with each
other without going through a router.
But not all networks are the same size.
So when we talk about a particular
network, we have to talk not only
about its network prefix but
the length of that prefix.
A network with a longer prefix
has less of the 32-bit address left
over to distinguish particular hosts.
And a network with a shorter prefix
has more addresses for hosts, so
it's a larger network.
The network prefix length is
something that has to be chosen when
the network is set up.
And it's usually configured
by whatever process assigns
addresses to the computers.
For instance, if you have
a network with a 24-bit prefix,
that means there's 8 bits left over for
the host part of addresses.
We would conventionally
write this is as /24.
For instance,
198.51.100.0/24 network block.
But if the network prefix is shorter,
say 22 bits,
then there will be 10 bits left over for
host addressing.
This would be a /22 network.
And you can't tell how long the prefix
is just by looking at the addresses.
For these addresses either a 22 or
a 24 network would be a possibility.
So how many hosts can fit
on one of these networks?
Well, 10 bits of host address means
2 to the tenth power addresses,
which would be a 1,024 except that
the top and the bottom addresses of
a network block are reserved and
the first address is usually the router.
So 1021 addresses are available for
hosts.
Similarly in a /24 network, there would
be 256 addresses but minus those 3.
There are usually about 253
addresses that remain for hosts.
Now why does this matter?
Subnet misconfiguration can
cause some pretty weird problems
on a server network especially.
Things like one machine thinks that it
can talk to another machine directly,
but the other thinks that it has
to talk back through a router, and
that can cause very strange
communications problems.
Getting a good grasp of how the stuff
works can save you a lot of trouble if
you're ever setting up a server network.