Now that we've got
the fundamentals under our belt,
let's check out some
advanced Groovy features.
The first one is called the closure.
The closure is essentially a different
way of declaring a function.
But a function that can be packaged up,
passed around and assigned to variables.
You declare one just using
curly braces like this.
Closures are so-called because they
also capture variables from their
enclosing environment.
So, this value of foo will
always be one million dollars.
Let's go ahead and try calling,
since myClosure is a function,
we can call it just by putting parenths
after it, let's give it a try.
Awesome, there we go.
We're getting print statements
from inside the closure and
the value of foo is respected
inside the closure.
Unlike normal functions, closures can be
passed around to different variables.
So if we declare bar and set it equal
to myClosure and then declare yet
another variable baz and
set it equal t0 bar, we can then invoke
baz because baz is now a function.
And there we go.
By calling baz, we got the exact
same result as calling myClosure.
All right, let's do some really
tricky stuff, hold on to your hats.
So, closures have a different syntax for
arguments.
You put a comma separated list of your
arguments on the left side of an arrow
and then do whatever you
want with the arguments.
So I hope it's clear that this is
actually a function that doubles
it inputs.
The tricky bit is that Gradle allows for
higher order functions.
That is, functions that take as one
of their inputs another function.
For example, here we have applyTwice.
Its first argument is a function and
its second argument is just some
argument to be passed
through that function.
And what it returns is function
applied twice to that argument.
Let's check out an example.
If we set foo equal to 5 and
then we apply doubleIt twice to foo.
Well, let's see what we get.
Before we run it, see if you can figure
out what it's going to be ahead of time.
Well, let's see, five doubled is ten and
then ten doubled is 20.
Awesome.
Let's talk about lists in Groovy.
Groovy allows for a super simple list
literal syntax and also allows for
some very sophisticated list processing.
For example, we can execute
a closure for each item in a list.
We simply define our closure.
In this case,
it's just printing out each item.
And then we call myList.each and
then our closure.
Let's see what this does.
And there we go.
Each item in our list gets printed out.
There's a couple things we can do
here to make our syntax a little bit
more compact.
The first thing is we can
define our closure in line.
Note we don't have any
parentheses around here because
Groovy syntax is awesome.
Also, if a closure is
only taking one argument,
then by default that
argument is just called it.
So let's try running this.
And there we go,
does exactly what we expect.
Let's talk about classes in Groovy.
Groovy has a simplified syntax for
creating classes, but
the classes themselves
are essentially Java under the hood.
So, here we've got a class.
It's got a member variable,
it's got a method.
We can create a new one,
just how you're used to from Java,
and then we can ask it
to print its greeting.
We can also change the greeting and
ask it to print that greeting again.
Groovy automatically creates getters and
setters for
all of your member variables.
Let's give this a try.
And our outputs are just as we expect.
First printing the default greeting
then after we've customized it,
it prints the custom greeting.
Closures can have a delegate object.
Let's check out this
closure we've created here.
It's trying to assign to
a variable called greeting.
But greetingClosure doesn't have
Actually, the only place the greeting is
defined is as a member variable of this
class.
What we can do is set the delegate
of greetingClosure to be an instance
of GroovyGreeter.
And now, greeting closure can
access the member variables and
methods of that instance
of GroovyGreeter.
So if all goes well,
when we invoke greetingClosure,
after setting its delegate
to myGroovyGreeter,
it should be able to set the greeting
and print the greeting just fine.
Let's give it a try.
There we go.
We have successfully changed
the greeting inside the instance of
GroovyGreeter from a closure.
Well congrats on completing
our whirlwind tour of Groovy.
I know that was a lot to cover.
Fortunately there are a ton of
resources out there to help you.
We've linked a bunch in the instructor
notes and I strongly recommend
checking out this demo again in
the sample code provided with the class.