In order to motivate, we're going to go let's do the math behind some
simple fitting that you, that you already know.
I'm talking about typical least squares line fitting.
All right, so in least squares line fitting we're going to assume that you know,
we've got some data points.
X1, y1 up through x n, y n.
All right.
And, we're going to use that equation y equals m x plus b
because it's just easier to show what we're doing here.
We had done that whole polar coordinate thing for
Hough transform, we don't need to, to do that here.
So, least squares line fitting would say find the m and
b that minimizes this error function, okay.
And this error function, which says I've got some y and
I want you to find an m and b that minimizes the difference the y that
was actually measured and the y that would be predicted based upon the x value.
Okay. And that looks like this in the picture.
All right?
So the idea is that the distance that we're minimizing,
is the this vertical distance to the line.
How do we do that mathematically?
well, it's pretty straightforward.
We take our original equation, and
all we're going to do is we're going to essentially vectorize and matricize it.
I know vectorize is a word.
Matricize should be a word.
It's just like a really great word.
So, in today's day and age, I'm going to trademark that, so
if any of you uses it on Twitter, you have to pay me money.
All right, here's what we're going to do.
It's pretty simple.
So, this was our original equation.
Okay, where what I've done is,
I've turned this component into vector multiplication.
All right?
And then, because I'm doing this sum,
okay, over this squares, what I'm going to do is, I say, okay.
I take this vector minus these squares.
Okay, that gives me what?
That's another vector that is just the deltas between the y and the prediction.
And I say I want the magnitude of the,
of the square magnitude, which would just be the sum of the squares.
So that just gives me this very simple expression.
So I go through all this mess to get this very simple expression, y minus Xh.
Where the y here is this y vector.
The x here is this matrix of the x and 1 for
all the rows for each of the points.
And then this h, I just use h to be the parameter for m and b.
So what we have is this y minus Xh squared.
All right? That's our error.
And what we want to do, of course, is minimize that.
All right?
So I just expand that out.
That's what I have here on the bottom.
All right. Group the whole thing.
I've now got this equation there.
So E is equal to that.
Just copy that error function over again.
And we're going to take the derivative of that error, with respect to h,
and remember h was just the little vector and b.
If you don't remember how to take the derivative of a quantity with respect to
a vector, go remember and look it up, all right?
Transform that, get to this very simple picture, okay?
And what you have is h is equal to this quantity times y and
that's the pseudoinverse.
Right? So I hope you remember that from your linear algebra.
Basically this is just the standard over-constrained least squares solutions.
So the model fitting has something to do with minimizing squared error and
when you work that all out you get to the pseudoinverse least squares solution.