In certain cases you might not want
to translate parts of a text string.
For example you might want
to create a string and
then leave spots that can be
filled in later with variables.
In that case you want to mark off
the spots that shouldn't be translated
With an xliff tag.
It wouldn't make sense to
translate the user's name,
but it would make sense
to translate name.
So, when used properly,
this whole string resource would show up
as name Colon and
then the person's name, like Amy.
With the xliff tag you give it an id,
which is name,
and then you can specify an example,
like Amy.
Inside the xliff tags you would but
the string that shouldn't be translated.
In this case,
we're using the %s formatter symbol,
which specifies that a string will
be substituted in here later.
If you're wondering why we don't just
add the strings using the plus symbol
in the Java code, the reason is because
declaring it as a string resource
allows the translator to decide if
this is the right format for the text.
The translator may decide to flip
the order of some of these words,
so that it makes more sense
in the local context.
The translator only has control over
the words in the strings.xml file.
They don't have control
over the Java code.
For the xliff tag to be recognized you
will also want to add this thing to
the resources tag in
your string.xml file.
Now in the Java code we're going to
replace this part of the order summary
with our string resource.
Now we're using the order summary
named string resource and
we're filling in the blank
using the name variable.
Normally this getString
method in the activity
would take as argument one input
which is the string resource.
But now it takes in two arguments
because we want to pass in the name
variable and have that be inserted
into the blank spot in this string.
If your string resource had two
spots that needed to be filled in,
then you would pass in two
additional inputs here.
So that'd be a total of three inputs to
the method call, and so on from there.
If you want anymore clarification on how
to use the xliff tags, you can can check
the localization checklist which is
linked in the instructor notes below.