NFS has been around since the 80s and
has gone through several revisions.
The popular NFS versions that are in
use today and that come standard
with Linux distributions are NFS
version 3 and version 4.
There is one fundamental difference
between these two versions, and
that is that, according to
the protocol specifications,
NFS version 3 is stateless whereas
NFS version 4 is stateful.
The fact that NFS version 4 is stateful,
allows it by design,
to support operations like
client caching and file logging.
And although NFS version 3 is stateless,
actual implementation
of this protocol typically
incorporate additional modules so
that file caching and
logging can be supported.
The caching semantics
in NFS are as follows.
For files that are not
accessed concurrently,
NFS behaves with session semantics.
On close,
the changes are flushed to disk.
For files that are not
accessed concurrently,
NFS behaves with session semantics.
On close, all of the changes made to
a file are flushed to the remote server.
And then on open, a check is performed,
and if necessary,
the cached parts of the file
are actually updated,
so the new versions of
those files are brought in.
However, as an additional optimization,
NFS also supports periodic updates.
These are used to make sure that
there aren't any changes on the file
that the client is working with.
And using these periodic updates,
we'll break the session semantics,
when there are multiple clients that
are concurrently updating a file.
The periods on when these checks
happen can be configured but,
by default, NFS uses these values.
It uses 3 second checks for the regular
files and, at 30 second intervals,
it checks whether there are any
changes with the directories.
The rationale behind
these numbers is that,
the directories as files
are modified less frequently, and
that when modified it is
easier to merge those changes.
So we don't have to check for
changes in the directories as
frequently as we have to check for
changes in the regular files, and
still have a consistent system.
NFS version 4 further incorporates
a delegation mechanism where the server
delegates to the client, all rights to
manage a file for a period of time,
and this will avoid any of the update
checks that we described here.
With server side state,
NFS can support locking.
The way NFS supports locking is
using a lease-based mechanism.
When a client acquires a lock,
the server assigns it a particular time
period during which the lock is valid.
It is then the client's responsibility
to make sure that it either releases
the lock within the leased
amount of time or
that it explicitly extends
the lock duration.
This helps deal with situations of
client failure, so in this case,
when a client fails, on the server side,
we'll just realize that okay,
the lease for this client expired, so
we can assign the lock to somebody else.
And then when the client comes back
again, or when network connectivity is
re-established, the client will know
that the lease expired, it no longer has
a valid lock, so whatever changes it was
trying to make, it simply has to redo.
They weren't applied
in a exclusive manner.
NFS version 4 also supports more
sophisticated mechanisms than just
a basic log.
For instance, it supports a reader
writer lock called share reservation,
along with mechanisms
serve on how one can
upgrade from being a reader to being
a writer for a file, and vice versa.