As a final debugging exercise, I want
you to debug the problems that I've
introduced to the visual debugging
scene of the so many bugs app.
Now you may be tempted to just copy the
code from the final working scene, but
I highly encourage
that you don't do this.
Instead I want you to use the debugging
tools we've learned especially
the visual ones to debug and
fix the problems in the scene.
As you work through each problem that
you can find write the steps that you
take to debug the problem
in this text box.
And if you're feeling really adventurous
also include your hypotheses about what
is causing the bug before you fix it.