Our goal is to find the maximum
point in this graph or
any n-dimensional graph in general
which represents some goodness function
we are trying to optimize for a problem.
One way to do it is
simple hill climbing.
Where we start somewhere say
at the right most point and
then improve our answer by traveling
up the gradient to some maximum.
The problem is we can get
stuck in a local maximum.
Mark the methods which can be used to
un-stick us and find the global maximum.
Again, we do not expect you to know
the answer to the challenge question.
But it is a way for you to preview what
you will learn in this section and
determine how hard the section will be.