So based on your suggestion, Charles,
I wrote down a couple different
something elses that might be tried and
I want you to see if you can figure out
if any of these are actually any good.
So the idea of maximum likelihood
would be to say, okay,
well we should figure out which arm
has the highest expected pay off and
choose that but
keep revisiting the question.
So after you've done the pull,
recalculate your expected
values again and again.
Choose which one has
the highest expected value.
And just keep repeating that.
That way, as new data comes in,
we're factoring it into our decision.
>> And so there'd be a similar
argument for maximum confidence?
>> No.
Well, first of all,
I wanted you to kind of say whether or
not you thought that was a good idea.
>> That's a bad idea.
>> That's not a bad idea,
but it's a bad idea.
>> No, it's a bad idea.
So in this case,
if I look at a and b, right?
Who has the maximum likelihood?
B.
>> Right.
Well, the max.
Let me say it this way.
It's the maximum maximum
likelihood estimate.
>> The maximum maximum likelihood?
>> Right.
So the maximum likelihood estimate
for this is 0.5.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And the maximum likelihood
estimate for this is 0.
>> Right.
>> And so
this one has the maximum
maximum likelihood estimate.
>> Right.
Sure.
Right.
So but here's the thing.
Since a has 0 and b has 0.5.
I should choose b.
But, no matter what happens from now
on when I choose b, b's likelihood,
b's expectation will always
be greater than 0, right.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
I mean it will begin to approach 0
after an infinite amount of time.
But even if I never see a payoff again,
it'll still be something
greater than zero.
>> Right.
>> Which means I will never,
ever look at a.
>> So what does this strategy
actually turn into in this case?
>> Always b.
>> Yeah, so that works 70% of the time.
>> [LAUGH]
>> That's true.
>> But that means 30% of
the time you're failing.
>> Right.
>> And we can do better than that,
we truly can do better than that.
All right, so maximum confidence
says now the strategy is
whichever one you have
the best estimates for.
You should choose that one.
>> Well that's a bad idea too.
>> All right.
Why is that?
>> Because whichever one I start out
with having the most confidence in,
I'm going to pull that,
that means I'll get more data,
which means I'll have more confidence.
>> So what would it do in this case?
This would be equivalent
to what strategy?
>> Always b.
>> Yeah, all right.
So this is, we now have two
other ways of saying, always b.
All right,
what about minimum confidence?
>> So you'll alternate between a and b?
>> Yes.
>> Well, you may not.
You'll eventually
alternate between a and b.
I don't know.
I guess you do a, and
then you would immediately have
the same amount of confidence.
So we have to break ties.
>> Yes, so if multiple things
had the same minimum confidence,
it doesn't matter which one you choose.
>> Right.
Although, I guess I would choose
the thing with the maximum likelihood,
minimum confidence.
On minimum confidence of
the maximum likelihood.
>> Oh, if you break that tie,
it doesn't matter.
because what's going to happen is,
these are all,
all the counts are going to be equal.
Then you're going to choose one.
And then that one's going to have
some additional confidence, and
the other ones are going to be lower.
So you choose one of
the ones that are left.
You're going to end up going
round robin through all of them.
So at the beginning of each round,
you might break the ties
in some interesting way.
But then the rest of the round
you're going to be going through and
getting everybody up to
the same denominator.
>> That's true, but
given that at any given time,
you might take the bandits away from me,
I should always pick the thing with
the maximum likelihood to break the tie.
>> Sure.
>> But, your point is well made,
Michael.
>> All right, thanks, but the point in
this case is that you could do this
minimum competence thing and
you're going to over time get better and
better estimates of
the payoffs of the two arms.
But you're never really going
to use that information.
>> That's true.
>> Right, so if you're always
choosing minimum confidence you're
really just going to be uniformly going
through and choosing all the arms.
It's not a strategy that's going to beat
either of these always a or always b.
Well, it's not going to be
always b in particular.
>> It'll be half the time always a and
half the time always b, so to speak.
So, it'll be 50%
>> Something like that.
>> Actually, it'll just be uniform
over all the things that you got.
>> Yeah, yeah, so it will never
actually be picking the better arm.
Or half the time.
I guess half of the pulls in any
infinite run will be on the better arm.
>> Well, one out of K.
>> Sure, if there's K arms.
Right.
In this case there's two arms.
But that's right.
Good.
All right, so
these are something else and these are
not better than always a or always b.
So we needed something else,
even something or else.
>> Okay.
It's going to be some
combination of these things.
>> It does seem like that ought to help.
So in particular maximum
likelihood is not a bad idea.
Minimum confidence is
also not a terrible idea,
because it is at least
bringing you new data.
But you want to somehow
balance these two.
And what we usually refer to this is is
the exploration exploitation dilemma.
>> Oh, yes.
This sounds familiar.
>> So the minimum confidence arm is
going to get you better estimates,
but the maximum likelihood arm is going
to get you more reward, probably.
>> Right, in particular,
like we argued before, if I've only got
one more thing to do, I should pick the
thing with the highest expected value.
>> Yeah.
So okay, so.
To actually make up a strategy that
is going to do well in this game.
We kind of have to decide what
we think the right metric is.
>> Oh.
>> So it's not so clear yet
that there's one obvious metric.
I kind of suggested using
these check boxes that
what you want to do is eventually
always pull the better arm.
>> Well yeah,
of course that's what you want to do.
Eventually.
>> Well, no.
>> Eventually.
>> No, no.
>> Okay, well look,
if you know what the better arm is,
you should always pull it.
>> Sure, but
the point is that there's a lot of fun
that happens on the way to that point.
And so in fact, I think all the fun
happens on the way to that point.
So I think we need to kind of talk about
what kind of metric makes sense before
we figure out which
strategy is the best.
>> Okay.
That seem reasonable.