The first one,
hackers breaking into your system.
This typically means that there
is attack traffic coming from
untrusted parts of the Internet or
even from a known malicious site.
So this can be stopped by the firewall.
The second one, Internet traffic that
appears to be from a legitimate source.
Firewall cannot stop this.
The reason is that
the firewall is designed
to allow traffic from a legitimate
source, such as another trusted network.
The third one, viruses and
worms that spread through the Internet.
This can be stopped by the firewalls.
There are several ways to identify and
block such traffic, such as the volume
of such traffic or that said traffic
has specially crafted packets that are
known to target vulnerable surfaces, or
the traffic is from some untrusted
networks on the Internet.
In short, the firewall can use such
knowledge to block such virus and
worm traffic.
The fourth one,
spyware being put on your system.
It would be hard for
a firewall to stop this because
spyware typically steals information and
sends it out to a site.
The external site can
appear to be legitimate, or
at least not known to be malicious.
And the volume of traffic
can be very small.
The fifth one, viruses and
worms that are spread through email.
A firewall typically
cannot stop this because,
while the firewall can track that,
an email is from a legitimate source.
It cannot track the contents
of the email itself