Actually, password is a pretty
popular password people use.
It did make the top 10 list.
123456 actually has also
made the top 10 list.
Again, maybe it's the ease remembering
it that's why people use it.
123456789 is also on the list.
Here someone is picking
a longer password.
It's not weird if it's a stronger
password or better password, but
it's commonly used.
Qwerty is faster to type,
well actually that made the list also.
Some of the other ones that we have
here actually are on the longer list but
not on the top ten.
What else could be on top ten?
A lot of sports fans, baseball,
football, made the list.
Actually 12345, 123456,
12345678, 123456789.
All these are on that longer list.
So, I think one takeaway here
is that people put their ability
to remember their password, perhaps
ahead of how good those passwords are.
And they continue to pick
passwords that are pretty weak.
And we're going to talk about why
common passwords are a bad idea.