>> And welcome back. While we were away we actually had to sensley take home the
the Golden Brain for detecting a difference of under 2%.
>> That's amazing, I guess that you were proved wrong, but your human difference
threshold average of 3%.
>> Well, Andy, that is why they call it an average.
>> Well, either way, it's pretty amazing and even more importantly I'm okay and my
bleeding has stopped.
>> Andy, it was a paper cut.
>> Lauren, it hurt.
>> Well, I'm glad you're feeling better.
>> Thanks, but this bandaid actually feels a little weird.
>> How so?
>> Well, I don't know. There's all these little groves in it, and they're kind of
bothering me.
>> Hmm. That's your mechanoreceptors sensing that.
>> Wait. My what?
>> Your mechanoreceptors. They're little neurons in your skin that are sensitive
to different things, like grooves or texture, shape, even vibrations and
motion.
>> And each one is sensitive to its own specific sort of texture? >> Yeah.
>> That's really fascniating. It's almost like the rods and cones in our eyes,
which we use to.
>> Andy, I'm going to stop you there, I just gt word from Susan that they're
going to start the brain ceremony. We'll get back to that in a minute.