Now let's have our method actually
switch to an island scene.
First up, let's do some prep work.
So Unity only recognizes the scenes
in your build that you tell it about.
So we need to add both our starting
scene and our main scene to the build.
So let's do this by going up
to File &gt; Build Settings.
Okay, so you see the space here for
scenes and build.
We want to drag, both our island scene,
and the take of a vacation scene,
into this space.
So we want to make sure that
take a vacation is on top.
As Unity will automatically load the
first seen in the Build Settings list.
So let's do that now,
so take a vacation and
falling coconut,
which is our island scene.
Go ahead and close this window
now that you set it up.
All right, now go back to
the Change Scene script and
load it up in model development.
Since when we click the vacation block,
we want to go to the island,
we need to change the GoToScene method
to change the scene to the island.
Let's go ahead and
type some code to do that now.
The code for
that is SceneManager.LoadScene and
then the name of the scene to load.
So name of scene 2 load.
Okay, but we have some problems here.
If we hover over Scene Manager, it says
it doesn't exist in the current context.
That just means that it has no
idea what to do with this code.
And that's because we don't have
access to Scene Management yet.
There are a couple different
ways to solve this problem.
The easiest one is to just right
click on this, go to Resolve &gt;
using UnityEngine SceneManagement.
That's because MonoDevelop is smart
enough to guess what you actually
want to do here.
So if you click that you'll
see it creates a line up here
called usingUnityEngine.SceneManagement.
But I'm going to Ctrl+Z and
undo that, and
manually type that up here at the top.
So I'm going to type,
using UnityEngine.SceneManagement.
And this gives us access to
the Scene Management name space,
which you might remember from the Unity
documentation lesson earlier.
So that lets talk to the Scene Manager,
which gives us access to
the Load Scene Method.
Then inside of the Load Scene Method,
you have a string that is
the name of the scene to load.
This actually needs
be the islands scene.
So let's go back to Unity, go find our
island scene which was falling coconut.
I'm going to click once and it's
going to select the name of the scene.
I'm going to press Ctrl+C to copy, and
then I'm going to go
back to Monitor Develop.
And then I'm going to replace that
string with the name of the scene,
which is 00 FallingCoconut.
Okay great, instead of typing the name
of the scene here I could also
use whats called an Index.
Which is the name or the number of
the scene, so scene 0, scene 1, scene 2.
That's a different way of doing it, but
for right now let's do it
with the name of the scene.
Go ahead and save the script,
go back to Unity, and hit play.
All right, and
now try clicking on your vacation block.
[SOUND] All right!
We just went on vacation.
So nice.
[SOUND]
[