Now you have to find the two
types of content URIs
that the to do list app will use to
do things like insert and query data.
The first type gives us access
to a directory of tasks.
And the second to a single task.
And you've added constants in your
contract class to help you refer to
these URIs.
But how does this all fit in
to how the provider works?
The provider has to have a way to
recognize the different URIs that
are sent to it, and based on the path,
match it with specific data.
So whether it receives a URI for
a large directory, or
just a single row of data, it can
interact with it correctly in each case.
And it's up to you to code
this URI recognition.
>> One way to recognize specific URIs
would be look at the URI that's passed
to your provider whenever data is
accessed, parse it as a string and
see if that string matches the format
for a directory or a single row of data.
For example you could write an if
statement like, if the UriString.is
equal to
content://com.android.todolist/tasks
then you know that this URI
identifies the tasks directory.
But this becomes tricky when you want
to check if a string has an integer ID
at the end.
And these statements can become
really long and hard to read.
But there's a better way to do this
with something called a UriMatcher.
It's the job of a UriMatcher to
determine what kind of URI the provider
receives.
And match it to an integer constant, so
that you can easily make a switch
statement instead of using
a series of long if statements
that check for equality.
Using a switch statement will make
your code much more readable.
And this will be easier to
understand in actual code.
So in our TaskContentProvider code,
let's build a UriMatcher so
that it can identify the two
types of URIs we defined.
The first thing I'll do in this code,
is create the integer constants
that these URIs will match to.
I'll make these final end variables,
since we'll be using them
throughout this code.
I'll name one, public static final
int TASKS and set it equal to 100,
this will be the matching integer for
the whole task's directory.
Then let's make another
called tasks with ID = 101,
which will match a single
row of data in our table.
It's convention to have
integer constants for
whole tables be rounded numbers,
like 100, 200, 300 and so on.
And for
smaller sets of data in those tables,
like single rows,
they usually match to a related int.
Like 101 or 102 in this case.
Okay, so we've defined integer constants
for our tasks directory and for
a single task.
Now let's actually build
our UriMatcher and
associate these constants
with the correct URI.
I'll be writing a helper
function called build UriMatcher
to help me in this process.
In this function I'll first need
to create a new UriMatcher object.
I can do this by passing in
the constant UriMatcher.nomatch
to construct an empty matcher.
Then I'll add the matches I want.
Which just means telling it which
URI structures to recognize and
the integer constants
they'll match with.
And I'll do this one by one,
calling the add URI function.
I'll use UriMatcher.addURI and
pass in three arguments.
The first is the content authority.
The second is the path string, and
together these two tell the matcher
what exact URI you want to recognize.
Then the third argument is the int
constant that I want this URI to match
with.
So let's add the URI match for
our directory of tasks first.
This URI points to our tasks table.
It has the same authority we've been
using that's stored in our contract.
And the path is just
the name of our tasks table,
which is also stored in our
contract as path_tasks.
Then our third argument will be
the end constant we defined earlier,
named tasks, which is the value 100, and
identifies this URI as
the multirow directory of tasks.
And then we need to define the URI match
for a second URI, for a single item.
This follows the same
structure as before,
plus this # symbol added to the path,
which stands in for
any numerical ID that points to
specific row in the database.
So as long as the URI has an integer
after the initial tasks path, this
matcher will recognize it and associate
it with the int constant task with ID.
These are the only two URIs we
need the matcher to recognize.
So to complete this helper function
you just need to return this
complete matcher.
You'll also want to declare this matcher
as a global variable named suriMatcher.
This is like a member variable, but
starts with a lowercase s
because it's a static variable.
This way you'll be able to access
this UriMatcher throughout your
provider code, and don't forget to
set it equal to the return value
of the buildUriMatcher method.
And later you'll need to refer to
the matcher to deal with different URIs.
For example,
after creating the UriMatcher,
you can call UriMatcher.match and
pass in a URI.
The match method returns an int value,
which will be the integer that you
associated with the passed in URI
structure using the add URI method.
And once you have this match number,
you can write a switch statement
to program different behavior for
a match equal to tasks.
Or to task with ID,
such as deleting all tasks or just one.
And if there is no match found that
means the URI is unknown to our matcher.
And later we'll add code
to handle that case too.
The next quiz, we'll give an example
of this matching process.