So what about a 2-D Algorithm for
a 2-D mesh or torus?
In fact, somehow intuitively, a 2-D mesh
or torus should be a better match for
matrix multiply given the fact that
matrixes are in fact themselves
two dimensional.
You can't keep me on a linear network,
weeee.
Here's an elegant algorithm called the
summa algorithm, that's summa not sumo.
We'll put a reference to a paper on
summa in the instructor's notes.
Summa starts with a 2-D distribution
of the matrix operands.
Each node is responsible for updating
a part of the C matrix that it owns.
For example, consider this node.
You know that eventually the owner of
this block needs to see all of this
block row and all of this block column.
The SUMMA algorithm
accomplishes this as follows.
First, it iterates over
vertical strips of A and
the corresponding
horizontal strips of B.
At each step, let's denote the current
strip by the index little l.
Now the strip can have any width in A or
height in B.
Let's denote the strip
dimension by little s.
Algorithmically, you can think of all
processes synchronously executing a for
loop that iterates over these strips.
Now in order for
all nodes in this block row or
this block column to proceed, every
node needs to see the current strip.
That means the owners of the current
strip need to send a copy to
all relevant nodes.
For example, this strip of A needs to
go to all processes in its block row.
The owner of the strip can simply do
a broadcast within the block row.
Now a similar thing should
happen in the block column.
Once both strips have arrived
each node can do a local update.
So what's the running
time of this scheme?
To keep things simple let's
assume square matrices and
a square process grid.
And though it's not hard to generalize
let's also assume that the square root
of P which is the dimension of
the mesh and little s the strip size,
both divide the matrix dimension in.
First observe that there are n
over s iterations of the loop, and
each iteration does the same thing.
Now for the cost of each iteration.
Let's start with the update step.
Each of these strips
is n over root p by s.
We can use that fact to compute
the number of flops for
this local update step.
This is the cost of the update step,
assuming that each flop costs tau.
Multiplying this out, the total
flop time is 2 tau n cubed / p.
What about the communication time?
The communication time is essentially
just the time for these two broadcasts.
Mm, I wonder how much time that costs?