Here's the solution.
To create your mLocationRequest,
you just simply call
LocationRequest.create and
then to set the high accuracy priority,
you call LocationRequest.setPriority and
pass it a constant
PRIORITY_HIGH_ACCURACY which you'll
find in the location request class.
You've already set the interval to 1000
milliseconds so then finally, all you
have to do on the FusedLocationApi
is requestLocationUpdates and
pass it to GoogleApiClient,
to LocationRequest, and this
referring to this activity so that the
call backs will come to this activity.
All of these code should be on one line,
I've just broken it up into separate
lines here for easy reading.
Now because you were
requesting location updates,
you'll need to implement a call back
called on location changed which,
as its name suggests, will get
called whenever the location changes
even just a little with this interval
and this high accuracy determining that.