Welcome to our next office hour.
We are recording according to questions you all sent us.
Okay, well let's get right started.
The first question is from Incu in New York.
It says while AI strategies for chess, a two-player deterministic adversarial game,
have been successful in beating professionals,
no strategies can compete with strong amateurs in Go.
What makes Go so difficult?
Go is just a game where people shine really well.
There are two problems for computer programs in Go.
One is called the branching factor,
because the number of combinations goes up so fast you can't search very dep.
The second is there are no good ways for computers right now
to really evaluate board positions they are so complex.
Even though advanced Go players play well,
beginners don't even understand what's going on because there are very different heuristics.
So far it's been an open challenge. We invite you to solve it. It would be really amazing.
That'd be great to see. Here's another challenge.
This comes from Jay Bochi who says what techniques would you recommend
for a game like the AIChallenge.org, which a game where you can put in your strategy
and move these ants around on a board.
I guess I have to say I'm not really sure. I haven't studied the game that carefully.
But I would suggest in most games that are like that what you start off with
is finding a bunch of little strategies.
How you can have your ants move around and find foods
or have two combined to do an attack or something like that.
You get a repertoire of actions you can do, and then try using reinforcement learning
to put them all together and see what works.
Yeah, I remember actually for a real game, which was backgammon,
Gerald Tesauro used to be the person who wrote the world's best backgammon program
called TD-Gammon, and at some point I ran into him at a conference,
and he said, "Wow. We had a student who did equally good a program,
only much, much simpler."
He used a linear simple deliberation function he crafted by hand
and then just randomly played to play the game all the way to the end,
which you can do if you randomly guess your dice
and just play your calibration function.
That kind of yielded--we played a couple of times--equally good performance
as the world's most amazing neural-network based TD-Gammon.
I was surprised, and so was he. It was really interesting.
Sometimes being creative about how you valuate things is actually really useful.
"How can we plan strategies instead of single moves?
If you can calculate the optimal policy, that's okay,
but in most cases you should deal with approximations,
and calculating strategies might be useful.
For example, something like occupy the center of a chess board and then--"
This is a question from Andre in Russia.
So Andre, the occupy the center is a great idea,
and that's been handled well by a lot of chess programs that have heuristic functions
where they put some weight o occupying the center,
and they have ways of calculating how well you control the center.
But the "and then" part--boy that's really hard.
So far, the leading chess programs haven't been very good at that.
There has been some attempt to use planning techniques like we discussed in class
to plan strategies, but they tend to be beaten out by the techniques that just look farther ahead
using alpha-beta pruning over a min/max search.
I should say pretty much any interesting program stops at some point,
because you can't search to exhaustion.
And also, features like occupy the center of the board in chess,
that's usually features related to the safety of the king, to the pawn structure,
to the number of pieces you have and where they are,
and how much control you have, how much mobility you have.
Those together are usually the ones that give you a good performance.
One of the interesting things has been, in the game playing domain,
to come up with a really good evaluation function that captures the generic goodness of a board.
You can argue if you do this perfectly well, you wouldn't even have to plan strategies.
You just take the best move and be done with it.
The next question is from Pedro in Santiago, Chile.
How do you extend the algorithms to support multiplayer games with more than 2 players
given there's no single min or max?
I always find it hard to find more than one, honestly. We're not playing, right?
Most people I can't even get one player. I'm happy to find one player.
Well, maybe know you'll have 40,000 friends that you can play with.
Oh my god, I would lose.
Yeah, I guess in some sense we cheated,
and we made the descriptions of the algorithms a little bit simpler by assuming
that they were zero-sum games and so min is the opposite of max.
If you don't have a zero-sum game, either because there're more than one player
or just because there are different outcomes, then you can't really
quite say that min is the opposite of max.
What you do is every player has got their own utility function,
and they're trying to maximize their own utility.
It's really max/max, but the max that you're trying to maximize is different at every node.
The function is a little bit different, but you can work that out.
Then I guess the tricky part ends up being a kind of diplomacy around
players forming consortiums to say I'll team up with you and together we'll tackle this other guy.
That's really more game theoretic rather than minimax.
That's illegal in many games, right? >>Yeah. >>That's the hard part.
If you know that everybody is maximizing their own utility,
you can plug in the same methods we talked about.
You just have to maximize for each player individually,
but, again, if they team up then it becomes really, really difficult.
If you don't know whether they're teaming up, it becomes even harder.
These are all open questions in artificial intelligence.
Let's jump down to this question from Jeanna.
It says, "In question 14.5 why is there no dominant strategy for A and B--
the best strategy to sell Blue-ray regardless of what the other does?"
Jeanna, I think you have to look more carefully at the payoff matrix,
because I think that's not true that if they both go with Blue-ray then they'll both do great.
But if one of them switches to DVD then the other one should also switch.
So it's not true that you should stay with Blue-ray no matter what.
Question from a student in Greece. Welcome.
In the fourth video, since the arguments of inspect are 10 and we only have 9 elements,
can we even consider using the inspect action? Shouldn't the path be much less?
That's a great question.
You have to go back to the way that the interpreter works for actions,
which is you have an action that's got a bunch of unbound variables and you have to find
bindings for those variables among the objects in the domain,
but the interpreter for actions doesn't know that they all have to be different.
You looking at it and understanding what the action does,
you can say that it's obvious they have to be different,
but that's not true for variable binding.
It just says you have any variable in computer.
They don't all have to have different values unless it works out that way.
So the way the interpreter works is it just goes through,
and it tries all possible values for the first variable,
all possible values for the second and so on.
Then it's the constraints within the preconditions that tell you whether that's going to work or not.
It still has to backtrack through them all.
This is on past content, not on the latest weeks' stuff, but we welcome that.
This is from Dave, who says, "I've read that Bayesian models cannot over fit.
That's reading from Bishop's book from 2006, which is a great book.
The phenomenon of overfitting is really an unfortunate property of maximum likelihood
and does not arise when we marginalize over parameters in a Bayesian setting. Can you discuss this?"
There is some truth to this, but it's not going to be as black and white.
Maximum likelihood tends to be more prone to overfitting given a model class,
because it basically puts all the eggs into one basket,
which is fit the data as good as possible.
What's being referred to here is Bayesian models.
There's often a prior over the parameters themselves,
and calculating the best model or the best model class wasn't being considered
in some Bayesian fashion of being integrated out.
As a result, the answer is usually less impacted by the data than it is for maximum likelihood.
The result looks smoother. There is certainly more bias in the learning algorithm.
More bias means less chance of overfitting.
Unfortunately, there's no free lunch, because if your priors are wrong, you might get a really bad answer.
It might not overfit, but you might still get a very bad answer.
So I think it's worthwhile solving studying these methods. I think they're very valuable.
But there is really no free lunch here.
Yeah. I would agree with that.
You'll get an error that maybe you won't call the error of overfitting,
but there's still a possibility of error depending on how good your prior judgments are.
Here's a question from C. Baird in Indiana.
"You mentioned that common filters are used more in control theory in previous office hours.
How would you characterize the different between AI and control theory?
Different problems or applications? Different approaches? What is the overlap?"
I guess I have to answer that one? >>Yeah, you're the robot guy.
Well, I can tell you AI is much more fun than control theory.
At some level there are a couple differences in methods.
AI, for one, looks at much more discrete decision spaces with discrete variables.
But for this specific question, I think we are both looking to continued spaces.
It tends to be the case that AI is more courageous.
So in classic control theory, you often deal with what is called linear models,
and you are really concerned with proving things like stability and so on--optimality.
In AI, AI researchers tend not to care that much about it,
and that's bad and good at the same time.
The methods tend to be much higher dimensional.
People are much more courageous in doing something crazy.
At the same time, in doing this, they'll actually scale up to much harder problems
than some of the control theory people have scaled up to.
For example, my colleague at Stanford has his wonderful work on flying helicopters through acrobatic maneuvers.
The type of techniques he uses are much more AI techniques than control techniques
even though they are clearly solving a control problem.
If you look at this machine learning class, you find that there is
much more elaborate and risky methods, so to speak.
They're much more courageous, but also give better results.
That is actually changing. I think the field of AI and controls is growing together.
People are exchanging more methods.
AI has become certainly mathematically more solid in recent years
and has rediscovered the common filter as actually a Bayesian method.
Control theories are being impacted by things like particle filters that no conversion proofs
but tend to scale really well in many practical applications.
I think the difference is vanishing.
Yeah, I would agree with that, and I could say in some ways the difference
between AI and control theory is kind of like the difference between game theory and mechanism design
in that the control theorist says what's the math that I know?
Then let me build something that fits the math so that I can control it with what I already know.
Whereas an AI person is more likely to say
I'm not in charge of designing what it's going to be like.
I'm given a phenomenon and now I want to analyze it the best way I can.
There's question from Belgium from J. Vurm.
What are the extra ideas in genetic evolutionary algorithms compared to those we learned about?
For example, MDPs which change and converge with every value iteration as an example we learned about--MDPs.
How could a genetic algorithm solve the same problem that MDPs solve?
We haven't talked much about genetic algorithms. It's an important part of AI research.
Of course, we can't cover everything in this short class.
I guess the reason we haven't covered it is because I tend to think of it as just another version of search.
In search we have a configuration or a state, and then we search to the next state,
and we keep going like that.
We discussed that problem in terms of saying you're at one state,
how can you change that state to get to a neighboring state?
In genetic algorithms, it's the same thing, except that the neighboring state
comes by mating together two different states and combining them.
Sometimes that's a great thing to do. They're very useful techniques.
People have gotten good results from it,
but sort of theoretically, I don't think it's that different.
That's one reason we haven't covered them yet in this class.