Another important trend in systems,
is the growing gap between compute
speed and communication speed.
Recall the basic
Von Neumann architecture.
It has a processor, a local fast memory,
and it's connected to a large but
slow memory.
Now, let's say the processor can
perform R operations per second.
As it turns out, this rate is
related to transistor density.
Transistor density is basically
the number of transistors that can
fit in a given amount of space.
Here's the classic plot of
transistor density over time.
Essentially this plot shows
that over the last 40 years or
so, the number of transistors that
you can fit in a given unit of area,
has increased by a factor
of about a million.
Now very roughly speaking,
as transistors get smaller you get
more of them, and the signaling
time between transistors shrinks.
This makes computation faster.
With respect to this plot, just think of
the number of operations you can do in
a unit of time,
as growing with transistor density.
Transistor density and therefore
performance has grown very, very fast.
This plot suggests that performance
doubles roughly every 1.9 years.
The other feature of
the Von Neumann system,
is the slow fast memory transfer cost.
Now, let's say you can move data
back and forth between slow and
fast memory at some rate.
Let's call that rate beta, measured
in units of words per unit time.
Like R, beta also has a natural
historical growth rate.
There's a standard benchmark called
stream that measures this growth.
So stream measures beta, and
beta has essentially doubled
once every 2.9 years.
Now, recall that the balance point of
a Von Neumann system is the number of
compute operations it can do
per word of data transfer.
Let's call the balance point capital B.
It's defined as R divided by beta.
In other words,
it's the peak compute throughput
divided by the peak memory bandwidth.
Here's my question.
What is the doubling time of B?
I want you to enter your answer here in
years, given to 2 significant figures.