Don't worry if you don't
know all of these by now.
Take the best guess that you can and
by the time you finish this course, this
will hopefully be second nature to you.
So first of all, you'll create
a blank that uses your desired API.
What do you think that would be?
Secondly, you extend your activity
with the blank call backs.
Which call backs do you
think they would be?
Third, you also extend your
activity with the blank listener
in case the connection fails.
And then, finally, after connecting
the blank, you'll wait for
the blank callback.
What do you think these will
be I'll give you a clue.
The answer in one and
the beginning of four are the same.
And which callback do you
think you'll be waiting for
when you connect to the services?
Once you've done all of this,
you'd then follow the requirements
of your specific API.
Fill out the blanks and then continue.