We answer this question by first writing down the fundamental equation here,
which is delta x over f relates to B over Z.
To see this, we find by equal triangles that this triangle over here
described by Z over B, is the same as these 2 things over here
put together into a single triangle, which is delta x over f.
This proportionality must be the case.
This can now be transformed to solve for Z.
Z equals f over delta x B.
If we plug in f with delta x, we get 10 times 0.1 which is 1.
We can resolve B is delta x over f times Z.
We plug in delta x, 0.05, divided by 50 is 0.001 times 100 gives us 0.1.
We can also resolve it for f, which is Z over B times delta x.
Z over B is 10 times delta x as 0.1 gives us 1 over here.
Finally, we can resolve it for delta x.
B over Z times f. B over Z is 1/50 times f as 200 gives us 4 over here.
All the units fall out by themselves.