To build this layout,
I open up the activity_main.xml file.
I know that I need a vertical linear
layout to put each of these views
in a vertical column.
So, I'm going to first change the
relative layout into a linear layout.
Immediately, it shows an error saying
that the opening tag does not match
the closing tag, so I can just copy
this over and then paste it down here.
Now the tags match.
Next, I can add in the views.
First, I have a quantity text view.
So I'm going to take this text view and
then change the text inside to quantity.
Next, I have a text view that says zero.
So I can copy the first text view and
paste it below it.
I'm going to change it so the text says
zero to match the screenshot here.
The last child in this
linear layout is a button.
We haven't added a button before in our
layout, so let's Google Search that.
If you open up a browser you
can search for button android.
This first link looks good,
it's a developer.android.com site.
And here's the documentation for button,
we can ignore most of this text here.
We scroll down to read
the class overview.
It talks a little bit about some Java
code, which we haven't learned yet but
down here we have some xml for a button.
We can copy this and
see what it does in our code.
In our layout I'm going to add
a button below these two text views.
I'm going to paste the code
from the documentation here.
And now instead of the self destruct
string, I'm going to go for
something a little
friendlier like order.
This last line we can also
delete because we don't need it.
Cool, so now you have a quantity text
view, a text view that says zero, and
an order button.
Let's run it on our app,
to see what it looks like,
by hitting the green play button.
We can see down here
that it's still building.
Oh, this isn't what we wanted.
It appears that our linear layout is
actually horizontal instead of vertical.
So let's make sure that we add
the orientation attribute.
We're going to change this to say
android;orientation="vertical".
That should fix the problem.
So let's hit run again.
Okay, that's better now.
The three children are showing
up in a vertical column.
Now we just need to
style these fields so
they look a little bit more like
the screenshot we were given.
From this screenshot we see that
the quantity text view is in all caps.
In lesson one we learned about
an attribute called android:textAllCaps,
and it's showing up here
in the auto-complete.
If it shows up like this,
you can just hit enter and
it automatically adds it
in the code here for you.
We set that value to be true
because we want it in all caps.
The reason why it's better to use
this attribute to capitalize the text
is because if we ever want to change the
UI so that quantity is in lower case,
like this, all we need to do
is just remove this attribute
instead of going and changing this text.
Next, for this text here that says zero,
we should use a text size of 16sp.
Let me add that now and it shows up
in the auto-complete suggestions so
I just hit enter and
then I choose 16sp for the value.
We also want it to be
a black font color.
I'm going to use the Android
system color for
black, which is referred to like this.
Cool, that takes care of both
the quantity and the zero text views.
The order button is fine as is, it will
automatically capitalize the text for
you in a button and the height and
width are wrap content.
We do have a need to resolve
this vertical space here.
We want 16dp of padding or
margin in between the quantity and
the zero text views.
We also want also want 16dp of
padding in between the zero and
the order button.
You can implement this
in many different ways,
I'm just going to choose to add it as
layout top margin for this button.
And I'm going to add it as a bottom
margin for this quantity text view.
Feel free to do it a different
way as long as it looks the same.
The reason why I chose to do a bottom
margin and a top margin is because I
know that this middle area
here is going to change later.
We're going to change it to be
a quantity picker with a plus and
minus button, and I still want to have
16dp of space between the quantity
title and the picker.
Same for the button.
Okay, let's run it again
now on our device.
Cool, and it looks just like we wanted.
The quantity text view is in all caps,
the zero text view is in
black font color, size 16sp, and
we have the order button here.
We also have 16dp of space
between these views.
Good job.
Oh, and I almost forgot.
The quiz also asks for what happens
when you click on this button.
Well, actually it does nothing,
for now at least.
Keep watching to find
out what happens next.