So I've talked about
the possibility axioms and
the successor-state axioms that's
most of what's in situation calculus.
And that's used to describe an entire
domain like the airport cargo domain.
And now we describe a particular
problem within that domain
by describing the initial state.
And typically we call that S0,
the initial situation.
And in S0 we can make
various types of assertions
of different types of predicates, so
we could say that plane P1
is at airport JFK, in S0.
So just a simple predicate.
And we could also make larger sentences.
So we could say, for
all c, if c is cargo,
then that c is at JFK in situation S0.
So we have much more flexibility
in situation calculus
to say almost anything we want.
Anything that's a valid sentence in
first-order logic can be asserted about
the initial state.
The goal state is similar.
We could have a goal of say, there
exists some goal state s, such that for
all c, if c is cargo, then we want
that cargo to be at SFO in state s.
So this initial state and
this goal says, move all the cargo,
I don't care how much there is,
from JFK to SFO.
Now, the great thing about situation
calculus is that once we've described
this in the ordinary language
of first-order logic.
We don't need any special programs
to manipulate it and come up with
the solution because we already have
theorem provers for first-order logic.
And we can just state this as a problem,
apply the normal theorem prover
that we already had for other uses,
and it can come up with an answer
of a path that satisfies this goal.
A situation which corresponds to a path,
which satisfies this
given the initial state and
given the descriptions of the actions.
So the advantage of situation calculus
is that we have the full power of
first-order logic,
we can represent anything we want.
Much more flexibility than in problem
solving or classical planning.
So all together now we've seen
several ways of dealing with planning.
We started in deterministic,
fully observable environments.
And we moved into stochastic and
partially observable environments.
We were able to distinguish
between plans that can or
cannot solve a problem.
But we had one weakness in all these
different approaches, is that we
weren't able to distinguish between
probable and improbable solutions.
And that will be the subject
of the next unit.