Now let's consider the case where we have parallel image planes.
It's a little hard to see here in the picture, but
the idea is that I've got two image planes.
My centers of projection are sort of out here.
And any point defines a plane that intersects these image planes.
And it's kind of, it's what's called actually a pencil of planes.
These planes rotate around that base line.
But we have parallel image planes.
What do the epipolar lines look like?
Well, they look like this.
In this particular case,
because of how they're shift, they're these horizontal lines.
And can see that for
the corresponding three points located on that chapel, they land.
Four points, sorry.
That they land somewhere on these epipolar lines.
So if the epipolar lines are all supposed to intersect at the epipoles.
And here, we've got these horizontal epipolar lines.
Where are the epipoles?
Well as somebody once explained to you somewhere in some metaphysical space,
sometimes various hallucinogens were involved it,
powerful lines intersected infinity.
Okay, so essentially he epipoles are out at infinity.
And if, if you're not sure about that travel to the Himalayas and
ask somebody high up on a mountain or just high up anywhere.
I don't know if I'm allowed to say that.
Just ask them about parallel lines.
And the idea is that parallel lines here are essentially at infinity.
One way of thinking about that is, as the two planes get closer and
closer to being parallel, the epipoles keep moving further and further.
And so when you take a limit, when they actually become parallel,
then the location of the epipole is at infinity.