But what happens when several projects
all want to send data to the moon?
At each end of our laser uplink there's
a router whose job it is to decide what
traffic needs to be sent
through the depths of space.
When there isn't enough bandwidth for
everyone who wants to use it that's
a condition of network congestion.
And like we saw before,
if an IP router has more
traffic to send onto a link than
can fit, it can drop packets.
Routers can be set up to
do this in different ways.
For instance, to drop some
traffic before other traffic or
to try to split the pain
fairly among all users.
Now we've seen earlier that when a TCP
endpoint notices that its packets
are not getting through it retransmits
the ones that are not acknowledged.
Now if packet loss were
mostly due to noisy lines or
something that would be enough, but a
lot of packet loss is due to congestion.
Given that, what else do you think TCP
should do when there's packet loss?
Should it transmit two
copies of each new packet?
Should it transmit two copies of
each new packet 50% of the time?
Should it, when packets are dropped,
send more slowly?
close the connection with an error?
Or should it give up on the Internet and
invest in a goat farm?