So let's take a look at the mean.
This one will be a little more clear,
all right?
So, this is the equation just copied
from the previous slide to this slide,
all right, for mu plus.
Step with me,
I'm going to divide by m squared.
Okay?
So, when I divide by m squared, okay,
so you see,
I've just divided by m squared.
So, there's an m squared down here and
this m becomes m there, and
this becomes an m squared there.
Okay?
Cool.
So, what is that?
>> I have no idea.
>> Well yes you do, here it is.
Look, see this yt over m.
Remember, y measurement
was just m times x.
So, yt over m, that's
the measurement's guess of what x is.
All right, if you were looking just
at the measurement, that's its guess.
Now mu t minus, what's that?
What mu t minus is,
that was our prediction, right?
Our, that's the mean,
that's our best guess as to what
x actually is at time t okay?
So, we've got these two things in here,
right,
we've got mu t,
which is our prediction, and
y over m, which is our measurements
guess, we have to somehow combine them.
Well how do we combine them?
Well, what's this value, right?
This is just sigma squared
divided by m squared,
that is the measurements
variance divided by m squared,
that's the variance if you were to
compute x just from the measurement.
So this guy right here, that's the x
computed just from the measurement.
The variance of that is sigma squared m
over m squared because y was just mx.
All right?
So that quantity right there,
circled in blue, that's the variance of
x computed from the measurement and,
what is the last term there?
Sigma t minus squared.
That's the variance of the prediction.
And you might say, well, so what?"
>> So what?
>> What do you mean so what?
No.
What this means is that the entire
mu t plus is just the average.
It's a weighted average
of the prediction and
the best guess based
upon the measurement.
And so down here in the denominator,
that's just the sum of the weights.
It is just a weighted average of
the prediction plus what the measurement
is telling you, which of course is what,
in some sense, the universe has to be.
Right?
The whole idea is you're making
a prediction,
you're getting a measurement.
Both of these are sources of information
and you want to integrate them