Yippee, it's quiz time.
I think this one will be fun.
Recall that,
given an input sequence that's bitonic,
a bitonic merge produces
a sorted output.
Your assignment is to create
a Bitonic Merge Network.
That is to start with this
empty comparator network, and
then do the following.
In each column,
I want you to insert one or
more non-overlapping plus comparators.
You can do that by selecting an even
number of boxes in each column.
For example,
suppose you checked these two boxes.
That implies a plus comparator
between those two inputs.
Now, if you were to
evaluate this network,
leaving all these other boxes blank,
then here's the output you would get.
Now, clearly, these intermediate
outputs don't match the final outputs.
So this can't be the full network.
Let me show you one more example.
Suppose instead that you
chose these four boxes.
Recall that comparators within
a column cannot overlap.
Therefore, those four boxes
correspond to these two comparators.
Were you to evaluate this network,
you'd get these values as outputs
from the two comparators.
As you can see,
they still don't match the outputs.
So if you start your network this way,
you'll need to keep adding
comparators in the other columns.
Of course, you can chain the output of
one comparator to the input of another.
Oh, and one more thing,
your network needs to be able to sort
any length a bitonic sequence,
not just the example I've shown here.
Have fun and good luck.