So now that you've seen a full examples
of contract classes, let's make one for
our pets app.
So here's the database
schema that we came up with.
So the name of the table is one
called pets, and the column names for
that table are id, name,
breed, gender, and weight.
So here are the general steps used for
creating our contract.
But the question now is
where in the program should
we actually create our contract class?
Generally, we organize our
code by making packages.
So packages are groups
of related Java classes.
And when we first make our application
we define a package that can be found at
the top of each class.
So, Android Studio seems that all Java
class files in the same package are in
the same folder.
So as shown here.
And the name of the package is
also the name of the folder.
So this name here
com.example.android.pets is the name of
the package.
Since we're going to be working on
a bunch of classes that have to do with
data, let's make a data package.
We'll do this to separate the classes
that have data-specific functionality
from the activity classes.
So in order to make a package, it's
really the same as making a new folder.
So in Android Studio, under our
package let's go to right-click,
new, and then hover to package.
And let's name this package data.
Right, so I decided to create a package
named data under our existing package.
Now, inside our data package I
want to create a new Java class and
name it PetContract.
So I'm going to right click data,
new, Java class, and
I'm going to name it PetContract.
So I'm going to modify this header and
make our contract a final class,
that can't be extended.
And that's because it's just a class for
providing constants, and
we won't need to extend or
implement anything for this outer class.
All right, so now that we have
the start to our contract.
I'll leave the task of completing the
rest of the contract to you in the next
exercise.
Remember to use the schema
that we defined.
Also make an inner class for
each table as well as the constants for
each of the column headings.
Now, one additional hint.
So contract classes often contain
constants associated with the database,
and so remember to add those in as well.
And what I mean by that is,
let's take a look back at
the headphones example from before.
So from the schema of our headphones
example, we might generate a store
contract specific for that database and
it might look like this.
So in addition to the basic structure of
the table, which includes the table name
and the column names you might
store some additional constants and
those are shown down here.
So these should be the possible
styles of our headphones.
Now remember in lesson one we discussed
the benefits of being able to map
numbers to values into your database.
Such as here in the headphones example
we've mapped headphone styles to
different integer numbers.
So we can give the styles
these constant names, and
then store them in our contract.
So the reason I bring this up,
this storing constants in our
contract Is because we'll have
a similar need in our pets application.
So if we go back to our pets example.
So in our pets app, we allow our
pets to have one of three genders.
So one specifying male,
two specifying female and
zero specifying an unknown gender.
Now, instead of putting the numbers
directly in here It'd be better if we
have constants for these numbers.
Which we can store in
the contract class.
So with that information in mind,
I'll leave implementing
the contract class up to you.
Now best of luck.
Now for this exercise, I'll adhere the
following conventions listed in a text
above this video in order
to make our pet up.
And I've listed them here.
So remember the name of the table.
We have a single table,
it's called pets,
and it has five columns, id,
name, gender, breed, and weight.
In order to create that contract class,
we'll first have an outer class that's
named something, or BlankContract.
Secondly, there'll be an inner
class named BlankEntry for
each table in the database.
And each of these inner classes will
implement the BaseColumns class.
Third, the string constants for the
table names and each of the headings or
column names should
exist in the contract.
And lastly, specifically for
this use case we'll also need to
create constants for each gender and
use them as appropriate in each class.
After having created the contract,
I want you to go ahead and
answer these questions.
So first, how many constants
will you need to make for
the columns in the pets table?
And that's including the id column.
Secondly, how many constants
will there be for gender?
Next, the gender constants
should be what type of data?
Should it be a string,
integer or boolean.
And lastly,
where will you use the gender constants
in the app besides in the contract?
Will they show up in the EditorActivity,
the CatalogActivity,
maybe the AndroidManifest file,
or maybe even the strings.xml?