While we're on the topic
of notifications,
it's worth mentioning a special type
of service called a foreground service.
One common example of a foreground
service is a music player that's able to
play music long after
you've navigated away
from the actual audio player activity.
Another example is when you get
directions via Google Maps after you've
closed the apps.
If you've ever navigated somewhere
while Google Maps wasn't active,
you've used the Google
map foreground service.
So what is a foreground service?
And what makes these two
examples foreground services
as opposed to plain old
background services?
A foreground service is a service that
the user is actively aware of because
Android requires that service post
a non-dismissible ongoing notification.
They are typically used to show the user
the real-time progress of a long-running
operation.
Because these notifications exist,
the user can do some rudimentary
interactions with your service,
such as pausing the music, or
stopping the service entirely.
In addition, because the service is
doing something very visible and
likely important for the user, Android
will prioritize not shutting these
services down if the system
is memory constrained.