Is it true that users often
start at the random point but
then fall back to a common pattern?
Okay, actually users typically
start at the left upper corner.
Because stuff in English and many
other languages, we go left to right.
So, sort of, that bias is still there.
So there is, people really
don't start at a random point.
I won't check that answer.
There's a bias in starting at
a point near the top left, okay?
We just said that so
we're going to check this answer and
the next one is the ease of moving
from current to next point.
Okay, going right or down rather than
diagonal in the opposite direction or
something like that.
The ease of moving from your current
to next actually also introduces bias,
an easier pattern on you and
how you sort of enter it.
So second and third options make
those patterns less random.
There are more common patterns because
of ease of use reasons, because of
the bias in sort of where people
like to start, and things like that.