If you have something almost,
but not quite working and
your getting frustrated with it.
It can be tempting to throw it away and
try again.
But sometimes your really
close on your first try and
the second try isn't as close.
Then you want to be able to
get back to the first version.
For short functions you can make
this easier by commenting out
the old version.
In Python just put a hash mark
before each line of the function.
Or you can turn it into a big string
by putting triple quotes around it.
Now text editors do have an undo
feature, but it doesn't usually let you
go back between multiple
different versions of your code.
So it's not really good enough to let
you compare different versions of code.
Undo is good for when you
accidentally mess something up and
immediately notice.
But, you can't rely on undo alone to
compare different versions of code or
to get back to an arbitrary
version you previously had.
You can copy code into a different file.
Files aren't exactly expensive,
after all.
Just make sure you save them
where you can find them.
Another reason to keep old versions
is that when you do ask for
help, you can show two or
three different things you've tried.
Software engineers use version control
systems like Git, which are pretty much
super powerful undo systems that let you
navigate to any version of the code that
have multiple modified versions and
share different versions and so on.
So keeping old versions isn't just for
beginners.
It's how software
engineering really works