Hi, I'm Sebastian.
I'm delighted to welcome you to
Udacity's Artificial
Intelligence Nanodegree program.
We think it provides
an experience unlike any other.
AI is really about unleashing one of
the most amazing things in the entire
universe, intelligence.
AI is growing exponentially and
will change our world at a rate that
will far surpass changes brought by
humans because AIs can
learn much faster than us.
Just look at self driving cars.
Any time you drive,
only one person gets better, you.
But with AI, anytime an AI car drives,
all cars get better,
including all future autonomous cars.
After completing this program, you'll
be positioned to take full advantage of
such changes that AI will usher in.
You will be ready to work with
trans-disciplinary thinkers and
practitioners to create technologies
that will shape our future world.