And we're live, awesome!
Hey, everybody, how's it going?
I'm John and this is Ty.
And today, we're going to spend
a little bit of time talking about
the Chrome developer tools.
Now, a lot has changed in the past,
especially if you've been going through
our courses and have been
looking at the tools themselves,
looking at these timelines and saying,
my gosh, this looks so different.
How the heck do I begin using these?
Well, we're hopefully going to clear up
a lot of those questions you have and
maybe clear up questions you may
not have as we're going to try and
go through all the tabs
in the developer tools.
And so Ty,
you want to introduce yourself, and
then kind of get us started here?
>> Yeah, sure, thanks, John.
So hey, everybody, I'm Ty.
I'm a CM here at Udacity, or
a course manager, rather, and
I'm also a front end and
back end web developer.
And like John said, today we're going to
be talking about the dev tools.
So let's get started.
Just for reference,
we're going to be using Chrome 48,
which is the latest stable
release of Chrome and
that's kind of important since
things change really fast.
So if you haven't updated your Chrome
and you're confused why what we're doing
looks so different,
that could be the reason.
But anyway, I'm going to share
my screen with all of you and
take you to the world's
worst website ever.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>> It's pretty bad.
I was not sure what to
expect when you said this.
And it's definitely [LAUGH] the worst
website I've seen in a long while.
>> Yep.
>> It really reminds me sort of like
Geosites.
>> Yes, we've got all of the worst
parts of HTML and CSS present here.
Once you guys make it through
the front end degree, you will
never have to worry about making
something that looks this terrible.
But anyway, I figured it would be
funny to use this one as an example.
So I'm going to open up
the developer tools, and
if you're on Windows,
I believe it's Ctrl+Shift+C
to open them, and
on Mac, it's Cmd+Opt+I.
So hopefully,
you can see the dev tools all right.
John, does that look okay?
>> Yeah, it looks pretty good on my end.
You can also zoom in.
If you guys do have trouble
seeing the dev tools,
you can zoom in to it like
you would any other page.
I believe Cmd+Plus makes
the font a little bigger-
>> Yeah, see, I'm using plus and
minus right here to make it
a little bigger and smaller.
>> So sometimes that comes in handy,
cause I know when I have my
big monitor up and running,
sometimes it is a little hard to
see some of the text in those tabs.
So even if you're not
screencasting like we are,
it's still handy to be able to do that.
>> Yeah, definitely.
So let's jump right into it.
So we're basically going to walk you
guys through each of the tabs in the dev
tools that you can see
them right at the top, and
we're going to go basically
left to right almost.
But we're going to start at
the left with the Elements tab.
And the Elements tab,
as the name suggests,
lets you inspect all of
the HTML elements on the page.
Kind of the most useful way to use it
is to take a look at your web page.
I'll make this a little smaller, and
let's say I wasn't too
happy with how this looked.
I decided, you know what,
I don't want to call this
the world's worst website ever.
In fact, we're going to call it
the world's best website ever,
which it's not, but we'll pretend it is.
>> [LAUGH]
>> So what I did right there was this
little button right here, or
optionally Cmd+Shift+C on Mac and
Ctrl+Shift+C on Windows, lets me
open up the element inspector and
you can see me kind of moving
around the page with my cursor and
elements are highlighting everywhere.
Those of you that have taken
some of the front end,
done a degree might be
already familiar with this.
But basically I can go around, and
then when I find the element I
want to look at, I can click it and
it will actually highlight right in the
dev tools, which is pretty convenient.
And then once I'm there,
there's a bunch of things I can do.
So I can change the actual content
by double-clicking right there,
so we're going to go, best,
and then there you go.
I can actually double-click some of
the attributes too, and change them.
So I could make this, let's say,
60 point, then it gets really big.
>> Just making it look worse and worse.
>> Yeah, exactly, if we want to make
it look better, we can make it smaller.
You can do this with all the attributes.
And when you right-click
on the DOM node itself,
it actually gives you
a lot more options, too.
So we can edit the entire node as HTML,
which opens up this little
kind of basic text editor.
That could be helpful if you wanted
add in, let's say, other nodes.
Blah, blah, blah.
We're not going to do that right now,
but you get the idea.
Could be useful if you
have an unordered list and
you wanted to add another element in for
some reason.
If we go over and
find a link on the website,
let's say right here,
we can do something pretty useful.
So if I right-click
on that link element,
I can actually force the element
to have a particular state.
So let's say you had a link that was
supposed to change color when you
hovered over it, if you wanted
to see what that looked like, so
you could actually force
the hover state on the element.
And while this website being kind of
terrible doesn't do anything fancy
with the CSS like that, you can
see how that would be very useful.
What we can also do from
here is go to the right.
I'll make this a little bigger and
inspect all of
the CSS styles that have been
applied to the elements on the page.
So if click a random
paragraph right here,
I can see that the text align
is supposed to be in the center.
It's in a table, which is kind
of an old school HTML element,
if you're not familiar with it.
It's still used today, but definitely
more of a 90s leftover at this point.
And we can kind of see that a bunch of
styles have been applied to the fonts,
some table-specific stuff,
and like I said,
like the text in the center,
things like that.
And what's cool is you
can actually enable and
disable those styles with this checkbox,
just by hovering over them.
Anything that's grey,
you can't change yourself.
Anything that's white, you can edit.
And if you wanted to actually add new
styles too, you can click right here
on element.style, and that'll let
you just import custom styles.
And Chrome is kind of smart, so
it'll actually autocomplete for you.
Whoops, did I mess up?
Good background color, and
then you can see it changed up here.
So that's pretty much
all you need to know for
the Element tab as far as the basics.
It's pretty cool, I use it all the time
in web development, very helpful.
>> I know one of the things that's
planned to be added to the Elements
panel as well is a color picker.
I think there's even plug-ins
that you can use for that.
And I think even in Chrome Canary,
it's available now.
So that will come in handy when you're
trying to just play around with those
styles and
you're just trying to fine tune a color.
I really do like that panel.
>> Okay, yeah,
that sounds super helpful.
I didn't hear about that, but
I do know that in Chrome 49,
which is the next version, there are
bunch of huge improvements coming, like
the developer side of things, including
even CSS variables from what I heard.
Kind of unrelated but pretty cool.
>> Yeah, I've heard of that too,
and I mean, a lot of this stuff.
Was shown off at the previous
Chrome developers conference so
you can feel free to go back and
watch those videos to see some of the
stuff that's coming out in the future.
So, I'm going to share
my worst web site here.
And I'm going to share
one of my favorite towns,
which is the console tab.
l And actually the console tab is super
handy because it's going to show you
a lot of things about your website.
It's a great place to see where
JavaScripts break in and where just
any sort of problems may be occurring
in the network and stuff like that.
It's basically a fully interactive
JavaScript interpreter for
you to sort of use on your website.
So basically anything that gets logged.
So basically anywhere in your code.
You do, you know,
console.log is going to show up here.
So that's pretty handy.
Especially when you're
trying to debug some things.
You maybe just want to throw in some log
reports in there to see, like, okay.
What's happening?
Let me log out this variable,
and see what's going on.
You can also do all kinds of other
useful debugging things like
console.warn, console.error,
console.group, a certain table.
You can also use console.time,
you know, time-specific functions.
But pretty much anything you would
write in your JavaScript file,
you can do here.
So I mean we can look at things
like the Window variable.
You can manipulate things
in the Window variable.
Anything that's accessible globally
on the client side is going to be
accessible inside this console.
So it's important to note, that's
kind of an important thing to note,
is any code that isn't wrapped and
immediately [INAUDIBLE] expression or
like in a document.ready for
jQuery users, it's going to be
accessible from this console.
So we can see that.
You know I have access
to the window object.
I have access to the document object.
Those are pretty common global objects.
And, you know, using the console I can
actually go in and manipulate these,
as well as being able to see some errors
that could be occurring in my code.
Now there's sort of two things
a lot of people have questions
about with the console.
It's like okay, my console's full
of crap, how do I get rid of it?
You can simply just run the clear
command and it'll clean out your log.
And then sort of the second
question that people often ask is,
okay well I want to actually
see things stay in the log.
So you can see when I
refresh the page here,
everything in my log kind of goes away,
and then it sort of reloads everything.
If I want to keep my log to stay
active between refreshings and
stuff, I can check this
Preserve Log Refresh.
It'll show me where I navigated to and
it'll re-log this information.
And there's all kinds of little
filters you can apply for
searching different things.
So if you only want to see the errors or
only the warnings, only sort of the
debug or things that have been handled.
You can hide just network messages or
you can sort of filter through
the messages you're getting
a lot of console errors.
Which is super handy to kind of dig
through when things like this show up.
You get a bunch of 404s and
you're trying to figure out
specific 404 errors that you have.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I think that's about it,
as far as the console's concerned.
Did I miss anything here?
One thing you might want to
mention is that little drop.
Yeah, you know yes that little drop down
it's pretty useful if you have like some
nested I frames in your code
because it lets you switch context.
Because you know what's
accessible globally and
the mainframe is not the same as what's
acceptable globally in the I Frame, so
that can also be helpful for debugging.
Good point, good point.
Yeah so this, as Ty mentioned this
drop-down here will let you pick and
choose sort of what I frame
you're looking in and
what frame you're looking in.
.
You can see I can access all of my
Chrome plugins here, like my last
asked library mode, my reactive tools.
So you can even go in and
kind of like access those and
play around with their consoles.
Sweet.
All right.
So let's see Ty, what's next?
I think we got the Network tab next.
[CROSSTALK] One thing I want to note
too is if there's a specific order
you like things in, so
I like having the console open first.
You should actually be able to click and
drag the tabs around now,
so you can order them however you like,
which is super handy.
>> Yeah you can and
I think it will persist right?
When you close Chrome and reopen it.
>> Yeah, it's connected to
the Chrome user profile so
it'll persist in between sessions.
>> Yeah, cool.
So yeah.
Next up is the Network tab,
which is another very commonly used one.
So I will share my screen
with you guys once again.
So if we go to the Network
tab right here.
Right now there's nothing, but
what you'll notice right up
here in the top left is that this
little recording button is active and
what that means is that it's listening
for kind of outgoing requests.
So if I refresh the page right here
with the Network tab open you're
going to see a bunch of stuff pop in.
So I can just scroll up, we don't
need to look at the page for this.
And this is kind of straightforward
it basically tells you all of
the http requests that
your website's made.
And as well it's like useful information
like what type of file was requested.
Where the request was initiated
like was it from an HTML file,
JavaScript Chrome itself, the size
of the request, how long it took.
Which is very useful for
a kind of debugging performance and
most importantly the status.
Did you get it, was it a 404?
Like, we can see right here
highlighted in red this updated .gif
file did not Show up we're going to
error 404 which means page not found.
And you can actually click these little
things at the top, the little tabs to
sort, which is very helpful especially
if you have like a ton of requests.
Sometimes websites will make dozens
if not hundreds of requests.
So can be helpful to be able to sort as
well as use this filter search bar to
find specific files that
you're looking for.
So what's more useful than this
is that you can actually click on
one of the resources
that was requested and
you'll get information
about the http request.
So you can see what the method
was right here is a get
the status code we got the full
URL that we were requesting.
So if I were to open up
that in a different tab,
you can see that this is the JavaScript
file that was requested,
it just happens to be from
the same domain name.
And then you can get a lot more advanced
information, like cookies that were
sent back and forth, session
information, all of the HTTP headers.
So, really really useful stuff if
you're doing front end development.
And Chrome will actually format
the response for you, or
it'll try to, at least.
It doesn't always work.
It generally works pretty decent.
>> Yeah, for
any kind of standard file type, it will.
Like an image,
it should show you the response.
So right there you can see the GIF.
So Chrome is really good about this
kind of stuff, it formats everything for
you nicely.
[CROSSTALK] And you can actually
get timing information too,
more details on the request timeline.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I'm not sure if there's too
much else to the Network tab.
It's pretty straight forward but
very, very, very useful.
Other than the search bar right
here you can actually filter by
the type of request as well or
the file type of the request.
So there's all the images,
JavaScripts, style sheets,
things like that It might be
worthwhile to just mention what XHR is.
>> Those are AJAX requests for acts like
they are transferring
JSON data generally?
>> Yeah, so usually anything that
more often than not you're
calling in through HTTP.
So, other Web sites,
resources, as Tye mentioned.
JSON files, things like that.
>> Yeah generally,
what you'll see there is JSON files
>> Actually not sure if it's
I don't think it's only JSON files that
can be X.M.L. and things like that too.
It's just just generally any
kind of like cross site request.
>> Cool.
So let's see what app do we have next
I think it's the exciting timeline
Which I'm going to talk about some
the pub back open my screenshare.
The best website I've ever seen and
let's talk about the timeline tap.
So the time when you know is where
you can kind of take a snapshot of
everything going on your
page at different times.
From recording what happens when
the user clicks a button to
recording what happens when
a user first comes to the page.
A few things that we can talk
about is these check marks here
is determined by what you capture.
Typically, at the bare minimum,
you kind of want to capture
just the JavaScript profile.
But more recently,
you can get sort of screenshots and
a sort of painting of the page, so
that basically gives you sort of
screenshots in time of what the page
looks like per every 100 milliseconds.
So let's take a look.
Let's actually record the timeline
of me sort of reloading this page.
It's fairly slow.
All right,
let's finish that recording, and
it takes a second, usually it's
processing a lot of stuff that happened.
So we're going to just kind of
wait a second here while it
finishes gathering all this information.
Hopefully, it doesn't take too long.
If I didn't just break it.
[LAUGH] Sometimes the timeline can be
a little mad especially with really
bad websites.
No, what happened here?
Did the whole console freeze up?
>> I think it might have.
>> All right.
Let's try this again.
Let's see.
All right.
Ready?
Let's capture a new timeline,
refresh the page, finish.
Man, I'm really so mad if the timeline
doesn't work for me today.
If it doesn't, we can always go
try another another website.
Yeah, hopefully it's not
the website working earlier.
Sometimes hangouts can slow
down Chrome quite a bit, so
I'm wondering if that is related.
>> Yeah, that's a good point.
I also have pictures of some
timelines that I can pull up,
but it's not as fun as doing it live.
Around me.
Let me try doing just
the timeline of Google.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
How any day that's going to be patient.
I'm not patient enough of this thing.
So I'm actually going to do a bit here,
you're going to hear some of this stuff.
All right, so I actually am
actually going to even pop.
Let me pop out my dev tools here and
share just that.
So you don't really need to look
at this terrible website to
see what's going on here.
So here we have our timeline.
So you can actually see
along the top here all
of this sort of time frame
your guns are out and going.
And we kind of see all these different
colors, green, red bars up here.
This is sort of the paint,
the layout, some load events.
You can hover over most things and
they will tell you what they are.
This next red stripe here,
this indicates to us sort of where
Google Chrome suspects there may be
performance or responsiveness issues.
So basically anywhere on the page where,
you know, it might not look so
well on a desktop or
a tablet, just anywhere where
loading something might cause
some chug for the end user.
The next thing we have
here is the FPS meter and
this is actually a sort of mostly
what the old time line was.
We used to sort of have a combination
of this timeline with the one below it.
Where these were the color bars and
you kind of saw like how
much yes they took up.
But this one's strictly
frames per second and
ideally you want these bars
to be as high as possible.
So anywhere where these bars are almost
touching sort of a red stripe above it,
is where we're performing
at about 60fps.
Anywhere where it's really
low is pretty bad, and
those are kind of like sections where
we might want to investigate what's
causing FPS to just
take such a huge drop.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The next chart we have here
is basically our CPU usage.
This is kind of giving
us a real-time look at
all the events that
are happening on the page and
sort of all the computations our
computer and browser is doing.
Typically I believe,
If remember correctly here.
Yellow is Java script, blue is paints,
purple is network events,
green is Gosh, layout events.
And gray is everything else so
just any sort of other event that
could be happening on the page.
When they're kind of reaching
the top here that means the CPUs
working at 100% capacity
trying to process that code.
Ideally you would like to see Got
on not quite this giant mountain
that we have going on here you have more
sections that are a little bit lower.
So you're not using as much
CPU usage this next section
where we see sort of these blue
stripes and yellow stripes and
green stripes are more of an indicator
of these events occurring so
any sort of network events
that are happening.
So this is probably requesting
the content to do this paint and
then it's actually
performing this paint.
So again,
if I remember correctly I believe blue
Yeah blue is network requests.
>> Blue is network request?
>> [INAUDIBLE] at the beginning.
>> Here we go, okay, cool.
So, blues networker banks,
yellows JavaScript events,
green is paint in layout.
>> [CROSSTALK] Yup.
>> And then purple is.
>> Purple I believe is when styles
are recalculated, actually.
So, if you edit CSS and the code itself.
>> There we go, purple is styles.
So, under your CSS.
And then gray is everything else.
The images loading, stuff like that.
And we can see that it took
screenshots along the way here.
So we can kind of go in and
inspect these little screenshots.
Which is pretty handy to be able to
kind of go in and browse these and
kind of see what has
loaded on the page and
what the page looks like
at specific points in time.
And then you know how to get
to see this next section.
We have our actual
flame view of all this.
Which we can, I believe toggle,
is two different modes so
sort of, this view which kind of shows
you should be pretty familiar for
those of you using the dev tools, but
we can basically see like the events
in sort of the order they execute.
And you can open up
some of them here that
have sort of a tree of things happening.
And you can kind of explore
the JavaScript files that
are executing here.
And then when we switch it to this view,
we can actually get an even
more in-depth look at this.
You can kind of zoom in and
out on certain events happening.
And when you click on these events
you get like a nice little summary
of what's going on.
It tells you what script is running,
how long it took to run,
what type of event it was.
It also can show you the call-tree, so
if there is more events that it calls.
You can sort of see those.
So you can see that there's a loading
event that happens, parsing the HTML,
evaluating a script, and then a few
other events going on below it.
Then you can also do it from sort of
a bottom-up perspective, where you're
basically just kind of going through
that tree the opposite direction.
So that it is pretty handy,
especially when you want to evaluate
the performance of your site and
figuring out where things are breaking,
or performance is just
taking a huge hit.
And as I mentioned, the great thing too,
is you can kind of like go from here,
click on this, and
it'll take you to the Sources tab and
directly see that chunk of code.
That actually segues pretty
nicely into the next bit,
which is the Sources tab, I believe.
Right?
>> Yeah.
So I will share my screen
with you guys once more and
we can take a look at the Sources tab.
And the Sources tab is essentially
where you can read, edit and
debug your JavaScript files.
So, this one right here only has
one file and that is animate.js.
So I can actually view
the JavaScript file itself and
it kind of like basic IDE or
a text editor view.
So I can actually go in and
add my own code right there,
that is not valid code for sure, and
actually this is pretty useful too.
If let's say, your site had minified
code, and what minified means,
if you haven't heard
that that term before,
is basically the file gets compressed
down to a usually one line and all
of the variable names become obfuscated
so usually just one or two letters.
It's basically to make the file
as small as possible so
it can be requested over
the network as quickly as possible.
So if you had minified or
poorly formatted code that you wanted
to expect, this button right here,
on the bottom left of the text editor,
two curly brackets.
It's called the Pretty Printer and
it basically will take your code and
format it in a nicer kind
of standardized way, so
you can actually go through and view it.
Another important aspect to the Sources
tab is using the debugger and
there are a bunch of different
ways to use Chrome's debugger.
So the first of all is actually
through your code itself.
If you were working on a website and
you wanted to test your JavaScript and
set break points in the code,
let's pretend I wasn't in Chrome
right now just in my text editor.
You could use the debugger keyword
there's a semi colon at the end of it.
And that essentially tells Chrome
to put a break point right there,
it will stop execution.
And actually when Chrome gets to that
debugger line it'll actually go ahead
and open up the Sources tab and
go to that file automatically for you.
Which is really handy.
So that's how you would do
it through your code itself.
With the Sources tab there or some other
way so you have to use the debugger or
you can set break points by clicking
on the line number to the left.
But why is that not working?
Maybe because I've edited the file,
okay let me try this again.
>> [LAUGH]
>> Yeah, there we go, okay, cool.
So I can set break points at you
know arbitrary locations and
any line and you'll see on
the right little tab, right here.
It will be on the right,where we are.
Break points I put on and
I can enable and disable them from here.
Or I can just completely get rid of them
by clicking on the line number again.
That's like basic break points
just through the JavaScript.
Another really useful on
type of break point or
two actually is DOM break points
which I can't create from here.
But if I want to go back
to the elements tab,
what I could do is pick a DOM
elements I cared about,
let's save this paragraph tag and
I could set a break point.
So on kind of different events.
So if the DOM style or
the domino style was modified by CSS or
JavaScript I could set a break point to
like kind of alert me when that happens
and stop execution.
If the node gets deleted
through the code, like jQuery,
I think it's like Dot Remove or
something like that or delete.
I'm not sure,
I haven't used it in a while.
You can set a break point there
through the Elements tab,
if we go back to the Sources tab.
You can also set break points on Events.
So click advance on different
things like that HTML.
being parsed scripts loading keyboard
you know mouse up and mouse down sir.
Lots of different ways to set
break points, all very useful.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I think that is it for the Sources tab.
What I find myself using the most
is definitely the little code
PrettyPrinter, and
then just kind of stepping through it,
understanding the code.
But break points are definitely
super useful too.
John, is there anything
you think I missed?
>> No, not that I can think of.
Maybe, nah,
I think that about covers it.
The Sources tab, I mean, it's really
handy for just kind of exploring
the files in this sight just kind
of setting those break points.
Other than that, I mean one of the
things that a lot of people ask is like,
okay, what can I edit my JavaScript
from, from the Sources tab?
And be able to go and lie,
basically lie about it my code and
currently there isn't a way to
do that improve their tools but
it is something that I've heard a lot
of talk about adding in the future.
So hopefully that will be
something that like gets added, so
you can kind of like mess with fewer
jobs for files in your source.
Luckily, it's easy enough with a front
end web dev to just edit the files
yourself and refresh the page, but
yeah I think that will be coming
to Chrome soon like the ability to
edit the file in the sources tab and
refresh the page and
have your edits processed.
All right last one
here that I am going to
screen share is the resources tab.
The resources tab shows you basically
all the resources the page has cached or
is storing, and really, just sort
of anything that this page has.
So we can look at all the images,
we can look at all
the scripts that have loaded.
So a lot of this stuff is similar
to what we find in the Sources tab.
But additionally, like I've mentioned,
we actually are able to see
information about whats in the cache,
if there's anything that's been
cashed by websites or IndexedDB.
You can also look at anything that's
getting stored on Local Storage.
So we can see that this person has,
let's make this a little bigger,
this a little longer, you can see that
their using Google ads on their website.
And they're kind of have
a few pieces of information
cached in local storage for
whatever reason.
>> Yeah, usually for advertising and
tracking things like that.
>> So yeah, and then we can look at
sort of a session storage which is some
local storage usually persists where
session storage is just cached for
this unique session.
Whereas, local storage persists for
a user account, typically,
for a couple hours or a day or two, and-
>> Yeah,
you can even close the browser and
reopen it and it'll still be there.
Mm-hm, cookie used, yum.
Same sort of thing,
we can look at all the information
that's cached by these cookies.
There's also, sort of, application
cache that you can set up and
the usually cache storage
you want to set up.
And for those who are interested in
service workers, this is actually
where you can look at any sort of
worker objects operating on the site.
A good, let's see,
I think Google actually should
have a service worker on it.
Let's take a look.
Maybe not,
we'll find out in a second, I guess.
Yeah, so we can see all the information
about our service worker here.
For those of you who,
this isn't something we cover in
the front end web developer nano degree.
It's a little bit of a more advanced
feature that's really new to the web.
But we do cover it in the senior
web developer nano degree.
So if you're interested in what service
workers are, what they're used for,
how you can use them, what the heck
this panel is in the Resources tab,
be sure to check out at Nano Degree and
specifically,
the offline first course where you
can learn a little bit about what
the service worker is and
why you would want to use one.
>> Yeah, at the most basic level,
if you just want a definition,
it's basically a script that
runs in the background, and
it's not necessarily attached
to the page that you're on.
Just, you kind of view it as a
background process on a computer almost,
but just for the browser.
Yeah, and
then I have a few extra tabs here,
like the security tab,
which is pretty new.
It's more just something implemented
by Google to make sure that the page is
secure based on what they
consider as secure pages,
you know, does it use https?
Does it have a valid certificate?
Is it using a secure TLS connection?
Is it using secure resources?
This is handy if you are kind of in that
sort of whole stacky part of the world,
where you're also kind of dealing with
this kind of stuff, but as a front-end
developer, you probably don't have
to worry about this page so much.
But it's still handy from time to time,
especially if you're doing some work
that server setup kind of
stuff on your page as well.
And then, the last couple tabs
I have here is an Audit tab.
This one's actually, eventually,
going to get officially supported by
Chrome, but this will let you sort of
audit your pages for accessibility
network utilization and performance.
So if you run it, it basically just
kind of does some test on your page and
then gives you a bunch Information on
whether or not your page is accessible,
are you using good colors so that color
blind people are able to understand
the page well, are you utilizing the
network by leveraging browser caching,
setting minimum cookie sizes, are you
doing the right things for performance.
So a lot of this stuff would be sort
of what you used to do with Page Speed
insights, and it's going to
be completely integrated into
the Chrome developer tools pretty soon.
But in the mean time, you can find
it on the Chrome store as a plugin
that you can install and
it'll automatically set-up widgets.
These last two,
I'm not going to dive too deep into but
they're just debuggers for
specific frameworks.
So there is a framework you're using,
say, Backbone, Amber, or Knock Out.
More often than not, you can usually
find some kind of debugging tool that
you just download, it installs, it sets
up its own Chrome tab, and it'll make it
handy for sort of debugging applications
that are using that technology.
Because sometimes it does
become difficult to debug those
using just the elements or
resources or console tabs.
>> Yeah, these JavaScript
frameworks are very complicated.
I think you can find those just as
Chrome extensions from Chrome web store.
>> Yeah, yeah, so most of those
are on the Chrome web store.
Even some of the frameworks,
the sites have them listed there.
But yeah, I mean, it's just as easy
as finding, Googling backbone,
or amber, or
angular Chrome developer tools.
And usually, the first link that pops
up in Google, Bing, Duck Duck Go,
whatever you use ideally will
be that Chrome web store link.
Yeah, so
that's pretty much the Chrome Dev tools.
If do you have any more
questions about it or
are if you're finding it
difficult to parse something or
understand something in the Dev tools,
where things change dramatically again,
which they always seem to do because the
Google team is constantly iterating on
these, we'll be happy to clarify any
points you guys have in the forum.
But let's take a look and
see if we got any questions.
We had one a little earlier from Jonas
about what regex is and I went ahead and
answered it in the chat, but
I'll say it out loud here as well.
Regex is just short for regular
expressions, and it's just a pattern
matching language that you can use to
sort of match patterns of strings.
It's really handy for sort of parsing
over data, and parsing over files,
and just picking out specific
pieces of content that you want.
It's a pretty handy language.
It's pretty common in most programming
languages to use some sort of
regex functionality ,and there's
a lot of regex interpreters online
that you can use to practice and play
around with your regular expressions.
We get this one from Alex that says,
it would be nice, in fact,
if you show an actual debugging process,
how to step around functions, etcetera.
You know what?
>> In the forum post, I can go into
a lot more detail with the debugger.
In hindsight, the website we picked
probably doesn't have enough complicated
JavaScript to do anything
worthwhile with the debugger.
But look out for that forum post
which will be Coming out in under
an hour most likely and I will go
super in depth into the debugger.
>> Yeah and I mean the debugger
is a pretty handy tool.
I would say I use it when I'm doing,
most of my websites are super
JavaScript heavy but
I think it comes in handy a lot for
projects like the classic
arcade game project.
Where there's sort of a lot of of
continuous JavaScript functions that
are continually running,
and looping, and
executing while the user is on the page.
Yeah, and single-page JavaScript, apps
using those big frameworks we mentioned.
Angular backbone, Ember.
That's when the debugger comes in handy.
Kind of static websites that
are mostly HTML and CSS-based.
You don't really need it, but for
those bigger JavaScripty websites,
definitely useful.
So yeah, again, I'll go into a lot of
detail in that in the form post and
with screenshots and
everything like that.
>> Cool.
It doesn't look like we have any other
questions unless they start coming in.
But yeah, I mean the DevTools are,
you're going to be buried in them.
It's a really good skill
to have as a web developer.
It's going to give you a lot of
insights in to your website and
websites other people build.
In fact, it's honestly the,
it's easy to learn by just going to
other websites that
you're familiar with.
Cracking open adept tools or
just kind of playing around with the.
The more experience you can just
kind of trying things out the easier it
is to remember them.
And the easier it is for you to remember
like hey, I can do this and go tools
are great for looking at websites and
trying to mimic things as well.
That's a big part of the learning
process as well I think.
>> Yeah, definitely.
It's great for if you get inspired by
something on a website you stumble upon
and you want to kind of
learn how to do it.
The dev tools make it just a click away.
>> Yeah, I love doing that and
I think there's there's a lot of
websites that I go to, a lot of blogs
that I see where some developers done
some really nice like CSS animation
or like a really cool fly out or
some really cool text.
And I'm like man what box is that?
And it's really easy to just highlight
it, crack open the depth tools, and
see it right away like, okay,
they're using this font.
This is how they're sort of
triggering this animation.
Or this is the JavaScript they're using.
It kind of
feels like you're playing detective
sometimes and I think I like that.
>> Yeah, definitely.
>> All right, so it doesn't look
like we have any more questions.
So any last thoughts from you, Tye?
>> No, like John said, the best way to
learn the dev tools is definitely just
jump in and start playing around.
In the forum posts that I mentioned
that'll be posting out shortly soon or
shortly after the call is that
Google has great documentation so
I'll be sharing a link to
the dev tools documentation.
That's really the only place you need
to go to learn about the dev tools.
They did a really good job with that.
>> Yeah and going here documentation,
there's still something
to you that need to be updated
especially on the timeline too.
>> Yeah the timeline.
Like I noticed in the docs it was
slightly outdated it looked like it was
from the last version of cry.
As far as the like the screen
shots need to be updated but
most of the information
there is very up to date.
And the tutorial also really helpful,
they kind of show you,
how to do all of kind of
the basic things we mentioned.
And there's a lot more advanced stuff
you can do with the death tools as well,
if you want to die then.
>> Yeah and like we mentioned if
you guys are having trouble or
forget about this webcast in the future.
You're like, I can't figure out
how to do this in the dev tools.
Always feel free to ask in the forum.
You can ping us directly
using @ John Nave And for
Tye, I think it's just @tye.
>> Yeah, it's either @tye or
@tyelucaskelley.
I think it's just @tye on the forums.
>> Cool.
Or slack that works as well
[CROSSTALK] from there.
All right.
Let's see.
We got one last quick
question in from Jay,
who says, are the devtools any
different with Chrome Canary?
And the answer is yeah, typically,
you're going to find a lot of sort of
beta features, and early features that
are introduced into the dev tools.
Most of the general stuff is
that pretty much the same
like they haven't completely
changed the constant tab, or
they haven't completely
changed the network tab.
But what you might find is you
might find that there is an extra
button there.
Or it might give you a little bit of
different information or maybe there's
a new tab on there that includes some
new features that you are able to use.
But generally, all the sort of previous
tabs and features that are accessible
and sort of earlier versions of Chrome
are available in Chrome Canary.
They haven't done any sort of real
gigantic overhaul where it's vastly
changed the way the dept rules work.
>> Yeah, you should still totally feel
at home and the canary adept tools.
>> One last question from
where do you find the page
that you were talking about.
We'll be posting under the forms and
will be sure to send out I'll
update this video's description
with the link to that as well.
And I'll see about getting
maybe the link emailed out for
those of you wanting to go back and
look at that.
But they'll be in the course
forums in the broadcasts and
announcements section.
Sweet.
All right, thank you everybody for
joining us today.
Thank you, Tye.
>> Bye everybody.
>> All right, cool, have a good rest of
your Monday and we'll see you next time.