If you have a list that you
want to shrink in parallel,
a really handy trick is to use
something called an independent set.
Consider a linked list like this one.
For each node i,
let N[i] = i's successor.
For this example here is
what N would look like.
Okay.
So what's an independent set?
Given a list, an independent set
is a subset of the vertices.
Such that any vertex
that's in the set does not
also have it's successor in the set.
For example, here's an independent set.
Notice how none of the successors of 3,
7 or
8 have neighbors that
are also in the set.
What about this example?
This set corresponds to these vertices.
Notice that 8 is a successor of 6, so
this is set is not an independent set.
Now computing an independent
set sequentially is super easy.
Start with an empty independent set,
then traverse the list from head to
tail, assigning every other node to i.
For instance, you could put
the head in i, then skip 2,
instead move to 7 and
add it to the independent set.
Then you'd skip 1, and
so on and so forth.
Okay, that was easy,
so what's the big deal?
Computing an independent set in
parallel is a little bit trickier.
Let's see why.
Consider a list.
Let's take any vertex in that list,
let's say i.
Now suppose you're processing all
the vertices inside a parallel for loop.
So how does any vertex know whether or
not it should go into
the independent set?
This problem is sometimes referred
to as the problem of symmetry.
Basically all nodes look the same.
Now what you need is a scheme.
A scheme to break the symmetry.
Ooh, a scheme.
How delightfully sinister.
A scheme.
Ooh a scheme.
Evil.
Here is one way to do it
which is based on a gamble.
At every node in parallel,
flip an unbiased coin.
Each node will get a head
with probability one-half and
a tail otherwise.
Let's adopt the convention
that any node with a heads
is a candidate to be placed
in the independent set.
Any tail will be left out
of the independent set.
Now this scheme has a slight snag.
It's possible that both a given node and
its neighbor are both heads.
Suppose a node has a head and
sees that its neighbor has a head.
Then what the node will do is
change its head into a tail.
So with this tweak, you can now see that
any head is adjacent only to a tail.
Therefore, if you now take
all the vertices with heads,
that will be a valid independent set.
Woot.
So to summarize, here is the randomized
parallel independent set scheme.
You're given a set of neighbors, and
you want to produce an independent set.
And of course you want to
do this in parallel, so
you need some space for coins.
Now, it will also be
helpful to have a copy.
You'll see why, but basically you
need to change some coins and
you want to do that in parallel safely.
First take each vertex in parallel,
then flip a coin at each vertex.
You'll get either a head or a tail.
And stash a copy for later use.
That's step one.
Here's step two.
Again visit each vertex in parallel.
At each vertex, check whether
you're in a double heads situation.
If so, replace a head with a tail.
The last step is just to collect
the list of vertices that have heads.
You'll recall that you can
use a gather If to do that.
That's it.
In just a moment you'll
analyze this scheme.
But first,
take a look at a pseudocode and
just make sure you
understand what it's doing.