I started here from within the afeat
because it already has the square target
which I want to add
an event listener to.
I set an event listener on the square
target listening to touchend.
And I also added
the callback showTouchEnd,
which will get called whenever
touchend occurs on the square.
And here's showTouchEnd.
It's pretty straightforward, but
I did add some logic to it to
make it disappear after a moment.
But you didn't need to do that.
All that's important here is that I
set the outputs innerHTML to touchend.
So when the touchend event gets called
on the square, showTouchEnd gets called.
And when showTouchEnd gets called, the
output.innerHTML gets set to touchend.
Okay, that's pretty simple.
Let's see how it looks.
So here's the site.
With the mouse, nothing happens,
which is expected.
But when I switch to device emulation
mode and move around, look at that,
touchend appears right here.
Cool!
All right,
that's a pretty good start for events.
Let's keep going.