So how do we use recycler view?
The first thing to note is that
almost every part of recycler view is
completely moduler.
The recycler view has an adapter
that is used to provide the recycler
view with new views when needed.
This Adapter is also used to bind data
from some Data Source to the views.
The adapter sends the views to
a RecyclerView in an object
called a ViewHolder.
The ViewHolder contains a reference
to the root view object for the item.
And you're expected to use it to
cache the view objects represented in
the layout, to make it less costly
to update the views with new data.
This way,
find a view by ID gets called only for
each data view whenever that
new item is created and
not each time you want to populate
the views in the item with data.
The Layout Manager then tells
the RecyclerView how to lay out
all those views.
It could be a vertically scrolling
list like we use in SunShine, or
horizontally scrolling lists, or
even a staggered list or a grid.
You get some awesome animations for
item insertion and removal for free.
Because it's based on a data source,
it's easy for
apps using Recycler View to allow for
filtering a list of items.
Android also has an older framework for
displaying lists of
data called List View.
It has mostly become outdated, thanks
to RecyclerView, for these reasons and
several others.