So, you know how to draw lines now.
Let's try drawing a really,
really complicated line
called the dragon curve.
The dragon curve is a fractal with
some really cool properties, and
it has a reasonably simple rule for
producing it.
The base case is just
an elbow like this, and
we'll call this L for a left turn.
Now the recursive rule is to
produce a dragon curve of order N,
you take a dragon curve of order
N minus one, turn left, and
then reverse and reflect the dragon
curve of order N minus one.
Sounds straightforward right?
Let's do a few examples.
So, the dragon curve of order two
is the left turn that we got from
the dragon curve of order one,
followed by another left turn, and
then we reverse and reflect this left
turn, which is just a right turn.
This is what this looks like.
We make a left turn, we make
a left turn, we make a right turn.
The third order dragon curve is already
starting to get pretty complicated.
We've got LLR from the second
order dragon curve.
We've got an L and then we have LLR
reversed and reflected, so LRR.
The fourth order dragon curve is
starting to get pretty squiggly.
And the fifth order dragon curve is
starting to get just ridiculous.
You can start to see some
interesting properties though.
The curve will touch itself, but
will never actually cross itself.
Once you get up to the tenth
order dragon curve,
it starts to look pretty beautiful,
like a crazy galaxy or something.
So to draw the dragon curve, we need to
first work out the turns the curve will
take, translate those curves
into line segments, and
then use ShapeRenderer
to draw a polyline.
Sounds easy enough, right?
Well, give it a try, but
this one's a lot harder than
anything else we've done today.
If you just want to check out
the reference solution, that's fine too.