So I can show you an example of this being done in 2D, that is,
with an image, here.
Okay?
Here we have a, an original image,
a beautiful little still life of some fruit in black and white.
And here is its Fourier transform power spectrum, just the magnitude, so
I'm not showing you the phases.
The middle, remember, we took,
we put the origin in the middle, is the low frequency.
And you can see that it falls off as you get out to the outside.
Now, we're going to blur this thing with a Gaussian.
And I'm showing you this Gaussian here at the same scale as the whole image.
So this Gaussian might be 15 by 15 pixels, but
it looks really small because we have a good sized image.
But it's get, that would blur the image a little bit.
And when I convolve the Gaussian with the original image,
I get exactly what we'd expect, a slightly blurry version of the image.
But look what happens in Fourier space.
The Fourier transform of this tight little Gaussian is this big fat Gaussian.
Remember, we said, small Gaussian in space has a big Gaussian in frequency.
And then we multiply this times this.
And what that's going to do is,
it's going to keep the areas in the middle, which you see here.
But it's going to attenuate the areas on the outside, so
it reduces those low frequencies.
And in fact, if I had wanted to, in order to recover this image,
what I could have done was taken the Fourier transform here,
multiplied it by this one, gotten this, and recovered back.
Except that to actually do the recovery,
it wouldn't be enough to just look at the magnitude.
I would actually have to keep the real and imaginary parts.
I'd have to keep the phase of the transform.
But here, I just wanted to show you what happens to the different
frequency power.