Let's see what I did
to get this to work.
In my app.js file I checked to see
if service workers are supported.
If they are, I register a service worker
served from the root directory of my
project to avoid any scoping issues.
Then, I added my service worker.
I added an install event,
that caches all of the files
needed by the app shell.
An activate event,
that will purge any of the old,
and outdated files and make sure that
we're always serving the latest.
And a fetch event handler that tries
to get the data from the cache, but
if not, goes and
gets it from the network.
You can download the solution I created
from the instructor notes below.