What about the correction?
Okay?
Well the correction is
a little complicated.
So what I'm going to do, is I'm going
to show you the formula for it.
Then I'm going to give you
the intuition behind it.
Then I'll show you,
actually, not the formula,
I'm going to show you
the simple formula for
the 1D case,
give you the intuition behind that.
And then give you the full formula for
the ND case.
First remember that we're assuming
our measurements are again just
some constant times the actual
state plus some Gaussian noise.
Okay?
That's our,
that's our linear system plus
Gaussian noise for the common filter.
Remember, we have our predicted state.
We just did that.
We said that that's Mu sub t minus.
All right?
That's the predicted mean, and
then sigma t minus squared that's
the variance of the prediction.
And what we want is we want
the corrected estimated distribution.
That's what this is, here.
All right?
So in Kalman with linear,
Gaussian dynamics and
Gaussian measurements, the corrected
distribution is defined to be, and
I'll show you that,
a new Gaussian, okay?
Which is now mu t plus and
sigma t squared plus, all right?
And what I want to do is, I want to
show you the formula for that and
then give you the intuition behind it,
okay?
This is the formula for the mean.
Okay?
So here is mu t plus, and
it's a combination of mu t and the y,
which we'll get to in just a minute.
The update the variance is here,
so sigma t plus squared, okay?
And you'll notice that what's
happening is that this number,
if you just do a little bit of this math
here Is actually going to end up being
smaller, okay,
than the predicted variance.
And that makes sense why?
Because remember after we take
a measurement our variance goes down.