Here are the answers. The first sentence is
true half the time and false half the time.
It would have been true all the time if we had written fire or not smoke, rather
than smoke or not fire on the right
hand side. The second sentence, is false when fire
is true and smoke is false and otherwise
true. The third sentence is always true. And this
is called the contrapositive. Smoke implies fire is
the same thing as not fire implies not
smoke. The fourth sentence is always true. And
you can figure that out by writing out the
full truth tables, or by reasoning about the
variable big. When big is true, the whole
sentence is true, because big is one of
the disjuncts. And when big is false, it's true,
because big implies dumb is true whenever the antecedent is false. And
the final sentence is also always true. And this is known as De Morgan's Law.