And Android has a very
expressive intents system.
Explain to me some of the differences
between implicit and explicit intents.
>> So, I'm actually not familiar
with implicit and explicit intents.
Intents, in terms of launching another
application or something like that I'm
familiar with or even starting a new
activity within your app using intent.
But in terms of the difference between
explicit and implicit, I'm unfamiliar.
>> Yeah, that's fine.
And so, for explicit intents,
you're very specific about
the activity you want to launch.
So that's probably what you
use most often is, I'm saying,
I need to launch my login activity or
some other activity in my application.
And that's usually done with explicit.
Can you have an idea of what
implicit intents would look like?
>> I would think that if
the explicit is to start an activity
in your application,
implicit could be if your application
uses something like a bar code scanner.
Maybe you launch an intent for
a bar code scanner on your phone.
Or maybe if you don't have a bar
code scanner, it checks for that and
then launches the Play Store
where you can download one.
>> Yeah, and that's perfect.
And so, yeah, with implicit intents,
you can kind of say,
I need to be able to send an email and
here's a message.
I don't know about the client
that's going to receive it.
You can also build them within
your own application, so
if you care about switching
out that implementation later.
You could do that using
implicit intents.
So if you wanted to throw
your login activity up,
you don't necessarily have
to specify the explicit one.
You could instead specify an implicit
intent to launch that activity.
>> So that would be, if I had
an application that was an image editor.
And someone opens an image, it could
launch an intent to my app if I enabled
that, is that what you're saying?
>> Yeah, it's perfect.