Congratulations, you're
done with Sunshine.
And along the way, you've learned
how to build an app that runs
beautifully in the foreground and
efficiently in the background.
>> And now, you're well equipped to
build Android projects on your own.
>> Of course, there's still more
to learn about Android, and
practice makes perfect.
So as you build projects, it will be
helpful to refer back to these videos or
look at information on
the Android developer website.
>> And there's even an advanced Android
course created by us here at Udacity
that can help you explore the next step.
>> For now,
great job on completing this course, and
I think it's time to celebrate.
[SOUND]