Now that you know how
to make markers and
info windows, you can use what
you learned to make your own.
Your goal is to create a map with
a marker, that when clicked,
displays an info window with
the coordinate of the marker.
Bonus points if you can get creative and
make some colored markers or animations.
Just kidding, there are no points.
Using the starter code below, fill in
the TODOs with the correct information.
Hint, use marker.position
to get the latlng.
Look at the JavaScript
reference documentation and
at the page listed below, to learn more
about the properties of each marker and
infowindow.
Were you able to show a marker and
an infowindow?
[BLANK_AUDIO]