All right, so let's now talk
about the different types of
ads that you can have in your ad,
and what they look like.
In this lesson, we will focus on the
following types of ads, banner ads, and
interstitial ads.
Banner ads only covers a portion
of the visible screen, so
they can be shared with
content displayed by your app.
And if the user clicks on the ad
the webpage will be opened
that has more information about the ad.
Banner ads can either be text or
an image, like the one you see here.
Interstitial ads on the other hand,
will cover the entire screen.
That makes it really important to decide
when to show an interstitial ad since
your app can not display anything while
the interstitial ad is being displayed.
Interstitial ads are perfect when
there's a natural break in your ad.
For example, between levels of a game.
In addition, to text an image ads,
interstitial ads can
also show video content.
These two types of ads,
banner ads and interstitial ads,
are the ones that we will
look at in this lesson.
And although this lesson will focus
on banner and interstitial ads,
there is one more ad
type called native ads.
And as of May, 2015,
native ads are still in beta.
Native ads give you much more freedom to
customize the look and feel of the ad.
This is accomplished using
two different templates.
App install native Ads which
can drive app installations by
advertising the app.
And content native ads which allows for
a more generic combination of text and
images that covers a broader scope.
But in this lesson we will focus on
banner ads and interstitial ads.
So let's look into more details.