So we want to talk about something
called a Time to Check versus a Time to
Use problem.
Time to Check is when you open the file.
Time to Use is when you either read or
write it.
So a time to check,
time to use vulnerability
arises because access check is
performed separately from use.
Typically when you say you want to use
a resource, you perform the check.
But the model that I just showed you
with the open call coming first and
then read writes happening later on, and
you can do as long as the file is in
the closed and the process is running.
Okay, so it could be a while
before you do your read or
write after the open was done.
So when the two are separated,
this vulnerability arises.
And based on what time to check versus
time to use, think about what these are.
I want you to look into these
two options that we have.
What is the reason for this TOCTOU
vulnerability that we're talking about?