Let's go back to
the calculate price method.
Once we call this method it's going
to return the total order price.
And we can store this value inside
this variable called price.
Then we can display it on the screen.
To integrate the calculate
price method into our app
we're going to need
to use return values.
Let's look at the pseudocode first.
Within the submitOrder method we want
to call the calculatePrice method.
It's going to compute
the total price of the order.
And it's going to return
that as the output.
So we're going to store that output
into a integer variable called price.
Then we're going to take that price,
and then display it on the screen.
Let's look at the actual Java code for
that.
In the submitOrder method,
we would add this line of code.
Do you remember the assignment
operator from lesson 2?
Whenever I see this,
I evaluate the right hand side first.
The calculatePrice method returns
a single value which is the order price.
And that should get stored inside
this local variable called price.
Then we can call another method,
displayPrice.
And the input to that method is going
to be the price variable that we
just created.
This is the first time
we're seeing how a method
can be used as part of an expression.
For example,
we can call this method, and
the value that gets returned from that
can be added to other numbers or,
if it was a string,
we can concatenate it to other strings.
All that matters is that the whole thing
on the right hand side gets evaluated to
a single value and then gets stored
on the left hand side variable.
But for the Just Java app we're just
going to use calculate price directly
and show that on screen.
For this coding task you'll be making
sure that the calculate price method
is getting defined and
called properly in the Just Java app.
First focus on how
the method is defined.
Modify the calculatePrice method
to have the correct return data
type in the method signature.
Also assume that there's
0 input parameters.
The next step is to modify
the inside of that method.
Make sure that it's returning
the correct price of the total order,
which is the quantity of cups
ordered times the price per cup.
You can assume that each
cup of coffee costs $5 and
you can just hardcode that
directly into this method.
Once that is all done, then you can move
on to how the method is getting called.
Call calculatePrice from
the submitOrder method, and
you can use the code that
we talked about earlier.
Then, go ahead and
display this price on the screen.
Now, you could use the displayPrice
method, but you did a lot of work at
the end of Lesson Two to show
some text on the screen as well.
It also said, thank you, so if you
could try to integrate this price value
with that text,
that would be most ideal.
It should look something like this.
So if you change the quantity and
then hit order, then the price
shows up here along with the text.
When you're done,
check these boxes to continue.