In order to solve this problem,
first notice that we have two unknowns, z and z prime.
What does that indicate?
Well, we probably need two equations to solve.
One is our by now familiar thin lens equation.
That is 1 over z plus 1 over z prime equals 1 over f.
Let us simplify this so we can express one variable in terms of the other.
Adding the two terms on the left hand side, and then cross multiplying.
Now say we want all the zs on one side, take z common, and
finally we can write zs, z prime f over z prime minus f.
Remember this last result.
Now, we need to think about a second equation.
Look at the diagram again.
See anything useful?
How about these two similar triangles.
They tell us that half of d over z prime is equal to half of w over z.
Simplifying this, we can write that is z equals w over d times z prime.
This is our second result, remember we found earlier that z equals z prime
f over z prime minus f, and now we saw that z equals, w over d times z prime.
Equating these two and solving further, we have z prime equals d f by w plus f.
Now putting the value of d, f,
and w here, you should get z prime equals 52.5 millimeters,
putting that here, should give you z equals one point o five1.05 meters