So let's try something
a little more difficult.
And we'll make it
the first coding exercise.
Instead of drawing just a single star,
let's fill the screen
with the star field.
Let's go ahead and import the project.
So it looks like in the course code,
we have Exercise-DrawStarField,
and Solution-DrawStarField.
You know what, let's open up
the solution first to see what
we're aiming for.
For a project that I don't think I'm
going to be running a whole ton of
times, I'll sometimes skip setting
up the desktop run configuration and
instead, just open up the terminal and
type ./gradlew.
On Windows, we just leave off the ./ and
then tell Gradle,
hey I want to run the desktop run task.
All right, there we go.
I cranked up the star density pretty
high in the hopes that you can
actually see this.
All right so this is what
we're going to try and make.
Let's jump over to the starter project.
All right here we go again, import
project, and this time we're going to
open the exercise project
instead of the solution project.
All right, we've got
the exercise project loaded up.
Let's open up the TODOs to
see what we need to do.
TODO, start here, sounds good.
Looks like we got some
instructions in this exercise.
We'll draw a star field of white
points on a black background.
The number of points will be defined
by a density parameter that states what
proportion of the pixels
should be white.
All right.
TODO: Run what you've got
before making any changes.
Since I do anticipate to be running
this project a while bunch of times,
I am going to go ahead and
create a run configuration for it.
If we run it, we get red.
The sky is not supposed to be red.
I presume we're going to
have to fix that later.
Oh well,
at least we've got a running project.
Opening up the TODOs again.
We've started here,
we've run what we've got.
All right, next thing,
initialize a shape renderer.
Okay, well that's easy enough.
shapeRenderer = new ShapeRenderer,
done and dusted.
All right, the next toTODO,
call initStars.
All right,
initStars takes this density parameter.
And looks like we have a constant
defined for that, okay?
All right, easy, we're on a roll.
Let's do one more.
Let's say I'm confused,
instructions unclear,
got charging cable stuck in ceiling fan.
Well, not to worry, we've got
the solution to this exercise as well.
Here we are back in the reference
solution, and if we open up the TODOs,
we see the exact same TODO list
as we had over in the exercise.
So here is the TODO we were stuck on.
And let's see, we get the screen width
using Gdx.graphics.getWidth, okay.
We get screen height using
Gdx.graphics.getHeight, all right.
And then starCount.
All right, so that's the height
times the width times the density.
All right, that makes sense.
So this is the total number
of pixels on the screen.
And then this is the proportion
of them that should be stars.
And then we just cast it to an int.
All right, seems straightforward enough.
Now we can hop back over to the exercise
code and replicate what we saw here.
Or we can just copy and paste if
we're feeling particularly lazy.
All right, time for you to tackle
the rest of the TODOs on your own,
using the reference
solution whenever you need.
When you're done check out the reference
solution anyway, as there will be
useful tips, best practices, and
maybe some extra challenges to try.
If your version doesn't look exactly
like the reference solution,
that's totally fine.
There are always a lot of ways
to accomplish the same goal.