[Thrun] So let me give you some examples of this method in action.
Here we have an actual planning technique that uses dynamic programming
and understands how far things are away.
And on top of it, it also considers local rollouts to avoid local obstacles.
These local rollouts are continuous trajectories.
They are variant by discrete decisions,
like whether to change the lane, and by various small discrete nudges around obstacles
so we can avoid obstacles.
And in rolling out to a certain horizon, like up to here,
and then connecting to the dynamic programming value,
we can calculate in actual traffic situations what is the cost of going a certain path.
Here is an attempt to turn right.
You can see the vehicle approaching a stop sign.
There is an entire maze of streets.
The best way to go right and then into the left lane is to take the right turn
and then initiate a lane shift, which is happening right now,
to reach a target location that is indicated by this big orange circle
that it's crossing right now.
If we increase the cost of a lane shift to a much larger value,
the answer that emerges is really interesting.
It doesn't turn right because of the cost of the subsequent lane shift.
Instead this vehicle goes straight,
takes a left turn, which happens to be much cheaper than the lane shift.
It then follows this left turn, takes another left turn,
and eventually takes a third left turn just to get to the left lane.
And if you look very carefully, you can now reach the goal location
without a lane change maneuver which would have much higher cost.
So here it is now in the left lane, and without lane-changing maneuver
it manages to reach the goal.
This illustrates that dynamic programming in the context of controlling actual cars
has a big value to play.
Here is the same idea applied to a passing maneuver in normal driving.
You see our vehicle following another vehicle.
This is actual data in preparation for the Urban Challenge.
Now we placed an abandoned vehicle on the left lane,
and you can see how trainers are being made that incorporate dynamic obstacles
by virtue of those rollouts and a dynamic programming function
by virtue of the background green to red to find the optimal actions.
This method has really enabled us to navigate complicated situations with self-driving cars.