The specific objectives, this lesson are for
you to learn about, the benefits of feature detection and
matching in two images, again, given two images I want to be able to find,
commonalities in these two images for a variety of applications.
I'm also going to discuss, what makes a good feature.
An example of a good feature in this context would be a corner,
some sort of an information that defines a corner in an image that would
allow us to find a repeatable match across multiple images.
And we'll also talk about briefly the Harris Corner Detector Algorithm, and I
will just introduce the basic concept of a SIFT detector, both the Harris Corner
and SIFT detector we'll discuss in detail, in a future lecture.