So that's everything you need to know
to get started with playing audio on
Android Auto.
The Android Media Framework is
used not just in Android Auto, but
in Android in general,
as well as Android Wear.
So by investing your time into this,
you get other platforms for free.
By exposing the media in your app to
Android Auto, the user is able search
and browse through the available content
using their voice or the touch screen.
Android Auto takes care of all the work
of presenting the interface to the user,
saving you time in building
user interface for cars.
So I'm looking forward to seeing what
kinds of cool music apps you build for
Android Auto.
I'll see you on the road.