In our own reserch, we also have applied eigenvector decomposition
to relatively challenging problems that don't look like a linear problem at the surface.
We scanned a good number of people with different physiques:
Some thin, some not so thin, some tall, some short, some male, some female.
We also scanned them in 3-D in different body postures:
The arms down, the arms up, walking, throwing a ball, and so on.
We applied eigenvector decomposition of the type I've just shown you
to understand whether there is a latent low-dimensional space
that is sufficient to represent the different physiques that people have,
like thin or thick, and the different postures people can assume, like standing and so on.
It turns out if you apply eigenvector decomposition
to the space of all the formations of your body,
you can find relatively low dimensional linear spaces,
in which you can express different physiques and different body postures.
For the space of all different physiques it turns only 3-dimensions sufficed
to explain different heights, different thicknesses or body weights,
and also different genders.
That is, even though our surfaces themselves are representive
of tens of thousands of data points, the underlying dimensionality
when scanning people is really small.
I'll let you watch the entire movie.
Please enjoy.
[SCAPE: Shape Completion and Animation of People]
We present a method named SCAPE for simultaneously modeling
the space of all human shapes and poses.
Further, we demonstrate the method's usefulness
for both shape completion and animation.
The model is computed from an example set of surface meshes.
We require only a limited set of training data:
Examples of posed variation from a single subject
and examples of the shape variation between subjects.
The resulting model can represent both articulated motion
and, importantly, the nonrigid muscle deformations
required for natural appearance in a wide variety of poses.
The model can also represent a wide variety of different body shapes,
spanning both men and women.
Because SCAPE incorporates both shape and pose
we can jointly vary both shape and pose to create people who never existed
and poses that were never observed.
We demonstrate the use of this model 1st for shape completion of scanned meshes.
Even when a subject has only been partially observed,
we can use the model to estimate a complete surface.
In this case, the entire front half of the subject has been synthesized.
Note that the synthesized data both conforms to the individual subject's
specific shape and faithfully represents
the nonrigid muscle deformations associated with a specific pose.
Mesh completion is possible even when
neither the person or the pose exists in the original training set.
None of the women in our example set
look similar to the woman in this sequence.
Shape completion can also be used to synthesize complete
animated surface meshes.
Starting from a single scanned mesh of an actor
and a timed series of motion capture markers
we can treat the markers themselves
as a very sparse sampling of surface geometry
and complete the surface which best fits the available data at each point in time.
Using this method, animated surface models
for a wide variety of motions can be created with relative ease.
In addition, the target identity of the surface model can easily be changed
simply by replacing the subject portion of our factorized model with a different vector.
The new identity need not be present in our training set
or even correspond to a real person.
An artist is free to alter the identity arbitrarily.