This one's going to
be a two-parter quiz.
For this first part, you need to
create the website for a bakery and
fill it with some static content.
The website will need routes for
the store and then routes for
some of the things it sells,
such as cakes, cupcakes, and cookies.
Once you've generated all these routes,
add an additional link for
the store's home page here.
Each route will need a heading so make
sure you review these instructions for
exactly what to put as the heading for
each page.
You're going to fill out the cookie
page with some actual content.
I've created this table for
you with some data that you'll
need to use on that page.
Let me give you a quick preview
of what I came up with for
this first part of the quiz.
I have a store route now,
the store has links to its baked goods.
All of these are nested routes.
Clicking on the cookie link displays
all of the information from
the instructions.
As you can probably tell I'm
a world class designer, so
I hope you can make your website
look at least half as good as this.
Actually I highly doubt you could
make it look any worse than this.
But the goal is more practice
with generating routes,
working with nested routes and
creating templates.
The link to the starter code for
this project is in the instructor notes.
When you finish building the template,
the feedback extension
will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page,
good luck.
Ember uses the queue
unit testing framework.
And I created a number of tests
that you need to satisfy.
These tests help guide you through
completing the assignment.
Once all the tests have passed the
feedback extension will give you a code.
Enter that code on the next page.
You can find a link to this project's
test page in the project's read me file.