In NDB,
most properties are indexed by default.
If your entities have
a lot of properties,
indexes can take up a lot more
space than the entities themselves.
Unindexed properties also cost fewer
write ops than indexed properties.
If you want to disable indexing for
specific properties, to save some space
in Datastore, you can explicitly disable
indexing when you declare a property.
To do this, when you declare the
property, you'll just add indexed=False.
And, take a look at the documentation
for NDB Property Types,
which is linked in the Instructor Notes.
And, find out which of the following
types are not indexed by default