It makes sense to start by
taking a look at worker.js.
Notice that when it receives
a message from the main thread,
it's going to get two things, the image
data and the type of manipulation.
E is the whole message
from the main thread.
And then the data is the user data
that we're sending to the worker.
So, when I post a message
to the web worker,
I'll make sure that both
of these are included.
Back in the image app or in this case,
my solution to it, notice that
the loop is gone from manipulateImage.
That's because the loop
now lives in worker.js.
At the top of the script, I created
the web worker from worker.js and
I just called it imageWorker.
Whenever I need to use the web worker,
I'll use the reference imageWorker.
Whenever I need to post
a message to the worker or
receive a message from the worker,
I'll refer to it as imageWorker.
Back in the image app or in my case
the solution to the image app,
I'll start by creating a new web worker.
The syntax is fairly simple.
And then once I create it from
worker.js I can simply refer to it with
this variable name.
Down below in manipulateImage, you'll
notice that the whole loop is gone.
And that's because it's
being handled by the worker.
When I'm ready for
the worker to start doing its work,
I'll simply post a message to it by
calling postMessage on the variable for
the worker that I created above.
And remember, the worker is
expecting image data in type, so
I'm sending it an object of both.
Here the image data is being collected
from the canvas after an image
is uploaded.
And the type here is coming from
the button that was pressed.
Here, let me show you.
Each of the image manipulation buttons
has an onclick handler, which posts
a different string representing the type
of manipulation that should happen.
This type here gets passed
to manipulateImage.
Next up is the onmessage
handler attached to the worker.
This function will be run once
the worker sends something back.
First off, I toggle the ButtonAbledness.
So that's what grays out or
grays back in,
I guess, all the image manipulation
buttons at the top of the page.
And then I go ahead and grab the data,
and then return it to the context.
Next up there's the onmessage handler
that's attached to the web worker.
This function gets run once the web
worker returns something back to
the main thread.
One again, it passes a message
back which is called e here.
And the actual image itself
in the web worker is e.data.
Assuming that there is an image,
it gets put right on the canvas.
As a good practice, I also included
an onerror handler on the web worker.
It also calls a function, which in this
case throws a web worker exception.
All right.
Now let's see how all of this runs.
I've opened the solution
in the browser and
I've loaded the Chrome
image like before.
I'll hit Invert and watch.
No Jank, it doesn't freeze up,
and then a few seconds later,
the new one appears.
Notice that there was no huge stutter.
There was no Jank
appearing in the timer.
That's a really good sign that,
that work, that image manipulation work,
is happening off the main thread.
Notice how the work pretty
much stays under 60 frames
per second the whole time.
That's awesome.
And also down here in the view, you can
see the WebCore worker being spawned.
This worker's work down here is all of
the image manipulation that happened
off the main thread.
Very cool.
But, there is still
that performance bug.
Let me show you what it is.
Remember, I said to start with
the manipulate function before.
This manipulate function can be
found inside ImageManips.js.
The whole of ImageManips.js
is this manipulate function.
And then, using the string
types that were passed to it,
it decides what that
function should be equal to.
And then it runs the function using
the parameters passed from the worker.
Okay, that seems fairly reasonable,
but why is this a bug.
Notice how this is happening
inside the for loop.
That means,
for each and every pixel on the page, a
new function object has to get created.
And that's just a lot of overhead for
the browser.
So, I refactored this loop.
Outside of the loop,
I figure out which function I need.
I'll show you where this
function came from in a second.
And then I simply call that
function inside the loop.
This is much more performant because
I'm not creating a new function
every time I hit a new pixel.
GetManipFunc is the replacement for
manipulate from before
in imagemanips.js.
And instead of running one of
the image manipulations on a pixel,
it simple returns the function.
This allows me to use
the function over and
over inside the for loop without
creating a new one each time.
So, how does this perform?
Let me show you.
I've got the before and
after fixing that performance bug.
First off, notice how the new timeline
looks way better than the old one.
And the function itself run by the web
worker finished in only one second,
which compares very well to the five
seconds when it was done poorly.
All in all, I would be very happy
seeing this timeline on any app.