As we saw so far, the interactions between the kernel and
the user-level library involve requesting, allocating, and scheduling threads.
And this you may assume there's some number of threads allocated at
startup to get the operating system to boot.
So as a quick quiz, answer the following questions.
First, in the Linux kernel's codebase,
what is the minimum number of threads that are needed to allow a system to boot?
Second, what is the name of the variable that's used to set this limit?
Each of these questions can be answered by examining the source code of
the Linux kernel.
And please refer to the Instructors Notes for some useful pointers.