Now that we've given you an overview
of what you'll work on in the iOS
nanodegree, it's time to figure out
if right now is a good time for
you to start the program.
To do that, you'll take the readiness
assessment, which you can get to from
your nanodegree portal or
from the instructor notes here.
>> Before we start
the readiness assessment,
take a second to start
downloading Xcode,
Apple's free development environment.
All of the development work in
the nanodegree will take place
right in Xcode.
It'll be our text editor, our interface
builder, our build environment,
our testing harness,
even our research tool.
It's a great development environment,
and
Apple has poured a lot of attention
into it in the last year.
You can download it for
free on the OS 10 App Store.
You'll see a link in
the instructor's notes on this page.
It's a big download, so
we recommend starting it now so
you can jump into writing
code as soon as possible.