Price elasticity of demand is
a measure used in economics to show
the responsiveness, or elasticity,
of the quantity demanded of a good or
service to the change in its price.
We can use A/B testing to analyze
whether a change in price
impacts the quantity of a good or
service as a result.
Remember, A/B testing analyzes whether a
change applied to an experimental group,
is statistically different
from a control group.
Measuring the impact of a change,
before applying it broadly,
could be useful in minimizing the
potential negative impact of a change.
For instance, if you're thinking
of running a promotion,
you would run a test
on a subset of stores,
to determine if a promotion had
a positive impact on profit.
If the test showed positive results,
you would roll out the changes
to the rest of your stores.
Let's work through a detailed problem.
Imagine that you work for
a chain of spas.
You're part of a team looking for
ways to increase the gross margin, and
you've decide to experiment
with the price of facials.
Currently, your stores offer facials for
98.99, and you'd
like to predict whether a change in
price would yield greater gross margin.
You've been asked to predict
the gross margin change
if the facials were at 87.99 or 76.99.
We need to creat an A/B test that will
help us predict the gross margin change,
with different prices of facials,
assuming that the average customer
visits a store about
once every ten weeks.
Remember the process for A/B testing?
First, we'll select the treatment and
control units.
Then, we'll prepare and run the test.
And lastly, we'll analyse the results.