In this question I'd like you to fit a Markov model.
We have 3 sequences of observation--A, B, C, A, B, C.
This is the first state--state0--and these are the other states.
Same for A, A, B, B, C, C and A, A, A, C, C, C.
These are 3 different observation sequences.
The first element here is state0.
All the other ones are examples of transitions from state to xt-1 to xt.
Using maximum likelihood, I'd like to know the initial properties for state0
and all the transition probabilities. Those are indicated by the arrow.
This is the probability that A at time t - 1 goes to A at time t.
Here they are.
For any of the symbols in the sequence, we see there are three possible outcomes--
A-B-C, A-B-C, and A-B-C.
Each has a probability. Obviously, these 3 over here have to add up to 1.
These 3 over here have to add up to 1, and these 3 over here have to add up to 1.