So why don't you tell me about your first, first solution.
What components do you have?
>> Sure. So I started with five components, and then I added one towards
the end because I realized I might need a distinction for this component.
So I have a line, and lines consist of words.
So there's two components I have.
And, and in- >> So, so you have a component that holds the data for lines?
>> Yes. >> And a component that holds the data for words?
>> Yes. >> Okay.
Go ahead.
That have index, which is this object that holds all of our titles,
which consist of lines and nodes.
I guess, actually, I don't, I think titles may not be necessary.
I feel like I'm saying the same thing.
The index consists of all of our lines.
>> So the index, the word index could either be a verb or a noun.
So this is, this, you're thinking of it as a data structure?
>> Yes.
>> Go ahead.
>> And then I have a, a system which contains this index of all of our lines,
and then it also contains, or also uses our passes control to a circle or
like a shifter that will shift those lines around.
>> Okay, well, which of the components is responsible for doing the sorting?
>> Okay, so I've worked that out.
I don't have one.
>> Okay, so one other one.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And so, the, the operation here would be the system
passing over control to the, well, tell, tell me how it would work?
What would be the, the steps?
>> So the system would pass control to the index, or
it would use the index to aggregate through all of our lines,
all of our, yes, all of our lines that had multiple words in it.
And as it's going through each line circler would then circle it in all
the different formations that the line could be in so that the index will grow.
>> So the, the system is doing the calling into the data structure index to
get a, get out particular pieces, it then passes those to the circular shifter?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. And then a circular shifter produces some results that are then
passed over to the sorter.
Okay.
And this order does its thing and presumably there's an input process at
the start of this and there's an output process at the end of this.
>> Yes.
Well the way you phrased one part,
the circler doesn't necessarily have to know about this order.
So the circler its, I'm thinking its only job is rearrange the lines and
then now you have this index all the different arrangements in your lines.
That index could then just work with the sorter and
the circler doesn't have to know about it.
>> Sure.
And now, what is it that breaks the file into lines and the lines into words?
>> I guess the, the system in this case would be the one that gets the file and
then gives that off to the index or populates the index initially.