All right, so to finish up the lesson.
Besides prospective projection, there are other types of projection operators
which in fact are sort of special cases and they're used sometimes.
So they're, they're worth mentioning here.
One interesting form of
special case of perspective projection is called orthographic.
And as it's drawn here, basically orthographic is when I take my world and
I just smash it right into my image plane.
And what's interesting about that is that it actually can be thought of
as a special case of perspective projection.
But where the distance from the center of projection to the image
plane is infinite.
And my object is infinite, right?
If those both were sort of infinite then basically what I end up doing is the z
value doesn't matter because those rays are parallel.
So that's why this is also called parallel projection and so
xyz just gets moved to xy.
This is actually some times used as a model for telephoto lens.
Because telephoto lenses are looking at things very, very far away.
So all of your rays are almost exactly parallel.
Now of course, it has to be scaled so you end up scaling the x and
scaling the y.
But it's the same scale value for your whole world.
I mention that, because we're going to
talk about something called weak perspective, in a minute.
So basically, when you throw away the z value and then you just scale the x and
y by some number, that's this parallel projection.
And since it can be, since I said it was a special case of
perspective projection, there must be a matrix operation that would recover it.
And here it is.
And you'll notice, now, that this value is zero, okay?
And this value is one.
So x, y, z one, the matrix just equals x, y one.
And when you divide out by the one, you just get the x, y.
So even this orthographic projection can be represented as the same matrix,
as a matrix multiplication when we use homogenous coordinates.
Another model is called weak perspective.
Sometimes called scaled orthographic but I, that's a bad choice.
There's also something called power perspective but
what we're going to call weak perspective is following.
The idea is that we know that when things get further away,
they're going to get smaller.
But what we're going to do is, we're going to say that all the points on
a given object, we're going to assume they're all at, at some constant depth.
We'll say z0 as it's written here.
Okay?
So for all the points on that object, xyz will get mapped to,
fx over z0, fy over z0.
So that object will get scaled.
But some other object,
might be a significantly closer object, it will get scaled by a different value.
So basically in weak perspective, what we're saying is that the difference of
depth over an object or over the range of an object, is very small compared
to the difference in depth from the object to the center of projection.
And if that's true,
then you can basically say that each object has its own scale factor.
Of course, as a special case of perspective projection,
we can do this in a matrix form also.
So, here we have the equation or, or
the transformation we said before, x, y, z goes to fx over z0, fy over z0.
So basically, f over z0 is acting like a scale factor, okay?
So here we have our projection matrix, which now,
instead of having a one over here, has a one over s.
And then when I multiply that through on the homogenous coordinates and
then divide, I'm dividing by the 1 over s, which gives me sx, sy.
So weak perspective gives you this scaled effect of each collection of
points that sit on a given object.
So those are the three camera projections that we'll talk about.
The one that we'll use all the time is perspective,
which ends up giving you fx over z, fy over z.
And we showed you how to do it in matrix coordinates using
homogeneous coordinate system.
And then we also talked about weak perspective where you have a scale factor,
sort of, per object.
Or orthographic, where you basically just throw away the z value.