Most people think of Chrome Cast
when they hear the word Cast.
But Google Cast, as a technology,
is much more than that.
Chrome Cast is a small USB powered
dongle that plugs into the back of
the HDMI port on your TV.
Google Cast itself is
a connecting technology.
Using the SDK, you can integrate
a Cast device to become part of your
application's output area.
And if you'd like, you can control the
Cast by sharing it with multiple people.
Chrome Cast is just one product
that supports the Cast protocol.
There are many others as well, including
Android TV, which is Cast built in,
as well as audio speakers from LG and
Sony.
Now as a developer, you don't need to be
aware of these different device types.
Once you cast enable your app,
it will work with all of them.
When you start working with Cast, you
typically have an existing application
you've already built and
would like to extend.
You integrate Google Cast into
your app using the Cast SDK.
And Wii of SDK is available for Android,
iOS, as well web apps running on Chrome.
The first thing to understand about
Google Cast are the concepts of a sender
and a receiver.
When you integrate the Cast SDK
into your existing app,
it becomes what we call the sender.
Sender applications send, or
cast, content to cast devices
either on the local network or
to cast devices running in guest mode
that can be detected based on proximity.
What you cast from your application
needs to be received by something, and
that's what we call the receiver.
Receiver's are small
HDML five applications
that run on a cast enabled device,
like a Chrome Cast.
Here's a quick overview of
how the cast process works.
First, you begin with an existing app.
Then you integrate the Cast SDK
to enable discovery of devices.
The SDK detects Cast devices
in the background, and
when one's discovered the Cast
icon becomes visible.
Clicking that Cast icon shows a menu
of the available Cast devices.
And selecting one will start the Cast.
The Cast icon then changes colors
to show that it's connected.
At this point,
the sender becomes the remote control.
Note that here,
we've connected to the Cast device
before we've started playback.
But it's also possible to connect
after playback's already begun.
When the Cast begins, the Cast device
loads the receiver app from a URL.
Here we can see the receiver's
been loaded onto the Cast device.
Now receiver apps run independently, so
you can tell it to load things
like media streams from a URL.
When you do that, the Cast device pulls
the content directly from the Cloud, and
this is great because the user can use
their mobile phone for other things,
like checking e-mail or sending texts,
while the Cast is in progress.
To control the Cast, you can send
messages from the sender to the receiver
to do things like adjust the volume,
start playing new media, or even send
custom messages, for instance, to enable
a thumbs up or a thumbs down button.
And we'll see how to do
that later in the course.
Receiver applications running on Cast
devices are just web applications.
They're written in HTML, CSS, and
JavaScript, just like any other webpage.
The Cast device itself runs
a special version of Chrome, and
you can think of that
as having a single tab.
It's optimized for video playback, and
typically, you'll have a single video
tag that represents the onscreen area
where the media is to be played.
For developers who want to
get started quickly,
you don't have to worry about writing
a receiver application at all.
Google provides a couple of sample
receiver apps that you can load onto
your Cast device during development.
And you can even use these in
production if you'd like, for
playing back simple media.
The one we're looking at here is
called the Styled Media Receiver,
and we'll get to that
later in the course.
Google's also built a whole
bunch of sample sender apps for
Android, iOS, and Chrome.
You can build and
run these on your devices to see how the
SDK hooks into an existing application,
as well as how to handle different
Cast scenarios, like DRM playback.
There are quite a few of these samples,
so
I'll point you in the right direction
to the best ones later in the course.
Finally, it's essential to keep
in mind that we're designing for
the living room.
We want the user experience
to be familiar and enjoyable.
To help you build the best
possible Cast experience,
Google provides a set of user experience
guidelines and a design checklist.
We'll cover these later in the course,
and they're optional, but
highly recommended.
Let's recap with a quick quiz.