Here is the version of
the algorithm we're going to use.
Just like hill climbing, we're going
to iterate with Simulated Annealing.
Looking for
points close to our current position,
that might have an improved value.
However, we're going to select
our next position randomly for
the points in the region near us.
If the new position is better
than our current position,
we're going to take it.
However, if it isn't better,
we are still going to take it.
With the probability of e to
the delta e divided by T,
where T is our temperature.
>> So we start with high T?
Do we change it later on?
>> Yes, in the algorithm,
we have a schedule for
what the temperature should be.
And we'll start with
T being very high and
when T is high, say close to infinity.
Delta e over T goes to zero,
no matter what the delta e is,
even if it's negative.
So, e to the zero is one.
So in the beginning,
we have a lot of random motion.
As we take all the random
positions offered us.
No matter how bad the new position is.
>> I see.
Just like in real annealing,
when the temperature is very high.
The particle is jumping around
a lot in the beginning.
So that, if the particle gets
stuck in a local maximum instead.
It has the ability to leave that peak,
ignoring that it is going the wrong way.
And instead,
end up at a different part of the graph.
Because the temperature is high,
the next point at fixed randomly.
Can make it move down the slope.
Given enough time, the randomness will
ensure we get off this particular hill.
And hit the hill with
the global maximum instead.
>> Precisely.
>> But how does it converge?
Won't we continue doing
this random walk forever?
>> Well let's first take a look at the
opposite situation where T is near zero.
We never want T to actually be zero,
because that will give
us an undefined answer.
So for illustration purposes,
let's say T is equal to 0.01.
We already said, that if the proposed
new random position improves our score.
we're going to take it,
if it stays the same, delta e is zero.
Or, if it gets worse,
delta e is negative.
Let's say delta e here is -1.
Now, we have e to the -1 over 0.01,
which is the same as e to the -100.
Which is a very small number.
So, we have almost no chance of taking
that suggested new random position.
Instead, we'll keep generating
new random positions.
Until we get one that improves e.
>> Then when T is small,
we basically have normal hill climbing.
>> Correct.
>> So, we'll just slowly
change T from very large,
where we're going to move
over the graph randomly.
To very small,
where we climb to the nearest peak.
>> Yup.
>> And if we happen to get stuck
on the plateau along the way,
like here, delta E is zero.
But that makes the equation
e to the 0 again.
So that the algorithm will take
the new random position instead.
>> And
that will happen no matter what T is.
>> And eventually we'll
random walk off the plateau.
Back to someplace where there's
a positive gradient, and
continue going up to the maximum.
>> Exactly, the great thing
about simulated annealing,
is that it is guaranteed to
converge to the global maximum.
If we start T high and
decrease it slowly enough.