In the previous lesson, we talked
about Distributive File Systems.
We said that Distributive File Systems
were an example of a distributive
service where the state, the files,
were stored on some set of nodes,
the file servers.
And then the file servers were accessed
by many distributive nodes clients.
All of the file access operations open,
read, write on these files.
Where then service that was
provided by these servers, and
that these client nodes
were requesting from them.
Our primary focus of
the Distributed File System lesson
was the caching mechanisms.
These are useful so that server
data is cached on the clients.
And this is a mechanism that improves
the performance that's seen by
the clients.
The clients can now access
these files more quickly.
Caching is also a mechanism that
enhances the scalability of
the distributed file system
overall of the servers.
Because some of the operations
are now performed by the clients,
the servers don't have to
perform every single access and
therefore they can scale to support
a larger number of clients and
serve larger number
of files potentially.
What we didn't talk about is,
what happens in the situation when
there are multiple file servers?
And how do they control and
coordinate the access of shared state,
of shared files, among them?
We also didn't talk about situations in
which all of the nodes in the systems
were both servers, storing files and
allowing access to those files,
as well as clients sending request
to other nodes in the system.
In such a scenario there really isn't
a clear distinction between client
nodes and server nodes.
Every single one of the nodes would
be performing all of the services.
In this is lesson
distributed shared memory,
we will talk about these kinds of
scenarios, the distributed applications,
where all the nodes in
the distributed environment are both
the servers that provide the state and
provide the access to that state and
also issue requests to other nodes
in the system to their peers.
So, perform some of the client
functionality that we saw before.