You can extend intent service to create
your own recommendation service.
When you need to refresh
your recommendations,
invoke the service by sending an intent.
Inside this method, we find items to
recommend from our Media Library.
This is just dummy code.
And of course you replace
it with something smarter.
Once we have items to recommend,
here's where we'll
use our RecommendationBuilder
to construct the notifications.
After they're constructed,
we'll post the notifications by calling
the notification manager's
notifying method.
This part is important.
The first parameter is
the notification ID,
and you'll need to keep track of this.
It's required when we'd like to update
or dismiss an existing recommendation.
Later on, if you'd like to remove a
recommendation, you can do so by calling
the cancel method on the notification
manager with a notifications ID.
Here's a gotcha.
If you want to update a recommendation,
don't cancel and resend it.
This could cause the position
of your recommendation to
change on the recommendations row and
that could annoy users.
Instead update your recommendation.
To do so,
simply create a new notification and
issue it by calling the notification
manager, dot notify method,
with the same notification ID as the
recommendation you'd like to replace.
Earlier, we said we'd add a pending
intent to our notifications to take
the user directly to our content.
We construct that intent using
this build pending intent method.
This is pretty standard.
The most important part is to
keep track of the movie and
the notification id by
putting them in the bundle.
There's one last thing to do here.
Our Movie Details fragment is
the fragment that's actually going to
receive this intent.
We need to insure that it responds
properly when it receives the pending
intent as opposed to being started
up directly from the Android TV
home screen, or from a search activity.
To do so, we check for the pending
intent inside the onCreate method.
Now we have our intent service ready
to go, but how can we start it up?
One option is just to update
your recommendations when users
are using your app.
Alternatively, you can use
an AlarmManager to always update them in
the background.
That's our approach here and
we'll kick off that AlarmManager
when the TV boots up.
Let's head to the BootupActivity
to see how this is accomplished.
And by the way, this class really
should have been named BootupReceiver.
This is a typo and, hopefully,
we'll have it fixed by
the time you take this class.
To start it when an Android TV boots up,
we'll declared this intent filter.
Inside boot up activity we created an
alarm manager with a pending intent to
update our recommendations.
And here's a performance tip.
When you set alarms,
it's important to use set in exact
repeating instead of set repeating.
The former lets Android adjust
your delivery time slightly
to keep the device in sleep mode for
as long as possible.
This saves power and is especially
important on mobile devices.
Although it's still
counts on Android TV.
If you're like to learn more about
Android Performance Patterns, check out
the Android Performance Patterns
course linked in the instructor notes.
And that's all there is to it.
Remember that high quality
recommendations will
lead to more clicks.
And those will in turn lead to your
recommendations being featured more
prominently.
Also, please keep your
recommendations family safe.