So we have full access to
the document object model, and
the JavaScript console.
We can see the HTML page and
the HTML tag for everything
that's listed on this web page.
We simply type in the word document.
Notice that if I hover over
the document node here in the console,
it also gets highlighted
in the HTML view.
And then we can see all
the nested objects inside there.
The other top level object that
is available is the Window.
The Window corresponds
the browser window,
while the document corresponds to the
HTML page that has already been loaded.
When you work with D3.js, you often
want to select elements on a page
either by the elements HTML tag,
their class or an ID.
The way that D3.js makes selection or
chooses items on a webpage is based
on the native DOM selection API that
get exposed through native JavaScript.
We can access an element by its
ID by using the appropriate ID
selector function on
the document itself.
So here I can use
document.GetElementById.
Notice that Chrome
tries to auto-complete
the functions that I can use.
So I can get an element by its ID.
I can get multiple elements by
their class names, and so forth.
So usually you won't need to use
these methods because there are so
many great libraries which
have selector functions.
These libraries like jQuery for example
make selecting DOM nodes so much easier.
Like jQuery D3 has many methods
in order to select DOM nodes.
So if you are are familiar with jQuery,
then selections will
make a lot of sense.
Let's try the simplest selection and
get an element by its ID.
I'm going to try and
select this footer element down here.
By right-clicking on
this footer element,
I can see the HTML source code, and
I can inspect the element itself.
Now, in this case,
I got the h1 that was selected, but
I can see right above it is
a div with an ID of footer.
So to select this footer using native
JavaScript, I'm just going to use this
document.getElementById and
I'm going to pass in the ID of footer.
What we see in the console
is a the return value,
and it's a div tag with
the ID equal to footer.
We can expand this tag to see every
child element that's contained
within it, just like the h1 tag
which I originally selected
when first right-clicking on this page.
Another selection method which is
defined in the DOM is querySelector.
querySelector allows us
to use CSS selector syntax
to grab DOM elements from the page.
Now, if you're not familiar with
CSS querySelector syntax, then,
pause the video and
refer to links in the instructor notes.
You'll want to learn how to select
elements on that page by either,
their class name or by using their ID.
One of the simplest and most used
CSS selectors is the class selector.
So if you add a dot or a period before
a class name then document query
selector will find all the DOM nodes,
which have that class.
So in this example, I'm looking in
my document for any HTML elements,
any HTML tags that have
a class name of main.
Notice that when I run this function,
I get returned a div with the class
with the name main, and if I hover over
the DOM node in the JavaScript console,
Chrome tools is smart enough to
know which element I've selected.
Now if I only want to
look at the DOM nodes.
I can hit escape and then look at
this html viewer, and then try and
find that div with
the class name of main.
And it's right there.
All right.
Let's see if you have
a handle on CSS selectors.