so our strategy to find lines and image
space will be to look for intersecting
lines in half space we do this by
dividing up our half space into a grid
and define intersecting lines as all
lines passing through a given grid cell
to do this I'll first run the canny edge
detection algorithm to find all points
associated with edges in my image i can
then consider every point in this edge
detected image as a line in half space
and where many lines and half space
intersect i declare i have found a
collection of points that described a
line in image space we have a problem
though vertical lines have infinite
slope in mb representation so we need a
new parameterization let's redefine our
line in polar coordinates now the
variable row describes the perpendicular
distance of the line from the origin and
theta is the angle of the line away from
horizontal now each point in image space
corresponds to a sine curve in half
space if we take a whole line of points
it translates into a whole bunch of sine
curves and half space and again the
intersection of those sine curves in
data row space gives the
parameterization of the line