Now that we've used the SDK tools to
capture enough data to know when we have
a memory churn situation, let's zero
in on the code that's causing it.
Well it turns out TraceView
offered us a clue.
Let's take a closer look
at the profile view,
when selecting a method
on the main thread.
Now if you were to scrub the main
thread's methods, you'd find multiple
recurrences of Java character ray
copy operations, like this one.
Now walking up the call stack, we get
more confirmation that the array copies
were used to enlarge a string buffer.
So now let's look at the source code for
the MemoryChurnAcitivity.
As you can see here in
the OnClickListener, we go ahead and
call this function
imPrettySureSortingIsFree, so
let's take a look at that code.
Now, in this method aptly named
imPrettySureSortingIsFree,
the code is constructing a new string,
one cell value at a time,
using string concatenation.
See the instruction notes for
the code I'm referring to.
But, here's specifically,
where the concatenation occurs.
Now, it might look harmless at first,
but,
why would this code
lead to memory churn?