No private addresses aren't private in
the sense of being secret or personal.
They're private, because they're
only any good on the local network.
They can't be used to directly
on the public internet,
because they're not actually unique.
Thousands or maybe millions of people
in the world are using IP addresses in
the 192.168 range, but each one of
these is behind a different NAT router.
Once again, there are three different
blocks of IP addresses which
are reserved for this private use.
By design, these addresses should
never be used on the public internet.
They're used inside homes, offices, data
centers, on mobile networks and so on.
If you're using a private
address on your computer,
there's still a public address being
used on the other side of your router or
your mobile provider or the like.
Web servers and other internet services
don't see your private address.
They see the public address,
whatever it is.
There are number of ways you can
find out your public address and
services that look at what address
they see on your request and
respond with what you say.
Search engines including, Google,
Bing and many others will all tell
you your public IP address if you
search for the term my ip address.
Now, let's try it out.
First, look in your
network configuration and
find your computer's
assigned IPv4 address.
Is that IP address a private one?
Yes or no.
If it is, what's your public address?