While you shouldn't concern yourself
with micro-optimizations like this one,
there are obviously steps you can
take to ease JavaScript's burden on
the rendering pipeline.
And that should be obvious, because
otherwise, there would be no need for
this lesson to exist.
Think back to the different
stages of RAIL.
Each stage has a different
window of time to
execute JavaScript without incurring
a user experience penalty.
That is to say, you have a small amount
of time to execute JavaScript, and
if all of it happens before
the window of time is over,
the app will still feel snappy and
smooth.
Looking at this timeframe for an
animation, you realistically only have
about ten milliseconds to do everything
you need to do to prepare the frame,
which includes running layout,
compositing, and paint.
So, with that in mind, how do you make
sure JavaScript is out of the way
as much as possible to hit
that ten-millisecond deadline?
Should you optimize your JavaScript
to eke every last nanosecond out
of your code?
Should you execute JavaScript every
16 milliseconds on a rigid schedule?
Should you defer JavaScript
to the very end of the frame,
to get the hard work done first?
Or should you execute JavaScript
as early as possible every frame?
Pick one of these four answers.