And here we have the result of some simulations of the exploratory agent.
We see it's doing much better than the passive agent or than the Greedy agent.
So I'm graphing here; and we only had to go through 100 trials.
We didn't have to go through 500--so it's converging much faster.
And it's converging to much better results.
So the policy loss and the dotted lines
started off high; but after only 20 trials,
it's come down to perfect.
So it learned the exact, correct policy after 20 trials.
The error in the utilities--so you can have the perfect policy,
while not quite having the right utilities for each state--
and the errors in utility comes down,
and that, too, comes down to a level that's lower than the previous agent's--
but still, not quite perfect.
And we see here that it, in fact, learns the correct policy.