There are many, many, many different
ways to do 6-DOF positional tracking.
Let's take a look at how two of
the major VR headsets do it.
First up, the Oculus Rift.
The Oculus Rift uses a tracking
system called Constellation.
Behind the exterior fabric,
the Rift has a large number of
infrared LEDs and it looks like this.
Each LED is blinking really,
really fast in a specific pattern.
There's also a separate camera
that is placed on your desk or
somewhere else nearby.
It looks like this.
The camera captures
these light patterns.
And a computer program builds up
a model of the light positions.
The model looks something like this.
That program then tries to
fit a 3D model of the Rift
onto the 2D model it
sees from the camera.
Based on this 3D model,
the measurements from an internal IMU,
it calculates your head position.
Needless to say, it tries to do this
extremely quickly and accurately.
But as you might guess,
it isn't perfect.
In fact, none of these tracking
systems are completely perfect.
But Constellation is really good and
it's pretty cheap.
And that's why Oculus chose it.
Next, let's talk about the HTC Vive.
The Vive uses a tracking
system called Lighthouse.
It also uses infrared light.
But unlike the Rift,
it uses infrared lasers.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
It works by measuring the time it takes
for a laser to sweep horizontally and
vertically across a fast photosensor.
It's actually a similar
principle to how ships navigate
by using time measurements
between lighthouse flashes.
That's why it's called Lighthouse.
If you look closely,
both the Vive headset and controllers
are covered with little circular
indentions for the photosensors.
A Vive base station is constantly
sweeping the room with a laser that hits
the photosensors.
The sweep times are used to
determine their positions in space.
It uses this data and combines it
with readings from an embedded IMU to
determine where your head and
hands are located.
So there you go, that's how some of
the major players do 6-DOF tracking.
If you look deeper,
you'll find that there are tons
of other ways to do it, too.
In the future, you'll probably own VR
devices that can detect the geometry
of the room you're in.
And they'll likely be able to
determine your full body and
finger positions as well.
We've got so much to look forward to for
the future of VR tracking technology.