To explore the Redis connection, navigate to redis.io, and
you see that Redis is in open source, advanced key value, cash and store.
You can navigate to Commands, and in our Storm setup,
we focus on the Redis Publish, and Subscribe functionality rather than Storage.
Clicking into the command Publish, we see that Publish consist of a channel and
a message, implementing this in JavaScript is straight forward.
Remember that we used the lettuce package to connect from Redis in Java.
You can search in Google for Java Redis Lettuce, and
you'll see some of the exact code I had to follow to make this connection.
But let's focus on the redis connection here.
In your text editor, navigate to any ReportBolt.
I'm using lesson three, stage three and we search for redis.publish.
Here I use the Redis Publish syntax of channel that I've
named WordCountTopology.
And our message string.
Now that we have the publish side of our connection using Lettuce and
Redis, let's explore the subscribe side of our connection.
We navigate to the subscribe command and
we see the general syntax of subscribing to a given channel.
I do this in flask by following by a really cool Redis flask snippet.
You can search snippets or tutorials using the search command, and I search for
basic messaging queue and Redis.
Click on the snippet.
Next, my basic approach was to follow the basic messaging queue with
Redis snippet, and also searching for Python documentation.
And using the Python documentation for redis-py.
In the Python documentation, if you search for strict Redis, you find
the syntax that I used to make the connection with the conventional port 6379.
And in your text editor, navigate back to app.py for a fly server.
And you see the StrictRedis function with port 6379 by convention.
I used additional Python documentation on Redis, searching for
pubSub, which stands for publish subscribe.
You see the publish subscribe section to create a pubSub object.
Back in Flask, I create my pubsub object.
And finally use my pubSub object to subscribe again to the WordCountTopology.
We navigate back to the ReportBolt and
just confirm that we have our WordCountTopology.
Now that we've seen the ReportBolt using the publish and
subscribe functionality commands of Redis in flask.
It's time to look at how this combined drives our D3 visualization to
create the word clouds that we've been using throughout this course.
We'll cover this in the next video.