So if you went searching through
these APIs, which I hope you did.
You'll find that each one of them is
made for very special kinds of data.
For Developer A, the Sunlight APIs
actually work really well.
They have all kinds of information
about legislators, districts,
and everything mentioned.
For Developer B, number five,
Riot Games API works the best,
and that makes sense.
Riot Games makes League of Legends,
so they have an API for it.
For Developer C, the OpenMenu API works.
It gives them the ability to display the
locations of restaurants that they want.
For Developer D,
the World Bank API works well.
This gives them
information about GDP and
other economic statistics for
countries around the world.
And then last, Developer E,
number four, the Gilt API.
So Gilt maintains all kinds of
information about top designer labels.
And that's what you'd want to use.
So, these five examples are really
only scratching the surface of
the kind of data that's out there.
You know, this is something as
a developer that you'll do a lot.
If you want to build an app, and
you know what kind of data you need,
the first thing you do
is go search about it,
and see if there's an API available.
If there isn't one,
you can actually build one yourself.
And, I'm not going to cover
that in this class, but
I'll put some links in the instructor
notes if you're interested.
For now let's go ahead and move on and
start building our first app.