Congratulations on making it this far.
You'll now get started
on your next project,
building a game-playing AI to
win at the game, Isolation.
Game playing has long been one of
the cornerstones of AI advancements.
One of the biggest advancements in
recent AI has been in this field
through Google's Go winning AlphaGo AI.
Similarly, one of the seminal events
of the 20th century was seeing
IBM's Deep Blue defeat Gary Kasparov,
a world chess champion,
in a game of chess.
Through this project,
you will take a huge step toward
understanding how these agents work.
Let's get down to the specifics.
In this project, you will design and
implement a game-playing agent to
play a game using adversarial search.
The agent will play Isolation,
the game you've been seeing
throughout these lectures.
In the game,
whenever either player occupies a cell,
that location is blocked off for
the rest of the game.
The first player with no legal
move loses, and her opponent wins.
Your goal will be to program a player
that beats its opponent consistently
at this game.
Additionally, you will design different
heuristics to perform the adversarial
search, and then you will analyze and
compare their performance.
Good luck, we're thrilled to see what
you'll build in this fun project.