And now let me show you the thing that I just blew right past you
that's even cooler about RANSAC.
All right? So how big does N have to be?
Well, we gave you this equation, right?
N is greater than 1 minus, log of 1 minus p over log.
[NOISE] Fine.
Look at that function.
What's p?
P is the probability of success.
What's e?
The percentage of outliers.
What's S?
The number of points in your minimal set.
Notice, what's not in there is the number of points in the image, or
the number of features.
So, you may have 10,000 or 1,000 or 100 or
500 punitive matches, let's say, for a transform.
Remember all those red lines that were going back and forth.
The number of samples you have to draw has nothing to
do with the number of possible matches that you're looking at.
It only has to do with the percentage of wrong ones.
And, then the you know,
the size, the minimal set and how sure you want to be that you got there.
So that's really great because that means that the whole algorithm is pretty
scale invariant with respect, or I should say size invariant with respect to
the number matches, the number of, of hypothesized points that you have.
And that actually is, is part of the reason that it, it, it works so well.
All right, so let's illustrate that here.
Let's suppose that I got two pictures, and let's just for
the sake here assume that there's just a translation.
So I'm just looking for one point match to one point.
And the system has proposed a whole bunch of matches.
So there's one, and there's another one, and
there's another, and there's another.
And all of these you and I know are actually correct, right Meghan?
Right. Okay.
But it also propose this one and propose that one and those are not right.
But of course only you and I know that and 9 million people watching.
Okay, but the computer is not so smart.
It doesn't know that.
So showing you how RANSAC works.
What we do is we select one match.
Here's one.
That blue one right there.
And we just count the number of matches that agree.
So one, two, three, four, five.
Okay, great.
And then we take a look at the ones that don't agree.
Two. So five out of seven.
That's 5 times 70%.
Or whatever.
Five out of seven of them agree.
Great.
Okay, so we gotta do it again.
We pick another one.
We try that one, count the ones that agree, one, two.
Count the ones that don't agree, one, two, three, four, five.
That's two out of seven, last time I checked,
two out of seven is way lower than five out of seven.
So you would basically say, a-ha.
Here is the set of matches that are right.
Now I've got five points matches for doing a translation.
How many points does it take to do a translation?
It only took one.
So, should I just pick one?
No.
I have five translations here, all of which are a little noisy.
So what do I do?
I just take the average.
I could even do sort of a robust average, but
you probably don't even have to at this point, right?
You just have to make sure you have enough points left in order to
take the average.
So basically, what you're doing is you're going to use ransack in order to
select the points that you believe actually come from the Gaussian noise model.
Get rid of the outliers.
And then you do an average,
which is the right thing to do when you have points from a Gaussian noise model.