So you might have gotten any number
of answers to this question.
In fact, if you run it twice
on two different computers or
two different times,
you might get different addresses.
Here, it is trying it twice and happened
to get the same address twice in a row.
But about the address you see
is not the same one as this.
It turns out that there isn't actually a
single host of the single address behind
google.com.
They actually have more
than one computer there.
Surprise, surprise.
Mild understatement.
When your browser goes
to look up google.com,
it can get a bunch of
different addresses.
Which helps Google balance load amongst
all their different data centers.
But how do we get from a host
name to an IP address, anyway?
Let's look at that next.