So, which of these scenarios
are right to be promisified?
I'll go ahead and
start at the top, working with
information from ajax requests.
Most definitely, the would
asynchronous is in the very definition
of ajax, and you'll be working
with these kinds of requests soon.
Next up, executing long running image
manipulation work in the main thread.
No.
Promises run in the main thread, so
you don't gain anything from wrapping
work in the main thread in a promise.
The work will still
happen synchronously and
still probably lead to
a gen key experience.
Next up,
creating a series of HTML elements.
No.
Creating and appending dom
elements is synchronous, so
there's no need to
wrap them in promises.
That being said, if these were,
say image elements, or
script elements with links
to external resources,
then loading the external resources
themselves, are asynchronous operations.
You could use promises to chain
actions after the resources load.
Likewise, if the data came
from an asynchronous resource,
then you could wrap this in a promise,
but that's not what's happening here.
Last up, posting messages back and
forth between the main thread and
a web worker.
Yes.
Web workers run on separate threads and
post data to the main thread.
They are certainly asynchronous and
perfect for promises.
All right,
that's enough discussion about promises.
It's time to start writing them.