The last feature of the app is
shaking the bugs off the web.
Before I show this feature to you,
I want you to download the app,
and then get acquainted with the code.
There's a download link posted
in the instructor notes.
Make sure to reference the final
bug view controller and
final settings view controller classes.
Those are the classes that are used
in the working version of the app.
After you've looked them over, I want
you to answer the following questions.
First, which method shakes
the bugs off the screen?
And second, which UIEventSubtype member
value is being used to shake the bugs?
UIEventSubtype, if you haven't seen
it is an enumeration value declared
by the UIEvent class, and the member
value is just another word for
the value of the enumeration.
I've posted a link to the relevant
documentation in the instructor notes,
and you can use them if you get stuck.
Once you've found the answers, write
them in the appropriate text boxes.