All right, so I am here in the course map where we
will discuss the things that we will learn in this class together.
This lesson, lesson 1 is an introduction.
Here we will explore Xcode.
Now you can think of Xcode as a canvas that will help us make an app.
Lesson one, will be all about making the basic structure of our app.
We will learn how to add buttons, images, and text.
In Lesson three, we will learn how to play sounds from our phone.
And we will also figure out,
how our app will navigate from one screen to the other.
Towards the end, in Lesson four, we will record our voice and
we will run our app on a physical device.
Now, throughout all of these lessons,
we will be asking you questions that will push your understanding on Swift.
Here is the first of those questions