Some Google services are now available
through a config file that you get from
the developers console.
This config file helps
by doing such tasks
as keeping track of your project number,
which will later be the sender ID
used to identify your messages
as distinct from another app's.
When you generate this file,
also take note of the server API key
because you will need
this value later on.
Once you have your config file, you need
to make sure it leaves in the app or
mobile directory of your project so
that the Android framework can find it.
And then you need to tell the Android
framework that it is there by modifying
the build.gradle files.
And the top level build.gradle,
you're going to add a dependency
on Google Services.
Then in your project level built.gradle,
you'll introduce the plug in for
Google Services.
Now to use Google Play
services specifically,
you'll need to first install the library
through the Android SDK manager.
You'll find Google Play services
under extras at the bottom.
But you should also see
Google Repository there.
Go ahead and install both Google
Repository and Google Play services.
The repository is where all of the jars
you will be referencing are so
don't skip this one.
While Google Play services will give you
access to offline docs and code samples.
Then you will need to reference
the new library in your app.
So go back to your project
level build.gradle file and
add the compile rule for
Google Play services.
The cool thing about this library is
that you can reference the specific
bundle that you care about.
In our case,
that is Google Cloud Messaging.
And you can avoid compiling
the entire library into your app.
Also the version number will likely
have changed from what you see here, so
use the Android Studio recommendation or
check the documentation for
the latest version number.
Finally, because it is hard to
anticipate the state of a user's device,
you must always check for
compatible Google Play service
APK before you access
Google Play services features.
There are two approaches to this and
you should choose the one
that best fits your app.
You remember Radel's explanation of
the Android activity life cycle right?
So you could handle this
flow while your app is
active at the moment you
wish to make the API call.
Or you can check for
the SDK when your app first start and
then attempt to resolve error such
as a need to install or update or
enable Google Play services at
the beginning of your apps execution.
If you're checking early, you can do so
in on creates that you can configure
various aspects of your
app based on the result.
But you may prefer to make this check or
an additional check in on resume.
Because you never know how
the user will use their device and
you don't want to end
up in a wonky state.
If your features are dependent on the
expectation that Google Play services is
available you'll need to check here.
For sunshine, we are only going to check
at creation because we are going to
design the messages separately
from the rest of the app.
If the APK is unavailable,
we will never enable the GCM feature.
And the user will not
receive weather alerts.
In this way the user should never even
notice that something is missing from
the app as the normal
app flow is untouched.
And that is what it is
to fail gracefully.
So, at the creation of the app,
we will check for
Google Play services with a call to
is Google Play services available.
Then, we will attempt to
solve any errors that we can,
such as prompting the user to update.