So, one way of dealing with it, that we're going to just talk about today.
We're going to do it differently next time,
is what are called Robust estimators.
And Robust estimators say, instead of minimizing the sum of squares, okay?
Instead, we're going to try to minimize some, some function row.
And row, is going to be a function of two things.
R here is for the residual.
It's the delta.
It is how far off the point is from your models.
So for fitting lines it's how far away the point is from the line.
So that's our error that we were using before.
And before we were just squaring that.
We're going to do some other function and it's also going to have a.
Scale parameter sigma, okay?
Or robust measure parameter sigma.
There are lots and lots and lots of Robust estimators.
We're not going to talk a lot about them.
I'm just going to show you one example because it works very simply.
So here's one.
This is rho as a function of u.
U is just be, going to be that residual, that, that, that r.
And here's my sigma parameter, and the function that I'm going to minimize,
is just going to be u squared over sigma squared plus u squared.
So.
Let's think a little bit about how that function works.
What it looks like.
So this is just this function y equals x squared.
Okay?
So for y equals x squared, you know,
you can see that it grows really quickly as x grows.
And that was the problem that we were trying to fix.
Let's think about what happens for small values of u versus large values of u.
Okay?
So if we pick some sigma squared.
When u is small compared to sigma,
sigma squared plus u squared is about sigma squared.
So that means the entire function is approximately u squared over sigma squared,
so that just grows by, u squared, the way our original function did,
and so it looks kind of parabolic to start with.
But, what happens when u becomes really large.
Well, when u becomes really large,
the Robust estimator here becomes almost u squared over u squared, or one.
And that's what this u is here, out here.
Okay, so the idea is as your error grows, it starts going up.
As a quadratic, just like our regular mean squared error, our, or
just like our regular sum of squared errors.
It goes up quadratically, but then it starts to level out, and
that's what you're seeing here.
It comes up, and it levels out.
Now, how, where it levels out, that's a function of what the sigma is, okay?
So for a very small sigma, it levels out quickly.
For large sigmas, it levels out much more slowly.
So here's an example, remember, we're going to.
Here's the same set of points.
Aha.
We have now foiled the even, the evil Megan point.
Right. So we have this point here.
And you'll notice that this line, goes right through those other points.
It's as if it ignored this point.
Now it didn't totally ignore the point, it gave it a constant weight, but it
didn't matter whether that point was here, or here, or here, or really far away,
because once that u, once that residual got too big, it got a constant weight.
Points that are nearby, they have the,
the, the square, error, weight that we had before.
So this is what it looks like when you get the scale just right.
This is like Goldilocks picking the first bowl, the first time.
Never happens, okay?
At least, not when I tell my kids, because then it would shorten the story and
they wouldn't be asleep yet, so what good is that?
If I set the scale too small, I get this weird line, right?
Well, basically what's happened is every point is giving it a constant error and
it's just kind of going, somewhere near all of the points.
And also, if I set my scale too large,
remember if sigma squared is too big then it's just like regularly squares.
So I get the the wrong solution again.
So, these Robust estimators are, powerful, but
you do have to have an explicit, not only do you have to have an explicit
choice of scale, it's pretty sensitive to your choice of scale.
The method we're going to
talk about next time also has some scale parameters for, for
noise that we have to look at, but it's going to be much less sensitive to that.