Let's select the horizontal constraint.
In the inspector,
you can see all of its properties,
some definitely seem mysterious.
First Item, Second Item,
Relation, Constant,
Priority, Multiplier, and Constant.
What's all this about?
Brace yourselves, for math is coming.
A constraint is a relationship between
two properties plus a priority.
Let's worry about
the relationship first.
We told Auto Layout that the leading
edge of the stack view was equal
to the leading margin of
the super view plus something.
There you have the properties
Leading Space, and
Leading Margin and
the relationship, equal.
So in this case, that equation
actually means that the leading space
of the stack view is equal to
the leading margin of the super view,
multiplied by something, 1,
plus a constant value, 7 in this case.
You can see this equation
on the top right corner
of Xcode when you click on a constant.
Click on the vertical one now.
Now, let's change its
constant to Standard Value.
That's what Apple recommends as
a separation between the items.
Jony Ive knows more about design than
I do, so let's accept this suggestion.
A priority means how important it
is to fulfill this requirement.
The default value is 1,000,
which means it's a must.
We won't mess with this very often.
In the next video, we'll learn how to
preview our UI in different devices.