So now let's look at
forward warping again.
And this time around, I've actually
changed the notation back where x prime,
y prime are the coordinates
in the target.
And x and y are the coordinates and
the source.
And we basically want to create
a transformation that takes
this function f and
generates a new function, g.
With, of course, the inside values
having information that show the warps.
So we have to basically now
take this in pixel value here,
transform it to this one.
So in essence, what we are trying to
do is send each pixel from f(x, y) to
its corresponding location in g of x and
y and the transformation is T(x, y).
So now the question comes up is,
what happens if the pixel
lands between the two pixels?
So now I'm basically
gotten rid of the images,
and kind of just pointed out what I
mean by the fact, that the pixel line.
So this is one pixel here, and
of course, now because of the fact,
we have changed
the domain of this image.
We now have pixel values here,
but this one is now falling
in between all of them.
To achieve this, we basically
have to distribute the color
among the neighboring pixel to
generate this new pixel, and
the technique widely used to
do this called splatting.