So here you can see I pasted my code in.
First of all, on my class,
I've created a few member variables.
I have a Google API Client, called
nGoogleApiClient, I have a text view
called nStatusText, and I have two
buttons called requestUpdatesButton and
removeUpdatesButton.
Then in uncreated self, I set up these
variables, so request updates button,
I use find view by ID to get
the request activity updates button.
And if you go back to the layout file
you'll see that's what we called it.
Ditto for remove updates button,
I use find view by id to get
the remove activity updates button.
And then finally for text,
I cast to a TextView,
and I use findViewByID
the detectedActivities.
So these are my three controls,
the requesting updates,
the removing updates, and
the status text that you may recall
from the demo we showed earlier on.
And then finally in OnCreate, I just
called this helper function called
buildGoogleApiClient and build a Google
API client is the standard thing
that you've seen all along, where I
create a new GoogleApiClient.Builder and
I pass it the various parameters.
Adding the on connection
callbacks to this,
adding OnConnectionFailedListener
to this, adding the API to be
the ActivityRecognition.API
because that's what we're doing.
And then building it, and
setting that to be my nGoogleApiClient.
So now that' we've done this, the next
thing that we want to do is that we want
to remember on our intent service we
were broadcasting the activities back
and we want this class to receive them.
So we have to implement
the receiver details on it.