We've already seen some examples of
how to create the class, extend it,
and then create some of the methods.
I'm here in my project, and inside my
data package I've created a java class
called PetDbHelper and this class
extends the SQLiteOpenHelper class.
Now let's go ahead and make some
constants for the database name and
versions that we want.
First off here, I created a database
constant named DATABASE_NAME and
the value is shelter.db,
and then the constant for
the DATABASE_VERSION as a value of 1.
For continuity we're going to
be using the same database name
that we used when we were working
directly with SQLite in the terminal.
And it's also standard for
database versions to start with 1.
Next up, let's make the constructor.
And here's the code for the constructor.
Because we're subclassing from another
class, we call it the pair constructor
via super, so we can take in
the first parameter context
from all that's passed in, and the other
parameters are the database name,
a cursor factory which we can just
set to null to use the default, and
then the database version which
we created constant for up here.
All right, so nice work, and
the constructor is all set up, but
it looks like there is still an error
with this class up here, and
let's take a look at why.
The error message reminds us that
we actually need to implement
the onCreate method.
Remember from the documentation,
that because we are sublcassing
SQL open helper, we need to implement
the onCreate and onUpgrade methods.
To help us out,
we can click this red light bulb here
and then click implement methods.
It's already sorted for us that onCreate
and onUpgrade methods we need, and
then click OK.
The onCreate method is called when the
database is created for the first time.
And this is where the creation and
initial population of
a tables will happen.
Recall the SQL statement we used
to create our pets table earlier.
Remember the one that looked like this?
Well we can use the same
pattern here but
our SQL statement needs to be a string.
In order to make the string, we can use
the constants defined in our contract.
Let's add an import statement to our pet
contract from our pet contract here.
And we're going to import all the way
into the pet entry class because our
constants live inside that inner class.
Back onCreate, let's start
creating that string statement.
Using that same syntax,
we can start off with create table and
concatenate on the table name.
And next we need to add
in the parentheses.
Now we can begin adding the column
names, like we did here.
First we'll need the ID, and
we want that to be of type integer.
We also want it to be our primary key,
and we want that auto increment.
These SQL keywords should be familiar
from our discussion in lesson one.
So far, we have this section of our
SQL command matching the string here.
All's we need to do now, is finish up
the rest of the command, and to do so
I'll just need to concatenate the rest
of the columns and their data types.
With that, our SQL command has
been translated into a string.
But we'll need to set it
to a string constant, so
that you can easily reference it.
I've set MySQL command to
be SQL CREATE PETS TABLE.
Now onto the task of
actually creating the table.
And to do so,
we can use a method from the SQLite
Database Class called execute SQL.
And this is what that looks like.
This method here, takes in an SQL
statement as it's parameter and
executes that statement.
We can pass in our
SQL CREATE PETS TABLE command.
Because this isn't a static method,
we'll need to execute SQL method
on the correct SQLite Database
class instance.
Notice onCreate method,
takes in an SQLite Database object.
By default this object is named
SQLite Database with SQL in lower case.
But we can always rename
this variable here and for
simplicity let's rename it for
DB, short for database.
That means I can update
my SQL method here and
call it db.execSQL.
With that, our onCreate method is done.
Now on to onUpgrade method.
Currently, since our database
only has one version,
this method can remain as is, so empty.
However in an upcoming lesson, we'll
need to migrate the database schema, so
then we'll come back and
revisit this method later, when we'll
have another version of our database.
The final step of the exercise, was we
needed to add that mysterious function
to the catalog activities
onCreate method.
And I did that over here,
this displayDatabaseInfo method.
If I did everything correctly,
when I open up the app,
it should show that there are zero
rows currently in the database table.
Let's run it and see.
And perfect.
As expected the catalog activity, now
has this logging statement that tells us
how many rows are in our
pets database table.