Okay, so the answer to this is that
we'll update the score to be 3 more than
it was before and then we'll display it.
Another way to say update the score
to be 3 more than it was before
is to say increase the score by 3.
So Step 1 would be D and
then to display the score is Step 2.
So, I'll select A.
Okay, so
these are the correct two choices.
We need to be clear that we're
increasing the score, which means that
we're taking the old value of
the score and we're adding 3 to it.
Okay, so let's look at this with
a little bit more detail as to why this
will correctly work.
Okay, so my score starts at 0.
And then I click the +3 button.
According to my Step 1,
I first increased the score by 3.
It's currently 0,
I add 3 to it, it becomes 3.
Okay, so far, so good.
And then, in the next step,
I display it to the phone screen.
Let's draw a little phone.
Okay, so there's my phone, and
it will display the score, which is 3.
Looks pretty good.
I press it again, it goes and
looks at the current score, and
then increases it by 3.
Making it become 6.
And then, it displays it to the phone.
And I can see pretty quickly
that as I keep pressing it,
the pattern will repeat itself,
it'll update, it'll display.
So that seems pretty good.
Now, one of the things you might
have gotten wrong is maybe switching
the order of these two.
So let's see how that would work.
Okay, so here's the step switch.
If I click the +3 button,
the first thing that I do in this
ordering is to display the score.
So it looks at scoreTeamA, and it's 0,
so it removes whatever was there
before and displays 0 to the screen.
Then I increase the score by 3.
Hm, okay, well, so it's displaying 0,
but the score's actually 3.
When I hit this again, remember, at this
point, the team has scored six points.
It goes and looks at my score
which is 3, and displays it,
and then it increases the score by 3.
Hm.
Okay, so in this case it seems that
my score is always three points
ahead of what's actually being displayed
on the screen, and that's no good.
Okay, so let's look at this scenario.
I press the +3 point button.
And Step 1 is to set scoreTeamA to 3.
And then,
Step 2 is to display that score.
Okay, that looks pretty good.
I press +3 Points, and
it's displaying 3.
Now, I press it again, though.
And Step 1 is to set scoreTeamA to 3.
Kind of silly, but
that's what you told it to do.
And then display scoreTeamA.
So as you might be able to see, I could
keep clicking +3, but it's going to
just remain at 3, because it'll keep
setting it to 3 and then displaying 3.
This is actually essentially what we're
already doing right now with the app.
But instead of simply saying display 3,
we're using a variable
that's value is always 3.
Okay, let's look at another example.
Now, you might have found
this option very alluring.
After all, it's saying display and
it's saying to add 3,
and that just seems like it's right.
Now, I'm not even going to put
anything in for Step 2 right now.
I'm just going to see what happens if
this is the only step that occurs.
So, I press +3 Points.
And then it displays the scoreTeamA +3.
So I look at the score for Team A,
which is 0, and then I add 3 to it.
So it's going to display 3.
Okay, that's looking pretty good.
Press it again, and
it's going to display the score for
Team A, which is still 0,
and then add 3, which is 3.
Hm, so this has the same
problem as the last one,
it's just going to keep displaying 3.
And this is because when I
say display scoreTeamA +3,
it's not actually changing the value
that's inside of scoreTeamA.
It's just using that value
to do some calculation.
Now, there is a way I could
actually get this to work.
Okay.
Let's look at this one.
So I press the +3 points button,
and it goes to Step 1,
which is to display the scoreTeamA +3.
ScoreTeamA was 0, so 0 plus 3 is 3.
And then,
it increases the score of Team A by 3.
Okay.
I press the button again, it looks
at the score of Team A, which is 3,
and it adds 3, so it displays 6.
Then, it increases
the score of Team A by 3.
So, this is looking pretty good, and
it actually is technically
a correct answer.
It will do what you want it to do,
but it's a little inefficient and
strange for a couple of reasons.
First, you do the same
calculation twice.
Here you're adding scoreTeamA +3 and
when you do the increase you have
add scoreTeamA +3 which uncovers how
it's generally just a little backwards
the way that were doing things.
This ordering seems a little bit more
difficult to understand, it's also
just a little bit more complicated
because you added that extra step.
So, increasing the score by 3 and
then displaying
is a more straightforward answer, and
the one that I'm going to go with.