So what did you get?
>> I wrote pile, tree,
node, and counter.
>> Okay, so clearly there's
an important concept of pile.
And tree is important,
counter is important.
What did you do about leaf?
Leaf to me seems like it's
just a special kind of tree.
It's just a distinction for a tree
that has no other children as a leaf.
>> Okay, a little while later in OOA,
we will look at the situation where
>> one
of the potential classes is a kind
of another one of the classes.
But for now let's include leaf
as a separate, separate class.
How about part?
>> So part is connected to,
I feel like I have a need to go back and
see what concept that's connected to.
Is that part of the pile,
part of the tree?
So the parts of a tree
already I believe are nodes.
So to me, I guess I'm substituting
the word node for part.
>> Well a part of a tree could
be a subtree as well, right?
>> It's a collection of nodes.
>> So
the suggestion is at this early stage in
the process,
>> To err on the side of including extra
classes which we can then remove later.
>> Okay
>> So I would suggest having part
as a candidate class as this stage.
And then the other question I have
is you threw the word node in there,
which isn't in the original text.
Now there's nothing wrong with
>> using your judgement on adding
classes in there, but I was wondering
what you were thinking as you did that?
>> Node I've seen use plenty of times
for tree to constitute a part of a tree,
a graph, a connected graph, and it seems
in my mind that using node here might be
a way to make it generic enough
that it could grow later.
>> It's a concept that's general
enough to trees and grass.
I think that's my premise.
>> So we'll leave it in for
now and we'll see what happens.
In general, as analysts you're going
to have to use that kind of judgement.
To add in concepts that
the original description may
have either assumed or
didn't think through at all.
And one of the values of doing
an approach like this is that it will
point out problems, and inconsistencies
and incompleteness in the documents.
So I would say go with your
intuition at this stage.
One other noun that you didn't say
something about is zero, okay?
So what was your thinking about not
including zero as a potential classer?
>> Zero to me sounds like
a description of a tree or
an attribute to a tree,
>> it doesn't seem to represent its own,
in a sense, an object.
It's just a state of an object,
for instance.
>> Okay.
Can you pick one of the classes here
which zero might gravitate toward?
Counter.
>> Sure.
So
the counter's going to count something,
and
one of the possible things it's going to
count, is it going to have values, and
one of the values it might have is zero.
So I think you're right at
this stage of saying let's not
worry about zero as being a class.
Okay.
But we can't forget about it either.
Okay?
It's going to be part of our
model eventually.