The first option implies that the hot cache means that
the cache is physically getting hot, then it will malfunction.
However, the term hot cache has nothing to do with the actual temperature of
the cache.
It merely refers that many of the cache accesses will actually resolve in
a cache hit.
The data will be found and cached.
So in this context, the more cache hits means that the cache is hot.
Now coincidentally, this also will lead to a rise in temperature.
However, the effects of that aren't going to be that the operating system will
context switch to another process.
Modern systems and platforms do have a lot of mechanisms to
deal with temperature rises, but that's beyond the scope of this lecture.
Let's look at the second option.
The second option is actually the most correct one.
If data is present in the cache,
it will be accessed much faster than if data is accessed from memory.
So, executing with a hot cache actually corresponds to
the state when the process performance is at its best.
And unfortunately, three is correct as well.
Although hot cache means best performance,
sometimes we must context switch although the process cache is hot.
And that's because there is another process that maybe has higher
priority that needs to execute.
Or maybe we have a policy where we have to timeshare the CPU between two
processes and P1's time has expired, so
we have to context switch and give the CPU to P2.