Let's examine some of the building
blocks of a time series.
Ever since mankind first noticed
the regular movement of the sun and
the stars, we have wondered
about the passage of time.
Our ancestors first recorded the phases
of the moon some 30,000 years ago, and
recording time has been a way by which
humanity has represented the progress of
civilization.
It's how we plan, schedule, or arrange
when something should happen or be done.
It's the events in our past,
present, and future.
For us, in this course, we'll discuss
time a little less philosophically, and
concentrate on the data that is
collected on recorded time periods.
The first defining characteristic
of a time series is a list
of observations where
the ordering matters.
Ordering is very important because
there is a dependency on time and
changing the order could change
the meaning of the data.
Now, to accurately
forecast future values,
we'll need each measurement of data
to be taken across sequential and
equal intervals, and with each time
unit having at most one data point.
Once we have collected our data,
as a business analyst,
we have two objectives in mind.
First, identifying the patterns
represented by the sequence of
observations, and second, forecasting or
predicting future values
of the time series.
The patterns we observe will tell us the
story of how our business interacts with
time.