So I've recorded my timeline
trace with the paint profiler on.
I've clicked on one of these boxes, and
I can immediately see that there
is one section besides document.
I'll click on tote's promoted.
Thank you again for
that great name Paul.
And I can see that this
layer was composited,
because it overlaps with
other composited content.
In this case the other content is
the color block section behind it.
Looking in the layers panel, you can
see that underneath the root document
there are two layers on the page.
Looking at the source for the page you
can see that the color block element
has a translateZ
transform applied to it.
This means it's promoted
to its own layer.
In order to maintain the draw order,
the section in the text with it,
this box right here.
Must also now have its own layer and
be placed on top of the color block.
If you promote an element to a layer,
you need to be careful because you could
accidentally create a lot of other
layers with it due to overlap.
So anyways, there you have it.
The paint profiler gives you an awesome
way to keep track of the layers that
you're creating.
The main thing is to try to balance
the compositing time in layer management
with time that you spend in
other parts of the pipeline.
Applying will-change: transform or
translate z0 to all of your
elements might seem appealing, but
it's going to send your memory usage and
compositing time through the roof.
In the end, you might cause
more problems than you solve.
Which is especially a problem on mobile.