Okay, let's see what
my daily special is.
Iceberg lettuce with lollipops.
I'm going to go ahead and change it to
gingerbread noodles with coconut sauce.
Save.
Don't forget to publish.
Easy enough to forget that,
but if you don't publish,
the changes won't go through.
All done.
Now let's see what happens if
I show my daily special again.
It's still the same thing, and
that's because I need to restart my app,
because the code to get
the container is in onCreate.
So, I will close this app.
Start it up.
Show Daily Special, and there it is.
It's got the new value
of the daily special.
Now let's have a look at the code.
So, here we are in the show
daily special activity class.
We've imported the container holder.
And then, in onCreate, I just make
a call to updateDailySpecial().
And then, in updateDailySpecial,
I get the container holder
from the application.
I get the daily-special out of it by
calling getString on the container.
I find the relevant text view.
I set the value of the text view,
and that's all there is to it.