Now that you've built a URIMatcher,
let's go through the detailed,
end-to-end flow for
how data moves from the task database
to the to do list user interface.
Let's say that your app is querying for
data to display in the UI.
First, from the UI code the app will get
a content Resolver and call query on it,
passing in the URI for the exact
provider and data you want to read.
Then the Resolver finds
the correct task content provider
based on the authority of the passed
in URI and passes on the query.
The Provider's query function will
then use the URIMatcher you've built
to decide how to react
to the passed in URI and
determine what kind of data to retrieve.
Whether that's one row of data or
the directory of all tasks or
some other specific selection.
Based on the match, the query function
will basically translate the URI and
other parameters into the correct
SQL code for selected data.
So, using the Matcher and the code for
your query, the provider will then
retrieve the desired data
from the underlying database.
Then the call travels all the way back
to the Resolver in your UI code and
returns a cursor with that data, and
this is how all calls from your
UI to the database will function,
passing through the provider
to reach the database.