Suppose you're given
this 2-D Mesh network.
It has a diameter that's approximately
2 times the square root of P.
Here's my question.
Where do you need to add links
to reduce the diameter by half?
Let's label every node by its
coordinates, starting at (0,
0) in the upper left hand corner and
going to (root P- 1,
root P- 1) in the lower right.
Here are your choices.
Is the answer to connect
the opposite corners?
Or is the answer to add a ring of
links that connect the corners?
Or is the answer to add wraparound
links from left to right and
from top to bottom?
Check all the ones you
think are correct.
If you think none of them will
cut the diameter in half,
then submit without checking anything.