However, I noticed we could have
stopped our search earlier.
>> How?
>> At this step,
we said the northern territory and
South Australia, both had to be blue.
>> So?
>> But these two regions are adjacent,
we know they can't both be blue.
>> I see, forward checking propagates
information from assigned to unassigned
variables, but doesn't provide
early detection for all failures.
Instead we can use constraint
propagation repeatedly to enforce all
the local constraints.
We can use arc consistency for a simple
version of constraint propagation.
A variable in a constraint satisfaction
problem is arc consistent with respect
to another variable if there is
some value still available for
the second variable after we assign
a value to the first variable.
If all variables in the graph
satisfy this condition,
then the network is arc consistent.
>> Let's look at a practical example.
Once we get to the stage of
assigning green to Queensland,
we look at all of its
neighbors that are unassigned.
And see if the assignment of green
reduces the number of colors
available to them.
If so, we remove that color
from the neighboring region.
And then look at its neighboring
regions to see if we need to propagate
the change onward.
We keep doing this process
until it terminates or
we determine that one of the regions
does not have any colors left.
>> So, here we have removed green
from South Australia's list, and
are now looking at its neighbors.
New South Wales is a neighbor, and
in order to be arc consistent we
will have to remove blue
from its available colors.
It can only be orange.
>> Victoria is a neighbor
of New South Wales, so
we look to see if the change affects it.
In fact, it does.
We remove orange from Victoria's
list of available colors.
Our choice of green for
Queensland has caused a chain of changes
in possible values for our variables.
>> Why don't we remove
blue while we're at it, so
Victoria doesn't conflict
with South Australia.
>> Well, we haven't gotten that far
in our queue of things to check yet.
Next we're going to look at the Northern
territory because they're just another
neighbor that might be affected
by South Australia's change.
In fact we see South Australia and
the Northern territory are both
restricted to blue which is not allowed,
so we return a failure and
force a search to try another option for
Queensland.
>> Wow, that was a lot of work.
>> But it can save a lot of
unnecessary deep searching for
more complicated problems.