>> Well, you're right about that. Software systems have long lifetimes.
During which they undergo evolutionary change.
Unless, the responsible developers are careful. The original structure of
the program may be lost as features are added, bugs fixed and
libraries migrated. For example, consider a banking application. Over time,
the particular functions such as interest computation, fees and tax rules may
change. All of these are functions. However, the need to represent accounts,
account holders and transactions. All of which are objects, will continue.
That is objects are more stable than functions, over the lifetime of a system.
Hence, designing a software around them, leads to more sustainable designs.