Let's do a quiz now.
Let's take a look at what happens when threads contend for a mutex.
For this quiz, we will use the following diagram.
We have five threads, T1 through T5, who want access to a shared resource,
and the mutex m is used to ensure mutual exclusion to that resource.
T1 is the first one to get access to the mutex and the dotted line corresponds
to the time when T1 finishes the execution of the critical section and frees m.
The time when the remaining threads issue their mutex requests correspond to
the lock(m) positions along this time axis.
For the remaining threads, which thread will be the one to get access to
the mutex after T1 releases control?
Your choices are T2, T3, T4, and T5, and you should mark all that apply.