So the first type of bot activity,
Spamming.
What is a spamming bot?
Is it A,
used by botmaster to fraudulently
increase revenue from advertisers?
Or used to gather valuable
financial information?
Or infect machines to send
out unsolicited emails.
It is obviously C.
The second type of bot activities,
Click Fraud.
What is a Click Fraud bot?
Is it A,
used by botmasters to fraudulently
increase revenue from advertisers?
Yes, a Click Fraud bot can click
on ads specified by the botmaster,
as if the clicks were from
the real human users.
Therefore, this can fraudulently
increase revenue from the advertisers.
So this is A.
The third one, Phishing,
what is a Phishing bot?
A phishing bot is typically used to
gather valuable financial information
from the user.
For example,
a bot net running a phishing campaign
can trick a user to enter
personal information or
financial data into a web server that's
controlled by the bot master because
the users were tricked to believe
that the server was a bank server.