The answer is it corresponds to the center red,
which is the guy over here.
Finding this is not easy.
This is the fifth pixel on the left camera image,
and it's the fourth pixel on the right camera image.
To make that correspondence, we have to understand that the best match matches
these 2 black pixels over here, followed by an occlusion pixel
that's only visible on the left but not on the right,
followed by the 3 corresponding red pixels,
followed by another occlusion pixel,
followed by 2 black pixels that basically correspond.
I now want to look into algorithms that can take entire scan lines of the left side
and correspond them to entire scan lines on the right side.