To add new guest to the database,
the first thing we need to
do is read them from the UI.
In the main activity, declare two
EditText fields to point to the UI,
one for the guest name and
another for the party size.
Then inside onCreate,
we use findViewById to get
the reference to those EditText fields.
The GuestNameEditText is defined in
the UI XML as person_name_edit_text.
And the PartySize is defined
as party_count _edit_text.
Now that we have a reference
to both of them,
let's scroll down to AddToWaitlist
that's linked from the AddGuest button.
First, we'll check that
both have text in them
otherwise we don't need to do anything.
Then we'll declare an integer for
the ParitySize and initialize it with 1.
We need to pass the text
in mNewPartySizeEditText
into an integer ,so we'll
use integer.parseInt and
pass in the result of
getTextToString to our variable.
To prevent an unexpected parse error,
we can wrap this in a try catch block.
So let's now insert those
values into our database.
To make our code more modular, we'll
create a method that will handle adding
any new guests into the database and
call it here.
Let's call that method AddNewGuest, and
it will take the guestName and
partySize as parameters.
To insert data into the database,
we need to use a ContentValues object
that maps column names as
the key to the desired values.
Let's call it CV.
Then we can add our values
using the put method.
The first parameter is the column name,
and we can get that from the contract.
The second parameter is the value.
Now that we have our
content value object ready,
we can call insert passing in the table
name and the ContentValues object.
This will insert a new row in the table
with the value specified in CV.
Notice that we didn't insert any IDs.
That's because in our SQL
create statement, shown here,
we declared the ID column
to be auto increment.
Which means every time
you insert a new row,
it'll automatically add one to the
previous ID, and use that as the new ID.
DB insert returns that new
ID that was generated, so
we'll return that as well as
the output of our addNewGuest method.
We need that reference to be able to
delete it from the database later.
Finally, head back to AddToWaitlist and
call addNewGuest and pass through
the guestName and partySize.
We're almost there.
If we run this right now, it will
successfully insert new guest into
the database, but we won't see
them appear in the RecyclerView.
That's because our adaptor is
still using the old cursor
with the old query resolve that
doesn't include the new guest.