Let's study the first case.
We saw left feature number 1.
The left one is over here, therefore this one will be feature number 1.
Feature number 1 will be seen at the center of camera B.
In the center of the left camera, we see feature number 2,
which must be this guy over here, because it's the center feature to be seen.
This will be projected to the right side of camera B.
Even though it's left in the image plane, the way a I drew it you can see that
the projection over here is on the right side of the camera chip.
The same with feature number 3, which is seen in R over here on the right side.
Hence, it'll project into the leftmost field over here.
Using a different color now, if camera B sees feature number 1 on its L position,
Then this must be feature number one, which will appear on the right position for camera A.
And feature number 2 is in the center position--this guy over here--
which shows up in the left position over here,
and the remaining fits in over here. This is the correct answer.