Looking at that scuba university thing again, here you can see that
with the dynamic programming we get a lot better solution than we had before.
Things are doing better here and little bit, quite a bit better there.
But one of the things you'll notice is that you get these streaks.
And that makes sense because every scan line is done independently of the other
scan line.
So it doesn't know anything about the previous solution, so it makes sense that
as you change scan lines, you might actually get a reasonable shift.
And unfortunately, you can't use dynamic programming to
find a spatially coherent set of disparities over two dimensional grid.
You have to do another approach.
So in motivating that other approach, let's think about it this way.
What defines a good set of correspondences?
Well, first of all, going back to our earlier work.
We want each pixel to find a good appearance match from left image to right.
Or, or right to left.
So we talk about match quality.
But the other thing is, remember when we were first doing filtering for
noise, we said one of the assumptions we make is that two pixels that
are nearby have similar, sort of, real values?
Well when you talk about depth you can also talk about how two pixels that
are nearby have a tendency to have approximately the same depth.
So that means that they probably should have about the same disparity.
So if, if this pixel is, has to be shifted over four,
the one nearby shouldn't shift a whole lot.
Okay, and I might want to penalize solutions that have lots of jumps.
So the method that we're going to use now looks at both of those things.
And it thinks of solving stereo as an energy minimization problem.
The first term the energy mini, oh, let me.
I should define that here we have i1 is the left image, i2 is the right image.
We've got a window in the left, we're going to look at it across the right, but
then all the way on the right is a disparity image, okay?
So that's the disparity that we compute.
And our energy is minimization approach requires two energy terms.
The first term is a data term.
And the date term just says that summed over all the pixels,
that the, the window subtracted from the window on the other image, so
this window minus that one squared, should be as low as possible.
So, we want to, if we're going to do an energy minimization our data term
basically takes a look at a look at the squared of the differences.
That's similar to what we were doing before.
So one way to think about it is, when we were doing corresponds through den
search, we were only looking at the data term.
The second term is called the smoothness term.
And, you'll notice that I don't have any window here,
I don't have any window here, I'm only looking at the window over here.
In fact, in the smoothness term, the image doesn't come in here at all,
neither the left or the right.
I'm only looking at the windows of the neighbors in the disparity image.
This is the disparity image here, all right.
Now, this row function, this is a function that's essentially a robust norm.
So what you want is you, it's okay to make small amounts of change and
then as you get expensive, to make large changes, but
it shouldn't get even more expensive to make even bigger changes.
because that's going to be sort of an adjunct edit occlusion.
So that row function's meant just to be a robust.
I mean, you can think of it as a square that, that, that maxes out.
But that's our smoothness term.
And for energy minimization, what we do is we have a total energy which is
a blend of the data term, and the smoothness term weighed by these coefficients.
And what you want to find, and this is the hard part, is you want to
find an assignment of disparities that minimizes this energy function.