Just like conditional statements,
you can nest loops inside of each other.
This doesn't add anything
new to your loops per se,
just an extra layer of complexity.
Here I have an example of a nested loop.
If you look at the first for
loop, there's another
loop nested inside of it.
Similar to what I did in the for loops
video, I want to take some time to walk
through each step of this code so
you can see exactly what is happening.
Because nested loops add
another layer of complexity,
seeing this code step through this way
should help you in visualizing what is
actually happening when this code
is being interpreted and ran.
Again, I'm going to add the table here
so that you can see the values of x and
y while we go through the loop.
Okay, so here we go.
When our first loop starts,
the value of x is set to zero.
Next, we check the condition
to see if x is less than 3.
And because that evaluates to true,
we jump in to the loop.
But now, we've got another loop.
So, just like we did with the first for
loop, again we're going to
set the variable of y = 0.
We're going to check our condition,
is zero less than 2?
Yes, it is.
So that's true.
And then we jump into this loop.
And we're going to print
out the value of x and y.
So that's a zero, zero.
So, once we get to the end of that step,
then we jump back up to the top of that
nested for loop, and we see how it's
been defined to move to the next step.
So in this one,
y's just getting incremented by one.
So we'll set y now equal to 1.
We'll check our condition.
1 is less than 2,
that's true, and we'll print.
And we'll keep doing this until that
condition is no longer satisfied.
So here, we'll increment y again by 1.
And now, 2 is less than 2.
That doesn't evaluate to true.
That's false.
So now, that means we're
going to jump out of our loop.
But we're still in that first
loop that we started with.
So what happens is, we go and
we look at how it's been defined to
increment to the next step for
that first loop.
In this one,
x is supposed to be incremented by 1.
So we increment x by 1.
We check our condition, is 1<3?
Yes it is, that's true.
And now we jump into the loop.
So again, there's nothing
new that is happening here.
It's just sort of an added level
of complexity that you have to pay
attention to.
And there's not going to
be any surprises here.
We're going to go through
the second loop twice,
it'll always evaluate to
true those first two times.
And then the third time 2 is
not going to be less than 2.
That will evaluate to false.
We'll jump out of that second for loop,
and then we'll look at our first for
loop.
So this will run a couple of more times,
and I'm just going to kind of step
through it here so
you guys can see what's going on.
And if this is a little too fast
feel free to kind of slow it down or
go back and watch.
But we're in the nested for loop,
and we're just incrementing y here.
Y is now 1.
That is less than 2.
It evaluates to true.
And we jump in, we print our statement.
We're going to increment
y one more time.
It's going to be 2 now.
And 2 is not less than 2.
That's going to be false.
We're going to jump out of our loop.
We're going to go to our first loop.
And this time,
X is going to get incremented to 3.
And 3 is not less than 3.
That evaluates to false, and
we jump out of the entire thing.
So again, nested loops don't add
anything new to our loops, but
just another level of complexity.