Now, we've seen probabilistic word models before.
If you remember when we were doing machine learning,
we talked about the bad-of-words model.
What I'm showing you now is a copy of a bumper sticker that my friend
Othar Hansson, who is one of the main engineers on the Google search team came up with,
the bumper sticker, of course, says "Honk if you love the bag-of-words model,"
but it says that in a way where the words are a bag rather than a sequence.
This just kind of indicates the power of the model--
that it gets the idea across while loosing all notion of sequence,
and thus making the probabilistic model simpler to deal with.
But we can move on from a bag-of-words model, which we can think of as a unigram--
sometimes also called a naive Bayes model,
because every individual word is treated as a separate factor that's unrelated
or unconditionally independent of all the other words.
We can move beyond those types of models to ones where we do take sequence into account.