We already have an app that can send and
receive messages, but
right now all the messages
are sent anonymously.
So anyone who has a copy free app,
can read every message and
write whatever they want.
So anyone could now delete
the entire database.
We wouldn't even have any
way to know who did it.
To learn how to secure your apps,
we will talk about firebase
database security rules.
We'll explore a few examples of how
to configure the database rules.
And then we'll finish out the data by
exploring authentication with firebase.
You might remember that we
changed the database rules
to allow anyone to read and write.
It was very useful when we wanted to
test out how the app was working.
But it's not a good idea to
deploy an app to your users
where anyone can read and write data.
So let's look at some ways that you can
protect your database with security
rules.