The right way is what's known as inverse warping.
Given some pixel in x prime, y prime, in the new place, transform back.
Figure out where it came from.
So now x y is the inverse, T inverse of x prime,
y prime in the first image, right?
So I have to figure out where it came from.
So I have a pixel on the right, I figure out where it came from in the left.
Now you have a different question to ask.
You no longer ask question,
what happens if I get sent to a location between pixels.
I now have to ask the question, okay,
what happened if a pixel comes from between two pixels?
Well, what you have to do is what's referred to as interpolation.
Interpolation basically says, if I have some set of pixels, and
I'll think of them as being at integer locations.
So I have some pixels here at the corner and I wrote that as, i j, i plus 1 j,
i j plus 1, and i plus 1 j plus 1, so those are the corners.
If I want to find the value of something that is say an a distance
in x, between the two pixels, and b distance or
b percentage in y between the two pixels, what's the value?
The general process of determining what the value of the function should be,
between points that you know, is referred to as interpolation.
Here we're back to thinking of our image as its functions a little bit, so
we have a value of the function at each of those integer locations, and
we need to guess the value of the function at this location that's
somewhere between the points we know.
That general process is referred to as interpolation.
The simplest interpolation is called nearest neighbor.
Nearest neighbor means, well, just like it sounds.
I land some place in my grid, and I say oh, you you're the closest value.
I'm just going to pretend that I'm that value.
So this quadrant would all have one value.
This quadrant would have another value, et cetera.
It's not a very clever, not a very smooth way of doing things.
A much better way, and perhaps the simplest computational way,
is called bilinear interpolation.
Bilinear interpolation basically says that I
figure out the value in the x direction along with both the top and the bottom.
And I do that by linearly interpolating between those two values, and then I
would interpolate between those values again using a different proportion,
in this case b.
But, because these are all linear operations, you can just write it
as one single linear operation, and you get this formula here.
And it's very clean and very easy.
There are more clever ways, by cubic, where you take,
instead of just fitting linear things, you fit cubic splines between them.
But, basically, the idea is that you're, you're interpolating.
And what's nice, now, is that you don't have any holes in your picture, right?
You went for every pixel in the target image, figure out where it came from in
your source image, interpolate that value, and stick it in the target image.
So there are no holes in your warped target.
By the way, it won't surprise you that Matlab and OpenCV and Octave and
all of these, support this interpolation generically.
in, in Matlab, you can take a look at this function called interp2,
that's two-dimensional interpolation.
And it will allow you to do this.