So agile development practices are
generally a good idea, provided that you
involve all the stakeholders and
not just the development team.
Running the production servers
using the devs' desktop OS,
probably not such a great idea.
Desktop OS and production
are completely different environments.
Involving the ops team
earlier in development
sounds like a pretty good idea.
We can make sure that everybody
knows what the expected technologies
are going to be.
Not have any nasty surprises
when we go to deploy.
Implementing performance tests,
that sounds like a great idea.
If the devs are regularly running
performance tests as part of their
development process,
then we won't have any bad surprises
about performance later on.
Buying faster server hardware
to make the app faster,
well that might work or it might not.
It may just be that the performance
problems are algorithmic, and
adding more server hardware
might not help for very long.
Making small incremental
launches instead of big ones,
this seems like a pretty
good idea to me.
Although, in some business environments
that might not be a possibility.
Still, it's something
very good to consider.
And requiring devs to only use
technology as vetted at the start of
the project.
This sounds like a recipe for
being very inflexible, and
probably would get in the way of
the developers making a good product.
So let's not do that last one.