Here are the answers.
The answer is 1.083, 2.672.
For the second question,
the answer is -8.350,
3.376, -1.434.
For the last question,
the answers are 1.969, -2.811,
0.848, 2.680 plus 1.040,
-3.361, 2.844 and -5.190.
You could've put these in either order.
So I didn't specify which
one was parallel and
which one was perpendicular.
The first vector is
the parallel component, and
the second vector is
the perpendicular component.
To add this functionality
to my python code,
I implemented the functions
component_parallel_to and
component_orthogonal_to in
my vector class.
Let's look at
component_parallel_to first.
I used the formula derived previously.
That the projection of
a vector onto a basis vector
is found by first normalizing the basis
vector to form a unit vector u.
Then, taking the dot product of u,
with the vector we're projecting.
In this case self, and then multiplying
u by the result of that dot product.
The only problem that could happen
here is if the basis vector is zero.
In this case the normalization will
fail, and an exception will be raised.
I check for the appropriate message and
raise a new exception detailing
that there is not a unique parallel
component to the zero vector.
Now having coded
the component_parallel_to function
I can implement
the component_orthogonal_to function.
I do this by recalling the fact that
v equals the parallel plus v perp.
Which I can re-express as the equation
v perp equals v-v parallel.
So I find the parallel component,
set it to the projection variable and
then return self.minus(projection).
In the case an exception is raised
by finding the parallel component,
I check to see if
the NO_UNIQUE_PARALLEL_COMPONENT_MSG
is found.
If so, I raise a corresponding
exception with the message
NO_UNIQUIE_ORTHOGONAL_COMPONENT.
Now that I'm done
coding those functions,
here's the code corresponding
to the questions asked earlier.
And here's the output after I run it.