Now that we're selecting
a random page number,
we need to make a second request,
get a random image from that page.
This request is going to look
a lot like our first request, but
just have that added page parameter.
So let's reuse some of our existing
code to create a new method called
displayImageFromFlickerbySearch that
takes the method parameters again, but
an additional parameter
called withPageNumber.
Now most of the code in this method
is going to be the same as when we
made our first request, so
while I normally don't recommend this,
I'll start by copying and pasting
over the code from our first request.
Gone ahead and copied it and
we'll paste it there.
And then, let's back this up to here.
Let me finish parsing the data.
So all that's the same.
Let's collapse this and
reopen our, oops.
Reopen our other one.
There we go.
There's our random page number.
Now there are definitely more
elegant ways to do this and
to avoid this duplication
of similar code,
but we're going to get to
them later in this course.
So let's go ahead and call this method.
There we go and
we can reuse our method parameters.
And then we'll use our
random page number.
Now with this method, we need to add the
page parameter to the method parameters
before we create our URL.
One quick way to do this, is to make the
method parameters a variable parameter,
so that we can modify it
in the body of this method.
So let's do that and then let's add
the page parameter to the dictionary.
Now the rest of the code in this
completion handler should be fine
up until the point where we
need to parse the result.
Remember, we need to get
the array of photo dictionaries,
select a random photo dictionary,
grab it's URL and
title, and
then display those to the user.
I've gone ahead and copied the code that
we'll need, and I've pasted it here now.
Now, don't be alarmed, you've seen
this code already where you checked
the status to make sure it's okay,
then we get the photos dictionary, and
then we get the array of our
individual photo dictionaries, and
then we make sure that we at least
have have one photo in the array and
we randomly generate our photo index,
or the index I should say for
the photo dictionary that we need.
Select our photo dictionary,
get its title, and
also get the url_m,
the url that we need for the image,
and then with all that in place we use
our perform ui updates on main and
we make our changes to the ui.
I've also added a little extra code
that displays untitled if we somehow
select an image without a title,
I think this has happened to me once.
That's it, let's run this.
I'll use the search term baseball and
it looks like it works.
For good measure, let's do a latitude
and longitude search as well.
I'll use the latitude 37.86,
and the longitude -119.53,
and these are the coordinates for
the Yosemite National Park.
And there we go, this looks great.
Now I want you to follow the steps I
just showed to complete Flick Finder by
selecting a random image
from a random page.
When you are done, check this box.