So when we request audio focus,
we must specify the stream type.
And remember that Android gives
you these options to choose from.
So we found these in the AudioManager
reference section in the public constant
section.
But after reading through
all these descriptions,
it looks like none of
them are a good fit.
We just have a short audio file.
So it's not an alarm.
It's not a DTMF tone, that's used for
dialing phone numbers.
And it's not really music or
a notification of anything.
And it's also not a system sound or
a voice call.
So of these options, it looks like
STREAM_MUSIC is the best fit.
So when you're developing an app that
plays audio, things like music or
a podcast player,
you'll likely be using this STREAM type.
So for the first question,
the stream type that we want
is AudioManager.STREAM_MUSIC.
So now let's figure out our third
parameter, the durationHint.
So let's go back to the
requestAudioFocus method documentation.
And reading through
the parameter descriptions for
the durationHint it looks like
the most appropriate one for us
is the AUDIOFOCUS_GAIN_TRANSIENT because
that means we're requesting audio focus
for a brief moment of time because
our audio files are really short and
will be only playing for
a couple seconds.
So the other audio focused states
wouldn't make too much sense
in our case.
For example, we're not playing
a long song or video, so
we don't need AUDIOFOCUS_GAIN.
Also,
AUDIOFOCUS_GAIN_TRANSIENT_EXCLUSIVE
means that the system sounds,
like notifications,
won't get played when we play our audio.
And we don't want our user to miss
out on those important sounds, so
we're not going to be using this option.
And lastly,
AUDIOFOCUS_GAIN_TRANSIENT_MAY_DUCK could
have potentially worked, but
using it could have meant there
would be some background noise.
Now to clarify what ducking meant,
let's click into this documentation.
So this first sentence here says that
it's used to indicate a temporary
request of audio focus anticipated
to last a short amount of time and
where it's acceptable for
other audio applications to keep playing
after having lowered their output level.
So that's referred to as ducking or like
ducking under or lowering the level.
Now in our case, for example,
if there's music being played and
the user wants to hear a Miwok word, we
don't want that song playing at the same
time the Miwok word is playing, even if
the song is played at a lower volume.
So when want to play our audio,
we want to temporarily
completely silence everything,
aside from system sounds.
So in this case, let's use
AudioManager.AUDIO_GAIN_TRANSIENT.
Great investigative work.
You're becoming more familiar with
AudioManager by reading through those
documentations.
So let's dive in further, and
move on to the next quiz.