So that was pretty cool, right?
You basically take this great big long
feature, based upon these HOG features,
Histograms of Oriented Gradients.
You take a whole bunch
of positive examples,
whole bunch of negative examples,
you throw it into this training machine.
You go get a latte.
And then another latte because it
takes a while and it comes back and
it says here are your support vectors.
Here are the alphas.
At testing time,
just build yourself a feature vector,
just take the dot product.
[SOUND] Multiply it by the alphas.
Need some other sound effect.
[SOUND] And sum them up.
[SOUND] I don't know.
Anyway.
And then if it's greater than zero,
call it a, a person.
If it's less than 0, not.
What if the data are not
linearly separable?
What if I can't just draw a line, okay?
So let's explore this, all right?
So some data sets, you know?
Linear, linearly separable,
to start out with.
So, here, I have them along the line.
So I got my pink points on one side.
My, my blue points along another.
And yes, I could draw a boundary.
And I would have a support.
I, I would have a margin between them.
But what about something
that looks like this, okay?
So here again, I've got 1D, all right?
And I've got my pink points here,
but I have some pink points there.
And clearly, there's no single
place that I could draw a line and
say all the points to
the right are pink, and
all the points to the left
are going to be blue.
So what do I do?
I'm going to map to
a higher dimensional space.
Doesn't it sound cool when you say that?
Map to a higher dimensional space.
Well, here's a very simple example.
All right?
So here I just have the pink points
along the single dimension x.
What if I plot them in 2D.
You might say, where does 2D come from.
>> Where does 2D come from?
>> She's on the ball now.
Well how about I just take x and
x squared, okay.
So I just take x and x squared.
So these points are the same points,
right.
In other words, well actually,
this shifted over a little bit,
this point should be right there.
Yeah, these are pretty much, right?
These points are the same points, but
I just took whatever their x-value was,
and just drew it on the x squared line.
Okay?
Well, that looks nice.
Let's erase that.
Now, is there a line here
that separates the points?
You know,
a line that looks something like that?
Well, if I push my magic button,
There it is, okay?
And there's only three
little support vectors.
One here, one here, and one there.
And all of a sudden,
it's magically delicious.
No, magically separable, okay?
So, that's a pretty cool trick.
It's about to get even
cooler in a minute.
Here's another example.
Here we have a bunch of points.
This comes from Andrew Moore.
Pink points in the middle.
Blue points on the outside.
And in the 2D space here,
is there a line that separates them?
No, of course not, but
there would be this curve here, right?
As drawn there and
that has something to do with sort of
how far away it is from the center.
Well suppose I map, using some function
cap phi, the points x to phi of x.
And suppose that puts it into a space
where along here is the distance to
the origin.
Now, and it's a little hard to see
the idea is that this plane in here
is separating that.
And the key to making this work
was this mapping function, right.
So we map phi of x, so
it takes x from its, its original
space into some higher space.
That's actually called
the lifting space but it just,
it's to a higher dimensional space.