So I have the DevTools
timeline open here and
I had it record what happened
during the load of this page.
Let's take a look at the records
in a little more detail.
The first thing to notice is
that they're color coded.
Blue records are HTML being parsed.
Now, normally this is really fast and
I haven't personally seen a performance
issue where this was the bottleneck,
certainly not past
the initial page load anyway.
Moving along a little bit, and zooming
in with the W key, just drag that
along a little bit, you can see that
we actually have two purple records.
One is Recalculate Style, and
then there's Layout as well.
Let's zoom in a little bit more.
And you can see I've got a green
one here which is Paint, and
a green one which is Composite.
Okay, there are actually two ways you
can view the timeline information,
and it's really up to you as to
which one you find more useful.
Firstly, I'm going to record again,
and scroll the page.
Up here are the two
options that we have.
We can switch on and off the frames,
although I don't know why you'd
ever do that, so leave that on.
But your options here are to
use a Flame Chart view or not.
Let's switch it off for
a second by tapping here.
Now, we have a slightly different view,
which looks more like a waterfall.
I can scroll up and down, and can also
tap on records on the left hand side.
The wider bar is in this view, the
longer it took for the task to complete.
The second view, which also happens to
be the default, is the Flame Chart view.
The chart grows down from the top, and
if one part of the pipeline triggers
something else, it's shown as
a child record beneath its parent.
I'm going to zoom in a little bit,
maybe a little bit more,
going to use the W key again.
And I'm going to scroll
across by click dragging.
You can see here,
this function call in Parallax.js
was a child of this scroll event.
Let's take a quick look
at another example,
this time the Chrome Dev Summit site.
I'm going to record the timeline,
and I'm going to expand the card.
Let's take a look in
this little bit here.
When we zoom in on the area of interest
you see that there's an animation frame
that's fired,
which called some other JavaScript,
which caused some Recalculate Style,
which caused some Layout.
So you can start to build up
a picture of what caused what.
Take a look at both of these views.
The old one with the waterfall,
and the new one, the Flame Chart.
It's the same information, just
packaged in a slightly different way.
It's really down to you
which one you prefer.
I often find that this view helps me
understand the relationship between
different parts of the pipeline.
But give it a go on your own projects
and find out which one works for you.