So given what you've seen so
far both in this course and
in your own experience of using
the internet and web services.
Which of the following problems
do you think might cause a TCP
session to time out for instance
between a browser and a web server?
First, could a timeout because
the host at the other end is powered
off suddenly?
Second, could a timeout because
a windstorm blows down the cable between
you and your ISP?
Third, could it timeout because your
DNS server has stopped working?
Four, could a timeout because
you're connecting to a server that
doesn't exist?
Or five, could it timeout because
you're using a Windows PC for instance,
to watch this course, but
Microsoft's website is down?