I choose to modify the list
rather than create a new list.
I looped over the daily
engagement table.
And for each row I first created
a new key, account key, and
set it equal to the existing
values stored under the key ACCT.
Then once the value had been copied,
I deleted the ACCT key
from the dictionary.
And I'll go ahead and run this code,
it doesn't have any output.
Now if you chose to create
a new list that's fine.
But if you gave it a new name, you'll
need to update the rest of the starter
code to use your name
instead of daily_engagement.
Now that I've changed this field
it will be easier to write
a function to get the unique
students from each table.
So I'll go ahead and do that.
First, I'll move this change up
above the previous investigation.
Since I'd already run this cell, it
actually wasn't necessary to move it up,
but this will make it so
that if I close the notebook and
reopen in, the code will still
work if I run all cells in order.
Then I'll insert a new cell below this
point and write my function there.
I'll name the function,
get unique students, and
it will take one argument, the data.
My code here looks very similar
to the code I wrote before.
I'm first creating an empty set,
then looping over the data and
adding each account key to the set.
And finally,
I'll return the set of unique students.
I could also have gone
one step further and
returned the number of unique students.
But I happen to know that later I'll
want to have access to these sets, so
I'm going to return them and
store them in a variable.
If I hadn't known in advance that
I would want the sets later,
then that wouldn't be a problem,
I could just change this function.
Then I'll update the later
cells to call this function.
And I'll rerun the cells to make
sure I get the same results.
Finally, I'll run this command I
told you to run to double check
that renaming the column worked.
And sure enough,
the account_key field is now present
in the daily_engagement table.