Congratulations.
>> We finished the course.
>> Yay.
[SOUND] Tommy, do you like the app?
>> I think he does.
>> Yeah.
[LAUGH]
>> So Tommy approved and
you're an official Android rockstar now.
>> Yay.
>> And you might be asking
where did she go from here?
>> Now as you continue to build on more
apps, you can either continue learning
with our intermediate Android
developer unit degree.
>> Or you can pick and
choose from any of the free Android
courses listed at Udacity.com/google.
>> Or perhaps continue practice
building an app on your own.
Maybe walk down the street to that local
small business you visit often, and
see if they need some help
in their Android app.
It's also fun to recruit some friends
along the way to help you out.
>> If you keep your eyes open,
there are opportunities all around you.
So we wish you the best of luck, and
keep us posted on how things go.
>> Now if you'll excuse us, there's a
particular fridge we need to go raid for
some cheese.
>> Good idea!
Let's go.
Come on, Tommy.
Bye, everyone!