Okay so let's talk about step two, accessing the content provider.
I'm going to go over to the code right now.
Okay so we're here at the MainActivity.
And the two lines of code that I want you to look at are these lines right here.
Let's go ahead and take a closer look at those.
Okay, so here's the code again.
And we've got some new concepts and
some new words here like ContentResolver and cursor.
So we're going to break this all down in the next few nodes.
I'm going to start by looking at the first line here, and
specifically we're going to talk about the ContentResolver.
So, this our original diagram that I've been showing you a lot.
It's pretty simplistic.
It's actually a bit too simplistic, so
let me show you something that's a little bit more accurate.
So the more accurate version has this class called a ContentResolver.
What is a ContentResolver?
As I mentioned before, there are a lot of content providers.
Besides the user dictionary provider that we're talking right now,
there's a context content provider.
There's a calendar content provider.
There's an alarms content provider.
And a handful of other standard Android content providers.
Also, your app is not the only app on the system.
So, what helps all of these apps communicate with the content providers that
they're interested in?
Well that, my friend, is the job of the content resolver.
The ContentResolver helps your app connect with the correct content provider.
It does this by looking at whatever request that your app sends to
the content resolver.
And then, looking up which content provider it happens to be for.
Using a ContentResolver, it's really easy for your app to talk to one or
two or even more content providers.
Knowing that, let's go back to the code, and take a look at what's happening.
Okay, so, now, this line of code right here, should be pretty clear.
This statement here,
is asking the Android system to give us access to a ContentResolver.
And it's saving it in an instance variable called resolver.
Now that we have the resolver, we're calling this query method on it.
So what does this method do?
There are really four major things that you want to do with data.
The first is, you want to read from the data.
You also might want to add one or more values to the data.
You could also change a pre-existing value in the data.
Or delete something from the data.
And these four actions map to four methods, query, insert, update, and delete.
So you can call resolver.query to read the data.
Note, when you call resolver.query,
it's calling the corresponding query method in the Content Provider.
Okay, so right now we know what the content resolver is and
we know how it helps us in some way access the correct content provider.
Although, we're going to talk about that a little bit more.
We've also talked a little bit about step three.
Right here we're
actually using the content provider through the content resolver.
We have a couple more mysteries to
solve before we can print out this information to the UI.
First of all there's all of these parameters in here which we
need to talk about.
We also need to learn exactly what a cursor is, so let's get started.