>> Should we use a longer key?
The answer is yes.
Because a longer key
length means more keys,
which means the attacker has
to search a lot more keys.
Should we use a shorter key length?
Obviously not.
Should we use a more complex algorithm?
The answer is no.
Because the attacker is to use
brute-force to blindly try
the keys one by one.
So, his search is independent of the
complicity of the encryption algorithm.
Should we use a harder to guess key?
The answers no.
Because the attackers is going to use
brute-force again to search blindly.
That is, he's going to try to key one by
one, he's not going to guess the keys.
So, the correct answer is
to use a longer key length.
Again, this would mean that there
are more keys for attacker to try.