In the event you're ever spelunking
in the parallel computing literature,
you will come across a variety of other
kinds of networks besides rings and
meshes and torii.
I want to mention a few here in passing.
The first is a tree network.
The compute nodes
are the leaves of the tree.
The interior nodes are just routers.
So you can assume these higher
level nodes in the tree are just
moving traffic.
They don't do any actual compute.
Now in this example,
these three nodes at the top are binary,
but they needn't be in general.
Now, what about the network
properties of a tree?
A tree with P compute nodes at
the leaves will have P links, it'll have
a diameter of log P, and it will have
a bisection width of just 1 link.
The scaling of links and
diameter is very good.
But the scaling of bisection width being
just a small constant is terrible.
The bisection width is poor because
to cut the network in half,
all I have to do is cut one
of these links near the top.
Now in practice, network designers
typically fatten up the bandwidth as you
move towards the top of the tree.
Here's an example.
At each higher level in the tree,
I put a lot more wires to
help carry more traffic.
This variation on a tree network
is sometimes called a fat tree.
Fat trees are quite common in
medium scale cluster environments.
By medium size, I probably mean on
the order of thousands of nodes today.
Another kind of important network
is a natural extension of 2D
meshes and torii.
The extension is to higher dimensions.
A d-dimensional measure of torus is
basically a high dimensional cube
that is, say,
the dth root of P nodes per edge.
If the object is a torus,
then it will have these properties.
Naturally, these values depend
on the number of dimensions in
an interesting way.
For example, the diameter
decreases by the d through the P.
So that's good,
because as you increase the dimension,
you'll decrease the diameter
on the one hand.
On the other hand,
the diameter also depends linearly on d.
So as you increase the number of
dimensions, the diameter goes up.
Now d-dimensional meshes and
torii are very important in practical
high end computing systems.
In fact,
many of the world's top supercomputers
use low dimensional toroidal networks.
As of the time of this recording,
there's even one that
has a dimension of six.
Related to meshes and torii is a type
of network called a hypercube.
Woah, easy there, fella.
Very roughly speaking, a hypercube
is a log p dimensional torus.
More specifically,
a P node hypercube has these properties.
It has P log P links.
It has a diameter of log P.
And it has a bisection
width that scales like P.
Compare the hypercube and
torus formulas.
Hypercube is much more expensive in
terms of the number of wires, but
it has a lower diameter and
a much larger bisection width.
So, what does a hypercube look like?
The easiest way to explain it
is by visual construction.
A hypercube is parameterized
by a dimension little d.
The number of nodes
is a power of 2 in d.
The smallest hypercube
occurs when d is equal to 0.
It's just a single node.
To make a one-dimensional hypercube,
start by making two copies of
the lower zero dimensional hypercube.
So here are two copies.
You then connect the corresponding
nodes of the two copies, so
that's a one-dimensional hypercube.
What about d = 2?
Again, start by making two copies of
the lower, one-dimensional system.
Then connect the corresponding
nodes of the two copies.
For a higher dimensional hypercube,
just keep repeating this process.
Make two copies,
then connect the corresponding nodes.
For d = 4, you do the same thing.
Two copies, connect the links, voila.
From this construction process,
I hope you can easily see that
the bisection width is just P/2.
That's because you just build the larger
network by connecting the corresponding
nodes of the smaller network,
each of which is half the size.
Now these days a hypercube network
is more of a historical intellectual
curiosity than something
people actually build.
There's a lot of elegant
theory around them, and
you'll see lots of algorithms
designed for them in the literature.
Now these have just been a few
examples of network topologies,
which is a very active area of research.
I'll put some more references to some
recent ideas in the instructor's notes.