Okay, let's get back to our
question of what is intelligence?
Given these building blocks, agent,
environment, perception, action, and
cognition, is there a more practical
definition that we can come up with?
>> Well here's one formulation that's
actually quite widely accepted.
An intelligent agent is one that takes
actions to maximize its expected utility
given a desired goal.
This is commonly referred
to as rational behavior and
it let's us compare agents regardless
of what cognitive mechanisms they use.
>> There is one problem with
this definition though.
It requires agents to behave optimally.
However as we have seen, it's extremely
hard to find the optimal solution
to many of the problems
we are concerned with.
We need to consider the constraints
the agent is faced with.
For example,
a partially observable environment,
limited computational resources such
as memory and processing speed.
Rules imposed by the task at hand
such as having to respond by a given
deadline, etc.
>> That's a good point.
Given these constraints,
we can not expect an agent
to always behave optimally.
Be we can come up with
a level of performance or
bound that we desire the agent to meet.
So for example we might want
a chess playing program to win
at least 60% of the time
against human chess masters.
Or a route finding algorithm
to always find a route.
It is no more than two miles
longer than the optimal route.
This is known as bounded optimality and
it serves as a practical and
feasible way of
quantifying intelligence.