I think one of the cool parts about
D3 is how its APIs design and
how it makes you think.
Since every method in D3
returns the element or
selection of elements that
method was called upon,
you can naturally chain
method from one to the next.
Keep in mind that any
changes that we've made so
far to the page are client side only and
they're not permanent.
We can refresh the page at any time to
get back to the original styling and
content of the page.
All right, let's try something
a little bit more difficult.
Let's see if we can change
the Udacity logo on the page
to a different version of the logo.
If I right-click on the element and
inspect it,
I can see that this is an image tag.
But wait, there aren't any class names
on the elements, and the element doesn't
have an ID, does this mean that
we can't select the image?
It turns out that we can select the
image, we just need to look one level
higher or multiple levels higher
at any of the parent elements.
This image tag sits within an A tag.
So, the A tag is the parent.
We can select this parent by
using the select method and
passing in the class name.
I'm going to pass in both class names,
in case the class names
are used elsewhere on the page.
This makes it so that D3 only selects
elements with both class names, of nav
brand and logo, which, should hopefully
just be the A tag element on the page.
And sure enough this
returns what I'd like.
Now, since the a tag also
has an ID of header-logo,
I could use that to select the element.
Remember that when using ID selectors,
you need to pass in the hash, or
pound symbol, before the name.
Let's save that selection
into a variable and
call it parent_el,
short for parent element.
Since D3 returned a selection,
we can use D3's methods to
make another selection.
So, I can use select
on the parent element
to select the image tag
that sits within it.
This returns the image tag
that we want to update.
To change the source of the image tag,
we need to change the source attribute.
We can use that atter method to do so,
by passing it an attribute name and
the value that we'd like to set.
So, if I just look at
the source attribute,
I'll see that it matches what is
currently there, assets/udacity.svg.
If we wanted to change a property
say like the all text and
I would pass in a different value as
a second perimeter to the method.
So we'll change this all
text of logo to Udacity.
Now, again I made this selection
a little bit more complicated than
it needed to be, since I used
this intermediate parent element.
To make the selection simpler I can just
make one selection using the parent ID
and then a space for the name of the
child element that we want to select.
So I'll select the parent a tag
with the id of header-logo, and
then I'll select the child image.
And here I'll change the alt
text from udacity back to logo.
There's certainly more than one way
to select elements on the page, so
don't be surprised or confused as
you work through this course and
our answers might be slightly
different than yours.
For example you might've tried
to use two class names to select
that parent element a-tag and
then change the all-text logo.
I find using the ID selection a little
bit simpler in this case but,
just know that there's always more than
one way to select elements on a page.