So far, we talked about the fully observable case,
and I'd like to get back to the more general case
of partial observability.
Now, to warn you, I don't think it's worthwhile in this class
to go into full depth about the type of techniques
that are being used for planning and uncertainty
if the world is partially observable.
But I'd like to give you a good flavor
about what it really means to plan in information spaces
that we reflect the types of methods that are being brought to bear
in planning and uncertainty.
Like my Stanford class, I don't go into details here either
because the details are much more subject to more specialized classes,
but I hope you can enjoy the type of flavor of materials
that you're going to get to see in the next couple of minutes.