Okay, the first thing you need
to know about JavaScript,
is that the code you write,
isn't actually the code that runs.
Now that may sound a little strange
if you never heard it before, but
it comes about because of the fact
that modern JavaScript engines
recompile your code to something
that can run more quickly.
It's done thru a Just In Time compiler,
or JIT.
A JIT compiler will optimize the
JavaScript bit by bit as it runs, and
it's a brilliant but
extremely complex engine.
For us as developers, what that means
is that there's no way to look at
JavaScript and know exactly what
code will run in the engine.
Take a look at this
JavaScript code here.
It's a for loop, it's pretty simple.
But if we use this tool
called IRHydra to look at how
Chrome's JavaScript engine V8 would look
at representing it, it looks like this.
Now you don't need to
understand any of this.
This is just how Chrome and
its V8 JavaScript Engine understands
the code that you wrote.
But what I want you to take away here
is that you should avoid what we call
micro-optimizations.
Micro-optimizations come about
when you try to write code
that you would think would be a little
bit faster for a browser to run.
Like say, which is faster,
this for loop or this while loop?
But the thing is,
we don't know how the JavaScript engine
is going to treat these
two pieces of code.
So there's no point in guessing.
Any micro-optimization you
write should be a last resort
once you've exhausted
all your other options.
In short,
what I'm saying is don't spend your time
comparing similar pieces
of JavaScript in this way.
It won't help you.
There are other things you
can do to improve performance
that don't involve micro-optimizations.
So you're done, right?
I mean,
you can't guess exactly how a JavaScript
engine is going to handle your code.
So obviously we can move on.
Well, no, actually.
It turns out there are plenty
of things that you can do
to make your code run better.
So let's get started.