So what does R look like?
Well there are two ways to think about this,
first we'll think about it the hard way.
R A to B expresses how each basis vector in A would be expressed in terms of B.
So the first column of R A B is the component of the I
vector of A expressed in terms of how much it has in the i direction in B,
in the j direction in B, and in the k direction in B.
So you can think of it as like the dot product between i A, and
each of the components of B, i B, j B, k B.
And likewise each of the following columns is done, is, is that way.
So, one way of thinking about this is that the columns of
R A B are the i vector of A expressed in the B coordinate frame.
Then the j vector of A in the B coordinate frame, and
the k vector of A in the B coordinate frame.
All right, so why is this true?
Well let's think about it this way.
Suppose I had a point, vector, in the A frame.
That was just at value of 1, 0, 0, okay?
So what that means it's actually a distance of 1 in the i direction of
the A frame and none in the j and k of the A frame.
What should the value of that be?
All right?
And I'll just write that down here.
Well, this multiplies this.
This to that so.
So it would just give me the iA dotted with iB.
So the first component of the transformed frame is just the i vectors amount in,
in the i direction of B.
Well, now lets go through this.
We go one, two, three.
It's again, is going to get iA.jB.
Okay, and again iA.kB.
In other words it's just what it says here is what we have to
get out if we had just a 1, 0, 0,
needs to be how that vector is dotted which each of the components.
And that's why this matrix can be thought of as having it's
column vectors as just being the each of the basis vectors of
the a frame expressed in terms of the b frame.
Do you get that?
So on the sides you'll have that.
So just press the pause button and that way you can.
See what's going on.
Just to remind you I labeled this that the columns of
the rotation matrix are the axes of frame A expressed in frame B.
Why? because we just went through all that nonsense showing it to you.
By the way, it can also be thought of as the rows are just the column,
are just the bases of the B vector expressed in the A frame, right?
So here's iB in, in the, in terms of the i component of A.
Here's iB in terms of the j.
Here's iB in k.
So you think about this is that if I were to transpose that vector.
So I made the columns the rows,
the rows the columns, I would now have instead of RAB, I'd have RBA, all right?
This is an orthogonal matrix, right?
The orthogonal matrix, all of the rows,
all the columns are unit vectors that are perpendicular to each other.
So the determinate so the, the magnets of determinate is 1.
And it's your traditional rotation matrix and
by the way, really important is that the inverse is equal to the transpose.
So, if you had a rotation matrix and you want to go back and
forth between the two, the inverse and transpose, which realize it has to be.
Because the inverse of RAB has to be RBA and we just showed how the,
the rows are the sort of the transposed of the spec to the columns.