Let's start with a very basic idea of what programming is. Look at this
toaster, what can it do? Okay, the toaster can toast. Good toaster. What about
this computer? The computer can run programs, why is that better? Why do we say
we are in the computer age and no one says we are in the toaster age. A better
way to describe that is that a computer can do any instructions that you give
it. Whatever you tell the computer to do, it will do it. And that makes the
computer such a universal device that can manipulate images, text, sounds and
much more whereas a toaster can just toast. There's just one catch in order
tell the computer what you it to do you have to speak it's language. You're
going to learn how to tell the computer what you want it to do in the language
that the computer understands. And that's a great thing because now you're the
master of the machine and it will do for you quickly and reliably any number of
tasks that you would find tedious or difficult to do on your own.