For backed up values for the min nodes, the backed up value is always the minimum.
For the chance nodes, it's the expectation, or the average,
and for the max node, it's the maximum.
Here the nodes that can be pruned.
This and this can be pruned because in each of these cases min has achieved
the best possible play that min can get, and therefore,
doesn't need to consider any other possibilites.
Once you know you can win the game or do the best you can,
you don't need to find another way to do just as well.
This node here can be pruned and thus, all the ones below it because
at this point, when we're trying to evaluate this node, max knows he can get
at least 1/3, and here once we know that this node is worth -1
then we know that regardless of the value here,
that has to be somewhere between -1 and +1.
So therefore, the expectation has to be between -1 and 0,
and if 0 is the best that this can be, max knows he already has 1/3 over here.