An alternative to the multi-process
model is to develop the web server as
a multi-threaded application.
So here we have multiple execution
context, multiple threads within
the same address space and every single
one of them is processing a request.
Again, this illustration is taken
from Pai's Flash paper, and
this is figure three there.
In this figure, every single one of the
threads executes all the steps, starting
from the accept connection call all the
way down to actually sending the file.
Another possibility is to have
the web server implemented
as a boss-workers model
where a single boss
thread performs the accept
connection operation.
And every single one of the workers
performs the remaining operations from
the reading of the HTTP request
that comes in on that connection
until actually sending the file.
The benefits of this approach is that
the threads share the address space, so
they will share everything
that's within it.
They don't have to perform system calls
in order to coordinate with other
threads, like what's the case
in the multi-threaded execution.
Also context switching between
these threads is cheap.
It can be done at the user level,
threading library level.
Because a lot of the per thread
state is shared among them,
then we don't have to allocate memory
for everything that's required for
each of these execution contexts.
They share the address space, so the
memory requirements are also lower for
the multi-threaded application.
The downside of the approach
is that it is not simple and
straightforward to implement
the multi-threaded program.
You have to explicitly
deal with synchronization
when threads are accessing and
updating the shared state.
And we also rely for the underlying
operating system to have support for
threads.
This is not so much of an issue today.
Operating systems
are regularly multi-threaded.
But it was at the time of
the writing of the Flash paper, so
we will make sure that we address this
argument as well in our explanations.