From Robert S. in Perth in Western Australia,
"What is Stanford's motivation for offering these courses for free?
Are academics--like us--being coerced or incentivized or are we just curious to see what happens?"
The answer is it's you. It's you people out there that we have a developed a great, deep relationship with.
I've received many hundreds of emails from people whose lives I believe we changed.
It's extremely gratifying to be able to bring our work and our teaching
not just to a Stanford campus but to the entire world.
That's the biggest thing I've ever done in my academic career so far.
I actually attended a Katy Perry concert on Monday, I have to admit.
I might not look like a typical Katy Perry fan, but I went.
There were about 16,000 people in the stadium. It was packed.
She was very proud of this,
and I was thinking, "Wow. We have more students in our class right now
that spend several hours a week studying material and being empowered by what we teach you."
It's been just amazing.
I would agree with that. It's been amazing.
How many of your would rather have gone to the Katy Perry concert
than of done your homework? Raise your hands.
Luckily we don't see them right now. >>Yeah, not too many, I don't think.
So we are doing it for you.
I guess from my point of view I did the text book,
and I thought it was great that I had some kind of connection with students
both when I taught the class personally, and then also knowing that
other professors were teaching the class.
But it felt like it was incomplete, and I thought we could do more.
We could reach more people and we could reach them in a richer way by putting the class online.
Yeah. And I should say we were kind of the first to announce an experiment like this.
There is, of course, more free classes on the way right now and about 10 more to come.
And I can tell you Stanford didn't coerce us.
In fact, Stanford was surprised we did this, and they embraced us.
They understood the vision of this. This is certainly an experiment that is unprecedented.
And I should say that there had been work going on at Stanford for years
with Andrew Ng and Daphne Koller and others and work at other universities--MIT and elsewhere.
We made a little tweak on it to push it out to you guys in way that's slightly different than what had been done before,
but we're really following up on work that's been done by others.
Professor Rodney Brooks from MIT--a good friend of mine, a person I admire--
once said in a documentary that Mars exploration should be done by a
swarm of smaller and independent robots.
It would be fast, cheap, and as he put it, out of control.
What do you think about this?
I was at NASA under the era that was known as "faster, better, cheaper."
But not out of control. >>But not out of control. They didn't mention that part.
But Goldin, who was the NASA administrator there was following up on some
lost missions that were very expensive ½ billion to 1 billion dollar missions,
and when they fail that's a lot of money down the drain.
So his mantra--similar to Brooks--was to say, "Let's see what we can do cheaper."
I thought that was a great idea of NASA, and I think it's a great idea for lots of applications.
Yeah, it's interesting. When he made that comment, I think we were just beginning to explore Mars.
The first Rover was being sent up. The question was legitimate.
Should we send one complex machine and just put all your eggs into that basket or send many of them?
I think history proves him wrong in the follow sense:
The reliability of the device has not been the issue.
It's not been the case that we send one machine and it got lost,
we send another machine and it got lost.
By and large it actually outperformed the expectations.
You can argue we're actually using swarms.
We're sending them out right now, this very moment--just sequential swarms.
To do certain measurements you need a certain complexity in instruments.
If you use very, very small robots, they just couldn't carry those instruments.
So in hindsight, it looked like we lost the most robots and it was a complete disaster,
but if we sent 10,000 times as many, we would've at least retained some.
I would give him right, but at this point I think he was actually wrong in this case.
Capture Whiz in Denver asked, "It seems the AI techniques we've learned could be valuable for human use as well as robots.
Have you used them in your personal life such as in decision making?"
That's actually interesting. It's a very deep question.
Herb Simon--I used to be very good friends with Herb Simon--
who was one of the founders of Artificial Intelligence, who passed away many years ago,
a Professor at Carnegie Mellon, a noble laureate,
and he kept telling me about bounded rationality was optimal decision making.
And in a single sentence, optimal decision making you really try to find the optimal decision.
In bounded rationality you try to satisfy,
so you have a threshold that says if the decision is good, I'm just going to implement the decision.
I find myself vastly on the satisfying side of it.
For example, take this class.
We could have sat down for years trying to make the optimal movies,
build the optimal server, or we could just do it.
We decided to just do it. In doing so, we made lots of compromises.
I think some of the early videos weren't very good.
We had lots of server crashes, which I deeply regret, and I apologize for.
But at the same time we were able to get something done.
I find myself much less on the optimality camp.
If people talk about optimal decision making, I always picture the people sit around forever and don't get their act together.
For me, acting and doing something is really important.
It's been the discourse with Herb Simon, who made me aware of that conflict
and made me polarize myself and say, look, I'm going to be a fast actor no matter what.
I think another thing that also came out of CMU is this idea of the reasonable person principle.
CMU has that as kind of a motto-- >>But then they kicked me out.
>>Yeah-- >>I quit. I don't know. >>Yeah.
The idea of the principle is if somebody did something that you thought is crazy
or you think is trying to attack your or undermine you,
go under the assumption that maybe they're a reasonable person after all.
They say, well, how could a reasonable person come to this crazy decision?
If you look at decision theory you would say, well, it could be because
he knows something that I don't know--his state of knowledge is different--
or because his goals are different.
If you think about things that way, it tend often to diffuse the situation, and you say,
"Ah, now I understand why somebody is acting the way that they're acting."
Okay, Peter--question for you by Max K. from New "Yoik", wherever that is. Sorry.
A lot of people noticed your books and the bibliography are staggering.
Any methods that you could recommend to us for dealing with learning a lot of complex material?
I guess you just have to read a lot, right?
Yes, there's a lot of entries in the bibliography, and we had some help there.
In the first edition, Doug Edwards especially did a lot of research work.
Since then we just got a lot of suggestions from people of things that we left out.
Coincidentally, a lot of the suggestions of things we left out happened to be their work,
but often they were right that that was something that we should add.
We went, and we read a lot of papers.
We just kept on trying to learn.
I think just being excited about the field and wanting to learn more and keeping at it--
it can be confusing and hard at first when you're first getting started,
and then it all starts to come together.
You say, "Oh yeah. I've seen this before. I've seen this author before.
I've seen this idea before. This idea relates to another idea."
You start getting to the point where it becomes easier rather than harder.
Keep at it, and you'll get there.
I can let you in on a little secret in my professional academic life.
Students join Stanford and ask me "what should I read?"
I tend to tell them don't read anything.
It sounds a little bit bizarre, but I deeply believe the best way to learn is to solve problems.
Pick a problem that's interesting and don't worry that it has been solved before or not.
Just make sure that it is challenging enough for you that you can actually do something about it.
It's not as challenging as something you can't do anything about.
Then start solving it.
As you solve it and as you solve the first version of it, then start reading papers.
The reason is, first of all, if you just read papers, your thinking will be so engraved in the way people thought before you.
It's really hard for you to find something new and something interesting.
Obviously, the problem isn't solved, otherwise you wouldn't have to read any papers.
Just buy the product, and the problem is solved.
Secondly, your ability to understand papers I think goes up greatly with your ability to solve problems.
If you really try to understand the subject really deeply, and maybe you fail or maybe have certain successes,
then these other papers will make much more sense.
I've always driven my own life by trying to solve problems that I have no clue how to solve,
and I just get into it. It has always worked well and worked well for my students.
The students that come to me with literature,
maybe they're successful with some other professor, but with me,
I tend to discourage them and say just do something interesting.
Now there's an interesting that's hard.
It's easy to come up with an idea that's so fundamental like building the human brain
that would be great if we solved it but you can't.
My favorite is inventing a gravity shield.
It's impossible to even know what the first step is how you go about inventing a gravity shield.
The trick is to find problems that are reasonably manageable.
Where you think if I sit down, I can do this in relatively short enough time to solve the problem.
As you do it, keep your eyes open to what's the next problem to solve.
If you're smart, then as you solve your first problem maybe in the first couple of weeks,
you'll probably find 10 other interesting problems that have really come up along the way
that you didn't think of before.
That for me has been always the best path of learning.
Then go back, consult the literature, see what people have written, but don't read too much, in my opinion.
You can quote me for that.
I think that's great advice. You're all going to be so busy anyways. You won't have time to read that much.
Congratulations to everyone. We got very good results on the midterm.
You did a great job and keep it up. >>Amazingly well.
Thank you. See you soon. >>So long.