The objectives of this lesson are for
you to learn about, what is a light
field, and the different seven
parameters of the plenoptic function
that go into creating a light field.
We'll learn about different
types of light fields.
Then we'll look at variety
of camera configurations and
pinhole systems that can
be used to view a scene.
Then I will talk about
the eccentric aperture and
its impact on a simple lens system.
Again, how we can use that
to capture light fields.
And then again, how we can actually
use an array of pinhole cameras
to create an array of images that could
be used to generate light fields.
And using all of this,
I'll introduce to you a basic camera,
a light field camera,
that can capture 40 light fields.