I believe it's displays document.
Is that the, that's the invariant
that when it's held to be
true showing us the correct
sequence in lines so
that's going to be broken
as soon as we move the bar.
>> So we move the bar.
Remember the direct effect
was that the bar moves.
But if our system has any meaning at
all that does what we expect it to do,
it better be the case
we see different lines.
Okay, and we've already decided that
the components have responsibility for
dealing into that and in particular
here the view port component has
responsibility for dealing with that.
Although it's going to have to
interact with the other components.
>> Right.
>> Okay.
So that's the job
the implementation has to do.
When the user scrolls, the event causes
a move handle method to be invoked.
Move handle causes the value of the
handles positions attribute to change.
That's a direct effect.
Because the displace document
constraint refers to handle position,
the value of the view contents
will change as we expected.
Hence the invariant will
have to be re-established.