You've decided like you need to create
a variable to keep track of score.
And for now, that's the only
variable that you're going to need.
Now, you might be wondering why
I don't just call this score.
Well, it's because I'm thinking ahead to
a time when I might need to keep track
of more than just one score.
And, it will be a little bit confusing
if I have a variable named score,
and another variable or
five named something else.
So, we're going to be very explicit,
and call this score Team A.
Now, in a fair basketball game,
both teams start with 0 points.
So, when you're creating this variable,
I want you to initialize
it with the value 0.
Before you get started though,
you should think about this a tiny bit.
For example, should this new variable,
score Team A be a local variable or
a global variable.
Once you've decided that,
you can go ahead and declare it, and
initialize its value to 0.
To make sure you did it correctly,
go ahead and
type the code here that you
used to make this variable.
We are looking for the exact spelling
and capitalization shown here, so
make sure that you use it.