All right Charles, what do you think
I was looking for on this one?
>> Okay, so highest expected payoff?
Well that's pretty easy in this case,
because they all have the same payoff,
maximum payoff of one,
and minimum payoff of 0.
So I really just want the one that has
the highest probability of coming up
with a 1.
And you did me a really cool favor,
of making each denominator easily
divisible by its numerator.
So I could rattle off the probabilities
of each of those and they are one-tenth,
one-tenth, one-tenth, one-fifth,
one-fifth, one-fifth and one-fifth.
So one-fifth is bigger than one-tenth so
I could put anything of d, e, f, or
g in the first box.
>> Good, okay so that was in
some sense not that interesting.
So if you had put g just because 8
is bigger than all the other things,
that would have been a right answer but
not for the right reason.
>> That's right.
>> So
you really do want to compute
what those ratios are.
>> Right and speaking of for
the right reason,
I think that's what your question
most confident sort of comes from.
And I'm just simply going to claim,
without writing equations,
that when it comes to understanding
expectations, your confidence is
a monotonically increasing
function of the number of samples.
So whichever has the biggest denominator
should be the thing that I'm most
confident in because that means
I've seen the most samples.
So that would be c and g.
Either of them.
>> Yeah, okay and in particular, I
wanted you to think about the fact that
a and c, even though they have
the same expected payoff,
scene 1 out of 10 are estimate of what
the actual payoff here is going to be
much less certain than if we did it 40
times and saw that it was 4 out of 40.
This is going to be
a more accurate estimate.
And so as you say,
the confidence is going to increase
monotonically with the denominator.
The more data that we've got the more we
believe our estimate based on the data.
>> Right.
So if I were to combine those two things
and I and I just now had to do a bandit,
I guess I would pick g,
because it has the highest expected
payoff and I'm most confident in it.
>> Well, that would be one thing to do.
And let's talk about why
that could be problematic.