The first statement, bots have
more sophisticated communication
capabilities, than worms and viruses.
This statement is true.
In fact, the ability to perform C&C, or
command control, is how we distinguish
bots from worms and viruses.
The second statement, bots require
direct communication with the C&C
server, before beginning an attack.
This actually is false,
because bots may include
conditions such as those based on
a specific time to launch an attack,
without the need to
communicate with a C&C server.
The third statement,
a botnet will be less likely to be found
if it uses custom
communication protocols.
This is false.
A custom communication protocol means
that it is a unique protocol and
therefore it can stand out from
normal traffic quite easily.
That is, if a botnet uses
a custom communication protocol,
it is actually more
likely to be detected.