The answer is that algorithm
two requires fewer transfers.
Let's quickly walk through this.
Consider algorithm one, the outer loop
of algorithm one iterates over rows.
Within row i, it loops over columns j
starting at zero Notice what happens.
Touching an element of
the row causes a block of L-
1 additional elements from the column
to be loaded into fast memory.
You might not be this exact block,
this is just an example.
This load is a consequence
of column major layout.
Now consider the next iteration.
It will require loading a completely
different block of elements.
Remember that the fast memory only has
space for two vectors plus a little bit
extra, so eventually, the first
block will have to be displaced.
In other words, traversing this
column major matrix, rho wise,
incurs block transfers for each row.
I hope you can see that that will
lead to a total of n squared
transfers to read a.
Okay, what about algorithm two?
The outer loop goes over columns.
The innermost loop traverses
within the column In this case,
the traversal order matches
the storage format.
That is, this access pattern does
a better job of amortizing the cost of
loading a block.
The total number of additional
transfers to read a,
then becomes n squared over L.
In other words, for large values of n,
you expect algorithm one to do
L times more transfers,
making algorithm two, L times faster.
The important point is that
in the sequential RAM model,
these algorithms look identical.
But in this simple two level
model with block transfers,
they look very different.
Oh, RAMy, I hardly knew ye.
Before leaving this quiz, let me
ask you one last thought question.
This is for
those of you who know about caches.
Suppose the fast memory is a fully
associative cache with capacity Z
words and line size L in words.
Do you think that caches alone would
help algorithm one match the performance
of algorithm two in terms
of the number of transfers?