So, this question I want to test your knowledge about
the dimension of the state space of a dynamic system.
In all these questions, I'm going to look at a ball, like a soccer ball.
The interesting thing about a soccer ball is its orientation
is an unimportant variable, whether it's upside down and so on.
So, in all of these questions we're going to explore this,
and the fact that this object is rotationally invariant.
Let me start with a simpler question,
which is the kinematic state, which is the state without any velocities
of the soccer ball, where it is on the ground.
And I'll follow up with a question with the same kinematic state
of the ball in mid-air,
the difference being between these 2 questions that on the ground
it's confined to be in a 2-dimensional ground plane,
whereas in mid-air, you might add another dimension or not.
There's also the dynamic state on the ground and in mid-air.
And for the dynamic state, I wish to ignore things like spin.
I just care about velocities as a person really far away
could observe them, just to make things clear.
And finally, I'd like to include spin,
so let me take the most complicated situation
of dynamic state in mid-air considering spin.
The last one is really a tricky question,
so I don't mind at all if you get this wrong.
But in all of those, I would like to exploit the fact
that I really don't care about the absolute orientation of the soccer ball that is a sphere,
so it's invariant to its orientation, but it might still have spin.