So we can represent a state,
not by an exhaustive listing of everything that's true in the state--
every single dot, and so on.
But rather, by a collection of important features.
So we can say that a state is this collection
of Feature 1, Feature 2, and so on.
And what are the features?
Well, they don't have to be the exact position
of every piece in the board.
They could be things like the distance to the nearest Ghost
or maybe the square of the distance--or the inverse square;
or the distance to a dot or food--
or the number of Ghosts remaining.
And then we can represent the utility of a state,
or let's go with a Q value, of a state action pair
and represent that as the sum over some set of waits times the value of each feature.
And then our task, then, is to learn good values of these waits--
how important is each feature, whether they're positive or negative, and so on.
This formulation will be good to the extent that similar states have the same value.
So if these 2 states have the same value, that would be good
because we could learn that, in both cases, Pacman is trapped.
It would be bad, to the extent that dissimilar states have the same value--
say, if we're ignoring something important.
So, for example, if one of the features was:
Is Pacman in a tunnel?
It would probably be important to know: is that tunnel a dead end or not?
And if we represented all tunnels the same, we'd probably be making a mistake.
Now, the great thing is that we can make a small modification to our Q learning algorithm
where, when we were updating, the Q of S, A got updated
in terms of a small change to the existing Q of S, A values.
We can do the same thing with the wait's sub-i values.
We can update them as we make each change to the Q values.
And they're both driven by the amount of error.
If the Q values are off by a lot, we have to make a big change;
if they're not, we make a small change--
the same thing with the Wi values.
And that looks just like what we did when we
used supervised machine learning to update our waits.
So we can apply that same process, even though it's not supervised.
It's as if we're bringing our own supervision to reinforcement learning.