All right, you're done.
Let me show you how I did it.
So the first thing, of course, we did,
we added the design library
into the dependencies.
Now, I did this using
the user interface,
but, this is actually what it did.
Note that we also want to make sure
we are using a compatible version
of everything.
If we have an old version
of appcompat in there,
it's not going to be
compatible with design.
So you want to make sure
all these versions match.
So it's probably good to go and
look in here if you're running into
trouble because they have to match.
All right, hopefully it wouldn't
compile if they didn't match.
Now as I said,
I did use a frame layout here.
I ran into a bug that I couldn't
work around without this.
It shouldn't really be necessary.
CoordinatorLayout should be
able to be the outside layout.
I'm using an early beta
version of this library.
So it might actually be fixed, but just
in case, I'm leaving it in this way.
We have CoordinatorLayout here,
which is doing all the fun work
of actually coordinating what's
going on between our views.
It's our nested parent.
AppBarLayout is actually
used to scroll the app bar.
And inside of that,
you can see we have our Toolbar
containing our ImageView
just like we had before.
So, no real difference here.
The only note is that we have
to have scrollFlags now,
scroll|enterAlways for our toolbar.
And our AppBarLayout is going to
use that to define behavior.
We could also pin it or
do one of the other cool things that
AppBar can do with these flags.
And then below that, we have our
RecyclerView, and we had to add this
layout_behavior, so app:layout_behavior
= our scrolling_view_behavior.
This is actually defined in the design
part of the support library.
And it is associated with our AppBar.
And note that we are actually
inside of CoordinatorLayout here,
not inside of AppBarLayout.
And so this is what actually
connects it all together.
Finally, for our TextView, which is
also in our CoordinatorLayout for empty,
I decided it would be cool to
anchor it to our recyclerview.
If you scroll while you are in the empty
state, it will still scroll up
the AppBar, and this will actually
follow it, which is kind of nice.
And so that's it.
That's all we had to do was
modify this XML layout, and
we now have these lovely,
lovely scrolling AppBars.