Since P is 4 units to the left of
the origin, it's x coordinate is -4.
Since it's 4 units below the origin,
its y coordinate is also -4.
So we can represent P by
the ordered pair (-4, -4).
Similarly Q can be represented
as the ordered pair (4,-
2 ) since it is 4 units to the right
of the origin and 2 units below it.
Remember that the only properties
that distinguish vectors
are their magnitude and direction.
Vectors don't have a location property.
So we only need to know the amount of
change in the x and y directions for
each vector to represent
them in coordinates.
Since V moves one unit left
its X coordinate is minus one.
And since V moves four units up,
its Y coordinate is four.
Finally, since W moves two units left,
its X coordinate is minus two and
since it has no vertical movement,
its Y coordinate is zero.