The goal for this first exercise is
to design this boarding pass layout.
We'll be using the constraint
layout to do so.
The provided code contains
a default empty relative layout.
Also, if you check the strings.xml file,
you'll find that we've created
all the text that should appear
in the UI as string resources.
Since we're only focusing on
getting the design correct for now,
we will just use those hard
coded strings and then later,
we'll see how to bind
the UI with actual data.
The constraint layout is built as
a separate support library that works on
all Android versions
back to the Android 2.3.
So the first step before we start is to
add the following compile dependency.
This compile dependency allows
us to use the constraint layout.
Make sure that you're
using the latest version.
At the time of this recording,
it was still beta.
Once you add the compile dependency,
don't forget to sync your project.
Now that we have the dependency added,
let's go back to our layout and
replace this RelativeLayout
with the ConstraintLayout.
Now, if we go to the design mode and
try to drag in a TextView,
into the visual editor.
It will stay where you put it.
This is just to make
the process less annoying.
But if you don't create any constraints
around this TextView, we will see later.
At runtime, this view will just go
to the default top left corner.
So, to define a view's position in a
constrained layout, you must add two or
more constraints for each view.
Each constraint represents a connection
or alignment to another view or
to the parent layout.
So for the constraint layout to
know where to place this view,
you have to define at least one
horizontal and one vertical constraint.
Sometimes, you'll probably
need more than that.
Now assuming we're going to use this
TextView as the passenger's name label,
we want to have a margin
on top of that and
a margin on left of that with 16dp's.
You can start by just dragging
this constraint circle here,
all the way to the top of the parent.
Which basically means, we want to make
sure that this TextView is 16 pixels,
as you could see here from
the top of the parent.
And if we do the same
from the left side,
then we've got our two constraints.
It might be hard to visually see what
just happened in the design mode, so
let's switch to the text mode and have
a look at what the generative text was.
You could see that the default layout
width and height were wrapped content.
It generated an ID for
us which we'll rename later and
it created a constraintTop and
constraintLeft for us.
The top constraint is pointing
to the top of the parent and
the constraintLeft is pointing
to the left of parent.
It's also set the margins for
top and left to be 16dp and
the marginStart is just for
accessibility
in case you're changing your UI from
right to left to left to right.
We'll talk a lot more about this later.
Perfect, so let's go ahead and
change the text value
to one of the string resources that
we had, which was passenger_label.
And let's also change the id
to something more readable,
I'd also like to add
a TextAppearance tag
to set the style to set the style
to the AppCompat.Caption style.
Now, let's have a look at the design
to see what it looks like now.
Very good, so let's add another TextView
for the actual passenger's name.
We'll just drop that down here and
then create a constraint
underneath the label and
the left constraint can be equal to the
same left of the actual label up here.
So, let's go back to our TextView and
see what that generated for us.
The first constraint is
a top constraint and
it's to the bottom of
our PassengerLabel.
And the left constraint is to the left
of our PassengerLabel as well.
This means that they will
always have the same left and
that the name would be
underneath the label.
Because of these new constraints that
we just created, if I just hold onto
the label and drag it to the side, it
would move the other TextView with me,
maintaining the constraints
that we just created.
Pretty cool.
Now let's set the text for
the passenger's name here.
However, you should never use
android.text attribute to set fake data.
That's why Android introduces a text
attribute in the tools library,
for that sole purpose.
If we set any fake data here,
this passenger_name would actually
appear in the design mode.
But once you run the app,
it will not display that value.
But that's all we need to
help design this app for now.
Now let's go back to TextView and
change its id to something
more readable as well.
And then I'd like to change the style
and color to be display one and
colorPrimary.
Let's have a look at the design.
That looks much better,
so let's move on.