Here are the redundant sections.
They were 1, 3, 5, 7, 8, and 11.
If we go back to the code,
we can confirm this.
For each network request that we
currently have in the project,
we need the API key, so
that's definitely redundant.
Then, we always need to build
the URL and the request object, but
sometimes the path
extension is different.
So the path extension part
itself is not redundant, or
the same,
between our different network requests.
Moving on, creating the network
task is always the same.
However in the completion handler,
we may handle errors differently.
For example, on both of these methods,
we may want to display an error back to
the user in the login view itself, but
that doesn't always have to be the case.
We may have a network request for
adding or removing favorite movies, and
for that we might want to use
an alert view or something different.
Next as we keep scrolling,
we always make the same guard checks,
these three here, and
then we always convert our data,
our deserialize the JSON
into a usable dictionary.
So these sections are redundant.
This is the big difference in our
code after we have the dictionary and
we start looking for
the values that we need.
So for all the other redundant
code that we've seen above and
even the task.resume,
this is redundant as well.
We need to move this
into something reusable.
And if you're thinking, hey why not move
the redundant code into a function or
method, then you're on the right track.
We're going to do this next.