These are four True or False questions
for computer vision, and specifically,
perspective projection.
Consider a projective image of an object.
Which of the following statements is true?
If the object moves closer to the camera,
the size of the projected image
of the object will increase.
Is this True of False? Please just check one.
If we use a camera with a longer focal length,
as a result of using the longer focal length,
the size of the projected image will increase.
Check one.
If we double the distance to the object,
the projected image will be half as large, as before.
Check one.
And finally, the ratio of the focal length
over the distance to the object
is the same as the projected size of the object in the camera plane.
Please check True or False.