>> So, there's many, there's many nouns in this in this paragraph description.
let's, let's concentrate on the ones of those having to do with the electronics,
the software for which we're going to be building in this example.
>> Okay. So, I have the water strainer, but in terms of the electronics,
there's a sensor that we talked about being associated with that,
that would tell us whether there's water in it or not.
So, there's that, the brew button.
And any other kind of control widgets, the on/off light for the coffee's ready.
As well as the warmer plate.
We're interfaced with that.
I wrote down Mark IV special, that's kind of like the facade.
Everything we're looking at >> The overall system?
>> Right, so, there's that element as well.
The other heating element, to actually, create the steam.
And you know, and then the result with the coffee so those,
those are some of the things that are listed.
>> Okay well we could have,
we could go through the whole process here of underlining the nouns.
We could put them into groups, we could stem them just like we did before.
But for now it's enough to get a sense of the the particular elements we're
going to have to be primarily concerned with