We're finally done with lesson four.
And now you can hear the pronunciation
of each word in the app.
So we've covered a lot
of difficult topics.
But I'm really proud of you.
So we learned how to
play audio in the app,
as well as how to handle audio
interruptions from other apps and
we even covered how to work with
Activity Lifecycle on Android.
But most of all you practiced
skills to learn a new Android API.
So you read tutorials and blog posts and
even created a small sample app
to learn how to apply that
information to improve the app.
Now as you come across new Android
topics on things that interest you,
topics like notifications or
location, you can use the same approach
to add more features to your app.
Now, best of luck.