So Jake,
did you manage to finish the project?
>> Yes, yes, it's all done,
completely offline first.
Here's how the final bits came together.
So over in our fetch event I'm going to
react to URLs that start with /avatars/.
For those I'll call respondWith,
passing in the result of serveAvatar.
Over in serveAvatar,
I'll start by opening the image cache,
then I'll look for
a match for the storage URL.
Right, here's where things start
to get a little bit different.
I'm going to do a network fetch for
the avatar.
And if I get a response,
I'm going to put a clone in the cache
using the storage URL, then I'm
going to return the original response.
Now I've got a response from the cache.
That might be undefined if there's no
match for this particular request.
But I've also got a promise for
the network response.
So I'll return the cache response or
the network response, and that's it.
If I go to the browser and ensure force
update is enabled and hit refresh,
I can now see in the resources panel,
if I hit this update icon here,
things are entering the cache
both photos and avatars.
So if I go offline now and
refresh the page, we have content,
photos, and avatars,
the full offline-first experience.