So one thing, if your attacked, you
can think about is, how can I actually
get into this process when the operating
system itself is coming to life.
And the operating system,
data structures are getting set up and
information is getting initialized.
How can I do some
mischief at that point.
I know once I start running user code,
once the operating system is in place,
the hardware is going to stop me from
going to the areas where operating
system cordoned data is,
unless I do a system call.
But can I get onto it
in the early process,
it's sort of what you would call
infant mortality kind of thing.
Attack it when it is coming to life.
So the way to think about it is that
when you actually power-on a system,
a computer system,
it runs a set of instructions.
And those instructions
are what is called firmware.
So these firmware instructions actually
run and the execution of those
instructions leads to finding
where the operating system is,
where it goes, loading it and
setting it up.
So, I said get onto it
early in the process.
Well, there was an attack like that,
which was demonstrated against Mac OS.
Macs have this Thunderbolt interface.
So what you can do is you can have
a device that you have maliciously
prepared that device, you can connect
it through the Thunderbolt interface,
the very early stage
when the Mac is booting.
So this is called bootware or Malware
that you can inject at the boot stage.
So, because the macs have this
extensible thumbware framework,
you can inject new thumbware
by connecting this
device to the Thunderbolt interface
that we were talking about.
And you can change the firmware,
when it's running.
You can actually run this malicious
instruction from the malware that your
malicious device has that you connected
to the Thunderbolt interface.
So there was an attack like this
actually we are going to provide
a link where you can
go read more about it.
And interesting thing about
this attack was that there's
no protection against it.
The second one is actually
really I said people get
creative to go after the system.
And this is another one
that really exploited
some property of the dynamic
RAM that we have.
So we talked about memory, the DRAMs,
dynamic RAM, and the attack actually
exploited, if you read some locations,
the RAM locations,
the RAM addresses repeatedly
then the way it is refreshed and
the charges that hold the value
that stored in that location work.
Actually this was demonstrated
that by reading aggressively,
reading again and again in certain
locations you can actually
flip some bits in an adjacent location.
Okay if the bit flip happens
to be the right way,
in particular in a location that is
storing information protection and
information about memory,
then you can flip it and
make something that will be readable,
you can also make it writable.
We're going to talk about
these protection bits,
that you can only read certain parts
of memory, but you can write also.
So this attack, again, I want you
to read and maybe the details.
Here is not important.
But sort of think about it by exploiting
some vulnerability that is DRAM.
The way these DRAMs are designed,
someone is able to gain access to
the OS part of the memory and
change something just by doing reads.
The operating system doesn't stop
you because you just reading ertain
locations.
But those reads actually
have this other effect.
In particular, this undesirable effect
where they end up changing a bit,
flipping a bit in another
location in the operating system.
Which, sort of, again,
I I should say that this is not easy to
pull off you can obviously corrupt or
affect integrity of that location but
to change it exactly the way you want to
do this idea of again privileges
that you didn't have.
For is quite challenging.
Again this is reported attack.
If your OS is written in
low level language so
it performs reasonable whatever it is.
Typically not type safe languages.
And if you're not careful you can have
buffer overflow possibilities too.
Buffer overflow means you can
alter the return address.
Maybe you can insert some code that
you can transfer control to and
that is going to lead to exploitation
of the operating system.
And you're in the operating system
running your code, that hacker's code,
and you can do whatever
changes you want to do.
Of course the isolation
is lost in that case.
So there are instances of
attacks like this too.