Hi there.
>> Hi, and welcome to our
course on building scaleable
applications in Python.
>> My name is Magnus, and I work at
Google, with cloud technologies.
>> And I'm Karl,
I'm a course developer at Udacity.
>> Together we will teach you how
to build great applications that
run on Google infrastructure.
And that can scale.
>> And scale.
>> Because at Google people really do
know how to build scalable systems.
>> That's right and after this
course you will also be able to
write scalable applications that
run in the Google data centers.
I will be teaching you the theory
behind building scalable applications.
>> And I'll be showing you how
to implement them in Python.
So with that why don't we get
right into our first lesson.