First let's look at the device
experience from a user's perspective.
If I prefer to use a different language,
I can go into the Settings app and
then tap on the Language and
Input setting.
If I tap on Language,
then I see the whole list of languages
that are supported on Android.
It includes character based
languages like Chinese, and
left to right languages like Arabic.
I'm going to change
the language to Spanish.
And just like that, all the text
is now showing up in Spanish.
You can see this across
the whole settings app.
If you check the other apps on the
device, those will appear in Spanish if
the developer chose to
support that language.
However, when you open
up our Just Java app,
it's a drawing experience because
everything in this app is still in
English, while the other apps
on the device are in Spanish.
So how do we make our
App support Spanish?