So, if you look this up using your
favorite search engine or online
encyclopedia or other reference work,
these are the answers you should find.
A CNAME record is what's used to make
an alias from one name to another, and
it actually stands for canonical name.
It means that the canonical or
official name for this name is
actually something else it's an alias.
Now an AAAA record is the IPv6
equivalent of an a record.
It's an address,
it's just an IPv6 address.
The name is kind of a joke,
since v6 addresses are four
times longer than v4 addresses.
That's how I always think of this.
And lastly,
the NS record type is a DNS name server.
An NS record for
a particular domain says
what DNS servers have the records for
that domain.