Let's continue exploring this idea of using filters as
templates of what we want to find in two dimensions.
Okay?
So a template is a thing that you give me and
you say I want you to find something else that looks like this and
we're going to do that through a filtering.
And here's a nice example courtesy of Christian Grumman as well I believe.
Although I'm not sure she made, if that's one these,
by the way this is early in the class.
You're going to see a lot of slides that have somebody's name next to them,
because I've got them, the.
And then what I later discovered is,
many of these slides came from other people, and from other people.
So the name that I put down is the name that I was able to track it towards.
And the rest of us on the internet we're just making our way.
All right.
So, here's a very simple example.
So here we have a scene on the left and we've got this template on the right.
All right? So this is the think that we want to find.
And you look over here and
you say, oh I see where it is it's, it's, it's, it's right over here.
So what we would like is our system to spit out something like this.
Say aha, here's my little green box.
Well what we can do is we can actually do this through a normalized correlation.
If I take that masked kernel template and
I do a normalized correlation with the image on the left, what I get is a map or
correlation image that looks like this.
Okay?
And you'll notice.
That, where black lies over black and
white lies over white, you can think of that as positive and
negative, so I get some brightness over here and some brightness over here.
But my really bright spot is right there
because that's the template having landed in the right place.
So that's how you use correlation in order to do this detection because now
we're thinking of filters not so much as doing an averaging or
a blurring but actually being a template that we're looking for.