Let's get started using Tag Manager.
The place to go is
tagmanager.google.com.
If you already have
a Tag Manger account,
you'll see a list of your accounts.
But if you don't, you'll see a screen
where you can create an account.
This UI has tabs at the top,
pretty much like the Analytics UI did.
We're currently in the Admin UI.
Enter your account name,
whatever you want your
Tag Manager account to be called.
Choose whether you want to share
benchmarking data anonymously.
If you opt in, then the data that
you collect through analytics and
tag manager will be shared anonymously
and used to create benchmarks,
and you'll be able to
see those benchmarks.
During testing,
I won't share my data, but
later on, my apps when they go
into productions, then I will.
Anyway, continue.
Set up your container.
Choose Android, obviously.
Give it a name.
And
we're using this container to
contain our daily specials, so
this name doesn't actually need
to match anything in your code.
It's helpful to name your container
in a way that helps you
remember what's in it.
All right, then Create.
Accept the terms and
the container is ready to be used.
Ok.
Good with that.
So now I notice that we're
in the Container tab.
And up here on the top left, next to the
app name, you'll see your account ID.
Okay, take a minute now to create
your Google TagManager account.
Okay, I'm going to redo the quiz.
So go to tagmanager.google.com.
Create an account for android obviously.
Create a container.
Check the boxes as you go and
when you're done, tell us what your
account ID is by entering it here.