So far we've been using a generic
UIViewController for our second scene.
Remember this view where you set the
background color? Now UIViewController
it's a great class, but we
can't add any code to it directly.
In order to do audio playback, we need a
UIViewController subclass that we can
add our code to. I’m going to show you how
to create this new class which will call
the PlaySoundsViewController. In the
Navigator panel, let's right-click the
PitchPerfect folder and go to New File.
Make sure iOS is selected and then
select the Cocoa Touch Class and click Next.
For the class name, let's set it to
PlaySoundsViewController and set it
to be a subclass of UIViewController.
And make sure the Also create XIB file
is unselected and the language is Swift.
And then click Next. Here we just make
sure that the file were created as part
of our project PitchPerfect and that
it's selected as one of the targets and
click Create. Now we can see our
PlaySoundsViewController in the Navigator
panel. There's one more step,
the storyboard doesn't know that we want
to use this file for the second
View Controller.
Let's walk through changing that. Back in
the Main.storyboard file, select the
second View Controller, then in the
inspector panel, go to the identity
inspector which has the icon that looks
like the ID card. In the drop-down for
class, let's select PlaySoundsViewController.
Make sure you press Enter for
it to take effect. And that's it, now
storyboard knows how to use the new
PlaySoundsViewController class
instead of just the generic
UIViewController