So the answer you can see
here in Android Studio.
First of all,
I create a GeofencingEvent object.
And I'm going to use the GeofencingEvent
abstract class with its
fromIntent method, passing it my
intent to get the GeofencingEvent.
Then once I have the GeofencingEvent,
it has an hasError property, so
I can say if geofencingEvent.hasError(),
do something.
I'm creating a string
called errorMessage, and
I'm using the geofencingEvent's
getErrorCode method
to create the error string out of that.
Now you'll notice here I have
GeofenceErrorMessages.getErrorString,
and this creates the string for me.
Now you may not find this class
anywhere in the documentation
because this is one that
I actually built myself.
And you can see it in here.
So the GeofenceErrorMessages
class is just a simple class
that converts an error code from
the GeofenceStatusCodes into a string.
So for example, Geofence not available.
There are too many Geofences registered.
There are too many
PendingIntents registered.
Each of these status codes has
a friendly string that we can associate
with it, and then that friendly string
will be returned to the caller.
So that's how we get our
onHandleIntent started.
We get our GeofencingEvent.
We check if it has an error.
If it doesn't have an error,
we'll continue.
If it does have one, we'll log it and
then just return out of this
function and end right there.