I would say that it depends on what you actually mean by square and rectangle.
So, if you define a square as a rectangle with both sides equal, then square is,
in fact, a specialization of rectangle.
That is, rectangle is the parent class, and square is the child class.
If you defined square as a class having one attribute,
which is the length of a side, and one method, for example, to compute the area.
And, if you define rectangle as having two sides,
that is an additional attribute, one for the height and one for the width.
Then every rectangle is, in fact, a square, in the sense that it has all of
the attributes the square does, and has all the methods a square does.
So, this case, we would say that the square is the general class, and
the rectangle is the child class.
The point being, you have to be a little careful what you mean by these classes,
in order to decide who's the parent and who's the child.