We will first look at the boss-workers pattern.
This is a popular pattern that's characterized by one boss thread and
then some number of worker threads.
The boss is in charge of assigning work to the workers, and the workers
are responsible for performing the entire task that's assigned to them.
Concerning our toy shop example, that means that the very first step,
the step where we accept an order will be performed by the boss.
The boss will accept an order and
then immediately pass it on to one of the workers.
Each of the workers will perform steps two through six, so
we'll parse the order, cut the pieces, stain the pieces, and
assemble the wooden toy and ultimately ship the order.
Since we only have one boss thread that must execute on
every single piece of work that arrives in the system, it means that
the throughput of the system overall is limited by the boss' performance.
Specifically, the throughput of the system is inversely proportional to
the amount of time the boss spends on each order.
So, clearly, that means that we must keep the boss efficient if we
want to make sure that the system overall is performing well.
In our toy shop example, the boss thread just picks up
an order from the customer and immediately passes it to the workers.
It doesn't really look to see what it's for.
That's why each of the workers starts with step two.
So in that way we're trying to limit the amount of
operation that's required from the boss on each order.
So how does the boss pass work to one of the workers?
One way is for the boss to keep track of exactly which workers are free, and
then hand off work to those workers.
So, it's specifically signalling one particular worker.
This means that now the boss will have to do more for each order,
because now it has to keep track of which of the workers are available.
And will also have to wait for that particular worker to accept
the order from the boss when, when its being passed, sort of like a handshake.
The positive of this approach is that the workers don't need to
synchronize amongst each other in any way.
The boss will tell them what they need to do, and
they don't have to care about what the other workers do.
The downside, however, is that given that the boss now has to keep track of
what the workers are doing, the throughput of the system will go down.
Another option is to establish a queue between the boss and the workers.
This could be similar to a producer/consumer queue, where the boss is
the only producer that produces work requests, so toy orders for the workers.
And then the workers are the consumers that are picking up work from this queue,
picking up orders from this queue and
then proceeding with the steps that they need to perform.
The upside of this approach is that the boss now doesn't really need to
know about what each worker is doing and whether it's free.
It also doesn't have to wait for a worker to explicitly do,
a handshake when it's passing off a work item to one of them.
The boss just accepts an order, so performs steps one, places the order on
the shared queue, and can go back to picking up the next order.
Whenever one of the worker becomes free, it looks into the queue,
at the front of the queue ideally, and picks up any pending work requests.
The downside is that now the workers, as well as the workers and the boss
amongst each other, have to synchronize their accesses to the shared queue.
All of the worker threads may contend to gain access to the front of the queue,
and any one work item can only be assigned to one worker thread.
And also the workers and the boss may need to synchronize when they need
to compare the front and the end pointer of this queue, for instance,
when they need to determine that a queue is full or that a queue is empty.
Despite of this downside, this approach of using a shared queue
among the boss and the workers when passing work among them,
still results in lower time per order that the boss needs to spend.
So it results in better throughput of the system overall.
So that's why we tend to pick this particular model
when a building multithread applications using this pattern