So, let's look at these
set of parameters.
This is, in essence,
referred to as the Plenoptic Function.
The Plenoptic Function is, in essence,
equivalent to putting a sensor, an eye,
a pinhole camera, any point in
the world, and measuring at that point,
which, of course, the location of
that point is Vx, y, and z, Vz.
Recording the intensity of the rays
of light with wavelength at any time,
and basically, at all possible angles.
Again, the bundle of rays of light
around Vz, or in terms of x, y, and z.
So, that's what we are interested in,
and this is basically,
what a Plenoptic Function is.
It's a concept that was introduced
by Adelson and Bergan in 1991,
look at the paper,
if you want more details please.
Just to be specific, the term Plenoptic,
is a Latin word, which kind of
merges the words plenus and optic,
and in essence, again, it's basically,
is capturing the light traveling in
every direction in a given space.
This allows us to kind of start
thinking of the Plenoptic, or
a Light field camera that basically
says, that at any point in the world
we can capture a light field, and
render pixels from that as needed.
So, now actually rather than converting
pixels right away, we want to
capture a lot more information about
the Light field at that point, and
then we can render pixels
whenever we need to.