[Thrun] So this is a difficult question.
Let me compute an auxiliary variable, which is P of happiness.
That one is expanded by looking at the different conditions that can make us happy.
P of happiness given S and R
times P of S and R, which is of course the product of those 2
because they are independent,
plus P of happiness given not S R, probability of not as R
plus P of H given S and not R
times the probability of P of S and not R plus the last case,
P of H given not S and not R.
So this just looks at the happiness under all 4 combinations of the variables
that can lead to happiness.
And you can plug those straight in.
This one over here is 1, and this one over here is the product of S and R,
which is 0.7 times 0.01.
And as you plug all of those in,
you get as a result 0.5245.
That's P of H.
Just take some time and do the math by going through these different cases
using total probability, and you get this result.
Armed with this number, the rest now becomes easy,
which is we can use Bayes' rule to turn this around.
P of H given R times P of R over P of H.
P of R we know from over here, the probability of a raise is 0.01.
So the only thing we need to compute now is P of H given R.
And again, we apply total probability.
Let me just do this over here.
We can factor P of H given R as P of H given R and S, sunny,
times probability of sunny plus P of H given R and not sunny
times the probability of not sunny.
And if you plug in the numbers with this, you get 1 times 0.7
plus 0.9 times 0.3.
That happens to be 0.97.
So if we now plug this all back into this equation over here,
we get 0.97 times 0.01 over 0.5245.
This gives us approximately as the correct answer 0.0185.