What if you did the following?
Consider each sink.
If the sink is at the end of an edge
that goes from a parent to a child,
then that means you're
descending into the tree.
So, let's put a +1 at those sinks.
Intuitively, the +1 signal
an increase in the level count.
The remaining sinks terminate edges
that go from a child to a parent.
Those nodes correspond
to decreasing the level.
So let's place -1 values at them.
To see if this works,
let's run a list scan.
Notice that as you descend,
you pick up +1 values.
And as you ascend,
you pick up -1 values.
So now to get the final result, we just
need to keep all the starred nodes.
If you do that,
this is what you should get.