The answer is sqrt(P)+2.
Let's take an edge,
I don't know, how about this one?
Let's see which logical edges
map to this physical edge.
There are square root of P edges
that come from the matching edge
as well as all of these vertical edges,
but that's not all.
There are also these
pesky wraparound edges.
This wraparound edge
corresponds to this path.
And what about the other
wraparound edge?
The shortest path for
this wraparound edge would start here,
go along the first row,
down this wraparound edge in the ring,
and back across the bottom row.
So notice that it also
has to touch this edge.
So the wraparound edges give me the + 2.
If you were off by one or two, the
auto-grader should have forgiven you.
Asymptotically, the important point
is that congestion grows by square
root of P.