Let's being by loading up our core scene
called Udacity Monitor Department.
First, go to your assets folder.
Then go to the Udacity
Monitor Department folder and
double click on it.
Then double click on scenes and
then double click on the Udacity
monitor department scene.
It's the one with the Unity logo.
Great, now for starters,
let's create a new material.
Go to the Project pane and
select the Assets directory,
then click the Create button.
And inside of here you'll see kinds of
assets you can create inside of Unity.
Go ahead and select Material, and
then give your material a new name.
So I'm going to call mine,
my new material.
Okay, this material represents
a thing called a shader and
its associated settings.
We'll talk more about shaders later.
For now, just know that they're
programs responsible for
creating the final images
shown on your VR headset.
Over here,
you can see the materials properties and
you'll see all kinds of options.
These are all the options for
Unity standard shader.
And, we'll talk about it
more later in the course.
For now,
let's just test out the albedo property.
Unless you've worked with
physically based rendering,
you're probably wondering
what albedo means.
The albedo parameter defines how
light changes when it gets reflected
by a surface.
For example, white lights falls on
to my shirt and comes back blue.
That's the albedo parameter,
the shirt material.
For now, just think of the albedo
as the material's main color.
Okay, go ahead and
change the albedo to a bright red color
by first clicking on this white box and
then selecting a nice red color.
Okay, go ahead and
close the color picker.
Now, we're going to assign this red
material to the apartment's floor and
walls.
Go ahead and drag and drop your new
material onto the apartment floor.
Okay, we have a really really red room.
Maybe let's dial it back a little.
Go back to your material and
change the albedo to a bright pink.
There, that's better-ish.
Maybe white walls weren't so
bad after all.
Anyway, now you know one way to create
materials and assign them to objects.