If you haven't downloaded the Color
Maker Project yet, go ahead and
do that now.
You'll find it in the instructor notes.
Then when you open the project in Xcode,
you'll notice that the code inside
the view controller is
already written for you.
Have a close look at this
change color component action.
You can see that it uses all four of
the outlets that are used in this app.
All in this one method.
Let's see what happens
when we run the app.
There are switches, they look okay, but
they're not actually doing anything.
I can't say that's all that surprising.
Because if you look here you can see
that none of these outlets are actually
connected.
If you look at these circles
in the left margin, I mean.
Connect the actions and
outlets in Color Maker and
choose the option that best
describes your experience.