Now let's create a new view controller,
make it the initial view controller and
then flip it to horizontal
orientation and preview.
Now, let's add two labels.
So both views have the same
compression resistance.
And put some pretty long
text in both of them.
It shouldn't fit in
portrait orientation.
And then we'll stack them.
The last thing we need to do is to add
there constraints to the stack view.
I will do this by using
the constraint button,
the one that looks like a TIE fighter.
At the three constraints and
oddly enough, the Stack View remains
in its position instead of the position
that our constraints are telling you to.
To add insult to your injury,
the compiler yells at us that the frames
will be different at runtime.
So what on Earth is going on?
This is one of the most common and
frustrating errors you
will get with auto layout.
But it's actually pretty easy to fix.
We told auto layout that the stack
view should be glued to the top,
little left, and the right side.
Is it?
No.
Will it be in run time?
You bet.
This discrepancy is what
XCode is complaining about.
You could say that XCode could
have updated the preview
to match the constraints.
I certainly agree.
Unfortunately, sometimes it doesn't.
This is pretty easy to fix by using
the pop up menu of the warning.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Select Update Frames, so the frames
in the preview match the Constraints.
Fix misplacement, and
now that it's fixed we see
the same behavior as before.
Whenever a view's intrinsic
content size must be changed
if all the compression
resistances are the same,
the one that is changed is
the first one from the left.
That's why this one as its size change
from its intrinsic content size,
while this one keeps its
intrinsic content size.
So what if that's not what you want?