As you may have started to see in other
apps, there are plenty of different ways
to inform the user that there may
be a problem with connectivity.
The material design spec offers some
guidelines on how to present this type
of error to the user, with an example
in the email app and the search app.
In the last coding task of this lesson,
and
of this course, we'll introduce logic to
check if there is network connectivity
before we initialize the loader
to kick off the request.
Now, if there isn't
internet connectivity,
then we'll change the empty state text
view to show a no internet connection
error message, like in this screen shot.
Now I'm providing you with a link to
this developer guide on how to connect
to the network and
check for connectivity.
Now one more really important
note here at the top of the doc,
you'll also need to declare another
permission in the Android manifest file
to access the network state,
as you an see here.
So make sure you add this
line to your manifest.
Once, you've completed
the first two tasks,
then test your app to make
sure it works with and
without internet connectivity
by using airplane mode again.
Now, remember the force stop
the app in between tests, so
that the activities is destroyed and
created again from scratch.
You can do this by swiping
app off the recent list