Now it's time to use your app and
see the usage data show
up in Google Analytics.
You can use the emulator in Android
Studio or your own Android device.
It's okay to use the emulator, but
it might not send data back
what device it's emulating.
I like to use a real device.
Make sure your device is
connected to Android Studio, and
click the Run button to run your app.
Make sure the app's running
on your phone, or tablet, or
whatever you're using.
Then click through to
a few different screens.
Make sure to switch the phone between
portrait and landscape, a few times too.
Okay, as you do these tasks,
go ahead and check the boxes.
Make sure, of course,
that your project compiles.
Make sure you went to some
different activities and
check here when you're done.
Then go ahead and
try the app in both orientations.
Do it in portrait and in landscape mode.
We're doing this so that we can
get the different orientations and
screen sizes to show
up in the dashboard.