To learn more about running tasks in
the background, notifications, and
scheduling jobs,
you'll be working on a hydration app.
Fun fact,
about sixty percent of you is water.
In fact, your brain, which thus far has
hopefully been pretty important for
getting you through this course,
is about seventy three percent water.
The Hydration Reminder app makes sure
you're getting enough water, and
avoiding the common health
consequences of dehydration.
Like headache, dizziness, or
not being able to shed a tear
when your tests aren't passing.
It works by sending you a reminder
notification to drink water every 15
minutes when your phone is charging.
Why?
Because when your phone is charging,
you're more likely to be stationary, and
by water.
Speaking of which.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay, so to start us off
let's learn about services.