[Narrator] Let me give a much simpler example
often called grid world for MDPs,
and I'll be using this insanely simple
example over here throughout this class.
Let's assume we have a starting state over here,
and there's 2 goal states who
are often called absorbing states
with very different reward or payout.
Plus 100 for the state over here,
minus 100 for the state over here,
and our agent is able to move about the environment,
and when it reaches one of those 2 states,
the game is over and the task is done.
Obviously the top state is much more attractive than the bottom state with minus 100.
Now to turn this into an MDP, let's assume
actions are somewhat stochastic.
So suppose we had a grid cell, and we attempt to go north.
The deterministic agent would always succeed
to go to the north square if it's available,
but let's assume that we only have an 80% chance
to make it to the cell in the north.
If there's no cell at all,
there's a wall like over here,
we assume with 80% chance, we just bounce back to the same cell,
but with 10% chance, we instead go left.
Another 10% chance, we go right.
So if an agent is over here and wishes to go north,
then with 80% chance, it finds itself over here,
10% over here, 10% over here.
If it goes north from here,
because there's no north cell,
it'll bounce back with 80% probability,
10% left, 10% right.
In a cell like this one over here,
it'll bounce back with 90% probability,
80 from the top and 10 from the left,
but it still has a 10% chance of going right.
This is a stochastic state transition which
we can equally define for actions,
south, west and east, and
now we can see a situation like this
conventional planning is insufficient.
So for example if you're plan a sequence of actions starting over here,
you might go north, north, east, east, east
to reach our plus 100 absorbing or final state,
but with this state transition model over here,
even with the first step it might happen with 10% chance do you find yourselves over here,
in which case conventional planning would not give us an answer.
So we wish to have a planning method that provides an answer no matter where we are
and that's called a policy.
A policy assigns actions to any state.
So for example a policy might look as follows:
for this state, we wish to go north, north, east, east, east,
but for this state over here, we wish to go north, maybe east over here,
and maybe west over here.
So each state, except for the absorbing states,
we have to define an action to define a policy.
The planning problem we have becomes one of finding the optimal policy