Let me show you how you track out some
compute-based performance problems
in your apps.
For this demo,
we're going to hook up the Sunshine
application with a profiling tool
called Traceview.
Let's go ahead and load it up.
>> First, make sure,
your device is connected.
And then, start the application
you want to profile.
In this case, we'll bring up Sunshine.
Okay.
And now,
let's hop back to Android Studio.
And in order to access
the trace view tool,
we're going to want to start
the Android Device Monitor.
Now, you can either do that
through the Tools menu by
going to Tools > Android and
Android Device Monitor.
Or you can click this little
green guy here up at the Toolbar
in the Android Studio IDE.
So I'm going to go ahead and
click this button.
Okay.
So once Android Device Monitor is up and
loaded, make sure you come over here and
check your tabs and
make sure that the DDMS tab is selected.
Then you'll want to hop over
here to your Devices pane and
select the activity that
you want to profile.
We're going to go ahead and
check Sunshine.
Okay, so now I want to draw
your attention to some
icons here in the taskbar.
Particularly this one right here,
that looks like three arrows
with a red dot on top of it.
This is the button that we can press
that has a little tooltip that says
start method profiling.
This is how we invoke Trace View.
Let's go ahead and click it.
You'll get a pop-up with two
ways of profiling your app.
You can either record every method's
entry and exit which is very resource
intensive down here, or
you can do some sample based profiling.
What that means is by default a profile
is going to ping your application
every one millisecond to find out and
record what function is
actually being executed.
So let's go ahead and
use the default settings.
I am going to go ahead and click OK.
So now that the profile is recording,
let's go ahead and
interact with our application and
see if we can profile some actions.
So I want to hop over here and
interact with Sunshine a little bit.
Oh, nice.
Some pretty good weather here in
Mountainview.
Unfortunately not so
good coming up this weekend.
Looks like we have some rain in store.
But, why don't we go down the coast and
see how our friends are doing
in Southern California?
Oh, weird.
They've got a strange winter,
very untypical of San Diego.
How about we check on
our friends in Texas.
All right, well maybe a little
bit more warmer weather, there.
68 and clear.
Not too bad tomorrow.
All right.
So let's go back to
Android Device Monitor,
where we want to stop our profiling.
Now we can do so by clicking the same
icon that we did to start it.
It's got this black icon or black square
on top of it now so let's go ahead and
stop our profiling by clicking on it.
Now, it might take a few
moments to load the trace.
Which is going to show up here in
the tab at the top of your window.
Just keep in mind it might take a little
longer depending on how much recording
you actually did.
All right.
Let's, so let's talk about trace view.
Now trace view has two
main components to it.
It's got this top panel here
called the typeline panel and
then it's got this bottom panel
with a lot of information.
It's called the profile panel.
Now the timeline is great in showing you
how your code is executing over time.
Each row that's shown here in the,
in display,
actually corresponds to a thread, and
each color that's displayed corresponds
to a particular method that's running.
So for example here we have all
the activity on our main thread.
And we can, we can see spikes when
methods were being started and stopped.
What's even more useful
is we can zoom down and
we can try to figure out particular
methods and how they're behaving.
They kind of show up in these U shapes.
With the left bar here that denotes
when the method is actually starting and
then another bar here on the right
which actually denotes when the method
is finishing.
And the width of the bar actually
represents how much time it took for
that method to be executed.
Now let's go ahead and
select the particular method.
Let's hop down here to the bottom
of the trace view window and
here we're going to look at some
profiling data that shows up.
Particularly, we get some
information about what methods
actually called the one
that we've selected,
which are represented by their
parents in this blue highlight here.
And we actually get some additional
information about which methods
are actually called within this one.
So, in other words we called
dispatch input event method
with a native pole once which is
what is selected at the moment.
And for each of these methods that we
have selected we get a whole lot of
additional statistical information.
For example,
we have the exclusive CPU time.
This is the time that's
spent in our method itself.
And we can use it to find specific
issues for that particular method.
Now the inclusive CPU time is for
the particular method and
all the methods it calls internally.
This can help you find problems within
the individual indication tree for
the method that you selected.
Oh, and another really useful statistic
is how many times the method was called
or called itself recursively.
We can find this information
if we scroll to the right and
we've got this column here
called calls and recursion.
Again, that measures how many
times the method was called or
how many times it was
called recursively.
Now there's a whole lot of additional
information here in this profile panel.
And if you don't have a really big
display it's kind of hard to see.
So you have to do some
scrolling back and
forth to kind of find
the metrics that you care about.
And don't forget this little nifty
search box that can help you kind of
zoom in on the functions
that you care about.
Okay so that's a little trace for
you let's go ahead and
use it on some real code