In fact, to make it easy to use these
as building blocks for your algorithms,
let's define some pseudocode interfaces.
Suppose every process has
a private array of size n.
To perform a vector reduce on all of
those arrays you would just write this.
Every process needs to call this reduce,
supplying as input its private array,
along with the ID of the root process.
This operation will
perform the reduction.
It will leave the final output on
the process whose rank is root.
And that result will be
in root's private array.
Now, this operation is called a
collective, meaning that your algorithm
or program must be structured in such
a way that all processes execute it.
Let me show you what I mean.
Here's an example of a program.
Remember, all processes are executing
this program concurrently.
Notice that only the process whose rank
is 0 will actually call the reduce.
None of the other processes call reduce.
So this program is actually invalid and
its behavior would be
essentially to deadlock.
Put another way, this program hangs
because rank zero starts to reduce but
not other process does.
So that leaves rank zero hanging.
Here's a different example program.
What is its output if there are say,
P = 3 processes?
Say initially we have 3 processes.
Each one initializes its local
private array with its RANK+1.
Then all processes enter the reduce.
Notice that the root is
the process whose rank is 1.
So the final result
should appear on rank 1.
So after the reduce,
the result should look like this.
A_local is unmodified on ranks 0 and
ranks 2.
The final output appears on the root.
Okay, let's move on.
For a broadcast, the dual of reduce,
I want you to assume this signature.
The process whose rank is root will have
the initial data in its local buffer.
When the broadcast completes,
every process will have the same
data in its local buffer.
So for a gather,
I want you to assume this signature.
Remember that in a gather,
everybody has a little piece of data and
you want to collect all
the data on one process.
So every process has an input
buffer of size little m.
The output is all m buffers from all
processes collected on the root.
Notice that the output
buffer is two-dimensional.
Now the output buffer need only
be defined on the root process.
So what does that mean?
That means in your algorithm,
when everybody calls gather,
output is only valid on root.
In fact, you can assume that the other
processes have no output buffer,
unless the algorithm needs it for
some reason.
Now notice I've used the symbol
little m instead of little n.
The reason is so that when you do
analysis, I want you to assume that
our usual problem-sized variable,
n, is defined to be m times p.
That is the size of the combined output.
This is basically just saying that we
always want to assume that p divides n.
Of course, in a real message passing
library there will be ways to send
variable amounts of data per process.
Now the dual of the gather, or
a scatter, looks essentially the same.
The difference is that the input is of
size m times P defined on the root.
Finally, we come to allGather and
reduce scatter.
Here's allGather.
Note that there's no
concept of a root rank.
The allGather essentially replicates
the input buffer everywhere.
Now reduceScatter is the same
as an allGather just going in
the other direction.
So in particular,
the dimensions on the input and
output buffers are reversed
relative to allGather.
Now we've been using these
two-dimensional objects, so
I want to introduce one
more useful primitive.
It's called a reshape.
It has two forms.
One takes a two-dimensional input and
produces a one-dimensional output.
The other goes from 1-D to 2-D.
This primitive is a purely logical
operation, rather than a physical one.
By that, I mean it doesn't actually
copy a 2-D object to a 1-D array.
It just says that it changes
the interface of the object so
that you can start viewing it and
operating on it as if it were 1-D.
In fact, if you're familiar with
multi-dimensional arrays in
languages like C and C++,
you know a dense multi-dimensional
array always maps to a linear
address base anyway.
As such you can assume
it has constant cost.
Just to be concrete, here's a picture
of going from a logical 2-D
representation to a logical
1-D representation.
The convention I'll use linearizes
the 2-D array column by column.
This is sometimes called
column major storage.