Here's an example of tracking
the predict update cycle.
And this is in a world in which
the actions are guaranteed to work
as advertised.
That is, if you suck,
you clean up the current location, and
if you move right or left, the wheels
actually turn and you do move.
But, we can call this the kindergarten
world because there are little
toddlers walking around who can deposit
dirt in any location at any time.
So, if we start off in this state,
and execute the suck action,
we can predict that we'll up
in one of these two states.
Then if we have an observation,
well we know what that
observation's going to be.
Because we known the suck action always
works, and we know we were in A.
So the only observation we can get is
that we're in A and that it's clean,
we end up in that same belief state.
And then if we execute the right action,
well then lots of things could happen.
Because we move right and somebody
might have dropped dirt in the right
location and somebody might have dropped
dirt in the left location or maybe not.
And so
we end up with four possibilities, and
then we can update again when
we get the next observation.
Say if we observed that plan B and
it's dirty then we end
up in this belief state.
And we can keep on going,
specifying new belief states as result
of successive predicts and updates.
Now, this predict update cycle gives
us a kind of calculus of belief states.
That can tell us really
everything we need to know.
But there is one weakness with this
approach, is that as you can see here,
some of the belief states
start to get large.
And this is a tiny little world,
already we have a belief state
with four world states in it.
We could have one with 8,16,1024,
whatever.
And it seems that there maybe more
fixing representations of a belief state
rather than to just list
all the role states.
For example, take this one here.
If we have divided the world up not
into individual world states but
into variables describing that state.
Then this whole belief state
could be represented just by
vacuum is on the right.
So the whole world could be represented
by three states or three variables.
One, where is the vacuum?
Is it on the right or not?
Secondly, is there dirt
in the left location?
And third,
is there dirt in the right location?
And we can add some formula over
those variables to describe states.
And with that type of formulation
some very large states, in terms
of enumerating the world states, can be
made small in terms of the description.