When you unzipped that zipped file,
did you notice that zip prints out
all the things it's extracting?
Let's take another look at
the output of the unzip command.
Scroll up through it.
Oh, hey look at this.
One of the files that it extracted is
called .secret, starting with a dot.
But when we ran ls we
don't see that file.
In fact, ls by default doesn't list any
files whose names start with a dot.
This is because files with names
starting with dot are often used on
Linux for caching and
configuration and other things that
you don't normally care about.
So the shell will hide them by default
because they're not usually interesting.
But there is an option to ls
to make it display them too.
To find out,
look in the manual page for ls.
It may take some searching around.
So using the manual, find out how you
can list all the items in a directory,
including the ones whose
names start with dot.
Put the command you found here.