I'm going to show you the process I
went through to solve this problem.
You can also find the final version of
my code in the instructor notes in case
you'd like to take a closer look.
The code should look pretty similar for
each file.
So first I'm going to copy
the codes that I used before.
Then I'll paste the code twice, and
I'll need to change the file
names into the variable names.
So this should be doing engagement.csv,
this should be projectsubmissions.csv,
I'll name this variable daily engagement
and this one one project submissions.
Then I'll go ahead and
print out one row of each and
since I want to print just one row in
the cell, I've used print statements.
This worked, but anytime you find
yourself copying and pasting code or
just writing two pieces of
code that are very similar,
it might be a good idea to
write a function instead.
That way, if you find a bug later,
you'll only have to fix it in one place.
In this case, the only thing that
changed between these three blocks of
code was the file name and
the variable name.
So I'm going to write
a function named read_csv that
takes the file name as an input and
then returns the list of rows.
I'll use this code that I've already
written as my starting point.
Then instead of the file name here,
I'll use the input that I took and
instead of creating a variable,
I'll return the list.
Now I can delete these two blocks.
And call the function three times.
Now I'll run the code again just
to check that it still works.
Since this function is so
short, it's debatable whether
writing it was helpful.
But I'm happy I wrote it.
For example, if I hadn't realized
I needed to open the file with
the argument rb, and
then later I noticed that I needed it.
I could have updated this function,
rather than updating the code
in three separate places.