Let me show you the solution
that we came up with.
We start by using this
series of guard statements.
First we check that no
error's been returned.
And then we check to see if we have
a status code that begins with 200 here.
And then we check if
the data is not nil here.
Now I know some of these guard
statements are a little redundant.
If we remember the documentation
it says that if the error is nil,
then we're guaranteed to have the data,
or if the data is nil then we're
guaranteed to have an error.
But we decided to put each of these
guard statements in here just to be
extra clear about what's going on.
So if we pass all these
guard statements,
then we use
the NSJSONSerialization class
to convert the data into
a dictionary that we can use.
Next, we start checking for those key
value pairs that we're interested in.
Remember, the response that we
expect looks something like this.
We have this top level
photos dictionary, and
within photos we have the photo, which
is the array of photo dictionaries.
And we also have this stack key
that gives us some indication
of how the response went.
And what we want to do is select
a random photo out of this array, and
then we want to get its title and
the url_m values.
So back in the code,
the first thing we actually check for
is that stat key value pair.
We want to make sure that the status,
stat, is okay.
And you don't have to do this,
this is just an implementation detail
that we like for extra security I guess.
Then we get the top level
photosDictionary and we also get
the photosArray, which remember, is the
array of individual photo dictionaries.
We also make one more check here.
We want to see if the number of photo
dictionaries, the account of the photos
array, is equal to 0, because then we
know that the search returned no images.
And we account for that here.
Otherwise we go ahead and generate
a random index, so our randomPhotoIndex.
And then we can use that to select
a random photoDictionary, here.
With our random photoDictionary chosen,
we get the title,
and then we get the url_m, that string.
And then we can use them to make
our UI updates inside of this
performUIUpdatesOnMain.
So this all looks pretty good.
And we'll give it a shot.
And let's search for something sweet,
I'm going to search for
my wife's favorite, French macaroon.
Yummy.
This is quite the search image.
We have have a macaroon and
we have typography, how fancy.
Now at this point we're almost
done with Flick Finder,
but there's one more
optimization that we can make.
We'll look at this next.