The last bit left in our app
is to be able to remove guests
when they've been seated.
We've decided to use the swipe
off feature in Android
to make this a cool experience.
So, let's see how to build
this feature step by step.
This is the last exercise for
this toy app, remove guests.
The first to do is to go
into the main activity and
create a method called removeGuest.
This method would handle removing
a specific record from a database.
It takes an ID of type long as an input
and simply returns a boolean to indicate
the success or
failure of the remove operation.
Inside, all we need to do
is to call the mDb.delete.
To delete something from the database,
you need to specify the table name as
the first argument and something called
the where clause as the second argument.
A where clause is simply a string
that defines a condition for
the row to be effected.
It usually starts with a column
name which you can always get from
the contract and then a comparison sign,
in our case just a simple equals sign,
and then the value to compare against.
Because here we just
want to delete one row,
which is namely the row
with that specific ID.
So our where clause is simply the column
ID is equal to the value of the ID
that was passed into this method.
The last argument which
we've just passed null for
helps creating more
complicated where clauses.
But it's not required for such a simple
delete query that we have here.
But feel free to check out
the Android documentation to find out
more about the delete operation.
Like, for example, we can now find
out from the documentation that
the delete returns the number
of rows successfully removed.
Which means we can use that to find
out if our delete worked or not.
We can simply check that the delete
operation returned a value larger than 0
and then just return the boolean
result of this comparison.
So if we did delete one row
which is larger than 0,
remove guest will return true.
Now let's move to the cool part.
To handle the swipe actions in Android,
we need to create something
called ItemTouchHelper.
We'll do that in the onCreate
method in the MainActivity.
The ItemTouchHelper needs a callback
to trigger when an item gets swiped.
So we'll pass in a simple callback so in
the constructor we're passing a simple
callback that handles both left and
right side swipes.
The 0 over here refers
to dragging items.
Which we're not interested in this case.
Again, check out the Item TouchHelper
documentation if you want to know more
about that.
The simple callback however requires
us to override two methods.
Unmove, and unswiped.
We don't care a lot about unmove,
for now, so we just return false.
But for unswiped, we need to
extract the idea of the guest so
that we can delete
them from the database,
but we're never really got to
save the ID anywhere in the UI.
How can we tell which
guest are we swiping off?
Well let's go back to the UI and
fix that.
Let's open GuestListAdapter and
try to add the ID somewhere in the UI.
First we can just retrieve the ID
the same way we retrieve the name and
the party size,
except that we're going to use the get
long instead of get string or ent
because the ideas always of type long.
Then we can probably store
the ID in a text field but
we don't really want to display
the ID anywhere in our app.
That's why the recycler view offers
something called a tag object.
It's meant to store any data that
doesn't need to be displayed.
To do that we just call
the holder.itemview.settag.
And pass on the ID.
This will store the ID inside this
item view without displaying it.
Now lets' switch back
to our main activity.
And now inside on swiped we can actually
retrieve the ID from the item view tag,
pass that ID to the removeGuest method,
and
then refresh the list by
calling the swap cursor method.
And just like we did with the addGuests,
we just pass in the getAllGuests call
to the swap cursor to refresh
it with the new guest.
Now that we've created
the ItemTouchHelper,
we just need to attach
that to our RecyclerView.
We do that by calling
attachToRecyclerView and
passing which recycler view
we want to attach it to.
Okay, let's give this a try.
Now if we run our app and try to swipe
one of the names off, there you go.
It disappears on the RecyclerView and
it deletes it from the database.
Our app looks pretty cool now.
Feel free to add more features to it,
like maybe changing the background color
for guests who have
been waiting too long.
Or you could go as far as sending
a text message to guests when they
make it to the top of the wait list.
But now it's time to
work on our Sunshine app.