Now that you got a POJO,
you might be really eager to start
inserting items into your code.
But hold on a second,
lets talk about performance.
I want you to consider a couple of
different database organizations, or
data structure organizations that we
could use for shopping list items.
Here's one I'm going to
call Data Structure A.
We have our root, our active list,
and then here's the data for
each of our lists.
When we add items, we'll go ahead and
add them inside of each of these lists.
So, here are our lists of items
within our shopping lists.
So for example, this shopping list here
who's name is stored somewhere in here,
lets say Smores Supplies, has four
different items each with their name and
their owner, and this shopping list
has two items each with their name and
their owner and so on.
This basically has all
the information for
a shopping list bundled together in
nice little shopping list objects.
This organization matches what we're
used to when we think of Java objects.
You'd probably have an array list
of items within your Java shopping
list object.
Okay, let me show you something a little
bit different, here's Data Structure B.
It starts out pretty similar,
and then instead of storing items
as part of the shopping list,
we make an entirely new node.
Maybe call it something like
shopping list items, and
then store the items for
the shopping lists here, separately.
So, my question to you is,
which data structure is preferable.
All right, here are two data
structures side by side.
To analyze which of these data
structures is better, I want you to
take a look at the two main screens
that we have in our app right now.
This right here is
the ShoppingLists fragment screen.
And as you can see,
it has all of our shopping lists, and
then we have the active
list details screen, and
list details activity.
And this is of course, the activity
that will contain all the items on it,
as well as information
about specific lists.
Now, before you answer this question,
I want you to consider this fact.
Each time you grab a data snapshot,
it takes a picture of a specific
portion of the database.
If you take a picture
of active lists here,
it contains all of these active
lists and all the children nodes.
If you take a snapshot of push ID K6215,
it will also contain all of its
children, but none of these
other nodes or parent nodes.
When shopping list ++ hopefully
becomes very popular,
we're going to have a lot of shopping
list items and a lot of users, and
we want to minimize the data sent
between the server and the app.
So if you had to choose one of these
two data structures solely for
getting all the information
that you need for
the shopping list fragment screen,
would you choose A or B?
In the same way, if you had to pick
one of these two data structures for
active list details activity,
which one would you pick A or B?