So just to quickly summarize, I showed
you a variety of different videos
of a rather practical way of
actually combining cameras and
projectors together.
So basically, we are talking about
how we can actually take controlled
light sources and
couple them with a camera,
where the camera basically knows what
light is actually being displayed, and
actually can control it to figure out
what light actually should be displayed
in a different types of contexts and
scenes.
Basically, what we described was
projector camera system, or procams.
This is a growing discipline that's
actually been now actually getting a lot
of attention.
You saw examples of something
as practical as, you know,
controllable headlights for
cars to augmented reality experiences.
Again, the intention here was to
introduce to you this concept and
show you a variety of examples.
For further details basically look at
these papers that I'm listing here that
go through all aspects of how Light
Stage works to being able to then use
different types of ways of calibrating
cameras and projector systems.
And then also, going towards how we can
actually try out the kinds of systems
that we saw in some of the later videos.
I showed you a whole lot of videos,
and actually you can see all of them
on your own, in their full detail,
from these sites that actually will also
be presented to you with the lectures.