As we've used break points, there are a
few icons that you may have noticed here
in the variables view that
I haven't explained yet.
I'm talking about these icons here,
the A, the L, and
there's other ones that we're not seeing
right now for this particular case.
These icons here are actually
pretty straight forward.
And while I could simply tell you what
they are, there's a much better way for
you to learn this information.
I'm here at Apple's WWDC
2012 Session Videos.
And if we scroll down, I want to look
at the Debugging in Xcode video.
In this particular session,
Apple's own engineers describe
each of the icons that we
see back in Xcode here.
While the session itself
is a little dated,
the content is still extremely relevant.
This particular session contains
a lot of valuable information about
Breakpoints.
It also contains information
about Breakpoint actions,
which we'll cover later in the course,
and other debugging features in Xcode.
You can watch the entire
session in the browser.
I know it works in Safari.
It may not work in some
of the other browsers.
Or you can download
the session itself and
skip ahead to the particular segment
that'll help you with this quiz.
And I've posted a link to this
page in the instructor notes.
And like I said, it's not required that
you watch the entire session to complete
the quiz, but I would really encourage
you watch this entire video and
really any of Apple's WWDC sessions
because they're such a great source for
iOS developers.
And the best part about it is
that Apple makes all of their
previously recorded WWDC sessions
available online for free and I posted
a link to where you can access all
those as well in the instructor notes.
So with that in mind.
Watch the video and
then matched the following icons
to their correct variable kind.
And by variable kind,
that's the term that Apple uses to
describe what these labels are.
They relate to a variable kind.
Your choices
are instance/global variable.
Local variable.
Static variable.
Argument.
Expression.
And register.
Next to each of the icons, write
the number corresponding to your choice.