So this quiz asked us to write code for
the function word-transformer,
which takes in a string word as input,
and returns a random noun if the input
word is equal to the string noun, all
capitalized which returns a random verb.
If input is equal to
verbal all capitalize,
else we just return
the first character of word.
All right.
So the first thing we need to
do is return a random noun,
if our input is equal
noun all capitalized.
We do this by comparing
a word to the string noun.
We'll return a predefined function
random_noun if that's true.
Now we have to return a random
verb if our input is equal to
VERB all capitalized.
As you can see the code we wrote for
this is very similar to
checking if a word is noun.
Now we have to write code for
our last case, which is if word wasn’t
equal to Noun or Verb, we just
return the first character of word.
As you can see, we did this by using
string indexing, and there we have it.
Now we can pass words into our function,
and receive random nouns, verbs, or
first characters.
We've just written a very
important function for
our bad libs which we'll put
to use in the next quiz.