On the server side, I must create a
function that handles the code sent back
from the callback method.
But before I can do that, I need to
import a few libraries in my project.pie
file that will be necessary for
this function.
The flow_from_clientsecrets method,
creates a flow object from
the clientssecrets JSON file.
This JSON formatted style stores
your client ID, client secret and
other OAuth 2.0 parameters.
We will use this
FlowExchangeError method if we
run into an error trying to exchange an
authorization code for an access token.
We can use this FlowExchangeError
method to catch it.
We will also use the httplib2,
a comprehensive HTTP
client library in Python.
The JSON module provides an API for
converting in memory Python objects
to a serialized representation, known as
JSON, or Java Script Object Notation.
The make_response method converts
the return value from a function
into a real response object that
we can send off to our client.
And requests is an Apache 2.0 licensed
HTTP library written in Python,
similar to urllib2, but
with a few improvements.
Now, going back to
the console.developers.google.com page,
and opening the Credentials menu, I
will click the Download JSON object and
rename this file to client_secrets.json.
And store it in the same
directory as my project.pi file.
I will then declare my client ID by
referencing this client secrets file.
Now I'm ready to create
my server-side function.
I will make a route and
function that accepts post requests, and
call it gconnect.
I now confirm that the token that
the client sends to the server
matches the token that
the server sent to the client.
This round trip verification helps
ensure that the user is making
the request and not a malicious script.
Using the request.args.get method,
my code examines the state token
passed in and compares it to
the state of the login session.
If these two do not match, then I create
a response of an invalid state token and
return this message to the client.
No further authentication will occur on
the server side if there's a mismatch
between these state tokens.
If this statement is not true,
then I can proceed and
collect the one time code from my
server with the request.data function.
Next I will try and use this one
time code and exchange it for
a credentials object which will contain
the access token for my server.
This line creates
an oauth flow object and
adds my client's secret
key information to it.
Here I specify with post message
that this is the one time code
flow my server will be sending off.
Finally, I initiate the exchange
with the step two exchange function,
passing in my one-time code as input.
This step to exchange
function of the flow class
exchanges an authorization code for
a credentials object.
If all goes well, then the response
from Google will be an object
I am storing under the name credentials.
If an error happens along the way, then
I will throw this flow exchange error
and send the response as JSON object.
Now that I have this credentials object,
I will check and see if there's
a valid access token inside of it.
I will store credentials.access_token
in a variable called access_token.
If I append this token to
the following Google URL,
the Google API server can verify
that this is a valid token for use.
In these two lines of code, I create a
json GET request containing the URL and
access token.
I store the results of this request
in a variable called result.
If my result contains any errors,
then I send the 500
Internal Server Error to my client.
If this if statement isn't true,
then we know that we have
a working access token.
But now let's make sure that we
have the right access token.
Here I grab the ID of the token
in my credentials object and
compare it to the ID returned
by the Google API server.
If these two IDs do not match then
I do not have the correct token and
should return an error.
Similarly if the client IDs do not match
my app is trying to use a client ID
that does not belong to it so
I shouldn't allow for this.
Lastly I will check and see if a user
is already logged into the system.
This will return a 200 successful
authentication without resetting all
of the login session variables again.
So, assuming none of these if statements
were true, I have a valid access token
and my user is successfully
able to login into my server.
In this user's login session I
will store their credentials in
Google Plus ID.
Next, I will use the Google Plus API
to get some more information
about the user.
Here, I will send off a message to the
Google API server with my access token.
Requesting the user info
allowed by my token scope and
stored in an object I will call Data.
Now, Data should have all of
these values filled in, so
long as the user specified
them in their account.
So I will store the ones I am
interested in, such as the user's name,
picture, and e-mail address, and
store it in my login session.
If this worked, then I should be able to
create a response that knows the user's
name and can return their picture.
I can even add a flash message to let
the user know that they are logged in.
Let me save my changes and
try logging in again.
And look, my user now sees a login
page and is then redirected to
the restaurants page once they
know that they're signed in.