Ok this is the same code we saw just before
This is from a completed version
of Pitch Perfect, so don't worry if your
code doesn't match this quite yet. We'll
get there. Let's dive a little deeper and
confirm what each line of code is doing.
First we have the import AVFoundation statement.
The AVFoundation framework
contains the AVAudioRecorder.
And without this import statement, Xcode
wouldn't know about any of the AVFoundation
classes and our code wouldn't compile.
Then we have this audio recorder
property which is declared. This property
gives this View Controller the ability
to use and reference the audioRecorder
in multiple places. This is really useful,
because we want to reference the audioRecorder
in different functions.
One for beginning recording and one when we're
stopping recording. Next we have the
function recordAudio. The first line
that I have highlighted is used to get
the directory path.
Specifically, this line of code grabs the
application’s documentDirectory and
stores it as a string in this dirPath constant.
Later in the Nanodegree, you’ll
learn about other directories and
storage locations available for iOS.
For this example, it just needs a place to
store the audio recording and the
documents directory will work fine.
The directory path then gets combined
with the filename for the recording
called recordedVoice.wav.
These two lines are the lines that actually
combine both the directory path and the
recording name to create a full path to
our file.
Next up an audio session is setup using
the AVAudioSession.sharedInstance.
If we hold down the option key and click
session, we can see its type. We see that
it is indeed a AVAudioSession.
A AVAudioSession is what is needed to
either record or playback audio.
And the sharedInstance that we access here is a
AVAudioSession that's already
created by default once our app starts
running, and it can be used with a
minimal amount of setup. Going a bit
further, the AVAudioSession class is
basically an abstraction of the entire
Audio Hardware. Since there's only one
Audio Hardware for device there's only
one instance of AVAudioSession.
Hence this is why we use the
sharedInstance
It’s the shared AVAudioSession across all
apps on our device. This idea of a shared
instance is a very common pattern that
you're going to see a lot as you're
working with Apple frameworks. This next
line of code sets up the session for
playing and recording audio. This line of
code is part of a try statement. The try
statement uses an ! which indicates that
it doesn't handle any errors if this
line of code fails. The same is true of
this line where we're creating
a AVAudioRecorder. We're going to cover
error handling later, but for now we can
just assume both these lines work. With a
AVAudioRecorder created, then we set
its isMeteringEnabled property to true,
we prepare to record and then we record.
And that's it.