Now let's take Andy's spaghetti code and identify what parts of it belong where.
Because as it turns out, you can do this.
If you separate functionality into these three buckets, model, view, and
octopus, you can take spaghetti code and
refactor it to be organized and extensible.
You can find the repository with Andy's actual code in the instructor notes.
Now, the first thing I do before refactoring is I run the app itself.
I play around with it and figure out what the functionality is, and
that will help me understand the code later on.
It looks like you can click any of these buttons here and
you'll get a different cat.
You can also click the image of any of the cats to increment the number for
the cat.
Now, go ahead and hop into Andy's actual code and
see if you can figure out how Andy is displaying the different cats.