Hello again.
So Colt just talked about Rado's phone
suffering from sleep deprivation.
Now this refers to the sad situation
where Rado's favorite apps would
continually drain his device's battery
by preventing it from going to sleep.
Now here's an example of what this
kind of hyper-active app behavior
looks like in battery storing and
output.
This is a screenshot from a Google IO
2014 talk called Project Volta,
that shows the activity
of 50 simulated apps.
Now I want you to notice a few things.
Notice the frequent wake lock activity.
Lots of gaps usually mean lots of
wake up cycles for the device.
Also notice the bursty network activity.
As we know, all these things contribute
to significant battery drain.
By the way, I strongly recommend
that you watch The Talk.
It's linked in the instructor notes and
it's a good 30 minutes well-spent.
All right.
Let's look at some code that might
contribute to a graph looking like this.
If you'd like to follow along,
go ahead and
check out the 3.21 wake locks
branch in the sample app.
Traditionally, if you want to keep
the device awake we would implement
a Wake Lock.
Now just an FYI,
when you build the code and run it,
you'll notice a new button in your
sample app called Release the Wake Lock.
Now this launches a new activity
with a button to trigger some code.
This code models what it might be
like for an app to poll a server for
an update of some kind.
Perhaps retrieving some new news
data on some periodic basis.
So let's look deeper into the code.
All right so
we're going to start looking at the free
the wake clock activity source.
Now as we can see,
we have a set onClickListener that
basically is going to call this
function called pollServer when
we press that button on our app.
Let's look into that code.
Now this method writes
some code to mimic
what it's like to poll a server for
some type of uptake.
Now this method is going
to use a wake lock.
Now, in code the first thing that's done
is you require a wake lock to keep your
device awake.
So that you can then proceed
to do the network update.
We then check to see if
the network is connected.
Now in real life if it's not connected
the app might just retry until it is.
If it is connected,
we use an async task to retrieve
new data from the server away
from the main UI thread.
Now, for demonstration purposes.
Within our simple download task, we
basically open up an HTTP connection to
google.com and get a simple get request.
And, when our background thread finishes
executing, we then go ahead and
we release the wake lock.
The inherent problem with wake locks is
that they're manually held and released.
So if you hold onto the wake locks for
too long,
you could be draining
the user's battery needlessly.
Maybe it's okay if one app is doing
this, but if multiple apps are using
wake locks inefficiently,
that's a recipe for sleep deprivation.
So the moral of the story is,
make sure to release your wake lock
as soon as you are finished
doing your work.
In the next video,
we're going to see how we can still
achieve periodic background updates.
Its but implement them in a way that
will help conserve more of your devices
battery power.