Okay, so let's look at the solution.
First of all, you can see that I
created a ToastAdListener class here.
And if we open up this file,
you see the ToastAdListener
extends the base class AdListener.
Then you can see we have a
ToastAdListener that takes a Context as
an argument because this Context object
would be required later on when we send
the Toasts.
Then we have our implementation
of the AdListener methods.
onAdLoaded, sending a Toast
with the message onAdLoaded.
onAdOpen, sending a Toast
with the message onAdOpened.
onAdClosed which sends a Toast
with the message onAdClosed.
onAdLeftApplication, also sending
a Toast with this message.
And then the onAdFailedToLoad,
that takes an errorCode as the argument.
And we're performing
a switch on this errorCode
to see what the error actually was.
And for each of the error cases, you can
see that we assigned a human readable
string to the field mErrorReason.
And, at the end of the switch, you can
see that we're also sending a toast
message with the onAdFailedToLoad
plus the reason in parenthesis.
And finally, for this class,
we create the getErrorReason method
that returns the error reason.
Now, let's see how we can add
this adListener to our view.
So, we go to BannerActivity.
And you can see here that before we
build a request and we load the ad,
we're doing setAdListener on our
View object with an instance of our
newly created class ToastAdListener,
passing the context as an argument.
And that's how easy it is
to get these callbacks.
Let's check out the demo.