So here's a Bayes Network, with 6 variables, A, B, C, D, E, and F.
And I'd like you to count parameters.
If this was a binary based network,
where each variable can take on two values,
then, A would require one independent parameter,
and B another one.
And C would require four independent parameters,
because there's four different ways A and B can come together in condition C.
Now in this question I'd like to ask you,
What happens if each node can assume three values, not just two?
So A can be, A1, A2, A3.
And C can be, C1, C2, C3.
For each node, specify the number of independent parameters required
to state the conditional probability of that node.
And I'll tell you this is a tricky question,
So for A, the correct answer is two.
I won't give you the other ones.
And, it's two because A can take three values,
but it takes two independent parameters.
The last one can be inferred from, one minus the first two.
Please fill in the values for all the other variables.