So, how do you go about solving this?
Let's first figure out what the number of blocks should be.
Since we're only interested in whole blocks,
we use the floor function to round off.
Okay, now initialize disparity as a row-vector.
For each block, let's compute the x coordinate of the left edge.
Note that MATLAB and Octave begin indexing at 1.
Use this to extract an image patch from the left strip.
Now find its best matching exposition in the right strip.
And finally, compute disparity as the difference between expositions in
the left and right images.
Okay? Let's run this.
Six disparity values, as expected, but they don't make much sense, do they?
Let's try to plot them.
Okay, so what does the 0 in the first block position mean?
Well, it just says that the best match for
the block in the left image was found at the same position in the right image.
How about the peak at position 2?
This says that the second block has apparently moved a lot.
You can actually verify this visually.
Look at this feature in the left strip and its position in the right strip.
Different blocks have apparently moved by different amounts.
Now, how do these disparity values relate to depth in the scene?
Think of what are the drawbacks of a simple approach like this.