It's time to fix our first bug in the So
Many Bugs app.
Right now I'm in the print
debugging scene and
no spiders are appearing when
a user taps on the screen.
We've already completed the first
step of figuring out this problem,
because we know how to reproduce it,
by tapping on the screen.
But we need more information so
that we can determine the root
cause of the problem.
So I'm going to stop the simulator so
that we can investigate the code.
Right now we know that the problem
could be related to some
incorrect behavior when
a user taps on the screen.
And we'll treat this as our starting
point, like we're solving a code
mystery, and we'll trace
the steps leading up to the crime.
Now for this problem instead of
using specialized debugging tools,
we're going to use a simple debugging
approach called print debugging or
cave man debugging.
It may also go by some other names, but
the key is that we're only going to use
print statements to inspect
what's happening in the code.
Now this is an extremely simple
approach, but a really well
placed print statement is sometimes all
you need to determine what's wrong.
I'll start by looking at
the PrintBugViewController.swift file.
This is the view controller that's
on screen when we're tapping.
And right now we have reason to believe
that the problem is related to our code
incorrectly handling a tap.
Now, it could be the case that our logic
for handling a tap is not even called.
So let's click this drop down so
that we can see what this
particular class contains.
And, if we go here to the bottom we
can see this handle single tap method.
Now, this method looks promising and
I'll go ahead and click on it.
Could of also jumped to this method
by using the Cmd+Shift+O hotkey
to bring up a quick search.
And then type in handleSingleTap.
And we're looking for the one in the
PrintBugViewController on line 83 here.
And tap enter and it will jump us there.
Of course, this assumes that we know
the name of the method before we're
actually searching.
Anyways, at the beginning
of this method,
let's add a print statement to make sure
that we actually call the method itself.
We can also see that a call's being
made to the addBugToView method.
If I command click on it,
Xcode will jump me to the location
where addBugToView is defined.
Let's put another print
statement here so
that we can see if this
code's being reached as well.
And we'll rebuild and
run the application.
I'll go to the print debugging scene and
then I'll tap.
And we can see in the debug area that
both of our print statements are showing
up for each method.
This confirms that the methods
are being called, but
the spiders are still not
being added to the view.
So the problem must be something else.
I'm going to leave it up to you to
figure out what the problem is.
As an exercise, I want you to use only
print debugging, like print statements
such as print LN, to see if you
can identify and fix the problem.
Then, once you've
identified the problem,
select one of the following statements
that best describes what it is.
Your choices are,
the spiders do not appear because bugs
are never created by the bug factory.
Bugs are created, but
they're not added to the view.
The bug maximum restricts
the creation of bugs.
And, bugs are created, but
they are positioned off screen.
Once you fix the problem, select the
most appropriate answer, and continue.