Now with more noise,
we need to increase k in k nearest neighbor
because a small number of neighbors might be insufficient.
So the answer here is True.
We'd like to generalize over more data points.
If we use k means,
we shouldn't increase the number of cluster centers.
We were just happy with the number of cluster centers,
and using more will make the situation worse.
Therefore, the answer is False.
In Laplacian smoothing,
we should increase k because
we smooth more, which will accomodate
the problems introduced by the additional noise.
Of course, we should never
use fewer particles in a particle filter.
That's clearly False.
And if more data is available,
we should always use it.
Irrespective of the noise,
but specifically, if we have more noise
we should go through even more efforts to
find more data.
So this is absolutely True.