So, let's take a look at what an impulse response looks like in an image.
So here we have an impulse.
Okay, and so, here's our impulse, right?
It's just a single pixel with a value of one, okay?
And we're going to filter it with some kernel, h, okay?
Remember kernel mask,
thing that we're moving around in order to make our filter, so we have our H.
So the question is, what is the output?
And again, I want to thank Christin Gramen for having made these slides so
I can change them, steal them, move them around.
So first I put down my filter, and
you see my filter's over here like this, right?
So it doesn't hit that 1 at all, and so its value is just going to be a 0.
Fine, no big deal.
All right.
Now, move the filter over a little bit.
Well, it just pulls out the f here, right, so this
pixel right there pulls out the f so an f goes right there, in, in my result.
Move it over one more time, what do I get, I get the e.
Move it over one more time again, what do I get, I get the d.
So, you notice that even though the filter goes D-E-F, left to right.
In the image, what comes out is F-E-D, going the other way, and
that's just because of how this correlation pulled it up.
And it won't surprise you that it, not only does it flip it left and
right, it also flips it up and down.
And that's what happens when you do a correlational filter of a impulse.
Just because of the way you slide it over,
you'll end up flipping that entire response.
By the way, something that I was being implicit about is I was assuming that
this center of that filter was what we were calling the reference point, right.
So wherever the center was located, wherever that center pixel.
That was the one that was being entered into on the result.
Okay.
You could use a different point, but we're going to assume that the center pixel
is the reference pintal, pixel of the filter.