So we can see that out of the 25
e-mails with the word, cheap,
20 of them are spam,
while 5 of them are not.
This forms an 80, 20 split,
so the correct answer is 80%.
If you said 80, you were correct.
So from analyzing this data,
we can conclude a rule.
The rule says,
if an e-mail contains the word, cheap,
then the probability of that
e-mail being spam is 80%.
We then associate this feature
with the probability, 80%,
and we will use it to flag future
messages as spam or not spam.
We can also look at other features and
try to find their
associated probability.
Let's say we look at e-mails containing
a spelling mistake and realize that
the probability of an e-mail containing
a spelling mistake being spam is 70%.
And let's say we look at e-mails
that are missing a title, and
the probability of those
being spam is 95%.
And we can keep going,
finding different features that will
predict if an e-mail is spam or not.
So, now, when future e-mails come,
we can combine these features to
guess if they are spam or not.
This algorithm is know as
the Naive Bayes Algorithm.