So let me show you now,
complete feature based morphing
approach here with these two images.
First we're going to put features, here
these basically kind of show off the eye
features, eyeball, lips, and everything.
And of course we can apply
the same to this image also.
By using this I'm now
basically doing the morphing.
We get.
So let me now actually show perhaps one
of the most widely used methods for
trying to do feature-based morphing,
and this was actually in the Michael
Jackson's black or white video.
This is a method actually
done by Byron Neely.
Very early in 1992 and actually just for
those of you interested
even the kinds of techniques we've
looked at like cross fading and
stuff like that were actually widely
used in the pre-computer era, in 1940s,
of trying to do fading between things
to kind of show the morphing examples,
I'm about to show you.
And the effect really was kind of do
fading between two different types of
images and kind of changing
the fade level to show you a morph.
Now of course, with the,
now with the kind of the geometry and
all of that stuff available, with great
patterns we can do a much better job.
So again, this is the video
that you may have seen.
Here you notice a couple of
interesting things happen, right?
And this is where feature based
morphing comes in and notice the hair.
They basically can control
how the hair comes in.
The eyes are all aligned, of course,
this is very nicely choreographed.
Everybody was doing the same
exact steps to music.
An, lot of things about features
if you notice this range and
shape of that is much
more nicely adapted.
Notice another example,
where you'll see the hair grow again.
And again,
these are because of the corresponding
feature lines help you do this.
I think quite an impressive piece
of work, and again, you know, and
this kind of image morphing is widely
used in the special effects industry.
Just for fun, let me actually show
you another interesting example,
I wanted to showcase we can do this
very easily, so I went ahead and
from our College of Computing
web page just took pictures of.
Our deans legally and the three of
us who are the associate deans.
Ron Arkin, he's an associate dean,
and Charles S Bell and myself.
And I'd just thought I'd generate
a nice morph of all of us.
So, kind of fun and interesting.