So, here you go.
So a very simple JAVA/Python program which kind of serves as a backend.
And is going to consume the tweets and
parse the tweets for the URL and just count them.
Right?
So then in order to present the nice interface to his boss, so
that he can use he can use it, so write a, you'll write a small web app
that in turn contacts the program every few seconds and to display the count.
So that when Lewis' boss goes to the website,
the realtime dashboard is always refreshing.
Right?
So to give that in perspective,.
So you have this job on Python backend, and
that is going to keep accessing that to the stream.
And the backend also does the same filters and calculates the count.
And there is a web app and
there is a real time dashboard that boss is going to use.
Whenever the AirTime request comes or when the,
whenever the board uses the Real Time dashboard,
you go to the web app that in turn gets the data from the Java/Python backend.
And you can get the visibility in real time right away.
Right? Now, the questions.
What are the issues with this solution?