First, use a one-way hash function.
This is obvious, because if the hash
function does not have one-way property.
Then from the hash value an attacker
can easily reverse the hash function,
and find the plain text password.
So, we have to use a one-way hash
function to protect password security.
Second, should not use
the avalanche effect.
The avalanche effect means that
a slight change of the input may cause
a large change of the output.
In fact, we want our hash
function to have this effect, so
that two similar passwords will
have very different hash values.
With this in fact,
even when the attacker has correctly
guessed a password, he still has
the same amount of difficulty to
guess another similar password.
Third, should only check to see that
the hash function output is the same
as stored output.
This obviously is yes.
Because password authentication should
only check that the hash function output
is the same as the stored value.