Wow, what a day.
>> Hey Chris?
>> What's going on?
Oh, hey, what's up?
>> I got tell you, man,
I'm really impressed with
this application you wrote,
that actually shows where all
your coworkers are in real time.
This is pretty cool, like it even
shows me as I'm moving it around.
>> Well, cool, thanks man,
yeah, it was fun to make,
the key is to keep an open connection
when the phone screen is off, so
that we can update your
location in real time.
>> Whoa, no,
tell me you're not doing that.
>> Well, you know, there were
some problems stopping the GPS
when folks entered the bathroom,
but I think that's a small.
>> Dude, Chris.
>> To fix.
>> My battery just died.
>> Oh, dang that sucks maybe it's a dud.
>> Dud, Chris this is a brand new phone,
your application ate through my entire
battery in eight minutes, are you even
taking into account the battery churn?
Those open GPS and
networking connections are taking up?
>> I thought so,
I ran it through a bunch of tools.
>> Oh wait, timeout.
What, what tools are you using
to measure battery, Chris?
>> You know.
The usual ones like Logcat.
>> [LAUGH] Okay.
Stop what you're doing,
we're going to go fix this now,
because this is an abomination,
all right, come on, let's get going.
>> 'Kay.
>> Oh, bring your backpack,
you're going to need it.