When your learning how to use
a new feature or language,
you'll often look at example code to
give you a model of what to write.
Then you'll write code that's
based on the example code, but
you'll change it to do
what you want it to.
But if that doesn't work, what then?
What a lot of new programmers
try at this point,
is to try making random changes
to their non-working code.
And then when that doesn't work,
they ask for help.
Here's another approach.
When your code doesn't work,
set it aside,
comment it out, like this,
then copy the example code.
Copy and paste, really.
Don't try to change it at this point.
Just run it ,and make sure that
it does what it's supposed to.
Then modify it in small steps, until it
does what you wanted your code to do.
That looks better.
And then once your done, see if you can
find where your original code had a bug.
Try that now.
Given what you've seen here, find and
fix the bug in the original
version of boldwrap.