Welcome to the walkthrough for
assignment number one of the deep
learning Udacity class. And I hope
you're enjoying the lectures so far. And
the first assignments which you can go
and take a look at on the Tenserflow
Github website will have you do
some data wrangling and preparing a data
sets that we were going to be using
throughout the class. So, the setup
depends a little bit on what your
machine looks like. For me, I’m going to
use the Docker image and the command
line to get it started
looks like this, and I can go to the URL
of the local Docker image like this. So,
this is assignment number one.
So, what we're going to do in this
assignment is look at some data, the data
that we're going to use is called notMNIST.
Referring to the ubiquitous
MNIST data sets, and this one will try
to look a little bit like MNIST but
try to be a little bit more challenging
a lot more interesting than just a
handwritten digits. This data set
consists of letters that are rendered in
a variety of fonts. And the goal is given
the image of the rendered letter
figuring out which letter
it represents, so it goes from A to J
there are ten classes just like a MNIST.
And, it's got a lot of data, and it's a
little bit more noisy than MNIST.
And, we will see later on. The assignment
starts with just setting up your
environment making sure that you have,
you can import all the things that we
will be using down the road. We first
download the data sets.
This is simply, you know, a few lines of
code, we verified that the data set is
the expected size. If you don't have it,
you might have to delete the file and
try again. It really depends on your
internet connectivity.
You could also just download it by hand.
It's completely fine.