In this question we study a particle filter.
Let's just zoom in for a second.
We have eight particles that land on this checkerboard.
They are labeled, 'A' all the way to 'H'.
And some of them are on black squares.
And some of them are on white squares.
Given those particles,
we'll assume that the probability of measuring 'black',
for any particle that falls on a black square,
is 0.7.
And the probability of measuring 'white',
for any particle that falls on a white square,
is 0.6.
From that you can easily calculate the probability of measuring 'white',
if a particle falls on a black square.
And the probability of 'black',
if the particle falls on a white square.
Now I'd like to what's the normalized importance weight, after normalization,
of the particle, labeled 'A',
if our measurement happens to be 'white'?
That's a number that you put in over here.
And I'm going to ask you the same question
about the normalized importance weight of particle 'A',
if the measurement is 'black'.
To calculate this,
you will go through these probabilities.
For each particle, you will assign the measurement probability.
And then you just normalize all of those,
so they add up to one.