Even more important than the selection
of the treatment stores,
is the selection of the control stores.
These stores will become the baseline
for the analysis of the experiment.
As mentioned before, the process for
selecting treatment and
control stores is known
as matched pairing.
Matched pairing is where each treatment
store is matched to a control store
that has very similar measures for
each of the control variables.
In our new product experiment,
we chose three control variables,
sales volume, number of products sold
and state where the store is located.
In the matched pairing process,
for each treatment store,
we would want to select a control store
that has close to the same sales volume,
close to the same number of products
sold, and is in the same state.