Eliminating redundant data structures can help save memory
in the control program running at the controller. Only
performing ,a fixed number of network management operations
such as routing, can insure that the controller doesn't
have to do too much, thereby improving scalability.
Caching forwarding decisions, that the control plain has already
made ,in the switches, can ensure ,that not
to much traffic, is redirected to the controller, and
running multiple controllers can distribute the load of
the control plane across multiple replicas, sending all
traffic to the controller only increases the controller
load, and would not help with scale ability.