I'll start from the first one, no.
The browser is really really really
really good of keeping
track of requests.
You don't need to worry
about a collision.
In fact, I just made that up.
So, no.
For this one, no.
Making lots of parallel
requests is totally fine for
the same reason as I just stated.
Is it this one, that nothing is wrong?
No.
I don't like trick questions.
So that must mean that the thumbnails
will be created in a random order.
Remember, you cannot predict the order
in which requests will return.
So you don't know when any of these
getJSON promises will resolve,
which means that they could resolve in a
different order than they were created.
In that case, the planet thumbnails will
be created in a totally random order.
Now, this isn't necessarily a problem or
a bug, but it does lead to the question.
Just how do you make the thumbnails
appear in the right order?
Keep watching.