First we need to modify
the activity main layout so
that we can add the text views for
price.
If the device preview
isn't showing already,
you can click on this link here that
says Preview in order to make it appear.
Now, when we change the XML, we can
just see it update automatically, here.
In this screen shot we provided for
you, the price was presented in
a similar way to the quantity.
We have a header, as well as
a text view, to show the value.
So we can just copy over these
two text view elements and
then paste it beneath it.
Now we just need to tweak
the values to fit our scenario.
Instead of quantity,
it should say price.
And, we should also change
the ID to be price text view.
You can have two views with the same ID.
But, anyways, in the quiz, we told you
to change this to be price text view.
So, it would match our code.
There.
And that makes the error go away.
Okay, looking at the preview, we have
the price header, and zero beneath it.
We also want to just change
this just to be zero dollars.
And you can use your own
currency symbol if you want.
The header is in all caps and
the actual price value has the text
size of 16 sp and a black text color.
That looks good so far, except I do
notice there needs to be a little
more vertical space between the price
header and the quantity value.
I'm just going to
change all the views so
that they have a margin top,
value of 16dp.
And then instead of margin bottom here,
I'm just going to do, margin top,
16, and that actually fixes it.
Cool.
Now all the views
are evenly spaced apart.
Once you think the XML
is in a good state,
then you can just run it on your device.
Cool, and that looks good.
Let's work on the MainActivity file now.
If this Android DDMS window pops up, you
can just collapse it using this arrow.
In the MainActivity,
we asked you to copy and
paste the displayPrice
method that we gave you.
Hopefully, you also modified
your Android Studio preferences
to automatically import things
if they were unambiguous.
That would help resolve the problem
of it not knowing what number format
referred to.
But now with the import statement,
the app knows that number format is
something that's provided automatically
by Java to help format numbers.
Then for the last step, we modify
the submit order method, so that when
the button is clicked, we display
the quantity and also display the price.