In the very first module of these
nano degree program, you used
some basic computer vision techniques
to find the lane lines on the road.
The first thing you'll do in these
module, is to write a better lane
finding algorithm that deals with
complex scenarios like curving lines,
shadows and
changes in the color of the pavement.
You'll measure things like how
much the lane is curving and
where your vehicle is
with respect to center.
These are the kinds of measurements you
ultimately need to make in order to
control the car.
>> After that, you'll implement
vehicle detection and tracking.
While deciding when to change lanes,
when to accelerate, and
when to hit the brakes, knowing where
the other vehicles are on the road
is crucial to
the decision-making process.
Trust me, I have friends who
change lanes without looking, and
it doesn't end well.
>> The project for
this module will come in two pieces.
First, the advanced lane-finding piece.
And second, the vehicle detection and
tracking piece.
At the end, you'll combine these two
pieces to simultaneously measure
where the car is on the road,
where the road is going, and
the location of other vehicles
in your field of view.