So we now learned about fully observable environments,
and planning in stochastic environments with MDPs
I'd like to say a few words about partially observable environments,
or POMDPs--which I won't go into in depth; the material is relatively complex.
But I'd like to give you a feeling for why this is important, and what type of problems
you can solve with this, that you could never possibly solve with MDPs.
So, for example, POMDPs address problems of optimal exploration versus exploitation,
where some of the actions might be information-gathering actions;
whereas others might be goal-driven actions.
That's not really possible in the MDPs because the state space is fully observable
and therefore, there is no notion of information gathering.