You already know that when you query for
data, you have to do so asynchronously.
Which means you have to retrieve
the data on a background thread.
This is because a query can
be unreliable or slow, and
you want to make sure that your main
UI thread runs quickly and smoothly.
So to handle queries for
our task data, we're going to
be using an AsyncTask Loader.
This loader implements call back
methods to start loading data,
perform a query in the background,
and finally return that data.
We can also tell our loader to requery
the task data whenever it changes,
like when we insert a new task.
In fact, in our main activity code,
there's already a requery that
happens in the on resume method.
In the on resume method, we restart
the loader so that any time you leave
the main activity and return,
like when you go to AddTaskActivity
to insert a new task, the loader
will restart and update the UI.
So all we need to do now is add some
simple code to load our task data
on a background thread.
So let's scroll down to our
loader callback methods.
In our loader callback method
named loadInBackground,
we can use a content resolver to
query for the tasks directory.
We'll surround our query in a try-catch,
which means we'll try to query and
catch any error that may
occur while loading data.
Here's the structure of a try catch,
our catch will just log
any errors if the data fails to load,
and return a null cursor.
Note that there isn't a return null
statement outside of this try-catch.
And in the try we'll try
to return a cursor of data.
We'll call query on
the content resolver and
pass in the CONTENT_URI that
points to our tasks directory.
The projection and selection arguments
will all be null, since by default,
null will select all the data.
And the last argument we're going
to pass in will be the sort order.
And we actually want to
sort by priority, so
that the higher priority tasks
show up at the top of our list.
So I'll put in COLUMN_PRIORITY
as this last argument.
And after this data is loaded, this
callback method returns this cursor.
And this cursor will actually be
passed to our custom cursor adapter,
which creates the task views
in the main recycler view.
So this simple query completes
our main display code.
And if you want to learn more about the
adapter code, check the notes below or
the comments inside that class.
Now it's time to try
running the app again.
You should be able to
insert new task data and
see that displayed on the main screen.