You may ask yourself,
can we define functions that
take more than one parameter?
Absolutely, here's a new function called
greet student that takes a string and
bool value as input.
In the definition, multiple parameters
are separated by a comma and
then added in the same way as our
original parameter using a name,
followed by a colon and a type.
So for our first parameter,
the input value is called student and
it's of type string.
And for
our second parameter the input is called
lateForClass and it's of type bool.
And if you wanted to add
even more parameters,
you'd just continue this pattern.
For example,
here's another function called
averageScore that has three parameters.
If we were to describe this function
aloud, we might say we have the function
averageScore that takes three
double values called firstScore,
secondScore and thirdScore.
Now let's take a look at how to call
a function with multiple parameters.
Again, we start with the function's
name, and then we have a comma separated
list of our inputs and
their corresponding values.
So for our student,
the value is Gabrielle and for
lateForClass the value is false.
And if you think about the purpose of
this function, it shows that Gabrielle
wasn't late for class and therefore our
printout that we have in the console
says, glad you could join us today,
Gabrielle, with a smiley face.
On the other hand,
when we call greetStudent, and
the student is Jared and he's late for
class, the output we get in
the console is a little bit different.
It says Jared, you're late.
Another thing to notice is that the
order of the input values when we call
the function is the same as
the order of the input values
where we define the function.
So the student comes first,
followed by the value for lateForClass.
[BLANK_AUDIO]