[Thrun] For answering these questions, let me restate the essential formulas.
W1 is obtained by M times sum of XY minus sum of X times sum of Y
over M times sum Xi square minus sum of Xi in brackets square.
And if you plug in these numbers over here for M equals 5
because there's 5 training examples, we get 5 times 88 minus 10 times 35
over 5 times 30 minus 100, which is 1.8.
That is the correct answer for W1.
W0 was obtained by 1 over M times sum over Ys minus W1 over M times sum over X.
And plugging in the table over here gives us 1/5 times 35 minus 1.8 over 5 times 10,
and that is 3.4, which would have been the correct answer over here.
And again here are the data points with the solution.
So if you take the axis where X equals 0,
the Y value is actually 3.4, and the slope is 1.8.
It's a little smaller than if you just click at the end points,
which gave us a slope of 2, because there is a residual arrow over here,
residual arrow over here, residual arrow over here, and a residual arrow over here.
The resulting linear function ends up splitting in a quadratically optimal way
the arrows between these different data points.