Now let's switch to the other part of game theory,
which remember we called mechanism design.
It could really be called game design.
The idea is that someone is going to be running a game
that players are going to be participating in.
We want to design the rules of the game such that we get a high outcome
or a high expected utility for the people that run the game,
for the players who play the game, and for the public at large.
Here's an example of a game.
This is the advertising game.
Here I've shown it on an Internet search engine, where you do a search,
and then ads show up, sometimes at the top, sometimes at the right,
sometimes at the bottom of the page, depending on the mechanism.
This is also done at sites like eBay that sell items,
and there's lots of places where auctions are run.
The idea of mechanism design is to come up with the rules of the auction
that will make it attractive to bidders and/or people who want to respond to the ads,
and make a good result for all.
Now, one property that you would like an auction to have is to
attract more bidders to make it a more competitive market,
and you could attract more if it's less work for them.
It's easier for the bidders if they have a dominant strategy.
You saw how hard it was to work out the value of a game
when you didn't have a dominant strategy,
and how easy it is to work it out if you did.
If you want to save everybody a lot of trouble, design the game
so that dominant strategies exist.
These strategies have various names in auctions.
Sometimes you call it an auction strategy proof
if you only need to know your own strategy.
You don't have to think about what all the other people are going to be bidding.
They also call that truth revealing or incentive compatible.