So great, now you've gotten
the geo-fence event from the intent.
The next thing of course to
do is to figure out, well,
what kind of event did you get?
Has someone entered the geo-fence?
Has someone left the geo-fence?
And in order to keep my poor
dog from getting confused,
you might want to play a different
sound in these circumstances.
To get a transition type
on a geo-fencing event,
you call the get geo-fence
transition class.
This would return an integer
which contain the value one,
if someone enters the geo-fence, or
two if they're exiting the geo-fence.
The geo-fence API contains constants
that will make your code easier to read,
instead of checking for
the values one or two.
Update your code to get the transition,
and then to check if it's an Enter or
Exit event.
And when you're done check this box.