Okay, so not everything
about drop downs is all bad.
For instance, the ability to give users
a predefined list of options actually
can come in handy.
It's just that forcing users to
scroll through massive lists of
options can be tiring.
And it's not very flexible because
they have to pick one of the options.
Incidentally, there is one kind of
input that combines the helpfulness
of a pre-defined list with
the flexibility of a text input, and
it's called the data list.
Here's an example.
With the data list, you still get
a pre-defined list of options, but
users also have the ability to type.
And as users type, they will see
options from the list get suggested.
But this doesn't mean that users
have to use one of the options.
They can actually keep typing.
This makes data lists a nice,
flexible solution.
The syntax is pretty simple.
Rather than putting options in a select
tag, put them in a data list tag.
Each option should have a value set to
whatever value you want it to take,
and you'll need to give
the data list an id.
The input should have a list attribute,
and
the list attribute should
match the datalist an ID.
Check the Instructor notes for
more information.
For this quiz you're going to be
building the data list you just saw.
I'll be giving you a version
of the demo with a dropdown,
and you'll be turning it into this.
As always, don't forget to take a look
at the instructor notes, and good luck.