Recall the merge tree for
a multi-way merge.
The initial input has n elements.
At the very start,
which is the top of this tree, the input
is divided into a bunch of sorted runs.
Let's say each of these
runs has about z items.
It would probably be some constant
fraction less than one of z.
fraction of z less than one, so
that you can do the initial
sorting step to produce the runs.
Now, suppose you do k way merging
as illustrated in this merge tree.
The total number of comparisons
it will turn out is n log n.
That matches what you would expect for
any comparison based sort.
My question is, what about the total
asymptotic memory transfers?
Assume that k is some large
fraction of z over L so
that you can always to a k
way merge in fast memory.
And because I'm so
nice let me give you another small hint.
The maximum number of levels L
in the merge tree is theta of
log base z over L of n over L.
Although I've given you this hint,
you should probably take a moment
to convince yourself that it is in
fact true.