So in this case, this first one
here looks like a pretty good rule.
Let's break it down.
Okay, so
the first part of the statement is here.
And what this part of the statement
does is basically look up
the shared with data for
the listing question which remember,
stores the key that has the same name.
And this part of the rule right here
gets us the email of the current user
as I showed you before.
Now, if this email is part
of the sharedWith list,
then it'll be equal to
something other than null.
And if this email isn't part of
the sharedWith list which means that,
that user hasn't been
shared with on that list,
then this whole value will be null.
We do that comparison right here.
And that gives us the correct answer for
the rule.