Now, there are many different ways to apply linear functions in machine learning.
We so far have studied linear functions for regression,
but linear functions are also used for classification,
and specifically for an algorithm called the perceptron algorithm.
This algorithm happens to be a very early model of a neuron,
as in the neurons we have in our brains,
and was invented in the 1940s.
Suppose we give a data set of positive samples and negative samples.
A linear separator is a linear equation that separates positive from negative examples.
Obviously, not all sets possess a linear separator, but some do.
For those we can define the algorithm of the perceptron and it actually converges.
To define a linear separator, let's start with our linear equation as before--
w1x + w0 in cases where x is higher dimensional this might actually be a vector--never mind.
If this is larger or equal to zero, then we call our classification 1.
Otherwise, we call it zero.
Here's our linear separation classification function
where this is our common linear function.
Now, as I said, perceptron only converges if the data is linearly separable,
and then it converges to a linear separation of the data,
which is quite amazing.
Perceptron is an iterative algorithm that is not dissimilar from grade descent.
In fact, the update rule echoes that of grade descent, and here's how it goes.
We start with a random guess for w1 and w0,
which may correspond to a random separation line,
but usually is inaccurate.
Then the mth weight-i is obtained by using the old weight plus some learning rate alpha
times the difference between the desired target label
and the target label produced by our function at the point m-1.
Now, this is an online learning rule, which is we don't process all the data in batch.
We process one data at a time, and we might go through the data many, many times--
hence the j over here--
but every time we do this, we apply this rule over here.
What this rule gives us is a method to adapt our weights in proportion to the error.
If the prediction of our function f equals our target label,
and the error is zero, then no update occurs.
If there is a difference, however, we update in a way so as to minimize the error.
Alpha is a small learning weight.
Once again, perceptron converges to a correct linear separator
if such linear separator exists.
Now, the case of linear separation has recently received a lot of attention in machine learning.
If you look at the picture over here, you'll find there are many different linear separators.
There is one over here. There is one over here. There is one over here.
One of the questions that has recently been researched extensively is which one to prefer.
Is it a, b, or c?
Even though you probably have never seen this literature,
I will just ask your intuition in this following quiz.
Which linear separator would you prefer if you look at these three different linear separators--
a, b, c, or none of them?