Couple little things to look at remaining.
The first is the impact of noise on the Hough transform.
So here what you can see is an image on the left where we've taken that
same cartoon set of dots and we perturbed them a little bit off the line.
So we've added a little bit of noise to their location.
On the right, you see the Hough votes.
And you'll notice that now, the peak, not so precise.
And in fact, if we had very, very fine bins, we might miss that peak altogether.
So, in a minute we're going to talk a little bit about changing bin sizes,
with respect to noise, as a, a way of making the thing work.
But, what happens is that small amounts of noise can bump you off.
So by the way, one really kind of cool thing you could do,
if you wanted to find sort of the general peak over here, what might you do?
You might smooth this image, right?
You could actually take a,
say a filtering of that as an image, then find the peaks.
And now you know you've moved the peaks around a little bit because
you blurred it.
But now you at least found the peak, and you say, I'm going to do
the Hough transform again, but this time I'm going to just focus on that area.
Okay, so I'm going to build a new array with much finer bins but only there, and
if d or theta are outside there, I'm not even going to count those votes and
that would let you go from a noisy image to, to a better one.
There's actually another problem.
What happens if we have a lot of noise?
Like, suppose all we have is noise.
Here on the left, what you've got is a bunch of points that are put down,
that are just randomly put there.
And on the right, everybody gets the vote.
Lara Croft or whoever you want.
Go ahead and vote.
Turns out there were no real candidates.
But maybe we don't know that.
You can accidentally find peaks.
So sometimes you have to worry about,
is the peak that I'm finding actually real or not?
It's helpful if you already know, let's suppose you know there's six lines in
the picture, well then you just find the six highest peaks, but
if you don't know how many are there, you have this question of, when is a peak
a real peak and when is it just the accidental alignment of votes?