Here's a solution to this exercise.
For the first example where we want the
content URI for the entire pets table.
We started off with our scheme, and for
content URIs remember
it's always content://.
Next part is the content authority,
which tells us the content provider.
In this case,
we've set up the content authority to be
com.example.android.pets, and the last
part of it is the pets table name,
and this tells us that we want
information from the entire pets table.
Now similarly for the second case,
where we want information but
just from a single row, we have the same
scheme, the same content authority,
and the same pets table name but
we want to specify the row ID here.
We end it with /2 because we want
the pet in the second row of the table.
And this is assuming that the table
starts counting from one.