So now it's time to look at
how you can show real ads and
see how much you can earn from them.
This is done by creating
an AdMob account.
Let's go back to the following picture.
So what we'll see in this section
is how to create real ad unit ID
that are associated with
real ads from advertisers.
And that when you use them,
you will actually load these real ads.
So let's look at what we'll do.
First of all, I'll show you how
to create an AdMob Account.
Then we'll look at how to add
an app to this account and
then we'll see how to
create Real Ad Unit IDs.
So this will be similar to the test ad
unit IDs from the perspective of syntax.
But they will actually be tied to
real ads created by real advertisers.
And all of these things we will
do from the AdMob web interface.
Let's start by looking at
creating an AdMob account.