Hey.
Nice work fixing up Mike's awful,
awful code.
[LAUGH] I still blame him even
though I may have told him to do it.
By now, you should feel
pretty good about yourself.
Let me give you some context.
Oftentimes when people learn separation
of concerns, they learn it by using
a framework or a library like Angular or
Ember or Meteor or Backbone or Knockout.
There are a lot of them.
And some of them start to think of
separation of concerns as something that
you need a framework or
library to do, but not you.
All the stuff we've been doing
has been vanilla JavaScript and
jQuery, no organizational
frameworks at all.
That's more than could be said for
a lot of novice developers,
so awesome, awesome job.
Now, from what we've seen, any project
that updates the DOM based on data with
JavaScript can be refactored
to use separation of concerns.
So now we're moving onto our
last project for this lesson.
You may have built the resumé
project in a previous course.
I've linked the course and
the instructor notes below.
If you took that course,
we'll be refactoring your
project to be more awesome.
If you didn't take that course,
I'll give you the repo for
the associated project.
We've seen that any project that
updates the DOM based on data
using JavaScript can be refactored
to use separation of concerns, so
that's what we'll be doing for
the resumé.
Now, you'll all have less guidance on
this project and more autonomy and
flexibility, which is exactly how
things are in the development world.
So, if you have code of your own,
make a new branch in your
resumé project repository.
We're making a new branch so
we still have the original version.
Do all of your work in that new branch.
If you don't have code of your own,
check out the repository down in
the instructor notes below and
take a look at the readme file so you
can figure out how to do the project,
keeping separation of concerns in mind.
Then, refactor the project to properly
utilize separation of concerns.
This might be as simple as providing a
view object with a render function on it
and ensuring you don't
mutate the model from it.
Remember all the different
ways we can refactor,
either by modifying the current
files as they are or
doing some version of burning it and
rewriting.