Now let's make the Hello App a little
more interesting by adding a new
endpoint with some different inputs.
Let's make it possible for your app to
say good morning or good evening or
even good breakfast time if you want.
Add one more endpoints function to your
application called greetByPeriod that
takes a period input as
well as a name input.
The period input could be morning or
afternoon or evening or, or
breakfast time.
And this function will return
a hello object, whose message is,
Good Breakfast Time Marcus Aurelius, if
that's what you happened to pass to it.
Note that you do not have to write
the front end code for this.
Just to find the endpoints method.
But of course, you're welcome to add
this functionality to the web front end
as well, if you wish.
So when you're done, check off
these items on the checklist, and
then fill in your project ID