Here is the result of such an operation.
We have yet again a left image over here. The right one is missing.
Here you can see what's called a disparity map,
which the map of the best match.
In the right image, the further the disparity, the more we have to assume the patch shifted.
We extracted every possible patch from this image, did the search on the right image,
and we find in the foreground, the disparity is much larger than the background.
Sometimes we get a black spot, like over here,
where the information itself is not good enough to make any decision.
Or in the pathway over here, there are no real features.
Same for the sky over here.
But in most cases, we can see a nicely shaded gray that decreases with distance
where the disparity decreases.
This is a very typical stereo vision result.
Here is a disparity map from driving in desert with our DARPA Grand Challenge car, Stanley.
We equipped it with two cameras, one on the left and one on the right.
You can see the two camera images, and on the right the disparity map.
It's not that informative, because there is very little structure in the road surface itself,
but by and large you can see things further away end up being darker.
The big dominant thing here is lack of texture,
which leads to certain areas in the disparity map just being black,
which means we don't know.
But where it registers it does a pretty find job.