Now that you've seen the nuts and
bolts of this app all in code,
let's take another look at how
Storyboard represents objects.
Storyboard has three different
ways of showing our objects.
In an expandable outline view,
in a visual canvas view, and
in the text editor itself.
It's important to find all three
of these to be sure you're
confident manipulating outlets.
To start out with let's focus on
this ViewController.swift file.
The first thing you're going to want to
do is delete any extra code you have
in this viewDidLoad method leftover from
when we built this app programmatically.
Make sure you hold on to these
two properties that we made.
And also this increment count method.
Right now, Storyboard doesn't know about
this label property that we've created.
But we can change that by adding
at IBOutlet in front of it.
This is how storyboard's
going to recognize this property.
Notice that when a property
is marked as an IBOutlet,
this circle appears in the left margin.
Let's close the assistant editor and
focus on the Storyboard for a minute.
Inside Storyboard, new controllers
are represented by yellow circle icons,
like this one in the outline view,
and this one in the canvas view.
The outline view is an expandable tree
that shows the view controller the view
and any subviews.
The canvas view is just another
representation of the exact
same objects.
If we control click on one of
the view controller icons,
we see the pop up connections menu.
And here we can see our label property.
You can see here that this
circle representing our label
property is empty.
That's because it hasn't
been initialized yet.
So let's go ahead and do that now.
To initialize our label,
first we open up the utilities pane and
drag in a label from the objects menu.
Let's close this utilities pane, and
then we can set our label property
by dragging from new referencing
outlet to the canvas view.
Here in the pop up connections menu we
can see that our label property is set.
If I control click here in the canvas
view I can also see that the label
property is set.
If I want to unset it I
just click on this small x.
I want to show you one more
way you can set that property.
So let's open up the assistant editor
and see that you can drag from
the circle in the left margin
here straight to the canvas view.
And then let's check again in
our pop up connections menu and
see that our label property is set.