For our next step,
we need to authenticate by logging into
the movie database, but this time we're
going to use a different offload that
goes to the movie database website.
Let's go back to Travis for
a little bit of context.
Travis can you explain this,
how we use this flow when we log into
the website to authenticate, and why did
you go with this approach instead of
using something popular like OAuth?
>> Yeah, no, for sure.
So back when I did the first
pass of authentication
OAuth was just a little bit of a mess.
And, you know, [COUGH] instead of
trying to force this system that
was just kind of broken onto our users',
I just had the tools or
something that was really close
to OAuth, but ultimately our own.
And, you know, you'll see as you go
through the principles of OAuth,
and our off flow are almost identical.
You do all the, you know, credential
checking on the website, so you're not
passing usernames and passwords over
the air they're really almost identical.
It's just that we, we just thought it
was a lot easier to do it ourselves.
>> Thanks for filling us in, Travis.
Rolling your own solutions definitely
sometimes the best way to get
the functionality that you want.
And before we move ahead,
let's take a look at those principles
that Travis was referring to.