In this lesson, we answered the big question, what is an operating system?
And we saw that it's important because it helps abstract and
arbitrate the use of the underlying hardware system.
We explained that to achieve this,
an operating system relies on a number of abstractions, like processes and
threads, a number of mechanisms that allow it to manipulate those abstractions,
and a number of policies that specify how those abstractions can be modified.
We saw that operating systems support a system call interface that
allows applications to interact with them.
We looked at several alternatives in organizational structures for
operating systems.
Then very briefly, we looked at some specific examples of operating systems,
Windows, Linux, and Mac OS to see some examples of
their system call interfaces or their organization.