So the last question,
where it was an algorithm question,
where we were asking, given an array and
a number, find two elements in the array
that add up to that given number.
The reason we asked that question,
or I asked that question,
is to check basic understanding of
does the interviewer know run times.
Can they reason about how long a program
they're going to write is going to take?
Can they reason about how much space the
program they're going to write is take,
Phillip did both?
And can they come up with
a solution that's as,
that uses as little memory pressure and
runtime pressure as possible.
And Phillip did really well on that.
It also tests your understanding of
using data structures that are common
across languages so a hash map is
something you'll definitely have to
use at your job,
regardless of what you're doing.
And Philip ended up using one,
and using it well.
And being able to reason
about how it works and
why you want to use your given data
structure is also very important.
And Philip did that well too.