(Sebastian) Okay, there's several questions in the online forum on particle filters, and they all boil down to,
"Can you be more precise, Sebastian, give us more precise examples?"
And it's a good criticism, in fact. I gave you some abstract description. I hope in the future we can do programming
assignments for this class, and then people can get source code from me for particle filters.
We're working with the infrastructure right now, but we haven't gotten around this class to do this.
Meanwhile, I hope that the robotics class clarifies some of the questions that people actually have.
So you're going to have lots of quizzes there. I can promise you if you do those quizzes right, then you've got it, you understand particle filters.
(Peter) Okay. And here's one from Dan Smullen in your old home state of Pennsylvania.
(Sebastian) Hi, Pennsylvania. (Peter) "I noticed that the course doesn't discuss expert systems or other rule-based approaches.
"Are such techniques still considered part of A.I.?" So yes, they certainly are.
Expert systems are still a big part of A.I., and it's a multi-million-dollar business, and lots of expert systems running to this day.
But it seems to be less important than it was in the '80s and '90s.
And since we haven't covered that much in the course, let me just say a little bit about it:
An expert system is when you go out, interview an expert, you say, "How do you do your task, what you do?"
And then try to encode that into a program. And rather than trying to encode it directly into Java or C,
you do it into a language that's specifically designed to capture this expert knowledge.
And sometimes that works great, but there are some difficulties.
One of them is that sometimes the experts don't know how it is that they do it.
So they know how to do the task, but they don't know how to explain it, they don't really understand the steps,
all the steps that they're taking, and so they can't explain it properly.
Another problem is that most of these languages were based on logic rather than on probability,
so if it's a clear, "A implies B," then it works well, but if there's uncertainty involved, then the languages weren't very good
at describing that uncertainty. And so they were limited in their application.
(Sebastian) Yeah, I guess today, the best (unintelligible) to do expert systems is Bayes Networks,
which really (unintelligible) uncertainties quite a bit. And they have their own problems, but they've been used
just like expert systems in larger applications today.
(Peter) Right. And I should also say that kind of the point of view of what computers are has changed since the '80s.
In the '80s you were dealing with large mainframes or even workstations, which were supposed to be smaller,
cheap computers, still cost $50,000 each. And so this was like the salary of an expert.
And so you wanted to replace this expert to get your cost back.
Today we think of computers as being helpers that are all around us. We have ones in our pockets,
on our desk, we're always carrying a couple with us. And so the canonical application of A.I. is not so much,
"Can we replace an expert?" but, "Can we help someone out in their daily life?"
(Sebastian) You know, I would love to be replaced by a computer. Honestly. So we could just go to the beach all the time
and have a good life. (Peter) I don't believe you, Sebastian. I think if you were replaced with your current job with a computer,
you'd find out some other job to do. (Sebastian) Yeah, but how do the students out there know that we're real?
We could be robots. (Peter) We've done a really good job of our artificially intelligent robots here, and we are on the beach right now.
(Sebastian) I think sometimes I sound like a robot, speaking for myself. (robot sounds) All right, next question.
"What are some big open questions in artificial intelligence, specifically for someone pursuing a Ph.D.?
"What is the best way to prepare for a doctoral course? What should one study before doing this?
"And sub-question, how can A.I. and machine learning be differentiated?" This is by a student in Heidelberg, Germany.
Hi, Heidelberg. (Peter) So I would say don't worry about the big open questions in A.I.
Just worry about doing something. So go out and find a task that's interesting to you. If you're interested in robots
or computer vision or whatever, just go out and start doing something, and at some point you'll get to the point
where you can't download a package or read a paper that solves the next thing, and then you'll know,
there you have an open problem. Doesn't have to be a big open problem, but it's one that's yours and is relevant to you.
(Sebastian) Yeah, so one of the things I teach my students at Stanford is that up to a Ph.D., you're in a mode
where someone gives you a problem and you have to solve the problem.
And when you do a Ph.D., you have to invent the problem at the same time, and that's a skill that is not native to people.
So you work on something, and you think you're solving a problem, and you get stuck by doing something interesting, regardless,
and what you really found is that you worked on the wrong problem.
So while you're trying to find a solution, you have to also find the problem that you're trying to solve.
That sounds like a red herring--you cannot find a solution and a problem simultaneously--but that's what it is to get a Ph.D.
If you stick with one problem and it's unsolvable, you're stuck forever, and if it's trivially solvable, it's just not interesting.
So being open to new problems as you work is one of the key skills. So one way to do this is when you do something
and you come across an interesting problem, write it down so you don't lose it. And later on, when you solve your problem,
when you get bored, go back to these written down problems and see if there's a more interesting one in there.
Second thing I want to say is I think it's actually important to work on big open problems for society.
Not a (unintelligible) problem, you don't want to solve all of poverty or all of cancer, but as a visionary thing that guides you,
so that you can explain to yourself and your grandmother that if you solved the technical problems you're out to solve,
you'd have a positive impact on society. I find this really important because a lot of academic institutions miss this point,
and people get engraved in a specific problem formulation. And sometimes they're good, but sometimes they're
really really bad, and even if you solve them, you haven't really changed a thing.
I really care about changing big things in society, like solve poverty, solve diseases, solve transportation, solve architecture.
There's amazing opportunities, I think, to solve big problems. Of course, take them as a guideline in your life,
not as the immediate problem you're trying to solve tomorrow morning. But do that, because it's really important.
(Peter) Another societal problem we're interested in is education, and so that's why we're here,
and we really appreciate that you're there and are participating in that experiment.
(Sebastian) And you should tell the students the story of the frame problem.
(Peter) Oh yeah. So we were just talking before of when we were in school, and if we had asked our advisors,
"What's the important problem to solve?" the list that was given then probably wouldn't be seen as so important now.
So one of the big problems then was known as the (Prain) problem, and it was solved.
Ray Rider was the most important one who did the most work on that.
But once it was solved, we didn't really get to where we wanted to be.
It didn't really mean that we could solve more practical things in the real world.
We solved an artificial problem, technical problem within A.I., but it didn't lead to practical solutions in the world.
(Sebastian) Yeah. When I grew up, it was the biggest problem. It was, "Solve the Prain problem and you're famous,
"you solved A.I." And then it was solved, and it was trivially solved, it turns out, it was really trivial.
The problem made no sense anymore, it was like an artifact of a specific way of using logic, the way logic shouldn't be used.
And nothing changed in the world, right? When it came out, people didn't even care about it.
And yet generations of students had written Ph.D. theses on how to solve it.
Today, generations of students have been writing Ph.D. theses on whether P equals nP.
And I venture to say, if you solve P equals nP, not much is going to change.
We're going to solve it, and we're going to say, "Oh, that's interesting," or maybe it isn't, but I don't think much will change.
(Peter) If P does equal nP, then it was constructive. (Sebastian) I doubt it.
I think if there were an efficient solution to exponentially hard problems, you would've found at least a couple of them so far.
And sometimes you find equivalency class complexity where there are theoretically the same,
practically have such a vastly different constant, that the difference doesn't matter.
So I don't think, I don't have any hope that this problem is interesting to work on, to be honest.
(Peter) Yeah. So I guess the conclusion from all this is don't listen to your advisors.
And so our advice to you is don't listen to us, right? (Sebastian) Yeah, that's true.
(Peter) Okay, so go out and solve some problems. Make up some problems on your own and solve them.
(Sebastian) Goodbye. (Peter) Goodbye, thanks. (Sebastian) Bye.