This is what the numbers
activity file should look like.
So down here, we deleted the for
loop and added
these three lines of code to create an
adapter and then set it on the listView.
Now we also modified
the activity_numbers.xml layout file.
So in here, notice that we used
a listView and it has an ID
list, by the way on Android Studio
if you show the preview window for
the activity numbers layout file
you notice that the device preview
shows a list of items and sub-items.
So since a list view needs to be
populated with list items using Java
code and not XML this is just a preview
of what it could look like, but
when you check your device you
won't see these exact items.
All right so
let's run the app on a device now and
this is what it should look like
displaying list numbers one through ten.
We also see a divider
between each list item and
this divider comes built in with
listView but you can customize it or
even hide it completely by
modifying listView XML attributes.
For our use case we're going to
leave the dividers as is.
Well now that we have a listView and
adapter in our app.
Let's go ahead and figure out what
on Earth they're actually doing.