Finally, I want to point out
one other aspect of JavaScript.
And that is memory management approach.
JavaScript is garbage collected,
which means for
us developers, we don't need to worry
about pointers, deleting objects, or
how to handle local variables,
any of that.
We can just declare things like this and
forget about them.
The downside is that the JavaScript
engine has to handle that itself, and
when it decides to run the garbage
collector, nothing else runs.
This can trigger visible
pauses in rendering the page.
Like I said earlier, the JavaScript you
write isn't the JavaScript that runs,
thanks to JIT.
So it's not always easy to predict
whether your code is going to be
garbagey.
It also depends heavily on the
frameworks and libraries you use, and
how you structure your code.
That's why you need to measure first.
Well, the good news is that Chrome's
DevTools will show you memory usage in
your projects.
Okay, take a look at this.
I made this a while ago.
Don't ask me, it's pretty weird.
I'm not sure what kind of
mood I was in that day.
Yeah.
Anyway, what we can do is,
we can see the memory usage of
this demo in Chrome DevTools.
You can see up here,
I've switched on the memory profiler.
And I'm going to run it like so,
and I'm going to stop.
What we see is this
sawtooth pattern here.
And that's actually fine.
We expect JavaScript to use some memory.
And eventually,
when this drop-off happens,
that's the garbage collector running.
There are two things we're looking for
here.
Firstly, are there a lot
of fast climbs here?
That can indicate that we're assigning
a lot of memory very quickly and
very often.
Secondly, when the garbage collector
runs, does it take it back to zero?
If not, we might have a memory leak.
If we're interested in a little more
detail on the garbage collection, we can
switch off the memory profiler here and
then go to the search down here.
If that's not on your screen,
you can hit Cmd+F or Ctrl+F.
Enter GC into the field.
And then hit Enter.
In my case, I've got seven results.
And I can step through
them with these arrows.
And you can see, for
example, I'm only spending
a fraction of a millisecond here.
If you find that you're missing frames
because of garbage collection, then
there are some fabulous resources you
can use to learn more about patterns and
practices that will help you
avoid creating too much garbage.
Check out the instructor notes
if you want more information.