Step 9 is to implement
the onActivityResult.
Now, the onActivityResult
override takes three parameters.
There's an int for the request code,
there's an int for the response code,
and there's an Intent.
The only thing we're really
interested in checking for is,
on the request code to see if
we're an RC_SIGN_IN and if we are,
we take a look at the response code.
If the response code is Result_OK, then
we want to set our signed in status to
STATE_SIGN_IN, which basically means
that we want to keep catching errors and
handling errors because they may be
more intent, such as the account or
such as the permission screen.
Otherwise if it's not Result_OK,
then we know we're actually
in a signed in state.
So we're good to go.
We just set our sign in
status to be signed in.
This is everything that
the onActivityResult needs to do.
See if you can implement it,
I know it's a little tricky.
If you get stuck,
the code is in the speaker notes.
But check this box when you're done.