We're going to take
the example just mentioned and
illustrate how you can do this Alteryx.
We're going to count how many
customers fall within five miles
of each store location.
We start our workflow with two files,
a store location file.
It's in Alteryx native format
with the extension yxdb, and
the other file is a customer
file in CSV format.
Notice that the customer's
file has a latitude and
longitude field associated
with each of the customers.
We can use this data to create
spacial points for each customer,
making it possible to use this
data set for spacial matching.
Now let's go back to
the store locations.
Notice how this file has field called
spacial obj with a value point.
That means that the records already have
a point spacial object attached to them.
To confirm this, we can simply add
a browse tool and run the workflow.
When we do this,
we can see points on a map on the left.
We'll use cloud made maps
as the base map layers, so
that we can view the map
with reference map layers.
But if we add a browse tool
to the customer's file,
we'll see only tabular data, no map.
So we know that this file is
not spatially enabled yet.
To spatially enable a file,
we go to the Spatial category, and
select the tool called Create Points.
Once connected,
we identify the longitude and
latitude fields in the customer file.
By adding a browse tool and
then running the work flow,
we'll see the customers on a map.
Coming back to the stores,
we wanted to find the trade area around
each store as a five-mile radius.
To create this,
we add in the Trade Area tool.
And we're going to specify the value
of the trade area to be 5 and
the units to be radius in miles.
Let's bring in a browse tool so
we can see the radii.
Browse tools always have to be used when
we're looking at the actual map objects.
They're not required for
looking at tabular data.
We can see the trade areas here,
and if we look close,
we can see that there's overlap
between two of the trade areas.
This could actually be removed by
going back to the Trade Area tool and
selecting the option
to eliminate overlap.
When we run the work flow again, we can
see that the overlap is eliminated,
basically by drawing a straight line
on the edges where the two radii meet,
getting rid of the overlap.
Next, we'lll use a spacial match tool
to find the customers that fall
within the five mile radii