Now we're going to add images to the
recording buttons. Right now we have the
Main.storyboard file open. But first
let's double check and ensure we've
created IBOutlets correctly for the
recording and stop buttons. Click the
assistant editor, hide the utilities
panel and double check to see if we have
IBOutlets for both of our buttons.
It looks like I don't have them, so I’m
going to add them real quick before we
get started.
All right now we're good to go. Let's add
images to make this app look even better.
I’m gonna go back to our standard editor.
Let's click on this Assets.xcassets
file in the project navigator.
This is the assets catalog for our project.
We're going to add a new image set.
Start by clicking on this plus
button on the bottom of the screen,   and
then select New Image Set. Let's name
this set to RecordButton. Click on the
existing name once and wait for it to
let me edit. And we’ll name it to
RecordButton. Now we need images for 1x
2x and 3x. We're going to explain 1x 2x
and 3x in full detail in UIkit
fundamentals later. For now just know
that we need different sizes for
different iPhones and iPads. Ok so what
images will we use? Lucky for us, our awesome
graphic designer Joseline has already
created these images for us.
You can download them in the resources section.
All I need to do is drag the
correct icons from the Finder folder
into the corresponding Xcode box. So let
me find the image for recording.
Here we go.
I'll drag the Record.png to the 1x box.
then Record@2x to the 2x box
and Record@3x to the 3x box. Now that was
a little tedious to do for each image.
The good news is that we can shortcut
that process. For the remaining images,
just select them all in Finder and drag
them into the assets catalog.
So here I've selected them all and I’ll
drag them into the assets catalog.
Awesome since our images have the same
names with 2x and 3x suffixes,
Xcode automatically knows how to create image
sets for each one.
Alright now that we have our assets in place,
let's add an image to our
recording button.
Back in Storyboard, select the Record
button in the document outline and make
sure you're showing the inspectors. And
let's find the image property for this button.
Click the drop-down and select
RecordButton. Note that our button now
has an image and text. We could remove
the Record text, since the image plus the
Tap to Record label does most of the
explaining for us. So I’ll delete Record
and make sure you press Enter for
the changes to take effect. Adding the
image to our button may have caused our
AutoLayout constraints to break. We can
fix this easily with the help of Xcode.
Click on the yellow disclosure arrow
in the document outline. Here we see the
AutoLayout issues. One is with the
recording button one with the recording
label and one with the stop recording button.
Recall that everything on the
screen is positioned based upon the
recording button’s position. So we need to
fix that first. Select it by clicking the
yellow triangle and make sure
“update frames” is selected and then fix the
displacement. This adjust the positioning
of our Record button. For these other two
issues, we’ll choose the update frames as well.
First let's fix the Record Label.
update frames Fix Misplacement. And we'll
do the same for the Stop Recording button.
update frames Fix Misplacement.
Great, they are all correct and properly
positioned based off of the Record button.
Now before we move on, I want to
show you a shortcut for situations like these,
instead of fixing each issue one by one,
we can fix them all at once.
I’m going to purposely move each of our UI
elements, so that their new positions
will conflict with what we've told
AutoLayout.
Now we see three warnings like we had earlier.
This time when I select the
yellow triangle to update the first frame,
I’m also going to select Apply to
all views in container. This should fix
the problem for the other UI elements,
because they all belong to the same
containing view. Boom that was easy.
Alright last thing, let's turn off that
green background. With the recording
button selected in the document outline,
let's find its background color property
and change it to the default transparent option.
There we go.
Our recording button looks much better now.
Below you'll find steps for adding
the icon to the stop recording button too.