To answer question 1 no. Thousands of
notes, images and whatever else a user
might store would be way too much
information for NSUserDefaults to handle.
The performance of your app would be
terrible.
The answer to question 2 would also be
no way. Even though NSUserDefaults could
store videos as NSData, it would be a
horrible idea.
videos are way too big for poor
NSUserDefaults. These would both be great
jobs for Core Data. we’ll learn more about
Core Data in lesson three. To answer
question 3,
yes, it would be a perfect match for
NSUserDefaults. This class was designed
for saving precisely this type of simple
user preferences. Go NSUserDefaults.