So how would you use analogical reasoning to design an agent to answer Raven's
progressive matrices? This might be a tough question at first,
because the agents we're designing only operate in one domain,
taking the Raven's test. They don't look at other areas. So, we're
going to get the knowledge necessary to do cross domain analogical transfer.
In this instance instead of the agent doing the analogical reasoning,
maybe it's you doing the analogical reasoning.
Can you take inspiration from other activities to inspire how you
design your agent? Or can you take knowledge from other activities and
put them in your agent, so that it can do the analogical reasoning?