In this exercise, we will set up
a notification that will eventually pop
up every fifteen minutes while
the phone is being charged.
The notification will remind us to drink
a glass of water and when we click on
it, we should be able to see the
application in the foreground again so
that we can update our account
by clicking on the cup icon.
However, for the sake of simplicity, we
will start by setting this notification
to pop up every time we click
on this notification button.
Just the test notification
functionality.
Then in later exercises, we will be able
to get a scheduled job that will trigger
this notification every fifteen
minutes in the background.
The first step is to create a
helper method called contentIntent that
will create the pending intent which
we need to pass to the notification.
Inside we'll create a new explicit
intent that will lunch the main activity
in the provided context by
creating a new content object and
passing in main activity class.
And then we get to call
the getActivity in PendingIntent,
to create the PendingIntent instance.
We pass to getActivity the context,
a WATER_REMINDER_PENDING_INTENT_ID,
which is just an integer value that
we declared initialized above.
The actual Intent that
we just created earlier.
And we've set the flag
to UPDATE_CURRENT.
Since we shouldn't expect to
recreate the same pending intent,
FLAG_UPDATE_CURRENT should work fine.
Because if we do create
a duplicate pending intent,
it will keep this instance valid and
update the extra data associated
with it with that of the new intent.
Next, we need another helper
function that will prepare a bitmap
image to display on our notification.
let's call our method LargeIcon and
set it to return a bitmap.
Inside, we need a content resources to
be able to decode an image resource.
And then using BitmapFactory,
we can call decode resources,
passing in the context resources.
And the resource ID of the cup image.
Then we just return that bitmap.
Now that we have those
two helper functions,
let's create a method called,
remind user because charging.
This method will create and
display the actual notification for us.
We will set it to take in a context.
Now, to create a notification,
we use something called the notification
builder to describe it, and then
a notification manager to display it.
The notification builder
constructor takes a context.
And we can call a bunch of setters while
creating it to set up our notification.
Like setting the color to primary color
and setting the small icon and large
icon of our notification to our imagery
sources and the bitmap we just created.
Also we get to set the title and
text of our notification.
And here we are just using the string
resources that we have created for you.
You can also set the style which
here I've used the BigTextStyle.
But you can check more styles
in the comments below.
We've also set our notification
to vibrate by default.
But to do that,
we need to add a permission in our
Android manifest to allow for vibration.
So after we add that permission,
we can go back to our constructor.
And then make sure
that we set the intent
to the pending intent
to help to function.
So the notification and
set the AutoCancel to true, so
that the notification get's
cancel when we click on it.
Finally, set the priority to high.
But setting such a priority will
cause the notification to pop-up
using the Android's new heads up style.
But because the heads up feature
is only supported by Jellybean and
above, we need to add this
if condition up here.
Now that we have a notification builder,
we need to create an instance of
a notification manager to display it.
As we have mentioned earlier,
the notification manager
is a system service.
So to create an instance we do that by
calling context.getsystemservice and
pass in the notification service name.
This returns a general object,
so we need to cast it to
the notification manager class, and save
it in our notification manager instance.
And then finally now,
we can call the notify method
in the NotificationManager.
We pass in an ID, which we've
initialized and created above here.
And we've passed in
the notificationBuilder.build method.
Perfect, okay.
So to test this,
let's create a dummy button that when
clicked, Will pop up the notification.
To do that, let's go to the activity
main and then just at the very bottom,
add a new button that
says test notification.
And on click we can create a new
method called testNotification.
Where inside all we do is call
remindUserBecauseCharging.
And pass in this as the context.
Now one last step we need to
do is to add the single top
attribute to our MainActivity so
that when you click on the notification,
it launches the already open activity
and doesn't start a new one.
Okay, we're done, let's test this.
And now lt's click on
the TEST NOTIFICATION and
the notification pops up perfectly.
Also when we clicked on the
notification, the app shows up again.