In this exercise, we've taken out the
random kicks the ball is receiving, so
that you can make the ball move
around in response to the arrow keys.
We've added two new constants,
acceleration and max speed.
If, say, the left arrow key is pressed,
what we want to do is subtract from
the velocity in the x-direction
the acceleration times the frame delta.
If the right arrow key is pressed,
we want to add the acceleration times
the frame delta to the x velocity,
similarly with the y velocity.
When we're done changing the philosophy,
we also want to cap how
fast the ball is going with a call
to the clamp method on vector two.
While there's no physically
inspired reason to do this,
and the drag in the system does a good
job of slowing the ball down, anyway.
Allowing arbitrarily high velocities
in your game often sets you up for
some very strange behavior
down the road, like,
things teleporting through walls and
so on.
All right, time for
you to add arrow key movement to a game.
As usual,
the real story's in the course code.
Check out the to-dos to get started.