In the other lessons of this course,
we've talked about some of
the pedagogical strategies.
Some of the research methodologies.
Some of the existing tools and
some of the broader issues
in educational technology.
With this knowledge, you're now
equipped with the information you need
to start to solve some problems or
investigate some phenomena.
In case you're curious
what you should look into,
though, we're going to spend this lesson
talking about some of the open issues
in the educational technology community.
We'll talk about some of
the problems that still exist,
that haven't been solved
by technology yet.
And we'll talk about some of the
phenomena that have been introduced or
emphasized by technology.
You really could use some investigation,
could use some better understanding.