So it needs to get
the new reported height.
>> Okay.
>> From the event that has occurred, and
it doesn't necessarily need to aggregate
anything down to the file manager.
It just has to change the size
of the view port itself.
Well, if the viewport size changes,
there might be more lines.
>> I see.
>> So it has to be responsible for
getting those lines if necessary.
>> That's true.
And I guess I overlooked
that it would also need.
Okay, so first things first is it
needs to get the new location of,
or based on the height it's going to
get the new position of the scroll bar.
And that scroll bar will
indicate if it needs,
well, the scroll bar doesn't move.
>> Okay, so this raises an ambiguity,
and it's good to raise ambiguities.
So the act,
if the size of the window changes,
the height of the tray for
the scroll bar changes.
So, at least in absolute terms,
the position of the handle may change.
But its relative position may or
may not change.
Okay, so go ahead.
>> Then based on that
>> It needs to request from the file
manager any additional lines
of support [CROSSTALK].
>> Okay.
And what was our other
indirect effect here?
If we now have, let's say,
a smaller or larger window?
The proportion of the skull
bar walls have changed.
>> The handled proportions can change.
>> Can change.
>> Okay.
So, the if we're aggregating all of
this, the viewport is then responsible
for informing all it's other
components of what it needs.
And asking them to make whatever
changes they have to make.