Here's the solution I had in mind.
Now this running time charges
you separately for flop time and
communication time, but, in fact,
doing the local multiply and
doing the sends and
receives are completely independent.
So a natural idea is to
try to overlap them.
That suggests that I
start the communication.
While the communication is pending,
do the matrix multiply and then wait for
the communication to complete.
So that's it, overlap,
computation and communication.
Now, why do I say that might improve the
running time by up to a factor of two?
Well, if you overlap computation and
communication, then the running
time should be the max
of the time to do the flops against
the time it takes to communicate.
This is a factor of 2 faster
because of an algebraic fact.
Namely, the sum of a and
b is always less than or
equal to twice the max of a and b.
That's why I said up to a factor of two.