And, what, what about what happens when you call super and
you go outside like, to process a Python script?
So in terms of working set, is that, is that, do you, are you
consuming memory from within the virtual machine or are you running outside?
The reason I ask is if you wanted to have a, a large fan out like,
50 instances of a volt and they're all going to run a Python program.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Unix will usually keep the program memory one copy, and
then and then the data is, is separate from the-
>> So, Python runs extremely friendly, but then stop?
>> Yeah. >> So, I mean a Debian is ee,
a Debian process on the [INAUDIBLE] occur in Java, all goes through the model of
the stoneworkers that it will be mentioned to you, right?
On another hand, the Python Topologies worked differently.
They acquired and also, like, the Python processes what do
you call it, created separately hanging off from the JDM, some work.
So then, what, what the, some worker gets the data, and
the data is to the Python has a couple be, couple bases, and
goes into a Python process, and it comes back to GVM before it opts to DVM.
>> So, that is a very different [CROSSTALK].
>> So, the child-child process, so
there's, if there's 50 instances, there's 50 childs.
>> Yeah. So, it's, yes.
>> Processes, basically.