First, import the sales
data into Alteryx.
Next, filter the data to
show only data from 2010,
including the week ending
on January 1st, 2011.
We'll add the formula tool and multiply
the weekly customer spend per store,
by 1.064 to calculate the 6.4% lift and
a new value for
average weekly customer spend.
Now we're ready to bring in the number
of weekly customers per store per week.
Let's import the data from the weekly
customers per store Excel file,
selecting sheet one for our data.
We'll use a join tool to combine
the data, joining on store ID and
their week ending value.
Also, we'll deselect the right values
of both columns to avoid duplicates.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Next, let's calculate the total
spent per week, before and
after the new candy introduction,
using the formula tool.
The formula for
total spent per store, per week,
is simply the average spent per
customer times the number of customers.
We'll repeat and calculate
the predicted new spend per customer.
And finally,
we'll calculate the difference
between the two total spend values.
Running the workflow,
we can see the new values.
[SOUND] The total spend column is
the average spend per customer times
the number of customers.
The new total spend column
is the predicted average
spend per customer times
the number of customers.
And the difference is simply
the difference between the two columns.
Our last step is to aggregate
the values for the entire year.
We use a summarize tool and select
the sum for the total customer spend and
new total customer spend and
the difference.
Running a workflow provides our answer.
The total sales amount in
2010 was $1.3 million.
Had we introduced the new candy line,
the total spend may have
increased to $1.38 million,
or, an increase of $83,462.