Welcome back.
All right, so today we continue on our tour through multiple views and
views, and today we're going to talk about homographies,
which we learned a little bit about last time, and a cool thing, mosaics.
In particular last time we talked about a variety of
projected transformations that said there were some special cases like
translation similarity that did not divide out by that last time.
But then the general case had eight degrees of freedom.
Eight coefficients and
you did do that division to go from homogeneous to inhomogeneous.
And that last one, the one that used all eight, was called a homography.
And we're going to use that extensively today.