Aw, yes!
You're now able to create
many shopping lists.
And get an ever expanding list of lists.
Now when you open a list,
I've provided in the drop down menu this
little menu item that says Remove list.
It opens a dialogue for
us to be able to delete the list.
But I haven't connected
it to Firebase yet.
Could you do that next?
Before you implement remove,
I got a quick question.
Given what you know about how
the FirebaseListAdapter works, and
that this is a class that helps keep
an array on your phone, in sync with
an array from Firebase, what should
happen when you click Remove?
So, your options are,
you manually remove the ShoppingList
from the FirebaseArray, and
this triggers an update in
the Firebase database via a listener.
Option B, is that you manually
remove the shopping list from
the Firebase database instead
of from the FirebaseArray and
then that in turn updates the array.
So this is basically
the opposite of option A.
Option C is that you actually have
to go and write the code to manually
remove the shopping list from both the
Firebase database and the FirebaseArray.
And D is that you actually
don't have to do anything.
The data is actually automatically
removed from both the Firebase database
and the FirebaseArray via a listener.
Once you've answered this question,
I'll send over a spec for
the remove functionality.