If your code passes all the tests,
congratulations!
This has been a pretty major project.
You've mastered some serious
skills in data base programing.
If it's not quite there yet,
don't give up.
It's normal for projects to go through
a lot of revisions before they're
feature complete.
Chat with your fellow
students on the forums, or
consult with your coach on things
that might have you stuck.
When you're done,
take a moment to reflect on what
you've accomplished in this project.
Are there any aspects of the design or
implementation that
ended up surprising you?
Things that you looked up
in the documentation, or
things that you discovered?
If you like, write down a surprising
fact you've discovered here.