>> The bottom line is in order for you to pick a threshold if you wanted to do
this sort of analytically, what you need is a noise model.
And unfortunately, this noise model is not the same model as the thing we
were going before.
It's not our line, it's our dist, it's our belief.
I'll use the word belief, maybe, instead of model of no, because it's model.
It's a model of how that the, the noise behaves.
So let's go back to our line example, you remember this?
So if we were just looking at a line so let's assume that we,
you know, we have this real line and
that our points are perturbed by a Gaussian by Gaussian noise.
This is the thing we looked at last time.
So the distance in a Gaussian is sometimes a complicated thing.
So you've got multi-dimensional Gaussian, you may know about Chi squared and
that the, and the square root of that is the distribution of, of the distances.
In one d, it's actually much easier.
It's essentially what's called a half normal.
Because basically, you know, the probability that you're d, o, a is, it's,
you could either be d this way or d that way, but d is only a positive value.
So it's just twice the regular Gaussian distribution.
That's what this dis distribution here looks like.
Because it says, d greater than zero.
But all that matters is given a noise model,
you could generate a distance model.
And given a distance model, you could pick a threshold.
So in fact, if you have this 1D Gaussian, let's say and
let's suppose it has a distribution of, of parameter of sigma squared,
then you could set the threshold t, based upon t squared.
Is this number 3.84 sigma squared?
Where the heck does 3.84 come from?
Well, I just arbitrarily said, lets pick a threshold such that
95% of the inliers would fall within that threshold.
So 95%, if you got sigma squared then I said, t squared at 3.84 sigma squared.
If you wanted 99%, you'd have to make it bigger threshold.
If you're willing to remove some points, you'd make it a smaller one.
But the idea is that you have some threshold.
And then you're going to accept the point if the distance D
is less than that threshold, you'll count that point as an inlier.
Okay?
Cool. All right.
So let's see, we've got our number of points.
We have our distance threshold t, it says what we did here before.
We've go one more.
The number of samples we're going to compute.
Now this is not s, the number of points within a sample.
Right? A sample is a set of points that it takes to compute a model.
This is how many times are we going to draw a sample.
How many models are we going to try and check.
So what we'd like to do is we'd like to choose N to be big enough.
That we can't actually guarantee that we're always going to get inliers, can we?
Right?
Because if we're randomly picking points, et cetera and
unless we were to exhaustively pick all, say, N choose two.
If we're just randomly picking things, it's only with probability that we
can say that, what's the likelihood that we got a good solution?
So what's we're going to do is let's pick a probability p and
what we want to know is how big does N have to be,
such that the probability is p, let's say, 0.99, 99%.
That at least one of our samples will just be made up of
points that come from the correct model?
Right?
So, that's a way of saying if,
if this line, I actually get two points that really came from the line.
Or another way of saying it is, I've got this,
all these putative matches that are compute and I want to compute a homography.
I want at least one set of four matches that I
test to actually be the correct homography.
All right.
So the question there is can we figure that out?
And in particular, it should be pretty clear.
What if all the points were right?
That is all the matches were right.
Well, then as soon as you pick some set of four, you would have four
points that's correct and you would get the right homography.
What if none of the point matches were correct?
Well, then you could be there all day and
you're never going to get four that match.
In between those is that there's some percentage of points that are not correct.
So if the ones that are correct are called inliers,
what do you thing the ones that are not correct are called?
>> Outliers.
So the question is for a given percentage of bad points, for
a given outlier ratio E.
So let's, E is 20, is 20%.
Means that 20% of your points are bad.
For a given ratio, how many samples do we have to check?