All right, you're done.
Let's take a look at my solution.
We start by adding a string that we're
going to display when the list is empty.
For now, we're just going to
make this a generic string,
just to inform the user that
we don't have weather data.
Next, we'll create a layout to be
displayed when the list is empty.
The TextView can just be added to
the FrameLayout that is currently in
the main fragment layout.
Since we will either be displaying it,
or the list content.
For consistency, we specify
the padding using the dimensions we've
already defined in Sunshine.
Finally, we need to tell the list
view that we have a layout for
it to display when it is empty.
We'll add it inside of onCreateView
right before we set the adapter,
and that's it.
We've made our app slightly more
friendly, but we can do more.
Let's test this to make sure
everything's working well.
We'll do this by uninstalling Sunshine,
putting the emulator in airplane mode,
and then launching.
So let's go to our emulator now.
We'll test this by first
uninstalling Sunshine.
Then we'll put the emulator
in airplane mode.
Now we'll launch the app, and
as you can see, we've an empty list.
Now when we leave airplane mode
our sync adaptor will run, and
bam, we get our list content again.
Getting out of schedule the way
network becomes available is
one reason sync adaptors are awesome.