Next, you'll be tasked with inserting
weather data into the database.
But we'll be doing this in a more
efficient way than just one day at
a time since there's always a week or
so of data to display.
Instead of one insert at a time,
we'll be doing a bulk insert,
which basically tries to insert an array
of content values, not just one set,
into a database.
It will respond to the URI that
identifies the directory of weather
data.
And then iterate through the array
of values and enter each one.
To write a book insert,
we'll override the book insert method
in the weather provider class.
This method takes in the URI in
an array of content values and
it returns the number
of values inserted.
The bulkInsert will start with
the same database accessing and
URI match code that you've seen before.
In this time,
inside our weather directory case It
will also include
a database transaction.
A transaction is a way to mark the start
and end of a large data transfer.
So you want to start a transaction,
then try to do all your inserts and
finally end the transaction.
So here we begin the transaction and
also initialize the number
of rows inserted to 0.
To try inserting and then end the
transaction we'll use a try statement to
do our inserts and then something
called a finally block of code.
Which will execute after
everything in the tri is complete.
In the tri we'll loop through all our
content values in a four each loop and
in the loop we'll insert each days
weather into the underlying database
using DB.insert.
And if an insert's successful we'll
update the number of rows inserted.
After this foreloop is complete, we set
the transaction state to be successful.
And down in this finally block,
we'll just end the transaction.
After the finally, still in the whether
directory case we'll notify the content
resolver that a change has been
made to the directory URI.
We'll do this with a call
to notify change, and
we'll also return the number
of rows that were intereded.
And finally,
we'll want to handle the default case.
In the default case, you can just return
the super implementation of bulk insert.
This is the implementation in
Android's content provider
class that this weather
provider extends from.
And lastly, don't forget to
delete this run time exception.
And that completes an efficient
book insert method.