Let's quickly check that you
remember the definition of power
as it relates to energy and time.
Consider two systems, A and B, each
one is characterized by its execution
time to do the same computation
as well as its execution energy.
Now, suppose A uses less energy than B,
but B takes less time than A.
If it helps,
let's visualize this relationship.
This is an energy time phase diagram,
and here's system A and here's system B.
Here's my question, which system
has lower average power, A or B?
If you think they have the same
average power then check them both.
Or if you think there's not enough
information to tell, then check neither.