Now let me actually have
you play around and
generate another simple way of encoding
the direction and intensity of lights.
Again, three different examples,
basically select which rst will
be highlighted for 2 and 3.
And I'll tell you what rst is.
What we're going to do is we're
going to focus in onto this region.
And of course, any ray of light in
this thing is basically coming in.
So if you notice in this form I
basically created a bunch of small
pinholes within this whole system here.
There's a lens, but down here,
after the light goes through the lens,
I've created a bunch of pinhole sensors,
right?
Smaller pinholes, and here I'm just
showing you an example of three.
Any light goes through this
pinhole will hit this one here,
and this one will go hit there, and
the straight one is going in the middle.
We will end each one of these pin
holes create three different regions,
r, s and t.
Right?
So of course in this case, when the
light is coming in, it's going through
the pin hole, the straight line
is straight, going straight to s,
this one is coming and hitting r, and
this one is coming and hitting t.
So let's see what happens in
the case of the first one.
I have the object at the right distance,
and
here I've just kind of color-coded
the lines red, green and blue.
Not to imply the red, green and
blue channels, just to differentiate it.
When it hits, basically, this instance,
you notice what's happening.
Now of course, to help us,
we can create a small decoding
platform out here, r, s, and t.
So here, of course,
this red one is coming in,
converging to the blue point,
and hitting this point.
Looking at this, this basically
suggests that red should be t.
The green one of course
is s as it should be.
And the blue one is r.
So, here in basically,
depending on where we are,
we are able to create a decoding in
this simple three by three grid,
to figure out where different
light sources are coming in.
Again, these are not red green and blue,
I'm just showing you rays of light.
So, for these two I would actually
have the same thing right?
Except this time around
the rays of light are not
converging to the same point.
Remember the previous
two experiments we did.
And for the far object, same thing.
Simply put, I want you to now fill
out the r, s, and t for this, and
for this, as to which ones would
be the ones highlighted for
the red light, the blue light and
the green light.
Just fill out the regions correctly, and
I will show you the answer in a bit.