Let's try and apply this equation to bring an object into focus.
Here's our lens, and image plane.
Now say we have an object point p,
that gets projected onto the image plane at point p prime.
Now let's complete the pin lens diagram.
We know that, rays of light from p that are parallel to the principle axis after
refraction, cross the principle axis at a point that is focal length away.
So that distance is f.
Similarly on the other side, that is also f.
The distance of the object from the lens is z.
And the distance between the image plane and the lens is z prime.
Let's say the focal length f is 50 millimeters.
Now consider two scenarios, one where the object is one meter away, and
second where the object is two meters away.
At what corresponding values of z prime would the object be in focus?
Enter your answers in the boxes provided in millimeters with up to
two decimal places of precision.