But first, let's actually just
have a small quiz to kind of make
sure that you folks are following
what's going on here.
Again, notice this video is the one that
was shown in the previous video too.
It's basically a camera that's
being panned from right to left.
In this case, of course you can
imagine it wasn't a tripod and
mostly it's a simple pan.
And it's slowly done.
What we are interested in is using
this to generate a panorama,
but at the same time,
of course not getting carried
away by actually trying to do things
like matching all of the moving parts.
So here's a question for you.
I have various ways of
building panoramas, right?
I can actually have a small
part of a frame and
I could then basically ask the question,
how can I build a panorama?
In this case, I have a video,
which basically would mean I would take
all of the video frames, and register
and align them to generate a panorama.
So that would mean is,
I would take this video and
as it's moving from right to left,
I will take all of the frames from this
one and generate a panorama like this.
Is that a legitimate way
of doing panorama building?
Or is this the other method?
And in fact,
this is the method you may recall again,
that we may have been playing around.
That is, I take basically
from all of the video frame.
Just select six different frames.
Of course, I'm talking about six.
It could be many more.
And again, remember all of the things we
may recall again from panorama building.
So, the question for you is, which of
these two methods is legitimate method
to generate panorama,
also could the answer be, both?