So our first step will be to create
a schema and a contract class.
So creating a database schema
is just a fancy way of saying
you need to plan out
your database structure.
And to do so,
we answer these two questions.
First, what is the name of the table?
And second, what are the names and data
types of the columns in these tables?
So what's nice about this
part of the planning process?
Is that you're a cool cat,
who's already created a database schema.
So to jog your memory, remember
this CREATE TABLE statement, And
how we could use our .schema command
in the SQLite 3 program in order to see
the statement used to create our tables?
Well using that, we can answer
these questions about our database.
Now, I'll leave that up to you
as part of the next exercise.
So here's our exercise for
identifying the schema.
So for this given SQL statement,
answer the following questions.
First, what's the name of the table?
And what are the names of the columns,
and their corresponding data types?
So as hints,
remember that the table name and
the column names were chosen by us.