All right Charles, so
what have we learned?
>> We have learned that unlike Texas,
you can mess with reward functions.
>> And what does that mean?
>> Well, it means that you can take the
rewards that you're given and you can
modify them to still get the same policy
but maybe to learn it more quickly.
You can shape them.
And thus shape the experiences
of your agent.
>> And I think we talked about three
different ways that we can do that.
Do you remember what they were?
>> I remember one of them,
potential functions.
>> Sure, that was the last one.
>> So, also you can just do a shift.
You can just add a constant, and
it doesn't matter what that constant is,
so long as it's a constant.
And you can scale them, so but
you want to scale positively, so
it does matter what that constant is.
>> Otherwise we can swap max and
min by accident.
>> RIght.
But
I think the difference
between the third one and
the first two is that the first two
sort of don't change anything at all.
They're just a kind of simple
linear changing of the function.
But the potential functions are set
up to help you learn faster,
not just learn the same thing.
>> So have we learned anything else?
>> Well,
I think we learned something, or
at least we, there was a subtle thing
we should have learned, which is, well,
potential functions can
help speed things up.
But we got the potential functions by
just talking about shaping rewards,
by just trying to change them in a way
that captured the parts of the space
that were better than others.
This is kind of pre-potential functions.
So I would say we learned about
reward shaping in general, and
that we learned that you
can do it really wrong.
>> And what happens when it goes wrong?
>> Well when it goes wrong,
you end up in these kind of
sub-optimal positive feedback loops.
And, in fact, the answer to that was
potential functions and that keeps us
from getting into these loops because we
subtract off the things that we gained.
>> Sure, okay, I'll buy that.
>> Okay, so that's good.
So we learned about reward shaping and
all of its various forms and learned
that it can hurt you and that potential
functions are a way to avoid that.
And potential functions
are kind of magical.
>> They do some really clever things.
It's probably good if on
the homework we look at some ways
of building potential functions.
Which things tend to speed
up more than other things.
So some nice empirical questions there.
And we should probably dive into that.
>> Yeah, I like that because I think one
could walk away from this thinking well,
potential functions are just magical,
they work, and everything's okay.
Except clearly then there must be
better potential functions than others.
Must be some that have no real
impact on learning, well,
have no impact on the speed of learning.
In some sense, all we showed is that
potential functions don't prevent you
from finding the right answer, but
presumably, you can come up with a
potential function that actually hurts.
>> Yes.
Right.
It could
lengthen the amount of time
before good behavior is learned.
>> Right.
Okay, cool.
Luckily we have homework for that and
the students can figure
that out on their own.
That seems great.
>> [LAUGH] All right, cool.
Well thanks so much for
going through this with me.
>> No, no, no.
Thank you Michael.
I enjoyed every moment of it.