Let's take a look at each of
the choices that are given.
The first statement is not correct.
The Linux O of 1 scheduler was O of
1 because it took constant amount of
time to select and
schedule a task regardless of the load.
The second statement is sort of correct
in the sense that as long as there
were continuously arriving higher
priority tasks, it was possible for
the low priority tasks to keep waiting
an unpredictable amount of time and
possibly indefinitely and
therefore, starve.
But this was really not the main
reason why the scheduler was replaced.
The final choice was the main reason.
Recall that we said that the common
work, workloads were becoming
much more and more interactive and
were demanding high predictability.
In the 01 scheduler with the active and
expired list,
once the task was moved to the expired
list, it had to wait there until
all of the low priority tasks
consumed their entire time quantum.
For a very long time Linus Torvalds
resisted integrating a scheduler that
would address the needs of the small
interactive tasks in the Linux kernel.
His rational was that Linux was supposed
to be a general purpose operating system
and should not necessarily be addressing
any of the needs of some more real
time or more interactive tasks.
And therefore he liked the simplicity
of the offline scheduler.
However, as the general purpose
work loads began to change,
then a general purpose operating system
like Linux, have to really incorporate
a scheduler that would address the needs
of those general purpose workloads and
CFS was really meeting those needs.