So what do you think?
I think the answer is 6.125 times 10
to the -10th squared microns per bit.
Start with the area.
Then divide by the capacity.
You'd end up with something like this,
area divided by the capacity in
bytes convert bytes to bits.
So what kind of
screwball number is that?
Let's zoom in on a bit.
Assuming this area is square, let's
take the square root of our answer.
That will be about a quarter
of an angstrom on a side.
Whoa, man, that is small.
It's basically the radius of an atom.
A single classical bit like this one,
as opposed to a quantum bit,
probably doesn't get any smaller.
And that in fact is the point of this
exercise, at some point you won't
be able to squeeze any more bits
into a given volume of space.
And at that point you
won't have any choice but
to think about locality
in order to run fast.