Next, we consider a randomized algorithm
for finding a minimum cut in a graph.
Likely this won't be as
familiar as quick sort.
We're given a connected graph G and the
goal is to find a minimum set of edges
whose removal from the graph causes the
graph to have two connective components.
This set of edges is
called a minimum cut-set.
Note that this is a different
problem from the minimum s-t
cuts that we considered in
the context of maximum flow.
There are no two particular vertices
that we're trying to separate here.
Any two will do, and
all the edges have equal weight here.
We can use the Minimum S-T Cut Algorithm
to help solve the problem but I think
you'll agree that this randomized
algorithm is quite a bit simple.
The algorithm proceeds by
repeatedly contracting edges so
as to join two together.
And once there are only two vertices
left they define the partition.
I'll illustrate with an example.
Consider this graph, and suppose that
we decide to contract this edge here.
Then these two vertices are going to
get collapsed into one.
And we're going to delete this edge,
like so.
Note that we keep all
the other edges in the graph.
Even if they end up being parallel
that is between the same two vertices.
From this graph,
suppose that we choose this edge here.
Then contracting this edge
will delete this edge
as well as this parallel edge here,
like so.
From this group,
suppose that we contract this edge.
Deleting these two here, as well.
Then the final result
is this graph here.
And from the result, we can read
off both the partition, 1, 2,
3, 4, on 1 side, and 5 on the other, and
we can also read off the cut-set
represented by the 2 remaining edges.
Just 3, 5 and 4, 5.
That is these two edges
here in the original graph.
Now, this particular choice of edges,
led to a minimum cut-set.
But not all such choices would have.
How then should we pick
an edge to contract?
Well, it turns out that just picking
a random edge is a good idea.
More often than not this
won't yield a correct answer.
But as well see even so
it will yield a correct answer
often enough to be useful.