And the last part of Sun RPC that
I wanted us to talk about is
the binding process.
The binding process is initiated by the
client using the following operation.
So, clnt_create with
a number of parameters.
For the specific squaring
example that we talked about,
this operation will look like this.
We will specify the host
name of the server,
as well as the protocol that we want to
use when communicating with the server.
And we will specify the name of the RPC
service as well as the version number.
These two arguments of
the clnt_create operations
are auto-generated in the RPC
generation process from the .x file.
And will be included in the header file
in the .h file as hash defined values.
What this means is that if the client
needs to now support a different version
number, it will need to be recompiled,
given that this is essentially
a static piece of information.
However, none of the other portions of
the client code have to be modified.
Also note that the return
from this operation
is a variable clnt_handle
that's of data type CLIENT.
This is the clnt_handle that the client
will include in every single RPC
operation that it requests.
And this handle will be used to
track certain information, such
as what is the status of the current
RPC operation, any error messages, or
it can even be used to capture certain
authentication-related conformation.