you've reached the end of the deep
learning module congratulations boy just
like Sebastian right there
thank you i try to be just like
Sebastian so do you feel like a deep
mourning expert now
well I wouldn't necessarily say expert
but I think I know what tools I've got
all right I think you're ready to build
the behavior of cloning network the team
at Udacity has built an awesome
simulator for you it's going to be your
job to drive your car around the track
collect data and then train a deep
neural network to do the driving for you
so how would you approach this kind of
problem
well i guess i know i compute the
gradient yeah and then once I got to
stop stop stop this is deep learning but
not computer vision denoting already
have no focus
good morning got it okay that I think
I'd go fire by simulator thank you when
you're done you're going to have an
awesome portfolio project to show off
actually that was kinda cool