The only correct answer is Virtual Box,
but let's talk about why.
First you must recognize that the goals
of the system or platform virtualization
are different than what's intended
by the 'ava Virtual Machine or
hardware emulator,
as in the case of Virtual GameBoy.
Remember that according to Popek and
Goldberg,
a virtual machine is an efficient
isolated duplicate of the real machine.
GDM is a language run time which
provides system services and
portability to Java applications,
that it is very different than
the underlying physical machine.
Also, emulators like virtual GameBoy,
they emulate some hardware platform,
the GameBoy platform, but again,
this is very different than the hardware
platform where this emulator is running.
With system virtualization, this is,
in the case of Virtual Box,
the physical hardware that's visible
to the virtual machine is identical,
or at least very, very similar,
to the physical platform
that actually is supporting
the execution of the virtual box, yes.