Sometimes apps have no data to display.
For example, there may be no new
messages in someone's email inbox, so
as developers we need to handle
this situation gracefully.
Well designed apps will even try to
make the experience a little bit more
pleasant with say a cute graphic for
example.
Even better would be to fill the empty
space with some starter content or
advice on how to get started.
This will vary based on what's
appropriate for your app.
For now,
let's focus on a very simple Empty State
that clearly communicates that
there were no earthquakes found.
This is much better then
having a blank screen.
Now, you're welcome to expand on
this and make the Empty State more
sophisticated in the future,
but the question of whether or
not the USGS web server will ever return
zero earthquakes, is a different story.
And in any case, it's ideal for
our app to contain logic to handle
the scenario if it ever happens.
Fortunately, the Android framework team
already expected that this would be
a commonly used case.
So they exposed a way for
developers to set an Empty View for
a ListView which will only be displayed
whenever there's no data on the list,
meaning the adapter's dataset is empty.
In this coding task,
you're going to implement this
behavior in the Quake Report App.
The first thing you should
do is modify the xml layout
to the earthquake activity to have
a view group that contains two children,
the ListView and
the TextView for the empty view.
Now, the Empty View and the ListView
should be sibling within the parent
view group,
both siblings should overlap.
And the ListView should take up
the full height and width of the screen
while the TextView should be
centered within the full screen.
Once you've updated the layout,
next I want you to modify
the EarthquakeActivity java class, so
that in the on create method, you set
the Empty View method on the ListView
object, and pass in the Empty View.
Here's the documentation for
the setEmptyView method.
What's its said when there
are no items in the list,
the entry framework will hide the list
view and make this EmptyView visible.
If there are items, however,
the ListView will be made visible and
this EmptyView will be hidden.
All these changes and view visibility
are automatically handle for
you which is pretty sweet.
One more caveat I want to point out is
that when you first launch the app,
there is data yet
because we haven't finished loading it.
To avoid having the no earthquakes
found message blink on the screen
briefly while the data is being loaded
for the first time, only assign
the text in the empty state TextView
after the first load is completed.
So here, in the onLoadFinished method.
Now, can you think of a way to
verify that the Empty View works?
Here's a little hint.
You want to temporarily
comment out some code.
Check these boxes when you're done.
Then you can try the bonus challenge.
Do you know of an Android app that
tries to make the empty state
be a pleasant user experience?
Go ahead and share a screenshot in the
discussion forum linked below the quiz.