So there's a couple of different ways to
get your function to produce some sort
of output.
You should already be familiar with
using console.log to print out messages
to the console, which you can do inside
a function or directly from the console,
which is something we did way back in
the very first lesson of this course.
Now, if you remember all
the way back to that lesson,
when you first used console.log, then
you might also remember seeing the word
undefined displayed after your message.
So the question is what is undefined,
and where exactly is it coming from?
Well, in reality, undefined is
actually what is being returned
back from the console.log
function when you call it.
You see, any function is always going to
return some value back to the caller.
If a return value is not specified,
then the function will just
return back undefined.
When you call console.log and
pass it a message, you are,
in effect, calling the console.log
function, passing it an argument,
which is your message, and
then it's returning back undefined.
However, the function is also printing
out the message back to the console.
So the way to look at it is there's two
different ways you can get your function
to produce some sort of output.
The first way is printing
messages using console.log.
And the second way is by
using the return keyword and
a value to return back
some value to the caller.
Two important things to point out
here is that the return keyword
will be used to stop
the execution of a function, and
it's going to return
a value back to the caller.
If nothing is defined as
a value to be returned back,
then undefined is going to be
returned back automatically.
Now, if that didn't make any sense,
let's look at some code, and
hopefully it will become
a little more clear.
Now, one thing to keep in mind as
I do this is that console.log and
return are not the same thing.
So this example should show the key
difference between the two.
All right, so I've got a function
here that I've written
to tell me if an integer greater
than two is a prime number.
Now, if you're not familiar with
prime numbers, a number is basically
prime if it can't be divided by any
other numbers besides itself and one.
That's not a super formal definition for
a prime number, but stay with me.
The important thing here is that you see
the difference between console.log and
return.
So the way this function works is if
an integer passed to the function
is a prime number,
then it's going to return true.
It's that simple.
But if the number is not prime, then
it will print to the console the first
number that our integer that we're
passing, here, is divisible by, and
then it will return false.
So, again, don't worry too much
about the details of this function.
But I'm going to copy it and
paste it over into the console.
And then we'll run it and
see what kind of output we get back.
All right, so I know 11 is a prime
number, so let's call our function and
see what we get back.
So I'll type isPrime(11),
and we get back true.
Perfect, that's what we want to see.
If you look at our function, that means,
when I passed 11 to it,
that it started at the number 2 and
went all the way to the number
10 because we're less than 11.
So this loop would end at number 10.
And it never found a number
11 was divisible by.
So it never hit this
conditional statement.
It never got inside this
conditional statement, and
it just returned true, okay.
Now let's try passing it another number.
So how about 49 because
49 is an odd number.
It's kind of weird, and
I can't really remember if it's
divisible by seven or not.
So, okay, cool.
So it is divisible by 7, and
we get the return value of false.
Again, if you look at our function
that means when I passed 49 to it,
that we started at 2 and looped until 7.
And when the loop reached 7,
our condition finally evaluated to true.
So once that happened, it printed 49 is
divisible by 7 to the console,
and then it returned false.
Now the key thing here is that when
this return statement was called,
this return false,
our function completely exited.
It didn't keep looping over more numbers
to find out if 49 was divisible by 8,
9, 10, and so on.
It printed this out.
And then, once our function
hit the return statement,
completely exited the function,
we were done.
So let's recap, biggest takeaways here
are that a function is always going to
return something, okay.
Let me remove these, return.
And let's run our function again without
the return statements in there and
see what happens, okay.
So now I've remove the returns.
And let's call isPrime,
and we'll do 49 again.
So it still prints out our statement
that 49 is divisible by 7.
And it looks like it's not divisible by
anything else either because it would've
continued to loop here and go 8,
9, 10, all the way up until 48.
But you'll see that here
it didn't return anything,
it just returned undefined.
So if you don't specify
any sort of return,
then your function's always just
going to return back as undefined.
So the second thing to remember is that
console.log is not the same thing as
a return statement.
So console.log is great for printing
out values to test your code and
giving you helpful feedback, but
it's not a return statement.