In the first lesson, we talked
about how to set up an experiment
by identifying the variables and
setting up treatment and control groups.
In this problem,
you'll need to figure out whether or
not one of your customers clicked
on the link to download the App.
Let's apply what you've
learned to your new task.
The target variable, in this experiment,
is whether or not an individual clicked
on the link to visit the App and
loyalty information page.
This is a binary target, yes or no.
The experiment will compare the
difference in the click-through rate for
the control and treatment groups.
A click-through rate measures
the percentage of people that click
on a link or visit a page.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The treatment variable is
which Web page they see.
The treatment group will
see the modified page,
and the control group will
see the original page.
Control variables and random
experiments are used to ensure that
both the treatment and control groups
are representative of the population.
This helps give confidence,
that if the change were applied
to the entire population
you could expect to see the same results
that you observe in the experiment.