AsyncTask has three generic parameters,
params, progress and result.
And the AsyncTask method utilize
this generics as place holders for
the actual data type we want to use.
You see the methods signature
refer the param, progress and
result placeholder data types.
When we subclass
a AsyncTtask in our app,
we can substitute the placeholders
with the data types we want to use,
like string or earthquake or
other object types.
I'll explain the purpose
of each generic parameter
in the context of
the below code snippet.
The download files task class
is meant to take one or
more URL's, download each of them while
publishing progress along the way.
And finally,
the task returns the total size of all
the downloaded files in units of bytes.
Once this class is defined
we can the constructor
to create a download files
task object instance.
Then, we can execute
the task immediately and
pass in any number of file
URLs that we want to fetch.
Here we pass in three,
url1, url2, and url3.
Let's take a closer look
at the class definition,
which is a subclass that
extends from AsyncTask.
Notice that the AsyncTask name is
followed by the names of three classes
in brackets.
The first generic type is params
which is the data type of the in
parameter sent to the background task.
In the code snippet
the params data type is URL.
That means the doInBackground method
will accept the list of URL inputs.
You haven’t seen this kind of dot,
dot, dot notation yet but all that it
means is that there's a variable number
of arguments that we can put in there,
this is often called varargs.
Any numbers of inputs here is
valid as long as they all have
the same data type in this case URL.
That means you can execute
the task with one URL, two URLs or
more depending on how many
files you want to download.
Back to the do and background method,
the input arguments get stored in
an array variable called URLs.
We can check the length of
the URLs array using urls.length,
then we can access each element of the
array using square bracket notation were
you're familiar with.
URL gives us access to the zeroth
element of the ray and so on.
In this example we used a four
loop to iterate to each element
of the URLs array and actually download
a file using the Downloader class.
We also keep a running total
of the size of all the files
in the totalSize integer variable.
Remember, doInBackground
happens off the UI threat.
So our app will stay responsive even if
the doing background part takes a while.
The second generic
parameter is progress.
Which is the data type used for
measuring progress of the work being
down on the background thread.
In download files task,
we periodically publish updates and
then update the UI with
percentage completed.
To do this we specify integer
as the progress parameter.
That means we call publish
progress with an integer
value while the background
work is happening.
Then, in the onProgressUpdate method
which is called by the main thread,
we received that integer input value and
can modify the UI.
Again, we see the three dot notation
following the input data type here,
meaning that we can accept a variable
number of input arguments.
If you call publish progress from
a background thread with two values,
then in on progress update
you will receive two inputs.
This functionality is useful if you're
downloading multiple files at the same
time, and want to show the different
progress values of each file.
Similar to the URL inputs above,
the progress variable is an array.
We can access each progress value using
the square brackets with an index
position, such as progress zezro.
Then we can update the UI
with a new progress value.
Similar to the URL inputs above,
the progress variable is an array.
We can access each progress value using
the square brackets with an index
position such as progress 0.
Then we can update the UI
with the new progress value.
Now, we've come to the third and
final generic datatype called result.
Result is the datatype of the return
value from the doInBackground method.
You can think of it as the datatype of
the result from the background work.
In this case, we return total size once
all the files have been downloaded.
The method signature of doing background
specifies long as the return data type.
Note that long is
spelled with capital L.
In the past, we've seen that long is a
primitive Java data type just like int,
that covers a wider numerical range.
However, generic data types must
be an object data type here.
So we use Long with a capital L,
which is just an object version
wrapped around the old,
primitive long data type.
In the AsyncTask the Long result
gets passed to onPostExectute.
Which is now back on the UI thread.
We don't use the variable arguments
notation with dots in this case.
The input to the on post execute method
has to be a single value with the data
type specified in the class declaration.
In this example,
we just wanted to show a dialog with
the file size that we retrieved.
Depending on how the sub
class is implemented,
we may not need all
the generic data types.
For examples, there may be no input
parameters, no return value, or
no progress value.
In those cases, use void for
the generic type parameter.
Make sure you capitalize v
in void because the generic
parameter must be an object data type.
Now, it's time for a quiz to
reinforce what you just learned.
Look at the provide code StepIt and fill
in the blank for the generic types and
the class declaration for
the download webpage task.