I admit that I pulled this
alpha-beta model out of thin air.
So you should be asking yourself,
where does this model come from?
Let's consider a linear or
1-D network having P nodes.
Now suppose node 0 has a message of
size n that it wants to transmit
to the last node in the network.
Let's say it does that
by taking the message,
breaking it up into n individual words
and transmitting one word at a time.
Now, let's assume this step
of preparing the message for
transmission costs you a fixed
amount of time, little a.
Then let's suppose that any time
a word goes from one node to another
that it incurs t units of time.
My question to you is,
what is the minimum time to
send this n-word message?
Type your answer here.
Now your answer should be symbolic, so
you should write it algebraically
in terms of a, little t, n, and p.
There's a little grading gnome running
behind the scenes that will do its best
to compare what you enter automatically
against our proposed solution.