[BLANK_AUDIO]
[SOUND]
>> Okay,
I think we're ready to add items,
take a look.
Each item that you request from
the store, be it a juicy intsarito or
some delectable cheesy flakes should
be represented as a object in
the Firebase Database just
like a shopping list is.
This is because items are going to have
a few things associated with them.
For example, items will have names,
they'll also have an owner for
who requested the item.
Eventually I think we'll also want to
store things like whether the item
has been bought and who bought the item.
The point is that an item like a
shopping list lends itself to be a Pojo.
So first things first,
you're going to make a pojo for an item.
Then you'll need to update
the UI to both create items and
display lists of them.
We'll just start by making the Pojo.
It should contain these two properties.
And for owner, we'll just stick
with the string anonymous owner,
like we've been doing for
the shopping lists.
Remember to follow all of the rules for
making Pojos that you learned before.
I provided a link to the material about
making Pojos in the instructor notes,
if you need it.
When you're done,
go ahead and click here.