All right, you're done.
I know that was long, but
I think this is really important stuff.
And RecyclerView is going to
be a really great and
important pattern in your future code,
I am confident.
All right, I'll show you how I did this.
And I think it's actually pretty cool
how straight forward it is in many ways
to at least get this far.
The first thing we did of course
was to swap RecyclerView in for
the listed view that was there.
And I also changed the name, so
that it would make more sense.
And I even changed the name
of our empty view here.
Even though RecyclerView doesn't
really have a concept of empty views.
I still thought it was important
to keep that parallel.
Since, eventually, we're going to try
to implement that using recycler view.
And the next thing we
want to look at and
where most the changes actually
happen are in forecast adapter.
The biggest thing of course is that our
forecast adapter is now going to ascend
RecyclerVew that adapter and
RecyclerVew that adapter will
take a paramitertized type of
the view holder, so pretty slick.
Our ViewHolder is defined here.
It's almost identical to the ViewHolder
we had before except now we have
this super class and we have this
constructor that takes the view.
And this looks a lot like
what we had there before.
The ViewHolder here is
actually designed very,
very much after the way that
the cursor adapter worked.
The RecyclerVewHolder
was designed pretty much
to be very similar to the way
that cursor adapters work.
And so we had new view,
which was there before and
now we have OnCreateViewHolder,
which is parallel.
And so the code is almost the same.
We take the view type and
we get the view group.
Now, the interesting thing is we're
actually going to have to get our layout
inflater from that viewGroup, because
there's no other ways to get this,
there's no other context
we have access to.
So sort of interesting.
Not something we're used to doing
in Android all that much but
use also has access to the context and
then we replace
what was BindBiew from the original
cursor adapter to onBindViewHolder.
And as you can see the code
remained largely the same.
Probably the biggest difference is
that we don't actually have a cursor.
We're actually using the one from the
adapter so we have to use m cursor and
move to position when we bind.
Rather than just having a cursor
that's at the right position.
So that's a fairly minor change,
but you can see other than that,
the code looks very, very similar to
what we had before for onBindViewHolder.
And then here is all the code
that actually implements
the important cursor adapter stuff.
So we have swapCursor and
we have getCursor.
swapCursor is really the only
important thing here, truthfully.
Which calls notifyDataSetChanged when
the cursor is swamped, and that keeps
that behavior of notifying the observers
that something has changed, in tact.
So there we have it.
A very, very,
very simple cursor adapter.
We're not done yet.
We still have to do some
work in ForecastFragment.
So ForecastFragment used to have
a reference to the list view.
Now we're going to store
one to the RecyclerView.
And just for fun we'll change
position to RecyclerView.no_position.
Even though it's the same value
as the list you endowed position.
And on create view we're now going to
get a reference to the RecyclerView.
And then the one thing we do have
to do is give this RecyclerView
a layout manager.
Because a lot of layout managers
there were actually people not
displaying anything.
It doesn't have
a default layout manager.
So we assign it a new
linear layout manager.
And then we can set the adapter.
And then it pretty much works similar.
Now of course,
we don't have it completely working yet.
But let me show you what you should
have gotten working by this point.
I'll run this project, and
you'll see why I warned you
all that it would be broken.
And it's really that on click handler
we don't have empty view handlers,
all these nice things that list gave
you for free we actually have to craft
ourselves with RecyclerVew.
So, first of all, you'll see
that the empty view is displayed
overlaid our regular view here,
but we can scroll and
we're getting the correct display,
so that's good.
But as you can see,
it's we can't click on anything.
So, it's definitely still pretty broken,
but it's a good start.
And we are now taking
advantage of RecyclerView,
which will allow us to use
some cool stuff later on.
But we still need to finish the work,
which is why we have using
Recycler View part two.