Here's a short quiz that looks at the principles we just covered.
Imagine that you have designed the following classes, one for a Motor, one for
a FancyMotor, and one for a Robot.
The Robot class contains within it an attribute of type motor.
That is,
it calls upon that motor to perform some computation, here called motor.run.
Assume that the Robot class is very complex, and
we now want to change it to instead make use of a new FancyMotor.
Making this change will difficult with the current design because it
violates which design principle?
There are five choices for you here.
There's the Substitution Principle, the Law of Demeter, the Hollywood principle,
the Dependency Inversion Principle, and the Open-Closed Principle.
Which of these is the one that's violated?