So let's take a look at our
responses to this exercise.
So here are the first three questions.
So in this first scenario,
with a travel app and items to pack for
traveling, most of the time when we're
dealing with some group of items that we
want to be able to read later, we'll
want to start with an array of strings.
So that's an easy way to
group bits of text and
would certainly work in this case.
So here, each item in the array could be
something like a toothbrush or pants and
these would be strings.
For a second scenario
with the YouTube app,
we'd like to store the number
of people who viewed a video.
So here in the situation since
we're hoping to store a number for
how many times a video is viewed
we can use an integer variable.
So in this scenario
with the Settings app.
We would like to store the languages
supported on Android device.
Here we're looking for
a group of items that can be read.
So we should use an array of strings.
So here is each item would
be the name of a language.
So something like Japanese or Arabic.
Now in this fourth scenario with
the shopping app and storing whether
a product is in stock or not,
since we're hoping the store some yes or
no information we can use
a single boolean variable.
The value of the boolean would be
true if the product is in stock and
false if it's not.
Now for the fifth scenario of
the lottery app and we'd like to store
the winning combination of 5 numbers for
a single round of the lottery.
Since we're looking for
a group of numbers we want to
use an array of integers.
So in this case since there are 5
numbers in the winning combination,
the array would be of length 5.
Now in this last case of the health
tracking app and storing the number of
miles or kilometers walked for
each day this week.
In this case we're dealing
with a group of numbers.
So again we want to use an array.
So it's likely that we'll be
dealing with non-integer numbers.
Now because of that we should use
an array of floats or doubles.
So data types that allow for decimals.