Congratulations, you're now
at the end of the course and
you should be proud of
how far you've come.
I want to take this
time to say thank you.
It's been a joy and a privilege
to share this content with you.
In this course we learned
a lot about networking and
how to use it in our apps.
We started with simple web requests and
built interesting and
fun to use apps that gave users
access to data over the network.
We also looked at how to design our
networking apps while adhering to
the model view controller paradigm.
Those are the two key takeaways
I want you to finish with.
Making web requests, and doing so
while considering good design.
These alone can get you pretty far,
and they'll be crucial for
completing on the map,
but I know you can do it.
So now it's your turn to go out and
network for yourself.
Again, thank you and
always remember, keep learning