So now that we have talked about the
importance of isolation of user code and
the hardware support with
the process execution mode,
memory protection, and so on.
I think it should be clear that
if you're the bad guy, and
I did say that the operating system
has the keys to the kingdom,
the best thing you can do is actually
compromise the operating system.
We said well if using user code,
it's hard for you to do that,
because if you tried to touch something
that belongs to the operating system,
the hardware is going to stop you.
So attackers actually have
been really creative,
because the operating system of the
trusted computing base being such a big
target, they have been really creative
in terms of how can they gain access
to the operating system and
the information that it keeps or
maintains to control
access to resources.
Now, I want you to explore these three
different options that we have here and
then we'll talk a little bit about them.