So you needed to select this element and
change the text.
To do that,
you can look at any classes or
IDs that the element might have
by inspecting the element.
Notice that the title is in an h1 tag,
and it has a class of main-title.
Now, you might have been tempted
to use the select all method.
And if you did then you would've run
into the problem of selecting the text
for this H1 tag here, and
this H1 tag down below.
Notice that the selection
returns two DOM nodes.
Now if you would've just
used the select method,
then the first element on the page that
matches the selector syntax is returned.
So, in our case, this would work.
The confusion of which items
you might be selecting
becomes more of an issue
as your web page grows.
The number of elements increases and
the number of class names and
IDs can increase as well.
So, to avoid any confusion, it's often
best just to use the most specific
selector syntax in your select method.
In our case, the HTML,
H1 tag is okay, but
I think the class name selector
works very well in this case.
So, let's use a class of main
title to select our H1 tag.
Finally, we set the text
of the HTML element
by chaining the .txt
method onto the selection.
We pass in the text we'd like
the HTML element to have, and
then we run it in the console.
Now we have our new title for
our main content area.