So if you look these up using your
favorite search engine or online
encyclopedia or other reference work,
these are the answers you should find.
A CNAME record is what's used to make
an alias from one name to another.
And it actually stands for
canonical name.
It means that the canonical, or
official name for this name is actually
something else, it's an alias.
Now a quad A record is the IPv6
equivalent of an A record.
It's an address,
it's just an IPv6 address.
The name is kind of a joke since v6
addresses are four times longer than v4
addresses, that's how I
always think of this.
And lastly,
the NS record type is a DNS name server.
An NS record for
a particular domain says
what DNS servers have the records for
that domain.