OK so the first pattern is *S* so
that will match anything that
contains a capital letter S.
So that includes GiantSquid,
and Squid, and
this Queen mp3, but it doesn't include
these which all include a lower case s.
You might have noticed that
*S* matches Squid.avi,
even though there's nothing
before the capital S here.
Star can match zero characters.
So the next pattern is Squid*.
That matches only things that
start with the word Squid.
That will be Squid.avi,
but not any of the others.
And finally we have this
one with a question mark.
Remember question mark
matches a single character.
So this will match p-a-s-s-w-d
as well as p-a-s-s-e-d.