That actually means that, and this was more important a little while ago,
but people still use it today.
If I wanted to let's say, do a convolution of a function with some
really big mask, which is generally expensive operation, I actually could do it
a slightly different way, all right, and that's shown here, right.
Suppose I want, g to be f convolved with h, let's suppose f and h are both very
large things, so you remember convolution is ugly cause it's N squared M squared
where N is the size of the image N by N and M by M, well so what we can do is,
we could actually take the Fourier transform of F, and a Fourier transform of H.
And, there are fast ways of doing Fourier transform called the FFT for
fast Fourier transform which we won't talk about, but
I can do those Fourier transforms quickly then I can multiply,
those two Fourier transforms together to get the new Fourier transform, and
then I can do the inverse Fourier transform to get back the answer.
Like I said, this was really important when machines were slower,
these days people tend to work in the spacial domain, but even today,
if you have a large mask or some large function you're trying to convolve
against a large image, it's not uncommon to use the Fourier trick to do that.