I want to talk just a quick second about computational complexity.
Mentioned it before.
As we said, if your image is N by N and your kernel is M by M or
we will call it W by W for sort of width.
And it's easier to say W being different than N because [INAUDIBLE].
Exactly, okay?
So the question is how many multiplies do we need?
And we said before that we need N times N times W times W,
or N squared W squared.
Doesn't N squared W squared sound better than N squared M squared?
Because when I say N squared M squared you have no idea what I'm saying if I
say it quickly.
N squared W squared works.
And that can get sort of big.
So there's a cute little property.
Sometimes your main kernel, your, your filter,.
Can be created by convolving a single row with a single column.
And when that's true,
you can take advantage of the associative property, in terms of how we do this.
And this is what's refered to as a linearly separable kernel.
So let me show you an example.
So here we have a single column, and here we have a single row.
And just think of 0s being around it.
If I convolve this column by this row I would get out
this new H which has 1 2 1 2 4 2 1 2 1 in it.
Okay? So c convolved with r equals H.
See, this is why we don't use my handwriting.
Let's suppose we wanted to filter something with H.
All right?
So that would look like this.
We have a function G that we're going to create by convolving F with H.
But we said that C convolved R is the same as H, so that convolves F.
And because of the associative property,
C convolved with R then convolved with F.
In order to get our new function,
is the same as C convolved with R convolve with F.
And the reason that's better is that I can do
two column convolutions instead of one square.
So now instead of being W squared N squared it's 2 times W times N squared.
And that can be,
that used to be very important when computers were not quite as fast.
But it's still reasonably important, because for
example, if W is say a 31 by 31, that's a factor of 15 difference, all right?
So that's more than an order of magnitude.
Anytime you can do anything that buys you an order of magnitude for
not a lot of money.
You should go ahead and make that purchase.
Because orders of magnitude are hard to come by.
So here's a nice way of doing this.
So when we do various kinds of smoothing,
etc, often we use linerally separable filters and you can just apply them.