Well the class model diagram is the components and their structural properties.
The composite structure diagram is the internal structure and
the possible interactions among them.
The component diagram is the organization of the physical
software components in the system.
Deployment diagram, that's the physical system resources and
how they map the hardware.
The object diagram, that's the static structure at a particular point in time.
The package diagram, well,
that's the one with the logical groupings and dependencies.
And finally, the profile diagram, that's extensions to the UML meta model.
Notice that there's a lot of overlap among these terms, which say,
that the different diagram types have a lot of overlapping themselves.