Let me try to give you some intuition as to what goes wrong when we write grammars.
Now, suppose this is the universe of all possible strings, sequences of words,
and suppose this--I'm drawing a Venn diagram here--is the language that we're trying to specify.
The ideal is that we can write a grammar which is very close to that language.
Say we write a grammar that specifies a language which we'll call Lg, the language specified by that grammar,
which is very close to the actual grammar. It only misses in a few places.
Now, if actual grammars were neat things like this rectangle here, then it would be easy to write grammars like that,
and we'd be in good shape. But it turns out that natural languages are not like that;
natural languages are messy, biological things that have evolved over time for use by humans in a variety of contexts,
and they are messy. They aren't just rectangles like this. They're funny-shaped things that go out in different directions.
To write a grammar for that is much more complicated.
We could write a grammar that covers everything, but then there'd be other stuff out here that it covers that it shouldn't cover.
We could write a grammar where everything in the grammar is grammatical, but then there'd be lots of other grammatical things
that are in the language that are not covered by the grammar.
Or we could try to deal with cases one at a time. We could start with this grammar, and then say,
"Well, let's say I add a little bump here to deal with these exceptions,"
and another one to deal with these exceptions, and hope that those rules to deal with exceptions are approximately right.
They got a little bit wrong. And hope they don't introduce an error someplace else.
Maybe if we introduce this rule here to try to capture this bunch, we inadvertently also capture another bunch over here.
And it turns out that over decades of trying to write grammars that fit natural languages just right has proven to be
an extremely difficult task. And so now we'll see some tools that go beyond the simple context-free grammars that we saw,
the grammars of the form "S goes to nP vP" that can get us closer to this ideal of having coverage
that covers the messy natural language.