You now have the ability to control the
flow of your JavaScript programs using
conditional statements and loops.
With just these simple tools,
you can already build some
pretty impressive programs.
>> However, as the problems you
face get more and more complex, so
too will the code you write.
But there's an easy way to fix this.
>> As the code gets longer and
inevitably,
there will a code that repeats
the same number of steps.
Instead of repeating the same steps
multiple times, we can package
up those processes into reusable
chunks of code called functions.
>> To understand why functions are so
useful, let's think about something
you might use in your day-to-day life.
>> How about a microwave?
We've got one right here.
>> Yeah, that works.
When you use a microwave
to heat things up.
>> Like pizza?
Because I hate cold pizza and we just so
happen to have some
cold pizza right here.
>> Yeah, like pizza.
When you use a microwave to heat things
up like pizza, you first need to
tell the microwave how long to heat it
up for based on the number of slices.
Let's say it takes about a minute and
a half per slice.
Then you need to set
the microwave to 50% power.
Since you are reheating the pizza,
not cooking it.
And after all that, you hit start and
you wait, and then there's your pizza.
[MUSIC]
This method for
heating up pizza works, but
it could be quite time consuming having
to set the microwave every time.
Thankfully at least in our microwave,
there's a pizza reheat button that
sets the power level in heating time.
>> James just needs to tell
it how many slices he has.
>> This pizza reheat button
works like a function.
Functions are just lines of code all
packaged together that we can use and
reuse when we need them.
In most cases,
a function is given some data,
performs operations on the data,
and then returns the altered data.
>> The input you give the function or
argument as it's usually
called in programming is
the number of pizza slices.
The operation it performs is setting
the power and time to reheat the pizza.
And it's returned output
is the reheated pizza.
>> It's like a shortcut.
>> Exactly.
The pizza reheat button hides
the steps for reheating pizza and
makes it easier to reheat as
many slices of pizza as we want
without having to redo all
the settings from scratch each time.
>> That's assuming all the pieces
will fit in the microwave.
>> Right.