For our second exercise, you might
be shocked that you need to open up
the second exercise project,
display toy list.
It will contain the next
valuable to-do items.
Any feeling of deja vu that you might be
experiencing at this point is completely
understandable.
Your next task is to go to
the Java Source Code, and
declare the text view variable.
But then we need to get a reference
to the text view from the layout, and
set the text view to display
the string containing the large list of
toys we've given you as part
of our concerted effort
to relieve you from
unnecessary creativity.
Feel free to come up with your
own toys if you don't like ours.
But how do we get a reference to our
text view that was created when our
layout was inflated?
First, we'll have to go to the layout,
and give the text view an ID.
Which is a numeric identifier
that Android uses to identify and
located the text view fortunately
the Android tool will actually
come up with a number for us.
We just need to assign it
a descriptive name like this,
@+id/tv_toy_names.
The @ sign tells the tools not to treat
the stuff inside the quotes as a string
literal.
And to instead, look for the contents
inside of the Android resources.
While the plus sign tells the tool to
create the id if it doesn't yet exist.
The id preceding the slash, lets
the tools know that we're creating an id
rather than a reference to something
like a style, string, or image drawable.
Then we return to the text view,
and use r.id.tv_to_named
with the findViewById
method to find our view.
But where did that mysterious
TV toy names constant come from,
that's very similar to what
we entered into the layout.
Well the R class is autogenerated
by the Android tool chain.
But because Java doesn't allow for
slashes in variable names,
the tools replace the slash
after the id with a period.
Then we get our toy names arraigned and
we can just call text view append
method with each of the toy names.
Separating each toy with with
a series of three line separators,
which on Android happens to be a \n.
All right, now it's your turn.
So we really want to do this in order.
We first add the ID to
the TextView to the layout XML.
This allows us to find it
within the Java source.
Finally, we've given you array of
strings containing different toy names.
You write code to take each of
these strings from the array and
append them one at time to the tax view.
Separating each one with 3\n