All right, so here we are,
back in Android Studio again.
Let's go ahead and look at the layout
design for Chatum Latinum.
So, there's actually three files that we
looked at that make up the design, but
the most important one that we want to
see if we can essentially flatten
is the layout XML for our individual
chat items, or distinct rows.
All right, so just to be clear,
whenever I'm going to bring up
the Chatum Latinum activity again.
And the layout that we're
concerned with the most here
is the individual chat items
that we see horizontally here.
So let's go back and take a look.
So here's the markup for
our individual chat items.
As you can see here, we have a similar
design to almost the unoptimized version
of the compare layouts activity
that we looked at just previously.
Now, this is a natural way to create
a list item, again it's nested in
structure or following something that's
similar to the dom like the web.
But this nested nature of linear
layouts is not necessarily needed.
And we can go ahead and
flatten a bit more.
So let's take a look at how we can do
that, I'm going to bring up a branch
that has an optimized version so
we can talk about it.
All right, so I've brought the phone
back on this screen to kind of compare
how we're able to achieve the same
design, that originally started as
nested, into a flattened version
using a relative layout.
Now as before, we have this image view
in our layout that represents the chat
avatar, but when we implement using
a relative layout, this can be sort of
like an anchor, that we specify
some other items relative to him.
For example, we have a bunch of text
on this screen, we've got the chat
author name, we've got a date and time,
and then we have the actual chat text.
And this is all declared in the IDs for
the individual text views.
Now, let's see how we can orient
them in a relative nature.
So, for example, we took the chat
author name, and we used this attribute
called layout to the right, to describe
it to be on the right of the avatar.
In similar we also did the same for
the chat text, which is also specified
to the right of the chat avatar.
But then we need to determine
that the core of the message,
actually lies below
this chat author name.
So we use this layout attribute to
say below the chat date and time.
And then lastly,
we have a chat date and time here, and
we do a small little adjustment to
make sure that stays to the right,
using the align pair right attribute.
So look at that,
with this relative description and
this relative design we've flattened our
layout, achieved the same thing visually
and gained a bit more performance,
as you saw in hierarchy viewer.
All right, so the main idea is
that when you're revisiting and
refactoring your layouts, see if you can
look for opportunities where you might
have inefficiencies like nesting,
and replace them
with implementations that are a bit more
flat, like this relative layout design.
All right, that was great, thanks a lot.