Now I'd like you to define the remaining
transitions according to our state
diagram.
This will be a programming exercise.
Please add the appropriate mythic
calls in this area of the code.
Make sure you use action ID 0 for
each of the actions you define.
Since each of the remaining
states besides the initial state
has only a single action.
You may also notice I've added
a getDomain method to the class.
This is workaround to allow
our greater to see the domain
object inside the first MDP class,
for the purposes of our grading.
This sort of method is
discouraged in practice
because it violates encapsulation
by exposing this private member.
For these burlap programming exercises,
clicking test run will compile and
run your code as it is in the editor.
Clicking submit will
run the grading script.
For this exercise,
the grading script will call the
constructor of your first MDP class and
check that all the required transitions
are present and are deterministic.
You can write test
code in the main method
to check that your solution is working.
We started you off by calling
the first MDP constructor, so
you can make sure no
runtime errors are thrown.
If you want, you can dive into
the Burlap API on your own
to learn how to examine your
domain object more closely.
One place you might consider starting,
is in the documentation for
the domain class.
You can use the getAttribute method to
find the number of nodes in your domain
object, checking the validity of
the actions is a bit more complicated.
It involves the getActions
method of the domain class.
As well as the getTransitions
method of the action class.
We'll provide the code used by our
grader in the solution video after
the quiz if you're interested in seeing
how to examine these objects yourself.