That ends the first lesson on frequency analysis, it gives you some relation
between sort of what's in the image, and the frequency components in it.
Next time, what we're going to do is we're going to talk about how filtering and
convolution are expressed in the frequency domain and
that's how it allows us to get to aliasing.
I'll also say if you didn't follow everything that just went through,
that's okay, I really just want you to sort of
stay focused on this idea of frequency, and the con, and the Fourier transform.
And then, as a way of, of getting the different elements.
And then I'm going to show you how the frequency transform relates to sampling,
which, or I should say,
frequency domain relates to sampling, which will get us to aliasing.