In the last examples, I showed you
that offsetWidth triggered the forced
synchronous layout when
interleaved with style changes.
There are other properties
that will cause similar issues
when called at the wrong time.
And you can check
the instructor notes for
this blog post from Tony Gentilcore
which has more information.
Essentially it's any property for
which a browser must run layout.
So anything to do with geometric
information like positions and
dimensions, that can cause a forced
synchronous layout to happen.
And here's something
else about this example.
Every single paragraph causes layout and
then recalc style.
Layout, recalc style.
This puts the browser into a cycle where
you read and write a lot of values and
we call this layout thrashing.
It's where you do a forced synchronous
layout, many times in quick succession.
And you would not believe how many
times I see this one out in the wild.
For instance, check out this.
Insane demo.
Yeah.
Let's record with timeline.
Do some scrolling.
And then stop.
We're going to switch
on frames with this.
And you can see immediately we're going
way over 30 frames a second line here.
Let's look in here.
Pick any one of these, and
we'll zoom in a little bit more,
with the W key on the keyboard.
And there we go.
A forced synchronous layout there.
We can also look at this
in the Waterfall view.
And notice how,
when we expand the scroll event.
You can start to see here, all the
individual forced synchronous layouts.
Each one of these is going to
make us run really slowly.