Let's step back from the quick report
app for a moment to learn about a new
control flow structure that you'll need
in the next coding test for the app.
In the first beginners course, we'll
learn about first control structure
the if else statement, by using
special Java key words if and else.
You can create different
execution paths.
Now instead of executing
every line of code,
one after the other,
you can execute one block of code and
then skip another block if
a certain condition is true.
Now we'll talk about something
called switch statements in Java.
The switch statement provides
a way to execute unique logic for
different discrete values
of a non-Boolean condition.
Here's a code example where we
execute different code paths
based on the value of a single
variable called numberOfStars
which represents number of stars
that a restaurant received.
Now, in each code path represented
in these case statements,
we can perform any kind
of logic that we want.
We just happen to be setting
a rating string to different values.
Switch statements are useful to avoid
writing lots of if statements, or
nested if statements.
Now you can achieve the same logic we
just saw in the switch statement above
with an if else statement.
But the if else approach is more repose
and contains way more repetition.
For example, we need to keep writing,
or checking numberOfStars equals, and
change each value every time.
For example, checking to see if
numbers of stars equals to one,
checking to see if numbers of stars
equals two, three, and so on.
A switch statement consists
of the switch keyword,
followed by the value we wish
to evaluate within parenthesis.
Now, between these curly braces,
we're going to go ahead and
list out our cases.
Each case consist of a case keyword.
The expected value followed by a colon,
for example, when a numberOfStars
variable is equal to 1 we execute the
lines of code within this case block.
This happens as a set of rating
string equal to bad restaurant.
We keep executing code, line by line,
within the switch statement,
until we reach a break statement.
Then it's time to execute the whole
switch statement itself and
continue executing the code
that comes after it.
Let's say, for example,
that the numberOfStars
variable doesn't equal one.
Then we skip over this entire first
case, and go to the next case,
where we check if the numbers
of stars variables equals 2.
If so,
we execute the code in here, setting the
rating string equal to okay restaurant.
And then we keep going until
we hit the "break" statement.
And then we exit the entire
switch as a whole.
We don't need to keep checking if
the other cases is math or not.
Now, if the number of stars
variable doesn't equal one or
two, then we go into the third case and
you know what happens here.
Now, you can have as many cases as
you want as long as the case value
is still an integer.
Because the original variable in
a switch statement Is an integer.
If your switch statement was testing
a value of a string variable,
then the case values would
have to be strings too.
In the lines of code within each
case can be as long as you want.
You can have zero lines of code in
a case, 20 lines of code, or more.
Here we have a special word default.
If the number of stars variable
doesn't equal any of the case values.
Then a switch may provide
an optional default case.
This is where we use the key word
default, followed by a colon.
Now if we fall into this case,
then the rating string becomes,
no rating available.
And then we break out of
this switch statement.
Now generally,
it's a good idea to have a default case,
in case the original value has a value
that you didn't write a case for.
At least you'll have some reasonable
behavior as a back up in your code.
As you may have noticed, the switch
statement has a very specific format and
uses some words that have special
meaning like switch and case.
If we check the Java key word list we
can verify that these words show up
in the list.
For example, switch is a Java keyword.
We can also see case,
break, and default.
So make sure you use
these words exactly, so
that Java can interpret
your code properly.
Here's another example
of a switch statement,
where we check the value
of a variable called grade.
Now, it's a char data type meaning
it holds a single character like a,
b, and c.
Now as you can see, the string message
changes based on the grade value.
In the case of a for example, we have
the string message equal superb work.
If you got a grade of b,
the message equals great job.
Now one interesting thing
to know about this example
is that you can fall
through other cases.
That means that the execution path
won't exit the switch they met
just because you finished a single case.
You need to explicitly add
a break if you want to exit there
Notice that there is no break
statement at the end of the D case.
If the grade is D the code is going to
fall through into the conditional code
for the F case where the message
string is set to needs improvement.
Now as we know the execution flow
is going to continue through
each line of code until we hit
our first break statement.
And then we exit.
So just to recap, in the cases
where there is no break statement
such as the D case, the code is
actually going to fall through.
Which means this logic is
actually common between the D and
the F cases until we hit this break
statement of course and then we'll exit.
Now let's test your ability to read
switch statements in the following code.
When you go into a restaurant,
sometimes they ask you how spicy you
want your food on a numerical scale.
So, given a certain spiciness level,
how would you use switch statement
to adjust the flavor accordingly?
I want you to take this table and for
each row where you're given a certain
spice level, I want you to apply that
value to the switch statement here and
then tell me what value would
be set to the flavor string.
For example, if we were given a spice
level of zero, we'd see in the switch
statement here, none of the cases
would actually be evaluated to true.
Therefore, our code would fall through
all the way down to the default case,
and therefore the flavor string
would be set to not spicy.