We've created an initial version of
the Miwok app for you to start off with.
But don't worry,
there's still plenty left for you to do.
When a professional Android developer
is joining a new project, it's very
common for the team to already have
an existing app that they're working on.
And it's good practice to learn
how to read an existing code base,
because often times you won't be
creating a brand new app from scratch.
So follow along with these instructions
to learn how to import the Miwok project
into the Android Studio
on your computer.
So first head over to this
GitHub repository link,
then click the Download ZIP
button to download the app code.
Unzip the downloaded
file on your computer so
that you have a Miwok folder.
Now go ahead and open Android Studio.
Now choose Import Project and
we downloaded it into
the Downloads folder here and
then click on the project.
It may take some time for the project
to be imported, if you have any issues,
remember to check
the troubleshooting document.
Once your app has successfully imported,
run the app on your Android device,
whether that be a phone,
tablet, or an emulator.
And it sure looks like this screenshot.
So currently, nothing happens when you
click on any of these categories and
that's expected.
To take a look at the project,
first open the project tab and
here you'll see the file directory.
When you're ready and
maybe done some exploring on your own,
move on to the next quiz.
Let's take a close look at
the code base of the app.
And by code base,
I mean all these files in the app.
Getting comfortable with this will help
us understand why the code looks and
behaves the way it currently does.
At this point,
it's totally normal if you feel nervous
about looking at a completely brand new
code base because everything looks
really foreign and there's a lot of it.
So now's a great time for you to
practice the skill of looking through
a new code base with
some guidance from us.