>From the FriendlyChat project
page in the Firebase console,
select Add Firebase to your iOS app.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
This opens up a window that asks us for
and iOS bundle ID and App Store ID.
A bundle ID is a unique
ID that Apple and
iOS devices use to precisely
identify your app.
And the app store ID is a numeric
ID that identifies one or
more apps from a single developer or
development team on the app store.
These settings usually
come into play for
apps you plan on publishing to the app
store, but since we won't be publishing
anything this weekend,
we'll use stand in values for now.
Let's go with
com.google.firebase.udacity.friendlyChat
for the bundle ID, and for
the app ID, 123456 is fine.
And we'll click Add App.
Once you click add app,
a Google Service dash info dot p list
file should download automatically.
This file contains all the information
that your app needs to find the project
on the Firebase servers.
If I click continue it will take us
through the rest of this tutorial on
how to set up our Firebase project.
Now you're welcome to read
through it if you choose but
we can just click x here because we're
going to cover the same steps now.
First open up the project if
you haven't done so already.
If you need to download the project for
this course you can do so
in the resources.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
With the project open I'm
going to expand these folders and
find our supporting files.
I'll right click supporting files and
add files to the FriendlyChat swift.
And I want to find that Google p list
file that we just downloaded and
it's in my downloads folder.
So we'll select it and add and
add it to the project.
Once it's added to the project,
if you click it in the navigator,
you'll see a dictionary of properties,
and I've highlighted the bundle ID here.
These properties will be used later
on by the code that we write.
Okay, so to recap, we've created
our app on Firebase console, and
we've added the plist
file to our project.
We should be ready to run our app,
right?
Well, not quite.
You'll notice that if you try
to run the app, it won't build.
Because among other things,
it cannot find a module for Firebase.
So, what's missing?
That's what we'll learn about next.