Let's first take a look
at these screenshots and
see what we don't really like.
First of all, it's not very clear
that this is a running game.
It just mentions this
in the last image and
the first screenshot isn't great because
it describes crystals that are appearing
but the text really obscures
a lot of the screen.
In the second screenshot there's
a lot of small things going on and
it's kind of confusing and the third
shot is just a boring intro screen.
It doesn't show anything
special about gameplay.
So these screenshots need to be
more clear and less crowded and
focus on the game features.
They could also benefit from some
explanatory text that doesn't
show up in the center of the screen.
So always design your
screenshots to be clear and
highlight interesting game features.