By the time you graduate from
your nanodegree program,
you'll have mastered relevant skills and
learned to work independently, and
we want to help you get there
as efficiently as possible.
That's why we focus
on learning by doing.
To graduate,
you'll complete a series of milestones,
most of which will take
the form of projects.
You can prepare for
these projects by taking your courses,
although reviewing all of the course
material isn't a graduation requirement.
If you come in with a ton
of prior experience,
feel free to try jumping
right into the projects.
However, most students go through
the course material thoroughly
to make sure they have the skills and
knowledge they need to be successful
in their projects and beyond.