my name is actually going I'm head of
autonomous driving here at mercedes-benz
research and development north america
in sunnyvale we started the group three
years ago out of a team of seven people
and we have grown it now up to 16 really
excited to working with hot topic
we have a very long tradition an
autonomous driving a mercedes-benz we
drove out anonymously on the highway
already 20 years ago during the
Prometheus project the latest big
achievement was driving the historic
events route from my name to call time
in 2013 showing that driving country
roads and in the city traffic is
possible we introduce the topic 0
assistant to 13 which allows you to live
semi-autonomous Lee in stop-and-go
traffic and we recently launched the dr
pilot which allows you to drive simulate
enormously on highways so we take turns
driving very seriously and I think we
have been really successful or in that
field when hiring people for the
autonomous driving team we're looking
for strong computer science skills
especially programming in c++ in
addition for prototypes were using
matlab and we are using Python for
scripting and deep learning tools
respective we are looking at the general
good understanding about autonomous
driving and how that works and we are
looking at the solid foundation in terms
of math statistics probabilistic and
algorithms when preparing for the
interview the applicant should brush up
their programming skills
secondly they should think how their
experience and education fits to the job
some applicants are surprised to hear
questions how does not number system
works and so on and people should
prepare that in advance should have an
understanding what's going on in that
field and also what procedures has
already achieved in that
field personally I want to see the
interview from the applicant that he or
she is interested motivated curious
about the topic wants to learn how it
works at mercedes we have lots of
interns and we are happy to train people
to get the right skills and get
experience in the field we have
employees from all around the world from
China are from India from Germany from
the u.s. from France from Spain from
actually all around the world
I think the winner agrees a great thing
to get the right experience in that
field so if you have already a really
solid foundation in computer science for
example you and have successfully
achieved the nanodegree you are a pretty
good candidate for first of all I love
the topics are working on autonomous
driving is terrific
probably I have the best job in the
world right now working in mercedes also
is highly motivating because we can
bring enormous cars to reality people
are coming here because they're
motivated to work on the best projects
in the world i think they are keen to
work on it
they're focused on getting the job done
and explore new ways of solving this
really challenging task of autonomous
driving in terms of T work and the
culture in the collaboration it's
awesome in here so we have highly
motivated team working together to solve
the problems
it's also man i love to come to work
every day if you want to shape the
future for autonomous cars and
mercedes-benz apply