Here's another example, which basically
talks about the registration and
blending effects that we have talked
about with panoramas, except,
now applied to video.
Again, something done in my group,
just showing you an example.
Here, you basically see
us warping around, and
moving the different view points.
There are five players still
moving around, and basically,
it comes from four different views.
All of them have some overlap,
we can register them together, and
as we move around different view points,
they get warped and morphed.
Of course, sometimes the view changes,
you can see some things kind of vanish,
but they appear from
a different view point.
So, in essence, in this instance what
we've done is basically, interpolated
and generated novel views by basically
being able to look for information
on the playground, and apply that to
be able to then model a virtual views.
Again, something we looked at when we
looked at things like morphing and
panoramas, except,
this time around applied to videos