So here's a sort of toy or a schematic, right?
So the, the general idea is that we've got some lighting.
All right? And the lighting hits objects.
And so we need physical models or models of the physics.
And the idea is that that causes light to impinge upon whatever your
photo sensitive system is.
Whether it's a, a retina or a CCD, or CMOS, or
whatever your imaging technology is, and then, of course,
that's the picture, that we're going to take a look at in the computer.
So there are all sorts of physical processes that impact the image that
you're going to see.
So, you know, here's a picture, I think,
actually, this might be from [INAUDIBLE] don't remember.
And you know, here is a picture, two pictures and
it is pretty clear to you what is going on here, right?
We've got sort of this textured stuff everywhere and
there is differential light falling on it.
There are shadows.
And so when you look at that,
you probably don't think that that's a texture painted on the, the surface of
the road, but rather that that's a shadow on a more uniform texture.
But of course, it could of been painted.
So it's your brain has to be doing something in order to understand that.
And this white tape that's shown here,
is just a little bit showing you sort of how things appear to you, right.
To you it's clear that this is a thing that's on the ground, right, that,
that is not part of the texture of the ground, but is, is something else.
So you said okay, that's one thing that is reflecting one way, and I've got
some other object, namely the, the, the asphalt, that's reflecting another way.
So that's sort of lighting surfaces and shadows.
Of course, there are reflections, right, so in both of these window pictures,
you know, you're probably guessing that's there's not like,
this thing here that's behind the window, and
maybe it's just a, a reflection of what's behind you.
Likewise, you can see in this tree, it's all distorted a little bit,
because maybe this glass isn't so perfect, but the idea is that you can
see this reflection, and that reflection is impacting the image that gets made.
Going along with reflection is refraction.
Right, so it's most easily seen in things like water, or
in various kinds of deformed glass.
So here, you know, these wavy lines on the bottom of the pool,
well, there are no wavy lines on the bottom of the pool,
at least I hope not but instead the water itself is no longer flat there.
There are some waves and
that's causing the light rays to bend in a particular way.
So, again, that impacts the image that you see.
This beautiful picture here, has got both reflection and
refraction going on inside of it.
An interesting property which is really,
it's just about reflection is what's referred to as interreflections and
both of these pictures are drawn from computer graphics.
It's not so much about the nature of the surface but what impacts the light that
you see at a point, and sometimes we tend to think of well,
there's just some light source and it's illuminating our objects.
Well, there's been a lot of work done sort of since the 90's on what's
referred to as interreflection, both in computer vision and computer graphics.
So here where we have the shiny materials,
you can see everything being reflected within it.
But I think a more subtle example is oh this is
the famous graphics teapot being rendered in a variety of ways, now of course,
in a shiny surface you know that you're going to see a reflection of this
purple teapot in front of it, but also in these partially reflective things.
You see this purple color in there?
That's reflective of this purple pot that's in front of it, so the idea is,
you have all this light bouncing around.
And all of that light can impact what's actually observed at a particular point.
In computer graphics there's a method called ray tracing, which basically,
as rays of light come in and they bounce off, they create illumination at all
these, different facets of the model, and you can get a really rich, rendering.
You know, one of the things that's a little different in
computer vision today than before is.
Traditionally when I talk computer vision I could assume that everybody had
taken graphics.
because there was sort of this connection between graphics and vision.
These days it's much more likely people have taken machine learning because it's
as if you have computer vision is a data driven inference problem.
And people are less likely to have taken a graphics course and
understand the physics that are here.
Computer vision draws both from understanding what's going on from data, but
also having built in models that have to do with the, the nature of the physics.
Then there is things that happen to the light between bouncing off a surface and
entering your eye.
So here's an example referred to as scattering.
Where this is what the picture maybe should look like if you think of
it as being very clear.
But if you actually just took a look at the raw image you would
see this because of moisture and
other particulates in the air, and the, the wavelengths that are absorbed.
That the light changes as it comes through.
And in fact there was a really cool paper done about depth,
from what's called The Dark Channel.
Which basically says that you know, the further away something is,
the harder it is for something to be black in your image,
because there's a little bit of fog all the way through.
So they actually estimate the depth of the seam based upon,
essentially, the amount of fog induced lightness that's there.
And this is all from an understanding of the nature of the physics.
And, there are lots of other phenomena that impact, you know,
the light that comes in, you know, here's fog, and water dripping, and,
and all sorts of, different types of effects