As a more concrete example, Fedorava
speculates that a useful counter to use
to detect the thread CPU NS versus
memory NS is cycles for instruction.
She observes that memory
bound threads take a lot of
cycles to complete an instruction
therefore it has a high CPI.
Where is the CPU-bound thread, it will
complete an instruction every cycle or
near that and therefore,
it will have a CPI of 1, or a low CPI.
So this speculates then, it would
be useful to gather this kind of
information, this counter about
the cycles per instruction.
And use that as a metric in scheduling
threats on hyper-threaded platforms.
Given that there isn't exactly a CPI
counter on the processors that Fedorova
uses in her work, and
computing something like one over IPC
would require software computations so
that wouldn't be acceptable.
For that reason Fedorapa
uses a simulator,
that supposedly the CPU
does have a CPI counter.
And then she looks at a better
scheduler can take that information and
make good decisions.
Her hope is that if she can demonstrate
that CPI is a useful metric,
then hardware engineers will add
this particular type of counter in
future architectures.
To explore this question she simulates
a system that has four cores where
every one of the cores is
four way multi threaded.
So, there's a total of 16 hardware
contexts in her experimental test bed.
Now, she wants to bury the threads that
get assigned to these hardware contexts
based on their CPI.
So, she creates a synthetic workload,
where her threads have a CPI of one,
six, 11 and 16.
Clearly the threat with the CPI of one
will be the most CP intensive, and
then the threats with a CPI of 16
will be the most, memoring threads.
And the overall work load mix
has four threads of each kind.
And then what she wants to evaluate is
what is the overall performance when
a specific mix of threads gets assigned
to each of these 16 hardware contexts.
To understand the performance in
tact of such potentially different
scheduling positions, she uses a metric,
the instructions per cycle.
Given that the system
has four cores in total,
the maximum IPC that could be
achieved is going to be four.
So, four instructions per cycle
will be the best case scenario for
where every single one of the cores
complete one instruction in each cycle.
And then she conducts several
experiments as shown in this figure.
In every one of the experiments
she manually and
statically changes how the workload
is distributed across the course.
So in the first experiment on core one,
the four hardware threads will
be assigned threads that have,
software threads that have a CPI of one,
six, 11, and 16.
The four hardware threads on Core 2
will be assigned software threads and
tasks that have CPI of one,
six, 11, and 16, and so forth.
In the first experiment every one of
the Cores runs identical mix, where.
Each hardware thread runs
a task with a different CPI.
And then in the last experiment,
each of the cores runs a very different
kinds of mix, where on Core 0,
all of the tasks are CPU intensive,
they have a CPI of 1.
Where as on Core 3,
all of the tasks are memory intensive,
because they have a CPI of 16.
And then the second and
the third round of the experiments falls
somewhere between these two extremes.
So what she's trying to do,
she's trying to make
some static decisions that
a scheduler would have made.
And in doing that she's trying to
understand whether it even makes sense
to build a scheduler that
will use CPU as a metric.