As part of building
a fluid user experience,
it's important you avoid leaving your
user hanging or waiting for feedback.
As a general rule, for
any action the user takes in your app,
you should give some visible change or
feedback within half a second.
If a task is taking
a particularly long time,
it's a good idea to show the user
that progress is being made.
As you can see here in
the material design spec,
there are guidelines on how to show
progress and activity to the user.
There are lots of great examples and
ideas on this page, so
be sure to check it out later.
Now I want to point out that there
a linear progress indicators,
as well as circular progress indicators.
Indeterminate means you don't know
how long the task will take, so
it's a generic loading indicator.
Determinate means that you know
exactly what percentage of the work is
completed, so
it gradually completes the whole circle.
In our case,
when they user opens their app,
they should see some immediate signal
that we're working on getting their data
such as a circular progress indicator.
Now when the results
arrive from the server,
we should hide the progress indicator
and show the data in the list or
sometimes there may be no
results from the server.
So, then we would hide the loading
indicator and show our empty view.
Fortunately, Android contains
a nice Progress Bar view.
One version of which is
a spinning loading indicator.
Since we don't know how long
the network request will take,
we'll use the indeterminate
version of the indicator.
In this quiz, you're going to add
a loading indicator in the app when
the network request is in progress.
So the first thing you want to do is
in the earthquake_activity xml, add
a ProgressBar view as a sibling to the
ListView in the empty state TextView.
Now, it should be centered
within the screen.
So check the cheat sheet from
the first course, for example,
on how to declare a progress
view in an XML layout.
Then in
the EarthquakeAcitivity.java file,
I want you to hide the loading indicator
by setting the visibility to gone
when the onLoadFinished() is called.
Lastly, I want you to test both cases
work by temporarily modifying the code.
So, see below for some hints.