All right. So why projective geometry?
I'm going to show you some of the math.
All right.
So, what is the geometric intuition of using homogeneous coordinates?
Well basically, the idea is that we're going from a per ray
in space is mapped to a point in the image.
So here you see a ray that intersects the image plane at z equals 1.
And the idea is that every point x, y, so every point x,
y on that image plane at z equals 1, is represented by this ray.
So you see this ray here, right?
And it intersects the image plane at x, y, 1.
But any point on this ray, sx, sy, s,
would in, intersect the when projected through the center projection,
would intersect the image plane at the same location.
And that's what it means to be projectively similar.
Okay? And that, that's the, the relationship between, sort of,
these rays and the points in the image.
So, we already know about sort of going between homogeneous coordinates and
regular coordinates.
So in 2D, for example, we take a 2D point, x, y, to make it homogeneous,
we just add a 1 to it and become a homogeneous coordinate.
That last coordinate can be thought of as the thing that tells you
about the scale.
So when you go from homogenous coordinates to regular you just divide by
that scale value, that's what's shown here.
But homogeneous coordinates actually allow us to do a lot more in particular,
they're going to give us natural way of thinking about lines, and
this time we mean two dimensional lines.
So here we have our standard equation for a two dimensional line,
ax plus by plus c equals 0.
And what's nice is, in homogeneous coordinates,
it can be thought of as just this dot product, essentially, right?
It's a, b, c transpose times x, y, 1, or I should say multiply by x, y, 1.
And, when you think of the line that way, a, b and
c can just be thought of as being the component of the,
the unit vector in the direction of the normal between the origin and the line.
And then every point on that line when you dot it with that normal,
has to be a distance d away so that, so that would be minus d.
But the thing to think about also is, it's saying that the normal, a b c
is perpendicular to the point x y 1, or to the ray that defines x y 1.
So what's this deal having to do with perpendicu, perpendicularity?
Get that out one word, right?
And in fact this perpendicular relationship is key to,
to using projected geometry to define our, our points and lines.