Let me explain k-means by an example.
Suppose we're given the following data points in a 2-dimensional space.
K-means estimates for a fixed number of k. Here k = 2.
The best centers of clusters representing those data points.
Those are found interatively by the following algorithm.
Step 1: Guess cluster centers at random, as shown over here with the 2 stars.
Step 2: Assign to each cluster center, even though they are randomly chosen,
the most likely corresponding data points.
This is done by minimizing Euclidian distance.
In particular, each cluster center represents half of the space.
And the line that separates the space between the left and right cluster center
is the equidistant line, often called a Voronoi graph.
All the data points on the left correspond to the red cluster,
and the ones on the right to the green cluster.
Step 3: Given now we have a correspondence between the data points and cluster centers,
find the optimal cluster center that corresponds to the points associated with the cluster center.
Our red cluster center has only 2 data points attached.
So the optimal cluster center would be the halfway point in the middle.
Our right cluster center has more than 2 points attached;
yet it isn't placed optimally, as you can see as they move with the animation back and forth.
By minimizing the joint quadratic distance to all of those points,
the new cluster center has attained the center of those data points.
Now the final step is iterate. Go back and reassign cluster centers.
Now the Voronoi diagram has shifted, and the points are associated differently,
and then reevaluate what the optimal cluster center looks like given the associated points.
And in both cases we see significant motion.
Repeat. Now this is the clustering.
The point association doesn't change, and as a result, we just converged.