Suppose you want to do
a broadcast on a 2-D network.
Here are two schemes.
In the first scheme, you run
a tree-based algorithm broadcast in each
row followed by a tree-based
broadcast algorithm in each column.
The second scheme has four steps.
Scatter in the rows,
followed by a scatter in the columns,
followed by a bucket all
gather in the columns,
followed by a bucket
all gather in the rows.
Stop for a minute and convince yourself
that these two schemes are plausible.
Then once you've done that,
I want you to answer this question.
Which scheme has the lowest alpha
term if you estimate the cost?
Is it Scheme 1 or Scheme 2?
Choose your answer here.