So you probably noticed in the
Conference Central code that as we build
up a query with filters, we've been
re-assigning the variable q like this.
But there's a somewhat
neater way to do this.
Every one of these filter and order
methods returns an updated query object.
That means we can just use
method chaining, like this.
We can compose a complex query
all on one line of code, or
a few lines of code with backslashes
as continuation characters.
So how would you write a query to filter
for conferences in Tokyo with at least
one, but less than ten seats available,
sorted by the number of seats available,
then by the conference name,
and then by the month?
Fill in the query here in Python.