To test your understanding of this, consider the following snippets taken from
the Oracle documentation of the format method in the Java PrintStream class.
Classify each of these snippets as to the guarantee level.
The first snippet states data formats are not synchronized.
It is recommended that you create separate format instances for each thread.
If multiple threads access a format concurrently,
it must be synchronized externally.
The second snippet is a snippet taken directly from the Java code for
PrintStream format method, including its arguments and the name of the method.
The third snippet comes from the context of the throw's IllegalFormatException.
It states that if a format string contains illegal syntax,
a format specifier that is incompatible with the given arguments,
insufficient arguments given the format string, or
other illegal conditions, then the IllegalFormatException is thrown.