And only the first answer is correct.
They are usually easy to implement compared to any other filter.
They do not scale quadratically, in fact, normally they scale exponetially
with the dimensionality of the state space because you need
exponentially many particles to fill up the state space.
The filter that scales quadratically is called a Kalman filter,
but we didn't really talk about it in this class.
They can only be applied to discrete state spaces is clearly wrong.
We saw how to apply the robot localization
which is a continuous real-valued state space,
and because this first one is true, the last one, none of the above, is clearly false.