Now that you've learned more
about your learning zones,
it's time to map your own journey.
Think about different skills
you've learned in the past, and
reflect on how you felt as
you were learning each skill.
It could be playing an instrument,
or a sport, or a new subject.
For me,
I've been dancing since I was young.
I was a dance major in college.
So I'm very comfortable and
familiar with dance.
So dance is in my safe zone.
When I graduated from
college I became a teacher,
which was something
I'd never done before.
I was definitely feeling stretched.
So teaching was in my stretch zone.
When I started learning how to program
it was totally unfamiliar territory.
And there are definitely moments
I was in my strain zone.
I was completely overwhelmed sometimes.
And I struggle to learn new concepts.
So programming was in my strain zone.
However over time with
the help of a community I
started to feel like programming
was more in my stretch zone.
Now it's your turn.
Chart your skills in
the learning zones below.
Write your current skills in the boxes
below for each learning zone.
They can be programming languages or
even different skills.
Remember there's no one correct answer.
Each person's journey into
the programming world will be different.