Jake, did you manage that one?
>> I did.
And here's how.
I'm going to bump the version
number of the database and
add a new section to
the switch statement.
Then I'll get the people object
store just as I did before.
I'm going to add a new index called
age that sorts by the age property.
Getting people by age is almost the same
as getting people by animal as we
did before.
I create a transaction.
Get the object store and get the index.
Now I called get all on it and
log out the results.
If I run that in the browser, I can
see all the people being logged, but
this time, ordered by age.
Also as confirmation, the index
appears in the resources panel.
Right this is it,
the final bit of the IDB crash course.
Deep breath, here we go.
At the moment, we're getting
all the items out of the store.
But we can actually go through
them one at a time using cursors.
Taking the age code from above,
rather than calling get all,
I'm going to open a cursor.
This returns a promise for a cursor
objects representing the first item in
the index or
undefined if there isn't one.
So if it's undefined,
I'm just going to return.
Otherwise, I'll log it.
The first person in the index
is in cursor.value.
Then I'll call cursor.continue
to move on to the next item.
This returns a promise for
a cursor representing the next item or
undefined if there isn't one.
Now here's a neat trick.
I'm going to name the function
we're in log person.
And I’m going to call at once
cursor.continue resolves.
This sets up a kind of asynchronous
loop until cursor is undefined.
Meaning we're at the end of the list.
So when we hit this next
step in the promise chain,
we'll have gone through
the whole object stall.
If I refresh the browser,
there's all the people being logged.
At the moment this is just
a complicated way of calling getAll.
But cursors become really useful
when you want to modify items
as you're looping through.
You can use cursor.update to change
the value or cursor.delete to remove it.
You can also skip some items.
Here I'm going to call
cursor.advance and
pass 2 in to skip the first two items.
Now over in the browser
if I hit refresh, yep,
we just get the last two logged.
Okay, you've just taken in the majority
of the index DV API in a very short
space of time, but in next chapter,
will put some of that knowledge
into practice on Witter itself.
Don't worry if you can't remember all
of the syntax we've gone through.
You can always come back to this video
and check out the instructor's notes for
links to the IDb API and the promise
base Shim that we're going to be using.
Or better still play around with
the code I've just written and
use it as a reference.
It covers all of the patterns we'll
be using in the rest of the course.
You can check out this code
by running git reset hard
to remove any local changes you have.
And then git check out idb
cursoring get the latest code.
Once you get to grips with IDB,
you may even start to like it,
that's what happened to me.
But I can't decide if
that's a good thing or
if I just have Stockholm syndrome or
something.
Anyway, in the next chapter we'll
create a database for Witter posts.