To calculate the size of the page table,
we know that a page table has number of
entries that is equal to the number of
virtual page numbers that exist
in a virtual address space.
For every one of these entries,
we know that the page table needs
to hold the physical frame number,
as well as some other information
like the permission bits.
Here is something that would make
sense on a 32-bit architecture.
So, each of the page table
entries is 4 bytes and
that includes the page frame
number as well as the flags.
The total number of page table entries,
that will depend on
the total number of VPNs.
And how many VPNs we can have,
that's going to depend on the size of
the addresses, of the virtual addresses,
and of the page size itself.
So let's say in this example,
we have a 32-bit,
both physical memory as well
as 32-bit virtual addresses.
So that will be 2 to the 32nd and
that will have to be divided
by the actual page size.
Different hardware platforms
support different page sizes, but
let's say we pick a common 4
kilobyte page size for this example.
In that case, if you do the math,
you will see that the page table
will be 4 megabytes and it will be 4
megabytes for every single process.
With many active processes in
an operating system today,
this can get to be quite large.
If we try to work through
the same kind of example for
a 64-bit architecture that, say,
has a page table entry size of 8 bytes,
and let's say we use also
the same 4 kilobyte page size,
we come up with a really scary
number of 3 petabytes per process.
So where does one store all of this?
Before we answer that question,
it's important to know that a process
likely will not use all of the
theoretical available virtual memory.
Even on 32-bit architecture,
it's not all of the 4 gigabytes of
virtual address space is used
by every single type of process.
The problem is that the page
table as we described it so
far, it assumes that there is
an entry for every single VPN.
And that is regardless of
whether the corresponding
virtual memory region is
needed by the process or not.
So this page table design really
explodes the requirements of
the page table size.
And what we'll do next,
we'll look at some alternatives
of how to represent a page table.