We'll teach you a lot about
the Gradle DSL in this class, but
you'll inevitably run into
use cases we haven't covered.
Fortunately, Gradle has fantastic
documentation that will allow
you to find the features you need.
In fact, let's get a little practice.
If you wanted to dynamically
decide at runtime whether or
not to run a task, to what method on the
task object would you pass a closure?
Write your answer in this box.
You can find a link to the Gradle DSL
reference in the instructor notes.
By the way, since we'll be back here
pretty often throughout the course,
this would be a good time to go ahead
and bookmark the Gradle DSL reference.