Hey Jake, did you get the GIF
responses happening for JPEGs only?
>> I certainly did and
here's how I did it.
Now we haven't actually covered how
to get the URL of a request yet.
So this task was a little bit trickier.
I've been doing service work for so
long that I have the API burned
into the back of my brain.
But if I didn't,
here's how I would have figured it out.
We've already seen event.request.
But what other properties does it have?
One way to find out is to go to
Google and search for MDN request.
MDN is a great place for documentation.
And there there's a result
about the fetch API.
In there it tells me that request.url
is the URL of the request.
Kind of obvious now we see it.
Alternatively, I could have
added a console log and
logged out event.request, as we were
before, and then refresh the page.
And because the console is
cleared when the page navigates,
we're losing the log for
the page request.
If I preserve the log and
refresh again, there it is.
And inside the request object there
are loads of details in there,
one of which is the URL,
and it's a string.
So with this knowledge back in
the code I can use an if statement.
So respond with is only called
if the URL ends with .jpg.
Ends with is a relatively new string
method, but it's really useful.
Since service work is only
run in modern browsers,
we can make use of some of the more
modern JavaScript features.
Back in the browser with force
update enabled, I hit refresh and
the page loads as normal, but
all the images have been intercepted.
So we started handling requests
dynamically depending on URL.
But there's a lot more we can do here.
Join us in the next chapter to discover
some request hijacking patents.