You know Puff, it is so cool that we
were able to build an app in a weekend.
>> Yeah, isn't it amazing?
I told you, you could do it.
>> It blows my mind.
>> Yeah, now and that explains
through the power of Firebase.
>> Right.
>> because it's really reused,
the real-time database.
Firebase storage, authentication,
notifications, analytics, and
we use remote config.
And they all came from one source.
So we didn't have to write any
surface head up codes, right?
We really actually wrote surprisingly
little client-side code.
>> I know, it's incredible and
like with all the database stuff,
I don't have to fiddle
with foreign keys anymore.
So I'm happy and I'm so happy,
I'm going to start planning
next weekend's app.
But between now and
then with this really nice weather,
I'm going to go work on my tan.
>> Yeah, I can imagine that.
Well, thanks everyone for
joining us to learn about Firebase.
I hope this gives you a foundation that
you can start coming up with your own
app ideas using Firebase.
But for more information and
inspiration,
check out the official Firebase
website on firebase.google.com.