Hello.
Welcome to the class on computational photography.
This is an exciting class and
I'm actually very pleased to be bringing it to you in this format.
And what I'd like to do throughout this whole semester is introduce to
you this amazing concept of computation and
photography, which basically is about the computational pipeline.
With the relationship to the photography discipline which has a lot of art and
aesthetics associated with it.
Again I want to remind you, this is a class on the computational and
the technical pipeline of photography.
And throughout the semester we're going to look at a variety of
things associated with how competition has changed the whole aspect of
how light is captured to generate images and photographs.