At this point I'm going to move
on from the wrangling phase to
the exploration phase.
Although of course I might find more
problems later and need to fix them.
What I want to look at first is how the
numbers in the daily engagement table
differ for
students who eventually pass the first
project versus those who don't.
However, there are a few
things about this question as
stated that are under specified or
would be a bit weird.
First, if I look at all records
in the daily engagement table,
that will include data from
after the project was submitted.
That data isn't really relevant, so
I might want to only look at engagement
data from before the submission
of the first project.
Second, if I do only look at engagement
from before the first submission and
students submit after
different lengths of time
then I'm comparing engagement data
from different lengths of time, but
student's engagement might
have trends over time.
For example, engagement might tend to
drop off after the first few days.
If that were the case, then comparing
average engagement over one month for
one student versus two months for
another might be misleading.
And third since the daily
engagement table we've been using
includes engagement numbers for
the entire nano degree program.
It's including engagement for
courses that are not related to the
first project, which is little weird.
To handle the first two problems,
I'm only going to look at engagement
data from the students'
first week of enrollment and
I'm going to exclude students
who cancel within a week.
That way I'll be comparing
equal amounts of time.
This will also have the benefit of
excluding people who cancelled during
the free trial which was seven days
at the time this data was collected.
The third issue doesn't seem
like a showstopper to me.
I'm going to go ahead and
look at engagement numbers for
any course in the nano degree program
and just keep this decision in mind.
If you did want to look at engagement
data in only the first course of
the nano degree you could do
that using the daily engagement
full table available in
the downloadable section
which includes a breakdown
by course as well.
But since this file is pretty big,
computations on it can take longer.
So, to make things easier, or in case
your computer doesn't have that much
memory, I'm going use
the non-granular version, for now.
As a first step,
create a dictionary of students
who either haven't cancelled yet.
Or who stayed enrolled for
more than seven days before cancelling.
If the student hasn't cancelled yet
the days_to_cancel column will be None.
And if they've stayed enrolled for
more than 7 days,
the days_to_cancel field will be > 7.
The keys of your dictionary
should be account keys and
the values should be the date that the
student enrolled, since this date will
be useful later to find engagement
records during the first week.
You should name your
dictionary paid_students.
Enter the number of students who
meet these conditions in this box.