I've refreshed the page and
cleared up the console.
You should do the same so
that way you can start from
the same base point as me.
We're going to be working together to
apply what we've learned about visual
codings and D3's basic functionality
to build part of a visualization.
The visualization is called Gapminder
and it's a scatter plot that shows
different aspects about countries,
including their population In size,
income per person, and
life expectancy in years.
Now the specific thing that we're
going to rebuild about this plot
is China.
We're going to plot
China in the year 2015.
So we'll basically want to create this
red dot in the same sort of position
as it is laid out in this chart.
Here's a look at what you'll
create by the end of this lesson.
Now, it doesn't look like much,
but there's so
much that goes in just
creating this one circle.
And, believe it or not,
once you know how to create one circle,
you'll have an arsenal of tools
to develop other visualizations.
So, let's get started by clearing some
area on this current page for a chart.
I'm going to inspect this
main content area over here.
And it looks like we have a container,
a title and a main content area.
Now, if I wanted to I could use D3's
remove method to remove this
DOM node from the page.
But I actually don't want to
remove the element from the page,
instead I just want to remove
the inner HTML content.
So, I want to remove this row.
Let's see if you can figure this
out by using D3's documentation.
Write one line of code to empty
the main content area of the display.
You want to keep the div that
has a class of main on it, and
you'll need to use a new D3 method
that we haven't seen before.