[INAUDIBLE].
So we have the details screen up and
running, sort of.
And, well, basically what I want to be
able to do is edit shopping list names.
I mistype texts all the time.
If I accidentally type something like,
I don't know, grassery list or
shipping list, I should be able to
change it before all of my friends see.
>> I know what you mean,
I'm all thumbs sometimes.
>> So, could I ask a favor?
>> Go for it.
>> So while I'm busy creating
the different screens for
the app maybe you could
chat with the developer.
Kind of get them up to speed on all
the ways you can write data in Firebase.
>> Sounds good let me pull up my screen.
There are five write and
remove methods for Firebase,
depending upon what you want to do.
The four write methods are, setValue,
which is the most basic write operation.
It writes or replaces data at
the specified database location,
replacing any existing
data at that path.
Update children, which is a method used
when you want to write to specific
children of a parent node but
without overriding other child nodes.
Push, the push method
adds to a list of data.
A unique ID is generated by
push based on the timestamp
each time a new child is added to
a specified database reference.
This allows multiple clients to
add children to the same location
at the same time without
any write conflicts.
Run transaction is used for
complicated data.
For example, when there
are multiple concurrent operations.
Using this method keeps data from
being corrupted when you have
multiple people updating
a single object like a counter.
In addition to the four write
methods the remove value method
allows you to delete data
at a specified location.
In addition to the four write methods
the remove value method allows
you to delete data at
a specific location.