We've been doing mostly our projected geometry here thinking about images, so
we're talking about 2D projective geometry, so
our homogenous coordinates are three long.
Well you can naturally extend this to 3D as well.
Remember the equation of a plane AX plus BY plus CZ eq, plus D equals 0.
So the homogenous coordinate is now just a four vector, wx, wy, wz, w.
But of course we've already seen that right?
When I, when we first introduced extrinsic coordinates and
we talked about combining rotation and
translation, we introduced this notion of the four vector.
And so in the two dimensional case we had a duality between points and
lines, because they were both represented by four dimensional vectors.
In 3D, we have a duality between a plane, whose normal is a, b, c, d.
Okay, that's the dot product.
Is represented by a four vector and a point.
So instead of points and lines like it is in 2D, it's points and plains in 3D.
And the projective transforms, instead of 3 by 3 are just 4 by 4.
So I wrote here that P prime equals TP, okay.
Well, that's just the 4 by 4 transformations that we had seen before.
So we've, since we've already seen that,
we're not going to talk much more about it.
Going forward, like I said, we'll talk about fundamental, fundamental matrix,
we'll talk about projective geometry in the 2D case using the three vectors.