To insert a question,
think about this set of formulas.
p is our probability that
a single component will fail.
Then 1-p is the probability that
a single component will not fail.
For there not to be a failure
anywhere in this system, so
we're trying to answer
the inverse of this question.
That means that not a single one of the
components in the system should fail.
If the probability of one
component not failing is 1-p,
then the probability of no components in
the system failing is (1-p) to the nth.
Their total of end
components in the system.
So this will be the probability that
nothing will go wrong in the system.
And the question here is what is
the probability that something
will go wrong?
So there will be a failure
somewhere in the system,
that's clearly 1 minus this result.
The formula for the total answer is,
on parentheses, 1 ,minus p to the n.
If you do the math, you will see
that with this probability, so
there's a 3% of something failing and
you have ten components.
If you do this math, you have a 26%
chance that something will go wrong.
If you increase the scale and your n
becomes 100, then if you do this math
you'll realize that with this
high probability of failure,
95% of the time you will have
a failure at some point.
Our cloud systems don't have 10 or
100 components.
They have thousands and
hundreds of thousands of components.
Yes, they may be more stable than
this 0.03 probability of failure,
but the point is that things will fail.
The more components you put together,
the more you'll have situations in
which something, somewhere, is failing.
So you have to have mechanisms that
are prepared to deal with
those kinds of failures.
For instance,
your software may have to incorporate
mechanisms that include timeouts, so
that you can detect that a failure has
occurred or to integrate mechanisms for
restart and retry in order to
be able to recover from failure.
You have to incorporate mechanisms for
backup, for application, for
checkpointing.
So you have to accept, you have to
embrace the fact that failures will
happen, and so you have to build robust
software that will be able to detect and
recover or
avoid failures from occurring.