All right, now lets do something
that is a little bit magical.
Without changing any code at all,
we're going to run the exact
same game we just ran on our desktop,
but on an android device.
If you've worked through our mini
course on installing android studio,
then you should already have installed
a hello world app on your phone.
And if you haven't done that yet, then
follow the link in the instructor notes
to learn how to set up your phone for
USB debugging.
Allright, so I've got my test device.
And we'll go ahead and plug that in.
There we go, this little icon says
that we're now doing USB debugging.
All right, now we'll switch our run
configuration from the desktop run
configuration back to the android
run configuration, and hit run.
When this device picker dialog pops up,
we want to select the actual test
device we want to use and hit okay.
And there we go,
we've got our game running on our phone.
Check it out,
it even does multi touch tracking.
Now it's time for you to try running
the Android version of the app.
Set up your phone for USB debugging.
If you haven't done that yet
you can check out the instructions
in the instructor notes.
Change the run configuration
back to Android.
Hit the green arrow.
Select your phone and
in the device choose your dialog.
And then you just get to poke
at your phone for a while.