Let's look at some examples of
real memory hierarchy parameters.
A register file with 16
registers of 16 bytes each.
An L1 cache that can hold 32
kibibytes with 64 byte lines.
An L2 cache of size 8 mebibyte
with a 128 byte lines.
A 256-entry TLB or translation lookaside
buffer with pages of 8 kibbibytes each.
In this case the slow memory is main
memory, and the fast memory is the TLB.
And finally a virtual memory setup
with 32 gibbibytes of physical RAM as
the fast memory, 32 kibbibytes pages and
disk as the slow memory.
My question is this,
which of these is a tall cache?
To answer the question,
you'll need to assume a word size,
which I'll tell you is 8 bytes.
Note that there might be more
than one correct answer, so
please check all that apply.