Okay, the solution is actually a one-liner.
Firstly, we know that we want pixels that have at
least the minimum magnitude specified.
We can use relational operators to directly compare matrices with scalar values.
This is essentially a thresholding operation.
Next, we use a pair of comparisons to say that gdir should be
between angle_low and angle_high.
Notice that the results of the three comparisons are combined using
the element-wise and operator.
And that's it.
Let's see which pixels have a 45 degree gradient.
Seems to work as expected.
Notice that the line is thinner than expected.
Not all the pixels with a gradient direction of 45 degrees have
been included because the ones with low magnitude have been filtered out.
Similarly, we can look at 0 degrees.
Here we specify the range as minus 15 to plus 15, 90.
Here's a negative angle, minus 135.
Note the low and high values.
180 degrees can be tricky.
Something for you to think about.