Okay.
Cool.
You now know about decorators, so
let's take a look at how
the endpoints are defined.
The endpoints API supports
a lot of arguments, but
here we're just using name and version,
which is the required arguments.
As you can see, the API name and the
class name don't have to be the same.
The methods inside this class will
become the methods of our endpoints API,
each gets decorated
with @endpoints.method.
And the arguments here tell what type
the method takes in their request and
what it returns and
some other things too.
Now, every API method has a request
class and a response class,
even though some of them are void or
empty.
The request and the response classes
end up being different subclasses of
ProtoRPC protocol buffer types, which
I'll tell you more about in a moment.
For the response class,
you just need to define a class that's
a subclass of messages.message.
It can contain as many
fields as you want.
In this simple example, it just
contains one field called greeting.
We also have to define
the request class.
This request is pretty simple.
It also just contains one field,
name, which is a string.
But later, we'll see requests
that are a lot more complex.
The resource container class supports
options that messages.message doesn't,
such as query string parameters,
which we'll use later.
So we'll use that now just
to have a good example.
And again, each API method is
a method inside the API class.
That function returns a message object.
Here we have a hello object and
we decorate that method with
the @endpoints.method decorator.
The decorator tells the API
system the request class.
Here we have VoidMessage and
then here we have REQUEST_CONTAINER and
the response class, which is Hello.
And some other information,
like the http_method.
And down at the bottom of the file,
down here on line 46,
we have the code that actually starts
the server that supports this API.
About these message classes,
what's up with them?
And why do these fields have
the number one on them?
That looks kind of weird, but
there's a good reason for it.
It has to do with how endpoints works.
Endpoints APIs use Google's
protocol buffers or protobuf,
which is a way of representing
data structures efficiently
across many different
programming languages.
Let's take a look at that in
some more detail, up ahead.