Earlier, I told you that database
tables were a lot like the tables you
might see in an infographic or
a reference book.
There are some differences though.
One of these is important when there
are multiple answers to a question,
which will often be the case just before
we use a count or another aggregation.
This table is about animals and
what they eat.
Unlike some tables we've seen before,
this one sometimes has
the same value in some of the cells
with different values over here.
This is how we say things like
brown bears eat fish and meat and
plants in a database table.
We split that sentence out
into multiple sentences,
which make multiple rows in the table.
Why don't we just make
multiple columns or
put several values in one column
separated with commas or something?
There are lots of
reasons not to do that.
If we tried using multiple columns for
the different foods each animal eats,
we wouldn't know how many
columns to make in advance.
Some animals do eat a lot more kinds
of foods than others after all.
And what's more, we want to be able
to use counts and other aggregations.
And those will only work if we have
our data separated out into rows,
not jammed together.
Now let's take a look at a real
database query against this table.
Select food from diet where
species equals orangutan.
This looks almost like ordinary English,
but
this is actually an SQL database query.
It's asking the database to return
particular data from the diet table.
In a moment, we'll run this
query using an actual database.
But before we do,
can you figure out which rows and
which columns from this
table it will return?