Welcome back.
In the last lesson,
you got a basic understanding for
how data is represented and
stored in the variables.
But what good is that data
if you can't put it to use?
>> When you're writing code,
the main goal is to solve a problem.
The steps your code takes to solve
a problem is known as an algorithm.
Ultimately, for any code that you write,
you will be breaking down a problem
into an algorithm that is
executed by a computer.
>> Let me try explaining it another way.
Let's imagine you're the computer.
Do you remember the last time you had to
decide whether to purchase something?
How did you solve that problem?
Besides figuring out if you
really wanted or needed the item,
your decision to purchase the item was
ultimately dependent on whether or
not you had enough money to purchase it.
So you ask yourself, self, do I have
enough money to purchase this item?
If you answered, yes,
then you purchase the item.
But if you answered, no,
then you didn't purchased the item.
The process you went through in
your head to solve that problem,
and the steps you took
in order to do so,
is really what's at
the heart of writing code.
And that's what you'll be
learning in this lesson.
>> Up next, you'll see a flowchart.
A flowchart is just a diagram for
how to solve a problem.
Take a look at it, and
try to answer the next question.