I'm now here with Arpan Chakraborty who
is one of our Udacity computer vision
experts.
And Drew Gray, who is the director
of engineering at OTTO,
which is now part of Uber.
So guys, in the end of this lesson,
students are going to
implement a pipeline to detect and
track vehicles in a video stream.
So Drew, maybe you could tell us
a little bit more about the role of
vehicle detection and tracking in
the self-driving cars that you work on.
>> Sure.
Knowing where the other vehicles are on
the road and being able to anticipate
where they're heading next is
essential in a self-driving car.
At Otto, we're writing software that
allows the car to recognize other
vehicles on the road.
And determine things like how far away
they are, which way they're going, and
how fast they're moving.
Much the same way as we do
with our own eyes as we drive.
>> Very cool.
Object detection and tracking is
a central theme in computer vision.
And in this lesson you'll be using what
you might call traditional computer
vision techniques to
tackle this problem.
You'll first explore what kind of visual
features you can extract from images
in order to reliably classify vehicles.
Next, you'll look into searching
an image for detections.
And then you'll track those detections
from frame to frame in a video stream.
>> Awesome.
So Drew, I know you've got a background
in both the sort of traditional computer
vision techniques.
>> Mm-hm.
>> As well as using deep learning for
computer vision.
So maybe you could tell us why it's
useful to study both approaches.
>> Sure.
With traditional computer
vision approaches
you basically tune all
the parameters by hand.
Which gives you a lot of intuition
about what works and why.
When it comes to things
like image classification.
In many cases a deep learning approach
works even better for the same tasks.
But can seem like kind of a black box.
We're not quite sure why it works.
By learning both approaches,
you can gain maximum insight and get
the best performance in your algorithms.
>> Cool.
Well let's get started.