Another part of it is the size
of the patch we've used.
We've looked at patches, and scale and
all that kind of stuff here.
If I have a smaller patch here
would result in much lower,
disparity calculations,
much smoother disparity when you
actually move to a bigger patch.
And you can see that more
information is available and
smooth information available.
In some areas but that might not
be the case across the board.
So here for example you see
a lot more finer detail, and
here you see a lot of
smoothness going on.
So, patches, and again refer, I refer
you back to all of the lectures we've
looked at on trying to deal with
frequencies and stuff like that, that
could be used, and scaling and using
pyramids and stuff could help with this.
And again, there are lots of other
methods that I'm not covering today
actually you can lookup that tell you
more about how to do this kind of
disparity calculation
from surrogate pairs.