Let's go through this algebraically.
So here we have our camera which has some viewing direction.
All right, and the viewing direction's not going to matter because we're
going to assume a Lambertian system which is what we have here.
We assume that it's just proportional to the cosine of the instant angle between
the light source and the normal, but the idea is that the camera is fixed.
And for each one of our sources, source one we take our first image.
Source two, we take our second image.
Source three, we take our third image.
Now notice, by the way, that rho is in these equations, right?
Rho is the albedo, so I'm not assuming I know the albedo.
So now I have three images, right?
And I can write these as a matrix equation for, this is for
a single pixel, right?
So at a single pixel, I would have three different values and
I could just write this equation as rho.
And these are the three vectors that are the source, directions and
by the way, I assume I know the source directions times the unit normal.
And the unit normal is the thing that I don't know.
So I need to solve for that, all right.
So remember we're making this Lambertian assumption.
So solving those equations is straightforward, its linear, simple system if we
have three lights, I is our three measurements three intensities.
S are the three directions to the light source and
we know those so I and S are known.
And then as we said before n is supposed to be uninormal, rho is the albedo.
So together I call them n tilda.
So to solve for n tilda is trivial.
N tilda is just s inverse I, but of course n tilda is not unit normal.
In fact it's magnitude is what?
It's magnitude is the albedo, so I can solve for rho, the albedo.
And I can solve for
the unit normal as well, by justing taking the magnitude of that.
Now of course, that's with three lights.
And anything that works well with three lights,
is going to work better with more lights.
So let's suppose we have more lights, like M of them.
Well, we get the same set of equations but now, we need a least square
solutions cause the system is over constrained and basically solve it here.
So M by one is the number of measurements we have.
And so, we have to take the pseudo inverse, and the pseudo inverse will give us
the least squares solution for n tilda, and then again you can find the albeido.