The app you will build will let us record our voice and
will also let us add different effects to it.
Although, to make things easy in this lesson,
we will start with the version 1 of our app.
In this version we will not record any audio.
Except that we will play a famous movie quote.
>> My momma always said, life was like a box of chocolates.
>> Let's make this app.
Before we start writing code however, let's think for a moment
about all the steps we will need to do to make this version one of our app.
I can already tell you that we will need to figure out how to
add buttons to our app.
We will also need to figure out how to transition between two different
screens on our app.
So it seems like we will need to answer a lot of,
how would you do blank in Swift type questions.
Here is your chance to expand on this list.
And think a little bit more deeply about what are some of the other things you
will need to do to make this app.
You should know that one thing experts in Swift do really well is that they
will take a large problem like making an app.
And then they will come up with a bunch of smaller tasks.
So see if you can come up with eight or
more things that you will need to learn do in Swift to complete this app.