This whole thing falls under the labeling of geometric camera Calibration.
In order to be able, for the camera to tell us about things in the world,
we need to know the geometric relationship between the camera and the world.
For reference, you can take a look at the Forsyth and Ponce book.
The sections are, are listed here, and there's a nice description.
So as we said, geometric camera calibration's composed of two parts.
There's the first part that goes from some arbitrary world coordinate system.
You know, put your origin wherever you want it to be to wherever the camera is,
and that basically tells you where the camera is in the world and its pose.
And then the second one is from the 3D camera to the image plane.
The first one is called the Extrinsic parameters.
That's the Extrinsic it goes from the world coordinate system to the,
to the camera coordinate system.
The Intrinsic, which we'll do next time,
is from the 3D camera system to the image.
So let's talk about camera pose or the orientation and
location of the camera frame with respect to the world.
In this diagram, this transform T is a transform that goes between the world and
the camera system.
Okay? And that's what this T with lower, lower w, upper C is going to mean.
All right.
We're going to talk more about this notation in a minute.
The transformation that we're going to talk about is this going from
world coordinates to camera coordinates.