Welcome to the first work session.
These work sessions are a way
you'll work on the web page,
that you're going to be building
through out the Nano degree.
And each session has two parts.
In the first part, you're going to
go over everything you learned in
the previous lesson.And summarize
in short concise statements,
all the important concepts.
In the second part, your actually going
to take the skills you've acquired.And
put them to use by
improving your web page.
Now, the purpose of each of these two
parts is to address two important gaps
in expertise.
And these gaps are what
separate novice from expert.
The first gap has to do with
the gap in what you know.
When you're a novice, and you're
presented with new information.You
typically see that information
as a bunch of scattered facts.
That's normal.
But experts, on the other hand,
they take these facts and
they actually see a logical
structure behind them.
And that logical structure makes
it much easier to recall and
use the new information.
And that, brings us to the second gap.
The gap in what you can do.
As a novice in any field,
you generally just can't do that much.
Again, it's normal.
You may have good ideas.
But until you cross that skills gap, you
won't the ability to execute on them.
So you won't be able to create amazing
things like one of the Web pages I love,
scratchpad.io.
But both of these gaps can be crossed.
Crossing the knowledge
gap requires reflection.
Reflection is what you do when you take
the time to deliberately think about and
process the facts that you've learned.
And that what you'll be doing
when you summarize each lesson.
Crossing the skills gap takes practice.
And practice is a especially useful
when you're just beginning to
learn something new.
But, with reflection and
practice, you'll begin to think like
an expert and act like an expert.
And since you'll be practicing by
building something really impressive,
you'll actually start to
look like an expert too.