Remember to think about touch points
when thinking about partnerships.
What are the touch points you
have with your customers?
When is it that you're going to be
in contact with your customers?
You're going to need to use your deep
understanding of your customers to help
you figure this out.
Think about their lifestyle or other
general information you have about them.
Now for us with The Bark Vet, we know
that our customers need us when they
travel and obviously when
they're looking for dog sitters.
So traveling and being out of town
are good touch points for us.
So we need to look at
partnerships related to travel.
This could be vacations or
business travel, travel by plane,
travel by train, travel by car or
booking hotels and other accommodations.
These are all potential
touchpoints with our customers.
So, for our Landing Page Content,
we're going to need to show a clear
value proposition that interests people.
Let's break this down.
Think about what problems
you're solving for them.
Now, you should already know this
after going through value proposition
in lesson one.
Our main value for
Obarkment is our quality.
So, the quality in this sitter and
the quality in the location
your dog will be staying.
With a high end dog sitting service.
You also need a notification form or
call to action.
It needs to be really obvious
where call to action is or
where the notification form is.
It has to be clear and simple where
they can subscribe, give their email, or
download your app.