Before we go on, let me talk about some of the basics of image matching here.
Imagine I have an image, small image, right here, and
I'm just going to put them on a axis of x and y because we want to look at how
various types of transformations on this small example image could be matched or
could be actually all, also determined by looking at an image.
So imagine in this X and Y plane, this image now has moved over here.
In a simple matter, what I'll basically say is that image has now translated.
In essence what has changed, is it's value of this image in X and Y.
And I can actually use this coordinate axis here.
And in essence everything in the image is the same except all values in
this image have been changed by change in x and y.
And of course some times depending on how I want to do it I may also
actually want to also use a frame of reference that is the middle of the image.
But again this is just a simple transformation.
Another way of looking at these images.
Again, this image now could appear and
again in the x y plane that we are looking at except now its also got
a little bit of an additional transformation which is that now it's rotated.
So it basically means that this image now if we were to have these two
axes is now appearing here at a different location x and
y, but in addition the the change in x and y.
There is also a additional change, which would be this angle theta.
So of course, now we can refer to this with three different degrees of freedom,
x, y, and theta.
So this is basically a rotation of the image from here to there,
with a translation.
What about this third transformation of an image?
Here if you notice this image is translated, moved to a different x and
y, but also in the same time it has been rotated.
So theta is different, but it's also smaller.
We refer to this transformation as scale.
So now we basically have four parameters x, y, theta, and scale radiation.
Here is another transformation.
I've moved this again in x and y.
And, if you notice, the shape of this image is also kind of different.
So, this is usually referred to as an affine transformation,
where in addition to x, y, and the angle, and the scale, we have actually kind
of looked at some sort of a simple warp that makes this image look different.
Yet another transformation is shown here.
This is referred to as a perspective transformation.
That is, now we have taken the image and
also kind of given it a little bit of a perspective warp.
So, if you notice now, is things are kind of looking shorter as I
go into the image this way, and this is again a transformation.
So, now we have actually added another set of degrees of freedom on this image.
Now, in essence, to be able to get the image matching going on.
We need to also look for all of these transformations.