How do you know that there's anything
happening in the back-end and
that's it's actually
using an Endpoints API?
After all, we could do all of these
things just directly from JavaScript
with no back-end involved at all.
Well, Google gives us a really cool tool
that lets us test out an Endpoints API
and access the Endpoints API
behind our app.
It's called API Explorer.
You can access it by adding
/_ah/apis/explorer to your URL.
This even works if you're on localhost.
And that will redirect you
to this APIs Explorer page,
which I will now make a little
bit larger so you can see it.
And APIs Explorer page is a very nice
way to test if your endpoints work
correctly.
You can look in it at endpoint, and
you can see the different API methods,
helloworldendpoints.sayHello and
sayHelloByName that that API exposes.
And if you look at one of these, you'll
see the fields, in this case, just name,
that that API supports.
Now, if I plug my name into that field,
press the Execute button,
down underneath,
it'll show a request and a response.
The request here is this GET HTTP
request accessing localhost port 8080,
sayHelloByName with my parameter.
And then down here at the bottom
is the response with a 200 OK and
an object containing one field called
greeting that says, Hello Karl.
So again,
these methods here correspond directly
to methods that are exposed by our API.
Now, it's important to understand
that the API Explorer page and
the home page
are completely independent.
There are two different paths
that access the very same API in
the back-end.
You could delete that Hello
frontend with the buttons entirely.
And the API Explorer frontend
would still be able to execute
the endpoint functions.
In fact, that same API can be accessed
not only through those frontends, but
also potentially through other frontends
like a mobile app, or in fact,
somebody else's code entirely as
long as you granted them permission.
So now let's go back to
the hello world front-end.
As you can see, the two methods are
exposed by two different buttons, and
the response is shown
as a JavaScript alert.
Let's take a look at how the front-end
communicates with Endpoints to
achieve that.
From the config file, app.yaml, you can
see that when the root URL is accessed,
the request is routed to a static_file,
static/index.html.
Let's take a look at that file
inside the static directory.
As you can see,
it's a pretty short piece of HTML.
It has two buttons and one input field.
What's more interesting
are these JavaScript includes,
although it's a static file hello.js and
it also loads this
Google API's JavaScript client library.
And once that's loaded, it calls an init
function, which is defined in hello.js.
Let's take a look at hello.js in
this init function specifically.
So here's the init function and it
initializes the GAPI client library with
the name of your endpoint,
helloworldendpoints.
And it is a callback,
which in turn initializes the buttons.
The API calls loadCallback,
which calls enableButtons, which sets up
the greetGenerically and greetByName
methods attached to the button onclick.
Which means that when the first button
is clicked, it calls greetGenerically,
and when the second button is clicked,
it calls greetByName.
And greetGenerically in turn uses
the GAPI client library we saw earlier,
in fact, the helloworldendpoints
API to call sayHello.
But on success, the request gets
passed back to sayHelloCallback.
GreetByName does much the same thing,
also passing the response
to sayHelloCallback.
And on that callback, the page displays
an alert with the value that was
returned by the Endpoints API.
So as you can see,
it's really easy to access an Endpoints
API using the GAPI JavaScript library.
But you don't need to use it because
you can access the endpoints for
development and testing entirely
through the API Explorer.
As a matter of fact, for the rest of
this course, you'll be working with just
the back-end code and we'll provide
the front-end code for you.