So this is the Foot Finder in action.
We have the title up here, a placeholder
for where the image will go, and
then the fields for searching by phrase,
latitude, and longitude.
And there are search
buttons here on the right.
So I'm going to start
with a phrase search.
I want to see an image for
my favorite baseball team,
which are the Atlanta Braves.
And here's a shot against
the San Diego Padres of the stadium.
So that's nice.
Pretty good seats.
And there is I'm not even
going to pronounce his name.
That's probably one of
our minor league players.
So now, let's search by longitude and
latitude.
I'm going to use 37 for the latitude.
And negative 119 for the longitude.
Those are roughly the coordinates
of Yosemite National Park.
I looked those up ahead of time.
So I'm going to play around with this.
See if we can't get,
looks like a squirrel here.
See if we can get a picture
of the mountain range and
all the other pretty scenery out there.
Just something big,
kind of landscape shot.
Hm, so it does say Yosemite.
I'm not sure how that's related.
There we go.
So, upper Yosemite Falls trail,
Yosemite National Park,
California, June 2014.
So, as you can see our fray search and
our latitude and
longitude search appear to be working
well, so this is flip finder and
this is simple, compact, fun, you know.
So let's build it.