Continuing with thinking about the digital audio, we can
think about sort of music or, or any other way of dealing with audio right?
When we record a sound, we have a microphone and
a microphone generates out a continuous voltage.
By the way, you guys know how a microphone works?
More or less a microphone works the following way.
We have a permanent magnet and we've got a electric coil alright with
some wires in it, and out, out of that coil comes another wire.
And usually, the the coil is on a little springy mechanism.
The permanent magnets are fixed.
You speak and that causes a pressure wave,
a press, a pressure wave causes the coil to move back and forth.
When you move a coil of wire through a magnetic field, that induces a voltage.
So that voltage comes out on that wire, and it's a continuous signal.
But, in order to encode this into a computer,
we put it through what's known as an A to D converter,
analog to digital converter, and we get out a bunch of samples.
And then, by the way in the old days we used to put those samples on
something called a CD.
Compact disk.
You guys probably don't even buy those anymore.
If, if you do, you only buy them to rip them.
But, basically, it's a set of samples, it's in a file, whatever it is, okay?
When you go to play this thing,
okay, what you do is you put your CD into your ancient CD player.
It pulls out the samples, and then it goes through what's called a D to
A converter, digital to analog converter.
And then we take that continuous voltage and we put that out through a speaker.
Which by the way, is almost exactly the same as a microphone.
Right. It's a coil of wire, you pump electricity through it.
It generates a magnetic, varying magnetic field.
There's a set of permanent magnets that causes the speaker to move,
with respect to those magnets.
And voila, out comes a continuous pressure wave.
So, let's talk about this sampling operation and then the reconstruction.
So, here we'll take as an example just a sign wave.
Okay.
So, I collect a bunch of samples.
If I collect a bunch of samples, then what am I going to do to reconstruct it?
Well, it might be enough to basically just connect the dots and
get back the next sine wave.
Alright, and so, as long as I had enough dots, that's easy enough to do.
So I have enough dots, I connect the dots.