So what makes a good feature?
Again I'm showing you two different examples of the two friends we've
looked at throughout lecture so far, Einstein and Darwin.
So, one more important thing we have to look for
is that these features have to be repeatable and precise.
We need to be able to find them again and again.
So if I ran the same feature detector on this image.
Today or tomorrow, or every frame between it,
I should be able to get the same set of features for both of them.
And this has to be repeatable, even with geometric variations in image for
photometric ones, that is geometric if the image is warped or
deformed a little bit, I should be able to find these features.
And, also, if the lighting conditions are different.
So, this repeatable, precise depiction of features needs to
have invariability to both geometric and photometric variations of images.
A hard task, but these are the kinds of things we need to look for.
Another measure we have to also account for
is the need to salient that is very specific and also be matchable.
Again, we are partly building on the repeatable part.
They need to actually have characteristics that I can actually match them from
one image to the other.
Of course, if you look at these two images,
while there are lots of features here between both of them.
If you notice, the commonality of these two features is this pattern here.
They were taken next to each other.
These two characters were of course sitting next to each other.
And, again, we will look at this later.
Basically the, kind of,
the matchable pattern between these two images is this region and this region.
So in essence, for matching on saliency and matchability,
these need to be features that have distinctive description mathematically.
That makes a unique aspect of these features that I
can actually find in an image.
Another characteristic of good features is they should be compact and easy and
efficient to compute.
Compact as in I can't really imagine taking each and every pixel of
this image and saying, I'm going to just use each and every pixel.
I need to find a few specific points and neighborhoods that I
can actually now match across those two different images and
I need to be able to do this efficiently.
Again, efficiency could be both computational, and
again, the number of features I want to find.
Another characteristic, locality.
Locality here means that each feature should have a small region of support,
which basically means that with each feature should just occupy a small part of
the image, not the entire image.
Which basically means that if I actually have small features like this here,
this here, I, I can match them much more reliably and
more importantly, these features would be robust to clutter and occlusion.
So again, if this was occluded, and there are some features behind it because of
various types of things, I would not be able to match them.
If, of course, I had taken the whole flower as a feature, I want to be able to
find smaller parts of this feature, which still allowed me to match to this.
And of course, even the fact, that if I had taken the whole flower as a feature,
it's of course occluded and therefore would not look good.
Or at least not match across images.