It's time to open exercise three,
display URL.
Our first to do is to implement that
GitHub Query URL that we talked
about in the introduction.
In our quest to help you avoid work, and
the inevitable errors that can come with
typing out long URLs, we've created
constants for the base GitHub URL,
the query URL parameter and the sort URL
parameter in the network details class.
Which also contains our first to do,
to fill in the Build URL method.
To build our search URL,
we can take advantage of
the Android URI.builder framework class.
It allows us to create a well-formed URI
without having to worry about
the particulars of URI components.
For example, adding ampersands
between query parameters and
encoding invalid characters with a
percent followed by the character code.
And yes,
a URL is a specific class of Uri
which is why this is a bit confusing.
Once we've created our base URI
by parsing the GITHUB_BASE_URL
string we create a Uri.builder
using the buildUpon method.
Then we can call appendQuery parameter
for our search query and sort fields.
Finally we call build to produce
the Uri we'll use to query GITHUB.
However this produces
an Android Uri while our method
requires a Java URL, all caps.
We can convert our new
built Uri to a Java URL
by passing it as a string parameter
to the Java URL constructor.
Then we move to main activity.
We'll make a method called,
makeGithubSearchQuery.
It pulls the githubQuery from the edit
text, calls the buildUrl method
we just wrote, and displays the
resulting URL in the UrlDisplayTextView.
Finally, we replace the toast
from onOptionsItemSelected.
With a call to
the makeGithubSearchQuery method.
Now when we hit the search
button in the action bar,
we'll display the URL that
we're going to query.
Now it's your turn, build the URL that
will be used to query GitHub, and
display it when the search
button is pressed.