As you can see, I have the same sample
app on both my phone and my tablet.
When I run the app and sign in for the
first time say on my phone, I'm going to
first get the dialog asking for
which account I want to sign in with.
I have multiple accounts on my phone, I
only have a single account on my tablet.
So I'm going to get this on here and
I'm going to say I'm going to sign
in as lmoroney@gmail.com and say OK.
Now I'm going to get the confirmation
dialogue as we've seen before.
It just wants to know who I am
on Google, so I say OK to that.
And then I go ahead and sign in, and
we can see that I'm signed
in as lmoroney@gmail.com.
So now what happens when I
try to sign in on my tablet,
I just go to click Sign In and
I sign in directly.
I have confirmed for
this application already using my
phone that it's okay to use it.
And my tablet recognized that and
was able to sign in directly.
Now a similar technology to this
enables over the air installs.
If the user is signed into your
website with Google Sign In and
you have a free android app, the app
can be delivered to the device directly
if the user wants to, of course, and
they never have to leave your website.
It's beyond the scope of this course to
show how to do this because you'll need
a website and an app in the Play Store
that's above a certain quality bar.
But there's a straightforward
step-by-step course available to you,
and I've put the URL for
this into the speaker's notes.