You can make check box preferences for
days.
So, let's add another preference type
to our repertoire, list preferences.
List preferences are preferences
that look like this.
They've a list of options
that you can pick from.
In XML, they look like this.
They have a default value,
a key, and a title.
And that's all pretty straight forward.
The two new attributes are entries and
entry values which, instead of being
a single value are an array of values.
The entries are the labels
that you'll actually see.
For example, red, blue, green.
The values are the values that
are actually stored in the shared
preferences file when you
select one of the options.
I'm going to go to my strings.xml file,
and define all of these.
Here are the new strings.
We have the label for the entire
preference, then the labels for
each of the values, and then the key.
The actual values have already
been defined down here.
I've already defined them for you
because when you're using the set color
method, you have to use
one of those values.
Going back to our XML, I have a default
value now, a key and a title.
But I still need to define these two and
for
that I'm going to need
a different type called arrays.
So, over here, within my values folder,
I'm going to make a new values
resource file of type arrays.
And within this file I'm
going to put two arrays.
The first array are the three labels
that we're going to be using and
the second array
are the associated valued.
Keep in mind that the ordering of
the label has to match the ordering
of the value.
So, we have red, blue,
green and here red, blue green.
And these arrays are using these strings
that are found in my strings.xml.
Also, note for the keys and the values,
I'm setting translatable to false.
All of this comes together in a
ListPreference xml that looks like this.
Let's see how this looks in the app.
Okay, let's check out
our preference screen.
Cool, and
we see our three different options.
I've selected blue but nothing changes
in the app yet, let's fix that.
I'm here in the Visualizer Activity,
let me remind you what actually
changing the color looks like.
If I go down here to
setupSharedPreferences I'll see that
the set color method takes one
of the color preference values.
In this case I'm always passing it red.
So, what I'm actually going to
do is make a new method.
And I am going to call it
loadColorFromPreferences and
it's going to take in
a sharedPreferences.
And what this method is doing is it's
calling set color on the visualizer
view, it's taking
the shared preferences,
getting a string from shared preferences
which has the key pref_color_key,
which is our color preferences key and
has a default value of red.
Okay, so,
then I'm going to call that method here.
And now that I've got this method, I can
also call it from our listener, okay?
And let's run the code, cool.
And I can already see that
it's changed to blue.
And if I go to my preferences screen and
try to changing it to green,
I can see that it does that too.
Woo-hoo!