When we first defined our tables,
we defined the relationship between
them in terms of constraints.
I'm going to show how we implemented
that relationship into our
query using a JOIN.
This JOIN allows us to
query the Weather table for
values from a specific location setting.
In Sunshine's case,
the user sets this in Preferences.
You'll notice that there's
an SQLiteQueryBuilder class variable at
the top of WeatherProvider.
As you might guess,
this class helps construct queries and
is actually used as the basis for
the query functions you've already
used in the SQLite database class.
We initialize the SQLiteQueryBuilder
in the static constructor of the class,
describing the join between both tables.
SetTables fills out the content in
the from part of the SQL query.
Note, since both tables have
a field with an underscore ID,
we must explicitly use the table
name in order to disambiguate
which ID we are talking
about in the join.
Then we define the selection.
The selection is defined using
the question mark replacement syntax.
The selection parameters
will replace these values.
As you can see,
our selection has two parameters,
a location setting and a date.
Then we have a function to get
the weather by location setting using
the same query builder.
Note that we fetch the parameters from
the URI and built a string array so
that they can be
substituted into our query.
We do that for both of the queries
that we're creating this way.
Finally, we added the functions into the
query routine of the content provider,
for both WEATHER_WITH_LOCATION_AND_DATE
and WEATHER_WITH_LOCATION