So in the last lecture we spent
time trying to learn about
image transformations.
We looked at how would we rotate,
translate, or
even do projective transformations on
images, and learn about image warping.
Now lets spend more time trying to
understand what happens when we do these
warps that are non-ridgid.
Specifically what I'd like to introduce
is the concept of image morphing.
That is how would we take one image
that we know some features in and
transform it and
morph it to look like another one.
This is a widely used technique
used in films a lot, and
actually is one of the stronger
techniques in competition photography,
something we'll be leveraging
a lot in future lessons.