To find the number of enrollments
I'll use the len function.
And running this cell I can see
that there were 1,640 enrollments.
To find the number of unique
students who enrolled,
I'll add the account keys to a set and
then look at the length of the set.
So, first I'll create an empty set
called unique_enrolled_students.
Then I'll loop through the enrollments.
And I'll add the account key from
each enrollment to this set.
Finally, I'll look at
the length of the set.
And it turns out that there were
1302 unique students who enrolled.
The reason these two numbers are
different is that students can enroll
then cancel.
Then re-enroll later.
Next I'll check how many entries
are in the daily engagement table, and
there are a lot more,
which makes sense since there should
be multiple entries for each student.
To find the unique number of students
in the daily engagement table
I'll need similar code to before,
so I'll copy and paste it.
First, I'll need to change
the table I'm lifting over.
Now, I don't technically need
to change the name of the set.
I could name both sets
unique students for example.
But then the second set would
overwrite the first set.
So when using iPython Notebook it's
often a good idea to give a new name to
each new variable so
that you'll still have access to
the previous variable if you want.
So I'll change the set name also.
I'll also change the looping variable
to make the code more clear.
Finally I'll need to change
the account key column name to ACCT.
Again since I copied and
pasted some code here,
writing a function would
have been a good idea.
I'll get to that in a later video.
The main difficulty in this case
would be that this account key
has become ACT in this loop but
it's possible to handle that.
And I saw that there where 1237 unique
students in the engagement table.
When I first ran this code,
I was surprised that these
two numbers weren't the same.
We'll see in a later
video why that happened.
And finally, I followed a similar
process for the projects submission
table and found there were 3642 project
submissions from 743 unique students.