Here the left one is the left image and the right one's the right image.
From the left image, we know that the person is standing in front of the tree.
Now if you imagine the two stereo cameras, then you'll notice that the left
camera is viewing the scene from a little bit to the left vice versa for
the right camera.
Similarly, if we look at the right image and
consider the two stereo cameras, same thing here.
Now if we know that the person is standing in front of the tree, then the only
combination that makes sense is that the left image is from the left camera and
the right image is from the right camera.
One way to think about it is the following.
If you shift your viewpoint to the right, then objects that are closer will
move farther to the left than objects that are farther away.