Another thing we can actually now look
at is a four dimensional light field.
Same equation as before there
are five parameters in there.
But we want to actually use that to
reduce the dimensionality by one,
so we can actually now pay
specific attention and
create controllable
types of light fields.
In this case,
it's a four dimensional light field.
What we really want to do is
create a bounding box and
suggest that basically a space
of all lines in 2D space is 4D.
Let me show you what
that means in a bit.
But in this one, the basic assumption
is, we will not be able to represent
occluding objects with different
viewpoints and directions.
The kind of concept that exists here
is basically something similar to
a globe that you may have seen.
Usually the plenoptic function, or
light field, is five dimensional.
But in this case, we can basically
kind of start seeing is that,
if this was my world here, anything
outside of the scene, outside the sphere
of the snow globe here, light does
not actually get occluded by objects.
And therefore, it could be
represented as a 4D light field.
The best way to represent this is by
creating these two different regions,
two different parameterizations,
u and v, and s and t.
And that will allow me to create a four
dimensional light field like this.
To achieve this, basically, what we talk
about is having two different planes.
Each plane has coordinate axes u and
v, and s and t.
Those are my four parameters that
give me this whole parameterization
in four dimensions.
In essence, you can imagine this to be
basically a beam or a slab of light and
everything is basically
contained within it.
So light really flows from
the uv plane to the st plane.
I'll show you examples of that in a bit.
Just to help us with
our parameterization,
we can always kind of say
is that parameters both for
uv space and the st space
are just simply between 0 and 1.
This will allow us to
create an array of images
that we can actually now use to
generate a light field from.
To help us understand this, let's kind
of create this parameterization uv at
the camera plane and
st at the focal plane.
Two different parameterization,
different discretizations would
exist for each one of them.
Now at any point,
I can actually now have a ray of
light come out from this point here.
So now I can put a pin hole here, and
that would capture this
whole scene from this point.
I can, of course,
have a pin hole at this point,
which also captures this whole thing.
There could be different
types of information here.
And, of course, using this we
could generate a variety of
different arrays of
images at the uv plane.
And, of course,
based on which viewpoint I look at,
I would have a different
field of view of the scene.