This is a case involving two companies.
One company had some,
lets say, proprietary
data that its customers
could download and see.
Except that you can get
a trial subscription, and
try it before you buy it kind of
a thing, and gain access to that data.
So, in this case, the person who got
a trial subscription was employee of
another company that competed with this
company whose data we are talking about.
This other company's employee got a
trial subscription, downloaded data, and
the data was available to anyone
who would provide information for
a trial subscription.
But the company whose data it was,
actually went to court.
And its attorneys said, the access
by the competition of the data,
it was unauthorized and
covered under CFAA, so
they should be a penalties for
this company.
And so the question here is,
do you agree with the attorney of
the company who wanted to
sue this competitor for
its employee having a trial
subscription to download this data?
Or do you think this is authorized
because anyone could actually
try the trial subscription and
gain access anyways?