Now, I wanted to show you how powerful n-gram models of language are.
That is, if we're only looking at word sequences,
what is it that we're giving up and what are we getting?
So I read in the complete works of Shakespeare into a small computer program,
and then built n-gram models and sampled from that model.
That is, generated random sentences that come from the probability distribution defined by that model.
And here are samples from the unigram model.
That is sampling from words according to frequency in the corpus of Shakespeare text,
but not taking into account any relationship between adjacent words.
And looking at this, it doesn't make much sense.
It does seem like real sentences.
You can tell the vocabulary is somewhat archaic.
You have words like "o'erthrown" and "thou" and "'tis" and so on,
but you aren't really getting very much from this.