Here are the answers.
The first pair is parallel but
not orthogonal.
In fact,
they differ by a factor of negative 3.
The second pair is neither parallel nor
orthogonal.
The third pair is not parallel but
it is orthogonal.
The last pair is both parallel and
orthogonal.
As stated previously,
the 0 vector is both parallel and
orthogonal to all other vectors.
So we didn't need to use
a program to answer this part.
However, it's worthwhile to make
sure our program can correctly
handle the special case.
Here's the code I wrote to
implement these functions.
I'll start with the function
is_orthogonal_to.
This one is very short.
We should just need to check whether the
two vectors have a dot product of zero.
However, due to precision
issues we should probably check
that the dot product has
a very small absolute value.
Maybe within plus or
minus 10 to the minus 10.
Otherwise you might get a lot of false
negatives when you check whether
two vectors are orthogonal.
The function is_parallel_to
is a bit more complicated.
Here I first check whether either
of the two vectors are zero.
To do this I wrote another
function called is_zero
that checks whether a vector's magnitude
is smaller than some tolerance.
If one of the two vectors is zero, then
I know the two vectors must be parallel,
so I go ahead and return True.
However, if they're both non-zero then
that means, to be parallel they must
either be pointing in the same direction
or in completely opposite directions.
So the angle between the vectors
will be either zero or pi radians.
Here's the code I ran after
defining my functions.
When I executed, I get the answers
to the questions asked previously.