And here we see a more
complete representation
of a problem solving domain in
the language of classical planning.
And here's the Fly action schema, I
made it a little bit more explicit with
from and to airports rather than x or y.
And we want to deal with
transporting cargo.
So in addition to flying,
we have an operator to load a cargo
c onto a plane p at airport a.
And you can see the preconditions and
effects there.
And an action to unload the cargo
from the plane, the preconditions and
effects.
We have a representation of the initial
state, there's two pieces of Cargo,
there's two planes and two airports.
This representation is rich enough and
the algorithms on it are good enough,
that we could have, hundreds or
thousands of Cargo Planes and so on,
representing millions of ground
actions if we had ten airports.
And, 100 planes, that would be 100,
1,000, 10,000 different flying actions.
And if we had thousands of pieces of
cargo, there'd be even more load and
unload actions.
But they can all be represented
by these succinct schema.
The initial state tells us what's what,
where everything is and
then we can represent the goal state,
that we want to have this piece of cargo
has to be delivered to this airport.
Another piece piece of cargo has
to be delivered to this airport.
So, now we know what actions and
problems of initial and goal
state looks like in this representation,
but how do we do planning using this?