Our next optimization
is forward checking.
Basically for each unassigned variable.
We are going to keep track of
the remaining legal values.
>> I get it.
So, if we ever make a decision that
causes an unassigned variable to not be
able to have a value.
We stop our search and back up.
>> Right.
>> Let's try that with
the Australia example.
We start with nothing colored and
all the regions could have
any of the three colors.
>> In our first step we assign
orange to Western Australia.
That removes orange from the colors
available to the Northern Territory and
to Southern Australia.
>> Suppose we assign
green to Queensland.
Now both the Northern Territory and
Southern Australia can only have blue.
And New South Wales can have orange or
blue.
If we assign blue to Victoria.
>> Then we see that New South Wales
can only have orange.
The normal territory can only have blue
and south australia can't have anything.
>> So, we figured out that we are stuck.
And can back track earlier than
we would have if we tried to
continue assigning variables.
>> Exactly, forward checking
is a early warning system
that a search is going
down the wrong branch.