Image pyramids.
The phrase was popular back
the late 70s, early 80s.
Paper that made it really famous was the
Burt and Adelson, same Ted Adelson that
I showed you an example of from before,
in terms of some visual illusions.
And they built something called a
Gaussian Pyramid is just this reduction
just like I told you before.
One of things we can do with Gaussian
images, or these reduced images,
is that we can also create
something called band-pass images.
And having this ability to do both
Gaussian and band-pass let's you deal
with scale very well, which is why I
want to show you this a little bit here.
So, what you have here is,
it says Gaussian pyramid and
it is a Gaussian pyramid, but
it's blown back up again.
All right, in fact, go,
remember these pictures,
where I'm showing you
the different Van Gogh's and
it says half resolution, quarter and
eighth, but they're the same size?
That's because I blew up
the eighth-sized one,
back up to the original size,
so you could see it, right?
So it would look the same way,
all right.
So here, I did the same thing.
This our Lena picture that
we talked of be-, before.
And these are, this is the original,
then blurred, and sub-sampled,
and blown back up again blurred,
sub-sampled, blown, again, again.
So these are the lower
lower resolution images.
What I can do is,
I can subtract one picture from
another to get this difference.
Right?
So this is a difference image.
Two things, first of all this is called
the Laplacian and you should know why.
If you remember when we
did the detections, and
we first did Harris corners, and
then we talked about the SIFT detectors.
David Lowe was talking about using
extrema points in scale space.
And we said, well, one of the things you
could do is you could run a Laplacian
over different scales.
Or you could take different
Gaussians and subtract them.
Those were the difference of Gaussians.
And difference of Gaussians
was approximately the same as
a Laplacian That's why these images
are called Laplacian images, okay?
They're also approximately band-pass,
and
we talked about this just a little bit
when we talked about Fourier analysis.
But the idea is that
the lowest frequency,
if this is frequen, i, frequency
here has them fall off like that.
So the next one, if it had higher
frequency, might look like that.
And if I subtract these two,
basically I'm mostly going to
be looking at that space.
So this is the power of the frequency.
And so when you take a Gaussian blurred
image and you subtract from that another
Gaussian blurred image that's close but
not the same amount of blurring.
You get this section of frequency that
you're mostly, that you're looking at.
It's not totally band-pass,
cause stuff leaks out this side and
stuff leaks out that side.
But that's why they're called,
in quotes, band-pass filtering.
So these images here,
these are called the Laplacian images.
What's kind of cool about the Laplacian
images is you can actually use them
to reconstruct the original
image if you have one thing.
So what's that one
thing you have to have?
You have to have the power.
No.
What you have to have is the smallest
of the original blurred Gaussian,
the top of the Gaussian pyramid.
The reason I have to have that is,
if I take this and
I add back in this, I'll get this one.
Here let me draw in Lena here like that.
Put in her hat and her eyes and
her nos Yeah, there she is.
All right.
Well once I have that,
I can add that to this and
get a finer version of Lena,
and then I can add this and
get back the original Okay?
So the Laplacian pyramid
plus the coarsest of
the level from the Gaussian pyramid
allows me to do reconstruction.
All right.
Keep going on this a little bit.
To show you how to do the construction
of a Laplacian pyramid.
because you're going to use exactly
the same steps for building a Laplacian
pyramid, you're going to use to
run hierarchical Lukas and Kanade.
That's why we're doing this,
so we can get over here.
You got that?
Good.