As the final method in this unit, I'd like now to talk about k-nearest neighbors.
And the distinguishing factor of k-nearest neighbors
is that it is a nonparametric machine learning method.
So far we've talked about parametric methods.
Parametric methods have parameters, like probabilities or weights,
and the number of parameters is constant.
Or to put it differently, the number of parameters is independent of the training set size.
So for example in the Naive Bayes, if we bring up more data,
the number of condition probabilities will stay the same.
Well, that wasn't technically always the case.
Our vocabulary might increase and as such the number of parameters.
But for any fixed dictionary, the number of parameters are truly independent of the training set size.
The same was true, for example, in our regression cases
where the number of regression weights is independent of the number of data points.
Now this is very different from non-parametric
where the number of parameters can grow.
In fact, it can grow a lot over time.
Those techniques are called non-parametric.
Nearest neighbor is so straightforward.
I'd really like to introduce you using a quiz.
So here's my quiz.
Suppose we have a number of data points.
I want you for 1-nearest neighbor to check those squared areas
that you believe will carry a positive label.
And I will give you the label of the existing data points.
So please check any of those boxes that you believe are now
1-nearest neighbor that carry a positive label.
And the algorithm, of course, searches for the nearest point in this Euclidean space and just copies its label.