Now that your visualization is running we need to connect Storm to Flask and D3.
We've chosen Redis to make this connection, and
this is your first exercise in modifying Storm, and remember throughout this
course, at the end of each exercise, your code will match the following stage.
So at the end of this exercise your code will match stage two.
If you run in to any problems along the way, you can find the solution in
stage two, and come back and either modify your code or just continue on.
In step one, if you're following around with the videos you
already have a second tab open with your python flask server, but if not,
you can follow the commands to open another shell in your tab, Vagrant SSH in to
your machine, navigate to the correct lesson and restart your visualization.
Therefore, in Step two of the written instructions in your second tab,
you should already be at Lesson one,
Stage one, if not, simply cd into /vagrant/lesson1/stage1.
Ls should show your pom, source and target files.
In your text editor, navigate to lesson one, stage one, source,
jvm, udacity, storm and open the file ReporterExclaimationTopology.java.
Maven uses a ProjectObjectModel.xml file, or
the POM.xml, to manage product dependencies.
Therefore, to make our visualization run,
we're using the lettuce module to connect our Java program to redis.
So in the first to do part one of four, is to import the lettuce module into
the POM.xml file, the XML dependency must be located in the section.
If you are unfamiliar with XML we will cover this in detail in
the solution video so, copy and paste the dependencies into your palm file.
And your palm file is located in again lesson one, stage one and palm.xml, and
you can simply scroll down and find where I want you to copy and
paste the lettuce redis.
Once that's completed, go back to your command line and
type in mvn package simply to confirm the build success.
Once you have build success following along in step six of the written
instructions, you are going to go back into your ReporterExclamationTopology and
fill in the import statements for
your lambdaworks.redis.RedisClient and lambdaworks.redis.RedisConnection.
Once your import statements are entered in part one of four,
scroll down to step two of four.
In part two of four, we're in the class exclamation bolt and
we're going to create an instance of our redis connection redis.
After that's complete, scroll down to,
to do three of four and instantiate the redis connection and
the actual connection, and the syntax is provided in written instructions.
Finally, in step four of four, simply uncomment the long count and
the reddish.publish to the stream word count apology,
which will take in the exclamated word.toString, separated by the bar, and
our long to stream of account.
This is the connection that will connect up with D3 through our flat server to
run our visualization.
Finally in step seven, go back to your command line, and
package your program, and submit again, using storm, jar, target, udacity.
Remember the hyphen with dependencies, and this is udacity.storm and
this reporter exclamationTopology and hit enter.
And, once you hit enter to submit your storm topology,
you can bring back your visualization and you’ll see that names along with
three exclamation points or six exclamation points will be shown, and
if you hover over any of the names, you'll see the long count 30 appear.
So, good luck on connecting your visualization and once you
see your visualization running, congratulations on completing stage one.
Remember that your code will now match stage two, so any problems along the way,
simply look at stage two code in order to complete stage one