After obtaining your Twitter OAuth credentials you're now ready to
connect to the Twitter sample stream to begin analyzing real time tweets.
In step one,
navigate in your command line to the text editor to lesson two, stage five.
Also in your text editor, go to lesson two > stage five > source > jvm >
Udacity > Storm and we're in our TweetTopology.
In step two, scroll down to the topology section, and
you see the TweetSpout credentials, here.
Remember to enter your OAuth Credentials in order that they appear,
your customer key, secret key, access token, access secret.
I've created a few fake credentials here that approximately match the same size.
And that's it.
Next, scroll down to your Topology,.
In step three, review the tweet topology.
What do you expect the output to be?
Where will it be displayed?
How about you post your predictions to the forum and comment on two other posts.
Next, run your topology using Maven package and submit your Storm topology.
Once you have built success,
remember to submit your topology by looking at the tree structure.
I notice that we have the tweet topology class.
Storm jar target udacity with dependencies, udacity.storm.TweetTopology.
Finally, following the written directions in step four, I'm asking you
to complete the topology by attaching a ParseTweetBolt with a parallelism of 10.
Followed by a CountBolt with a parallelism of 15, and
finally a ReportBolt with a parallelism of one.
What are the needed groupings to connect each topology?
Package your topology using Maven and rerun.
Remember to refer to lesson three, stage one if the tweet topology for
the solution if this is needed.
Finally, in part five, take a screenshot or video and upload this to the forum.
Explain the apology you created and
why you chose each grouping to connect your spout and bolts.
Comment on two other posts, and optional now that you have a Twitter account,
you can tweet your screen shot with your thoughts on the class.
Good luck.