String interpolation is
another incredibly convenient
feature of switch strings.
Here's an example, let's say you're
moving into a new apartment and
you need to pay the first and last
months rent' plus the security deposit.
Let's use string interpolation
to replace the word Total
with the correct total.
Will start with the dollar sign and
assume this might be in US dollars, and
through string interpolation,
we can insert that expression
right into the string.
And the result is here in the sidebar.
We looked at some common
string manipulations,
including string concatenation.
For example,
we can combine our monkeyString and our
thiefString to make a very short story
about a monkey with sticky fingers.
We also learn that strings come
with a host of useful functions
including the contains function and many
more, let's see those one more time.
Let's call the contains function
on our silly monkey string.
Here, we ask if the sillyMonkeyString
contains the string key.
In the sidebar we can
see that this is true.
Here is another one.
Let's say our Wi-Fi password
is Meet me in St Louis but
we need to switch it up a bit.
Let's replace all the es with 3s
using the string function replacing
the currency of with and over here in
the sidebar we can see the result.