So one more question.
And we're talking about
legal deterrents having
CFAA or BMC and those kind of laws.
We didn't talk about privacy laws.
I did say that they exist.
But let's go back to sort of connect
the privacy discussion we had
with some of the stuff
we talked about was.
So we said poor privacy,
what does poor privacy mean?
Somebody collects data about you, they
don't tell you what they're collecting,
they don't protect it, they share it
with whoever, and things like that.
So that would be poor privacy.
Good privacy is, you know what they
collect, you know what they use it for,
you know who they share it with,
and they protect it,
work hard to protect it.
So poor privacy would be one of
those things not being done.
So poor privacy is good for bad guys,
because they can use
information about you.
Poor privacy means they can
gain access to information
that you consider private.
They can get hold of it.
So why is that useful to them?
That's why we need those legal
deterrents against them.