We'll be getting to our Sunshine
updates at the end of this lesson.
In the meantime, though,
we're going to take a deep dive into
an app called Visualizer Preferences.
It's a little known fact that Larry,
our creative lead,
mixes beats in his free time.
Lately, him and
I did a collaboration of sorts.
And, [LAUGH] no, it's not me singing,
I will spare you that.
Instead, Larry wanted to
make a cool visualization
to go along with his demo tracks,
and thus, Visualize was born.
Visualize shows an auto visualization
of one of Larry's songs, with a circle,
square, and
triangle bumping to the different
frequencies of the sound of the music.
Now Larry loved this visualization, but
he wanted a way to be able to fiddle
around with the parameters
of the visualization.
Things like the color, or
the size of the shapes, or,
even, which of those shapes
appeared on the screen.
Now I have actually already written
all the code to be able to do that,
but there's no way for
Larry to be able to actually modify
these parameters in the app's UI.
This is where you come in.
You'll be making a settings screen for
this application that will let any
user modify the following attributes.
First, which shapes are shown, second,
the color of the visualization, and
finally, the size of the shapes.
Let's go ahead and dive into the code.