Okay, so here we are at
Firebase's Example Datasets.
These are some public data sets that
are freely available to access.
You can access the data and
use it in your app,
though you can't write to the data set.
They're also good examples of what
larger Firebase databases look like.
So while I take a look at
the links I just sent over,
why don't you pick one
that looks interesting so
that we can discuss one of
the more populated data sets.
>> Let's see.
I'm liking the look of that
Cryptocurrencies Data Set.
You know,
I might want to incorporate BitCoin and
DogeCoin shopping into shopping
list plus plus someday.
And for the developer, if you're
not sure what a Cryptocurrency is,
the short answer is that
it's digital money.
And the long answer is
in the instructor notes.
Anyways, yes, Cryptocurrency it is.
>> Sounds good.
Let's take a look at the
Cryptocurrencies Firebase dashboard to
see what a mature Firebase
database looks like.
Here, I've got an app dashboard
that looks a lot like mine, but
with a bit more data.
I can see here that I've got
three different key value pairs.
And instead of BitCoin having
one value associated with it,
it has a map with five
child key value pairs.
Look at the URL, this is known as the
root URL because it's the main page for
your Firebase database.
One of the cool things about Firebase is
that any of these collections of data,
which I'll call nodes,
has a URL associated with it.
For example, I can click on
this node that says dogecoin.
I am then directed to a page that just
shows the dogecoin subset of the data.
Similarly, the URL has updated
in the address bar, and
in the bread crumb of the interface.
If I click on a child node of dogecoin,
like bid, I can see the full path for
this in the address bar and
in the bread crumb.
So every piece and subset of data
in the database has a unique URL.
This is the location of the data,
also called the database location.
Just like a URL or file location,
you can enter the unique
URL in the address bar and see
the specific data you are interested in.
It is important to understand how these
paths specify the location of your data.
Since you use these paths to refer to
data that you're reading and writing.
Now let's navigate back to the root URL.
You might notice how the database
will occasionally flash yellow.
Yellow means that something is changing.
In our example, it might indicate the
time when the Bitcoin is last updated.
Notice how the parent objects of
the changed value are also changed.
Whenever a child is changed,
all parents also flash yellow,
because a part of them has changed.
As you add and
remove data from your app, you'll
see similar types of interactions.
Whenever any child data is added,
removed, changed or
moved, the parents also flash yellow
to show that they have changed.
What's the URL for ask in litecoin?