The L stands for Linux, and that's the operating system on which
probably the server side of the application is going to run.
Linux is a well controlled and uniformed operating system family,
and you can take advantage of that as a way of
controlling the variation that's going on in the system.
The A stands for Apache, and what's meant here is the Apache web server.
The Apache web server is the most popular web server, and using it and
its configuration file enables you to evolve in a controlled fashion.
The M stands for MySQL, which is now part of Oracle.
It's the database engine, it supports a standard relational type of
database access using the SQL language, so there's another standard.
And the P stands for PHP, which is a means of
essentially embedding the database interactions into your HTML program so
that on the server side, that can then become SQL transactions to the database.