Its actually quite straightforward
to make your apps content provider
available to third party apps.
The key is to modify the export flag
in the manifest entry here to true.
As simple as that, any app that knows
the content URI can use the content
resolver to access it,
the same way that you do.
Now depending on the sensitivity of
your data, you may want to protect it
by requiring specific permissions
to read or write to the database.
So if you want to,
you can effectively limit access only
to other apps you've created, or
to third party apps which know other
permissions and users agree to.
Then you just need to
publish this contract to
interact with the content provider.
Specifically the URI and column names.
And as simple as that, you've created
a new API just for your data.
This is exactly the same approach used
by many of the native content providers,
including the context database,
media store, calendar and call log.