For the two direct effects, which we, we use the term
event handlers for, it makes sense to have methods responsible for doing that.
And, with methods, we have pre and post conditions.
And, it's pretty straight forward, which components are receiving the events, or
the ones that responsible for, for dealing with them.
For the three association, constraints that we've now assigned to components.
Those were invariants.
And remember that, OCL has pre-conditions, post-conditions, and invariants, and,
as the system, as the user interacts with the system and makes a change,
let's say, to the scroll bar handle, it's a responsibility of the system.
To make sure that all the inter, indirect affect take place.
That process is called invariant maintenance.
An invariant is something which is always true.
We've temporarily made it untrue.
So we have to reset the system to a consistent state, we move the handle,
we have to change what the contents on the screen.
So that's and example of the, maintaining that particular invariant.
Taking that a step further,
when the user scrolls, remember we had three invariants.
Which of those invariants do you think might break?