So here you can see how I've
added to the MainActivity.
I've set it so that it implements
GoogleAPIClient.ConnectionCallbacks and
GoogleAPIClient.OnConnectionFailedListe-
ner.
I've then implemented
the onConnection function,
which takes a bundle connectionHint and
overridden it.
I've implemented onConnectionFailed,
which takes the ConnectionResult
that I call result and I've
implemented onConnectionSuspended and
this takes an integer
which is the cause.
You should log each of these events
as they happen, but just for
brevity I'm leaving them blank.
In the onConnectionSuspended when
you have a Google API client,
you should connect it but I haven't
defined my GoogleAPIClient yet.
And so I've just commented it out.
So then you're going to
do this in the next step.
And we'll get our onCreate
function going so
that we can set up the GoogleAPIClient
and the UI and the other goodies.