But first,
I want to introduce you to another idea.
It’s the idea of 1 x 1 convolutions.
You might wonder, why one would ever
want to use 1 x 1 convolutions?
They’re not really looking at a patch
of the image just that one pixel.
Look at the classic convolution setting,
it’s basically a small classifier for
a patch of the image but
it's only a linear classifier.
But if you add a 1 x 1 convolution in
the middle, suddenly you have a mini
neural network running over the patch
instead of a linear classifier.
Interspersing your convolutions with 1
x 1 convolutions is a very inexpensive
way to make your models deeper and
have more parameters,
without completely
changing their structure.
They're also very cheap because
if you go through their math,
they're not really convolutions at all,
they're really just matrix multiplies
and they have relatively few parameters.
I mentioned all of these,
average pulling and
1 x 1 convolutions because I want to
talk about the general strategy that has
been very successful at creating
cognates that are both smaller and
better than cognates that simply
use a pyramid of convolutions.