In module Eight I'm going to introduce to even specia,l and
really kind of from the, recent research efforts some of
the exciting new topics in computational photography.
For example, we'll learn about newer camera technologies.
How we can actually even control lighting in cameras,
to be able to generate newer forms of images.
How does concept of blur and deblur in images, and how do new forms of
computational cameras can be used to deal with those, types of artifacts?
More importantly, we'll also deal with the fact that now,
cameras are everywhere, and
this has led to a whole new form of social and crowd photography.
Again we'll discuss those types of examples, more importantly I
do want everybody to start thinking we will do a final project.
Or more appropriately you will do a final project of your own choosing, on
a topic that we covered in class, or something that you want to do on your own,
and we'd like to provide you with various types of supports to get you there.
But more importantly, we want you to play around with newer concept on your own.
So that's an important part I want everybody to think about as you will
select topic, I will provide some examples of the kinds of things you could do,
and you will make it work for real in the last few weeks of class.