Recognizing what's in an image is
the essence of computer vision.
When we look at the world
through our own eyes,
we're constantly performing
classification tasks with our brain.
>> That's right.
And in the case of self-driving cars,
reliable object detection and
classification are essential to giving
the car to see the world just like we
do.
In this lesson, your goals to learn how
to identify vehicles and images but
it doesn't end there.
You'll need to come up with the methods
for separating false positives from
real detections and in track the real
detections from one frame to the next.
So Arpan, where would you like to begin?
>> Well,
like any good machine learning problem,
it all begins with feature extraction.
So, first we'll look at how
to compute features that
we can use to reliably
identify cars in our images.