Let me talk a little bit
about image morphing.
Here I'm going to demonstrate this.
And again, just to point out,
this may not be exactly the images.
But, we're just going to learn about
how we're going to do image morphing.
In the previous slide, I showed
you how we can use triangles and
deform them with the displacement
map to be able to generate
a morph field between two frames.
Of course,
we don't have to stick to just triangle.
It could be a quadrilateral
mesh that's also displaced by
various types of
interpolation techniques.
Minimum energy methods are widely used
with this to compute the best possibly
way of deforming from one surface to
the other or one mesh to the other.
So for example, in that case,
we would basically take a like this,
have another one that would be
deformed appropriately for this and
that would allow us to
generate in between images.
Another method we can use is find
corresponding features between
these two different images.
So in this case, of course,
it's an image we can actually relate to
quite well and
start identifying common features.
Both of them are faces, so basically
what I can do is now mark out the,
you know, the corners of the eyes,
crners of the nose, tip of the nose, and
also the three points on the lips.
And of course, I can do the same for
the leopard, or a cheetah image.
Again, if you notice,
these eyes have different forms, but
now I have these corresponding points.
And I know this point is that one,
this point is that one.
And remember, all of the work
we've done with feature detection,
some of these will come out off
using things like algorithms.
Then they could be matched.
We can actually do more.
We can actually come up with
corresponding oriented line segments.
Which, in essence,
also defines details like
how would the translation rotation and
scaling happen on these region.
Of course, what that kind of mean is,
now the nose is this direction.
I want to keep that,
that nose basically may have shrunk
in size if I draw a line like this.
And if the eye's were smaller,
if I connect these two lines,
the eye's will also get smaller.
So in essence, to achieve this,
we will basically now create
oriented line segments that
are connecting these regions and
giving it a lot more structure.
So now if the eyes were small and
these two types of things,
you would notice the difference here.
Here, you basically see the line
segment is smaller for the target.
And of course, the lips have moved down,
the nose is approximately the same, but
the the tip has moved up.
Now, of course, all of this
detail is basically important,
because now we can actually do
the image transformations like,
translation, rotation, and scaling,
and allows us to have more control how
we want to actually see these things.