Okay, Charles, how we going to
reduce this to a single number?
>> We're going to follow those
steps that you have outlined.
I don't know the answer, but
I think I know how to get to the answer.
>> All right, let's do it.
>> Okay so, well first off,
are we doing finite or infinite here?
>> T = 5 it says.
>> T = 5, so we're definitely doing
T equals, that's what I thought,
just want to be sure.
Okay well, so all I have to do is
actually turn everything that I see
into, turn the state transition into
immediate reward, so I can do that.
Would you mind writing some stuff for
me?
>> Not at all.
>> Yeah there you go.
So let's do ones over the greens and
minus 0.2 over the reds.
But actually I don't really care about
the one you just wrote down because it's
more than T = 5 away.
>> All right.
Well that's going to
come up in the next step.
Truncate according to horizons.
So one, two, three, four, five, cut.
>> Mm-hm.
>> One, two, three, four, five, cut.
One, two, three, four, five, cut.
Now [LAUGH] I was a little bit
sloppy with how I defined the five.
It could be that you actually
put it one step deeper.
But I was careful to
pick a horizon link.
So that it wouldn't matter
which way you interpreted it.
This would just add zeros to it.
It wouldn't change anything.
So anyway here we
are cutting it at five.
>> Okay, pretty smart, Michael.
All right, cool.
So now that we've done the truncating,
I just need to summarize each
of the sequences in turn.
So I know that whatever I would give for
the first value,
would be 0.8 to the zero or to the one.
Where are we starting from?
>> That's another good question.
So that's going to actually change
the answer depending on how
people interpret that.
I would say, to take this literally,
that we're talking about
the first reward being r1 and
then the next one being r2, r3, r4, r5.
And the gamma corresponds
to the index number here.
>> That doesn't seem right.
>> Yeah, but it is what it is.
>> Okay, seems like it should be zero,
one, two, three, four.
>> Oh, I see!
If you call the first one zero.
Oh, I like that better!
>> Mm-hm.
>> [LAUGH] But probably for
the quiz, we should accept either way.
>> Sure.
>> Or either way.
Okay, so now that we know what
all the words for the rule was,
that's pretty easy.
Actually, I think that's going to
work out pretty well for us.
So then for the first sequence I
know it's going to be 1 times 0
plus 0.8 times 1.
And actually everything else is 0.
So.
>> Yep.
>> As I explained it.
>> So this first sequence actually
has a return of 0.8.
>> Right.
So the second sequence
is pretty similar.
It's going to be 1 times 0 plus, blah
blah blah, so that's 8 to the third,
or pointing to the third,
times 1, which is some number.
Okay, so the return for
the second sequence is 0.512.
So for the third sequence,
we're going to do the same thing,
it's going to be 0.8 to
the second power, times 1.
>> First power
>> To the first power,
thank you very much.
0.8 to the first power times 1 which is,
in fact, 0.8,
+ 0.8 to the fourth power x minus 0.2.
All right, so we got 0.8,
0.512, and 0.71808.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And so, we just have to add
those together, get an average, but
a weighted average.
>> Mm.
>> So it's going to be 0.8 times
0.6 plus 0.512 times 0.1
plus 0.71808 times 0.3.
Which is obviously.
>> All right, so
when you've just worked out, then you
get something that's very close to 0.75.
So that's the summary of this particular
outcomes of this particular policy
according to these various
parameters that we've chosen.