For the number of seconds in 40 years, I know that I need to start the number
with a 1. So here's my decimal point. I need to move this decimal place over
here. So if I thought about moving this decimal place, I would need to move it
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9 places. So I have 10 to the 9th. This should make
sense. My exponent is a positive 9, so I just move this decimal place to the
right 9 spaces. Okay for the red blood cell I know I have 6, so 6 needs to start
my answer. I'm moving this decimal place to the left. because I have 0 still
left of 6. So I will move it 1 2 3 4 5 6, 6 places left. So I have 6 times 10 to
the negative 6. Okay.
Scientific notation is also pretty helpful, because when I compare 2 numbers
like the dominoes toppled or. 4 million, I can compare it to 1 billion. I notice
that the difference in the powers is 10 to the third. That means there's 1,000
times the number of dominoes. When I look at these two numbers in scientific
notation, I can tell how many times larger a number is than another number. For
example, the number of seconds in 40 years is 1,000 times the number of dominoes
toppled. I know this because the difference in the powers is ten to the third.
So the number of seconds in 40 years is 1000 times the number of dominoes.
Alright, let's get back to our original problem.