So looking at that we can think about it this way, all right?
So, the surface, E of u,v, in this quadratic form,
is being approximated essentially by this quadratic or, or
sort of parabolic shaped form here, and that's just written the equations out.
Now, let's think just for a moment if you were to take a fixed value of E.
Okay. So, we're just going to pick some constant value.
All right.
So, that would look like this.
And here I've written it two ways.
I've written it sort of down below in sort of the elegant matrix way,
which we're about to cover up.
because I like inducing pain.
And the top way is just the algebraic expression of
that expression equal to a constant.
And what you can see here is,
now you remember, this is the equation of an ellipse in u and v space.
All right, so you remember A x squared plus B xy plus C y squared equals D or
something like that, was a, was a, was a an ellipse.
And if the middle term, the xy term, was 0, it meant that
the ellipse's major and minor axes were aligned with the x and y axis?
Well, this is the same thing.
This is just the, an ellipse in the u v space, all right?
So we can draw that out like this, okay?
So here is different ellipses for different values of k.
So you can think about that the way we're approximating this
whole surface is as a quadratic surface that gets bigger and
bigger, and each different level is an ellipse.
Okay, so that's what you get when you do the type of
second order quadratic Taylor expansion of, of this function.