So, this quiz asks us to insert
the proper slicing indices for
the substring variable so
that the slicer turns the string that
contains everything after a noun.
So, this piece right here,
is what we want.
To solve this,
you need to find the first position
in sentence that starts after a noun.
Let's take a look at the sentence
variables index values.
The beginning of the string, or
index zero, has a value of A.
Index one is a blank space,
index two is N,
index three is O Index four is u,
and index five is n, and
index six is a space.
Now we've found where noun ends.
Let's use this index as
the beginning of our slice.
Since you want to keep
everything after noun,
we can leave the right hand
side of the colon blank.
And there we have it.
Those are the indices used that will
give us everything after A noun.
As we see, string slicing allowed us
to keep the parts of the string that we
wanted to use and
let us cut out the parts,
like a noun that we didn't want to keep.
We'll see very soon how string
slicing will help us build a simple
mavericks generator.