We know enough now to start
building a plane class that will be
very similar to our line class.
Let's go ahead and do a quiz so
we can get the framework built
before starting to tackle the problem
of intersections of planes.
For this quiz, I've provided
a Python module called plane.pie.
In it, I provided very similar
functionality to the line.py module.
In fact, it is the same except that all
instances of the word line have been
replaced with plane.
You can find this module in
the downloadable section of this page.
For the quiz, I'd like you to
add two functions to the module.
One to test whether two
planes are parallel, and
another to test whether
two planes are equal.
To check your code,
here are some test cases.
Please indicate whether each of
the following pairs of planes are equal,
parallel but not equal, or not parallel.
The first pair of planes is -0.412x +
3.806y + 0.728z = -3.46.
And 1.03x- 9.515y-
1.82z = 8.65.
The second pair of planes is 2.611x
+ 5.528y + 0.283z = 4.6 and
7.715x + 8.306y + 5.342z = 3.76.
The third pair of planes is -7.926x
+ 8.625y- 7.217z = -7.952.
And -2.642x + 2.875y-
2.404z = -2.443.