We saw in the previous morsel that
the use of timeslices delivers certain
benefits.
We're able to start the execution of
tasks sooner, and therefore, we are able
to achieve an overall schedule of
the task that's more responsive.
But that came with certain overheads.
So the balance between these two
is going to imply something about
the length of the timeslice.
We will see that to answer this
question, how long should a timeslice
be, the balance between these two
differs if we're considering I/O-bound
tasks, so tasks that mostly perform I/O
operations, versus CPU-bound tasks,
so tasks, these are tasks that
are mostly executing on the CPU and
don't do any I/O or do very little I/O.
We will look at these two
different scenarios next.