Let's start by working through our
waypoint system for navigation.
Waypoints are awesome for
mobile VR, because they allow
users to effectively navigate
around their entire environment,
with the single press of a trigger.
Once you understand how to use
this script you will be able to
easily add navigation to
any VR scenes you create.
Back in our island scene,
let's add some waypoints.
To do that, we go to Art.
Prefabs.
Systems.
And this waypoints,
we just drag into our scene.
Let's reset the position and
move it to a good space on our island.
As we saw in the demo,
each of these green orbs represents
waypoints that we can teleport to.
Our goal in this video,
is to be able to add additional
waypoints, change the way they look, and
change how quickly we move to
a new waypoint, when we click it.
If we look at waypoints
in the hierarchy,
you'll see that there are two scripts
attached, waypoints.cs is right here,
on each waypoint and
then on the waypoints root node
we'll see that there's also
navigation.cs attached here.
Let's open up these
scripts in MonoDevelop and
see if we can look at what they do and
modify them.
Let's start with the waypoint script.
But to help us better understand it,
let's also look at how
it's used inside Unity.
We can see that each of the orbs
has a waypoint script attached, so
we know that the script probably changes
the attributes of individual waypoints.
We can also see it keeps track
of a bunch of different states,
such as when it's occupied or active or
focused to name just a few of these.
Knowing this,
let's jump back into MonoDevelop.
Now let's try modifying some things.
First up, let's animate our waypoints,
then change their default color.
Here let's try to get our waypoints to
animate much larger than they originally
did.
Looking through these variables we can
probably discount material color and
highlight.
But there's also highlight scale
which looks super promising.
I'm also modifying the waypoint's
local scale using it.
Taking a deeper look at this line,
we can see that we're changing our
transform using the original scale,
highlight scale, animation scale, and
also the pulse animation parameter.
Going back to the top of our script,
we'll see that animation
scale is set to 1.5.
Let's try adjusting it to 3 and
see what happens.
We'll try that now, we see that it's so
still feels the same.
This is because Unity allows us to
change public variables in the inspector
and override those values in scripts.
To change them, we actually need to
set them in the inspector itself.
And now we can see our orb
animating a lot quicker.
Now let's try adjusting the speed.
Luckily for us, there's a clearly
marked variable called animation speed.
Let's reduce that to 2 and try it again.
And now we can see, that's pulsating
a lot bigger but also slower.
Awesome.
So now that we've changed how our
individual waypoints look and behave.
Let's dig into our navigation script and
adjust how we can interact with them.
The top variable here is the viewObject.
If we take a look at the comment it's
defined as the viewers game object
which already gives us a hint that
we should put the VR camera there.
However, if we also take a look at
the first line of start right here
we'll see that if we don't
assign anything to view object,
the script automatically assigns
the camera main object to view object.
Isn't that nice?
But to be explicit,
let's assign our camera anyways.
So we now know how to change
the way waypoints look and feel and
how we can move between them.
But when we're building scenes they
won't be in the same layout as this one.
Let's get some practice creating new
waypoints by adding more to the scene.
Doing this is actually pretty simple.
Just drag a waypoint
prefab into the scene.
Once we position it where we want it, we
then need to set the waypoint neighbors.
To do that,
all we have to do is drag references
onto the neighborhood property.
You'll be able to use these waypoint
scripts to create a navigation mechanic
in any VR experience you
create in the future.
So don't be afraid to reuse the code.
No sense reinventing the wheel.
But time to move on to something a bit
more visual like modifying our ocean.