There are several advantages of
deploying host based firewalls.
For example, specific security policies
for service can be incremented
with different filters for
servers used for different applications.
Since the firewall is not at the network
parameter, both internal and
external attacks can be stopped
by the host based firewall.
That is, while an attack coming
from the internal network
is missed by the firewall
at the network perimeter,
it can be stopped by
the host based firewall.
We typically deploy host based firewall
in addition to network firewall, so
therefore, host based firewalls provides
an additional layer of protection.