So now let me actually introduce
you to a fun quiz we're going to do
with Harris Detectors.
And you'll get experience of actually
using some code online to be able
to kind of see how we can actually
do Harris Detectors on an image.
To do this quiz, you'll have to work
back to the browser where, basically,
you've been getting to see
all of your lectures, and
go to, and this site, and go to Sandbox.
Of course, whenever you are in
the sandbox some code should be existing
there that's been working on before.
And in this case I have something for
feature matching.
So, for this quiz,
what I want you to do is basically
look at this code and run it.
Let me show you what's happening here,
and
this is the code that actually
does Harris corner detection.
And our goal at this quiz is to
take piece of codethat is there and
find this image.
And in this image, find the corners.
Of course,
all of the processing steps are shown,
and here you basically can see that it
did find corners, but not all of them.
So one, two, three, four, five.
It missed these two.
So what I want you folks to do is,
first, go ahead and
find the documentation for
this function.
And here, basically,
in this function in the code,
basically change the parameters that
all eight corners are detected.
Then you hit the Submit.
The code will be evaluated
against two different images and
you'll get an answer.
So that's what I want you to for
this assignment, or this quiz, please.