There's another interesting kernel
that's used in computer vision
I want to mention it explicitly,
because it, it works so
much better than what people
might've tried originally.
Often in computer vision
we'll build histograms
of some distribution
to describe something.
So, one we'll actually talk about it
just a little bit when we talk about
video activity recognition.
You might build up what are called a
bunch of video code, visual code words.
All right?
So, you you find a whole bunch of
interest points in video or set, and you
say well, they're all different kinds.
But let me create a whole
bunch of buckets,
maybe a thousand different buckets,
and I'm going to
map each one of these points to
being in to one of those buckets.
So, if you give me a chunk of video,
it could be described by the histogram
of how many of each
visual code word show up.
So, I've got two different pieces of
video, and I want to compare them.
I want a similarity metric
between these histograms.
So, people used a variety of things.
You can think of them as distributions,
so you can use KL divergence or
symmetric KL divergence,
or Bhattacharyya distance,
which is another was of computing,
of comparing, densities.
But Jitendra Malik and
students came up with what is called
a histogram intersection kernel.
And the histogram intersection kernel
is incredibly simple, all right?
So your xi's and xj's, they're
now the vectors of the histogram.
And you just sum up over all of them,
the min of the two values, right?
So in bin one, whichever one is smaller,
you take that.
Oh, and by the way, the histogram's
been normalized to sum to one.
And if you take that value and
you sum them up,
you'll realize the minimum
value is zero, right?
If, if one bin is empty when the other
one is full, always take the empty ones.
So, I can sum up all zeros.
And the maximum it can be is one,
because if they're all identical,
then it doesn't matter which one I pick.
And the histogram has been
normalized to sum to one, anyway.
So, it's got, so it can have a large
number of dimensions, if you have, for
example, a large number of code
words that your histogramming.
And it's very effective, and, sort of
caught people a little bit by surprise,
I think, because people had been doing
things like Euclidean distances on,
on histogram, which,
turns out to be a bad idea.
And this is just much more effective.