With a depth limit of 2 we get a very
different result than with a limit of 3.
>> Yep,
at level 2 the losing center moves.
Both have scores of 3, while
the winning moves have smaller scores.
>> Does that mean our
evaluation function is bad?
>> Not necessarily.
It may mean that we are not searching
deep enough to get good answers.
>> How do we tell?
>> One way to check is to see which
branch is the Minimax algorithm
recommends at each level of the search.
If the results vary widely
between certain levels,
it may be because a critical decision
is being made at those levels.
Let's try it out on
the example isolation game.
We will continue to use the number
of my moves evaluation function,
which can have a maximum score of 5 and
a minimum score of 0.
If we find a branch where
our computer player loses,
we'll give it a score of negative 1.
If we find a branch where
our computer player wins,
we'll give it a score of 100.
With this example isolation game at
level 1, the number of mime moves of
the valuation function would
recommend the two center moves, and
the top left move.
Each of these have scores of 4.
By level 2, the two center moves are
considered the best with scores of 3.
At level 3 the center moves
are considered worst.
that continues for level 4,
5 and 6.
After level 3,
we've reached a state of quiescence.
The recommended branches
are not changing much.
We know we are in good shape.