To make things concrete,
let's look at a file system
that's supported on disk devices.
We will look at ext2, which stands for
Extended Filesystem version 2.
It was a default file system in
several versions of Linux until
it was replaced by ext3 and
then ext4 more recently,
that are the default versions in
more current versions of Linux.
It is also available for other operating
systems, it's not just Linux specific.
A disk partition that is used
as an ext2 Linux file system,
will be organized in the following way.
The first block,
block 0 is not used by Linux and
it often contains the code
to boot the computer.
The rest of this partition
is divided into groups and
exactly what are the sizes of the groups
that has nothing to do with the physics
of the disk.
What are the disk cylinders or
sectors or anything like that.
Each of the Block Groups in this
partition will be organized as follows.
The first Block in a Block Group
is the Super Block.
And this contains information
about the overall Block Group.
It will have information
about the number of inodes,
about the number of disk
Blocks in this Block.
And it will also have information
about the start of the free Blocks.
The overall state of the Block Group
is further described in the group
descriptor.
And this will have information
about the location of the bitmaps.
We'll describe what they mean, next.
About the total number of free nodes.
About the total number of
directories in the system.
This information is useful
when files are being allocated
because the ext 2 tries to balance the
over all allocation of directories and
files across the determined
Block Groups.
The bitmaps are used to quickly
find a free Block or a free inodes.
And for every single inode in this
particular group and every single
Data Block, the bitmap will be able
to tell the upper layer allocators.
Letter that inode component or
the Data Block are free or
they're used by some other file or
directory.
Then come the inodes.
They're numbered from one up
to some maximum number and
every one of the inodes
is in ext 2 128 byte
long data structure that
describes exactly one file.
It will have information like,
what is the owner of the file,
some accounting information that system
calls like stat would return, and
also some information like how to
locate the actual Data Blocks.
So these are the Blocks
that hold the file data.
Again, a reminder, a directory will
really be just the file except that
in the upper levels of the file system
software stack there will be these
entry data structures created for
each particular component for
the particular directory.