[Thrun] And the answer for this one is really interesting.
A is clearly not independent of E because through C we can see an influence of A to E.
Given B, that doesn't change.
A still influences C, despite the fact we know B.
However, if we know C, the influence is cut off.
There is no way A can influence E if we know C.
A is clearly independent of B.
They are different entry variables. They have no incoming arcs.
But here is the caveat.
Given C, A and B become dependent.
So whereas initially A and B were independent,
if you give C, they become dependent.
And the reason why they become dependent we've studied before.
This is the explain away effect.
If you know, for example, C to be true,
then knowledge of A will substantially affect what we believe about B.
If there's 2 joint causes for C and we happen to know A is true,
we will discredit cause B.
If we happen to know A is false, we will increase our belief for the cause B.
That was an effect we studied extensively in the happiness example I gave you before.
The interesting thing here is we are facing a situation
where knowledge of variable C renders previously independent variables dependent.