You've done a lot of preparation for
a job and review by now.
You know what to expect and
have strategies to help prepare for
whichever questions come your way.
Remember that what works for someone
else may not be what works for you.
And that's okay, it is you going
into the interview room that day, so
you get to decide how
you want to prepare.
Our advice is to practice a little
every day for interviewing,
such as thinking over a potential
question or researching the company.
If you come across a topic you
don't feel comfortable with,
continue practicing until
you get comfortable.
The career resource center has a lot
of tips and resources for you.
The day of the interview,
walk in calm and confident.
Remember, you're already one of the most
qualified candidates for the role.
You'll ace the interview.
[BLANK_AUDIO]