[PROBLEM SOLVING]
In this unit we're going to talk about problem solving.
The theory and technology of building agents
that can plan ahead to solve problems.
In particular, we're talking about problem solving
where the complexity of the problem comes from the idea that there are many states.
As in this problem here.
A navigation problem where there are many choices to start with.
And the complexity comes from picking the right choice now and picking the right choice at the
next intersection and the intersection after that.
Streaming together a sequence of actions.
This is in contrast to the type of complexity shown in this picture,
where the complexity comes from the partial observability
that we can't see through the fog where the possible paths are.
We can't see the results of our actions
and even the actions themselves are not known.
This type of complexity will be covered in a later unit.
Here's an example of a problem.
This is a route-finding problem where we're given a start city,
in this case, Arad, and a destination, Bucharest, the capital of Romania,
from which this is a corner of the map.
And the problem then is to find a route from Arad to Bucharest.
The actions that the agent can execute when driving
from one city to the next along one of the roads shown on the map.
The question is, is there a solution that the agent can come up with
given the knowledge shown here to the problem of driving from Arad to Bucharest?