Sometimes problems are not always
as simple as buying something from
the store, in fact,
most problems are a lot more complex.
>> With most problems,
there's more things to consider before
you can actually solve the problem.
For example, me deciding what
I want to do this weekend.
>> What were you planning
on doing this weekend?
>> Well, I was thinking I would
hang out with my friend Colt.
And, if he's not busy and
the weather is nice so
I was thinking we could go to the park.
>> That sounds like fun.
I think, this is the perfect time for
us to transition into more
complex logical expressions.
>> It is?
>> Well yeah, think about it.
For your plans to happen, there are two
conditions that need to be true.
Call tests not be busy and
the weather needs to be nice.
If both of those things happen, then,
you and Colt are going to the park.
>> Okay, I see where you're going.
In JavaScript, we can represent more
complex problems by combining logical
expressions with special operators
called logical operators.
Check it out.