Lets now explore the Twitter4J API if your interested in
modifying your data spout using the link in the instructors node we open the de
facto official Twitter API Twitter4J as you've already explored in
lesson 3 tweets are called status.
We can search for the get text function, to explore what we have been using.
And we see that getText returns the text of the status or tweet.
Navigating to the TweetSpout, say, in lesson two, stage six,
you see again that we've implemented this for you.
Scrolling through the Twitter4J status options,
you see we have information regarding a number of interesting data points.
That you may want to explore in your final project.
One could be getFavorite count, which indicates approximately how many times,
the tweet has been favorited by Twitter users.
Or maybe geoLocation, which returns a geoLocation object.
Clicking on the geoLocation object, and
scrolling down, we see in the method summary.
The getLatitude, and getLongitude methods.
These functions were used by one of our Hackathon's teams to
drive their US map visualization.
Navigating back to the status page,
another interesting status method is getLang.
In your final project one simple extension you could add is to
emit tweet temples in only your favorite language, or
emit language data in your emit schema.
Another approach is to modify your Twitter4J listener.
We navigate to the Twitter4J package.
And navigate down to Twitter stream.
Scrolling down a bit further,
notice the function firehouse, which starts listening on all public statuses.
This function listens to all public tweets, how cool is that?
Here's an MIT Technology Review article from November 12th 2014,
talking about the Twitter Firehose, and the ebb and
flow of geolocated tweets as a social microscope about New York.
It shows that the same functions we're exploring,
are being used in popular research, culture, and analyses.
Navigating back to the twitter4j.
Twitter stream.
Above the firehose, we see the filter method.
We click on the FilterQuery, and scroll down to the Method summary, and
we see that we can filter queries based on count,
follows, language, location and keyword using track.
If we click on Locations.
We see the function our Hackathon team uses,
to filter queries from Twitter based on a double 2D array.
In the package overview, remember then after your basic implementation is
complete, you can explore all types of data, filter queries and data types
coming from Twitter, or choose data completely on your own from another source.
I also hope you're following along with some of the discussions in our
Hackathon teams.
And use this as inspiration for some of your own awesome projects.