Now, you should have determined
that message is a global variable.
And you can tell this from looking at
where it's declared, which is up here.
It is not declared in
any of these methods.
It's declared, in fact,
outside of any methods.
It is, though,
declared between the curly braces
of what we've been calling
the main activity class.
Okay.
So the next question is,
should message be a global variable.
Well, whenever we use message,we
see that we set what message is,
and then we immediately display it.
When we set what message is, we don't
look at a previous value of message.
Global variables are good for keeping
track of a previous value between
things like button clicks or
other events you might have in your app.
They're a way to save
the state of an app.
What they're not good for
is when you're using a variable
as a sort of intermediate value.
Remember, when you're executing
the code inside one of these
blocks called a method,
you do each statement sequentially.
If your variable is only needed within
the sequence of those statements then it
doesn't need to be a global variable.
It's being used locally.
It's being used just in the method.
And that's the case with message.
It's a kind of intermediate
value used just at that moment.
So, message should not
really be a global variable.
Now, will the program not work
because it's a global variable?
No, it'll work just fine, but let's
say I forgot to type this line here.
Okay, so if I click the No button.
What it's going to do is, well first
it's going to take healthLevel and
subtract one from it.
Now as a side note you might
be wondering what the value of
healthLevel is.
And well,
we'll talk about that in the next video.
But for now let's just assume it's zero.
So we take zero, we subtract one.
Their healthLevel is at negative one.
And well,
we don't have this line anymore, so
we just print out whatever message is.
Well, what is message?
When a global variable is created and
it isn't given an initial value,
it's given a default initial value.
For strings, the default initial
value is the empty string,
which is basically is a string
that has no text in it.
This would mean that the user doesn't
see anything when the no message
clicked.
That's not great, but
not entirely unexpected behavior.
When things get really kind of funky,
is let's say that you hit
the Yes button first.
This will make it, you answered yes,
current healthLevel is one, and
show it on the screen here.
Let's say then after that,
you hit the No button.
It'll subtract one for the health level
making the health level zero again.
But it won't set message to
another value because let's say we
deleted this line.
So message will have
the old value from up here.
You answered yes,
current health level is one.
And it will display that again.
Again, this all happens because
healthLevel now exists between
multiple methods.
So whatever value was here before,
if we don't change it here,
we'll still be there.
And no sort of compile
error will be thrown.
Now if message was a local variable,
when you forget to set it to anything
here, it will complain and
actually not let you run your app.
But because you've made it a global
variable, it won't complain.
It will just print out what it had
before from the previous method.
Which is wrong.
So to summarize,
message should not be a global variable.
Why?
Well it's not really
used in between methods.
Or it'll have some value
from another time that
the variable was used in another method.
Because a global variable will
have a default value set, or
it will have an old value from when it
was used in one of these other methods.
Now it's only if we make an error,
and we forget to set it to the correct
thing, but we shouldn't make our
job any harder for ourselves.
Okay, that's only one of
the variables in this example, so
let's look at the other one,
healthLevel.