So far we've learned how
to create simple shapes.
But of course,
you want to build VR experiences
with more than just primitives.
You want interesting, elaborate, 3D
models with color and animation, right?
Unity makes it easy to use meshes
of any shape you can imagine.
Check out this rad model.
Unity can totally handle this guy.
But Unity does not provide you with
tools to create those kinds of models.
You have to create them in another
program like Blender or Maya, or
you can download them from
the Internet or the Unity Asset Store.
Unity cleanly separates itself for
digital content creation tools like
Maya, 3D Studio, Modo or Blender.
That means you have to learn one of
those programs if you want to make
complicated models for
use in your VR worlds.
It turns out this was a really
smart decision by the Unity team
that made it much easier to learn.
Unity doesn't handle 3D modeling,
texturing, character rigging, etc,
etc, instead it's a master
of assembling 3D scenes.
Let's look at how simple it is to
import a complex model into Unity.