Let's go back to the JustJava app for
just a moment.
Let's look at the MainActivity
class displayMessage method.
Things are starting to make
a little more sense in here.
We already recognize that we're creating
a variable called orderSummaryTextView.
The data type of this
variable was TextView.
We didn't understand this part yet
though.
On the next line, we call a method
on this text view object.
We use the same variable
name as declared up here.
So we call orderSummaryTextView.setText.
Then we pass a string as
an input to the method.
This string message originally
came as an input parameter
to the display message method.
Now let's dig in to this part of
the code, which we don't understand yet.
It looks like findViewById
is a method call, though.
Because its preceding these parenthesis
with what looks like an input argument.
But, what's weird is that this method
isn't defined anywhere in this class.
If I double-click on this name and
then hit command F, or
control-F if you're on Windows, then
we can try to do a search in this file.
I only see two occurrences
of findViewById, and
they're used in similar ways.
But I don't see any method
that's called findViewById.
Speaking of which,
earlier in the main activity class,
we see a call to setContentView,
but if you search for
this in the file, it's also not
defined in the main activity.
So, where are these methods defined?
Well, MainActivity is
actually a pretty short file.
It's only about 90 lines long,
but there's actually more to
this class than meets the eye.
The code says,
extends AppCompatActivity.
This means that the main
activity is an extension
of the functionality in
the AppCompatActivity class.
On your computer if you see action
bar activity here, that's okay,
that's just an older version of this.
The latest version that you should
be using is AppCompatActivity.
And AppCompatActivity gives us
backward compatibility support
on older Android devices.
The AppCompatActivity is part
of the Android support library.
It allows us to use the latest
UI features on Android,
while still working on
older Android devices.
By extending
the AppCompatActivity class,
we're getting all the functionality,
all the state and
the methods from here within
the MainActivity for free.
We don't have to copy and
paste any code from here.
We can just simply extend that class.
If you're interested,
you can find out more information on
AppCompatActivity by googling for it.
Here's the reference doc for
the AppCompatActivity class.
Since I have the Chrome
extension installed,
I can view the source as well.
And this is the code for where
the AppCompatActivity class is defined.
You can see that there's a lot
of functionality here, but
the key message is that you don't have
to understand how it's implemented.
All you need to know is that when
you extend AppCompatActivity,
you get all of this functionality for
free.
At a high level you can
visualize it like this.
This is a class definition for
MainActivity.
And say you have some
methods defined here.
When you extend AppCompatActivity
then we can access the state and
then the methods from AppCompatActivity.
Now, they're not physically added
to the main activity class, but
you can imagine that they're there,
because you can still reference
the state and the methods as well.
And that's how our code can refer
to things like setContentView or
findViewById.
Because we inherited those methods, we
didn't define them in the MainActivity.
The MainActivity is shown as
a screen on the device, but
we didn't write the code for that in the
MainActivity, we inherited that as well.
We don't have the state and the methods
from AppCompatActivity directly
in the class, but now we know that
they're there and we can refer to them.
Speaking of inheriting things,
there's good and bad parts about that.
Sometimes we'll want to
inherit behavior but
other times we might want
to modify it slightly.
If you want to change some of
the behavior from this inherited class,
you can override certain methods.
You can add this @override text on top
of a method so that the computer knows
that you don't want the version of
the method from the AppCompatActivity.
But instead, you want this
version that you've defined here.
This is a tricky topic, and
it requires a lot of practice.
But we have seen one example
of overriding a method
from the AppCompatActivity class.
And that method is the on create method.
By overriding the on create method in
the MainActivity, we're specifying our
own implementation for what should
happen when that method is called.
Don't worry if you don't
understand this right away.
I'm just giving you a brief overview
of a bunch of object-oriented
programming concepts.
It's absolutely expected that you
would still have lingering questions.
And still need to read up more
these topics in order to fully
understands them.
Another way to visualize the
relationship between the MainActivity
and the AppCompatActivity classes is
to draw a Class Hierarchy Diagram.
This is different from
a View Hierarchy Diagram, because
the View Hierarchy Diagram shows a tree
of views that are shown on a screen.
The Class Hierarchy Diagram
shows the relationship
between different Java classes.
We have AppCompatActivity as superclass.
Since MainActivity extends
from AppCompatActivity,
then this is known as the subclass.
So whenever you see this class
definition whatever you extend is known
as the superclass.
This would be the subclass.
So if you created another activity
called detail activity and
you extended AppCompatActivity,
this would be the subclass, and
this would be the superclass.
Here's another example of
Java class inheritance.
If you think about it,
the text view, image view, and
button views all have some
common aspects to them.
All of these views have a width and
a height on the screen.
We haven't learned this yet, but
they also have a visibility state.
So they can all be made invisible or
visible.
There are a couple of other properties
as well, that are common among them.
Instead of writing out code for these
properties within the text view class,
and then copying it over to image view,
and then button class.
We can do something a little smarter.
We can create a view class.
We can extract the common properties
among all of these views and then put
them inside this view class that way
the code only has to be written once.
But then how do we make the connection
between the text view class and
the view class?
If you're thinking inheritance,
you're correct.
In the TextView java file we're
going to define the text view class.
That way we'll inherit all this data and
the methods from the view class.
Then we won't have to have as
much code in the TextView class
because part of the functionality is
already written in the view class.
The same would apply for
the ImageView and
Button classes,
we don't have to write as much code.
In these files, we only have to
write about what's different
about the ImageView
compared to the View class.
I think of this as specifying a delta,
so the ImageView class only has to
specify what's different about the
ImageView compared to the View class.
If we don't want to inherit certain
behavior from the View class,
we can just specify the updated
behavior within the ImageView class, or
any of these classes.
To remind you of the terminology,
in this case,
TextView would be the subclass,
and View would be the superclass.
If we go back to the documentation for
the TextView class,
we actually understand this part now.
It says TextView extends view.
Now we know that it means that
we're inheriting the state and
the methods from the ViewClass.
And down here is a class
hierarchy diagram.
It shows that the TextView class
is inheriting from the ViewClass.
And in turn, the View class
inherits from the Object class.
If you explore around,
you can find other classes,
like the EditText class, which actually
extends from the TextView class.
So it takes the behavior
form the TextView class and
then adds a little more
specific functionality to it.
So EditText extends from TextView.
And TextView extends from View,
and View extends from Object.
And this is the class hierarchy diagram.
There's a lot going on, and
you can look at it for hours.
But let me just show you one thing
on the TextView documentation page.
I want to show you the method for
SetVisibility.
Here's the Java method for
SetVisibility within the TextView class.
This changes whether
the view is visible or not.
If I click on this method,
it actually brings me to the View class.
And then it describes
what this method does.
So you can see that a TextView
object has a set visibility method.
But it was actually inherited
from the View class.
So we got this functionality for
free, from the View class.
Okay, we just covered
a ton of new concepts.
Normally this would be spread out over
a semester of a computer science course.
We're going to do a little
bit of practice now and
hopefully it will start to
connect the dots for you.
But know that it will
take a lot more time and
practice until you fully
grasp these concepts.
Okay, first exercise, I want you
to create another new Android app,
because we don't want to
mess up the just Java app.
Once you create the project,
then run the app.
Once you create your app,
you're going to see a MainActivity file.
That MainActivity file will
extend from AppCompatActivity.
In your version of Android Studio,
if the MainActivity extends from
ActionBarActivity instead,
that's okay too.
That's just an older version
of AppCompatActivity.
By removing this method override,
we're going to fall back to
the way that onCreate method appeared
in the AppCompatActivity class.
The presence of this method says we want
different behavior in the MainActivity
for the onCreate.
So removing it brings us back
to the original behavior in
the AppCompatActivity class.
When you run the app,
what do you notice is different
compared to when you first ran the app?
Write your answer in this text box.