To answer this,
you can ask yourself what would
happen if everyone acted like this.
If everyone started sending
double copies of their traffic,
congestion would just get worse and
nobody's traffic would get through.
But on the other hand,
if we just dropped the connection at
the first sign of imperial trouble,
somebody would probably want to
have us frozen in carbonite.
And let's not talk about the goats.
But on the other hand.
If every end point slows down
when there is congestion,
the congestion will be relieved.
And even though end points can't send
as fast as they might want to, but
these traffic will get
through eventually.