Let's open exercise four,
Wiring up RecyclerView.
Now we've created all
the individual pieces.
All that remains is to
connect them all together.
Everything we need to do is
in our main activity file.
After creating a static variable
indicating the number of views we
want our view to hold,
we need number variables for
our GreenAdapter and RecyclerView.
In our on create method,
we need to get a reference to our
RecyclerView using findViewById.
We will use this reference
to assign a layout manager,
in our case a LinearLayoutManager.
And after instantiating
the GreenAdapter,
assign it to the RecyclerView as well.
Assign setHasFixedSize to true
allows RecyclerView to do some
optimizations on our UI,
namely, allowing it to
avoid invalidating the whole layout
when adapter contents change.
We then create a new GreenAdapter and
store it in our mAdapter
member variable.
Finally, we connect the GreenAdapter
we just created to the RecyclerView
with a setAdapter method.