So how'd you get along with this one,
Jake?
>> Everything cached and accounted for.
Here's how I did it.
Event.waitUntil takes a promise and
cache.open returns one.
So I'm going to start with that.
Then once I've got the cache,
I'm going to call cache.addAll
to cache all the URLs.
I could just reference the array here,
but
I'm going to move
the items across instead.
AddAll also returns a promise,
so I return it.
So wait until it receives a promise for
both actions combined.
Now if I refresh the page,
that new service worker will run and
I can go to the resources panel in
DevTools and there in cache storage,
is the new cache recreated and
the resources we added to it.
Success, but it's no good having cached
items if we're not going to use them.
So let's use them in responses.
To do that, wait, Mike,
why are you still here?
>> Come on,
you've already covered responses and
getting responses out of caches.
I think the student can take this on.
>> Well fine, makes my life easier.