We start by adding a string for
our SharedPreference.
In the Sunshine sync adapter, we add
a function to set the location's status.
Since setLocationStatus will be used
on a background thread, I use commit.
One would use apply if it
were on a foreground thread.
In onPerformSync, if the server
returns an empty string, or
I get an IOException.
I set the status of server down.
I set the status of server invalid if
there is an exception parsing the Json.
We also set LOCATION_STATUS_OK
at the end of a successful sync.
Let's put some breakpoints
in to check to see if these
are actually getting set correctly.
For a URL that I know is going to
produce an error not expected by our
app, I'm going to use this one.
Let's debug it and see what happens.
As before,
I've uninstalled the app first.
And as you can see, we nicely get
a location status of, server invalid.
Which of course leads us to no
weather information available.
Which is what we do in the case
of not knowing why something has
happened as of yet.
We'll fix this later.
Let's try a URL that
we expect to be empty.
Once again,
I'll uninstall the app first.
Now let's debug it and see what happens.
As you can see, we now get SERVER_DOWN
rather than INVALID, as expected.
This will help us a lot when we move
to the next part of our implementation.
Let's set everything back to normal to
make sure we didn't break anything, and
there we are.
Everything's working
just as we would expect.