Okay, so when I press this button I see
that the Firebase database updated to
have the data.
Now this is actually a pretty complex
thing that just happened here.
Notice how I didn't need to make
a new AsyncTask or start a background
thread or anything fancy like that,
Firebase does it all for us.
And I'll actually go ahead and
put my app on another phone.
And I can actually make
a new list with this.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Press the Create button.
And I see it's also all
contacting Firebase.
Now right now,
we're just writing data to Firebase.
We're not reading data yet.
So even after the change happens
here I'm not seeing it in my app.
We'll fix that a bit.
But first, let's learn a little
bit more about data and Firebase