Let's look at another method to do mixing and merging of two images.
Let's put these two images on top of each other as we've done before.
And rather that in the previous times what we've done is basically take
some sort of a weighted pixel value of the top one, or the left one,
and the right one, and give you a new answer.
Here is another way of looking in the same problem.
What I've done now is basically found a boundary between these two
images here and taken all the pixels from this side from this image and
this side from this image.
So here this boundary now kind of says is,
I'm going to take all of the pixels from this image,
from the left image here and all the pixels from the right image here.
And this will allow me to now kind of create a new image that basically has
the actual pixels themselves rather than a mixture of two pixels.
Here you can see the boundary a little bit, of course.
But we know by doing various types of simple feathering and
stuff like that, we should be able to get rid of this artifact.
And this would be a perfectly clean image.
Let's look at a real example that would allow us to do this.
Here basically I'm showing some of the work by Davis et al, here.
And the idea is now let's imagine I took a camera and
I rotated the camera, panned the camera over sight.
And now I basically have images from all the way from the right to the left.
And now I have the sequence of images,
I want to merge them together to generate a panorama.
This basically shows you the sequence of images.
As the images panned across a construction site,
you see a construction crane followed by a, you know, a dump truck,
a person, and, all the way out we end up in porta-potties like this.
Here is the video again.
Panning across, a person is moving, lots of motion, and the camera is moving.
Here are the images six of the eight think images.
This sequence has about I think 12, so here are construction crane, dump truck,
construction worker moving as the camera is moving to all the way
towards the other end of the scene, we're interested in taking all of them and
merging them together to generate a new image.
Here basically is the process we can actually do to find a cut
rather than blend.
Here I basically take two images, and I align them and
after I align them I basically look for
a difference on these types of things, I'll talk about that in a bit.
And this is going to start saying where all of the things are similar and
where there is some sort of merging going on here because, the person moved,
there will be a little bit ghostly artifacts here.
But within there, there is a region which might actually
be the best possible one to cut between them, it's also shown here.
If I found this cut between these two images, now I can blend this, and
the person will actually be not ghostly,
because I've just taken this part from there.
So in essence what would happen is for this right image and
the left image we basically found all the pixels from here and
all the pixels from the right image for this one.
And this is where the seam is.
To say that, which parts of the image I should be picking up information from.
So, again, in that image if I had basically done blending as we’ve looked at
in the past where I take overlapping images and find the best pixel and
kind of had a weighted, you know, pixlar arithmetic between them to kind of
come up with it, I would find there would be,
you know, ghostly artifacts with the person in the dump track.
So moving objects like with a moving camera will cause some sort of ghosting.
So we want to do is find an optimal seam as opposed to blend between two images.
Finding an optimal seam will allow me to now come up with an image like
this where everything is crisp and clear, no merging of information.
So this image shows you the boundaries that we can compute.
And these boundaries basically allow you say that I'm going to
take all the pixels from here, pixels from this one and
allows me to now find basically the exact pixels that we want.
So in essence, by doing this we're finding the exact pixels that
were captured by the camera.
And figuring out the best pixels from each and
every one of the different images we caught, we captured.
And therefore we get a crisper image.
No blending or ghosting