Now I want to switch gears and talk about machine translation between two natural languages.
Here we have Spanish translated into English, and we talked about this a little bit at the beginning of the class
where we showed the Chinese menu and talked about how we could learn from data as represented in the menu
to learn a model of transfer from one language to another.
Now we have more tools at our disposal, and we can think about the transfer at multiple levels.
So it could be at the word by word transfer, and we could say, "What's the probability that 'tomorrow' would be chosen
"as a translation of mañana?" and we could build a table of those types of word by word probabilities.
Or we could move up a level to the phrase level and talk about phrases like "lojare" as a phrase,
and consider multiple phrases at a time, "I will do it tomorrow," or we could go up to the level of syntax.
So we have words here, phrases here, trees here, and we could think about a syntactic tree,
"I" being a noun phrase, which is part of a sentence, and then the verb phrase being "will" and so on.
Just as we talked about the probability of word for word or phrase for phrase, we can talk about the probability
of a tree in English corresponding to a similar tree in Spanish.
And I won't spell it all out there. And we also have the option to go up even higher into the level of meaning or semantics,
and try to understand what it is what this sentence means, and have some representation of,
say this is "doing action" and "time is equal to mañana" and so on, and transfer that into a corresponding meaning in English.
And from there, generate out the words.
And so this whole structure, as we go up, we have multiple levels at which we can deal with the translation.
And this has been called a pyramid. It's known as Valcroix's Pyramid after a linguist called Bernard Valcroix.
And we can do the translation at any level or at multiple levels.
And I'm going to show you a little bit more closely about how to do it, concentrating at the phrase level.
But I should say that modern translation systems do use multiple levels, including the syntactic level.