So, in general, if the case of two calibrated cameras.
We had talked about parallel optical axes, all right.
So that they were lined up and the parallel, and
the planes were, were coplanar, but of course, they can be what's called verged.
They could be pointed in some particular way.
In fact, they don't even have to necessarily be verged on the same point.
Usually they are because we're used to human systems.
But what we're going to do is we're going to talk about epipolar geometry,
the epipolar constraint in both of these cases.
So let's start it this way.
So if I have an image on the left and some point p projecting in that image,
the question is where can p prime the image of that same point on the right be?
Well, basically the actual scene point could be
anywhere along the ray that contains p prime.
Each of these red dots correspond to possible locations along that
ray of the actual scene point that's projecting to p prime.
Now remember, in perspective projection,
one of the things we said was that lines project into lines.
So the line containing the center of projection and
the ray that goes through that point, that's a real line in space, okay?
That line mu, in, must project into a line in the right image.
So that's the constraint we are going to talk more about.