So as usual, you're going to be using
a Google API Client and in your OnCreate
function you'll build it, and in your
OnStart function, you'll connect it.
When you're connecting to the signin
APIs, a number of things can happen.
First of all, it will generate an error
if you haven't chosen an account, so
if your device has
multiple accounts on it,
you'll see a dialogue pops up
asking me to choose which account.
Once that dialogue has been accepted,
the sign in connection will continue.
They can then throw another
error to give you permission.
So the first time you're running this
you'll see that consent dialogue and
you'll stay in this error state
until consent has been given.
If you refuse to consent,
then the connection will fail, and
you'll go directly to
OnConnectionFailed.
If you give the consent,
then the sign in will continue,
and if all else works, you'll end
up in your OnConnected function.
So you'll need to implement
your OnConnected, and
your OnConnectionFailed, and
you'll need to catch these errors.
It can get complicated really quickly.
But you'll see how to do that
over the next few steps, and
we'll go through this step by step.