So to quickly summarize.
I introduced a concept of how we can actually use cuts where we
find the seams to allow us to blend images or merge images that does
not require us to do blending or fading between two pixels.
Basically, the concept of seam is very valuable as it can be used to kind of
generate original images or new images that actually use all of
the original pixels from the source and target images.
And we looked at various advantages of each one of the methods.
Both of them are powerful methods and
should be used, again, depending on what you want to accomplish.
The effects of ghosting and blurring are much more popular with blending.
Less so with any kind of seam calculations,
because you're actually giving you the same exact pixels from both views.
As we get into more advanced topics, I will get in the habit of also show,
sharing with you a variety of papers.
Here's a list of papers that I talked about a little bit.
Again, they will be made available off the course website for
you to look at too.
And what I'm going to do next is, I'm going to get into the whole topic of
detecting and finding features in images,
because those are the ones that'll actually allow us to do more advanced things.
And here are just some cri, you know, sources that I've been picking up
information from for a variety of the topics I've discussed so far.