So here you can see my
button_custom.xml file.
Now you'll notice I put
it in res drawable and
I just called it button_custom.xml file.
On it I have my selector,
and my selector uses
the Standroid Android naming scheme.
And within my selector,
I then have four items.
These items are for signin_pressed
where state_pressed is true,
signin_focus drawable when stay_focused
is true, signin_disabled drawable
when enabled is false, and then just
the normal drawable for everything else.
It's good practice to put your normal
drawable at the bottom of the list.
So remember state_pressed is true, will
give you your signin_pressed graphic,
state_focused is true,
will give you your signin_focus.
The slightly different one
is when it's disabled and
you want that ghosted image
that we saw earlier on.
And that's where
state_enabled equals false,
there's no state_disabled equals true.
Just watch out for that one.
And then of course like I said,
your normal one is last.
Now let's take a look at how that
changes my button definition
within my main activity.
So here's my activity main layout,
and you can see the button here.
First of all notice that I've just
change my button from being the sign in
button to just a standard button.
So then the standard button,
if you look at the background setting,
I've set it to drawable/button_custom,
so
that's telling the system
to use button_custom.xml.
If you have named your
xml file something else,
just make sure that you
use the drawable here.
I've also made a couple
of other changes.
Buttons in Android always default so
that their text is all in capitals.
But we wanted to have a sign
in with capital S, capital I.
So I change it so
that text all caps is false and
then my Android text sign
in will work properly.
I get capital S, capital I.
You could also take that text and
load it into a string resource, but
I've just hardcoded it here,
just for brevity.
You can also take that string and
load it into a string resource, but
I've just left it in here, for brevity.
Finally, because we've changed
our sign in button to a button so
that we can customize it, we have to
refactor our a code a little bit.
So let's go and take a look at
the changes on the main activity.
It's pretty straight forward.
Earlier I had a sign in button
called M sign in button.
I'm just changing that to be a button.
Then when I'm creating the click
handler, I just cast the fine view by ID
sign in button to a button
instead of a sign in button, and
then nothing else changes.
Let's take a look at what the app would
look like now with a nice Google sign-in
button, instead of the red branded
button that you saw earlier.
And here, you can see the same app.
I've just laid out
the buttons differently,
I laid them out vertically
instead of horizontally.
But, now you can see I have this
Sign In button instead of the red
Google Plus Sign In button.
And when I touch that,
I Sign In as before.
As you can see I'm signed into my
app and I still have to sign out and
revoke access button similar
to what we had earlier on.
So that's just what the new customized
Sign In button looks like and
that's more in line with
the web sign in etc.
etc.
And it adheres
to the sign in guidelines that
we saw in the earlier videos.