So a variety of proposals have been made.
Most famous is by, Edwin Land, actually, and it's called now the Retinex Theory.
He had a variety of, ways of going about this but
overall the whole process is called the Retinex Theory.
This was Edwin Land, a remarkable inventor.
He was the inventor of the Polaroid Land camera.
So he originally was doing, polarized filters, and
Polaroid the company got started and he was part of that.
And then when, they invented, he invented the instant film it wasn't enough to
call it the Polaroid Camera, it was actually called the Polaroid Land Camera.
He was incredibly industrious, and har, driven, and driving kind of guy.
He used to give really interesting,
remarkable demonstrations of humans perceiving different lightness, using.
In fact, he had this really cool way, he could show an image of just one color.
Kind of, this pink, with these different squares.
And then a, a greyscale image, of, also, different squares, and overlay them.
And humans would see color.
And it was, it was remarkable.
I had the opportunity to see him,
when I was still a graduate student in Cambridge.
And he's kind of giving this talk, and
then also shows this thing, and these colors appear.
And the whole audience broke out in applause, it was kind of cool.
Anyway, Land, invented, or, or, or put forward a, a variety of what's re, called
the retinex theory, and I'll give you just the general idea of how that works.
So the goal, is to remove the slowly vary, it's the slow variations in
the image, and there are a variety of ways of doing it.
One approach, that I'll show you in just a minute.
Is to, if L is equal to the product of R times E,
then if I take the log of both sides.
So, obviously, the log of multiplication is just the sum of the logs, right?
And then what you're going to do is we're going to, and
I'll show you this in a minute, we're going to hi-pass filter this,
only keep the high frequency.
And then we're going to threshold to remove.
Any of those low frequencies.
And then we're going to invert it to get back the, actual reflectance.
So let me show you what that looks like