Let's walk through each of these
methods and then fill in the table.
This is the gist of code that we
provided to you in the instructor notes.
Let's start with Method 1.
This method is meant to
create a reminder message for
a particular calendar event.
The message will be composed
of the event's name, and
event location as well as how
many minutes away the event is.
So the method name is
createCalendarEventReminder in
Camel Case, and then the list of
inputs is in between the opening and
closing parentheses here.
There are three input parameters,
the first is String eventName,
then String location, and
then int minutesAway.
The output of this method or
the return value is the reminder
message, which is text.
So that's why the return
data type is a string.
And this is what it looks
like filled in the table.
Technically, this should all be
one word without any spaces, but
it just doesn't fit in this box.
And this is the second method.
The goal of this method is to deduct a
certain number of points that were used
from the overall number of points,
which is 100.
So, it returns the remaining
number of points.
The method name is
called deductPoints and
there's one input parameter
in between this opening and
closing parentheses It's called
pointsUsed, and the data type is int.
The return value is numberOfPoints
remaining, and that's a number, so
that's why the return
data type is an int.
In the table,
this is what it would look like.
And this is the third method,
the goal of this method is to create
a text string that says the sum
of all the individual trip lengths
the method name is findTotalTripLength.
Then we have to scroll to the right
to see all the parameters.
We have three input parameters
here in between the opening and
closing parentheses, and
they're separated by commas.
The first is Int distanceOfFirstTrip,
the second is Int distanceOfSecondTrip,
and Int distanceOfThirdTrip.
So, within this method,
we can refer to each of these variables.
Since they're integers, we can add them
all up to the total length of the trip,
which starts at two miles.
And then we can concatenate
that to this string message.
Since this message is text, the return
value of the method is string.
And this is what it
looks like in the table.