One of the biggest
misconceptions about monitoring
is that it's only for alerting.
That monitoring is there to page
Ops when the service is broken.
But alerting is really only one of many
different ways that monitoring can
help you and your organization.
Monitoring doesn't just tell you
when your service is misbehaving,
it also tells you things
that are business relevant,
such as how your service's
traffic is growing.
That's important not only for capacity
planning, hey, we need more servers, but
also for business purposes.
Like, you want to buy our website?
We get 10,000 page views per second.
Your service exists for some purpose,
like making money or teaching people or
letting the world read your brilliant
postmodern hypertext novel.
Your monitoring can tell you something
about how well your service is meeting
that purpose.
For instance,
when you're AB testing new features.
Monitoring can also be
a big help to developers.
Let's say you want to make optimizations
to the code to make your service faster.
How are you going to know
whether you've succeeded?
The service monitoring provides
you a source of truth on that.
It's also good for
finding certain kinds of bugs.
If you see your service's memory
usage creeping up over time,
that's a pretty good sign that it has
a specific kind of bug, a memory leak.
And if something changes during
a release, like say a big increase
in CPU usage, that can be
a good sign of a bug as well.
Because good monitoring can be generally
useful throughout the organization,
it should be widely accessible.
When business managers, sales people, or
developers want to know the growth
trends of the service, they should be
able to go to the same stats that
the services operations people use.