I wana focus on a key point that Travis
mentioned about this new outflow.
He said that the credential
checking is done on the website.
Instead of passing usernames and
passwords over the air, the users
are asked to give their consent for an
app to access resources on their behalf.
Behind the scenes,
this interaction can get really complex.
And the standards are always changing.
So I just want to give you a high level
view of what is happening, and why.
>> For many apps you may have
seen are screen like this one.
This is the app Trivia Crack, asking me
for permission to use the Facebook API,
on my user's behalf.
Notice the glaring similarities between
this screen, and the screen for
the movie manager.
In either case, whether I'm selecting OK
here, or Allow here, what's happening
behind the scenes is that both of these
apps are going to be given some type of
request token, that'll allow
them to access user resources.
For instance, if I select OK here,
then I've given consent for
Trivia Crack to use Facebook to
access things like my friends list,
so it can display it in the app.
Some of you maybe asking
the same question that I did,
which is to even get
to this consent form,
doesn't it require me to pass my
credentials over the air at some point?
Yes it does.
However, the main difference is that
your credentials are shared with a third
party.
Instead of your apps.
For example, here the credentials
are shared with Facebook and
a Browser instead of Trivia Crack and
for us the credentials are shared with
the Browser and
TheMovieDB instead of the movie manager.
If you were instead enter your
credentials directly into the app.
Or even worse, store them on the app.
This could be a big security problem.
Instead, this approach takes the
liability away from our apps and puts
them on the third party and the browser,
which are pretty trusted systems.
For the movie manager, we'll use
a UI WebView to handle this process.
Alternatively, one could use Safari
to handle this entire interaction,
where the app opens Safari.
Ask the user for consent and
then we go back to the app, but
we won't take this
approach in this course.