As the last thing, we'll learn a very
useful method to recycle our data
called k-fold cross validation.
As we have learned, testing is done by
separating our data into a training and
a testing set.
But this is not always ideal as we seem
to be throwing away some data that
could be useful for
training our algorithm.
Is there anything we can do
to not throw away this data?
But at the same time not cheat?
Well here's the solution, and
this is when K Fold Cross Validation
comes in to play.
What we do with K Fold Cross Validation
is to break our data in to K buckets.
In this case, K is four.
Then we just train our model K times.
Each time using a different
bucket as our testing set and
the remaining points
as our training set.
Then we average the results
to get a final model.
The command to do this in
sklearn is very simple.
All we have to do is
create a KFold object
where the parameters are the size of the
data and the size of the testing set.
It is always recommended to randomize
our data to remove any hint of a bias.
Here we are still splitting
our data into buckets,
except these are chosen
randomly instead of in order.
Randomizing is also easily
done in sklearn by setting
the shuffle parameter to true when
we initialize our KFold object.