Another useful feature of an address
book, would be to delete a contact.
So let's start working on
specing out that feature.
Just like before, all,
to find a new spec with the it method,
I'll accentuate my addressBook and
thisContact variables just like before
and then I'll add the contact to my
address book so that I can delete it.
Now, we haven't written
a deleteContact method yet.
So we know we're going to get a failure.
But what should our expectation or
our test for this spec be?
My test for this spec is if I get
the first contact from my address book,
I expect that object not to be defined.
If I deleted it, it shouldn't exist.
After refreshing my spec runner,
I now see an error again.
I have two specs,
with one of them failing.
One of them passed, and one's failing.
It says undefined is not a function.
And, it's on line 16 of AddressBookSpec.
This is in reference to
my deleteContact method.
So I need to go write that function.
I can use the splice method of
an array to remove an element.
I then rerun my test and see that
my implementation was successful.
My address book can add a contact,
and it can delete a contact.