To test your application,
we provide a messaging simulator
that looks very similar to
the Car Experience from Android Auto.
It's actually downloaded as part of the
SDK Manager, so let's get that going so
we can download it.
So we go to Tools.
Android SDK Manager.
And if you scroll right to the bottom,
you'll see it here as
Android Auto API Simulators.
So check that.
Hit Install.
Agree to the License.
And it's downloading it now.
Close the SDK Manager.
Once you've downloaded the APK,
we now need to use the terminal
to install it to the device.
The Messaging Simulator is located in
the SDK's extras/google/simulators/
directory.
You need to ADB install the Messaging
Simulator to your Emulator.
So let's now go back to the Emulator and
run it.
You'll notice that the application
needs to run in Landscape Mode.
So, let's rotate the Emulator.
Typically, you can press Control F11 or
Control Fn F11 to make
this happen like so.
Let's just move the window
up a little bit.
Next, it'll ask for
permissions to be able to get
access to your notifications.
Click continue, check on the box here,
and hit OK to agree to it.
To allow it to see your messages.
Now press back to get back to
the messaging simulator again.
The simulator interfaces to
the Android notification system, and
implements the car extender extensions.
So you can see here how the car
will interpret your messages.
This is great for
testing at your desk during development,
when you don't want to be
sitting in a car for testing.
So now that we've got the simulator
working, let's start up our app and
see how it works.
So let's build it and
install it to the Emulator.
OK.
Go to the Emulator.
Can you see here our sample is running?
So press the DO IT button and
generate the notification.
You then slide it down,
you can see the notification is there.
So now let's switch over to
the simulator to see what it's showing.
So, we click on the square icon which
shows all the apps running, and
we click on the messaging simulator.
And so, if you look here you can
see that we've got our message, so
that worked great.
So, let's click on the message
now to hear the audio.
>> New message from Lane P,, received.
Hello there.
How are you?
>> You'll also notice in the logout
output that you've seen acknowledgment
that conversation ID
number 42 has been read.
Let's click the Reply button now.
Note that we can't actually
talk to the simulator here.
That's actually not
supported by the simulator.
But you can't see the string, This is
a reply, was passed to our broadcast
receiver, which handles replies for
conversation ID number 42.
So that's everything.
You now know how to make a fully
Android Auto-enabled messaging app.
Test and install your application,
as well as the simulator, and
verify that you can hear a message and
also reply to it.
Check all the boxes once
you've completed each part.