As I just mentioned,
we're going to briefly explore a new
sample app called Did You Feel It?
This app will look at specific
earthquakes and let you know what
the perceived strength was of the quake
among the people that might of felt it,
and reported their experience
to the USGS website.
Here's what the app should look like.
Let me show you where
this data comes from.
On the USGS website,
there's a page called Did You Feel It?
This data is crowd sourced
from earthquake events.
If you feel the earth literally shaking
beneath you, you can go to the USGS
website, find your event and
enter whether or not you felt the quake.
So, let's find recent
earthquake to look up.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
If I go to
Significant Earthquake Archive.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We can look around for earthquakes
that have happened recently and have
a significant magnitude, and I really
want to find one that happened near me.
Here's one that happened in
Borrego Springs, California.
So, let's try this one.
So here, we can see that the earthquake
is a magnitude 5.2 that happened
20 kilometers north northwest
of Borrego Springs, California.
Cool.
Right below the event title,
there's an indicator for DYFI.
DYFI stands for Did You Feel It and
if I click this item,
it takes me to a map that displays
a colorful map of postal code areas.
This DYFI value is a precede intensity
value that is aggregated across all of
the people who visit the USGS website
and recorded what they felt by clicking
the Did You Feel I,
tell us link near the top of each page.
If you click the Tell Us link,
I can see what form looks like.
I can enter my location,
click here the yes or
no to indicate whether I felt
the earthquake and then send it away.
There's a bunch of
other information I can
fill in on this form about what was
my situation during the earthquake?
Did it wake me up?
And so on.
For those of you who want to know how
the value for DYFI is calculated,
you can follow the link below the video.
For this next exercise, please download
the code for the Did You Feel It app
from the GitHub project link in
the lesson notes below the quiz.
Once you've imported it into Android
Studio, run the app on your device.
Here's a secret.
When you run this app on your device,
the app is going to crash and
this error dialog will appear.
You need to figure out what exception is
causing the app to crash on launch and
then write your answer in this text box.
There's no need to fix the bug
until later in the lesson.
Just read the logs for now in Android
Studio and see what you can find.