For this exercise let's launch
the memory churn activity.
Oh hello there pirate.
Now press the button,
do interesting things with arrays.
I'm sure you noticed that the dancing
pirate hangs or pauses, but
then eventually resume dancing.
As you know, this is Jank and
it's bad for many reasons.
So let's go ahead and fix it.
Now this should sound familiar, so
go ahead and profile this activity
using trace view and when you're done,
you should see a tool
output similar to this one.
Notice the frequent GC events that are
happening within a short period of time.
Now given what you know
about garbage collection,
what do you see in this timeline view
that might be hurting app performance?
Write your observations in this box.