As part of this class,
I want you to start to get a glimpse
of the whole world of Android.
There's so much more that lies beyond
this course, beyond Android Studio,
beyond the documentation
pages that we've read.
One of the reasons that I love being a
part of the Android developer community,
is because there's so
many cool open-source apps
out there that I can browse.
An open-source app means that the source
code that was used to create that app is
made available for other people to see.
There are certain restrictions
on how you can actually use it,
if you can adapt it or modify it, so
you have to check the license of
the individual app for more details.
If you see a really cool feature in an
app, you can Google Search for it, and
try to find code for that.
If it's an open-source app, you might
be able to find the exact code, or
you might be able to find a library
that has that specific
functionality that you can look at.
Let's try to Google Search for
some open-source Android apps.
Then we can see how something like
Android resources are used in action.
I'm going to Google Search for
open-source Android apps.
This Wikipedia link looks good.
And there's a whole list of apps here.
So I want to bring your attention to one
app in particular, the Google IO app.
Google IO is an annual conference
organized by guess who, and
it's for all the developers
who use Google technologies.
So Android developers for example,
will attend this conference, and
learn about the latest changes in
Android, how to make their app better,
and meet other developers.
For the conference,
Google creates an Android app.
Let's click on the link to open it.
So for this conference, Google creates
an Android app, and then the Android app
is made open-source so
other developers can look at the code.
This is what the app looks like.
It listed all the events for
the conference.
If you have your own conference coming
up, and you want to build an app for
it, this would be a good
example to look at.
So anyways,
lets go back to the GitHub code.
This is where all the code for
the Google IO app is.
I'm going to look for how they use
Resources, within a certain activity.
I'm going to hit
the keyboard shortcut T, and
that will immediately begin
a search across all of their files.
It's a pretty nifty shortcut.
So I'm going to type Activity, and
this will show me all files
that have Activity in the name.
Let's look at the WelcomeActivity.
And this is the code for
the WelcomeActivity.
It's a pretty short Java file.
To find how they use resources,
I'm going to hit Cmd+F, or
you can use Ctrl+F,
if you're on Windows.
I'm going to search for R dot.
I believe that Chrome doesn't
have case sensitive search, so
I'll just have to search for
incidences of the capital R, myself.
So in this first case,
we have R.layout.activity_welcome.
It looks like the layout for
the WelcomeActivity is stored in
the activity_welcome XML file.
That's pretty cool that we can tell
all of that, just from this one line.
The next resource is here.
It says R.id.button_accept.
Since the resource type is id, and
we're talking about a button here,
it looks like this is the view ID for
the Accept button in the app.
And the Accept button should
be in this XML layout.
And look,
there's something similar down here.
It says, R.id.button_decline.
This looks like the view ID for
the Decline button,
that's also defined in this XML layout.
So stepping back a bit,
it looks like this welcome screen has
an Accept button, and
a Decline button of some sort.
But you're not exactly sure,
what you're accepting or declining.
Let's scroll down some more.
The last resource ID is
android.R.string.ok.
This part looks familiar, R.string.ok,
this looks like a string resource.
It probably contains the word ok,
that's just a wild guess.
This is new though,
it starts with android dot.
This means that this string resource
is provided by the Android system.
It's built-in to Android.
It makes sense though because it's
a pretty generic string, so instead of
creating our own string that says, ok,
we can just use the one in the system.
So those were some interesting
use cases of resources,
within the WelcomeActivity
of the Google IO app.
Let's navigate back to the root
folder of the app to look more
at their Android resources.
I'm going to click on
the android folder,
because I think this is where
the Android app code is.
And then click on source, main, and
then here is the res directory for
all of their resources.
Inside the Res directory,
we can see a lot of the folders
that we talked about earlier.
There is a folder for
animation files, colors, graphics.
This is the default folder for graphics,
and it's called the drawable folder.
You can also provide alternative
graphics in these other drawable
folders.
These are for
different screen resolutions.
We also have layout folders,
menu folders, mipmap folders for
the launcher icons or the app icons,
and we also have values folders.
This is the default folder for values,
and then you can see all these
other folders that start with values,
but they have a different ending.
This is where you can provide
alternative resources,
like text strings in German, or
Spanish, or French, and so on.
Or you can provide specific resources
for different versions of Android.
In the values-v21 folder,
you would put in resources that are
specific to Lollipop devices and above.
That's because Lollipop is version 21.
Let's look inside the values folder,
to see what they have.
In the colors.xml file, we see a bunch
of colors are being defined here.
In the dimens file, we see a bunch of
dimensions, and a bunch of dp values.
And in the strings file,
we see a bunch of text strings
here that appear in the app.
Now, it's your turn.
Go ahead, and skim through the articles
that we talked about earlier.
These are all linked in
instructor notes below.
Then try to search for an open source
app, that you find interesting.
Look through one of their
Activity files, and
try to identify some uses of resources.
Then post about it in
the discussion forum.
This is a pretty open ended exercise,
to help you explore the open
source that are out there.
And we want you to try to identify the
things that you've learned in this class
within those apps.
We look forward to hearing,
what you find out.
And feel free to give other students
feedback on the forum as well,
to help guide them in their learning.
When you're done, tell us which
app you chose by writing it here.
Have fun.