I want to introduce we're going to
keep doing this Kalman Filter now on
the 1D state.
And I want to introduce
a little bit of nomenclature.
Some a way of writing things down.
So what we have here is, we have this
inner loop that we talked about.
Where we predict, make a measurement
correct and then time advances.
Okay.
So we time advance we predict,
we make a measurement we correct.
The first thing I want to show is,
in our prediction,
which is probability of x t given
the measurements up through t minus 1,
our prediction in Kalman land here
is going to be model written as,
mu minus sigma minus,
sigma squared minus right.
This is and see of timed t.
So mu minus sub t, sigma squared or
sigma minus sub t,
that's the prediction of the mean and
the co-variance before I take
the measurement at time t.
That's why it's referred to as minus.
Then I take my measurement.
All right.
And my corrected version, which is now,
the, the distribution of x given
the new measurement y sub t is referred
to as mu plus sub t sigma squared or
sigma plus sub t.
So I have these two things.
I have mu minus.
Sigma minus the time t that's
the prediction before the measurement.
Mu plus sigma plus at time t,
that's my correction after
I've taken my measurement.