All right, so
your goal is to select the top level
Udacity navigation bar up here.
So let's start out like we always do,
and try and inspect this element.
When I inspect this element,
I get taken to this navbar-header,
and it doesn't seem like I'm
selecting the entire navbar.
If I look one level up, I have a
container, and then if I look one level
even higher, I have a nav element,
which looks like my topmost element.
All right, this must be it.
So this element has a lot
of different class names.
I have navbar, navbar-inverse,
and navbar-static-top.
So let's try one of these to see if
it will work in our query selector.
So just trying the first one,
I'm going to run this, and
sure enough,
I get the DOM node that I want.
Now, it's also worth mentioning that
these other class names would have
worked, as well.
navbar-inverse also returns
the correct DOM node, and
navbar-static-top works, as well.
And if you're wondering if a combination
of the class names would work, well,
in this case it wouldn't, but
this is because I've separated
the class names by a space.
If I would have looked for two class
names or an element that has a class of
navbar and a class of navbar-inverse,
then I would get the correct DOM node.
So any single class
name would have worked,
as well as any pair of class names, or
all three class names would have worked.
This just goes to show you that there's
many different ways to select elements,
so keep that in mind
throughout this course.