So you could identify lines in different ways.
For instance, this could be a short segment,
a longer segment to the right-hand side and a diagonal cutting across.
Now this is a consistent set of line segments, which almost accounts for
all of the edge points.
But there are other possibilities.
For instance, this long segment going right through and
two shorter segments on either side.
There's no single correct answer to this question.
If you entered 2, 3, or 4, we would accept it as correct.
Hopefully, this will give you an idea how finding line segments in
an image is not a trivial task.
This is especially true if you don't have any additional context and
are looking at edge pixels individually.