Now we're actually done,
coded all of the provider cred functions
that this to do app list will use.
So congrats on your completed app.
But I just want to take
a second to talk about two
tiny functions that every
content provider includes.
Just so if you ever need to use them,
you know where they'd be used.
The last cred method that we have
left is the update function.
This would be useful if you decided
to include a feature like editing
pre-existing tasks, or a checkbox
to change the task date to done.
The update function takes in a URI,
content values, a collection, and
selection args, and then it returns
the number of items updated.
These parameters may remind
you of the insert method.
The main difference here is that
the update will alter some existing data
by using what's in the updated
content values, and
it won't create a new row of data or
a new URI location.
And again, our app won't use this.
You don't need to implement provider
methods that you won't actually use.
But if you plan to make your content
provider publicly accessible and
share your data,
you'll want to be really careful
about leaving any method unfinished.
And so as an example, I'm providing
you with the provider code to update
a single task in the code link below.
So this is the last of the Cred Methods.
But what about that sneaky get
tight method we mentioned earlier?
Let's learn a little bit
about that method next