The first thing I'm going to do is
actually make a new package, and
I'm going to make it here on this level,
the main shopping list plus, plus level.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And I'm going to call
this package model.
And it's going to have all the POJO
that I end up having in my app.
So inside the model package,
I'm going to go ahead and
make a new class, and I'll go ahead and
call that class shopping list.
All right, let's start by
making the member variables
that'll be the properties of my object.
There's only two and
they're both strings.
To satisfy the second rule,
we're going to need to
make an empty constructor.
Now I find that using keyboard shortcuts
when making these objects is a complete
life saver.
The keyboard shortcut that I use
is control return on a Mac or
alt insert on a Windows machine.
I've included these in
the instructor notes.
Okay, so this opens up the generate menu
and I'm going to go to constructor and
I'm just going to hit select none,
which generates an constructor.
And while I'm at it,
I'm also going to make a constructor
that has all of the variables
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I'll just select both of these and
hit okay.
Now rule two doesn't prevent you from
creating a constructor like this.
It just requires that
you have this empty one.
Okay, so for
rule three I need some public getters.
I'm going to use the same generate
shortcut to make getters.
And I can just select all of these and
click okay, and
then I have my public getter methods.
Now we only have two variables right
now, but when you have a bunch of
member variables, it's really important
to make sure you make getters for
all of them and
you don't miss any of them.
All right, so that's actually it.
Your POJO is done and ready to be used.
So I'm going to integrate
it with the rest of my app.
We'll start with updating
the right portion.
Now remember the right happens
in the add list dialog fragment.
So I'm going to open this.
Okay so I'm going to scroll down to add
shopping list which is where I actually
do the right, and I'm going to make
a new instance of our shopping list
object, and I'm going to go ahead and
pass it the user entry for the name.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then we need an owner.
Since we don't have user accounts yet,
I'm just going to put a string
that says anonymous owner.
[SOUND] And we'll update that
as soon as we get user accounts.
Okay, and now instead of just
setting this value here,
ListName to a single thing, I'm
going to go ahead and comment this out.
Instead what I'm going to do is do ref,
going to get a child.
So I'm going to call the root
known active list and
that's just an arbitrary key for
this object that I'm adding.
And then I'm going to set value and
I'm going to just pass
in that shopping list.
Okay.
So, we also need to change the code
where we grab the data from Fire base.
And that is in the fragment class
over here, shopping list fragment.
Okay now we actually need
to change the read code.
First things first, so here, instead of
having a listener attached to list name,
I'm going to attach it to active list.
Okay.
Then we can actually keep
using the get value method.
But we have to tell it.
That we're expecting
a shopping list class,
so we pass the object class in here.
And we actually don't
need this cast anymore.
And this is no longer a string.
It becomes a shopping list, and
we're going to go ahead and
call it ShoppingList.
All right let's line that up.
Then here I don't have a list
name to reference anymore but
I do have a shopping list which
has a get list name method.
Cool.
Now I actually need to reference
to another text view that I
could put the owner text in.
So I'm going to go down to
the bottom of this class and
here's where I initialize all these.
Okay and I'm going to go ahead and
make a TextViewOwner.
Okay, and I'm going to grab the view
of the id.text_view_created_by_user,
which is an I.d which is found
in the layout for this fragment.
Okay, now I actually haven't declared
this so I'll go to the top of the class,
declare it.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay.
And now back down here.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
In the listener, I can get this
new text view that I have and
I could do set text.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Get the shopping list.
And then get the owner.
And then here, I've gotten the owner.
OK, so now what I want you to do is
make those edits for yourself, so
that you could see both the shopping
list name and the shopping list owner.
And then, I want you to break it.
Go ahead and remove one of the getter
methods, and tell me what error
you start getting as soon as you don't
have one of those public getters.