What is design? Design is deliberative, purposive planning.
As far as software is concerned, this translates into solving some problem.
Given in a, as a set of requirements. What is engineering?
Engineering adds in the element of science and mathematics. And
we're going to see the role of formal methods play in software design.
What is craft? Craft is some sort of skilled occupation.
Those skills come from long experience, and we'll see that with software design,
the more experience you have on a particular kind of problem the better.
And what is art? Art is the conscious use of skills. Taste and
creative imagination in the production of aesthetic objects. And
later in this lesson, we'll see that, certain design principles and
aesthetic principles can play a role in software design.