Let's see now what is a Process Control Block.
A Process Control Block is a data structure that the operating system
maintains for every one of the processes that it manages.
From what we saw so far,
the Process Control Block must contain process state like the program counter,
the stack pointer, really, all of the CPU registers, their values,uh, as they
relate to the particular process, various memory mappings that are necessary for
the virtual to physical address translation for the process, and other things.
Some of the other useful information includes a list of open files, for
instance, information that's useful for
scheduling, like how much time this particular process had executed in a CPU,
how much time it should be allocated in the future.
This depends on the process priority, etc.
The Process Control Block data structure, or
PCB as we call it, is created when the process is initially created itself.
And it's also initialized at that time.
For instance, the program counter will be set to point to
the very first instruction in that process.
Certain fields of the process are updated whenever the process state changes.
For instance, when a process requests more memory,
the operating system will allocate more memory and
will establish new valid virtual to physical memory mappings for this process.
This will reflect the memory limits information as well as
the information regarding the valid virtual address regions for this process.
And this perhaps doesn't happen too often.
Other fields of this PCB structure change pretty frequently.
For instance, during the execution of the program,
the program counter changes on every single instruction.
We certainly don't want the operating system for
every instruction that the process executes to
have to spend time to write this new PCB value for the program counter.
The way this is handled is that the CPU has a dedicated register, which it
uses to track the current program counter for the currently executing process.
This PC register will get automatically updated by the CPU on
every new instruction.
It is the operating system's job, however, to make sure to collect and
save all the information that the CPU maintains for
a process, and to store it in the Process Control Block structure whenever that
particular process is no longer running on the CPU.