So to help you understand more about what makes a good feature, remember what we
discussed just previously, which is the various characteristics of what makes it
a good feature, repeatable, compact, and having kinds of information that
would allow us to match reliably across the image what are the features.
So, just for us to play around with this, here's a simple example that we
will play with, the three musicians image from Pablo Picasso.
I'm going to, in this one, put up different boxes, and
the center of those boxes is what I'm going to suggest is what you
want to say are good features features are not.
So total there are eight boxes.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
All right, the question that I have for you is, so
right in the middle of these boxes, for example here, or here, or
here, or here, or here, and again, you can consider them to be lot,
rather big, to include various types of things here.
Or here and here and here.
Are those good features?
Okay?
So please, select the ones, on this image, which you can make for good features.
Again, remember, there are one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
Eight regions I'm asking you to look at.