Let's do the first one,
it says TextView = new TextView, and
then we pass context in as an input
parameter to the constructor.
The problem with this line of code is
that we're creating a new object but
we're not storing it
properly in a variable.
We're saying that the variable
should have data type TextView but
we forget to give it a variable name.
So the correct code would
look something like this.
TextView followed by a variable name and
then equals new TextView.
You can call the variable
name something else but
we just chose to use textView
with a lower case t.
So in this case,
the error was missing variable name.
Let's do the next one.
It says, image view img = new ImageView.
The problem here is that this
is not a valid object data type.
Android defines a class called ImageView
with a capital I and a capital V and
it's squished together into one word.
A valid class name can't
have any spaces in it.
The variable name looks okay, and
then creating the new image
view looks okay as well.
So the only error was that it
had an incorrect class name.
In the third statement, we're trying
to create a new toggle button.
It says ToggleButton button
= create ToggleButton.
We're calling the ToggleButton
class here, so
we need to use the Java keyword new,
not create.
And this is the correct code.
It says ToggleButton
button = new ToggleButton.
The problem here was not
using the Java keyword new.
New is the keyword that indicates that
we're trying to create a new object.
In the fourth statement,
we're trying to create a new toast.
You could've Google searched for
how to create a new toast and
then compared it with this code here.
The problem here is that toast needs
to be spelled with a capital T,
because this is a class name for Toast.
This is using a factory method
like we talked about earlier.
This creates a new toast object and
then it gets stored in this variable.
So the error here was just
an incorrect class name.
So now that we know how to create
objects, how do we use these objects?