The answer is true.
You should pause for a moment to
savour this fact which is really cool.
It's likely that your intuition from
sequential algorithms tells you that
the complexity of a tree algorithm
somehow depends on the height
of the tree.
So, that would lead you to
believe that the claim is false.
The tree after all could be very
unbalanced like a linear chain.
But the whole point of the Euler
tour technique is to turn the tree
into a list.
Once you've done that,
the tree-shape doesn't matter anymore.
Jeez-o-pete.
Of course, all this hinges on being
able to convert a computation into
an equivalent Euler tour computation,
which is not always possible.