Welcome to your first coding
exercise in the course.
We've put together a bunch of demo code
and exercises to accompany this course.
The absolute easiest way to get the code
is to download it from the downloadable
section of the classroom.
However, if you're familiar with GitHub,
you can also find the code here
at github.com/udacity/ud867.
Once you've downloaded the code it
should look something like this.
Inside the Run Your First Task
directory, you'll find a bunch of files.
These three, the Gradle folder and
the two Gradle-W files are part of
the Gradle wrapper that
we already talked about.
The files you want to concern
yourself with are build.gradle and
solution.gradle.
Every single one of these exercises
will have that pair of files.
The build.Gradle file contains all of
the instructions for the exercise.
And the solution.radle file
contains all the solutions.
Let's open up the build.Gradle file and
your favorite text editor.
I'm going to use Sublime.
All right, so here's the instructions
for your very first exercise.
I'll let you read them on your own.
Your challenges are going to be using
the Gradle wrapper to execute a task and
then modifying that
task in a simple way.
Remember if you get stuck,
check out the solution.gradle file and
it'll help you out.
All right, give it a try and
then see if you can answer
the question on the next slide.
Once you're done running
your first task,
you should be able to
answer this question.
What is my favorite kind of candy?
Is it chocolate, taffy,
jelly beans, or bacon?
And while you're at it, did you
go ahead and run your first task?
If so, was it awesome?