Your shell, and every other program for
that matter, has a working directory.
You can think of this as
the directory that it's looking at or
focused on, or the one that it
uses as the default location for
most commands to find files in.
For instance,
when you've run LS before, you got
a listing of files in a directory.
But which directory?
LS with no arguments will list files in
the shell's current working directory.
If you want to know
the path of that directory,
you can use the pwd command which
stands for print working directory, and
this says that here the working
directory is /home/vagrant.
You can change the working
directory with the CD command for
change directory.
There are a few
different ways to use it.
You can give the full path
of a directory Like var/log.
Or you can give the name of a directory
that's inside the current one.
For instance,
if there were a directory called three,
you could say cd three, but there's not.
And you can also use cd..
to go up the tree to the parent of
the current directory, for instance,
from var/log to var.
So let's go back to where we started,
and you'll see that inside /home/vagrant
there's something called ocean.
Well, that's a directory,
and so we can cd into it.
And if you take a look
inside the ocean directory,
you'll see it has some contents.
So using the cd and ls commands,
map out the sub directories and
files you find inside
that ocean directory.
Put them here in these boxes.