So surely let's say you are in
a free throw competition right.
And if you win you get
one hundred dollars.
So you have two options,
either you get two shots.
Each with two thirds probability of
being made or three shots each with
one half probative you made you win
if you make at least one shot.
Which one would you take?
>> Okay.
>> Feel free to use the board.
>> Yeah I think I will.
So let me just.
I'm going to trying to catch out
make sure I've understood and
we'll try to figure it out.
So I think this kind of
lends itself to a tree.
So you said, two shots with two-thirds
or three shots with a half.
So.
Either I, what's the word,
success or fail.
So that's two-thirds of the chance
of success and one-third fail.
And I get two shots like that.
Yeah?
>> Yes.
>> And so I want there to be at least
one success so I could draw something in
here but there's no point because
>> Like
already if I win on
the first shot I'm good.
Yes.
The other one was the same thing but
this time I'm just going to shorten
success to S, fail and each one
>> One's a half.
Okay.
So I think the easiest way to
evaluate each of these would be to
look at the probability of failure.
And then if I fail all the way
through then whatever's left over is
me winning $100 or so.
So the probability of failure like
these I'm assuming this is independent.
I guess I might be disappointed.
>> Yeah. No, no, no.
>> If i miss the first time.
>> [CROSSTALK]
>> Yeah.
>> But if I
>> Okay, okay.
So so
the probability of failing in this case,
is going to be a third
times a third is a ninth.
>> Okay.
>> And in this case.
>> Where i've got three shots
the probability of failing is
a half cubed, a half times a half,
which is an eight.
So, and I want the biggest
possible probability of success.
>> Okay.
>> So
i would rather go with this version.
Because a ninth is less then an eight.
Yes.
So yeah that's great.
So what if you had to
make two shots to win?
>> Okay.
So if I had to make two shots to win,
how could I okay so I need to
modify my diagram a little bit.
So I can add bits in.
So on the top one.
And I guess, so now,
the easiest thing to calculate is
the probability of success on here,
because I'm going to have,
I want to have the probability new,
because it's the new situation, [LAUGH]
>> Yeah.
[LAUGH]
>> Of S, is going to be two-thirds
squared, which is four ninth's, this
one is a little bit more complicated.
>> Yes.
But I can do that S, F.
So here this track I'm done.
So that's good, so this is a half.
Okay, so now I'm just going to
highlight the ones I'm
interested in because this is
looking a bit more complicated.
So this is good.
This is good.
These are both with two successes.
This isn't okay and here.
Okay I need to i'm missing
a bit of tree in there.
But.
Okay i'm sorry about my diagram.
[LAUGH]
Okay and then.
It's going to be.
Is this and this is okay.
And anything after that
includes two fails.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So now,
the probability of the new success for
here.
I'm going to have to multiply and
then add.
>> Yes.
>> So
I'm going to have a half times a half.
So that's a quarter.
Plus a half times a half times a half.
And another one of those.
So that's one-eighth is that.
And that's another eighth.
So that's two times one-eighth.
Picture's a quarter so
the whole thing is a half.
So the probability of success,
in this case,
is better for the new situation because
a half is bigger than four-ninths.
>> Yes, actually that sounds perfect.
You're ready to make a hundred dollars.
[LAUGH] Only if I can shoot.
>> [LAUGH] Awesome.