>> Continuous delivery is the next
logical step after continuous
integration.
Now you know that after each commit,
developers need to integrate their code
and see if it builds and passes tests.
Hopefully, it will.
And if not, you'll get very fast
feedback about what went wrong.
>> But the code itself is not the only
thing that is needed to get the product
in front of the customer.
The code has to be deployed
somewhere in the right environment.
It has to be tested for
big picture issues beyond just,
does this method work?
It should be tested for usability,
performance and security.
A lot of these steps can be automated,
like configuration of the environment or
the deployed processes themselves.
Some of the tests can be out
of it as well, some cannot.
>> And this brings us to some
elements that form the basis of
continuous delivery.
Every commit is treated,
as a potential release candidate.
Feedback is immediate, so
that the team can fix problems ASAP.
All steps of the process are visible
to every member of the team to
promote collaboration.
Build once, deploy anywhere.
Binary should be built only once to
avoid hard to debug problems that may be
caused by rebuilding in slightly
different environments.
>> And the process that the code
undergoes before being deployed is often
called the continuous delivery pipeline.
Let's explore the parts of this pipeline
and discuss what you gain by using it.