So, m equals Vy is the last column.
And, here's something, just because of what we said before,
these singular values of A, that's d, well the singular values of
A are the square roots of the eigenvalues of A transpose A,
and the columns of V are the eigenvector of A transpose A.
So, I could show you this, it's actually pretty, well, I was going to say but
you know, if I just write out this,
since A is we know is written to UDV, transpose.
Okay.
A transpose A, is just that transpose, so that's VD transpose U transpose.
Well, okay, U is an orthogonal vector, so
U transpose is also U inverse, so that's an identity, okay, so that goes away.
D transpose D, well D is a diagonal matrix, so D transpose D is just, I'll,
I'm just going to call it D squared, it's just the squared values, okay?
And V transpose V.
So, I'm just, so I'm just going to write that A transpose A is equal to VD
squared V transpose, and that is the equation of the eigen-decomposition,
where V is the, eigenvectors of A transpose A.
And by pulling out the very last one,
I'm pulling out the eigenvector with the smallest value of A transpose A.
Just to recap.
Given that, what we have is Am equal 0 for some long A, what we do is we find
the eigenvector of A transpose A with the smallest eigenvalue, and that's our m.
That is the set of values that create the calibration matrix for us.
Cool.