So this has actually been something
that's been, kind of been thought up and
hoped for a long time.
In fact, as early as 1908,
Lippmann proposed that we could actually
use this to generate what is referred
to by him as integral photography.
He actually was a physics person,
and he won a Nobel prize for
this kind of stuff.
And again, you know,
lot of fun stuff was done by
actually doing the physics
on the sensors like this.
So, I should, of course,
spend a brief moment on the history
of light field cameras.
The concept has been around for
a long time, as early as 1908.
And Lippmann, a Nobel laureate
in physics, actually introduced
the concept of integral photography and
basically talked about how, actually,
you know, the physics of light
itself could be used to reproduce
colors based on interference
patterns and stuff like that.
Since then, much work has happened.
1930, they kind of constructed
parallax panograms.
In 1992, Adelson and
Wang proposed a plenoptic camera and
used it to generate stereo
from a single lens.
And in fact, some of the stuff
that I just showed you,
was based on the work that they did.
Similarly then,
kind of early stuff happened,
in terms of building light fields.
Again, the example of using the UV and
the SD kinds of stuff, planes,
UV plane and SD plane was based
on some work these people did.
And of course, the plenoptic
camera that you also see now.
Actually what has happened
now in about 2012,
Lytro actually invented this light field
camera which is commercially available.
There are advanced versions of this now.
When we looked at some of our
earlier cameras, we saw various
cameras which had an array of
cameras connected to each other.
They can also be used to
generate light fields.
Much more advanced stuff has
happened in this space, and
I encourage you to look it up on
your own and study more about it.
But again, you know these,
this is one of commercially available
light field camera these days.