Okay, let's take a look at the code.
Over here, in activity_main.xml
is the code for the new button.
It's very similar to the other buttons,
and the onClick is showDailySpecial.
And see here.
Just the third button.
It just shows up as another
button on the main screen.
And here's the code in main
activity that gets invoked
when the user clicks show
daily special button.
Very simple, takes a view,
because it's a button on click and
it sends an intent to start
the show daily special activity.
Let's take a look at
the Show Daily Special Activity itself.
So here I hard wired the daily special.
You can make that be whatever you want.
This is the same code for
putting information into the info box.
This is for
the other screens like show recipe.
We get the TextView.
We set the heading.
And we put information into the info
box in this case the DailySpecial.
And then down here, the order online,
this is just the method
that gets invoked by the order
online button, as before.
We just send an intent to
start the OrderDinnerActivity.
Passing the dinner,
in this case, the daily special.
Now moving onto the layout file for
show daily special.
It's a scroll view with a linear layout.
It uses the info box fragment
to display the daily special.
And it has a button for
ordering online, and that's it.